foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guests this week are two
awesome cannabis researchers Paul coxon
and Patrick veezy Paul has been on the
podcast before on episode 59 talking
about his paper on cannabis deficiencies
be sure to check out that episode if you
haven't already and also this is a good
one to go to the podcast page at
kisorganics.com just click on the learn
tab then podcast I will have links to
all the papers so you can follow along
as well as a link to their new website
that shares all their research in one
central location it's a great resource
Paul has been working in the hemp world
as a researcher since 2018 and in plant
science research since 2016. he has a
background in Horticulture agroecology
and floriculture from his time at NC
State currently he's pursuing his PhD at
the University of Kentucky while working
with Industrial Hemp Paul's primary
research focuses on rhizosphere
management and brings strengths in plant
mineral fertility plant hormones and
growth Regulators substrate research
General Diagnostics and Greenhouse and
growth chamber expertise
in addition to a strong Greenhouse
background Paul is also literate in
field level agronomic processes Paul's
passion is for mentorship and sharing
the research process with undergraduate
students
when not doing research Paul and his dog
Groot can be found hiking in local state
and national parks
Patrick visi has been working in the
hemp world as a researcher since 2019
and has a plant science researcher since
2018. he has a background in
Horticulture and floriculture from his
time as an undergraduate researcher at
NC State currently is pursuing his
master of science at North Carolina
State and is focusing on Greenhouse
substrates for cannabis and other
floriculture crops Patrick's primary
research focuses on plant mineral
fertility substrate research and general
Diagnostics
I was super excited to talk to them
about their latest published research on
cannabis and hemp now on to the show
hi Paul hi Patrick thanks for coming on
the show today
hey great to be here thanks so much Todd
thanks for having us
all right well let's uh let's go ahead
and start with Paul I know you've been
on the podcast before but can you tell
listeners just a little bit about
yourself
yeah sure
um my name is Paul coxon
um currently I am at the University of
Kentucky working on my PhD I'm working
with the hemp Agronomy team here under
the direction of Dr Bob Pierce
um and a lot of the work we're going to
talk about today was actually done at NC
State
um and Patrick was heavily involved if
not one of the driving forces behind
pretty much all this work and this was
completed like I said at NC State under
the direction of Dr O'Brien whipker who
does Plant Nutrition work there
that's awesome and and Patrick can you
tell us a little about yourself as well
yeah I am Patrick Beezy I'm a master's
student at NC State under the advice of
Dr Brian whitker and I currently focus
on substrates and prolite replacements
for cannabis and other floriculture
crops most of this work was completed
while I was an undergrad but we're still
working with cannabis heavily at NC
State under Dr Brian woodgar's program
it sounds like a great program I I love
the research that you guys have already
put out for those that aren't aware
Paul's already been on the podcast he
put out an excellent paper that we've
talked about on the podcast called the
characterization of nutrient disorders
the Cannabis sativa so I highly suggest
checking that out
um
but Paul can you tell us a little bit
about
um
the phosphorus paper that we're going to
discuss and why that was an area of
inquiry that you decide to pursue with
your research
yeah for sure
um so to kind of begin with um you kind
of have to go back a little bit
um we've been working
um in hemp
um under with Brian whipper for quite
some time and uh when we first started
um the we really didn't have a lot of
scientific foundations for nutrition
work so there weren't really Leaf tissue
standards there weren't really uh
externally verified replicated
um fertility work that had been done
um and so kind of our our journey
through hemp we we actually first paper
that we put out was a General survey so
we went to a larger operation and we
surveyed quite a few cultivars we took
Leaf tissue did a survey got some you
know General upper and lower ranges and
we published that and from that we kind
of had a good idea of what you know an
adequate fertility regime might be and
so we kind of springboarded from that
into the nutrient deficiency work so
trying to really categorize the those
visual symptoms and marry them with the
critical Leaf tissue values and one
interesting thing we saw out of that
study was the phosphorus deficiency it
came screaming in very early and uh you
know the tissue values were extremely
low and we started looking at some of
the the popular press stuff out of there
and recommendations and we were kind of
shocked at how high some of the early
phosphorus recommendations in hemp and
cannabis were and so we decided to do
kind of a rate study which was the the
first paper that we'll talk about here
so we had a phosphorus fertility rates
ranging from
3.75 to 30 parts per million and then
kind of explored that and then once we
kind of finished that up Patrick got
really excited about the upper ranges
and wanted to see you know what would
happen at those higher concentrations so
then his work kind of married into that
line of inquiry and then he tested the
upper ranges so that's kind of the
background of this paper and uh how it
all got started
awesome so the the title of the paper
we're going to discuss first is called
impact of phosphorus on Cannabis sativa
reproduction cannabinoids and terpenes
Paul is the lead author on that and it
was published in September of November
of 2020. apologies
um before we get into that though can
you talk a little bit about
phosphorus in relation to
plant growth plant health and maybe even
more specifically with with cannabis in
what you found from your original your
original work
yeah for sure
um you know like I said phosphorus was a
an easy low-hanging fruit early on just
because
um the the massive amounts that were
being recommended to some Growers
um
and so um physiologically speaking
um phosphorus is uh really important in
Floral development a lot of crops it's
an immobile element and so essentially
um what that means is that it will
um
or I'm sorry it's a a mobile element
um and a Spoke there
um and it will
um come in pretty early on
um and the plants will be pretty stunted
um you'll have this olive green spotting
um on the lower and older leaves and
then you know that will progress up the
plant and eventually you'll get some
defoliation and like I said an overall
stunting of biomass so with its impacts
on you know floral development and then
also that kind of stunting was kind of
our early interest in it and that kind
of segued into some of the rates that we
chose
um
so I wanted to ask you so you saw in
popular literature around cannabis a lot
of very high application rates so was
your initial hypothesis that maybe we
were in general over applying phosphorus
as an industry
was that sort of where you started
yeah most definitely
um if you look across the board at you
know say a floor culture
um in general and everything
um you're you're very rarely going to
see phosphorus concentrations as high as
we're being recommended
um and and furthermore if you you know
over apply phosphorus
um you can get some some pretty
pronounced
antagonisms and uh um lock out some
nutrients
um so I I was a little surprised that
some people hadn't experienced more
issues with the extremely high
concentrations that we were seeing
well I'd add too that we're also dealing
with phosphorus shortages and over
application of phosphorus leads to algal
blooms and other environmental issues so
there's definitely some sustainability
challenges around
you know the overapplication of P so I
think it's great if we can figure out
what's you know what's optimal for
for this plant
take me through your I guess take me
through this paper take me through your
research then and what you guys found
sure I'd love to
um so the first thing I would like to do
is just acknowledge all the people that
actually worked on this project you
mentioned earlier that Dr whipper's
program produces a lot of great research
and honestly that's really because of uh
who he is as a person how he runs his
team and then kind of the the team
mentality and and uh group support that
we have so I'd like to definitely
recommend that uh you know you all take
into account that this was not just you
know a one-person show it was truly a
lab effort and everything
um but like I said we uh we wanted to
kind of uh explore the uh lower end of
phosphorus fertility
so typically when you're looking at
nutrients
um you have you know your deficiency
level and then you kind of have this
linear increase for your nutrients and
at some point it's going to Plateau on
the upper end
um for both you know biomass production
but then also
um the accumulation of that nutrient in
the plants and if you get too high
you'll actually see a growth decrease
and and we know that just from
literature that'll kind of have this you
know plateau and then decreasing type
relationship and so we were more focused
on the beginning portion of that curve
so we chose lower phosphorus
concentrations and our rates were
informed from our previous work and our
surveys so from our survey we knew that
you know in leaf tissue across you know
a couple cultivars you're going to see
you know 0.26 to 0.43 percent phosphorus
in the leaves and that work comes out of
gen Kowalski which is another paper that
we had published in 20 20 I can provide
that link to you to add if you would
like great
um
so we started at 3.75 parts per million
and we went up to 30 parts per million
phosphorus so our rates were 3.75
7.5
11.25 15 22.5 and 30 parts per million
phosphorus so those were our six comps
concentrations
and we wanted to take the plants from
the very beginning of their life cycle
all the way to full bud maturity
um so it's 16 weeks eight weeks
vegetative and then another eight weeks
reproductive and we wanted to just kind
of track how the plants developed over
time and then at the end analyze the
buds and see what impacts the
cannabinoids and terpenes if there were
any that these phosphorus concentrations
had so that's kind of a general overview
of the paper
yes so a couple of quick questions I had
so is this paper is based all of on one
specific cultivar is that correct
that is correct Okay so
one question I'm going to have right
away is how much variability do you
think we'll get across
cultivars as we look at different all
the genetic diversity in cannabis has
anyone looked at that yet
yeah so um that's a great question it's
something that a lot of people ask
um and uh like I said I mentioned that
paper from Jen Kowalski she looked at
aox Cherry 2.0 Cherry Citrus Cherry
cross cherry wine early pearly Electra
endurance Midwest Stout severe Haze and
sweetened as well as a cherry Cross by
Cherry winecross and Chic categorize
each and every individual one of those
and looked at the phosphorus
concentrations in the leaf tissue and
oddly enough
um you know we we saw some differences
um some very significant differences but
they all kind of fell within this
General range of 0.26 to 0.43 phosphorus
in the leaves and that's really the
driving force and the reason we chose
baox for this study was because that was
a a high performer a very consistent
genetic consistent phenotype for us in
our research but yes you are right
different environmental factors abiotic
factors cultural factors and genetic
factors will impact this slightly okay
okay now that's I mean that's great and
I love the methodology of your of your
paper here um
I thought you guys did a really good job
with that uh one one question I have
then so these varying uh P
concentrations they were supplied so
let's just take the
3.75 PPM concentration you applied that
every single irrigation all the way
through from vegetative through
flowering is that that is correct at the
same concentration the whole time
constant liquid feed of that fertilizer
concentration throughout so no bumping
up or bumping down or boosting during
flowering
um and again that comes from some
preliminary work that we did looking at
comparing constant liquid feed versus
variable feed that we're still sifting
through the data on okay okay
um
great well what uh I guess take me a
little through some of the things that
you measured in your in your study
and then we can talk about about some of
your results
yeah so um early on
um in the vegetative stage um four weeks
in we took some height and diameter
measurements so just kind of looking at
a general stature of the plants and how
they may be growing over time and um
irregardless of phosphorus concentration
we actually saw
um the very no statistical differences
between either height or plant diameter
and diameter is just the average of two
widths so
um which was kind of surprising to see
given our early nutrient deficiency work
um you know I kind of surmise that some
of that may have to do with just the
um overall cultural conditions um
growing in them we did have a little bit
of phosphorus in our water from the test
values that we ran but four weeks in we
didn't see much of a um a different
so you would you'd expected to see a
little bit more of a pronounced
efficiency at that point in time or
stunting on the lowest
concentration
yeah yeah
interesting
um so four weeks not a big difference
what happened is you move forward or
were there any other metrics at Key
metrics that you wanted to touch on
yeah um so early on um like I said we
were just kind of tracking biomass
production plant height plant diameter
um but you know you kind of fast forward
to eight weeks um and that's where you
really started seeing um the statistical
differences and again this is still
um vegetative so we did see
um you know this kind of
um variable response and plant height
and diameter but for the most part
plants that were um you know sitting
right at about 11 and a quarter parts
per million phosphorus above that
concentration they were all
statistically similar and so
um we were again kind of surprised that
that was a lower concentration and we
saw the same for a total above ground
biomass so half of the plants in the
study we destructively harvested at that
eight week vegetative stage because then
the remainder of the half
we took out to the full 16 weeks of
flowering
okay
um and what uh
what did you find then at the full 16
weeks
yeah so um there's there's a nice figure
in the paper that kind of categorizes
the the lack of
um differences that we were seeing at
that 11 and a quarter
um parts per million phosphorus
concentration so I'd encourage you all
to be looking along in the paper while
I'm talking here
um but essentially
um once we got to the
um actually I'm going to back up a
little bit here and I'm actually going
to talk about the leaf tissue because we
did take Leaf tissue concentrations at
eight weeks
okay
um so one interesting thing that we saw
um you know so early on very little
difference that we're seeing in those
phosphorus concentrations once you get
to that eight week Mark you know we're
seeing some differences there but at a
much lower concentration I was
personally expecting something around 30
parts per million to be adequate for
um hemp that we trialled but one thing
that was interesting is that when you
actually looked at the leaf tissue so
after eight weeks under the leaf tissue
um
uh most recently matured leaves you saw
that
um as we increase the phosphorus
concentration we did not see an upper
response or a plateau response like we
saw in the plant biomass so the plant
was just sucking up the phosphorus and
allocating it to the leaves and we
didn't see an upper concentration there
even at our highest concentration so
this was a really interesting find
because it kind of maybe points to the
fact that cannabis may be really good at
sequestering that phosphorus and
actually storing it and so that may be
um kind of a factor that could help
explain why even at these extremely high
phosphorus concentrations that we were
seeing recommended we weren't
necessarily seeing any of these
phosphorus toxicities
interesting so
just I'm looking at the graph here and
we'll have links to these papers so
people can follow along I'm on table two
here and it looks like
you you saw statistically significant
increase in height and diameter and
above ground dry weight but not in below
ground dry weight or route to shoot
ratio across all concentrations and then
that significance in height and weight
started at 11.25 PPM
all the way to 30 and was essentially
there wasn't a lot of significance
within that range did I state that
correctly
that is correct yeah so essentially
above 11.25 parts per million you're
going to receive the same height and the
same diameter and the same above ground
um dry weight or biomass even if you're
applying more phosphorus
now I had always Associated phosphorus
with
um root growth and root health is that
not something that you saw in this study
in terms of there being any significance
at different concentrations
uh yeah you're correct um it does have a
role a large part in um root development
razor sphere management
um branching Etc
um and it was a little bit surprising to
see
um I I think in this study
um just looking at the root balls so
when you when we were terminating we
kind of broke apart a few rupoles I
think it more had to do with the fact
that um the rhizosphere volume was
actually a little more limited and so
maybe if those would have been larger
pots or even some maybe like quar blocks
we could have maybe seen that those
differences come through
okay so you think that one of the
limitations might have been just overall
root space
yes correct okay yeah because I'm
looking at your photo of these plants
and
um
they're not the most robust plants I've
seen
um no ever I don't know a nice way to
put that
um they look just visually you know to
me a little maybe a little bit nitrogen
deficient
um what what did you think of your of
the overall plant health
in relation to this experiment I guess
that would be my first question
yeah so
um we saw the same thing
um you know uh you're very you're very
correct
um you know sometimes we as scientists
were really good at running experiments
but sometimes our plants may not be the
uh the most uh beautiful
um when it comes to that aspect but um
when we actually looked at all of our
macro and micronutrients we were still
within our survey ranges so while the
plants may not look the most overly
robust and green and dark foliage
um the the tissue values are still
within a healthy range okay oh good
um
so moving forward from eight weeks I I
would assume you would start to see more
more drastic spread in terms of plant
expression and plant Health
um what what happened at that point
yeah so um again we uh sampled at about
12 weeks
um looking at plant height and diameter
and there we did start seeing more of a
trend so we saw the the highest height
at a higher concentration so 22 and a
half to 30 parts per million as well as
diameter so once they go into that
reproductive phase and start
reallocating nutrients from maybe older
leaves into developing sinks which are
going to be your flowers we did start
seeing more differences there which
again was a little surprising you know
given how quickly the nutrient
deficiency came in from the deficiency
study but at 12 weeks we started
releasing that value of those higher
fertility concentrations
you know one thing that's common in the
industry is to have these uh you know PK
boosters where you're you're applying
high phosphorus high potassium in flour
how does how does that reflective upon
your study in terms of what your
findings were do you do you feel that
that phosphorus is potentially
beneficial or do you think that maybe
the potassium is providing some more of
the benefit that people are seeing from
these applications
um
I guess what are your thoughts on that
yeah that's uh that's a really
controversial uh question there because
there's a lot of people on both sides
that have very strong opinions on that
um so I'm gonna speak more from like a
plant physiology standpoint on that
um typically what you see in most crops
is that um there will be this kind of
lag phase behind
um the induction of the reproductive
phase versus the vegetative phase
and most of the time what you're seeing
is that the nutrients that that plant is
taking up in the vegetative stage a good
portion of those will get reallocated
into that developing sink but you will
have this slight overlap between where
it's switching from vegetative to
reproductive and I think what a lot of
people are seeing in the industry could
be that kind of lag and overlap
different crops will have a different
kind of lag phase and uh you know I
think that we kind of saw that thumb
here
um I don't know necessarily if it's
going to be the potassium or the
phosphorus that's giving that benefit
um but like I said I'm going to answer
that question more from a plant
physiology standpoint and kind of say
that you know it's not just this
complete switch where once they go
reproductive they're not going to take
up any more nutrients
um
so as plants which
from
you know a vegetative stage to a
flowering stage as they're you know
completing their life cycle
they are still taking up nutrients and
the ratio of those nutrients
I assume changes
um
so you're saying that there's a lag
between as they make that switch in
terms of what nutrients are most needed
is that what you're kind of getting at
yeah yeah essentially so um you know
it's when a plant switches from a
vegetative stage to reproductive stage
it's not going to be an automatic on off
switch where they're going to
immediately stop taking up any
phosphorus any potassium any magnesium
um you know they're going to continue
taking up those nutrients as they're
transitioning but eventually
um they'll start slowing down on that
uptake at least
um from uh from a common physiology
understanding and you can kind of see
that in other crops as they start
dropping leaves and they start senessing
and ending their life
um you know the plant's just gonna at
some point stop taking up those
nutrients as much as it would in say a
vegetative stage and it's going to start
heavily reallocating what it's already
taken up
yeah I mean that is a contentious
subject in the industry in terms of what
an optimal harvestable plant looks like
some people really like that senescence
the the colors and and knowing that
there's not as much chlorophyll in the
leaves and other people will say you can
really increase your your weights at
Harvest by pushing the plant harder and
maybe having what you know looks like
less of a finished plant I guess at
Harvest Time
maybe higher levels of nutrients in that
plant tissue are accessible to the plant
in the media prior to harvest so
I I think that's an interesting question
I'd love to see more research on that
oh we would too
um it's definitely needed so looking at
uptake partitioning and reallocation in
industrial hemp would definitely be the
next kind of iteration of this level of
inquiry
um so it's been something that I've
wanted to do for a very long time I'm
just given the the
current state of understanding and
knowledge that exists within the
Cannabis industry and within the
literature yeah I mean I'm sure for both
of you there's a million experiments
that you have in your head that you
would love to you would love to get
around to
um at some point
um well let's let's get back to your
paper sorry I kind of went off topic
there
um
were we were we at 12 weeks right now or
were you up to 16 weeks where would you
like to continue on from
yeah we can we can kind of go to the the
bud results
um and kind of the the cannabinoid and
terpene results if you'd like great yeah
yeah so once once we finished uh the
experiment again we took height width
biomass and we took fresh bug weight
um one thing I will say about that is um
a lot of the bud material we were
analyzing a composite so we're looking
at the the terminal Bud
um an axillary Chute
um terminal bud and then a Bud from the
interior of the plant
um so we were kind of limited in taking
um our dry mass and so that's why we
took fresh weight on this but I will say
I wouldn't lean too heavily on the the
brush weight just given the natural
variability that's going to exist plant
to plant in that
um
but like I said we did a composite
sample
um
sorry did you have something to add
no I mean since he paused I was just
going to ask if you did any any trimming
on these plants or pruning
um during the flower cycle or not
or if you just kind of let them grow
that was just one question I had
yeah so for the for the purpose of this
experiment we um did not do any trimming
so just kind of as they were throughout
the growing cycle and the reason we
decided to do that is um we didn't want
to potentially interfere with removing
biomass that could still have some
phosphorus resources that could be
allocated for the bud or those
developing reproductive leaves
that makes sense
um okay sorry keep going
cool
um so then
um like I said we looked at the the
different cannabinoids um and then some
terpenes
um and the results were kind of
surprising so you know after that eight
weeks of vegetative growth or sorry
reproductive growth
um we really saw again this kind of
plateau at about 15 parts per million
phosphorus so when you look at your
Delta 9 THC
um you know and then if you also kind of
looked at CBD and CBC those had a
plateau at around that 11 and a quarter
parts per million so 11 and a quarter to
15 parts per million above that
concentration we really didn't see an
increase
in those cannabinoids so again kind of
mirroring what we saw early on at that
kind of plateau range in the the lower
phosphorus concentrations that we
studied
that's that's really interesting
um that's much lower than I would have
expected yeah
yeah no it was very surprising for us
too
um which is part of the reason we were
really um excited to publish this and
tried to get it out um pretty quickly
um but one thing I I will mention on
this
um in the paper
um these are listed as
um milligrams per gram
um so when you're looking at those
tables don't assume that that's a
percentage
um
okay that makes sense
yeah
um so when we when we looked at the
actual like um active pools
um so everyone's pretty familiar
um with kind of the acid tools versus
the the active pools
um they're um in the paper we broke
those up and we analyzed them separately
because we wanted to see okay so
if you are under a state that is going
to regulate off of Delta 9 versus total
THC
um and then looking at you know what's
in your acid pool and what's in your
decarboxylated pool
um we we kind of separated those so when
you look at the acid pool on the acid
pools which is where most of your
cannabinoids are come from
um when they get decarboxylated there
um again we saw a very pronounced
Plateau at that 11 and a quarter parts
per million phosphorus for cbda thca
total THC Total CBD and total
cannabinoids when you kind of sum them
all together and then divide by the
total cannabinoids analyzed which was
again pretty
um surprising a lot of times in science
you don't see something that cut and dry
um but this was this was a pretty strong
trend
so almost like a bell curve like a kind
of uh with 3.75 on one side and 30 on
the other it kind of Peaks at the 11.25
range for almost all your cannabinoids
slightly
maybe it's more of a um
roller coaster going up to the top and
then just coming down a little bit
yeah yeah more like that so kind of kind
of the first half of like a bell curve
or a horseshoe so you know you're coming
up you're coming up you're coming up and
then you level off kind of at that bend
and then you kind of stop
now was that sickness statistically
significant I couldn't say it between
the 11.25 treatment and the 30 parts per
million treatment and the difference you
saw there because I see that your total
cannabinoids for example are higher at
11.25 you know your total THC is higher
was that considered significant though
it was not statistically significant and
part of the reason there is if you look
at the standard deviations
um we had some quite a bit of
variability a little bit more than I was
hoping for
um again it's important when when
looking at any type of graph or figure
to look at how much the data is varying
um and so our standard deviations were a
bit higher but you are correct between
11.25 and 30 parts per million even
though the means were higher at 11.25
compared to the 30.
um you know they were not they were
statistically similar
okay so if we were just going off this
research
in this table we could confidently say
that 11.25 PPM
is going to produce
better cannabinoids than 3.75 but you
can't confidently say that 30 PPM is
necessarily worse than 11.25 other than
the fact you may be over applying
phosphorus based on
these charts
yeah so it's it's kind of hard to make a
sweeping generalizations
um in the sciences and everything I
think everyone's pretty pretty well
aware that based on you know your vapor
pressure deficit what type of Lights
you're running what temperature you're
going for you know are you using kind of
a living bed or are you working in an
inner media you know all of all of these
recommendations will change and again
when you add into that you know the
slight
um cultivar differences that you're
seeing it makes it really difficult to
make an absolute all-encompassing
definitive statement on this is
unequivocally the best phosphorus
concentration
um the thing I always recommend is you
know this is what the data's saying and
at the end of the paper we kind of give
a general range but to always make sure
you're correlating that back to Leaf
tissue values because if you're just
focusing on what you're applying once it
goes into your system you know microbes
may use some of it if you're amending
with microbes and you're going organic
and so that may decrease the available
phosphorus to the plant but your Leaf
tissue is always a good go-to because it
tells you how much phosphorus the plant
is actually getting which is again why
we started with the survey ranges you
know because if if you're in a highly
organic system and you're amending with
a lot of bone meal
it takes time for that to break down you
know there's a cost as that phosphorus
goes to the microbes and then gets you
know mineralized with the plant and so
you really want to fine-tune your own
specific operation by checking your Leaf
tissue
yeah absolutely I I don't mean to imply
to listeners that uh this study is at
all definitive about optimal phosphorus
levels
um
and that there's still a lot of research
to do but I think that the trend that it
points to is is really interesting and I
think it would give people a starting
point for where to consider uh you know
starting a trial or experiment in their
own in their own garden or or facility
yeah absolutely
um I definitely agree there's way more
research that needs to be done other
scientists other cultivars need to be
studied we can only all get better
together as more and more data comes in
um but you know
um
kind of um going back to the the next
table in the paper where we looked at
the the terpenes
um pretty much across the board
um we saw a lot of variability and not a
lot of statistical significance
um and so you know we were we were
somewhat hoping that we could kind of
correlate these uh mineral nutrients
going into the system and potentially
see an impact there but really the only
one that we saw on impact in
um was I'm going to butcher this I think
it's granol or or Journal I can't
remember off the top of my head how to
pronounce that I do apologize
um and that one
um we actually saw lower concentrations
above the 11.25 parts per million for
that particular terpene
would you have expected phosphorus to
play a bigger role in terpene expression
based on what you know of the of how the
plant utilizes phosphorus as a mineral
so as far as like Upstream effects um in
the physiology
um you know your phosphorus your sulfur
your nitrogen are going to play kind of
a role in most enzymatic processes
um and so we were potentially thinking
that there could be some Downstream
effects
um but it was a long shot
um but you know you you miss 100 of the
shots you don't take so we wanted to try
and throw in this data set to see if we
could uh kind of quantify maybe some uh
far Downstream effects
oh no I think it's great that you guys
took that data I think it's really
interesting that you didn't see a
difference
I don't know what I would have
hypothesized but
um yeah that's very interesting so I'm
glad you guys did that
um
can you tell me a little about your
about the discussion probably your paper
and sort of what some of your your
conclusions were around around this uh
this trial
yeah so um you know when look at this
um the the story is kind of
complicated
um you know a lot of times it's it's
easy to sit down and give kind of a
straightforward story
um like you know we want everything to
be cut and dry but really the the
results of this paper
um that we go through in the discussion
um it's kind of like
um
we really want Growers to take this data
and apply it to their own operation so
you know if you're going for clones you
may have a different phosphorus
recommendation than if you're trying to
produce biomass for say a distillate
market versus you know quality bud
that's going to be sold to like you know
a uh just as a Distillery for
um
you know actually
smoking that that fresh bud so where
you're aesthetic is a lot more important
um so uh really
um
the best thing that I can I can comment
on for the discussion is
um you know are Leaf tissue values for a
phosphorus
um they were within the previously
reported values from Bryson and Mills
which was encouraging
um and again we compare that to some
early work that we did with Hunter
Landis in the survey
um and then like I said I mentioned the
the newer paper which in walski
um but you know early on we talk about
how plant height and width weren't
necessarily all that statistically
significant but later on
um you know we we did see those
increases so
yeah kind of a very very cursory summary
of the discussion
sure do you feel like
I mean because you applied the same rate
of phosphorus throughout the entire uh
life of the plant
would you just speculate that there may
be advantages to applying phosphorus at
different concentrations at different
plant stages
from a from a grower perspective
yeah
um so you know obviously if you have a
developing seedling
um you're not going to want to dump on
you know kind of a nutrient regiment for
like a a full-grown plant
um so most of the time
um you know there will be variability
within your nutrient program
um but as far as correlating that to
specific stages
um at this point I really do think that
we we need quite a bit more research
um you know going into that because a
lot of
um This research here
um is not necessarily a one-to-one
comparison
um or for most Growers because they are
on that variable regiment
um uh model and so you know one of the
things we have to do in science is kind
of go back to
um kind of the the least common
denominator there and we have to kind of
eliminate that variability from the
phosphorus so we apply that phosphorus
at a constant rate so that we don't get
any confounding effects from a variable
rate of phosphorification but I would
love to see this work continue and then
actually testing different regiments and
different timings
um so you know that I don't know if that
directly answers your question
yeah it's it's challenging
for me because in the on the industry
side most Growers don't have access to
Leaf tissue analysis
so we're relying on
visual symptoms and which can be very
challenging because there can be
confounding variables when as as you
know when it comes to deficiencies or
toxicities and a lot of those can relate
to
watering and environment so it can get
very confusing or were required to use
soil tests so a lot of what the work
that I'm doing is using
um
soil testing in soilless organic media
looking at like a malic-3 and a
saturated paste test and then
making decisions based on that you know
if we're talking about specifically with
phosphorus availability we look at the
pace test and see how much is in
solution and then make estimations off
of that as to how much phosphorus is
going to become available throughout the
growth cycle
and it gets even more complicated
because we have
microbes processing all of these
amendments like you mentioned with bone
meal or other P sources
it becomes very very challenging to know
exactly how much phosphorus the plant is
getting at any you know given stage of
growth or
any particular date and in its growth
cycle
yeah it does it does make it really
challenging and it's kind of one of
those things that I cringe every single
time I have to say it
um because I feel like I I just
constantly am advocating for nutrient uh
sorry Leaf tissue analyzes and like you
said it's not either acceptable to the
industry or it's just not common at all
um and there are a few other works out
there that I've seen potentially
correlating spectral Imaging to nutrient
concentration or even looking at say
like a pour through method or um you
know some sort of a leashing analysis
where you know what you're putting into
the system and then you can check what's
coming out at the other end either at
the you know draining from the pot or
from your you know slab and then trying
to extrapolate back out to that you know
what may be taken out by the plant but
again like you mentioned it gets
complicated because you also have the
microbes in there potentially algae but
you know know there's definitely more
research needed to try and potentially
find a quick and dirty method for the
industry you know so that we don't have
to rely on these costly
resources yeah and like you mentioned
affordable too because it that's a
that's a big issue for a lot of Growers
right now especially in the current
state of our
of where our industry is at nationally
which is I'm really curious to hear as
we move on to Patrick's work because one
thing that we found
in in our testing and just you know
correlating the data that we're getting
off of soil tests with plant health and
and yields in the facilities that we
work with is that we can apply
significantly lower levels of phosphorus
and even have lower like one of the best
performing facilities I work with has
consistently low available phosphorus
and yet if you if you look at their bud
and dry weight it's phenomenal so
I've always leaned towards lower P
levels so I'm really curious to hear uh
Paul or Patrick what you have to say in
terms of the research that you did if we
can move on to your paper how does that
sound
yeah
um I did want to make a comment on the
variable versus continuous phosphorus
rate
um
I think it also really stems back to
your production practices
here we were not pruning nor are we
defoliating the plant because phosphorus
is stored in those lower leaves and it's
mobile
so as the plant needs it has the ability
to move them up to those sinks which
would be your developing buds
so one of the things is that if you are
not pruning and you're not defoliating
you actually kind of have a small
storage unit in those lower leaves that
the plant's able to move up to where the
buds are developing
so you may not need to boost later in
the production cycle as you're having
Bud set however if a grower is pruning
or defoliating you are removing those
nutrients off the plant that could have
potentially been mobile to go to that
new sink
so I think with us using a continuous
rate and not pruning we were able to use
those mobile nutrients that were stored
so that you Growers should also evaluate
their production practice practices but
this is a good starting block for you
know the bare bones of the plant to see
how phosphorus interacted in the plant
without pruning additional work does
need to be done with pruning defoliating
and leaching of the system and flushing
to see you know do you need a boost
later if you remove the phosphorus that
you store up at a young plant when it's
not necessarily needed before flowering
yeah that's an excellent point I'm glad
you brought up that comment
um and I do hope we do see more research
come out around pruning because we have
a pretty wide range of
uh cultural practices in the Cannabis
industry ranging from removing pretty
much all families to leaving a
significant amount of canopy
um so yeah I would love to see that
research
maybe that's something you guys will do
someday
[Laughter]
well let's tell me a little bit about uh
so the so the paper that you authored is
um with Paul and Dylan Kidd and uh Brian
whipker is called elevated phosphorus
fertility impact on Cannabis sativa uh
bayox growth and nutrient accumulation
now what led to you
um your interest I guess and and
uh formulating this trial and writing
this paper
so initially we started off with Paul's
work looking at the lower fertility
ranges
and I remember I went into one of the uh
hemp grow stores which was close to
where me and Paul had our research going
on
and they were selling products that had
close to uh 200 apartment phosphorus in
it and I had I struggled to understand
how I could get or we were getting uh
healthy looking plants at you know 11
and a quarter fifteen Thirty and someone
is selling a product that is 200
popularly and phosphorus in it
and you know we were seeing other things
online saying that you really needed to
boost it up even up to the 250 300 range
and it was uh harder for me to
comprehend why that was needed and why a
grower should invest that much money
when we were able to get results for uh
much less
so Paul and I decided to build upon his
work and expand it further to these
upper rates
but then also backpedaling to Paul
Nelson who was a former professor at NC
State and Josh Henry who was a former
PhD student
they looked at other floriculture crops
and phosphorus is growth control
so as you increase phosphorus to higher
levels you get more internode stretch
so Paul's work was looking at those
lower rates where we might have been
seeing growth control and not seeing as
much internode elongation
so we wanted to compare it to what the
industry was doing and how that affected
plant growth did we get really lanky
plants that needed to be supported or
were we controlling that internode
stretch by using less phosphorus while
still getting the same growth pattern as
the other two researchers found with
many other floriculture species
so this was more of well we know what
happens at lower rates less tests
against what we're seeing in the
industry of these uh what we considered
elevated phosphorus compared to what was
needed to be considered healthy
that's great well take me through your
paper I guess
um what was the sort of your methodology
and uh what were you measuring
so I followed a very similar system that
Paul used I used four different
phosphorus fertility rates of 15 60 120
and 180 Park a million phosphorus
and this was constant feed and the only
element that I modified was the
phosphorus rate we held nitrogen
constant uh all the other macros and
micros constant other than the
phosphorus so that we try to have that
fair comparison of everything is held
equal but the phosphorus rate
um so just because we did have high or
low P doesn't mean that our nitrogen
changed so that we didn't see impacts of
other elements
I grew the plants for 12 weeks in total
four weeks vegetative and eight weeks
reproductive and once again similar to
Paul's I did not prune trim modify the
plants
um
and
at Weeks
12 we looked at plant growth overall and
nutrient accumulation
and total Bud weight
but the two studies are very similar in
how we conducted the research
we basically had a cut and paste system
for the two where we only modified the
phosphorus rates that were used to try
and get that fair comparison
now do you feel like container side
could have been a limiting factor in
terms of root growth in your study as
well or
did you not see that
uh when I was terminating the experiment
I didn't notice any root bound plants
um but I only went out for 12 weeks
compared to 16 weeks as Paul did and you
know that extra four weeks of vegetative
growth for Paul's I really think
um increase that biomass a fair bit
potentially looking at a different
container size maybe going up to a three
gallon pot instead of a one gallon pot
we could have seen a little bit of
difference as well
but uh what as soon as those roots got
to the side of the container they really
took off and
um thrived under all of the phosphorus
rates
okay so you went
12 weeks total so eight weeks of
veg or reproductive growth and that oh
sorry you did four weeks of Edge and
then eight weeks of flowering is that
correct correct so you did you did four
weeks shorter than Paul did on the veg
side not on the flower side
correct all right perfect and uh
okay I'm looking at table two at 12
weeks of growth can you kind of tell me
what your findings were
yes so after 12 weeks of total growth we
did not see a difference in height
diameter or total total above ground
biomass
um
from 15 to 180 everything was similar
I will comment on the height I was
slightly surprised that as we increased
all the way up to 180 Park million P we
didn't see a difference in height I
expected the 180 part million P plans to
have a little bit more stretch in the
internodes leading to Greater Plant
height
but we didn't even see that
um total budweight was significantly
different
um however everything here is within two
grams
of the means and
um we don't notice a clear trend
we see it Peak at 60 PPM but then go
down
and the only difference we could say was
between 60 and 120 but everything is
fairly consistent across all of them and
I wouldn't say that
um you know picking one of these rates
will yield you a greater Bud weight
compared to the others
yeah that is interesting it
it doesn't look like there's much of a
difference like you said over the over
the whole uh
quite a significant range and P rates
you know going from 15 to 180.
um
did you look at below ground wait wait
at all biomass or anything uh that
wasn't visually assessed root growth
um however we didn't wash Roots like
Paul did
um visually we didn't see a difference
however I can quantify a difference for
you but for all these rates they looked
fairly similar visually
did you
um
did you did you notice anything else
visually amongst the the difference in P
rates like if you were to walk into the
greenhouse could you see a significant
difference from one treatment to the
other if you didn't know
anything about the experiment
I honestly could not tell any
differences across the board
looking at them we could have
potentially expected a little bit darker
Foliage for those that
had greater uh
phosphorus concentrations
however looking across the board of the
plants they all looked very similar and
we it was very hard to tell that
anything was different amongst any of
the phosphorus fertility rates
and did you see any issues of toxicities
or anything like that I'm guessing no if
you didn't see any real visual
differences
so we did not uh we didn't report any uh
phosphorus toxicity symptoms even
getting up to 180 part per million P
constant feed
typically when you get phosphorus that
high you actually see an antagonism with
iron
so with having high phosphorus fertility
rates in the plant of taking High P you
actually will block the plant from
uptaking Iron and
we did not see a clear trend on iron
levels other than
um actually the lower uh phosphorus
fertility rates
shown a lower iron concentration which
is actually backwards from the
anticipated antagonism that's in the
literature
um so nothing visually different and we
didn't see the antagonisms that are
typically associated with phosphorus
either
yeah I'm looking at that chart right now
was there anything else in this in this
chart that you wanted to point out on
the terms of nutrient accumulation in
the leaf tissue at 12 weeks
so on the 12-week nutrient accumulation
I definitely want to highlight the
phosphorus and we notice down at the uh
15 million p
we have the lowest uh phosphorus foliar
concentration which is to be expected
however we notice that we don't really
see a plateau
15 to 60 is a linear increase 62 and 120
they're not different
but even when you get up to 180p it's
significantly different than all the
other ones so you can supply the plant
with as much phosphorus as you possibly
can it seems and it will uptake it
however just because that plant's
uptaking it we're not seeing that return
in investment on your growth
so the plants exhibiting luxury
consumption and it is likely that it can
sequester it very well all day and it
won't antagonize other elements of the
plant and it's good at storing it
however you're not seeing a return on
that in terms of plant growth in this
study
but you're not seeing any antagonisms
necessarily either at those high doses
so it's really not you're just wasting
your money kind of things
it's not harming the plant but you're
not seeing a benefit of it it's seeming
that it's uh just storing it in a plant
and it's sitting in the leaf not harming
or helping you
[Music]
um
so this kind of points to
you know if we can get away with that 15
to 30 range that Paul noted why do we
need to have
108 uh part per million phosphorus
supplied to the plant when it will
uptake it of course it's not just
leaching out the bottom of the pot but
you're not seeing that increase in
growth or increase of Bud weight
yeah so
why
I'm trying to figure this out in my head
as I'm as I'm saying it so
this may not be a complete thought I'm
noticing that the K levels went down
uh or sorry the K levels went up as you
went from 15 to 180 PPM your calcium
levels went down
is that related to pH at all or I would
have initially thought that you would
have had greater root biomass
potentially leading to Greater overall
nutrient uptake with higher P levels but
that doesn't seem to be the case
how would you
begin to explain
I guess those
those numbers
uh looking at the uptake patterns for
those
seeing the
calcium increase
I'm not aware of any literature that's
uh
published on
increase in potassium foliar uptake with
increasing P
um however we do see that strong Trend
but I also want to point that it's
following similar to
the phosphorus where that 60 and 120 are
fairly similar as well
um with in being greater than 15
but not necessarily
uh similar to the 180 it kind of seems
to have plateaus for a while and then
increases once again
um
and then for the calcium decrease I'm
not aware of an antagonism between
phosphorus and calcium polar U
H so if if you refer to
um there's a chart called Mulder's chart
m-u-l-d-e-r apostrophe s chart
um and if you're not aware of this
resource it's a it's a good chart to be
familiar with it looks kind of weird to
begin with there's a whole bunch of
nutrients
um kind of around a circle and a whole
bunch of arrows going together
but as far as phosphorus is concerned um
you will see an antagonism between
phosphorus and calcium and that's kind
of what the arrows are indicating you
know one nutrient May essentially have a
stimulation or a synergism with another
element so if you get an increase in
phosphorus for example you may get more
magnesium
um and then if you get phosphorus too
high like Patrick said it can cause
antagonisms with iron and calcium is one
of those that it can cause antagonisms
with so I would say that that decrease
is probably uh what we're seeing there
and again this is more of a guideline
it's going to really depend on what type
of system you're in are you in soil are
you in a substrate are you using you
know water-soluble fertilizers are you
in an organic system so Mulder's shirt's
more of a guideline in general Trends
but there are some nuances that could
exist
um like you said Tad um pH is one of
them
yeah it's definitely complicated
um
I found it not to be quite as useful for
me in organic production just because
it's there's so many more variables
associated with it and the nutrient
cycling from from microbiology just
contributes a whole other Factor there
and also another level of buffering I
find
um
but I my initial thought when I saw
these results was okay there's the
increase in P is probably leading to a
greater root biomass which means we're
getting better nutrient uptake which
explains the k
and then I got calcium and I I didn't
know quite what to do with that uh they
kind of threw out the window I thought
okay well maybe uh the the P the higher
levels of P are lowering the pH which
would cause maybe less calcium
availability but
um that didn't explain the case so
I was just curious what your guys's
thoughts were on that
and actually for the ph and you see this
study it was consistent across all the P
fertility rates
um so the fertility wasn't or the
phosphorus input was not altering the
substrate pH or the EC that was that
remained constant across all treatments
here
so how does how does that work because I
would assume that a level of
phosphate that high would lower your
pH or at least lower your your solution
going in
more than one of 15 it was that not not
really the case or did you guys buffer
it
um so we started off with using a custom
Blended substrate where
we Blended ourselves so we don't have
any inputs coming in other than our line
charge and our wetting agent as well as
the perlite
um we did not have to buffer the pH at
all in the study
we use the modified hoaglands so
everything was fairly well balanced
and after 12 weeks we didn't see a
impact on substrate pH
um
and that is partly by you know trying to
really carefully balance the salts
and the plant taking them up rapidly but
after 12 weeks of growth we didn't see
any impact on ph or EC
Paul when you were increasing your P
fertility rates the juicy impact on your
pH or you see
yeah so um we didn't we didn't see an
increase either
um and one one thing I'll piggyback off
of that is that you know with the
modified Hopeland solution
um you know you're you're keeping your
water soluble Ion at a constant
concentration but the individual salts
that you're adding into that recipe will
change and based on that change we did
have to add in some sodium hydroxide
into the system to kind of even out some
of those
um pH charges there so kind of to answer
your question Tad we didn't necessarily
amend the substrate pH but when when
we're custom blending these fertilizer
Solutions sometimes we do have to
increase our sodium hydroxide to kind of
buffer out that increased pH charge that
could be coming from um you know
adjusting some of the salt inputs okay
gotcha sorry this is not my world I'm an
organic guy so um bear with me when I
don't totally wrap my brain around
exactly how you guys are formulating
these uh
these fertilizers so I appreciate you
explaining to me
um if I could real quick
um but your your spot on though um Chad
that you know this this Mulder's chart
here is very much a tool for you know
substrate based cons you know
water-soluble ions
um not necessarily
um an organic system so but you know you
you you're spot on in a lot of your
insights here so don't sell yourself
short man I appreciate it I really
appreciate what you guys are doing and
you know coming on the show to share
this research
um as an organic grower
when we start talking about P rates my
initial thought goes to
well one the environmental impact which
we already kind of touched on a little
bit but P solubilizing microbes and
mycorrhizal fungi and the role of those
play in making P available because
typically in an organic system and even
in a lot of conventional systems we have
high levels of unavailable phosphorus
and it's really getting available P
that's the big challenge
did I mean your research doesn't exactly
speak to this but did you guys have any
thoughts in on this or anything I
mentioned there as you've been studying
phosphorus so much
or maybe not yeah no I can I can comment
on that um I was I was given a little
time buffer there
um but you know you're you're very
correct
um that once you move into a soil system
or something more like a living bed or
even an organic system the microbiology
just becomes so much more important
um and you have you know your adsorption
your desorption of the ions you know
your complexation as well as you know
what the microbes are going to eat the
rate of microbial growth and
mineralization and it becomes just so
much more complex and uh oftentimes you
have to dump a whole bunch more Reserve
phosphorus into that type of system just
to get your plant available
um
so you know one one of the things that
would be just absolutely amazing
um would be looking at the adsorption
and desorption of phosphorus under these
main systems that the industry is using
you know whether that be like a living
bed or actual like you know
um some sort of soil based
um work so but you know before we get
there there's a few key aspects that
need to be explored such as uptake and
partitioning
um and then reallocation would be
another but your your spot on Tab that
you know this this is an extremely
dynamic system and oftentimes your
reserve or soil PH can be just so much
higher than that um which the plant
available uh concentrations would be
and to kind of go off of that I think it
really comes back around to
as a grower what are your production
practices
um
so if you're going in a hydroponic
system this kind of acts as a
Cornerstone to say you can really dial
your phosphorus right back
compared to being in an organic system
unit you may need to increase it and
give yourself a little bit more of that
buffer
but this kind of access what is your for
plant available P how much of that is
needed in certain systems and it's kind
of a good Cornerstone for wire Growers
can start to look at
but
everyone needs to kind of modify this uh
baking recipe for
what they're doing and how it's going to
work for them while this serves as a
good Cornerstone of literature
because it's been all plan available P
those who are using more soil or organic
systems will need to modify it but this
is a good starting point oh absolutely I
think this research you guys did is is
huge
I can't thank you enough for it because
at the end of the day as a grower if the
only takeaway I get from this research
is to start experimenting with lower
rates of phosphorus that could have a
dramatic input on the impact on the
industry in terms of the amount of P
that we really need to mine or purchase
or apply to our plants that's a big deal
so I hope people will consider you know
experimenting in their facility with
lower rates of pee and see how their
plants respond and if that has an impact
on yield and I look forward to seeing
some you know real life
results in you know in the field and see
if those mirror and Trend along with
what your research has shown
yeah and I'll just I'll piggyback off of
that again here Tad and say that you
know this is this is one of the most
exciting areas for me personally
um you know you can you can be a
scientist and you can do this work and
you can publish it and sometimes it
feels like you're just shouting into the
the void and so it's it's moments like
these where people can come alongside
and talk through the science and then we
as scientists can learn from you know
people who are in the industry and in
production
um you know because it's a give and take
right it's a relationship you know we we
have the science and we hold things
constant and we you know do this stuff
but really it it's people like yourself
doing the amazing work that you're doing
with the organic stuff and then industry
input and everything you know we're
we're all only going to be better
together
um so
oh yeah you bring up a great Point like
as as a grower
my challenge is not just finding
information and research but being able
to understand that research you know and
not drawing conclusions that may not
necessarily
be accurate or jump into conclusions
based off of one paper and that's where
you know people like you and Patrick can
come in and say oh okay slow down here's
what we can kind of say from our
research and here's what we can't say
necessarily at this point but maybe we
can point you in a direction and then
what what Growers can give back is hey
this is an area that really needs to be
researched and something that we need to
we need to get more data on so we can
make better decisions in the field so I
love that sort of synergistic
um relationship that I hope we can
improve on because historically that's
always been a challenge in agriculture
between you know Farmers or Green Cross
Growers and you know Academia so
it's kind of where this whole podcast
idea came around um so I really
appreciate you guys sharing this uh
on that note
um I do want to just once again plug
your original paper
um talking about nutrient disorders Paul
I think that paper is is wonderful
everyone should have it as a resource I
recently shared that poster on our
Instagram page that you guys put
together is that something you're ever
going to be
um
printing or are there other places
people can find that
yeah no we've we've had so many
inquiries about printing and everything
from that and you know we're we're still
trying to figure out how to you know get
that out there
um as far as like a printing service
goes and everything
um but eventually yes uh we're hoping to
get that in some sort of form
um but one thing I I will say is um
we've had a lot of requests over the
years to just kind of have a centralized
location
um for all of our research and our
resources and uh Patrick actually has
been spearheading that so I'll let him
kind of talk about that and and kind of
plug the the newest development there
so to kind of build off of the poster
that Paul created that we got a lot of
positive feedback on
um we took that poster in me and Paul
built this website where we house all of
our resources at one location and it's
cannabis scientific and it'll be linked
below
but we do have each nutrient disorder
has its own tab where you can read the
description and then we have
for most of them at least one resource
attached below I know phosphorus we have
both of these articles in one or two
other popular press
but this website was really to build a
culmination of all of the grower
magazine and extension alerts that we've
put out as well as our scientific
research
so for those who are just simply trying
to diagnose something it's an excellent
place to start and if you want to go
into detail on you know how can I craft
my
phosphorus rate or my magnesium rates
you know you can go on there and you can
find more of the in-depth science of
what we observed as well as all of the
images and photos that we've culminated
and put in different places now we
finally have them all housed in one
location for
people who are trying to problem solve
awesome yeah I'll definitely have that
link available uh on the podcast page
and where social media allows me to put
links I know Instagram makes it really
challenging so we'll definitely have
that on the podcast page for folks
that's so cool that you guys make that
available to people
the last thing I want to touch on and
um hopefully have you back on here soon
guys is to talk about you have another
paper out called magnesium impact
magnesium's impact on Cannabis sativa
growth in cannabinoid production I would
love to get you guys back on soon to
talk about this most recent paper
talking about magnesium
for sure yeah so that's wonderfully was
the one that spearheaded that
um so you know it'll be nice to come
back on because uh I'll be able to take
the back seat on that one
wonderful well I'm sure we'll get
questions out after this phosphorus uh
podcast post and maybe we can answer
those and then tackle this magnesium
paper here soon I really appreciate you
guys uh thanks so much for coming on any
any last words before we sign off
uh just thank you so much for allowing
us to highlight our research and really
get it out to Growers and everyone who
could you know hopefully benefit from it
and thank you for all the work that
you've done with the industry
thanks Patrick yeah
yeah I would again just say thank you so
much for having us Tad
um it's it's great to be back on I
always really enjoy your podcast your
Instagram your posts and everything
they're always just super insightful and
I love how you just bring this amazing
synergistic view to all of your work
um and this attention to detail it's
it's really inspiring so we appreciate
you highlighting the research and and
your partnership and to all the Growers
out there
um you know keep keep growing keep doing
what you're doing we're we're all only
Better Together
awesome well you guys have a wonderful
rest of your day over there on the east
coast and uh look forward to talking
soon
sounds great thanks Dad thank you
[Music]
that was Paul coxson and Patrick fizzy
and you are listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram if you want to support the
podcast check out the wide range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments and beneficial
insects sticky cards soil test analysis
and Consulting you can also sign up for
our newsletter on our website homepage
to stay up to date on the latest
research and information thanks for
listening