[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge don't
forget if you want to stay up to date
with everything we're up to you can
subscribe to our newsletter on our
homepage at www.cannainsider.com/itunes
currently the largest natural farm in
America growing over 800 acres of
macadamia nuts they have returned sick
trees to vital health completely
eliminating three fungal diseases that
academic said was impossible now Chris
and I talked about the successes he's
had with Korean natural farming and the
philosophy behind it which you'll hear
both of us refer to periodically as KNF
we don't go too deeply into how many of
the nutrients are made as I don't think
audio is the best format for explaining
in detail how to make the IMO preps but
if you go to the podcast page on the
kiss organics website you can find links
to more information and videos from
Chris detailing exactly how this is done
I really enjoyed our conversation it was
great to hear about the amazing projects
Chris is working on right now I hope you
enjoy it too
welcome to the show Chris I really
appreciate you coming on today I'm
excited to hear and learn all about
Korean natural farming and sort of your
role in that in that realm so maybe you
can start off telling me a little bit
about your personal history and how you
got into Canada yeah I'm glad to be you
thanks for the invite and I I grew up
for me
the place I was born in hula on the Big
Island of Hawaii was a farm we had goats
and cattle and milking cows and yeah
good stuff and growing up we tried my
dad found a bunch of different things
and some super successfully and some not
so successfully which is the life of a
farmer and I loved it I appreciated that
perspectives and kind of life growing up
I guess here I grow up a little bit in
California Monterey California as well
as Hawaii so you know I grew up a roping
cattle and castrating with the pond Yolo
in Hawaii and then I go to I'm a city
life in California you know haven't
eaten cow testicles over the summer and
people are like just no perspective of
anything rural and country living so it
was it was a fun back and forth they
learned quickly that not to talk about
that castrating cattle in a city school
because people don't really get that but
we yep um and so my dad brought over
some of the first hair sheep to the Big
Island which is a type of sheep about a
ton of wool so it's real short hair
great for tropical environments because
the wool sheets get all kinds of skin
diseases in the warm kind of humid
conditions of Hawaii so they brought
them over with the idea that they'd be a
little bit closer to Micronesia and some
of the other city balance because
there's pretty poor protein sources
there they have cattle but often not
refrigeration so family to butcher a cow
you know they don't they can't really
deal with it in the nest time for it and
all of us boil the sheep will be a
better option so we're still working on
that this
December I think we'll ship some sheep
for breeding to Cambodia as part of that
come a long term vision and help with a
small farm there that's trying to create
a feeding program so yeah we still have
about under sheep we had a thousand
about thirty years ago my dad started
farming macadamia nuts the situation
happened there was an existing orchard
and we got to move in start a permanent
you know home the land release the land
um so we used to run about a thousand
feet in the workers and then some of the
law has changed and yeah so we run about
200 sheep now but I still have the farm
so currently my family farms 800 acres
of organic macadamia nut all using
Korean natural farming and just
composting that's the exclusive kind of
nutrition program for the trees and it's
working really really well we're in a
better position as a farm kind of than
we've ever been and that's exciting in a
journey well I can't really a little bit
because my father had a nursery and
landscaping business growing up so I
grew up around plants myself and having
parents that were really into farming
and organics and growing plants in
general so I I understand that
connection between family business and
farms and that sort of thing and I feel
very fortunate to have have that growing
up myself and I got to see a little bit
of what you're talking about when I
visited the Big Island in terms of the
the horses and the Cowboys the the
paniolo I think it is with what they're
called is I think that's what you said
so really interesting history there too
now everyone says that you're the guy to
talk to when it comes to Korean natural
farming here in America I know there's
other people too but they are unwilling
to necessarily bridge the gap between
cannabis and in agriculture which I
can totally understand and respect but
people do talk about how much success
you've had and you're you yourself or
not a cannabis farmer is that correct no
I'm not so you've been growing the
macadamia nut trees and how did you how
did you find out about Korean natural
farming to even bring it onto your
property yeah that was a bit of a
journey and you know I can I am
definitely not a not a canvas farmer but
there has been times in my life where I
have been a cannabis farmer I wouldn't
quite call that a farmer I don't think
anything a high schooler does considered
farming for the most part by that yeah
for us in the trees that was a journey
and I grew up with a lot of really smart
people in my industry and the in order
crafts in Hawaii where kind of the
cultivation of macadamia that as a
commercial operation was begun there was
there's a lot of really informed and
knowledgeable people so I have to be
around them growing up which was a real
gift and hear recommendations retrieved
and the way things work
yeah method 18 that came from Australia
originally but they were just kind of a
wild I never really cultivated tree
there and Hawaii began connotes variety
trials and started that and then the
Australians to get back from Hawaiian
and began on their own so for us it was
a bit of a journey to recognize about 12
years ago maybe 13 that people that were
experts in our industry and macadamia
nuts might not be able to explain
everything that's went on in nature and
how Bastet under the trees we had an
event where we had a major crop failure
long story but the short of it is we had
to let our organic we were
operation at that time better left at
about 360 acres will fallow and during
that time they became far healthier than
they'd been with expensive amendments
and stuff we were doing kind of
traditional organic practices with some
purchased amendments and composting and
in three years of left being left alone
they were healthier than they had been
in a really long time and that we made
kind of a commitment
um I guess it was my job but made a
commitment to kind of not know anything
so we began to just kind of what what
did nature do what is nature doing and
how can we kind of do that in in the
future how can we partner with what just
happened we watched trees go from yellow
to green and from low in production to
higher in production well being
completely ignored for three years and
that led us to explore different things
that were going on in the aquaponics
explosion and and then into Korean
natural farming there were people
bringing so none of the initiator this
was this guy dr. Park dr. Haines Park
he's a pediatrician turns like after 50
years of watching kind of disease
increase at the same time as medicine
got better who said there's something
wrong that must be our food and he went
to Korea s that in a 10-hour two-day
class you know to two days of ten hours
a day standing room only and a little
shed to listen to this guy Johan you and
who people called Master Joe which is
just a term for teacher in Korea he came
back and excited he started just being
that share of that information I went to
one of the first classes he was teaching
about
and people are heckling tackling them
because it's a bit of a mind shift on
how we traditionally do things so one of
the things that really got some hassles
or whatever laughter from the crowd was
he talked about transplanting a tree and
I don't know if you threw your listeners
transplanting the tree traditionally
it's just really gentle and you you know
really try and alleviate any shock I you
know not not disturbing it too much and
stuffing your hole and there's there's
all kinds of good ways to do it but I'm
coming that you're farming you take it
you wash off all the potting soil or all
the dirt you trim the taproot and you
let it dry for a day or two depending on
the size of the tree and everybody just
slipped out and I'm scratching my head
because that is not how you transplant a
tree but then he's like and then we take
this nutrient you're soaked it and any
plants is Miss whole idea is helping us
to move out and that cedar root seeking
water he's given it this idea that it
needs to work on roots because there
could be a drought and so I was like
well I committed not to knowing anything
and just look like what is this and I
really works I've done that many times
that was ten years ago
a little more than ten years ago and it
works it's it's an incredible way to
change that trees and the trees do you
work on reproduction um before leaf
production in that scenario I make it
you know stronger if they if they
survive they're going to continue to
survive and it's this fun but then
Master Joe and his daughter came to my
tiny small town in Kahala so it was just
kind of a right place at a time when we
were already seeking these answers
because of what nature's that
on our farm and then I began a journey
of going to create a bunch of times to
study and when we started we were just
kinda skeptical as farmers tend to be so
we we just decided to do it really well
but had no real preconceived
expectations they're just gonna watch
what it did and we had results we had
really great results
we had a disease and mekka dating in
that industry called macademia quick
decline at ami a slow decline and it's a
reborn fungal disease called
Phytophthora and we had some effective
trees and the affected cheese and the
sporting cheese how we did and we
started applying IMO we had made some
biochar and gym spray and we've done it
right according to you know we've barely
been diligent with the process of
natural farming we didn't know it was
gonna fail it not but we didn't want it
to fail because we screwed it up one day
I'm gonna give it a good try and we have
these trees recover these disease trees
that in our industry push on that
three-year tube and they bounce back
within a year they re foliated these
streets that pulley defoliated and then
just kind of keel over and they'd be
foliated within a year and by here to
who they were back in production and by
year three they were like healthy
vibrant trees and um yeah there's
there's a whole lot more to that journey
of scaling up you know going from these
concepts that were being taught to us
and wheelbarrow kind of scale to 800
acres scale that was a serious journey
that was pretty much for me it was
pretty much by myself I did have a buddy
that come out and just be a real
encouragement and helped me understand
poncho NP Joey's
crazy horse tourists and and he was he
was he just made it fun you know they
have somebody to work because most of
the people on that farm was just like
what do we
doing your crazy I've got a mad
scientist but now we were fulfilled we
have a big ol operating lab our kind of
warehouse facility all geared around
just kind of efficiencies in the natural
farming process yeah for our large farm
Wow so basically you had this you were
on this journey of trying to find the
right the right method for your farm and
try something new and so you just
started from scratch and decided you
were gonna give this a shot and you kept
having more and more success following
these these tech natural farming
techniques is that about I mean the jist
of it yeah yeah we didn't we didn't
start natural farming because they're
like oh this philosophy is what we have
to do we had 30 employees and their
priority on our farms they're kind of
the main reason in a kind of
economically success town and so we
weren't going to do something that
jeopardized and I was taking care of
what we had to do we had to be farmers
first so we weren't going to go out of
business for some Korean natural farming
philosophy we do Korean natural farming
and we continued some kind of the step
by step trials and scaley not because it
worked and we just saw success at each
kind of scale step so that brings up a
question for me how do you feel Korean
natural farming compares to other you
know organic or natural farming
techniques that you see out there like
Fukuoka with one star revolution or
biodynamic you have your soil food web
people regenerative agriculture
probiotic farming you know there's all
these different groups that are all
slightly different but on a similar path
what separates in your eyes you know KNF
from from some of these other methods
yeah it
don't a lot of ways there's it's all
kind of the same thing right these work
or don't work because they work or don't
work with how nature's designs or
function it's it's like gravity you know
most sports that you have all have these
similar kind of features go anywhere in
the world because they all play on
gravity affecting the ball falling back
down you know it's it's so a lot of
these things play into they use the
principles of nature and that's why they
work so there's not one method to tend
to the life of your soil there's been
methods all over the world throughout
the centuries that you know there were
scientific methods
no Sciences is the observational study
of nature and and they were scientific
and that they stopped doing what didn't
work and kept doing what work farmers
aren't stupid you know so after you know
several generations the things that
worked or the ones that were passed down
those were successful things for the
farmers so you have like Iceland they
take you know manures from the end of
the season stuff it in a hollowed-out
horn and bury it you know below where
the freeze goes and then next year they
dig it up and they spread it on their
field right when after the thaw and they
have a jump starts the microbial life in
their soil and the production of crops
well they didn't know what microbes were
but they knew that work somehow somebody
figured out that work and you know that
was a way to basically protect the
vibrant soil life from a freeze and get
it you know back up to speed a little
faster so that you could get a little
longer season for their crops so yeah so
short answer and the difference is
methodologies etc and what I like about
being natural farming is that
for for me it's an elegant method so as
I encountered all these inputs and ways
to do this I I kind of dug in and that's
why um that's kind of how my mind works
I need to kind of understand I need to
know especially as I scaled what things
can I mess with or what things are
shifting below and what aren't and I
know that I can't just change things
because I don't want to do it because if
I don't understand it I don't know what
I'm changing than what I'm losing and so
as I dug into the whys I found a lot of
solid science a lot of the things that
we were teasing that understanding and
you know um microbiological world were
principles of this was based on and and
so on you studied in Japan with enzymes
and doctors and some of these natural
farming kind of leaders there and it's
it's based on good science so it's a way
that is scalable that is extremely
effective and works for commercial AG
and that some that's not true in in all
kind of natural farming principles and
practices and though they are all paired
with how nature works and some of them
are extremely difficult to scale or just
the efficiencies of farming kind of make
them untenable like permaculture for
example permaculturist wrath and based
on the principles of nature but if you
give me an 800 acre farm and my spinach
is sparse here and there over 800 acres
when I have a spinach that's been
harvested Arvest spinach it's pretty
high just because of efficiencies you
know the inability to get it all in a
basket and get it to market
but if I have a small family or a few
families and I have a giant permaculture
food forest in my backyard then it's
great we can just go out and pick
whatever we want when we want to eat and
you know permaculture doesn't work for
us and it did wouldn't have worked for
us on our farm because of the jurassic
inefficiency that would have basically
been real dollars and cents issues see
see I would argue well first off I want
to say that I love your your philosophy
there I I'm in a similar boat in the
sense that I believe that all of these
groups including permaculture are all on
the same path and there's many ways to
grow a plant and you know KNF being one
of them and i love the idea that we can
you know all go in the same direction
and maybe pull and use information from
all of these without throwing science
out the window and I to me that's an
important aspect of all of them and I
think that you know taking a scientific
approach to something like nature is is
very doable and they're not mutually
exclusive approaches or ideas and it's
in terms of permaculture just from my
own experience I would I would almost
want to say that that's a that's an
inefficient permaculture design because
really the way I see permaculture it's
just it's it's all about design it's all
about patterns and utilizing the
resources that you have in whatever
location or project that you're working
on so if if spinach harvest is part of
your revenue then you need to utilize a
design that will make it efficient for
you to harvest that spinach so that your
overall processes can be you know can be
maximized so you know not not every
permaculture is a food for us because
food forests may not make sense
depending on what your overall goal for
that property is if that makes sense all
right so I love permaculture and I like
all the principles in it because I feel
like it's an observation of nature and
the new thing how nature works but why
does
trees and permaculture help the overall
production the the fruit trees the the
tree aspect of it the tall canopy plant
oh boy you know I'm not I guess strong
enough in permaculture to really be able
to answer yeah no no though it was
rhetorical outside okay yeah so the the
trees take this incredible strength they
have as they grow and they create
relationships soil food web site they
create relationships their root tips and
they they shuns that fungal Network in a
way that some of the lower plants don't
do as well they're just really good at
creating partnerships with fungus that
they're at the root tips and there's
such a big organism that all that
photosynthesis and energy and an
exchange really tends to the whole area
as a result the whole area is benefited
and so the the idea is getting the
taller tree and it's benefiting are
helping with the diversity in the soil
is is a great concept and it's true is a
true observation of nature and and the
partnering with how nature works but and
as a farmer if I think that diversity of
microbial life and tend to that
microbial life by bringing in the
diversity of the florist and and it's
helping it get established in my
farmland and then just tending to it
being established just helping it stay
kind of vibrant in my soil then I can
get the benefit of the diversity of
microbial lives without needing a forest
in my farm to do so and that's where I
think permaculture has got it and yes as
a row crop farmer I can get that affect
by bringing in a indigenous microbial
highly diverse mix then unlike go that
route
other than canyon trees so you're trying
to imitate some of the benefits that you
would get from something some of these
permaculture designs are a food forest
but in more of a traditional
agricultural design that's more
efficient for harvesting this is
essentially what I'm efficient yeah
efficiently so so the science is the
study of nature you don't partner with
nature
and do it scientifically science is just
learning from and and studying nature we
we've just deviated and think in science
and nature one because we've gotten off
into the you know production of
chemicals but you know or what not but
all those polymers and chemical they're
all based on principles we learn from
nature what nature's already doing and
you know it's it's fun so yeah all those
all those things you mentioned soil food
web bio dynamics they've all observed
something about nature and they're just
trying to emulate it so on that note I
guess I should have been more specific
in terms of saying scientific method
instead of just science in the sense
that we're controlling for a variable
and observing their results and I think
that's something that can be applied to
anything and that's something that I
really do believe in when it comes to
really understanding how something works
cuz my brains the same way like I want
to know more about the how and why
rather than just the process itself but
I guess my my problem I have and this is
not with KNF and this is not necessarily
with any of these sort of different
methods but some of the the fanaticism
that I see when people are you know say
that maybe KNF is the way that you need
to grow it's the only way or bio
dynamics or soil food web or you know
whatever type of methodology to the
exclusion of the other methods to me
that's I really struggle with like you
can almost feel cultish in some cases
and I haven't necessarily seen that with
KNF but I have seen it with some of
these other methodologies what's what's
your experience or thoughts on all that
yeah I see that
and
in natural farming they're creating
natural farming as well there's there's
people especially in the beginning and I
just as a farmer this same you know I
had this to say you know what I gotta
figure out if this works and if it works
and makes you know where we can be
productive farmers then there's a reason
for it
I'm I can't just pick it up as my
religion or something that's not that I
should work for us to be farmers you
know because I'm and it doesn't work for
for the world to change and have
increase in quality of foods either you
know the pitch to take go to a
conventional you know we farmer corn
farmers say hey I got this idea I think
it's really good for the world
you should go out of business little by
little over the next 10 years to to jive
with my philosophy that's a hard sell
they're like no thank you
we're gonna keep doing what we're doing
but if I say hey I make more money than
you and my crops better and I have more
time with my family
I think he should check out what I'm
doing and that's that's a much easier
spell and and it's true you know for us
on in the farm in Hawaii um you know
nurse our industry hasn't gotten into it
yet they don't really understand what
we're doing they like the look of our
trees and our crops but they don't
really know what we're up to
I'm gonna speak in China actually in
October if I can submit my PowerPoint
before they yell at me but um they're
the International mecha team that
symposium the southern China this year
and they asked me to speak about what
we've accomplished on a trees because
some of the leaders and the
international community came out and saw
our trees more like what it's going on
here but no it can't you can't mean just
a philosophy or farmers can't get behind
it and if this is the movement of
farmers and I think farmers have to be
able to get into it and so it has to
equate for a farmer to increase
production or
time or quality of product it has to or
it's like why and and then as far as
each individual group you know it's it's
what people know you know that they
can't get behind something they don't
know and if it's if it's their
livelihood that they're they're making
money from you know the selling of their
idea then you know they also don't want
you not and the other idea because that
might threaten or whatever so um when
somebody you know knows something and
they don't know something else then it's
just normal to you know say oh this is
good and I don't know about all that or
or to even be kind of antagonistic
towards something else because they just
don't understand it and that's I'm a
human condition so we're all kind of on
a similar path in terms of these natural
farming in these different methods and
as I would venture to say as you come to
oh no it's okay I was gonna say as you
come to understand the how and why
behind some of these practices which I
want to talk to you about next maybe you
can pick and choose the ones that are
best fitting for your environment so I
have some good cannabis friends that are
growers and excellent growers and they
use certain aspects of KNF in their
gardens and it works really well for
them they're not doing everything the
way a Korean natural farmer might do it
but they've definitely pulled aspects
because they've taken the time to learn
and understand what those particular
inputs and things will affect that
they'll have on their plants yeah
yeah it's and the thing is like there's
some aspects to each one of these that
probably aren't super good for that
given a change could be better and
that's the part that's the part that you
know if if somebody and it just because
it's something they do or something they
like they know and that's where like
nothing I know I don't want to stay on a
ship that I know has a hole in it just
because it's got my name on the side or
you know something like that so I I
think if we can be honest as we learn I
think that's the key so you know the
whole world's learning right now that
there's a whole lot more to the
interconnectivity of nature then we knew
as a scientific community and and that
there's a long journey ahead of us and
as each group or you know camp learns oh
this actually isn't very good um if
we're honest about that and we can adapt
to move forward and I think it'll be
just uh it'll be a lot of fun to see
what kind of world our kids get to do
and play with and agriculture yeah I
mean at the end of the day we're all
promoting organic farming and healthier
ways to grow food locally and that's
better for the environment so and then
they were all on the same side I totally
agree with you on that
so just turning switching directions
here can we talk a little bit and and
maybe all maybe we'll get into this on
another podcast or something down the
road but can you give us just a general
idea of some of the inputs with KNF and
and sort of the philosophies specific to
KNF yeah some of the philosophies are
like a similarity of plants to
humans you know in lifecycle in kind of
Edison flows of nutritional needs and so
one of the ways that that philosophy
plays in the practical kind of work for
a farmer is the idea that we need a
little bit of nutrients or the writer
chooses the right amount of nutrients at
the right time and so philosophy wise
where we're not a front-loading with all
the plans nutritional needs from day one
were we're tending to the kind of
changing needs of our plant based on its
growth cycle so you know and a lot of
cannabis farmers understand that concept
and in Korea natural farming it applies
to corn to trees lettuce all across the
board
you know the whole infancy and the low
nutritional needs and then vegetative
growth a change over a period where
there's kind of a morning sickness like
a human has and then reproductive growth
and and all the all the ways you observe
your plants and feed it accordingly
that's that's pretty central in the
feeding of in Korea natural farming and
the concept of using indigenous microbes
the balance and diversity that works or
has worked for kind of untended for
thousands of years in undisturbed forest
or kind of land in the surrounding area
is what we'll self-perpetuate on the
farm so that that idea of getting the
thriving kind of soil food web or
microbial life from your area and
applying it in your area it's a central
idea and so yeah this kind of the
microbial input which is
microorganism and that that process is
pretty entailed and then there's the
kind of nutritional and feed aspect of
Korean natural farming which is a
variety of inputs that are able to be
soiled rinsed in or taken into foliar
feeding so I don't want to get into all
the inputs because I know it's a rather
complex subject and there's a lot that
goes into it and if someone really wants
to learn they're going to have to do
more research than they can pick up in
you know listening to it to a podcast
for an hour but I want to give them a
taste of sort of the philosophies of it
which I think you did so essentially
what we're talking about here is is
locally sourced nutrient inputs and
essentially locally sourced
microorganisms as sort of the two main
drivers for KNF is that is that accurate
yeah and it's also inexpensive the idea
is that you can use you can use things
that you might otherwise think of as
waste or kind of low value become pretty
valuable or usable and the natural
farming form and so like on our farm we
weave everything all of our byproducts
now are really cared for and because we
didn't do so much with them they become
so musical and yes or our farm has
become kind of a real recycler of local
inputs and user and and that's I mean
when we're on an island if it's not
shaking things in can can really equates
dollars and cents as well oh yeah I mean
that makes a ton of sense because we're
reducing our environmental impact with
fossil fuels and getting material out to
you you're gonna save a ton of money and
I totally get that so can you give me an
example let's say someone on the
mainland might use of a waste product
nutrient source that can
is recycling back into a beneficial
input on their soil sure so all be yeah
let's see so fermented plant juice is a
input in Korean natural farming that's
the plant food
it's a ferment and some of the
misconceptions I've seen online that we
have to get it like store-bought you
know nice for you to make amended
statutes and that's actually really
Korean natural farming philosophy is
just something that got a little changed
online but you can go out and get a wee
quite literally local invasive or a
local just grows everywhere but never
touch it it's always healthy and green
and that can become a real food source
not a theoretical food source but just
like people buy kelp you know they get
kelp and they use kelp and they're like
wow I get great results with kelp and
the beneficial bio chemicals in any
surviving plant and for whatever reason
the plant that's thriving the weed
that's thriving in your zone is able to
take up nutrients extremely well great
to thrive there when nobody farms it
it's just the thing that grows
everywhere and it's always healthy it is
taking up nutrients well and it's going
to be filled with the kind of the plant
growth hormone and other beneficial bio
chemicals that plant actually benefits
um it's not it's not pretend it's it's
kind of in the world of cutting that
research that a lot of your your plant
companies are looking at now they know
that plants have these bio chemicals
that can help other plants grow they
don't know exactly how it works yet and
they're trying to isolate them and
figure out how each one works
individually but you can just take this
concept of using the new growing tips
the thriving fresh plant and for making
it and getting out that nutrient and
then applying it to your plan so all of
a sudden you're Iceland or your IV or
your rhubarb or 100 other kind of weed
type things in your area become a
resource that actually has equates to
production on your farm and that's
that's pretty cool so you're taking like
a healthy biomass from whatever plants
are thriving in your local region and
then fermenting it and making it into a
liquid nutrient essentially yeah now my
initial thought on that is many weeds
just do tissue testing and things are
quite low in macronutrients right
definitely but you're getting a lot of
trace elements like you mentioned kelp
and kelps wonderful for the reasons that
you do get you know 70 different trace
elements you get plant growth hormones
and regulators and as a ton of benefits
it's been widely studied but not
terribly high in NPK there's a little
bit in there but are you thinking that
the main benefit from these things then
would be would be trace elements or you
know mineral nutrients that are a little
bit a little bit smaller and maybe
lacking in the soil or lacking in the
plant's ability to take them up so I
have all kinds of theories and I can tie
it to a lot of current research in this
kind of realm of how these you know
they're taking these plants from the
desert that grow like crazy they're
extracting the specific phytochemicals
combining with other similar properties
and other plants and then applying it to
plants and getting these incredible
results and exactly what's going on
there and by Stan's respond like that to
these things I don't understand
personally
and I think a lot of the people
researching them understand aspects but
how they work together how that you know
might help a plant with its root zone or
its interconnectivity with the soil food
web or any number of things its uptake
of nutrients its ability for the
microbes and its roots and uptake
nutrients or transfer nutrients do that
a lot of questions that were all as a
community of researchers asking right
now I'm trying to learn so what I like
and claim in nature is that I've held on
to that and there's actually a core
natural farming principle but we started
it before we mean natural farming that
held on to that thing that happened on
our farm where I was like okay I'm gonna
I'm gonna know nothing I've had a
lifetime growing enough of experts in my
field I'm gonna check that knowledge at
the door not that I throw it away
because farming knowledge is awesome and
it and it all interacts with and applies
in using green and natural farming but
I'm gonna say it's okay to not know and
learn something and so empty mind is a
core kind of philosophy in natural
farming that's very an evasion thought
by them it's helpful because it's like
hey imagine for a moment they don't know
everything about what you're talking
about or what you form imagine for a
moment that that's true and what might
you learn or what might you be up for
trying to see how it works or succeed
and so exactly why a new growing tips of
a vibrant plant in your area equates you
a real response in a plant and when
combined with the vinegar and oriental
Oracle nutrient which is something we
make you know and vinegar micronized or
helps
water powder particles and uptake you
know why all of this you know why plants
responded like this I'm not sure I have
again they have ideas and things I've
read it's like oh wow that's part of it
and we're learning about that but a lot
of this is research that we did we're
going to get wash get to watch and come
to fruition over the next ten to ten
years where we actually understand how
this all works yeah I totally agree with
you on that like there's no so much we
don't know about the soil and about how
plants utilize nutrients in the soil
that we're still learning so it's
entirely possible and I think it's okay
not to know why at the same time I don't
I don't think we need to be afraid to
say we don't know or to say or they
still want to do something as long as
we're being open-minded like you said to
learning more and if if we learn down
though down the way that maybe it wasn't
the and and this may not be the best
example but maybe maybe you were getting
the results because of the vinegar or
because of the particular water or one
of the other inputs sure then you can
adapt in and pour the sugar sure yeah
which I doubt and this is the best
example of that but I think that sort of
philosophy of always wanting to learn
and applying scientific method to what
you're trying so you can really find out
what's making a difference in that
plants health it's really important
totally that's I think yeah I think what
you just said the scientific method like
everybody's like oh well I think this is
a good idea if I just throw all this
stuff and I'm not gonna put it on I like
my plants are super healthy this year
and it's like well would they have been
healthy this year if you didn't do that
like I love the idea of side by side
child and and the control and yeah we we
played with a lot of that over the years
on the farm because I didn't understand
what I could change and what was helpful
and I am Elena him actually and I'm
coming to again my tiny town and in
Hawaii and teaching us to use the
microscope and and make qualitative
assessment
was was a huge key for me to kind of in
this journey in natural farming to be
able to change things based on what kind
of microbial growth and life and
diversity I was seen under the
microscope that was that was a big deal
and that was actually came and again
coming just the right time when I was
asking those questions I want to talk
about that so there's two things that I
really want to talk about with you the
first one would be indigenous
microorganisms since this is such a key
aspect of Canada the idea of sourcing
and using local microorganisms so I gave
you the example when we were talking
earlier offline about how Steve Solomon
stalks him he's a he's a mineral
nutrient guy so he's he's not as big on
salah balaji but he's really big about
remineralization of soils so assuming
but-- Steve Solomon oh yeah he he wrote
a book called the intelligent gardener
which is a really good book on
mineralization and understanding soil
testing for people that are looking to
get into that but one thing he talks
about that I that really resonated me
with me was the idea that you know he
was farming on land that was exceedingly
low in calcium and so his crops were
suffering and they were low in calcium
as well and he didn't know this at the
time but he'd you know he's calm he's
composting those crops and he's eating
those crops primarily and his health is
starting to go downhill and when he was
finding was when he took that compost
that he was making and then applied it
back to the land he was really just
compounding his problem because if his
if what was limiting the the biggest
limiting factor to growth in his soil
was calcium and he was putting applying
compost that was low in calcium
he was just compounding a problem so I
would apply this to indigenous micro
organisms so if your soil if you're
using indigenous micro organisms in the
soil that is say deficient or depleted
or has the wrong ratio of microorganisms
wouldn't bringing in an outside source
add diversity that would either die off
and become food sources for your in
digit
microbes or possibly survive and fill a
niche that was previously on occupied by
the best beneficial microorganisms yeah
I think I think the the question that
you're asking is Anna two parts you're
talking about minerals Solomons example
which is a great a great question and
really interesting one and how nature
works in balance on a mineral level we
see it in seawater the incredible
diversity of mineral seawater and how it
stays and some sort of balance and
actually have an example of a a guy in
Waimea how come well in on the big
island and you said wow farms he's a
tomato farm and great tomato fun and he
teaches a lot of Hawaiian people to to
farm like he does on their land and just
a cool cool family then just killing
that in production of tomatoes and he he
didn't agree natural farming he does
organic farming and front loads and
minerals
he lets across he lives with tomatoes
grow one full crop and then he replaces
them with fresh start
he's just he has it style but he had a
he was so firm it was it was atmospheric
mineral um that just was destroying his
crop and he he doesn't have this extreme
like college background in agriculture
he studied other things and so he just
intuitively I need to balance the
minerals and so he loaded up all this
other huge kind of overloaded the plants
way more than he would normally do to
balance this at
newest ulcer that came in through the
rain because of our volcanic ash and he
he loaded up on the other minerals that
balanced or worked in conjunction with
and he had just the most beautiful crop
and it went all these plants recovered
and went gangbusters and these these
guys from the university system are like
well why did you do that why did you add
in all these other minerals like those
those are way too much minerals or this
and that and he's like well I just
seemed right to balance it that's why
they were something somebody imbalance
this this one imbalance that came in you
know he doesn't he's not apologizing for
not understanding exactly why is he's
just saying it worked
and there would need to be a lot more
study to say that's empirical evidence
of this or that but um it just them I
see that in nature we nature wants um
balance or for a lot of the crops that
we would grow or a little you know some
crops like a little imbalance one way or
another pH um but I'm yeah so I could
totally see deep you Solomon canna
playing with those things and seeing the
results and taking an imbalance crop and
keep applying it you perpetuate the
imbalance and with soil microbes though
I think it is actually an entirely
different question that's being asked
though I recognize that those kind of
connect for you I don't believe they are
quite the same in it is totally possible
that you could buy some last round
microbe and add it to what's going on
and then it finds some niche and stays
established and that's totally possible
generally what we see with microbe grown
you know like Okinawa is microbial life
brought in to grow crop is but it has
incredible results first of all so
there's no
nothing wrong with buying bugs in the
jug and a soil microbial life from
someplace that makes it but it tends to
have about a six months fall-off now an
indoor grow I think there's a lot to
study in that and how how that all might
work but you know the the generally
speaking outdoors you're going to have
this kind of complete dissipation over
six months though it totally helps
plants grow food and all you need to do
is reapply it to kind of get it up again
and feed it and etc but the idea of
using indigenous microbial life so say I
go and I got cropland and it was killed
or farmed with pretty noxious chemicals
from a different farming method and I
had come in to farm it and I want to
tend to life the soil well you know
bacteria can come in on the wind and
yeast can fungi doesn't easily and so I
might have a very very small range of
microbial diversity on that land even
though the surrounding area might be
rich or untouched
I had a soil scientist out where we
farmed in Hawaii and he was studying the
difference of a hundred feet away from
each other when downhill a hundred feet
or you know from this fence line he had
this fence line that's the divider on
one side of the defense line and had
been farmed in sugar cane which is a
pretty intensive and not always very
holistic farming practice done in
islands and on the other side it had
never been in crop production
there had been cattle on it but had
never been kind of the land with that
and the amount of soil microbial
diversity or the soil life was um he I
forget the exact numbers but it was it
was major like ten ten to one as far as
different microbes and we're talking
literally 100 feet and the same
and the same rainfall barometric
pressure everything just on the other
side of the fence and so as much as
there has been rain and and animals
traveling a lot of that microbial life
didn't bounce back it didn't just come
from that uphill spot and move in back
into this area so the idea of
transferring indigenous microbes is is
something where we're just helping to
take soil food web or the the microbial
thriving life of fertile zone and bring
it in and we don't just pick one spot
and natural farming or trying to get it
from ten different spots in the local
area where it's kind of untouched
microbial diversity and we're hoping for
exactly that we're hoping that some of
them might be the exact same thing that
already exists on my land but some of it
might be something that actually needs a
little assistance to move back in
because it doesn't just blow in on the
land and so we bring in some soil from
our farm and hopefully some from just
outside or and then we bring in we try
and cultivate and collect indigenous
microbial inoculant from the local area
again hoping that it does kind of sell
in and and that doesn't mean that
there's not another way to get some
increased microbial diversity or that
some things that somebody grows in our
lab wouldn't establish in some places
but there's very slight differences in
varieties of microbes and what's those
differences equates you and how they
interconnect with our other microbes we
don't really understand all that sure
there's so much we don't know about this
all food web and nutrient cycling in
plants and the rhizosphere that we love
to learn so I totally agree with that
and I guess in terms of indigenous
microorganisms versus outside sources my
thought was not so much
man man-made or man propagated microbial
sources but rather compost teas or
extracts or things like that because
they've done research that shows that so
microbes are relatively ubiquitous in
that ninety-nine point whatever percent
of them are found worldwide but in
different diversity and ratios and
things like that that's why this
slightly different to make up yes so the
idea that you know you're sourcing from
different areas around say an island
like that mm-hmm
I I think that makes a lot of sense I
guess it's all how you define indigenous
if you're talking about just within your
property then I wonder if that that is
enough diversity or not and I guess it's
not really a question we can answer but
no yeah I'm natural farming you don't
just go within the property you gotta go
you know 500 feet up in elevation as
possible and definitely to places as
little disturbed for as many thousand
years as possible but I have heard that
that argument before or that comment
regarding these you know let's let's
just say bugs and jugger outside
microbial sources when they're added in
as not persisting in new in new areas
and I I guess that's something that I've
never seen really good data on and I
don't really understand it now if you
were to say that you apply a particular
microbe species like a lactobacillus for
example and it persists for the life of
that crop and then when that crop dies
and something else comes in this soil
then it disappears and you have to
reapply it I could totally get behind
that but the idea that it would last for
around six months and then suddenly have
a die-off without any environmental
change I just don't understand why that
would occur because it would have I mean
if it's lasting for six months that's
successive generations of any bacterial
colony you know at that point or species
being relatively healthy and surviving
and reproducing right yeah yeah and and
I think I think you've touched on
something that is probably wrong in my
language six months
is far too much of a generalization for
any you know real science talk and as so
III I just want to place a delicate but
on the term six months because I think
you're right I think exactly which
microbe and which bugs in the jug and
how it persists in which environment
those are all going to be completely you
know needing to be looked at
individually and you know I can't I
can't make it I've heard this
generalization not just for me but from
other other people mostly soil food web
people and I'm really just asking the
question I'm not trying to pass judgment
one way or another on it this was just
my initial thought regarding it the idea
that if something is going to persist it
either well persist or won't persist it
and if it's not persisting it's it's
only gonna last you know a matter of a
day or two and beam I thought before it
either ran out of food sources or got
eaten by another microbe in the soil
because we're primarily adding bacteria
if that's what we're talking about so I
yeah and and so I I don't I don't have a
total understanding in this but as far
as it's just to try and help wrap around
some of the kind of possible
environmental changes that can occur on
a microbial level the so say it say
something comes in and if maybe your
your land is needing some conditioning
it's a little hard or there's not a lot
of thriving life and you bring in
something like a like a lactobacillus
string something in that that family and
they break up the soil and you're
feeding them in conjunction with that
and watering it kind of putting in this
crop then some of the things that were
there but maybe weren't thriving get up
to speed to because now your soil is
more aerated earthworms it comes and
stuffs getting better or or whatnot
the indigenous guys tend to beat out for
territory
things that maybe don't it isn't their
favorite zone maybe not temperature
maybe whatever it is rainfall moisture
dry next and so my understanding is that
there's a losing out to the locals that
that happened in in kind of just
competing for space in the in the soil
column so that's kind of how I
understood it yeah I mean it's not
something we can necessarily settle
today it's there's so much like he said
there's so much we don't know I just
wanted to have a discussion about it
because I think it's an interesting
topic and I've heard these things said
and I just was curious to hear another
another idea on it one other thing that
I'm curious to get your opinion on is I
hear especially from from soil food web
people this idea of microbial ratios
your fungal to bacterial ratio being
what destroys your overall soil health
and plant health and by adjusting this
that's how you really control that like
that that is the controlling variable
for plant health and so health and
that's something I haven't really been
able to get my brain around as I've
learned more over the years I mean
that's sort of where I started in this
industry with my father but I've kind of
and I don't want to use the word evolved
because I don't think that's fair but I
would say I've changed my perspective a
little bit into looking more at minerals
and nutrients and their effects on soil
health as well and how all of these
things sort of work together but I've
heard a lot of claims from you know
certain consultants or certain
philosophies around the idea that if you
know your fungal the bacteria ratio is
right everything else is gets corrected
what are your experience or their
thoughts with that yeah well one of the
things that just to touch on that youth
Senate's not into is one
the biggest hole in all of this of our
understanding is in a realm of
interconnectivity and/or in a relation
so a lot of our study in the microbial
world in the world of how that didn't
microbes interact plants and all this
stuff has been on this kind of odor
concept or concept that I don't think
we're going to be able to keep moving
forward which is isolation and and it
has a role we need to we need to
understand the microbe individually but
we isolate individual microbes we try
and figure out what their function is
how they work how they contribute to
this overall idea and we don't actually
understand how they work in community we
don't have like the the data processing
the ability to track interconnectivity
we're just not there technologically we
don't understand how these complex
groups of microbial organisms interact
arm on a level with the nutrients in the
soil on how they help each other or
serve each other that whole zone of
understanding is pretty dark so we we
start like looking at one thing as I am
scientists or different you know camps
of understanding we're like well I
understand this I've studied it a lot
and so this might be the whole answer
but really we have this soil column in
any kind of soil grown crop lamp and
it's full of all kinds of stuff and and
they are organism to smaller organisms
and plants for synthesizing and pushing
things down in the soil and the
exchanges that happen there and how it
all works together is where we really
need to grow in understanding that's
that's where that big hole is because we
don't understand how all the yeasts and
bacteria
together on the leaf of the plan to
actually do something you know what is
that how does that interact them to do
and when it falls in the drip line what
does that do and who's benefiting or how
the east and the bacteria and the fungi
work together to process and deal with
minerals and make them plan available
and you know those those areas of
interconnectivity is where the star trek
would be going if they were soil
microbial frontier explore and we're
we're just beginning there to ask the
right questions and to have tools to
answer those some but in the world of
fungal bacterial ratios and how that
benefits plants I think it's a huge deal
I think each plant has its ideal zone as
far as I'll go to bacterial reishi I've
seen that evidenced um you know for a
long long time and in my personal life
growing up as a farmers kid and getting
to play with it and and I've actually
done a bunch of research on that front
and seeing incredible results when
messing with the fungal bacterial ratios
and what plants died in what plants
right I almost killed five acres of
trees once by messing with this in the
wrong way before I understood it I took
so when I got in the National farming
first they brought over this machine and
I was doing it I was making it for five
acres and was a ton of work and they
brought over this machine from Korea to
try and make I am out on a large scale
and I was like man if I can just buy
this stuff that's just that's great
and so I bought twenty times I am oh
maybe machine applied it on five acre
block of trees and I nearly killed them
all I mean they all turned the craziest
yellow like overnight within a week they
were all like it looks like I had just
started them of water
all nutrients combined for over a year
and I was like what happened everything
else in Orchard's greening thriving only
where I applied this not um did I see
these change like nearly croak and and
so then I that was good time that was a
moment when I realized I can't leave
understanding this up to anybody else
like if the experts are giving me stuff
that they're gonna kill my crops I need
to know what's going on there's not no
one was extra that that's something
people didn't know what they're doing
but um so I dug into it I got a
microscope and I looked like what is in
this and it was all bacteria and it was
made in 24 hours and a boiler system
kind of machine and my trees weren't
having it there was there was nothing
happy about this scenario for them and
what it was that took a kind of stable
soil environment that was far more
hungrily leaning than this inoculum I
put down and I just test it with stray
bacteria and I'm a tree farmer I know
I'm trees not happy and those trees were
not happy and it was just I just messed
up the balance they didn't put poison on
there wasn't there wasn't any real
nutrients in that it was simply an
inoculum and I almost killed him on the
flip side of that the University of
Hawaii's research and development has
granted me money to research project I
did where I took this invasive with
telling all the Tao and because I I
theorized that it actually does is a
bacterial loving plant because when we
were conventional in our herbicide
strips ever side the tiger using it I'd
like to say to them the oxygen makes the
soil it reduces the ability for soil
oxygen transfer and so it kills all the
fungus and everything that loves the
oxygen in the soil and so
they killed everything the first thing
from that bacteria and the first plan to
thrive in these herbicide strips we used
to get the trees off the ground I was a
nut off the ground with our ground
harvesters was this fire weak it was
always the first thing in the strip's
I was like oh they love crazy bacterial
mmm and and it only messes with a real
kind of surface and soil so it's about
this complete devastation of but it's
pretty bad anyway so we don't do that
anymore our trees are happier for it but
what I did for a cow farmer a rancher on
this two acre kind of hobby parcel that
he had no more grass production all the
antis fire we got these folks to do all
this stuff - it wasn't gonna change
anything
and I was like okay he was a friend of
our family so I went in and I brought a
highly fungal inoculum and I just
applied it and then I seeded some grass
where it had kind of been grass list and
I watched and over the period of three
months all the fire weeds died
I got powder in mode you got fur dated
on by a Finch
so I I would go out and look we didn't
pull any of those two acres and like I
pulled all the wheat and two acres is
miserable and so I went out and looked
at it and it would be powdery mildew and
just little scene and time or if you
looked at it right where it messed the
soil be all covered in aces and what
happened is this plan just became the
weakest thing in the area
all the grass went gangbusters went
ballistic he actually was able to run
for tattle on two acres for two years in
a row and because he couldn't keep up
with grass production I've since told
him like that's not a good idea for
sustainability because something it's
his land but right on the other side of
the fence where we didn't apply I am
though the neighbors faster still was
the exact same problem that still with
SolidFire we as far as you can see and I
had you age extension agent amount
university of hawai extension eights
come out and look at this and watched it
over four years and anyway so we're
running the trial right now to show that
empirically so that they can use that to
help farmers on the island so they've
spent millions of dollars and to fix the
fire we thought so fungal bacterial
balance yeah I have a couple thoughts on
that I want to hear your opinion so
first off I loved what you said there
first
about the how much we don't know about
soil biology there's a lot we don't
understand I heard a wonderful science
soil scientist once speak and he talked
about how we know more about what's
going on at the bottom of the ocean and
in outer space than we do literally
under our feet and it is symbiotic you
know and you can't take an isolate one
microorganism without looking at all the
other so I totally agree with you on
that now when we start talking about
fungal the bacteria ratio to me that
feels too simplistic for the reasons you
just stated the idea that we since we
don't know what's going on the idea that
we just take a plant succession chart
which is sends our soil succession chart
as soil moves from highly bacterial
towards more fungal and saying
old-growth forest versus a you know a
new pasture yes that's the case but I
wonder if that's not being pushed more
by the by the plants that are sort of
incorporating than those areas so the
idea that a grass a grass or a tree you
know is putting out these XE dates to
select for the type of microorganisms
that are it's going to be most
successful with with tree selecting for
a more fungal environment and the
grasses or annual crop selecting for
more bacterial environments rather than
us controlling it and I guess on that
note you gave the example of applying
this IMO solution that essentially
really hurt your macadamia nut trees and
I'm wondering if it wasn't so much that
the soil was had a particular bacterial
fungal ratio but maybe that the bacteria
you applied was more efficient at
utilizing the nutrients in that soil for
that period of time and so the plan was
actually nitrogen starved or unable to
access
those soil nutrients because or possibly
that bacteria had so much food source
there that actually created and
generated you know an exothermic
reaction to reproduction and heated the
soils around the roots of the plants
which would stress it to you
III just I wonder if there's other
explanations for it beyond just a strict
bacterial the fungal ratio and I could
be wrong
you know I'm fully willing to admit that
these are just my initial thoughts
regarding you know sort of that subject
I don't know way I think about any other
yeah and yeah the the potential for
there to be other things specifically on
those trees and then yellowing as a
result of that totally is it possible
that it was another thing yeah I think I
think what we have is what we can answer
so like for that cropland or that grass
plant
I took microbial laughs of the whole
place before I started and it was an
extremely you know that's really
grasslands I'm not suitable for grass
production and then I took a master and
the you know the amoeba increased and
you know all kinds of other you know um
affiliates increased and but the the one
of the big changes was the balance of
fungal the bacterial ratio and so yeah
you can I mean maybe there's an
invisible reason in the
interconnectivity of all this that we
don't yet know how to look at and that
could be the cause but I think right now
what I have to work with and the power
of observation I'm looking at that and
saying these plants don't like it when
there's talent soil fumbly to bacteria
II and I think that's probably pretty
accurate and could there be a lot more
to it totally but I think where we're at
and understanding that it's a pretty
good
Toula now it might be that there were
looking at some some disconnected cause
or effect of something more complex that
we don't yet understand and that that's
possible but I think that it might be
just reasonable to say yeah there's
something to this fungal bacterial ratio
how forests grow and yeah yeah and this
is tough for me because I totally agree
with you on what you're saying I just I
cautious about drawing a conclusion from
a result without knowing what all the
variables may be so when we like for
just to use this example of this IMO
solution that you apply to the macadamia
nut trees we don't know what it is about
that application that caused the results
that it did and and you think it's you
know you believe it was because of the
fungal bacterial ratio and I'm just
suggesting maybe it was from something
else entirely
having to do with that solution maybe it
was too acidic or the pH was offer I
have no idea I'm making stuff up at this
point but the idea that we we observe
something with nature and then have to
be able to replicate it but also be able
to draw the correct conclusions for what
the mechanism of action is I think is
really important and it may very well be
like you said this fungal bacterial
ratio but it's just it brings up a sort
of a greater philosophical question for
me when we evaluate all of these
methodologies and all of these ideas
around around farming is all yeah and if
I can go and spray this fungal erased
inoculum and kill fire weed while making
grassland an increase in fertility
well then even if I don't understand
exactly what's going on there I've
employed the principles of observation
and fine to come to a conclusion that I
can tend to the fungal life of grassland
well and kill a noxious weed well
increasing for that
and thus increasing the dollars in the
pocket for a farmer and I might not need
to understand a whole lot more for
effective use of these pencils sure I
mean totally at the end of the day it
all comes down to plant growth and
health and soil growth and how often
you're obviously a very successful
farmer and have had great success with
this and what you're doing I think is
amazing and I love the fact you're
working with the University to spread
these ideas and get research done on
these ideas like I think that's just
that's just incredible so please don't
take any of my suggestions or comments
as in any sort of negative way cuz that
only is not my intent I just I enjoy the
discussion and I like trying to figure
out the how and why behind what you're
seeing we know what we're observing I
think and that's that to me is a journey
it's not it's not black and white and
it's not anything that's good or bad
it's just it's just it's it's
fascinating and I think it's something
we want to keep striving towards I'm in
no way offended and I think it's really
important to have those conversations I
agree
and and I think that what we're gonna
come to as we learn and and kind of come
to write thought or how things actually
work we're just gonna keep partnering
with our nature works I think whoever
painted nature the painter of it is got
a pretty good touch it does be the
deeper I dig into looking at it under a
microscope and and understanding some of
these interconnectivity things the more
I just go wow so I go symptom me like
like literally everybody's playing their
their tune and in in flawless you know
kind of combination even even it in
degrees with chaos you know where
there's life there's beat composition
and there's new growth and it's still
like a symphony it's it's really fun I
really enjoy it and I think thank what
you're saying is is um is on where like
what what is things are actually doing
this how can we better partner with that
yeah well I know I know you have to get
going right now so we can sign off
but I just want to say thanks for your
time today and I know we didn't get we
didn't totally talk about KNF maybe as
much as I wanted to or you wanted to but
I'd love to follow up with you another
time and just and just chat and maybe
I'll have another person on to talk hey
enough here in the near future cool man
well thanks for having me and yes super
good doctor
that was Chris Trump a master natural
farmer certified by Master Choa of Korea
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad Hussey don't forget
that there's more information and
articles available on our website and
blog at WWE is organics calm as well as
links to the data and information we
discussed in this episode on the podcast
page thanks for listening