[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge and if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe on iTunes or
whatever platform you're listening on
and leave me a rating and review this is
really helpful and allows me to keep
producing good content by drawing more
of the top names in the industry to the
show also sign up for our newsletters on
our website at WWE and at a newsletter
approximately every two weeks and this
is the best way to ensure you know what
the next podcast has been released they
also have the latest discounts new
product information blog posts and
what's happening in the industry our
guest this week is Suzanne Wainwright
Evans she is an ornamental entomologist
specializing in integrated pest
management Suzanne has been involved in
the green industry for more than 25
years with a focus on biological control
and using pesticides properly she is a
graduate of the University of Florida
with degrees in both entomology and
environmental horticulture she has
worked throughout the United States and
internationally consulting two
greenhouses nurseries landscapers and
interior escape companies she is the
owner of bug lady consulting now in
business for over 16 years if you missed
my first interviews with her I highly
suggest you start there
Suzanne reached out again because she
wanted to come back on to talk about
scouting and other topics that she's
noticed have been issues for many
cannabis growers on her farm visits just
a reminder if you are a large-scale
commercial cultivator and are serious
about consulting or setting up an
integrated pest management program
utilizing beneficial insects I can't
recommend her enough her website is
www.antakungfu.com
other information on the podcast page
now on to the show
hey Suzanne thanks for coming back on
the show I'm not even sure what we're
talking about today you reached out
saying there was a bunch of stuff you'd
come across in the last year since we
last chatted on on air and wanted to
share it with listeners so yeah take it
away
well first thanks for having me back
again and not that I forced you to have
me on but I just thought it would be a
good idea to come back and talk about
some of the things I'm seeing going on
as I travel around the country working
with cannabis growers of all different
sizes which is actually good because the
other podcast you've got me in touch
with a lot of other growers around the
country and we've had some great
discussions over some issues but the one
of the biggest things I'm finding when
I'm actually at visits when I'm
physically at facilities is that growers
really don't know how to look to find
their pests and to know really what's
going on and there's been a lot of
assumptions and a lot of guessing and
you know it's it's not as simple as oh
you can snap a quick picture throw it up
on Facebook and have somebody ID it
growers really need to have a good solid
scouting program that there's there's a
system to it so that they can be
consistent they can keep records and be
able to put together a good salt program
because I am seeing a lot of waste in
the sense of people are spraying when
they don't need to or even buying
biocontrol agents they don't necessarily
need or buying the wrong product for the
wrong problem out there so one of the
things I think that is critical is that
everybody's got the right tools and
their tool bag anybody that had me into
their facility will see I carry you know
I have a giant nerd bag I carry I'm not
quite wearing a fanny pack yet but I do
have a giant fanny pack but it is really
convenient I mean as much as you know
they could be completely nerdy it's so
convenient because you do need to have
your hands
free while you're out looking for pests
and I honestly I'm I'm really shocked
and surprised how many facilities I go
into and the people that are in charge
of finding paths don't even have a hand
lens just a basic 10x hand lens and
that's something everybody can afford
and that's something everybody should
have it actually you should have almost
all your staff or you know whomever is
in your facility having them so that
they can actually look and see what's
going on I think that's that's really
critical because I'm sure you carry a
hand lens right oh yeah I always carry a
hand lens when I go somewhere yeah there
you go into a growing situation of
course yeah no I totally agree with you
and there they are they're cheap you can
get them on eBay or Amazon something
usually under 10 bucks I got one free at
a trade show at the advanced nutrients
booth which is the only advanced
nutrients thing I will ever have her use
but yeah well okay I know bio best often
gives them away for free like at you
know we did that all day insect ID
workshop at cultivate a couple weeks ago
and I talked to Bach fest and they
provided hand lenses and lanyards for
everybody that came to the workshop so
they often have them sometimes BASF has
them and as a side little plug that's
like the only thing I saw on my website
but I'm not promoting myself at all but
if you can't find them or get one for
free I do some other website not not
necessary to make money off of them but
it's because I was tired of growers
having excusive well I can't find them
well now growers don't have an excuse
you know and the one I carry just
because I'm a little more mature in my
age than you young uns it has an LED
light in it so if you're in a darker
growing situation or if you're down into
the plant canopy that LED lighting there
actually really helps back in my my
youthful days when I was like 20 I could
actually you know see a lot of stuff
without hand lenses now that I'm you
know creeping up on 50 yeah that's a
those days are gone and having that
extra light in there can really help and
you want minimum ten
magnification you can get some up to
like 30x with just you know that the
traditional handheld loupe but they can
be very hard to use I think the best
thing to do is to use like a 10 maybe 15
X out in the field then when you find a
problem I like to snip a leaf put it in
a bag label it where it is then I take
it to the office or wherever you know
there's a desk and then is when I bring
out the Dynalite which again if you
don't own a Dynalite I don't want to
call you you know stupid but it is one
of the best investments you can make
because you can take really good
pictures with it and that way you can
zoom in better get more refined pictures
to be able to send because people
especially on Instagram you got to stop
sending me cell phone quick snaps on
instagrams you cannot zoom in on
pictures when you private message
somebody it's nearly impossible for me
to help you if you want people to help
you with your ID you need to get a good
picture with something Dynalite and then
email it so I can take it and I can zoom
in or other people can zoom in Instagram
is one of the worst social media
platforms for using photos for diagnosis
because of its lack of manipulating
images you know even on Facebook you can
download the image and zoom in but again
when you upload images you do lose
quality and that's why emailing is one
of the better ways to do it
texting is maybe second but again
because of the data compression to make
images smaller to save on data texting
alternative reduces file size and when I
need to get in there and look at you
know tiny little hairs and tiny little
parts you know I need to have as big as
image as you can get me and you know it
may seem expensive spending 150 or $300
on a Dynalite but if it if it saves a
plant or saves a couple plants you know
or saves you from having to buy in a
pesticide or even some bios it's paid
for itself
it's an incredibly useful tool and I
recommend that everybody have one
and I did dad aren't aren't you making
them available now yeah I followed your
recommendation I went out and got myself
a Dino light I think it was in the three
hundred dollar range and tried that out
and then also contacted the company and
now on our website I offer a few options
let's sort of a good better best from
what sort of they recommended and also
my conversations with you but I have to
say the Dynalite is great it's very easy
to use the quality of the images is
amazing we were looking at our the pores
of our skin and other things around the
around the house with it just because I
didn't have any bugs handy to take a
peek at but I'm excited to get it out
into some grow operations and actually
look at some insects yeah and you can
not only is it with your computers or
USB you can get like a $2 $3 connector
USB converter on Amazon or whomever else
and you can connect it to your
smartphone or your tablet and the
software is super easy to use you know
there have been precursors to this there
was like the IPM scope but the IPM scope
was extremely difficult to use having to
manually go into the settings of your
computer and change things to make it
work where I mean I think the Dynalite
is pretty much idiot proof it's just
plug and play and I use it all the time
so you know that's another thing that's
really important and so you know I
talked about putting things in bags you
know having you know little Ziploc
baggies to put samples in is really
important because you just don't want to
you know if you suspect something has a
problem you don't want to carry it
around through your different rooms or
near other plants you want to quarantine
it immediately because I do think that
one of the the big issues that's
happening in cannabis is just self
contamination where people you know will
go in in the morning and they want to go
see their pest problems and what's going
on and so they start in the dirtiest
part of the facility and then end up in
the cleanest part later in the day and
now you've just spread the problem and
if you're carrying around open exposed
plant cuttings you can do that so when
you're scouting you always want to
start with the cleanest part of the
facility and then work your way to the
dirtiest through the day and put samples
in bags I think it's good to carry
irrigation flags so that way if you find
a problem you can stick a flag in a pot
and that way if you do do a treatment
you can come back and check that exact
plant to make sure it worked it also
will allow other people the facility to
know you know if there's a problem so oh
you know this this old colored flag
means there's a mite issue so we know
it's here oh here we know you know
there's a disease issue because you've
got the striped flag and that will help
people know because if you say oh go
back into house to bench three and go
find the hem for us it mites that's
going to take somebody else a bunch of
time but if the the tags are flagged you
know that I'm so the plants are flagged
the plants are tagged with flags then
they're easy to find so that's another
critical tool to have you can also use a
flagging tape or you can come up with
some other system but irrigation flags
come in lots of colors they're
inexpensive to use and readily available
so that's another good thing I've found
and then I mean of course having your
phone with you to take overall shots
it's pretty important but again the
quality of the images for identifying
insect issues it's it's really hard and
I see a lot of people guessing on what
problems are due to these overview shots
and I you know I don't like to guess I
want to see actual images I want to be
able to count legs I want to look at
antennae to make sure that we're getting
the right diagnosis because nobody wants
to waste money or use an ineffective
treatment on that so I think you know
those kinds of things aren't pretty
important another thing that's not as
important but I again it's worth every
penny is you know infrared thermometer
gun to know what your temperatures
really are in your plant canopies not
just your air temperature and that way
when you're making decisions on
biocontrol agents you really know what
what kind of temperatures are running
inside the plants and not just in the
air because you can find some pretty
significant differences depending on
plant
canopy leaf size color of the plant
there's a lot of variables that are in
there when you start looking at that and
again it can make a difference on what
biocontrol is you're gonna select the
other thing that I mean it's I don't
know it's kind of exciting for me to
show growers this and they get so
excited when you show them for the first
time and it's so simple and it's
something again we've done in
ornamentals and vegetables for years
it's just to take a whiteboard I mean
you can even use a sheet of paper but I
think whiteboards work the best and just
put it next to your plant and then bang
your leaves on it and things like thrips
and might not necessarily hemp for us it
might have broad might because they're
too small to see with a naked eye but
things like - spotted spider mites
thrips EFA's they'll just fall out
because when I go into facilities and
people are you know
scouting they're taking a leaf and
flipping it and they're taking leave
from flippin a first of all that takes
too much time and your chances of
finding stuff's pretty slim you take
this white board you hold it up next to
the plant bang the leaves on it and
stuff falls right out because I was in
one facility recently and they were
flipping leaves looking for thrips and
couldn't find them as soon as we banged
him on a board thrips just came raining
out so that's an easy way that I mean
and again pretty standard practice in an
agriculture to find where the pests are
so I think that's you know a pretty
important tool there - to have and to
use I carry a small one in my my nerd
bag when I'm out in the field one of the
things you can also use is the lid of
the styrofoam cooler from the shipping
from the biocontrol agents save those
lids they make really good bang boards
out there for when you're you're
scouting now when you say a bang board
now you're talking about a relatively
thin piece of cardboard or wood yeah
that's just painted white I don't want
to picture people going out with a 2x4
trying to like hit no no it's again I'm
I you can use a white painter's palette
that's that thin white plastic you can
use a white and note ad but the thing
with no pads if your plant is wet at all
then you end up getting your notepad all
wet again the lids to the styrofoam
coolers you can use because it's you
know it's about a inch thick flat piece
of white styrofoam you can for smaller
plants you can literally pick them up
and bang them on the paper
I'll see if I've got I know I've got
some videos somewhere that maybe I can
send you some that you could attach
somehow to the podcast maybe is that
something you can do that people could
see it or maybe I should just post a
little video up on Instagram so people
can see it well I think people should be
following you on Instagram so you should
definitely let people know your
Instagram title but then on the podcast
page I can put up any videos or links to
okay alright we'll get that worked out
because it's something that it's good to
see how it's done and so yeah if you
could never get to any of my scouting
workshops or classes you know it's it's
a it's good to see it firsthand because
it is it's kind of hard to just explain
and that's what's really hard with pest
management just reading stuff online
oftentimes isn't enough you need to be
out doing stuff firsthand and seeing it
to kind of you know make it work so take
me through the process
after we've knocked the insects onto the
whiteboard the bank board and we can see
them there
you're then taking that and taking it
into another room to look closer at the
insects are you killing the insects so
that they can't move like with alcohol
or anything is there a process for that
and then when I go to take that picture
to send it to an expert what do I want
to make sure is included in that photo
okay so when I'm doing it only because
I'm old and crusty and been doing this
for a long time I can pretty much tell
really fast what they are just again it
just comes with experience and it's
something that as growers do this more
they'll get better you know it's easy to
see thrips because they're you know more
cigar shaped when they're running on the
board
oftentimes we do crush them just because
we don't want them going back on to the
plants but oftentimes to if you're using
biocontrol agents your predatory mites
can fallout aureus on my new pirate bug
will often find immature aureus falling
out and obviously those you don't want
to kill and actually you want to kind of
shake those back into the plant
if you need to collect specimens to get
them ID'd what you need to do is have
what's called an aspirator and you can
buy those from bio quip i think they're
about ten dollars and it's basically
like a mini bug vacuum and what you do
is you basically can you put one end of
the tube in your mouth and you suck but
there's a filter in there so you won't
suck up the bugs but it sucks the bugs
or mites or whatever into a vial and so
if you try to pick thrips ups and mites
up you're going to damage them and crush
them this way they get sucked into the
vials and you can put alcohol in there
and you can snap a lid on and then you
can send it off to get it identified and
once these insects and mites are off the
plant material you can ship dead insects
and alcohol to anybody across state
lines to get them identified what you
can't do is pluck a leaf and then ship
the plant material across state lines
with the insects on them and so this is
a way you can get your stuff identified
that's legal yeah that makes a lot of
sense so one of the things you mentioned
is that things like broad mites or
hamper acid mites you won't necessarily
be able to see them are those ending up
on that Bank board like should we have a
spray bottle with alcohol in it for
example to kill anything that we can't
see that may still be on there or what's
the protocol around that yeah I don't
know if I mean if you've got broad mites
or hand for us it might killing ten of
them's not gonna you know not gonna make
that much of a difference I wouldn't be
too worried about it
now if you are suspecting that a plant
does have you know broad mite or hemp
for us it might and you use your hand
could use your hand to bang the plant or
even if you see spider mites before you
go to other houses or other plants I
would probably wash my hand off because
your hands going to be touching the
plant and we know that these very small
mites
you know since they're spread on even
the legs of insects they're spread on
birds feet they're spread very easily
your hand could be act as the vector to
spread these around so you could wear a
latex glove if you wanted or you could
just wash your hands between but just
you know think about that you've got to
think about em ice spreading my problems
around a greenhouse and a lot of times
I'm finding it people are doing it to
themselves by just you know they're
trying to treat in one area then they
spread it to another and you know having
you know wearing lab coats and booties
that you know we're not doing this to
just look like nerds you know you do
this to stop the spread of these
problems and I tell you the hem for us
in might and broad mites are a pretty
serious issue and people just keep
spreading them and having you know just
think about sanitation all the time
because a lot of these issues can be
stopped through good sanitation
practices so yeah my thought was that
bang board might be a source of
contamination well but you would have to
rub yeah but you have to rub the back
board back up on to the plant and you're
not because the bang words not
necessarily always touching the plant
because you're smacking the plant and
knocking things to fall on to it you cut
your hands kind of acting like a
hurricane
smacking trees and then stuff falls out
of it and it falls on to the board now
at the end of the day yeah you could
definitely rinse it off before you you
know you put it in your office or
whatever but we've never you know
sprayed or cleaned it between every bang
because you're walking down the line and
going bang bang bang bang and you're
doing a bunch of it and if you to stop
and spray and then wait for the alcohol
to evaporate you're never getting
anything done got it that makes sense so
can you take me through a like a
traditional morning scouting routine
that you would want someone to do well
first when you get in you know put on
your your your work clothes
because you know I'm finding that
definitely people that have states where
it's legal to grow at home those growers
are having a lot more issues in states
where they can't because people are
bringing pests ins from pests in from
their their own plants at their house so
that's something you have to be well
aware of change into your air-quote you
know work clothes I'm even you know you
know you can do washable scrubs you can
do tie-back suits you know the people
you do lab coats there's all different
kinds of options you know you just have
to look at what works best for your
facility and then again start in your
cleanest room and work your way through
to the into the dirtiest and you know if
you go into the dirtiest room and you
have to go back to the clean room you
know it's best if you can change your
lab coat or change your clothes or
change something because you don't want
to take the pests back in and ideally
you know your propagation area should be
your cleanest I'm finding that's not
necessarily true
and because of that people have a lot of
pests and propagation and then they just
keep it keeps moving with the plants all
the way through the plants life and the
the problems are spreading so again
ideally you'd want to start in the
cleanest room you have your hand lens
you have a notebook you have you know
your camera which is on your phone you
have your bank board you have some files
you have some bags and then you go out
and one thing I do suggest is that you
don't walk the same pattern each time
because you do see different things from
different angles and depending on the
size and there's a lot of variables on
how we come up with you know how many
plants are you going to sample you you
do that and you also and I've had to do
a lot of firmly pushing on growers
lately you need to use sticky cards and
you can't leave them up for three months
and you don't need to be paying a dollar
a sticky card that's crazy expensive I I
don't know why the cannabis industry is
just not wanting to adopt this really
easy method to know what pest you have
or that you have out there I'm seeing a
lot more thrips in cannabis that's been
the biggest thing the last month or so
and if growers had sticky cards up they
would know that they had thrips in there
probably before they started seeing
damage and could mount an attack also
leaving them up for months and months
and months that doesn't do any good if
we're talking about monitoring sticky
cards they have to be changed every week
so when you come into work on Monday
morning whoever's doing your scouting or
management the first thing is to go to
the sticky cards they should always be
dated and then they can go by look at
the sticky cards see what they're
finding if they start to see a few
thrips you know all right we need to you
know mount an attack then on thrips
before they get out of control and
what's very interesting is thrips damage
on ornamentals and vegetables is very
different than the damage we see on
trips on cannabis it looks different so
looking at some of the damage images
online you have to be very careful about
and I think sometimes people are
mistaking spider my damn purse damage
for spider mite damage because they can
look kind of similar but that's where
banging them and seeing what falls it on
the leaves looking what's on your sticky
cards will give you a clue to what's
really going on out there
but you need to change your sticky cards
every week I'll tell you right now and
this is not you know I get no money and
no kickbacks but companies like
beneficial in Sector E they have really
good dry sticky cards which are the kind
of sticky cards that growers need you
don't need the really wet gloppy ones
because those are for more for trapping
larger beetles and things you're looking
to trap you know fungus gnats and shore
flies and thrips and other small flying
insects again bio best
I'm sorry beneficial in sector E has
great ones bio best has some great cards
they and they come in an array of sizes
they also offer sticky rolls and they
can really help guide you on what size
of cards you need for what
doing you know nothing against Amazon
because let me tell you I'm on Amazon
every two to three days buying stuff but
the cards people are buying on Amazon
are not the right cards and they're
paying too much money for them I had a
little rant I post on my Instagram
because when I'm at grow facilities I
like to see the price people are paying
for things and again I have a heart
attack seeing what the cannabis guys are
paying in comparison to what the
ornamental guys are paying and yes when
you buy a pack of sticky cards from
beneficial insectary
you know there's 50 cards in there
you're going to use them if you're
changing them every week and also cards
don't expire you know that pack can you
know last year year or two and they
don't go bad it's not a disposable item
necessarily and it's much better to have
them and use them so that should be part
of that routine on Monday morning when
you get in and then you need to record
what you see you've got to keep records
and it seems like it's a pain in the
butt let me tell you after you do it
over and over you start to see patterns
and you can forecast things that
potentially could happen with your crop
you'll start to see well this time every
year we get an influx of this pests so a
month beforehand let's start getting
ready for this pest problem there
there's a reason why we focus so hard in
this and agriculture because the end of
the day it helps save money and we can
head off a lot of pest issues before
they get started so when you go in
you're going to check your cards you're
going to write down what you see you're
gonna have your bank board you're gonna
walk around you're gonna knock on
numerous places and you're gonna write
down what you find and it's best to you
know if you can put it like into an
Excel spreadsheet and then it's
something that you can share with other
people in the facility so then you can
have good communication because somebody
may not know you're having an outbreak
of thrips in you know house are room B
and go in there and then accidentally go
into your propagation area afterwards
and spread the problem so it's really
important to have really good
communication skills and have that
information of what pests are where to
let everybody know in your facility know
you know
you don't want to hide pest issues with
your coworkers you need to let everybody
know so the problem can be stopped
through there and those over all these
years of doing it the the the facilities
I've worked with that have really good
pest management communication and
record-keeping we just have the best
pest management programs so when you
talk about sticky cards you're using
them for monitoring now I know some
people are using them to trap like adult
fungus gnats and things like that or the
sticky tape are there sort of different
purposes for different cards or do you
not even like to use sticky tape at all
in facilities so that's that's a that's
an excellent question
tad so there's sticky cards that I've
just been talking about are for
monitoring that's why you change him
every week because if it cards like 2
weeks old and we find fungus gnats you
may not even have fungus gnats anymore
because the adults only live a week and
those might have been the adults from
you know 1014 days ago so sticky ribbons
and a very large cards those are used
for what we call mass trapping and those
are not they you know the little four by
six cards you don't do math trapping
with the small ones mass trapping is
done with large ribbons and larger cards
and those we leave up for months and
months because we're not using those to
monitor what pests are there or how many
are there we're just you know it's like
a vacuum cleaner they're going to be
drawn to it and just stuck to it and
it's a way to just attract and kill
pests so there's a very distinct
difference and again the small cards are
monitoring cards and the mass trapping
things are more the ribbons or the much
larger cards on for using the sticky
ribbon it all depends on how your
facilities set up some people have great
ways to put them up other people don't
you don't want to get them too near the
crop because if you get your plants
stuck in them you'll never get them out
if it's somewhere near head height
speaking from personal experience you
don't want to you know lean your head
into it because those sticky ribbons are
pretty sticky so you have to assess your
facility and
even if you have the right setup to use
them so again that's why working with
somebody that knows about that stuff can
say this is a good location this is not
necessarily good location and after you
get your head stuck in sticky ribbons a
few times you do learn oh I've done it I
don't even have much hair but I've
definitely gotten those cards stuck on
my stuck on my head and it's it's gross
takes a lot to get rid of it and yeah
and that's why there go ahead one of the
things you mentioned was location and so
if we're putting up monitoring cards can
you talk a little bit about where we
want those cards to be located in the
facility or in the canopy even so it can
depend on what pest you're really
targeting and depends again on how your
actual facility is set up but generally
I always like to have monitoring cards
near the doors because that's usually
the entry point of pests especially
since I'm seeing so many growing
facilities without vestibules or proper
you know ways to stop pests from the
outside from getting in so by the doors
is always very good if you're more
concerned about fungus gnats you
definitely want to keep them lower to
the soil line because fungus gnats tend
to be down there if thrips are an issue
they're better to be just up above the
plant canopy that's a good location for
them so again this is why you know it's
it's very general information I'm giving
you and that's why I having somebody
that worked with the stuff to help set
up where you need to put what you know
can really help and you know there's
several people out there that that can
do it but I you know you know I have
issue with you know some people out
there promoting themselves as pest
management people which just don't have
the experience to do it so just make
sure the person you're dealing with is
knowledgeable on the situation and has
had experience with it you know people
like Kelly Vance and Paul cool both have
been commercial growers for years before
they went to go work for biocontrol
companies so they know I mean they put
sticky cards out themselves they've
counted them they know how to place them
you know so there are people that do
have really good experience
with this kind of stuff but doorways
areas that are more problem prone and
definitely propagation for sure because
that's often where you see fungus gnats
starting because they tend to be a
little moisture in the soil there and
again all the way up to finish crops and
so with with canopy cannabis since it's
so tall we are putting some down low on
the soil and some above the canopy and
again depending on how you're set up you
know is there something you can attach
to a staked you need to put them on a
pole you know are you hanging them
there's all these different variables
depending on how you're actually growing
depending on how we position and how we
actually put them out well that's good I
think we covered that pretty well I kind
of wanted to ask you a little bit more
about what you've been seeing as you've
been going out to the facilities like
what types of insects in particular
you've been dealing with over the past
year okay
well interesting like I said I mentioned
as of late we're seeing a lot of threats
and different flowers rip species out
there I know some people have been
really great and collecting thrips from
weeks we're still trying to figure out
you know all the thrip species we're
seeing it's really hard to identify
thrips from their immature life stage so
really we need the adults which can be
also difficult in itself but thrips are
definitely something i think that people
are so fixated on broad mite right now
Andrew David's that the thrips numbers
are definitely coming up so that's
something to definitely keep an eye out
for but the good thing about thrips is
the adults do fly if you do have sticky
cards out and you don't need to buy the
expensive blue ones for thrips yellow
works just fine on the sticky cards for
trapping thrips and they're very tiny
though so you have to make sure you know
what thrips on sticky cards look like
but you can detect them very easily on
the sticky cards just before they start
becoming a real issue and you know we've
been discussing so you have a little
feeding damage here a little feeding
damage there you know it's not really
going to impact your harvest probably
not you do need to come in you know with
the big guns and nuclear facility
probably not you just don't want the
thrips numbers to get out of control
because threats are you know pretty
prevalent in the environment and plants
can you know again live with some
feeding damage but you just don't want
them to get out of control but also
thrips are known in especially the
vegetable industry for vectoring virus
we honestly don't know yet in cannabis
you know all the viruses that are out
there for cannabis and if thrips are
vectoring them or not we just don't know
yet so it's best just to try to keep
them in check I think that that's a wise
thing to do and to do that you got to
detect them early and take them out
early and then probably the next thing
I've been getting a lot of emails on our
route acids which you guys are spreading
the root aphid amongst yourselves I
think that when people are getting
cuttings in and we you know I think we
discussed this thoroughly on your other
podcast we're talking about dipping
because with the rue de food since they
do live on the roots people think if
they getting cuttings they're not going
to get rude aphid but what I'm seeing
happening is when those rue de foods get
to a high population they start climbing
up the plant and then the a late or the
winged form is on the foliage and if you
take a cutting and it goes to somebody
else and that one adult a fit is on
there the female then she can start a
whole new colony because you know these
are not coming in fine numbers from the
outside even though the particular 1/3
we're seeing at this point it can be a
pest in other crops like rice and some
ornamental plants but I'm not seeing
high numbers in in the ornamental crops
of this I have seen it but it's not a
huge problem so it's just getting spread
around through the industry on its own
so that's why again sanitation and
proper protocol on dealing with incoming
plants is really critical because
the that the Rudy food hemp for us it
might again you're bringing it in on
plant material completely can press it
mites are still a big issue
definitely self seen them around but I
think everybody is getting settled into
programs at least people I'm working
with but we can get them down to you
know such a low level that yeah there's
a few here and there but we're not
suffering yield loss at the end because
you're not going to be able to eradicate
them unless you you know completely shut
down scrub everything down and then find
clean plant material which is a
challenge because I've seen plants that
are you know young plants being sold and
they have him for us at might and so
it's it's very challenging to keep it
from coming in and growers have to
understand that eradication is is not
gonna happen that that's not even a term
we use anymore in pest management it's
keeping it below the economic threshold
keeping the pests number so low that we
don't suffer any economic loss from it
so so you mentioned you mentioned thrips
you mentioned Rudy fits impressive my
broad mites what insects are we bringing
in I guess from the outside what we need
to worry about from the outside
environment things like spider mites for
example whereas certain things are like
broad like not broad mites but
impressive might see mentioned are only
spread on plant material from cuttings
yeah so what things are environmental in
terms of just our outside atmosphere we
might be bringing it in from our you
know from our outside garden or just
from walking around versus things that
are being spread specifically on
cannabis plants so what is just you know
everyday kind of pest definitely to spot
spider mite that's something that I mean
I have it in my yard right now which I'm
pretty excited about because I need some
because I've been on this videography
filming binge lately and so I will say
for those of you that are coming I'm
teaching a workshop next month in
Charlotte North Carolina for biocontrol
for
plant propagators and we're actually
gonna go to out to Metrolina greenhouses
it's a hundred and eighty acre
greenhouse and we're going to show you
how we do biocontrol releases their show
about nematode applications it's going
to be a really good hands-on workshop
but then they're going to be lectures on
the Tuesday and Wednesday you guys are
going to be wowed and dazzled and
thrilled at all this new video footage
I've shot of of I've got footage of you
know like Swersky feeding on Western
flower tips
Kika merits feeding on Western flower
tips I actually got footage and I'd
never even seen it in my life before and
I was so excited I ran in and woke
William up at like 3:00 in the morning
to tell him and I got the that's nice
dear but I got footage of a Western
flower thrift actually hatching out of a
leaf and most people never see it in
their life but I'm gonna be able to show
those videos at this workshop back to my
point
I need spider mites to be able to you
know show the predatory mites feeding on
spider mites and I just went out to my
yard and on my milk weeds I have to spot
spider mites just right in my yard right
there so that is something that is
really what we call a cosmopolitan pest
we went down to any retail Garden Center
we could probably find it it's just
around so that's something that's very
easily can easily get into your facility
I do think the commercial cannabis
growers they're on top of the spider
mite problems because that is something
they can recognize early on it's bigger
the damage is pretty obvious and there's
so many different predatory mite options
depending on how you're growing to use
and the growers I'm working with a lot
of Marge's doing a preventative program
because if you look at a preventative
spider mite program and using something
and again this depends on where you are
in the country and how you grow but like
per symbolist you're talking about every
two weeks it's less than a penny a
square foot for a preventative program
and so the prevention costs are so low
that it's definitely worth doing so but
that spider mites that's very out there
now broad mite I do believe broad my
being spread through cannabis cuttings
but broad might is also a test in
ornamentals and it's a pest in
vegetables so again it's somewhat
cosmopolitan but the broad might I don't
find in the landscape so much but
definitely a commercial growing
facilities for again ornamental hanging
baskets people that produce a pepper
young pepper plants that we can find the
broad mites there and we are definitely
finding them in cannabis so they could
be coming on cuttings or if you go to
somebody's garden sit in the morning or
out in a pepper field and then go to
work there's a chance you could spread
them that way and vice versa where you
could pick broad might up at work off a
cannabis and bring it home to your
ornamental plants and you know with
broad might it's so tiny you know it's
it's it's tiny like the hemp for us it
might is you have to you know you
usually see the damage before you really
realize you have them and then you have
very high numbers luckily a lot of
commercial growers are using Keuka Maris
the predatory mite and Keuka Maris will
feed on flower thrips their first instar
but also feeds on broad night and it
also snacks not controlled but will
snack on to spot spider mites so using a
cue camaris program like a base four of
that is a really good way to go they're
inexpensive to use beneficial insectary
is producing them right in California
there's also you know other good
suppliers like bio best bio line so you
know there's there's other options to
get them from to now one of the things
that you mentioned was pepper plants
having broad mites and that got me
thinking about how a lot of growers that
are doing living mulches did I hear
about and I worry about that as a
potential vector for some of these pests
is that really a concern with a lot of
these cover crops or other crops that
they may have in the facility are you
are you have you seen
any facilities like this well I haven't
seen many cannabis growers that are
doing that because usually the cannabis
growers that I'm working in our bit
larger facilities and they're doing more
containerized plant material and not so
much the living soil as much because the
scale of the facilities I'm often
dealing with don't lend itself to that
kind of growing but that said you know
we've had lots of years of experience
with using you know these nectary plants
in Ag and ornamentals and everything and
you'd better know what plants you're
putting in there because I've seen
people make mistakes and turns out that
the plants they're using are harboring a
lot of the pests and the pests are
reproducing on those plants and so
that's what you better be very careful
you know marigolds are one that I just
cringe at people using because those are
very prone to having spider mite issues
they're very prone to having thrips
issues they're a very buggy plant
because when we grow them for you know
the the homeowner market they they have
to get treated a lot because they do
have a lot of insect and might issues so
that's why we're very selective on the
plants we're using like with our banker
plant programs and we are sticking with
specific ornamental peppers but we also
treat those peppers with our beneficials
so that you know when you're applying
your aureus and q chimera it's not only
does your crop get it the those plants
would get an application to in the
growing situation you're talking about
is or they should be doing it because
peppers I think are something and again
this will be a whole nother podcast will
have to do talking about using peppers
banker plants for cannabis production
because I think there's a lot of
potential there and actually there is a
greenhouse facility in New York State
Dickman farms they're getting ready to
go into some serious production of
ornamental pepper plants grown with
biocontrol agent
so that when cannabis people want to
move into doing this that they can
contact Dickman get these plants they
won't have pesticide residue on them and
they can't advertise that they've been
raised with beneficials because you
can't ship insects across state lines
without having permits but know that
these plants have been grown using the
beneficials on them wink wink nod nod
and that so you'll be able to move them
into your facility and then it will
provide a good resource for aureus the
mine at pirate bug yeah I actually
ordered some seeds and grew out the
purple flash pepper in our greenhouse
this year we didn't bring in any
beneficial insects just because we
didn't have much of a budget for it and
I just was curious if any would
naturalized so I need to actually go
back and see if we did get anything on
there but all things aside they're just
they're beautiful plants I mean for me
that aspect of our business is it's
really just a you pick for the community
so it's not a high-value crop for me or
part of my revenue if it was I would
definitely put more time and energy into
maintaining it well and and and there's
a big difference between growing outside
and growing indoors so if you're outside
you don't necessarily necessarily need
to inoculate them if you come again to
this this workshop I'm doing next month
they're at Metrolina one of the mum
fields is 20 acres and I think there's
another one that's like 16 acres we do
put out a lot of these in Sector II
plants but we have pre-inoculated some
of them with beneficials but then the
other plants do attract in native
beneficials because this is being done
outdoors now the plants that we use
strictly inside you we do have to
inoculate with the beneficials because
you can't get the numbers of beneficials
coming in from the outside and you know
there was a really good learning moment
like that I was in Colorado working just
recently I'm actually got back yesterday
and I went to lunch with the growers and
as we were walking back to the car they
had some planners in the city
they were filled with a lissom and then
they also had petunias and some other
plants in there and I had him stop and
look and if you looked at the alyssum
the ilysm was just just tons of insects
were on it buzzing around there were
been officials there are pollinators
there all kinds of stuff there was
nothing on the petunias and the other
plants and it just shows you that if you
plant the right plants and this is for
outdoors
you can't attract beneficials in it but
again you don't want to plant things
that are going to be a big magnet for
pests though so you do have to be
careful in your plant selection you have
to look at you know what your
environment is what your key pests are
and that's how we put all these programs
together you're not going to find one
solution that works for everybody and
you know pest management really today
has to be pretty customized for
depending on how you're growing what
you're growing who you're growing for
you know all these different variables
also what's your budget how much time do
you have because a lot of my growers
they don't have time to do banker plant
systems or nectary plants or mess with
that so they'll just rather buy
beneficials every two weeks and dump
them out other people have the time and
on a tighter budget and they'd rather
try to you know encourage some of their
native their own beneficials but you
really have to know what you're doing
because you have to make sure you're not
breeding pests yeah one thing you
mentioned there earlier on was about
applications and propagation and I know
I've heard you mentioned to me before
that one of your issues with some of the
other recommendations you're seeing from
people that are going around is bug
consultants is that they're they're
doing too heavy of applications too late
in the plant's life and it's really
important to get started right away with
that cutting to really establish those
beneficial insects and keep the the
pathogen or pest populations down early
on is that pretty accurate oh my god I
want to stick a gold star on your shirt
right now for like at least I wouldn't
talk I mean it seems like I mean I mean
I don't know everything and I'm still
learning every day too but that is one
of the most important things you've got
to start clean I don't understand this
we'll deal with it later mentality
because all that's going to happen is
your numbers are gonna get worse and the
cost of doing a bio program and
propagation when the plants are tiny and
close together it's so inexpensive
comparatively to try to come in and
flower and clean up an epidemic problem
and that's something we're really going
to focus on at this workshop which by
the way it's called the plug and cutting
conference it's a very quaint meeting
it's not super big but it it is and it's
not just for pest management it's it's
the whole meeting talked about a lot of
propagation stuff and there's a mini
trade show with it but my focus there is
to yes beat you propagators up or people
that are propagating young plants on
more so how to use BIOS and propagation
and again Metrolina
you know if you've got a greenhouse
facility that's 180 acres and they're
using bio control in their propagation
if you can do it on that scale anybody
can do it
and I'm actually going to have the
employees that actually when they come
to work they actually put out the bugs
I'm actually gonna have them they're
doing it so you see how they actually do
it but then we're also going to talk
about you know other different situation
you know storage and then there's going
to be a tour we're going to go out and
see the mum fields where we're doing the
banker plants I think it's going to be a
good educational opportunity for poor
people and they only run this meeting
every few years so and as a side note
some really good plant pathologists will
be there like dr. chris hayes who he's a
good close personal friend but he is an
awesome plant pathologist in a view and
at AAG disease for Biological disease
management that's a guy that sounds
great I will put up a link on the
podcast page to the conference so people
can sign up and check it out if they're
interested yeah and also well since I I
mean I generally don't like to do self
plugs but it seems like this show I'm
doing them I'm also doing another one
who I'm gonna have to look at the date
but it's the biocontrol East conference
and that's going to be up in Rochester
New York and on the Friday of the show
I'm doing a four hour
insect ID class which if you missed did
it cultivate which by the way I had a
lot of cannabis growers come and I was
so excited to see them that are really
getting into the insect ID we're
basically going to be doing the very
similar thing at the biocontrol East
meeting up in New York where you're
going to get four hours of pretty
intensive insect and mite ID which
applies to ornamentals vegetables in
cannabis because as we've discussed
there's a lot of crossover pests and I
do have some of the cannabis specific
pests included but we're also putting
together like a booklet to take home
with you from that meeting from that
class that will basically be a pretty
good insect ID booklet for you oh that's
great I went to the bio controls West
one as you're as you may recall and I
really enjoyed getting to hear some of
the speakers and also the the course you
taught relating to insects and cannabis
so it's it's definitely a great
opportunity if you're close by I can
check it out yes
so and by the way back the backtrack a
little bit you're talking about pest
don't forget about your foliar aphids
because those species and we are seeing
several different foliar aphid species
out there that's something that you
don't necessarily always pick up on
sticky cards because again sticky cards
are more for flying insects and if
you've got flying Foley or aphids and
you've got a really high population
somewhere in your facility or you're
open to the outside and flying aphids
from the outdoors have come into your
facility we see that sometimes and those
wing to evens may not even be a species
that can survive on your crop but you've
got them trapped on the cards and so
that way you can you know look to see if
this is an issue or not but we are
definitely seeing foliated problems you
gotta have a pretty high number of them
before they really cause an issue but
you don't want them to get out of
control luckily there's you know we have
several of our commercial parasites
there's you know predators like lace
wings which you've seen doing a really
good job and those are inexpensive to
use and you know even just hosing them
down with
you can knock a lot of them off your
pants so just yeah we are seeing fully
races and several different species so
keep an eye out for those yeah I just
want to remind listeners that it's so
important to start with identification
and that's something that you've taught
me because I I still talk to growers and
they're there talking to me about all
these different pesticide applications
that they they start immediately the
moment they notice an insect pests and a
lot of times I try and get them to
backtrack and make sure that they
actually have a positive identification
because the treatment for broad mites
versus a phase versus thrips can vary
quite a bit and if we're gonna throw
money at a problem or potentially stress
the plant through a pesticide
application we want to make sure that
we're doing the right one to deal with a
problem so that is something else when
it actually you you just got a second
gold star tag I'm learning you know this
this is important this is the time of
year here in Washington where we start
seeing aphids on our vegetables so I
just went out and pulled some kale that
I fed to my chickens because it had a
fence on it that was my way of combating
it but this is the time of year when you
start seeing powdery mildew when we
start seeing athens
and certain sort of insects like you
mentioned that tend to be more seasonal
with certain crops and since i'm not
growing cannabis i noticed it on my
vegetable crops but i do know that the
same thing is happening in cannabis
towards the end of the season the plants
starting to senesce it's finishing up
its flowering and you're going to see
higher levels of some of these insects
yes yeah / sure but and this is where
you know like with your kale most likely
you had on there what's sometimes
referred to as the crucifer aphid they
tend to be a little gray inner fuzzier
almost like they've got a dusting on
them and that yeah see that I'm in my
life and I highly doubt it would ever
move into cannabis oh if you did have
your kale next to your cannabis green
house yeah I wouldn't worry about it but
if you were growing you know let's say
mums and you saw a green peach aphid on
that I would be concerned because we
know that can move into cannabis so he
had got to know what you have and God
please stop you know
pending on the internet God's to
identify your problems because I just
see such bad ID because there's so many
armchair quarterbacks in the cannabis
industry that sit behind the computers
and say it's this this this and it's not
the problem and I'm done getting into
fight to these people on the internet
I'm just done you know going to these
groups because I just get attacked
oftentimes and and I'm done with it
trying to help that way but again many
of you know you've reached out to me
through like Instagram or texted me or
you know numerous other outlets I try to
help everybody I can but then only have
so many hours in the day and I'm working
seven days a week right now so um be
patient with me if I don't get back to
you immediately oh great well I
appreciate you covering more of the the
issues around scouting and some of the
insects that you're seeing now that
you've been working in cannabis for
another year is there anything else you
wanted to chat about before we sign off
just there are some scouting apps there
is actually one that's getting better
and it's it's from Cornell and it's the
the green house Scout app now they've
had some issues now because of all the
new cookies and security issues so I
don't think it's available right now but
and again it's not focused for cannabis
but it's a good general overall with
some of the basic pests the beneficials
actually some pesticide compatibility
information in there and it's one of
these ever-evolving
apps that Cornell keeps adding to and
being that it's from a university you
know they're very focused on being
scientifically accurate and everything
but you can go in and you know if you
look up you know a pest then it can give
you some of the key beneficial that are
being used for it they also have some
where you can do tracking of populations
in it and you can actually print reports
from it and you know for ten bucks you
can is a lot of good information from
that and again it's it's ever-improving
out there
and that project again is it's a Cornell
University project but dr. Elizabeth
lamb is who's been working on that and
again when I talked to her like two or
three weeks ago the again they're still
trying to get worked out with Google
about getting it back for sale because
of the security stuff and it's not there
was a problem with their app it's if
you've noticed every website and every
everything you've got to agree to this
these new messages about cookies and
stuff they just are working on getting
that worked out there so you know that
can be another important tool and if I
come visit your green house and you
don't have sticky cards I'm going to
poke you in the eye
I just you've got to have those sticky
cards up because they can be such a
great resource great well I'll
definitely put a link to that app as
well for people so they can at least
monitor it and see when it becomes
available again and I just want to thank
you for your time again today and
sharing with our audience I always learn
something new every time I talk to you
so I really appreciate it well I
appreciate you giving me the opportunity
to get this information out because
again I'm I'm working in multiple
industries you know the workloads been
pretty intense and I'm trying to help
everybody I can and I think sometimes if
I can educate the masses a little bit
more then it might cut down on some of
the other you know after-hours
communications which again I don't mind
helping people but it's just you know it
gets a little overwhelming at time
because I do want to be able to help
people and I'll get you those links of
my upcoming talks I do keep a list on my
website my websites bug lady consulting
if you go to the home page and please
don't criticize me for my website I am
NOT a web developer I'm happy I have
what I have but if you go there there's
a little button and it's like where's
the bug lady or it might be upcoming
talks I can't remember you go there I
have a list of any of the upcoming
sessions that I'm going to be speaking
at and usually have links to to the
actual conferences and meetings for that
so and then I'll also get you those
links to tad because I do think
that both those opportunities the
plugging cuttings and in the biocontrol
lease there's going to be some real good
information and actually - for your BC
listeners I'm actually coming up to
speak in British Columbia this fall also
at a greenhouse conference so I'll be up
there - cool I will yeah thanks again
all right thanks dad have a good
afternoon that was entomologist Suzanne
Wainwright Evans also known as the bug
lady her website is www.antakungfu.com
right on the podcast page at WWE is
organics calm just click on the podcast
menu on the top of the home screen and
don't forget to sign up for our
newsletter on our website right on the
home page and subscribe on your favorite
listening platform so you can stay up to
date with all the latest information and
podcasts right as they come out you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey thanks for listening
[Music]