during this holiday season I would like
to take a minute to thank all of our
listeners and guests for making this
past year so special thanks to your
continued support of the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast and our
advertisers we can keep doing our part
to bridge the gap between research and
cultivation we are honored that you
choose to spend time with us and we wish
everyone a safe and healthy holiday
season
[Music]
foreign
to the Cannabis cultivation and science
podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey of Kiss
Organics this is the podcast where we
discuss The Cutting Edge of growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is my good friend
Suzanne Wainwright Evans also known by
many as the bug lady she's an ornamental
entomologist specializing in integrated
Pest Management Suzanne has been
involved in the green industry for more
than 25 years with a primary focus on
biological controls and using pesticides
properly she is a graduate of the
University of Florida with degrees in
both entomology and environmental
Horticulture Suzanne has been on the
podcast multiple times and I highly
suggest folks go back and listen to some
of her other podcasts if you haven't
already this podcast though is a
two-part Series where we discuss some of
the latest research in cannabis and hemp
from a recent invite-only conference she
attended one of the biggest topics being
viruses and cannabis now on to the show
oh
hey Suzanne thanks for coming on the
show today well thanks for having me
it's always exciting to talk to you
you had called me uh recently on the
phone to tell me about a conference that
you had gone to up in Canada where there
were some new information and research
that come out that you wanted to share
with Growers
um so I'll just let you dive in and
explain some of the stuff that you
learned okay well
from Canada
um so that was probably where the
confusion happened it was actually at
Colorado State out in Fort Collins and
it was
um a hemp research meeting it's for the
researchers in western United States
that are working on hemp pass there were
some hemp researchers from the East
Coast there but it's the the people that
are focused on insects disease mites
nematodes and actually there were even
some presentations on
herbicide trials um
for outdoor fiber production because in
in that situation
trying to grow hundreds of acres of hemp
without an herbicide has is a really uh
big problem because the weeds are just
overtaking the hemp crop and you don't
get a harvestable crop because you know
some of these weeds I don't want to call
them quite super weeds but they can
overtake the hemp pretty easily
um
and so uh work needs to be done on that
because currently there are no
registered herbicides for hemp so the
researchers are doing the work there and
trying to figure out like what
pre-emergent herbicides can be used or
um more targeted herbicides that would
be safe to use for fiber hemp production
so it was a a combination of multiple
disciplines
which was super interesting but the the
thing that I found super interesting is
a friend slash colleague of mine from
Canada uh Dr zamir punja um he and I
have spoken together at a handful of
meetings uh he's with Simon Frazier
University and being that he's in Canada
he's got an advantage over some of the
U.S researchers because again notice I
said I was at a hemp meeting
um because we still have that same issue
where the university people can't really
work on cannabis they can only work on
hemp where up in Canada zamir
um can work on hemp and has been
actually doing a lot of his work in
actual cannabis production facilities
which really helps to give us a better
Real World perspective
on
um
on what's happening out there
um and one of the things that I found
super interesting and again I am not a
plant pathologist I will never pretend
to be one you guys know I will not
consult on Plant Pathology but I dangle
around the edge of it because I have
several friends that are plant
Pathologists and I do see a lot of
things out in the field is that when
they started looking at fuserium which
fuserium
has been a pretty bad problem in
cannabis and hemp
um that they're finding multiple
fusarium species most people just think
fusarium is fusarium but fusarium is not
fuserium
um most of the time when you look up
fusarium
um you are learning you come across
fusarium oxosporum that is one that we
commonly see in ornamental crops
um
and there is a significant amount of
research on it but they found zamir
found
in Canada that about when they find few
serum about 65 of the time it is access
Forum
um and so there are other fusarium
species out there
um and though again I'm not a plant
pathologist and I'm gonna uh butcher
this and I can already feel my friends
my plant pathologist friends cringing
when I want to pronounce this uh there's
a pro-lifer a team and it's
p-r-o-l-i-f-e-r-a-t-u-m they're finding
that few cerium about 25 of the time so
there's a 25 chance that that's the
fusarium you could be dealing with and
there's some other more obscure runs
um but just be aware that
um
you may need to do a little more digging
if you are dealing with you serium and
you may need to get tested
um to find out which one you have to
find the best management practice and
one of the other things that was
interesting
um and I've mentioned this before is
that we always think about fusarium
being a root board disease and being
systemic inside of the plant
um there is a foliar or aerial fusarium
and they've actually been recovering
fusarium from flower buds
um on cannabis plants and
one of the other interesting things that
um they've been observing and this comes
down to propagation is that root bound
plants which I see a lot of root bound
cannabis plants tend to have more
fusarium issues that having those
spiraled roots that girdle in on
themselves are not good and you need to
make sure you have really well
um developed but also you know branching
root systems and not spiraling to help
prevent a few serium issues
um in your plants and it was interesting
when they were talking about that like
all the researchers were like yeah yeah
especially when they talked about uh the
the spiraling girdling roots in pots and
how important that is for them not to
have that because what I often see is
people hold plants too long in either a
four inch or one gallon and then the
roots go around the edge of the pot and
then they just pot them up and then it
doesn't grow out of that circular root
ball shape
um and it just the roots get Tighter and
Tighter in on themselves
um if you're not familiar with you know
how to untangle your roots and kind of
flange them out make sure you do some
reading on doing that and better yet
don't let them get root Bound in the
smaller containers
um yeah let's let's touch on that for a
second
um so
on Instagram I see people posting photos
of their bragging about their roots and
in a lot of you know whether it's a
mycorrhizal company or something like
that and a lot of times in those photos
like you said the roots will be wrapping
around themselves so essentially you can
remove the pot and you'll still see the
shape of the container just out of made
up of root mass and
um well that's a good root biomass
that's not optimal for plant health and
and like you said so what you need to do
is transplant sooner or if you're using
fabric pots or the fertile pots those
types of pots that helps prevent this
root girdling and uh you want white
bright white roots not the brown or
mushy looking roots that typically a
sign of fruit disease so I just wanted
to touch on those points why since you
brought up root health and yeah people
do need to transplant sooner a lot of
times I like to transplant a
I guess my biggest visual clue since
this is a podcast would be when the
roots are visible through the soil or
the media and have enough structure to
hold
the the shape of the
of the container that they were coming
out of but yet are not seen visibly
starting to turn and wrap around
that container does that make sense yes
100 and I would I would agree with that
statement
yeah I mean it's easy to check too so
that's the thing people need to be
checking their plants to see what stage
of root growth they're at in transplant
accordingly yeah you actually the
probably where I see this the most is in
the tree industry
um and people go by you know uh canned
in pots trees and and then they just go
pop them out of the pot and stick them
in the ground and the trees as the tree
grows it literally chokes itself to
death so it might not die in the first
few years but later on in life it will
choke itself to death and
um I've been in enough like forensic
dead tree talks and they'll show how
they'll pop these trees up and the tree
just girdled itself to death because it
was the roots were girdled or with trees
also planting too deep is one of the
biggest tree Killers
um people plant them too deep and pile
up soil around the top of the tree and
that can be fatal there's a famous study
where they looked at how many trees
coming out of Nursery production and
then planted in yards are planted too
deep so I mean roots
planting them correctly not having
girdled roots not planting too deep is
all really important now I will you know
have to say that certain plants
especially like tomatoes you can plant
deep because they throw advantageous
Roots cannabis can throw adventitious
Roots too but you know know your plant
no girdled roots and know how deep to
plant it
yeah and if you do get root girdling
like that you actually want to go
through and score the roots so I'll take
a knife or a sharp tool and and go and
go down at least four or five times
around a circular pot as a way of
loosening those roots up and and
spreading them out so it's not the end
of the world if it does happen but if
you don't want to plant that plant as is
you actually need to
break up the roots I guess yeah we're
more aggressive than people realize with
it the plants can handle it yeah you
know we will tend to because you know we
have seven acres here and we've been
planting lots of trees here we'll tend
to take the roots and just like pull
them out and then plant them with the
roots then kind of out in the hole to
spread them
um that said if you do cut your roots or
root prune them before planting make
sure your tool is clean and then also
you know anytime you wound there is a
chance of pathogens can get in
um and you know good old fusarium
um you know interesting
um uh zamir has not only looking at what
diseases they have he's also been
trialing
um some products as far as prevention
and like with the fuserium they found
that
um
uh root Shield did really well in their
trials and that's trichoderma they also
did pre-stop uh pre-stop is a newer
product from lollymond and then also
asparillo which is coming from biobest
all three of those products formed well
as a preventative
um to getting a few serum and it's not
going to fix it
um and that's why for me I've always
been really big about trichoderma
applications early on because
trichoderma will actually eat fuserium
and protect your roots and prevent you
from getting the problem because once
you get few cerium it's very very
difficult to manage so prevention is key
here so they are finding in their
cannabis trials on fusarium that again
root shield pre-stop and esparillo have
been doing a very good preventative job
of preventing the plants from getting
the pathogens
did they talk about environmental
conditions or seasonality affecting
um prevalence of fusarium no because he
his his stuff that he's doing is
controlled in indoor environment so it's
not as seasonal as it would be outside
in outdoor production
okay
because it's it's it's summer year round
inside of a greenhouse
sure but we still see it showing up
obviously in greenhouses and
environments um and you know things like
even though cannabis doesn't get it like
downy mildew you don't get that to later
see season because on the East Coast
that's got to blow up on the the jet
stream and so you can see seasonality
disease because the environment's moving
um the disease around
um but no he didn't go into that too
much and at all on the environment
um as far as that is crazy to me too I
remember hearing that at a talk about
how these spores actually go up
into the atmosphere like quite high in
the environment like you mentioned the
jet stream I I had no idea that the
spores could travel as far or as high as
they they do or the researchers found
yeah yeah no there's some crazy stuff
where they're actually you know the
going up there and then looking for what
they can find up in I don't know if the
right words the atmosphere
um
and
and look and they're finding pathogens
up there
um and that's why yeah you know with
hurricanes you know I grew up in Florida
um and work a lot in the Florida
industry too and why we see
um bad disease issues after hurricanes
and I kind of thought it was because oh
there's so much rain but they think now
part of it is is just the giant wind
blender of moving all the pathogens
around and then dumping the pathogens
um so there's some interesting work
being looked at with that stuff
so cool what uh what other research did
you find
um was presented at the conference that
well you thought would be relevant to
cannabis I think one of the biggest
focuses that zamir has been working on
is hopsulate and viroid which is you
know a very I don't know if it's a
sensitive touching I don't know what the
description is but it's it's a
it's it's it's an issue
um and for a while I wasn't sure I was
convinced how much of an issue it was
only because again I don't run in this
Arena again I run with six and eight
legged things but
um they had done
or they have been doing
um up in Canada some really extensive
testing and
um in 2020 through 2022
um they started testing
um cannabis plants
um for
um different diseases
um mostly virus stuff well virus and hop
sleep and viroid which is not a virus
and looking at the different things and
they did find
um through their
serving out there in Canada they tested
uh 1700 over 1700 cannabis plants in
Canada and they found that about 19 of
those plants tested positive or hops
latent viroid that's almost 20 percent
of the plants tested positive
most people
um don't know they have it and I would
say until it's too late but since
there's no way of curing or fixing it
um
you know it's it's too late it's just
too late just having it is too late but
they start seeing you know the smaller
plants the smaller flowers but one of
the biggest take-home things for me was
the imagery
um that they had
um of the trichomes and how the
trichomes were significantly smaller you
still have the same number of trichomes
but you have smaller like these deflated
it's almost like a deflated balloon of a
trichome head and leads to less THC and
less uh CBD
so
um it can be pretty devastating uh to
the crop
one thing that was this was one of the
very interesting things for me
um
and again don't come back to me and ask
questions because I'm not a plant
pathologist
um and zamir has put out some really
good papers and he's done some really
good
um YouTube videos
um out there but one of the things they
started looking at was if they're
testing plants and people like yeah test
my plants they test negative and then
they you know sell off clones or move
them to other facilities why is it
spreading so much well what they started
looking at is they were tests they
tested the roots the stems and
um the leaves of the plants and what was
super interesting is that
um
on on the testing they found that and he
had this really great chart
um which I talked to him about
recreating this chart for an online
infograph and I need to talk to him
about getting that done but basically if
they tested a leaf you could have a
negative result if you tested a stem you
could have a negative result if you
tested that same plant and you tested
the roots you can test positive
but
if the Leafs test positive the roots are
always positive
so if you really want to know if you
have it or not you have to test the
roots because again if the the roots are
the the
the the the the the one consistently
positive thing in a way because again
you can have negative leaves and
negative Roots but you can't have
positive leaves and negative Roots if
the foliage is positive and the stems
are positive the roots are going to be
positive but you can have positive roots
and negative stems and foliage so just
testing the foliage is not enough and I
think possibly this is what's happened
is because we're also trained for
testing the Foliage for viruses you know
I wasn't ever taught to test roots for
viruses
but then when people started talking
about it more they're like well yeah
certain viruses move to the root systems
and they hang out there
um and then later on they express
themselves thus latent viroid and so
they think this is part of what's
happening is people test their plans and
in good faith they think they're
negative but they're actually positive
because it's it's positive in the root
system and so I think this is kind of
what's created some problems confusions
and you know you think you have clean
plans but then you end up with the
viroid and how did you get it and
there's been lots of speculation on how
it is being transmitted out there so
that was a super interesting thing
um for me to realize that you can't just
be testing foliage that you need to be
testing root systems but be cautious
because you can't test like roots with
soil because the soil can mess up test
results you have to
um you know talk with your testing
company on the procedure and protocol
and um when I was at MJ bizcon last week
with you
um I did talk to some of the the testing
companies and
um I'm waiting for some answers on
protocol for testing Roots because the
people at the show didn't have a clear
answer because again you have to be able
to remove all the soil but you can't add
anything that could possibly mess your
test up
yeah I've been talking to uh Three
Rivers biotech about this and I'm just
going back here to my notes they did
some research where they also found
um similar results where uh they had 14
positive root samples only seven of
those were positive on Leaf samples out
of uh 35 cultivars it looks like they do
have the ability to test Roots
um because I'd ask them this after
talking to you last I need to confirm
that because we've been working with
them to offer buffer testing for top
slate and thyroid
and I know one of the recommendations
was you test the plant then test it
again a few weeks later
and that's another way of of kind of
getting to that
positive answer or negative or more
confirmed negative
zamir says three tests three tests
before you can say a plant does not have
it the problem is is you test it you
think it's negative and it's sitting
there and it's possibly positive and
then you get into the this the spread
and this is stuff that zamir has been
looking at where they're looking
um at the movement like they he had
these maps of greenhouses and showing
which plants are positive and you could
see you know hot zones and the question
is has it been spread I know it's been
thrown out there about rude aphids
vectoring it pretty much all the
research people have you know said
that's not likely
um I I had been corresponding with Dr
Susan Halbert
um she's one of the top aphid experts
um in probably North America
and you know the general consensus is
most likely not
um you know there's enough mechanical of
people with pruners and touching plants
and this and that
um and one of the areas they're just
starting to look at is it could be
waterborne
um again not my wheelhouse we're gonna
have to wait until more research comes
out about this and again I know that um
in the hemp side of things here in the
United States like Purdue's looking at
all this stuff you see Riverside and up
in Canada Simon Fraser universities
who's uh doing a lot of This research on
this stuff so there's not clear answers
yet and you know again
uh this is so you don't think it's past
it's spread by pests at this time it's
not it's not a likely Vector when you
say waterborne though are you talking
about splashing from when people are
mechanically watering or you're talking
about like transpiration
like through water Movement Like through
sub irrigation sharing like ebb and
flood benches things like that I wonder
if that's okay part of well yeah for me
I think the bigger implication is for
those of us that reuse the media if that
soil has had a plant that had a you know
a positive test for a virus um
I don't know if we have ways of
remediating that at this point in time
yo though I have Growers with you know
currently doing quite well that have
tested positive for the virus and are
reusing their media in those beds um
they just have to really manage
the plants and keep them really healthy
and then they don't see a lot of effect
from the virus I guess but if they if
they miss it and the plants are not as
healthy as they should be then it seems
like they just really crash much harder
than a non-infected plant would well
just like people you know if you're run
down you're not eating well you're
having Coke for breakfast every day
you know yeah I just you're I just want
to be careful with our human analogies
because I feel like some people take
them too far I I agree in this case I
think it applies but in other cases I
think people start making comparisons
that don't necessarily fit I agree I
agree but we all know anything if you're
healthier you're less likely
have issues I mean that's that's a
wonderful thing
and that
um
with having healthy plants I mean you
can and just like rude aphids I mean
I've seen people with rude aphids and
bad ones but they have a healthy looking
crop um because the plants are healthy
enough to get through it uh and and I
agree with you that's one of the things
that scares me about reasoning soil is
you know chopping the plants off and
then planting right next to it you're
not removing the the roots that can have
pathogens in them
um also when people chop the foliage and
put it on the soil surface because you
can just be recycling pathogens and
pests right back into your system and I
I know the the the that we've got enough
healthy things to fight it well you hope
you do you do until you don't
um and from an environmental standpoint
I understand
you know
reusing the soil because that's you know
much more eco-friendly to do but at the
same time you have to know your crop and
you have to know your risk to know if
that's right for what you're doing and
also depends on on the size of your your
production because if you've got you
know some of my Growers on ornamentals
you know there are hundreds of acres and
trying to micromanage all those crops
you know it's just it's it's too
difficult if you have a smaller Growing
System often like you do in cannabis you
can micromanage the crops better
well it's different too when the plants
leaving the facility as a living plant
consistently like you see with your
ornamental side you brought up this
concept though of healthy plants being
more resistant and that kind of in my
head led me to the bricks discussion
that you see and I just feel like we
should at least talk about it because I
still see it out there quite a bit um
can you just explain to me because I've
mentioned this to people that there is
research out there that shows that
um and uh correct me if I misstate this
but that it doesn't really matter how
healthy your plant is if there's insect
pressure that is sufficient
you will still the insects will still
eat the plant more or less right and
sugars did not equate healthy
okay I mean if
I mean just take us through it I guess
so
um there is this should I say urban
legend and you know the people that make
these claims
say they have data but they won't show
you any data or any research
but as of yet the research that has been
looked at that
pretty much disproves it just because
you have high bricks does not mean you
have pests and I see this in almost
every talk I give
if you walk out your back door and
you're in like virgin forest in the
middle of Montana or you know Wyoming
every plant you're looking at there is
getting eaten by insects because plants
are designed to be eaten by insects
that's what they do it's an ecology you
know you look at oak trees caterpillars
eat the leaves that's why trees have so
many leaves the caterpillars poop on the
ground it makes the fertilizer for the
tree it's not a bad thing plants being
eaten but when we have these
monocultures and what perfect plants
this is when you know this human
you know we're trying to create a crop
for humans and we have zero tolerance
really for insects even though plants
can still perform well even if there's
feeding damage on them
sugars really I mean you think about it
if if insects didn't like to feed
on sugary plants why do things eat
apples why do things eat grapes why do
things eat blueberries I mean those
fruits are all super high in sugars and
you know you look at drosophila Suzuki
eye I'm trying to remember the common
name right now
it's it's a huge pest in berries where
this uh drosoft it's a fruit fly comes
in lays its egg inside of blueberries
raspberries all these different berries
and then the maggot eats uh the fruit
and that's high sugar so how is high
sugar stopping that it's not and that's
the crazy thing to me I I just don't
know the whole idea of the bricks and
the in fact I I do have over in my
drawer right next to me I have a bricks
meter that's more testing sugars for uh
uh for understanding for grapes for
knowing the sugar content for you know
food consumption
um and this whole idea of just pumping
your bricks and you won't have pest
issues there's just no evidence of it
out there
so could we could we say though that if
you had two cannabis plants and one had
a higher Brix level it may in theory be
a healthier plant if it's the same
cultivar
being healthy
I mean that's the correlation that a lot
of Growers or Association that a lot of
Growers have been making is supposedly
it's going to be healthier and if you
hit a certain bricks number on that for
that particular crop and it's going to
be a different number for blueberries
apples cannabis then you will not see
pest pressure on that plant
um that's I mean that's the argument
that's that's being presented where's
where's but from an entomologist you're
saying that you just haven't seen any
research to support this well there's
not
supports it um we've seen
there's like one paper that was kind of
inconclusive but pretty much the
research that has been done in the past
disproves this claim
um and again the people that are
currently making these claims
they'll just say they say they have data
but they've never publicly released it
they've never published a paper on it
they've never written a scientific
journal article nothing it's like we've
got this big secret but we're not going
to tell you how we did anything just
trust us even though we're not going to
tell you anything and okay so if anyone
has data on this and is listening send
it to Suzanne
and uh we'll we'll do a whole podcast on
bricks if uh if someone can prove it to
be effective so
um one one other note though when we're
talking about this though there there is
like you mentioned this human analogy
there is it is the same with plants if
you have a healthier plant it's going to
be more resistant
to past pests tend to go to the stressed
out plant
um in your room right I mean that's
fairly
is is that safe to say you're kind of
making a face like yes but at the same
time
you know I I also think part of our
problem is is the the fact we're dealing
with so many invasives that that kind of
throws everything out the window because
you look at the United States and ash
trees and they're they're basically all
gone because of emerald ash borer and
you cannot tell me these millions of
trees that have been killed were
unhealthy
um it's because we had an invasive come
in emerald ash borer and wipe out all
the trees
um and those trees have been living
healthily for you know hundreds of years
um in the forests here so I think that's
nothing I mean yes plant health and
not going overboard with plant health
because there's this fine line of
you know NPK and other nutrients and
plants but you know
giving them too much love too much
nitrogen can definitely create pest
issues
um we know that for sure there's been
really good research out of like Texas A
M looking specific specifically at
nitrogen levels in correlation to
Western Flower thrips and two-spotted
spider mites showing that pushing your
plant with too much nitrogen creates
past problems so there's this happy
medium of not overfeeding not under
feeding being right in the million
middle that makes it less attractive or
because there's a difference between
plants pests being attracted to it or
pests having a higher reproductive rate
on the plant because of its nutritional
content those are two completely
different things
um you you look at
um I think one of probably the most
famous case of that is
um actually a medical oprid which I know
legal cannabis curve is going to use
it's one of the neonics
um it's been used for decades it's it's
kind of at the center of the B
controversy but one of the things we
know about that is if you treat a plant
with that and then you put two spots
spider mite on it those spider mites
females actually live longer and have
more babies because a metacloper without
going too deep basically acts as a plant
growth stimulant making the plant more
nutritious for spider mites so in that
situation
you know you can have a healthy plant
and just by putting a pesticide on it
you can create a spider mite problem
I hadn't heard that that's really
interesting it's super interesting
because initially
um the research
um they thought what was happening in
the landscape was a metaclobin was
killing off the beneficials and that's
why the spider mites were exploding but
one of the guys involved with it might
grew up at the University of Maryland he
is an amazing uh landscape research
entomologist uh he and his wife are
Paula shoes bear like a Powerhouse of of
nerdum I love them to death they're
great people
um but Mike got involved and he helped
figure out that no it's not that it's
killing off the beneficials and and they
actually I've seen
images where plants treated with
metacloper the leaves are actually
bigger than non-treated plants in a
controlled study because again it's it's
acting as a plant growth stimulant so
there's I mean there's so many things
going on that we and we want a simple
answer and we want to simplify
everything
um and you can't because no matter what
you do there's going to be a consequence
to what you do but what we try to do is
have minimal impact reduce our pest risk
and you know follow science as as what
we know and at the same time try to be
environmental I mean that's my goal
yeah so that made me lead back to the
the bricks thing maybe that's a
simplified explanation but maybe there's
something that some that people are
doing in their ways of supposedly
attaining higher sugar levels that may
increase pest resistance that we a
mechanism we haven't identity but then
they they should be able to see that
yes that would that you would think it
would be reflected in the in the
research unless those researchers are
not replicating what you know people are
claiming in the field but
so many so many
people that you know everybody thought
and it makes sense that you know you
apply a pesticide that's going to kill
off the beneficials and you have more
pest issues you know we see that quite a
bit with especially like bifenthrin and
things like that so that's where
everybody just assumed that was the
result I mean that was why it was
happening but not till we really get in
there you know it really had nothing to
do with the beneficials in that
situation and I think people
jump to anecdotal conclusions without
having controls and without having
replications because if you're a
commercial production facility it's very
hard to have a a control where hey we're
just not gonna you know treat or do this
or we're going to treat in a different
way and then have replications because
your goal is to produce a product and
get it out the door not do research and
I think sometimes people jump to
conclusions
um which
I will say though
that these anecdotal observations that
Growers do see are very important
because that plants the seed for the
research and then we need to look at
that and be like okay is this what's
happening and that's where the whole
start of the bricks thing years ago
um because a lot of this bricks work is
really older work
um it's not something that was done the
last couple years probably decades ago
um that they did go out and and look at
these
um and you know
get the research from an anecdotal
observation so I'm not discounting
anybody's observations it's very
important to be observant start you know
thinking about well why is this
happening why are we seeing this why is
this plant doing this and try to figure
it out and then and this is kind of what
I do with my observations through the
industry as I travel everywhere I'm in
all kinds of production facilities and
then I'm like okay well we don't
understand this and then I'll go to my
research friends at the University who
they can do the controlled research and
help work with them to
um formulate the the trials that need to
be done
um I'm actually heading to Michigan next
week because I'm on an advisory
committee for
um High tunnel uh production and I'm
going to be working with several
universities on helping steer research
from observations I've seen in the field
of like what research we need to to do
and so that's how this whole process
kind of works and I think sometimes
people make observations and they jump
through the science they jump past the
scientific method and make a claim
so they go straight from hypothesis to
conclusion without
running a controlled trial and I you do
see that and I think it's really hard
not to when you're
in a in a facility or in a functional
grow room because like you said if you
see something and and you get a result
that you like you want to repeat that
result over and over again and just in
your head make an assumption for what's
actually going on and it may not be
accurate so yeah that's a that's a good
point but let's we got way off topic I
didn't even mean to bring that all up
you that's all you attack
it was it was it was something on my
mind when you brought up plant health so
let's get back to it though what other
uh what other research was shared at the
conference well the other thing that
took me by surprise again normally you
know I'm when they're talking about
disease stuff I'm off doodling and you
know not paying attention
um but again zamir stuff is just so
interesting
um because past the hopsulating viroid
onto viruses
um is the viruses they're finding which
um tobacco mosaic virus which
um I've known to have been in cannabis
but I was actually kind of surprised
that when I mentioned this to a group of
cannabis Growers they didn't think that
tobacco I mean that cannabis got tobacco
mosaic virus
um and
I guess there's still a myth out there
circulating that it doesn't really get
it but again over sampling over like 2
000 plants they found 53 samples with
tobacco mosaic virus the thing that I
was surprised about was I did not know
that cannabis could get tobacco streak
virus and they actually had 56 samples
of tobacco streak virus which was
um
surprising to me because again I I
honestly didn't know too much about
tobacco's streak virus so you know
immediately to the internet to go learn
and read about it
um at lower levels they did found a
rabbit's mosaic virus
um they found tomato bushy stunt virus
um cucumber mosaic virus and very low
low amounts of like um Alfalfa mosaic
virus so overall looking at all their
samples and everything
um that it basically kind of came back
to out of all their samples about seven
percent of the plants they tested
carried a virus not a viroid but a virus
of some kind so the viruses are out
there
um and you know some of them can be test
for
um with a Lysa test kits that you know
you can get from companies like idea
um which you know most my ornamental and
vegetable Growers keep those uh test
kits in-house so they're always
available in case they need to test
right then
um but it is something that can be
causing some problems that you may be
mistaking for nutritional or other
issues so the viruses
um are out there so just uh to to don't
discount those
um on there and just you know with zamir
too
um and I can I don't know if I send it
to you not he actually put out a really
good publication
um with the disease stuff for cannabis
if you don't have it I'll send you a
link and then you can link it out or
attach it however you do your internet
magic
um but um I highly recommend if you ever
have a chance to hear zamir speak he um
he does an amazing uh job presenting
okay I'll have to try and get him on the
podcast
I know somebody that knows him that
could probably get him on the podcast
for you
I you are my main source of podcast
guests thank you
um that's really interesting I think the
the tobacco mosais virus stuff sort of
came from no one actually having an
actual test it was all speculation
um it was kind of like like you said
that Growers making observations and
then we finally got in a laboratory and
now you've seen tests that actually show
that it is showing up in cannabis
because I for the longest time didn't
think it was an actual
cannabis disease because no one ever
actually had a test to support their
claim around it but
um it makes me wonder when you say all
the viruses I wonder how many times
people have thrown out a
potential promising cultivar because it
underperformed and maybe it wasn't even
the the cultivar it was the virus
sometimes viruses can improve
plants too so
yeah yeah I just wonder how that's
affected our yeah genetic choices by
breeders and things like that so yeah
it's interesting
um
yeah we might have to do a show on
viruses now that we're talking about
yeah I'm not doing that I've given you
my my virus knowledge of limited again I
mean this is really outside of my
comfort zone because
I like to stick with my bugs but I find
it very interesting and obviously there
is a correlation with things that do get
vectored
um by insects and things like that
um because can you touch on those like
what are the main diseases
that you would see vectored by in
cannabis by the virus West Coast only
East Coast people you guys have died
Dodge bullet
West Coast guys if you're not familiar
with beat top curly virus and it's
Vector you
um
you really need to uh be aware of it
there was talk after talk after talk in
fact some of them that talked about
um how it has messed up their field
trial research
um one of my friends a researcher out in
California she got it in her hemp trial
plans and it's it's vectored by the beat
Leaf Hopper
um
and it's all up and down the West Coast
what I I think one of the more
interesting things I found out about
this is some of the researchers
commented when they tried to rear the
beat Leaf Hopper just on hemp they
couldn't what it sounds like is
happening because this is actually
um
a a an insect that feeds on multiple
plants and it's picking up
um the virus as it's feeding out in the
environment it hops onto a hemp plant
you know sticks its mouth part in
because they have a piercing sucking
mouth part feeds a bit transmits and
like yeah no and then leaves the plant
and now you're infected and so it's not
like hemp is its primary hose it just
kind of I don't want to say it's
accidentally getting it but it's kind of
just it's it's it's feeding and getting
off and it and it's spreading it now in
other crops how they manage this is they
get rid of the weeds back to the problem
with outdoor hemp there are no
herbicides and you know if you're
growing 20 plants sure you can hand weed
when you're getting into 500 acres of
hemp you're not hand weeding
um and and now you've got the Weeds now
you've got weeds taking over your plants
and now you've got weeds that can have
the virus and host your vector and it's
just all downhill from there so it's
it's a it's a multi-pronged issue but
the the key to management
seems to be
um is uh you know managing the weeds in
the area that have it on it
so is there anything we can do for leaf
Hoppers because I cannot stand those
little buggers they drive me nuts
um do we have any control options you
mentioned weed removal but like in my
home Garden
they were a terror this last season
well then I would get into which ones
were they and what kind of damage were
they actually doing kind of thing
um I mean I hate to say
natural pyrethrins
um
but you run the risk of
you know kind of disrupting any bio
program you have out there uh this is
where crop covers can also be used it's
same methods we used for like flea
Beetle management
and where you put floating row covers
over and things like that to to exclude
them but
as far as biological or softer products
with the softer products it's going to
be natural pyrethrins and soaps and they
don't persist so you're going to have to
be continually treating for them
well they fly away so quickly too I mean
to hit them with the adults challenging
the adults because immatures don't have
wings
okay I guess I need to go back and even
look what an immature looks like I
always just noticed the adults yeah like
I'll shake my sunflowers and they'll
just it'll be like a cloud sometimes
they're not causing any problems it it
just
are they a problem or not and and in the
case
um hemp for Western United States
especially in the warmer areas
um yes it's an issue but I mean I've got
tons of leaf Hoppers here on my property
I can go photograph them every day and
they are of no economic importance to
they don't do damage to any of my plants
here
anything else
it's the only one you guys get hey
we were just talking about ticks the
other day on the phone so uh don't get
me started on uh issues with the east
coast and and disasters and disease so
um
getting back to it though are there any
other
before we move on from Leaf Hoppers do
they Vector anything else besides that
virus not that I know of at this time
but again as time goes on and these
researchers are doing more their surveys
we'll find more but that's really the
only one right now
um I think that is you know
of what I'd consider major economic
importance
okay so what about spider mites Rood
aphids time brusset broad all broads all
these other more common uh cannabis
pests are those vectoring any pathogens
or other diseases potentially well we
know
functor um
and The larva feeds in the soil they
pick up the pathogens in their gut and
then when they're adults and they fly
around and poop they deposit on Plants I
mean that's well known well studied and
that's why it's so important to manage
your fungus gnats
um but I don't know in cannabis of
anything any of the mites are vectoring
um you know white flies convector virus
but so far nothing in hemp or cannabis
um I think really that's you know most
the other viruses are more mechanical in
nature of of being vectored
um so we're spreading it most likely
with our clothes our scissors our hands
yeah things like that our our watering
all of those things okay can you talk
again about you mentioned natural
pyrethrins can you talk a little bit
about pyrethrins the pros and cons
around them because I still hear some
some questions I I've chosen not to use
them
um in my garden
but people get this idea that because a
pesticide is natural in this case I
think from the chrysanthemum or this
idea of planting uh African
chrysanthemums they'll get pest
resistance can you just kind of talk a
little bit about all of that okay so
there's pyrethrins as you said and those
are derived from a chrysanthemum and
there's pyrethroids so you have to be
very careful when you re read your
labels pyrethrins are more expensive
because they're a natural they're
naturally extracted out of the plants
pyrethroids are what has been
synthesized in a lab it's a synthetic
version of it where they can make it
very inexpensively
the pyrees roid the synthetic is much
more stable
when that is sprayed on a crop uh we
cannot reintroduce beneficials in there
for typically two months because of the
Persistence of that on the plant at
least eight weeks is what we have to
wait natural pyrethrins
um that are you know in like pyganic
those are not nearly as stable uh those
tend to break down and this it can be
very variable depending on overhead
irrigation or drip irrigation are you in
Maine are you in Florida you know UV
heat there's a lot of variables but I
like to at least wait a week maybe 10
days but it can again depend on which
beneficial you're using before you get
back in
um
indoors under artificial lighting with
no overhead irrigation they can persist
much longer
um than that
um they are broad spectrum the problem
is since they are one of our earlier
pesticides pyrethrins and then again we
developed the pyrethroids have been used
so heavily there's a lot of resistance
issues in the sense that they may not
even work on your target pass because
the pest has had so much exposure to
them
um that they possibly have developed
resistance so it can be sometimes a
little bit of a crap shoot whether the
product's going to work or not also
they're very non-selective
um it's going to kill your beneficials
just as much as pests if you know
they're all susceptible and again it's
it's not selective and this is what
makes
you know my job challenging because you
know I want to be environmental I do I
mean that's why I do my job is to reduce
PES use but you know when we start
looking at what I call some of these new
designer pesticides
um I think Sultan mitocide is a really
good example from BASF again cannabis
Growers can't use it but ornamental
Growers can
um strawberry vegetables though they can
so here you have a strawberry plant and
let's say you've got two spot spider
mites you can come in and spray it with
Sultan and it is only going to kill I
think it's five or six spider mite
species are on the label and that's it
it doesn't do anything for broad mites
it doesn't do anything for russets it
doesn't do anything to any other insects
or anything it doesn't hurt the
Predators and it it's dialed in just for
those handful of mites so we can spray
that
and then use our beneficials in
conjunction with it flip to the flip
side you know I'm going to be organic
I'm going to be natural and you come in
and so we're going to spray a natural
pyrethrin like pyganic that's fine
it kills everything it's blown out your
beneficials it may or may not even kill
your spider mites and actually
pyrethrins pyrethroids are known for
actually causing spider mite flares
which is a whole nother discussion so
you could actually make your your issue
worth but you're being organic and in
theory being better for the planet but
now you're gonna have to retreat again
and Retreat again so it's really hard
sometimes because these new designer
products are so targeted to just kill a
few different insects and not be broad
spectrum Killers where a lot of the more
natural products
are very broad spectrum in their nature
in killing so it's it's a it's a tough
you know
walking this road sometimes on making
recommendations for me
um because with these new targeted
products that again they're not going to
be registered for cannabis stuff or
approved for use in different states but
for ornamentals and vegetables but we
can just with pinpoint accuracy go in
it's kind of to me like the difference
of how you know we're doing targeted
chemotherapy today where they can just
put it in one spot where the old days
you would inject it and get it
throughout your entire body and have to
deal with it
um so it it's tough so I mean there can
be a place where natural pyrethrins I
think for home gardeners that just oh we
have a little spot here we want to spray
um and you know for cannabis because
many states do allow it for use but
their consequences to using it
um the fact that it will blow out your
beneficials it it can be iffy on its
persistence indoors
um and it can let definitely last longer
indoors than out
um and it's too broad spectrum for me in
a way
okay
um any issues though
so you mentioned this you know these
more selective options that we have
um
which is which is great uh I don't know
that I necessarily trust all these large
AG companies to have my best interest
from a health perspective in mind
um as well and small and organic
companies do
no I mean we we've already seen that in
the industry you know I always bring up
Guardian might spray because it's such a
great example
um but there's been other companies out
there too that have put out products but
how do we
you know are there any issues first of
all with pyrethrins in terms of human
toxicology or safety if we're going to
be combusting and hailing eating
our product like if I was going to use
this on my vegetables or things like
that
um Let me let me ask you that question
first and then I have a couple others
okay well I'm not a medical doctor and I
don't really study or understand I mean
that's not my specialty
um but the fact that it does break down
in UV sunlight outside relatively
quickly compared to other compounds
um and it can be washed off plants it's
not systemic
um that that is something right there so
if you're going to spray it on your
strawberries since we're talking about
strawberries you can just wash it off
um if you're concerned about that also
you know the label is the law and if you
know you have your REI and this is
what's really frustrating so if you're a
commercial grower you have Reis and then
you also have post Harvest intervals so
REI is you can spray it and then how
long before you can go back into that
area to work for your safety and then
post Harvest is okay you spray it and
how long before you can Harvest your uh
your goods none of that information is
available on homeowner pesticides Only
commercial pesticides even though
oftentimes it's the same active
ingredient so a homeowner doesn't have
as much access or cannabis Growers that
are buying homeowner products they don't
have as much access to as much
information on safety as commercial
Growers do
sure because the regulation is
just not as strict and then the same
thing around is it's 25 B right that's
the 25 bees are the exempt from EPA
registration
yes because you will see company I mean
we were both just at MJ bizcon for
example you'll go to a Convention Show
or you'll see you'll look online you'll
see this product that claims that it's
you know all safe ingredients are all
natural and that basically just means
it's most likely registering as a 25 B
product
where they don't fall under that EPA
registration there's just some marketing
terms around there that can make it
confusing I think for Growers to really
understand
what's going on so can you talk a little
about 25b and why you tend to gravitate
away from those products look at them
all
don't get me wrong I will
not product away from look at it because
I'm still hoping
some um potential but basically
um the EPA decided that there is a group
of food grade inputs basically that if
you want to make a pesticide out of them
you're not going to kill yourself in the
process and so they are allowing you to
companies to scoot around EPA
registration
um which EPA registration in the United
States is about I think we're at like 10
years to get a product to Market about
10 million dollars because you've got to
prove bee Safety Human safety you know
all these different you know tests they
have to do
um
where the 25b basically I mean if I
wanted to I could go to my kitchen take
my 25 b list which you know has you know
like soybean oil I think corn oils on
there uh rosemary oil and I can make
that into a product and I can call it
bug lady bug killer and then depending
on the state like some states you go to
they want you to register and basically
that's just filling in a paperwork
saying you're going to sell it here it's
a super easy process and basically I can
make any claims in theory that I want I
can say it's safer beneficials only
kills pests you know and all these
different claims but the EPA doesn't
care about efficacy they don't care
about phytotoxicity they don't care
about any of that stuff as long as
you're not going to kill yourself or
totally destroy the environment they
just kind of like go go do what you want
and that's where there's been this whole
crop a product spring up that don't have
the level of testing
that most pesticides do
um which is
you know challenging because people can
say whatever they want basically and
they're getting away with it for right
now
and you've done some tests with Growers
actually on a few products and we won't
obviously name the names of those
products here but you found not only
were a lot of these products more
expensive but you've noticed
the phytotoxicity issues not actual
control I mean it might knock back a
little bit some of the insect
populations but you'd see a Resurgence I
mean you've we've talked about this
before off air yeah quite a bit yeah and
I'm not throwing again all these
products out with the bath water in fact
we're testing 225b products at one of my
facilities ornamental facilities right
now we're actually spraying them on full
color poinsettias
um because full color poinsettias are
super super sensitive I mean that's kind
of like you know the skin of a redhead
it's the best way to put it and so we
are testing them not only for
phytotoxicity but we're also testing for
efficacy to see if these products
potentially could be used
um the reason I'm super interested in
the 25b is of finding one
um is because we don't have a re-entry
interval which can be very challenging
for some of my Greenhouse facilities
that run three shifts a day there's no
shutdown time to spray pesticides and
also for dipping cuttings coming in
because right now I mean the most famous
research study was done with stuff oil X
up in Canada dipping cuttings showing
how amazing it works
um no phytotoxicity I mean it it's one
of the best things you can do but in the
United States dipping is not on the
label yet it's been at the EPA for years
we've been waiting for it so it's coming
but right now legally my Growers cannot
take their cuttings dip them in stuff
oil and root them even though that is
one of the best way to stop you know
like Hamp russet Mite and two spots
spider mites and Broad mites from even
getting started the 25 bees you don't
have the the restrictions of an EPA
label so we can just let's try dipping
let's try you know drenching oh let's we
can try all these different things and
it's not illegal because they don't have
restrictive labels
so
um we are testing a couple products
currently
um and I have high hopes for these
um because of the amount of research
these companies have put into these
products
um and they're they're not just somebody
making it at their house and you know
spelling the insects wrong on the labels
oh my God like six years ago I was at
um oh which trade show was it it was in
I think it was I almost said Comic-Con
that's the wrong wrong show wrong
completely at uh
canacon and like I was looking at some
of these 25b products and they didn't
even have the pests spelled right on the
packaging and I'm like ah how can I take
this product seriously when you can't
even spell the name right on your
product it's not like it was a typo in
an email you sent me it's on the printed
label of the product and when I really
would start talking to these guys in
these 25 B products they bailed on the
conversation and don't want to talk to
me because I'm asking the tough
questions
um because most of these uh 25b products
are non-selective
um they generally are going to kill the
pests just as equally as beneficials so
you do have to be cautious with that and
again you said the price point I mean I
was calculating some of the prices and
you know for for sixty dollars of stuff
oil if for some of these 25 bees it's
almost 400 for the same amount of
product
um it's it's it's crazy
um Canada does not allow this to happen
Canada doesn't have this exemption list
also in Canada if you want to register a
product in Canada you have to prove at
least 80 percent efficacy to get the
product labeled up there
[Music]
all right
that was part one we'll pick up our
conversation next time on the podcast
that was Suzanne Wainwright Evans and
you were listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram and don't forget at kiss
Organics we have a wider range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments beneficial insects
sticky cards soil testing analysis and
Consulting I also recently added a
patreon for folks interested in
supporting the podcast directly and
lastly you can sign up for our
newsletter on our website homepage to
stay up to date on the latest research
and information thanks for listening
foreign