[Music]
thank you
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
my guest this week is Steve Cantwell
Steve is a former mixed martial artist
and entrepreneur known for his time in
the UFC and his involvement with green
life Productions Steve was born in Long
Beach California and he began training
in martial arts at a young age and
developed a passion for Combat Sports in
2005 Cantwell made his professional MMA
debut and quickly gained attention for
his aggressive fighting style and
well-rounded skills he amassed an
impressive record in Regional promotions
which led to assigning with the UFC in
2008.
in recent years Cantwell has focused his
entrepreneurial Endeavors particularly
in the Cannabis industry he founded
Green Life Productions in 2014 a
prominent Las vegas-based cannabis
cultivation company glp is known for its
organic and sustainable approach to
cannabis cultivation producing high
quality cannabis
cantwell's involvement with glp has
allowed him to combine his passion for
entrepreneurship with his interest in
health and wellness his contributions to
the company reflect his ongoing
dedication to promoting sustainable and
responsible practices within the
Cannabis industry now on to the show
all right well let's uh let's talk cover
crops you brought him up
um you're a big proponent there's very
few commercial facilities that I see
successfully running cover crops indoors
and showing it online
um I have a lot of guys I've worked with
that have tried it and failed
um
I'm not a huge proponent of cover crops
indoors not because I don't think they
have some benefits but for me the cons
outweigh the pros but let's talk about
what those pros and cons are and why it
works so well for you and your facility
so I'll let you start yeah um first off
uh if you plan on using cover crops
listen to everything Tad says uh because
if you don't you're gonna make him right
okay because everything he says has a p
has a point he's not he's not making
stuff up it's not it's a very um you
walk a thin line when rubbing cover
crops and doors and cover crops in
general I'm going plants in general
um so I think there's definitely some
people who kind of overdo it they have
too much fun with it and they create
more work and responsibility than it is
intended uh so like we've run a very
basic cover crop um and I do mix it up
from time to time based off of what
we're facing both indoors and Outdoors
um but for the most part I see the
benefit of it uh it's against it's not a
perfect
um process
um but you know nothing in farming is
perfect uh the benefits that we find
from it and I feel like it creates a
shelter this living mulch crisis shelter
over my soil that keeps my soil
organisms where they're supposed to be
in the soil and keep things from just
blowing up all over my plants I really
do that's a huge component in the cover
crop obviously
um we spend a lot of money on light you
know so in early in days my cannabis
plants aren't catching all that light if
I let it hit that soil I'm just wasting
energy so I like the idea of you know
cover crops and catching that light and
photosynthesizing and turning into
energy that my soil and plants can use
further at a further date
um so I think a little bit efficiency
there is a juice worth the squeeze I
don't know
um but uh
for the most part is it's just one thing
I use I've used a part of my IPM program
so I'll plan specific cover crops to
attract pests I'll plant cover crops to
a Repel pest like we had a rat issue
real bad one time you're the rat or like
two years ago
um yeah the year they're bad and it hit
this whole town hardcore uh and got some
rats and I'm starting to noticing some
um um Predator packs would get destroyed
um we get eaten
um so we quickly started doing some
research and in my mind the way it works
what's the natural predator for cat for
a rats so we got a cat and put it to the
cat next door
um got some uh in our warehouse and then
uh we probably mince in our bed so I I
blew out my whole beds with mints
um and the Rats never came back uh never
seen after men's took over our beds
we've never seen a single rat in this
facility
um but then I let the mint get too far
um didn't cool them in time and that
shit's super invasive uh and you had to
pull a bunch of mint out so now I had to
learn how to better manage that mint it
was good for one thing but the double-ed
sword it turned around and it kind of
bit me in the butt on the other side so
um if you are going to use a can a cover
crops I recommend
picking with like one basic variety with
like a dicondra start with that that's
your blanket cover crop it doesn't
really serve a whole lot of purposes
other than just covering the soil all
right and then I started to add other
little things have a reason for it uh
and then have a place for it like you
can't judge a face by how well it climb
the tree
um because you have it in the wrong
place put it in the water then see how
well it swims then make your judgment
you know um so I feel like if you have a
purpose for these cover crop or these
companion plants and you put them in the
right place
um then they can add value to the system
but if you're just going in there and
throwing seeds doing the little salt
dusting uh and just having this
beautiful Lush cover crops and flowers
everywhere yeah it looks good for IG
don't get me wrong some of my most high
tracks and pictures are ones of miracles
in it
um but in the day you're you're creating
more work than you want the whole idea
of creating these systems is to create
systems that manage themselves like
that's why I love worms because if I
were to pay somebody to do a worms job
they wouldn't do it as good and costs a
whole lot more money
um so finding these systems that are
easy to manage that make life easier not
harder um it's a fine line um and we
walk it every single day
yeah and some of the other benefits that
you you I don't know if you touched on
were what sort of water management
um it's going to keep that uh initial
level of the soil the first couple
inches a lot a lot more moist and by
keeping active plants in there and Roots
you're gonna you're probably getting
better nutrient cycling in that soil
before the cannabis plant really has a
chance to take off
um so those are some more
yeah Pros pros of cover crops I would
say I look at it as like diversity thing
if you want more diversity diversity is
good
um it helps to have more diverse cover
crop or more diverse plants in the
system that doesn't attract and grow
different you know microbial communities
so I I try to have you know as many as I
can afford to take care of uh plants in
the system like right now we're gearing
up to to do our Marigold runs again to
get some flowering plants in the rooms
again in springtime every year I cut
back and I just run at that Conjuring
wood chips minimize any potential risk
from the outside and then anything I do
with more of a trap pant so it's a trap
plant so I'll put them in the Trap plant
in the corner of the room
um for my cover crop or for my companion
plant that that cycle
um but yeah it's uh I think as long as
you're mulching I I'm just proponent of
mulching uh I think we're okay whether
it's living mulch or or you know brown
mulch whatever the case may be um I'm
just a huge proponent for covering your
soil in general
um but yeah obviously I'm a cover crop
guy and to be clear the first time I saw
cover cops was uh my buddy Brad Thurman
showed me Matt Davenport's Instagram
like eight years ago and uh he has some
clovers in the bottom of his pots and I
thought it was the stupidest thing I've
ever seen and I'll never forget this
lazy dudes not even pulling weeds like
this is so lazy it's stealing nutrients
like all these things went off and here
I am eight years later kind of known for
it so it's kind of funny
that is funny I see the first time I
thought I saw it I was like oh that's so
cool what a great idea
um and then I kind of backed off and
changed my mind over time so it's we've
went opposite directions
um well I think you covered the reasons
folks would choose to use cover crops
really well
um
I want to give my thoughts but before I
do uh what what cover crops will you not
use you mentioned some that you really
like but what would you just never use
as a cover crop besides mint
would not I use mint um I just I'll just
make sure I call it at the end of every
cycle I won't let it grow so wild
um so the demand I still think mint has
a value in the system especially if
you're an area where there's rats or
things like that it could definitely
help out um just don't let it grow wild
you definitely want to chop and drop it
pull it back hold it as much as possible
um one cover crop that I won't use
indoors all right yeah we'll use this
out I'm about to use it Outdoors don't
use it indoors ever again
um it's Clover uh I think it's too much
risk versus reward I think there's a lot
easier ways to get nitrogen back into
the system
um than attracting pests and disease
like uh like Clover does anytime I've
ever had past outbreak
um it fed off the Clover heavily
um so we eventually called all the
Clover from all of our soils
um placed here with dichondra nothing
really likes psychonja I mean May
Ling Grande conjure a little bit but
nothing's going out of their way for
decondra
um so that's kind of been like the
ground cover that we we choose to use um
Clover is done though
um
anything I wouldn't use oh crawling
stuff uh anything that's going to crawl
to plants
um obviously like it's when you're
growing 500 plants you can't afford to
be you know pulling you know beanstalks
and and all these little vets and all
these little crazy things out of your
cannabis canopy so use things that are
definitely low laying cover crops for
sure
um
other than that I mean again time and
place for everything
and I will say like
I think you brought up another good
point and that is that you know use your
cover crop with a purpose
um all cover crops have different
purposes whether that's to break up the
soil better
um or to add nitrogen or to create more
organic matter you're going to grow a
different cover crop for that there's no
perfect cover crop and a lot of people
will run like multi multi-species cover
crops outdoors and I love cover crops
outdoors I think they make a ton of
sense the reasons and all this reasons
why I don't like cover crops indoors so
much and then you know Growers can make
their own decisions based on their own
facility and I don't just because
someone used cover crops I don't think
they're a bad grower that they're making
a bad decision I just think people need
to be educated on why they do what they
do so for me with cover crops it's it's
another crop that you have to manage and
in a commercial facility that can be
problematic because you already have
your hands full a lot of times managing
your cannabis plant your cash crop
that's what's bringing in your revenue
and you're in business in addition to
that
uh I really like to mix my nutrients
into the soil to get it back into the
rhizosphere as fast as possible because
we're cropping five Cycles uh a year
we're going a little faster
um than than what you're doing at Green
life and so
um we want to get those nutrients right
into the rhizosphere where the plant can
happen and I like a little bit of
disturbance in my soil you mentioned
this whole idea of of cannabis being a
little more bacterial I don't have a
problem with a little bit of soil
disturbance I'm not tilling my beds keep
in mind you know we're not using a
mechanical tiller we're just digging in
some nutrients and I think that's a very
different process that people don't
consider when they talk about you know
tilling versus no-till we're not tilling
indoors I think that cannabis
uh agriculture in general is artificial
we're selecting for a crop here so the
diversity that we have in you know a
given indoor space is not or even
Outdoors is not going to be anywhere
near the diversity that we see in a
healthy forest ecosystem or a prairie
land or something like that so
um I I like to pull what practices we
can from nature I think Mother Nature is
amazing and we want to use those
practices but we want to use them
strategically I'm not creating flood
events you know or doing you know it's
blasting my plants with wind because a
tornado may occur in nature you know
these sorts of things so I just want to
be aware that like what we're doing is
artificial
um and we're doing it in the sense of
trying to create the best yields and the
best uh plants that we can not just
because of the business because we're
but also because we're growing this
plant because we love it and you know
it's medicine for a lot of people and
then the last point that I have around
cover crops for me is
we're growing this indoors in controlled
environment agriculture we can control
the environment so that's one more
variable that we have to add to this and
there's already so many variables in
cultivation
um
I don't like the risk of the pest
pressures that it may bring in you know
you mentioned Clover crops my my brain
or cover crops with Clover my brain
immediately goes to thrips
um like I I don't like the risk of
having that and then
um oh I thought of one other point so
last thing is hop late and viroid
I like to now pull Roots because we know
that hop latent is uh in higher viroid
levels are in the root system than in
the leaf tissue and we can test for that
better by testing Roots so I want to
pull the roots to lower the viral load
in my soil because at the end of the day
I'm not ready to throw this whole living
soil methodology out just because we
have
you know hop late and viroid now in our
in in most facilities and it's such a
problem in our industry so
all right what are your thoughts all
right well first we jump to the The Hop
Layton thing before I wasn't ready for
that one uh let's back up a little bit
though so I can tackle that one too
though um to your point though yeah if
you're trying to use cover crops the
whole idea is like you said we have a
whole lot to manage we're trying to
manage a cash crop you have to be in
order to be your agenda if you have to
be sustainable
um and run a good business so there is a
fine line like I said you have to walk
um in my situation I'm literally setting
up the easiest self-managing cover
cropping systems a possible like when I
do put a banker plant or a trap plant
I'm not planting it throughout my whole
facility I'm finding in very specific
areas
um like at the end the corners of our
beds while playing like marigolds so if
you look at old GOP photos start to look
at where some of our marigolds are some
of our more campaign not cover crops
where companion plants are placed um
they're then placed in a high traffic
area where it's easy for us to manage
them where it's easy for us to see if
there's a problem or not
um so we try to minimize um the workload
at 100 because
um there's a lot going on especially
with the the whole regulated side of
things things to manage not just the
whole health of the cash cop we have all
these crazy things going on so you
definitely want to simplify take the
best of what we could what we can learn
from nature and apply it
um I go a little bit further with it
than some do no doubt uh but it's it's
not to say that uh I'm just going
willy-nilly I'm not just getting lucky
um everything that we do has a sop
designed around it
um and we manage these things very very
thoroughly and precisely I see a lot of
people doing things that I was doing
eight years ago but just going crazy
with their cover crops and like I'm
stoked for them they're having fun
they're learning or at least I hope
they're learning and they're paying
attention
um but I expect to see you know the
those people in years to come sharpen
their sticks a little bit and minimize
some of those potential risks like you
talked about
um I can't remember some of the other
points now because I'm I'm stuck on on
the uh Hop Latin viroid
um part of it now uh but you you I threw
a lot at you all your points are good
though invalidated points
um but yeah I just just I just seem a
little bit differently as far as some of
the solutions to them goes and how to
use them but as far as the the hob Latin
viroid
um
so
when we first opened up um we had a
correct me from wrong but I think back
in the day everybody was referring to
him as dads like I think pipsweed uh was
a dude online and we called them Duds uh
we call them over here at GOP we called
them uh shiners um back to that pure
Sunshine strain
um so uh in in medicinal geonomics
um so back in the day pure Sunshine
um had a hotline real bad
um uh every single time I planted a bed
it would dud out like 50 60 of that bed
would dead out I didn't think it was a
virus because I didn't see it spreading
to other plants so for like two years I
I thought I thought it was like a
mutation I thought that back in the day
it was was it mutation it was a viroid
there was all these topic or all these
conversations going on um and I was on
team mutation based off of what I was
seeing on on my commercial bro uh I
thought it was if it was a virus it
would spread like wildfire throughout
the whole room
um and I just wasn't seeing that
um we eventually pulled the pure
Sunshine because of that we couldn't
grow it no more it was just too much of
a pain in the ass
um
and uh be honest I don't see it anymore
I I used to see the occasional dutting
plant we see the occasional sick plant
um and and and I just don't see it in
the morning and in the living organic
system and I leave roots in the system
and as far as root balls go um yeah you
have a great Point
um but early on we would Harvest our
root balls
um to make room for the next pot and
what we found out that we were doing is
we were harvesting the majority of the
life that we just grew
um the worms the bacteria the fungi
those are all nesting right there
feeding off those exudates so every time
you remove that root ball we just kind
of took two steps back we said one foot
step four or two steps back
um it got to a bad tour our our worms
population our beds was almost none um
just harvesting the root balls over and
over again
um so that's when we started designing
our grid technique where we planted here
one cycle the next cycle we plant right
next to it allowing this root ball to
break down then all the biology do its
thing
um and again uh I I don't have I don't
have dating plants I haven't seen a
dating plant since I got rid of pure
Sunshine now that's not to say that this
virus isn't real I just believe that hey
it's it's always been there I think
certain plants are gonna you know hold
certain viral loads more than others or
they're more susceptible
um but if I had it my way every plant in
my facility
um
what would be I want to say my meal but
would would have a little would be had
to be able to tolerate this virus
um that way I might have to worry about
it because I've seen people that tissue
culture 100 to their propagation method
is through tissue culture because it's
virus uh I feel like
that's a bit Overkill uh I I've
literally walked in some of the most
highest state-of-the-art facilities with
100 teaching culture propagation process
and and sealed rooms this and sealed
rooms that and then they're showing this
whole tissue culture um set up and then
I go to one of their flowering rooms and
it looks like a powdered donut factory
because their facility has powdery milk
there's not their plants
um and things of that nature so I feel
like it
viruses are real they're definitely out
there not to belittle that
um I I think it's a bit of a of a scare
tactic though just from a commercial
perspective I just don't see it as much
as I used to when I got rid of the
strains I contained it or that that that
showed it nowadays I
it's not even really a topic here at GOP
we don't see it no more
I mean there is there is research to
show that certain genetics are going to
not express it as much
um based on the work by Dr punja um my
next podcast it's actually gonna come
out before this one will be all on Hop
late and viroid uh so I learned a lot on
that too
um the dining thing I think is
interesting because uh like from working
closely with my buddy Justin at Mako
farms and he absolutely has it because
we've tested for it there um he finds it
he can keep the plants healthy and not
stressed he doesn't see that expression
of of dating or the viroid itself so
like you I think if we can keep a plant
healthy and reduce stress we're not
going to see that expression of it
because it is a latent viroid and that
helps a lot so coming in with clean
plants even if your bed is
um you know you had plants with roots
that had the viroid
um
you're still able he he crops huge huge
yields and pulls a ton of biomass and I
know you do too so I know it is possible
um
one other reason I like to pull Roots
because you mentioned the worms thing
and the bacterian fungi and I think
that's that's interesting um
one of the reasons I like to pull Roots
is because of heavy metals as well so
lowering viral load removing heavy
metals from the system through through
biomass again I think is important if if
that's an issue for for a lot of
facilities and then for us with the
worms what we see is we see a lot of our
worms coming up on the blue soak tape or
where the irrigation systems are so I
wonder if because of your watering and
um well I guess you're watering the
whole bed because you have cover crops
in there my thought was maybe a lot of
your worm populations are going to be
more concentrated in the root ball
versus what we're seeing and being more
along where the irrigation lines are run
because I haven't noticed a large change
in worm populations based off of
how long but you were probably shaking
the The Roots back into the bed
or the downstairs yeah yeah so so when
we Harvest typically we you know you you
get the plant out and then you shake off
the soil and then you take the you know
so we're not getting all the root hairs
and everything out of the bed it's a
pretty quick
simple process that makes sense uh yeah
ours is a little bit different but real
quick back to the the virus too um it's
all about setting the stage too so I
think if you you know people always ask
oh you you have all these bacteria and
fungi and how are they not how do these
bad ones not take over how do you not
get but try this how do you not get hot
black how do you not get all these
things because I'm not setting the stage
for those things that we try to you know
maintain a healthy aerobic environment
full of diversity
um of beneficial organisms but you know
typically you have to set the stage like
similar to the whole don't judge a fish
by how well it climbs a tree
um if I keep that fish in the water it's
gonna be great you know if I keep that
cat out of the water in the tree it's
gonna do great uh so just setting the
stage for for for whatever it is that
you're trying to do for the proper
outcome I think is key
um so good air circulation good
filtration
um good healthy aerobic soil good good
um good compost all these things good
practices are going to help set the
stage for success uh where if you're
willy-nillian going in there you know
hand watering without a meter
um you're not following the schedule
you're doing all these crazy cool kid
techniques you see on the Instagram
um what are you setting the stage for
you know
yeah and you've brought up your Sops
multiple times
um I did a recent podcast with Cassandra
maffey just talking about Sops I don't
think people give enough credit to how
important Sops are and following them
because
um
that's I think that's what makes uh
separates kind of like a good grower
from a great grower or a bad grower from
a good grower is having Sops and
following them
yeah no it's definitely key um like I
don't grow for the most part I don't
grow cannabis anymore I grow employees
um and and they they follow Sops that I
wrote
um and it's in this clutch that way if
something goes wrong we can look back to
hey what did you do did you follow the
SOP oh you didn't okay well that's the
problem and we can always kind of find
the problem that way and work towards a
solution
um but then also estate Regulators
they're then ask for Sops like when one
state regulars come in and especially
that they've only seen clean sterile
grows and they start seeing all those
crazy cover crops in in in in beneficial
insects heavywear they're going to want
to see Sops that show that you're in
control of these things that you're in
control of these processes
um otherwise it doesn't mean everything
a passing disease and shut you down so
uh Sops are definitely the way to go
um yeah 100 but I hate it I hate writing
them uh my wife is uh is really big on
Sops he just raised her hands shout out
to kuanine uh that's kind of her
strength uh is is the the whole she
takes my craziness and it makes it legal
basically she put basically fits into
regulation
yeah let's give a shout out to your wife
because uh I know she does a lot behind
the scenes I know you're the face of glp
but I know that she's really the heart
of it too and uh I don't think she gets
enough credit for everything she does
She lays well she she stays out of the
Limelight dude but she's definitely
um I basically built her business
basically I built the business for her
to run
awesome awesome all right so uh I feel
like we covered a lot in this podcast
um one thing that we absolutely need to
talk about though before signing off is
um bottomless pots and this Tech this
Tech that you came up with
um I think it's really interesting why
don't you share sort of your your
thought process and then how it's been
working in reality yeah so uh you know
when we first uh started GOP um we were
digging um half gallon gallon pots um
into our soil so we dig out the soil we
took out we didn't go into a bin uh we
put a pot in there that's what we took
out we're then going to the next cycle
um of the edge uh and that was our whole
process for a long time and and then we
just that's when we started harvesting
our worms and things like that by taking
out the old Brews that's when we
designed the root system I'm sorry a
grid pattern to where you plant here one
cycle plant here the next cycle so
you're just constantly switching grids
each cycle
um but we were still digging holes
there's still quite a bit of soil
disturbance I'm trying to stay true to
the whole um no-till uh or no sole
disturbance
um scheme of things uh it just never
kind of felt right uh it just felt like
we're kind of I don't know taking a step
back every time uh and then one day I uh
I had a seed plant and it's a small pot
and I was supposed to transplant it got
busy forgot to transplant it I sat down
on the mother bed never got around to it
it came back like a week later and this
plant it was totally stressed out and
yeah following a week later was just
completely blown up re-greened super
healthy I want to grab it to move it and
it was it was stuck to the bed and and I
was like man this is kind of kind of
like the old rock wool they said the
Little Rock Wall on the big rock wool um
kind of technique and my gears just
started rolling just thinking about all
the labor we can save um if we not to
dig holes and the mess that we wouldn't
have to make if we got to dig holes and
uh so I just took a I think it was 12
pots um I cut the bottoms off plastic
pots set them on a saucer fill them with
soil put some clowns into it I let the
root ball develop at the bottom um so it
kind of held also at the bottom and then
we're just able to Simply pick them up
and then set them on top of the beds not
dig a single Hole uh and then the plants
would just continue growing downward the
original going downward into the beds
um now when we first did this it was all
I was thinking was reducing labor was
the main goal
oh and we achieved that we it turned uh
what took us a day and a half turned
into a half day
um I have two female Growers that run my
entire facility
um it took them a half day to place we
call placing a room
um we don't plant we place
um so anyways we started with a small
bed here and there I'm doing it I I
didn't show it at first because I was
too embarrassed too for a long time I
had to make sure it works because nobody
nobody was doing this at the time you
know I want to put my foot in my mouth
um so I actually did it for about a year
or so
um and then people started seeing
pictures of the of the bed in the corner
we started asking questions what's going
on over there
um and then we did the whole Grassroots
I reached out to Tyler from Grassroots I
had to make a fabric version of the pot
without a bottom on it and those guys
are awesome by the way whatever you need
those guys are willing to do they're
pretty pretty cool and very versatile
um anyways so we ran with the bottomless
pod technique and just kind of designed
the whole system off it and uh what we
kind of learned was yes it's a
drastically save the amount of Labor and
the amount of mess you make the amount
of soil disturbance all those things are
definitely then cut back on it but then
to our surprise is we got faster better
growth rates we managed to reduce the
amount of transplant shock uh the plants
to seem to just take off faster and
healthier so in my system we can't
really shed time off of it but I get 4.3
Cycles a year just to be clear on that
so I get I get uh I get 13 harvests a
year is what I get
um but uh we can't really afford to save
time the way my systems work I have
seasons Set uh and and my Seasons don't
wait for plants my plans don't wait for
the season
um it's just it's A Clockwork I've been
running the same schedule for eight and
a half years now without missing a
single beat
um
uh uh I forgot my I forgot what I was
saying with that
um
yeah my bad where were we at about that
sorry uh no you you covered a lot of it
um I guess what so the originally
started as like a labor saving thing and
then it became an actual like better not
only was it saving labor but it was also
uh yeah why was that giving you better
yields yeah I couldn't save time because
of our schedule but what I did was in
the same amount of time I had allocated
to grow my plants and veg my plants I
was able to grow my plants twice as big
so it didn't save me time in it because
again we're kind of set on a schedule
but it did get more out of the time so
our plans just went to flower much
bigger much healthier and we've seen a
huge increase in yields by doing it over
time
um the only place I would say it might
not work one if you're a home Gardener
and you got a small sale maybe a ceiling
height is an issue
um maybe it's not the best technique for
you but if you're a large-scale
commercial grower you're planting you
know thousands of plants a month and you
have high Bay ceilings I definitely
think it's a technique worth trying uh
try it on one bed first or try it on one
pot first see if you like it I think
you'd be surprised on how easy and how
just simple the whole thing works
yeah it's definitely something I want to
play around with I think it's a really
interesting concept and very like very
ingenious so yeah hats off to you on
that I think it's very cool
um
one question I had is what lessons have
you learned in terms of like
like tips and pointers for people who
want to try it out like uh is there a
certain size pot that you think works
best
um I I don't know any watering
differences
um yeah I mean I would say uh make sure
you clear the soil off you don't want to
be setting it on like uh if you if
you're running a living mulch or any
type of mulch you don't want to set it
on top of your mold testers this doesn't
cause decomposing the root Zone like
rotting and stuff like that you want to
avoid so make sure you clear you get a
nice little access point to the soil
straight into the soil when you set it
down I recommend watering the pots
directly
um at least a couple times a week for
the first like you know two week and a
half two weeks
um give the the the plants time for
their roots to grow into the beds
um so because yeah I think quite enough
capillary reaction to to water up
through those pots from the bed so I'm
going to want to water them directly
once the roots get into the bed you're
fine you can kind of ignore the pots and
just focus on the bit at that point
um other than that yeah it's it's pretty
self-explanatory I do the video on my
Instagram
um that kind of explained it and people
ask me all the time and it looks like I
don't answer but all I do is I tag them
in the original video
um so that I don't have to explain the
whole thing so feel free to ask me
online anytime I'm just gonna go and tag
you in the original video and you can
watch it it's about 10 minutes long and
it gives a whole detailed breakdown on
on what I've learned and not much has
changed
um since I made that video and I don't
think anything's really changed
um since the making of that video
um yeah it's still running it very
strong now uh our state Regulators hated
the idea of bottomless pause and fought
me insanely hard on the idea for
absolutely no reason
um and uh what's that
yeah they actually even call Tyler and
they had all kinds of weird like that
was crazy
um but it's now it's a it's a validated
technique that you can use in Nevada
um that they aren't arguing anymore so
that's kind of cool
that's so they wanted to talk to the
manufacturer of the pots about yeah they
they that's crazy you gotta understand
these Regulators they come in they walk
a thousand grows and they're all you
know sterile
um you know chemical facilities and they
walk into GOP and they're just like what
is this place no way any of this is
legal uh so there's always this huge
learning curve that we have to
um walk them through and this last year
this new Regulators of the CCB in Nevada
have been extremely difficult
um and we've spent a lot of time
educating them on just Organics in
general
um for everybody's sake because a lot of
these regulating bodies are gonna take
the same
um regulations and just kind of repeat
them over and over again until we get to
Federal legalization so if once stays
successful in something then the other
say system repeat it similar to disaster
you need to knit this in the ass before
um Camp becomes pretty legal because
then we get to able to change anything
um
but for the most part uh yeah bottomless
pause for the win for sure
yeah you know it's funny because people
see us online and sort of you know I
guess we have personas or you know we
share what what we do and what we
believe and people think that we're
um
you know we don't agree on a lot of
stuff or that we're like opposed to each
other but in reality like at the end of
the day like we're all trying to promote
regenerative practices sustainable
agriculture organic cultivation we're
all on the same side and uh I love being
able to have these conversations because
one of the things I I struggle with
online and it's really discouraging and
I bet you see this too is like anyone
can leave a comment on your video anyone
can make a comment on social media and
they can be they can be jerks they can
say whatever they want and be critical
and like this is your life this is your
career this is what feeds your family
and you put a lot of your passion into
it and it can be really discouraging
um so like and it's hard to have a civil
conversation you know personal attacks
come into play other things that aren't
related to the topic and I found that
people like yourself that I can have a
conversation with and stay on topic even
if we you know have slight differences
in opinion that level of respect goes a
long way so thank you all right I
appreciate you man there's not too many
people's opinion I appreciate or respect
more than yours that's why I started off
saying this like
if people don't listen to you and and
and consider what you're saying they're
only going to prove you right as far as
no cover crops and things of that nature
you have to listen to everything you say
everything you've ever said whether I
disagree with it or not I had to take
into consideration earlier and it kind
of pushed me to either you know level up
or or even change some things you know
awesome man will you you challenged me
too and uh if people like this podcast
we'll have to follow up with other
topics and other conversations because
uh I think I think it's a lot of fun and
I enjoy the chat so thanks again for
your time uh I got one question for you
before we go because you mentioned
something oh earlier before I get to
other department you can cut this out
later if you want
um we mentioned um uh I saw a video
earlier you're talking about teas and
you had mentioned a manure team
um that people do and how it could have
certain contaminants
um and I just want to be real I just
want to say something some people real
quick I know we don't like talking
regulations and things like that but in
the last two years I've learned some
really important things first of all
food wave community that you all need to
take into consideration
um and there's certain um guidelines in
in the in regulations that we have to
follow that no one is
um so when the state tried to shut me
down one of the things that they quoted
me on was I think it was a they was it
NOP water guideline quality
was it MLP right
so it was an NLP water quality
guidelines um saying you have to have
below a certain amount of like E coli
and this other type of bacteria so in
order for you to do a compost tea you
have to have a uh you have to have a
thermophil or a a validated method of
composting so you have to use like a
thermophilic compost so that that could
be a problem for a lot of knif guys use
their imos and and things like that not
to say that there's an issue with those
techniques but I'm saying if they're not
validated by the USDA or NLP
um you're not going to be able to use
them much longer okay now once you get a
validated method like thermophilic
compost and you end up with a good high
quality compost then you make a tea brew
and you have to make two separate tea
Brews with the same recipe and again
both tested by a third-party lab to show
that they're below a certain amount of
of uh of E coli in a camera where the
other bacteria is until you do that you
cannot legally use a compost tea now
extracts without Brewing you can use
without limitation uh if you're using a
thermosilla compost but teas you have to
get tested by a third party
um just throw that out there guys uh it
sucks I did it
um and it's a yearly thing
is that in the that's in the state of
Nevada then yeah but it's it's actually
it's actually an NLP um type USDA water
guideline thing so it's actually a
national restriction that the state of
Nevada found and just tried to hold me
to we we looked for months before we
even found out how to use Chris Von Hook
from clean Green certified to actually
find the regulation they were speaking
of because they misquoted the number and
just sent us on this Rat Race
um so people just got to realize that uh
like the Dr Lane mingum I kind of hinted
at it earlier
um there's a lot of things she does like
with counting um you know in science and
a lot of these um these Regulators if
you can't count it it's not science it's
Bro Science and you're done
um so that's why a lot of those crazy
things I don't really
sign up for it so much or uh subscribe
to
um they do they do kind of make sense um
under the right you know perspective uh
on the under the the realm of Regulation
I guess uh so just be careful if you're
out there if you're using these validate
techniques you're trying to write Sops
um based off of
um something you did in your home bro uh
just just take a look to look take a
time to look into USDA and I'm not a fan
of USDA um regulations or any
regulations for that matter
um but it's worth looking into before
designing an entire system
um around practices that may not be you
know allowed
yeah I mean there are NLP guidelines
that actually I don't know if they've
tried to apply these to you but um I
think it's 60 days before Harvest you
can't apply a compost tea and that's
just a standard NOP guideline yeah
that's been around for decades
um
uh just to prevent E coli salmonella
contamination on leafy greens and things
like that yeah and I think that's again
it's a compost tea regulation and I
think that's also if you're using manure
in your compost or or animal byproducts
I think is when that one comes into play
if I'm not mistaken the exact uh
verbiage in that one um but yeah no
there's a hundred percent little little
little tricks like that you have to be
aware of
um again like if this is a cash crop so
people it's becoming more and more
popular in in it More Money More
Problems for the organic grower I'll
tell you that for sure so it just helps
to be aware of these things
um for sure I recommend people getting
online just kind of looking at UST
regulations and kind of applying that to
their facility as much as possible just
for the long-term success of their
facility of their business it's
definitely worth looking at
yeah I think the regulatory side is
important I think the the actual risk
associated with compost tees is
significantly lower
um than is stated by a lot of people and
that's you know this idea that people
need to move to a compost extract
um from a regulatory reason I I think
that can make a lot of sense but aerated
compost D's in general have so much more
microbial activity in nutrient cycling
that I think they have a lot of benefit
when you use the right compost that's
really the key to it and you know a
brewer that's going to create the
optimal you know dissolved oxygen levels
that you need but
um yeah my dad did testing with Elaine
you know decades ago where they
intentionally introduced E coli and it
was you know the kiss Brewer that they
used and found that the E coli did
couldn't survive in in some of these
highly aerobic conditions so
uh you know I'm like I said I think I
think the risk is overstated but it's
absolutely there
um a lot of the failures I hear for
people failing for E coli in agriculture
were actually from like having cows
Upstream that were crapping in the water
and then that irrigation water gets
pumped onto the leaves of the plants and
then and then the plants get you know
the lettuce and stuff gets hit so
yeah manures are definitely something
that that people need to be careful with
and yeah I think there's probably do
some more posts on on compost tea
because uh yeah so I mean it's an
interesting topic and I love compost
teas I think less is more as far as
their food source I think it's a lot of
problem people have is they over feed
their compost teas it goes anaerobic
before they can get back and then now
they're just kind of watering you know
some ciliate poop soup kind of thing
going on
um I think that's the main thing is like
on Commercial scale extract teas are
harder to mess up uh where I could brew
a bad team have to double down the drain
um so I my my garden my Growers are all
certified on the Elaine system so they
know how to use a microscope and Tech
teas
um as far as like human pathogens we've
never had an issue with human pathogens
and teas it's always just been with the
wrong organisms as far as like ciliates
uh that have been the the the main game
changer for a good team versus a bad tea
um just it's not very efficient nutrient
cyclers uh in the in the long run
um but yeah it's compost tea for for
foliers extracts for drenches that's
kind of our our routine
yeah and I don't think people realize
just how much fertility they're bringing
in sometimes with these compost teas
um they're probably getting nitrates uh
as well as other minerals and so we've
seen people that are like we didn't do
anything this cycle but compost teas and
their soil tests show an increase in
fertility at the end of the cycle
sometimes with nitrogen being like way
too high so it is something that I want
to mention for folks that are
considering you know some of these knf
options some of the the compost teas
whether it's an extract or an aerated
compost tea you are bringing in
nutrients and those can impact your
plant For Better or For Worse a lot of
times it's for the better but it's
something to be aware of yeah 100 same
thing with the cover crops and you know
if you're chopping and dropping your
cover crops you know seven weeks in the
flour
um you then create some microbial
explosion in your soil some nutrient
cycling is going to take place um it
might be counter unproductive to what
you're trying to achieve as far as
growing a good taste in plants so uh
yeah 100
yeah well I've heard I haven't I've
never tried uh glp flour but everyone
I've talked to that has tried it says
that it is it's top shelf and it's great
stuff so uh yeah hats off to you and
your crew out there well I appreciate
you appreciate your time today uh
don't hesitate to reach out man if you
have any questions I always appreciate
um what you got to say man for sure
all right awesome thanks man all right
[Music]
that was Steve Cantwell and you're
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Tad
Hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on Instagram we also have a
patreon where you can get Insider access
to the team at kiss Organics through
Hangouts as well as earn some cool perks
and benefits for supporting the podcast
lastly you can sign up for our
newsletter on our website homepage to
stay up to date on the latest research
and information thanks for listening
foreign