[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
i thought it would be good to do another
podcast from the growers perspective and
some of the successes and challenges
associated with running a commercial
facility my guest this week is michael
wilson mike is the owner and head
cultivator of mainecraft cannabis a
cannabis cultivation company licensed
under maine's medical cannabis program
mainecraft cannabis grows organically in
living soil beds and i met mike when he
reached out in 2018 regarding consulting
and dialing in the program in his
facility we've stayed in touch ever
since sharing ideas and test results as
we continue to learn
before joining the cannabis industry
mike had a career in mechanical
engineering designing industrial
centrifuges and x-ray machines if you
want to learn more you can check out
main craft cannabis at
mainecraftcannabis.com
or on instagram at maine underscore
craft underscore cannabis now on to the
show hey michael thanks for coming on
the show today
thanks for having me dad
absolutely so you started mainecraft
cannabis in
and uh i've known you for i think since
2018 or 2019
but i wanted to talk to you today a
little bit about your sort of the the
methodologies and timeline of your
evolution as a grower um
going to a commercial scale here with
main craft cannabis can you kind of take
me through that a little bit
uh yeah sure so my wife and i started
the business in uh
in the commercial facility right in the
beginning of 2018
um
and
you know kind of from the beginning i
think we were
always wanting to be organic and we were
sort of in um you know smaller pots at
the time and
we were using cloth pots and
you know we ended up kind of like
leaning on bottle nutrients here and
there and you know if if we got the
organic amendments to run right it was
sort of a
threading the needle sort of operation
and you know we were having some issues
really getting the
quality we wanted
um and that's when i kind of came across
your podcast and reached out to you and
that kind of began the relationship and
you know you've really guided me towards
the larger soil volumes and all that
which i had my resistance to
um
you know and since then we've sort of
just gone down this journey and things
have really
started clicking pretty well
yeah can you elaborate a little bit on
that
process of sort of where you where you
started in the facility in terms of you
mean you were in these pots
can you talk about how you were growing
and then i you know i mean i can talk a
little about our conversations and where
that started but um
i'd love to hear it from your
perspective
for sure yeah um so we were just you
know
i think we first started we were just
you know mixing our own soil
and you know we weren't really getting
repeatable results at that point and
you know we ended up with a lot of like
week five problems basically we could
you know get through veg pretty well
and then by the time we got to flower a
lot of times we just had
deficiencies popping up and you know we
saw some of that in in veg once in a
while but it was a lot more manageable
um
and
you know
at the time so i was testing all sort of
you know different amendments and stuff
um and then with the mixing because
we're in maine so it's really hard to
mix soil um in the winter at my location
because you can't really do it indoors
where we are um so i had this you know
like okay i'm gonna do a bunch of soil
testing i got a bunch of different soils
and tested them out and um you know
found one that i thought that was really
great we sort of standardized on that
things went pretty well and um you know
their their internal recipes sort of
changed and it really created um a lot
of problems and basically we had way too
much nitrogen is what happened um
and then i think that's probably when i
started reaching out to you i was
listening to your podcast which
i'll interject here i actually really
wanted to say thank you for doing the
podcast because you know you have a lot
of really amazing people come on your
podcast and
i'm really flattered and like
a little beside myself to be on it
because i think that
um most of the people that come on have
really in-depth knowledge on specific
subjects and
kind of my background is is more
somebody who's just you know figured out
the living soil thing in one specific
application so
um
i just really you know thank you for
doing the podcast and i've connected
with a lot of people you've had on which
have been really great resources for me
um
so anyway so i reached out to you and
you know basically everybody i knew like
just whoever would
talk to me at that point like everybody
you know
is having problems you just call people
who might be able to help you um
and that's when you know
i made the decision of like okay i'm
gonna try to learn how to manage my own
soil
and we started moving up to larger pots
and
you know by the time i got to about 20
gallon pot that's when things were i
just noticed the mending is a lot easier
um
you know it's it's the inconsistencies
sort of go away and it's not like
everything was perfect
um but it was
we weren't threading the needle anymore
to get a crop to finish the way we
wanted to
um and that's when you know
we did our first you know test bed um we
it was about a yard of soil that we put
in and we did a test and we did side by
side
um and it was
night and day and i was really nervous
about going to larger to these huge beds
about how to move them around and
if we're going to move around and
it really just made things a lot simpler
and
you know more manageable and more
consistent for us
yeah well i i first off thanks for the
nice words and i appreciate you coming
on the podcast um i think it's important
to offer a grower's experience uh from
time to time and i think your story was
really unique um i do i actually think i
met you when you were still mixing your
own soil because i remember you were top
dressing with a lot of um
different amendments um and you were
using piano at the time and um you were
like trying to go off of what the plant
was doing and then you would add the
amendment
so you were always playing ketchup in
these pots yeah yeah and yeah in the
guano i remember that one specifically
because
um
that was one of our least reliable
amendments it was like you know you can
put the same amount in and that's when i
started really to
um
just notice like okay this is a this is
a product you're buying and it's got
these
numbers on the front of the but it's an
organic product and it's going to break
down and iguano was a lot of times it
was really hot it would just
you know we just overdo it so um yeah i
remember that we definitely talked about
the guano i think he steered me away
from it
yeah yeah and you just i remember you
had a lot of variables going on so
between the small plots and the
the various amendments and then trying
to diagnose the deficiency it can be it
can be really challenging um and i know
we i think i talked to you in the
slightly larger pots i i tried to talk
you into beds and you were like there's
just no way in this facility you were
adamant that it was impossible
um yeah but when you went to the larger
pots the plants got better
um not perfect like you said but i think
that solved some of it and then i
remember um i think i actually may have
mentioned this soil company to you
because i just knowing where you were
um was hoping that that would be a good
solution for you
and then
you you describe what you were seeing
when you when we talked about the
nitrogen thing because i didn't
notice it until i saw the soil test but
you had a buddy come in there that was
really good at looking at plants um yeah
yeah
i had a friend
yep i had a friend who'd
you know
been growing for a real long time and he
basically just casually mentioned this
nitrogen toxicity that i had going on
and i was like i don't know what you're
talking about
um and it was just like really dark
curled leaves especially on you know
ones that don't get as much light
and um you know that sort of brought up
the
the idea of that and then um
you know we got some soil analysis back
and the nitrates were just like through
the roof
um and that actually
you know i hadn't realized it but i
might i wasn't having as much success in
veg i was getting these like
kind of really
leafy bally plants that just weren't
they weren't growing the same and the
root zones weren't doing what they
normally do
um so i think it actually was hurting me
more in veg than i realized um he
noticed it in the flower room so then we
just looked at the soil analysis i
remember i shot it too because i didn't
know anything about looking at a soil
analysis at the time
and then you were the one who who
brought that up
and then
yeah so
at that point i was like okay so
if i buy a product it's just like i
i can't really rely on anything
the quality control of another
organization and that's when i really
made the decision to
really learn how to um
you know manage my soil and i you know i
read like the steve solomon book the
intelligent gardener probably listen to
that podcast like five or six times
um and that's what sort of engaged me in
really trying to be basically the idea
that i was going after with reusing the
soil is one i mean it's the economics
and the sustainability of it but also
it's
if you can manage your own soil you're
in control of your own destiny you're
not kind of hoping that the thing that
you've been buying all along hasn't
changed and it's
in organics that's a that's a big
big thing i mean you know organic
products just aren't as consistent
yeah that's i think that's a really good
point uh i i found
i've heard this story a couple times not
just with soil but with bottle nutrients
too with with companies changing the
formulation and growers being aware of
it and then having issues potentially
but then there can also be mixing issues
with with batches and things like that
too so that's that's absolutely a
legitimate concern right
um now you got into the soil testing you
really dove with both feet into that um
i think your engineering brain kicked in
and
gave you some quantifiable numbers to
allow you to
really look at what was going on
in your room and have some numbers to
support it um
and this is i think a really interesting
aspect of this because you got really
heavy in the soil testing and now you've
kind of
backed away a little bit from that can
you kind of talk a little bit about that
process
yeah for sure the uh the steve solomon
book the intelligent gardener like he
goes through
um when i read that book he basically
goes through how to do all your own
calculations for you know if you're
going to use these amendments how to
break down what the
you know numbers on the bags mean and
be able to
you know do your amendments to hit your
targets
um and uh yeah like the engineering
brain definitely was like okay this is
like i love math like let's do this
whole thing so i got the whole
spreadsheet going and um definitely went
all in on the
you know the math of it all
and then
you know
i wouldn't say quickly but i think over
time i really started to
[Music]
see that the soil analysis results
didn't always make sense
and then through that process i kind of
talked with
um so i've always used logan labs and i
talked with susan in the lab there and
kind of really was trying to understand
like okay so what happens like after i
take a soil
sample and send it to you like
you know because i was trying to
duplicate just you know basic things
like ph and ec if i
before i send it to them and then see
that i'm getting the same result from
there and i'm getting a lot of variance
um just on basically you know
soluble salt just
it was i would i would get numbers that
were orders of magnitude different
um when i tested that same you know
sample that i took and then sent it to
them
and then the um and i just learned more
about how they do their testing and you
know where some of the variances are
and you know the the
sample size was one of the things i
remember susan
telling me about and the fact that like
those soil analysis were never really
meant for
um indoor soilless media they're meant
for field soils which are mostly mineral
soils and you know she's like i can't
even do a um i have to like see your
material it doesn't sift through the
sieve it just clogs it up because of so
much organic matter you know like we
have 25 organic matter which is that
doesn't really exist in most field soils
as far as i know
um
so they can't even really do the test
exactly the same way and then it's such
a small sample
which in again in field soils isn't
going to matter it's just much more
homogeneous but with um you know indoor
soils if you get a clump of perlite or a
clump of whoever knows what like a you
know a little sulfur ball or whatever
you're just going to get more scatter in
your results
so then i started doing even more
testing
which got quite expensive i would do
multiple so i kind of have averages to
look at
and then i just kind of backed away from
that quite a bit and i still do soil
testing every round on every bed
but i'm really looking at more of that
as a
pattern and i can
know what the soil result looked like
from the previous run and when i added
for amendments and then if something
doesn't look right i have a pretty good
idea now so i use them as a guide now
but i don't really react to any one
individual result i ever get anymore um
but i still do quite a bit of the
analysis i just
mix it in with
intuition and in what i'm seeing a lot
more than i used to because
um
if you if you took it with all of like
100 accuracy like every bed every round
would be getting totally different
amendments and that's just not what's
actually going on
yeah so the sample size
it does so a couple of things i want to
highlight um that i've learned not just
from you but from
people like bryant at soul doctor
consulting and bill mckibben over at
logan and talking to their lab because
you were the one that actually brought
to my attention that how small i think
it was like a half a teaspoon or
something that they're using on the m3
test is that right whatever i think it
was two milliliters or something like
that i can't remember now but it was i
remember like asking her like
is that yeah it's not two teaspoons
because i was sending them like a baggie
full of soil like a sandwich bag yeah
and then i'm like that's what's going
into the analysis so if you took 10
different samples from that same bag
you'd get 10 different results and she's
like 100
yeah and then
you know bill and susan both were like
you know really steering towards the
saturated taste
um so now i do both but anyway sorry to
interrupt you no that's great and and
this so just to remind people um i
actually heard this analogy uh in the in
the soil and mineral group through erica
reinheimer recently um a link to an
article that was talking about the
differences between the malik 3 which is
the standard test and the
saturated paste so the the malik 3 is a
acid extraction i think it's a 2.5 ph
acid that they use um so it's a really
strong acid in that it will tell you
everything that's in the soil that's
sort of your savings account but it
doesn't really tell you what's available
right now and they look at that like
that's where the saturated pace comes in
which they were calling sort of your
checking account and
you know for some people that may be a
useful analogy
one other pointer with a saturated paste
is you can send in your own water sample
with logan too and that will give you a
more accurate result as to what's being
released to your plant based off of your
water not the deionized water that they
use as a default if you don't send in
water so
a couple of pointers there i
still lean fairly heavily on the
standard but most agronomists who i
respect and people that i know lean more
towards the saturated pace so i think
that's more my
my lack of education on it
but i can look pretty quickly at a test
and at least at least figure out like
what the most likely limiting factor of
growth is
and that's right what i think is most
useful about these tests um
and and i don't know that you know you
necessarily need to test every bed what
one thing that bryant and i have talked
about offline is that
um when we see a grower that tests every
bed and then they also do a sample where
they take all the beds and mix them
together assuming all the plants were
you know the the treatments across the
beds were standardized and the plants
are all relatively doing what you don't
have like this one problem bed
um
the results end up being within a you
know a standard deviation a range where
uh you don't you know you could save
that money because the tests do get very
expensive like you mentioned so yeah
have you found that that sort of mirrors
what you're you were seeing on your end
too or
yeah yeah very much actually so
um
yeah i shouldn't really say that i test
every bed every run anymore so
um in in the
you know
in my older room the the beds are still
one yard each
and i used to test every bed every round
and now what i do is i do them in groups
of three so there's basically six
um you know volumes of soil that i'm
amending because i do you know i sort of
do like av testing if i'm gonna like
um you know try out a different
amendment or a different um target on
something so a lot of times i have like
a cultivar that i'm running
you know four beds in the same room so
i'll do like
you know
different i'll have like two be a
control and then um you know two of
those beds will be control beds and then
i'll do one with like you know let's say
i'm gonna try
adding nitrogen at different points or
something one will be like some nitrogen
here and then another one might be more
so i'll sort of use them
um
to do tests against each other so i do i
kind of have six pods in there the way i
think of it in that room and then in the
newer room those beds are three yards
each and then i just take one sample
from each one of those beds well we take
three samples and then do like a
composite mix it up so there's only one
um
yeah so in in something like 20 yards of
soil per room i'm taking like six tests
which does save quite a bit of money um
and i
actually i look at the saturated taste
as more actionable than the
standard test nowadays sort of like what
um you were saying i think the calcium
is the big one on the standard that just
throws everything out of whack um
because
it tells you how this incredibly high
amount of calcium you don't need to
amend anything and then i'll look at the
ppms on the um
on the saturated paste and
you know this was one of the first times
that i was like okay this saturated
paste is super important because i was
seeing that
um you know it's having 50 ppm of
calcium when the standard was showing
insanely high numbers
so now i kind of disregard the calcium
on the standard and really watch it more
on the saturated paste and i could track
that with results and
you know justin your friend justin
mcgill
um you know he's he was a really good
person to talk about that as well and he
shared some of his data um and i've been
able to
you know really identify
that pattern of making sure you have
enough calcium
on the saturated paste and that's what
sort of drove me that direction and now
um
you know i took bryant's course too the
um his i don't remember what was called
but it's like that cannabis course on
his uh on his website
and that really connected a ton of dots
for me and he does
you know talk about how to weigh the two
um which was kind of what i was already
doing and it really it connected a lot
of
um
it connected a lot of things for me and
really made a lot of sense so
you know that was that was really
helpful for me
how to use all of his exact targets but
i think that
the methodology of a lot of that was
really helpful
yeah and i will say one one thing to
mention is that steve solomon's book was
really designed for people growing
vegetables in actual soil and it wasn't
designed around maximizing yield it was
designed around
increasing nutrient density so he gets
much more involved with trace trace
minerals and his targets are not
optimal i would say for cannabis and i
think he would admit that too that that
wasn't the initial goal with his with
his writing so
uh bryant's targets are i think much
better for cannabis but again you're
going to want to make adjustments for
your own facility
just a just to plug brian's class i've
taken it too it's it is excellent
if you want to learn how to do this
stuff yourself i think that's the best
resource online and there is a coupon
code for uh if you put in kiss organics
in in on the website you'll save i think
100 bucks off the test or 150 i can't
remember but or off the course so
uh shameless plug there i'll throw that
in there um
bryant's brian had that coupon code when
i took it
you should have uh i'm sorry about that
um
yeah yeah so it's a good it's a good
course and it's interactive too so um
yeah if people want to learn more they
can definitely check that out so
yeah just wanted to mention that
um
so in terms of the in terms of the
testing now i think you bring up a good
point so you find that the tests give
you good actional information but they
don't tell the whole story can you talk
a little bit more
about that
um yeah i mean i mean the way you said
it kind of sums it up pretty well i mean
i i definitely do all of the testing
because
um
i feel like with no testing i'm just
kind of flying blind because i do see
that the
you know
like i'm not amending the same thing
every round and i do see
the need like to change the amendments
every round so if i didn't do
any testing i would feel like i would
have really
you know a pretty vague idea how to do
the next rounds amendment and it'll
probably be fine but successively i
think that it would be tougher to course
correct um
without really ever seeing what those
changes are
so
you know i don't look at the individuals
i just more look at the trajectory and
the patterns that i see um
and you know i do trust that i think at
one point i was really like okay
these tests are just too erratic and i
can't really make good judgments on them
um and now i've kind of come around the
other way where
you know like i have
a history of the testing in in in the
facility in the beds and i know
in general um where i want to be and if
things are you know like sometimes i'll
just get an insanely
ridiculous number on on something and i
just disregard it completely it's just
an outlier which means
nothing but if i see you know on all six
or seven tests from the same room
they're like okay i have
plenty of nitrogen right now i'm not
gonna amend any nitrogen
or um you know it doesn't really ever
happen with potassium i can't seem to
add
enough potassium um
but
you know
that information is still it's critical
to what i do every round
but i just i'm looking more at it as a
trend or a pattern
of what i'm seeing in the roman analyze
i think that
that answer your question is kind of
vague but
yeah i find the two levers that we pull
the most on with our soils and tests and
this is a lot reflected with justin's
test too is usually nitrates and
calcium so we'll see sometimes we'll see
too much calcium over time
build up but again we have to watch that
availability on the saturated paste but
then nitrates that's the other one that
for some reason will show up and i think
some of that is just in these in these
large beds you have all these worm
populations that explode over time and
then break down
additional organic matter and are
releasing
uh minerals and so we kind of have to
keep an eye on that because i've had
runs with justin where we don't amend at
all or we just add
a little bit of egg sulfur or something
very very minor maybe a little bit of
potassium sulfate but have to cut back
completely just because we see nitrates
showing up yeah
really high even though they didn't add
a lot of nitrogen around before
so yep it's kind of interesting one of
the things that i
one of the things that i think i've um
you know started to hone in on and and
it solidified for me during um when i
was taking the course with uh
with bryant was the compost because
that wasn't really something that i had
an analysis on it wasn't something that
i was really
factoring in much so when you're adding
compost every round
it can take a really long time for that
compost to
you know release its nitrogen
and
you know like i'm really speaking right
outside my lane here but i'm gonna do it
anyway um so he's talking about the
carbon to nitrogen ratio
i think like anything like over 20 it
can actually be
a nitrogen sink if i remember what he
said correctly
and i was looking at some of the compost
i was using and it was 22 23
um carbon and nitrogen um
and
so i think in my case what might have
been happening is i was adding compost
was actually a sink for a little while
and then you know months later it was
this wave of nitrogen that was coming
out possibly from the compost
and you know justin and i actually had
the same sort of
nitrogen surge
at the same time when he was cutting
back his
amendments for uh for nitrate i was too
and it was also during the summer so i
have a it's a little bit far-fetched but
i'm going to do it anyways this summer
um i'm going to send in a refrigerated
sample of soil and then one you know in
the heat of summer because one of my
theories is that possibly the nitrates
is changing just during the course of
um it being shipped and then getting
tested a week later and i don't i don't
know what your opinion on that is but
i'm i'm going to test either way because
i'm just curious it was
both of us had this nitrogen surge in
the summer
um
but i also did see you know high
nitrogen my plants and i didn't demand
and i didn't run out of nitrogen so
there was a bunch of nitrogen in my soil
yeah so when i what we look for too is
to just for people that are testing is
not total nitrogen that's not a very
useful number but you want to look at
nitrates and ammonium and then right
that ammonium number should be very low
like below one um a lot of times it
doesn't even register on our tests
because if that number is high what
that's telling us is that there's
there's still organic matter it's still
hot that's going to break down and
release into nitrates
and it gets a little tricky that tells
me that you used probably unfinished
compost most likely
into the bed whereas that nitrate number
is fairly
is is a fairly useful
number in determining how much nitrogen
your plant's going to have available
that cycle and you can have target we
have targets around that for depending
on what week you're in
but i haven't thought about it in terms
of the temperature of that soil if the
microbiology due to the heat and travel
in the in the mail could somehow affect
that that's interesting i hadn't thought
of that variable there's always other
variables you don't consider and then
yeah i remember i talked to um i talked
to susan logan about it and she was like
maybe she seems kind of skeptical but
she was like it's possible like it's not
going to
it's not going to stay exactly the same
you know so the question is how much
does it vary so i'm like okay once once
we get some hot weather again i'm going
to send in
you know a pack that's a little ziplock
that's nice and refrigerated and kind of
not doing anything and then sending
another one to the regular mail
so yeah i will say though like like you
what we found with justin was there
still was sufficient nitrogen next cycle
so the test was
relatively accurate no i'm in that
regard
um
yeah i pulled back on my compost
amendments quite a bit so i i just don't
add as much compost and i end up adding
more
other nitrogen amendments
and
you know
that
seems to be working well for me right
now it's a something i started doing
like maybe about a year ago
um
yeah and i don't i don't think you
necessarily have to
add compost every cycle um
yeah so that's that's a that's a valid
point too because you're also going to
be bringing in fungus gnats potentially
every time you bring in compost or
you can definitely bring them
every time
yeah yeah so that's that's one thing
about compost that's a little bit
challenging or any soil that has a
compost fraction it's it's relatively
unavoidable
um
well let's talk a little bit i want to
i kind of want to go back to this idea
of all the variables that you consider
when evaluating your plants beyond just
soil testing because
i know for us like when we get a soil
test from someone i have a series of
questions that i needed that i feel like
i need to get information on to make an
accurate recommendation i i'm not
comfortable doing it off of just a test
alone because like when i started you
know it was like you was with that
solomon's book that was where i really
started learning about mineral balancing
and albrecht and and started going down
that whole
uh
that whole path um
and i was just using the grow abundant
calculator that erica reinheimer put
together it's a it's a good resource if
like if you just want a quick and easy
test like i use it for
my garden beds if i don't feel like
doing math
you can just plug the numbers right in
the subscription is very affordable and
it'll spit out something that's
based off of
their book the intelligent gardener she
was a she was a co-author on that
but if it's for my cannabis plants and
we're talking about really maximizing
fertility
there's a lot more variable there than
just a soil test like i know i want to
know what the co2 levels are they're
running in the in the facility and what
the light levels are at canopy and maybe
a little about what type of genetics and
how long are you vegging and flowering
and what size are your containers and
how are you watering um
there's you know there's a whole list of
things there and and i see photos of the
plants how did your plants finish are
you happy with where they finished and
the yields and all of those things go
into
the analysis it's not just you can look
at a number on a test and then
make a recommendation
yeah totally agree
um so are there any other things that
you really look at to when you're
when you're going to re-amend the soil
you know take me through sort of i know
i i just stole your thunder a little bit
on that by naming a whole bunch but i
was gonna say you covered a lot there
were there other ones that i didn't you
know miss off top of my head it is
yeah one of the things that
has really been really fun and
interesting and eye-opening coming from
an engineering background into this is
just the amount of things that um the
amount of variables that go into the
process
and
you know it's like
like i want to bust out a spreadsheet
that has all of those variables and then
i can do like
you know data regression or something
and try to figure out how to optimize
all those parameters and there's just
too many um
so
i don't really have like a set process
on that i think it's like one of those
things where you're just you're watching
every run as it's going um because even
like light spectrum i did um
in in my new room i did a bunch of
different light types and uh you know
one of them is this um it's a dragon
alpha from science and i really love
those lights and i had all these ideas
on how i was going to start messing with
the spectrum at different times
during the growth cycle
and do all this testing to you know
look at the you know red and blue and
all of that and
i've sort of backed off on it because
there's so many other variables um going
on in there
that i i kind of i'm not a good point
where i can like okay really get into
that and consider that as a as a
an a b test at all
um
so
i don't know i mean i think i just
didn't answer your question i think i
answered the request by saying that
there's a lot of gut feel and i don't
really have um a process other than just
seeing how that run finished and i'm
kind of always trying something a little
bit new every run trying to dig my
zigzag my way to optimization but it's
just too many things just too many
things so what you're calling your gut
is really um
your subconscious giving you
uh feedback based off of experience
because you've done
you know you've been doing this for how
your gut's definitely gotten smarter i
guess is what i'm getting at
i mean how many cycles they have like i
have my ideas on when i see something
going on with a leaf pattern of what i
think that means and you know
i just i really
try to avoid making any solid
conclusions like okay i know that this
little yellowing on the on the
serrations of the leaves is telling me i
have a potassium deficiency which is
what i believe but i also i'm like okay
that's probably what i think that is
so i'm like taking in all that
information um
and you know and just seeing what
the the pattern of growth like if i
don't see
that first few weeks that explosion like
i normally do you know then i'm thinking
about what my nitrogen was probably
doing earlier on in
um you know in the flower room and then
so i might change the way i look at the
um
the nitrogen on the next round or
something like that because that's the
one that
for me i trust the least on the um on
the analysis i almost
you know
i just look at and be like okay am i
good here to not amend anything right
now but even if it's
higher than i would like it to be i'm
still planning to add something a week
or two later into flower because i know
it's going to drop down
um or at least that's my mental model
but
yeah i don't know i mean i think you
just
what are you adding then uh just for
listeners when
when you are i mean i had a lot of your
yeah i add a lot of your um your
nutrient pack and then
i have a lot of specific amendments um
you know i add a lot of gypsum potassium
sulfate i have a few different
nitrogen specific amendments just you
know like alfalfa meal sometimes some
feather male um
fish bone meal i use a lot of that
um
calphos
[Music]
so i
i mean i don't know i think i think i
probably have you know probably about 10
or 12 different things that i use
regularly
right now i'm doing a whole bunch of
investigation on micronutrients which
we've already discussed but um
you know i don't really have a lot of
that stuff on hand in general besides
maybe manganese
i actually do want to talk to you about
trace minerals that was a question i was
saving because
oh okay
yeah because in my experience you know
like if you go the intelligent gardener
route you're adding trace minerals
pretty much every cycle to get a balance
whereas my experience with cannabis and
looking a lot of tests i now won't touch
trace minerals for at least a few cycles
of testing because i want to so
for me the first thing i look at is ph
um how available the nutrients gonna be
and then from there you know on the
standard like i'll throw out some
numbers like i don't really worry too
much about the organic matte percentage
on the standard um bryant has a really
good explanation on that
the cec on the standard is a very useful
tool with potting soils and again brian
has a good right instagram video
explaining why
um
but when we talk about uh
trace minerals i i find that uh
the only time i really look at it is if
something looks really really high
or it's just virtually non-existent i
mean if there's a little bit in there on
showing up on the test then i usually
don't worry about it and just focus on
my macros but what i know you got into
fiddling there for a little while
yeah i definitely that's what i do yeah
yeah
um
so you know in those
in that room with the pods as i was
describing i sort of did a
you know three pods were controlled
where i didn't do any micronutrients and
then two pods were sort of
um you know one regime of micronutrients
and one pod was another one and then so
it was basically half the room was
you know
status quo no micronutrient additions um
and then the other one i think i added
then i ended up adding
um copper zinc manganese i had a lot of
manganese um boron and um
maybe one other one i can't remember
right now um
and i do think that that side of the
room has benefited from it more than the
other side but i don't see any there's
no game changers in there the plants
just they seem to be a little less
water stressed i see i just feel like
they can drink a little easier
um and
you know i i don't see like any
accelerated growth but
you know when i first put the plants in
there's one cultivar i have which just
hates me um in veg it's a strawberry
sour larry which is it always finishes
great but i i have trouble with it and
veg every round it is the first to tell
me if it's pissed off um and that plant
when i put it into the beds that have
the micronutrients and i've done some
micronutrient testing in veg too but
um more sporadically
when i when i bring that cultivar into
that room and i put it in the in the
beds that have had those micronutrient
amendments um
and i don't know like which one it's
reacting to or just the
all of them combined that plant reacts
more quickly in the beds that have the
micronutrients so it's more like
fine-tuning in general is
is what i think i'm seeing more than
okay
there's this magic micronutrient that
has been missing that has
you know
changed my world or anything
where i'm more interested in doing it is
in um in veg for propagation for taking
moms um because i do think that there's
you know propagating organically is
it's always been the thing i'm the worst
at
you know they tend to stay in the trays
a little bit longer they don't root as
quickly
i'm not using a rooting gel like a plant
growth regulator
and
you know that mother plant nutrition the
health of that mother plant is just that
much more critical when you're growing
organically
in doing propagation organically so
i'm really targeting that in in
in veg for propagation purposes and just
getting the healthiest cuttings i can
to root more quickly because i do think
that
potentially with forming calluses like
i've done some experiments on callus
formation and
you know
on some of them like the strawberry
sarah larry i'm not getting a callus
sometimes for 10 or 11 days so no wonder
i'm not getting explosive root growth um
you know so i think that
it's one of my theories is that that
whatever it's missing that's really you
know it's upset about veg is probably
the same thing that's really preventing
it from being able to callous up and um
and even though like when you take that
cutting they look great they look
healthy
um because the moms and veg have bigger
pots
but as you know after a week and a half
in a tray you can really start to see
that it's not doing as well and you know
if you check for calluses you know they
just they're not forming at the pace i'd
like them to and
i guess my theory is on the
micronutrient is more for propagation
than for flour although i do see
i feel like i see benefits in flower
okay okay
and uh how many cycles in are you now
with some of your rooms
oh i don't know um
i mean it's like you know
five cycles here in a room so
um in that room i think i'm probably
with your soil like three and a half
years or something
so
um maybe
15 to 20 range something like that
okay okay awesome um have you had ups
and downs there in terms of i mean how
much does your yield fluctuate cycle the
cycle
not much it's actually really consistent
right now um
some of my older cultivars are kind of
trending down just the vigor is
decreasing
the quality is still
doing great but the yield on some of my
older genetics is kind of declining
that's one of the other reasons i want
to look at some micronutrients and
propagation is
you know there's probably been some
rounds where the cuttings haven't come
off of a mom that's as healthy as i
would like and that sort of just tends
to accumulate i think
um
so
some of my yields have tracked down a
little bit but then on the newer
cultivars i bring in you know they're
just smashing again so i don't think
it's a soil thing i think it's just a
you know
having genetics that have been
propagated for four years you know
but because the yields are are pretty
predictable i have a pretty good idea of
what i'm going to get for yield in each
room on each cultivar at this point
yeah now one thing we haven't talked
about as a variable uh when reamending
soils or evaluating plants is is pest
pressure
uh are you comfortable touching on that
a little bit
yeah sure i mean i we we did that video
um on instagram with the aphid that was
our
um
test
experience really that was really
traumatic i mean we dealt with a few
paths over time but we had the cannabis
aphid
um
yeah so what was your specific question
oh i guess i was just thinking about
things that will influence um
plant health and yields when we're
talking about re-amending if i'm
re-amending and i know that you know the
you know the
person is battling you know cannabis
aphid or spider mites or thrips or broad
knights brew defeats whatever
whatever it may be that can have an
impact on
overall yields and plant health yeah
depending on how they're managing it
and so
that also should be factored in when i
talk about reamending
the soil if they're seeing something on
the plant well it may not be from slow
it may not be a soil fertility issue i
guess
yeah i mean um
since the cannabis aphid thing we
haven't really had any you know pest
pressure issues
i put out a lot of beneficial these days
um i like to think of my facility as
you know just loaded with starving
insects ready to eat anything that might
find its way in um
saw some thrips a little while ago
you know suzanne's been a really great
resource for me i sent them off to her
you know we did um oh geez i can't
remember the name of it we did a release
of
one of the predatory things for thrips
and and i've been using cucumaris for
years now
and
we just we saw some thrips on a few
plants for a little while and they just
thought it went away so we haven't had
to um
you know deal with them but the uh the
fungus at issue has been um you know
especially in propagation with the
younger plants the fungus that issue has
been
you know consistent for us
you know growing organically
so we use a ton of you know nematodes
and
there's been a couple of times where i
think the fungus population in the in
the younger plants has kind of stunted
some of them
um but not really from like an amendment
standpoint because i'm not amending that
soil
okay yeah yeah sf nematodes are great
for dealing with fungus gnats and i
think they're they're just something
that people should have as a maintenance
routine
um
yup just just to stay ahead of things
it's much easier to
to get ahead of it than try and battle
it so
yeah i learned that one the hard way
when i had that cannabis after that i
just loaded up on beneficials and
um
you know we've been
lucky since then i guess
well having good practices to keep
things out of your facility is always
i think the best
the best thing
you can do yep
yep you're just going to learn it the
hard way
because before that i was like oh man
these beneficials are a bunch of money
i'm just going to make sure that i don't
bring in any genetics and
you know
i'm just going to keep my fingers
crossed basically
so no more no more of that for us well
you're in a building too where there's
other grows right or in an area right
there's a little more
risk yep for sure i mean we're in a
building with other growers and
um you know i don't i don't think that
there's a high probability of
you know
many bugs flying around the building and
flying in my door but also
you know like
our grow isn't super sophisticated we
you know we have doors that come into
rooms and then doors go into other rooms
so
in the spring it's entirely possible
that we're going to have an aphid
find its way in an open door you know
either on a person coming from the car
into the building or
just finding its way in because our
plants smell nice or whatever you know
so as
as someone who you know started this
facility and as you know sort of evolved
to where you are now what are some of
the biggest challenges that you've
experienced along the way and this
doesn't necessarily have to be
cultivation
related in terms of an answer
um
i mean
i think finding good information
is probably the biggest challenge um
you know it's like
good information on cannabis is tough to
find and it's an it's in a growing field
you know
a lot of this has been
you know behind closed doors for a long
time so you're just calling somebody you
know or
you know finding some stuff online that
you can go from and god knows how
accurate that is
um so
historically it's been next to
impossible to have great information and
now there's a lot more coming out
um and you know through your podcast is
one of the sources honestly for me
um
but
yeah i mean just just
being able to get really good
information and you know like
like googling i mean i can't you know
googling leaf deficiencies you take a
picture of your leaf and you're sitting
there with your iphone you know trying
to compare this to a picture you find
online and it's
you know that's it's next to impossible
so when you're trying to
call somebody who might add a similar
issue um
so that's been that's been a process is
just getting good information you know
um
i think another one is um
[Music]
that can of safety i mean that was like
a that was a hard time
um you know i wasn't sure if we were
gonna
make it through that because at that
time like you're you know you're kind of
living cropped a crop i mean all of us
growers know it's like
everyone thinks we're raking in the
money but you know there's a lot of
money going through the business with
power and rent and trying to pay
employees and you know when you have
a couple of crops that aren't going to
go well i mean it's not it's not long
before you're not paying your bills
so that was a that was a pretty scary
time because if we hadn't gotten rid of
that thing
you know one of my solutions was to
because i was i mean i was probably
overreactive at the time i was you know
really just terrified of this bug that
supposedly wasn't on the east coast i
didn't know anybody else out here that
had it and i remember justin talking
about it and he really scared the crap
out of me
and then i remember i sent when i first
got a picture of it i think i sent it to
you
um
because i don't think i knew suzanne at
the time um actually that's when i met
susan this is through the cannabis aphid
experience
and then justin and justin's reply was
getting ready to go to war man
um
so
so let's let's just touch on it i don't
i don't want to get too into
into pest advice just because i
we have suzanne who's really the the
expert
on that yeah really the foremost expert
on that and we do but um i know justin
through you know some of his processes
is able to we're never allowed to say
eradicate because out of respect for
suzanne it's not a word that we can use
when we're talking about pests
but we can they have not spotted another
aphid in their facility in over a year
or two now um it sounds like you're in a
similar boat
what what really like put the nail in
the coffin for them
in your facility so for us it was the
heat treatment we we cooked the place
um which was a
risky move and it was a dangerous move
but it was we only had
um you know we only had it in a few
spots and i was just really scared of
this population exploding really quickly
and i
you know i wasn't really sure what to do
and i remember reading about how fast it
can replicate and i i found one i put in
a baggie and i went back the next day
and there were six in there um in a
24-hour period and i was like holy crap
so
you know that's when
i
basically panicked you know like
suzanne wouldn't say that this was like
a smart thing to do um and i try not to
tell other people like you know this is
what you should do because i think a lot
of people probably can't do it but um
you know i heated the rooms you know
aphids don't like heat and i cooked the
rooms up to 120 degrees for two hours
um
and you know i lost some plants and veg
for sure and i was in there watering the
whole time and thank god we had large
soil volumes because if you didn't have
if i was in pots like the the root zone
temperature would
you'd kill the plants um
you know when we did kill some plants in
the bedroom
but that's what i did and it worked and
we never saw another aphid again i did
that and then i did a huge release of
the the wasp the comani and her irve or
something
um
and then you know lace wings all over
the place so we just went full bore on
that and then did a huge so we did the
knock down talking with suzanne that the
the heat treatment was to do a knockdown
um
and then the
you know the beneficial release after
that i never saw another eight but and
that was i don't know a couple years ago
now
that's great yeah
um
okay so i wanna i wanna change direction
there's a couple questions that we
there's a couple things we haven't
talked about that i think people might
find interesting especially if they
start following you on
instagram um
so two things one i want to talk first
about your blue mat experience
um because okay i think that's
interesting and i think we should add
contrarian views to you know our
experiences
as as everyone knows we're big fans of
blue mats i we use them in quite a few
commercial facilities uh justin mcgill
who's a good friend of mine and mike
michael knows them too
he uses them very successfully so you
bought a bunch of blue mats tell me
about your experiences
yeah when i first bought them um you
know i bought a few to try them out and
had really great results some of the
best results i've ever had is on blue
maps to be fully transparent
um
and just as we've tried to
put them out on a larger scale and i
don't have a large facility you know we
have two flower rooms each one's you
know one's like 400 square feet the
other one's 500 square feet of canopy
um
trying to get the consistency that i
want out of the blue mats i just haven't
been able to accomplish it um you know
like my philosophically one of things i
don't love about the blue mass is you
don't really know if you're
underwatering until you see an unhappy
plant wilting
which if that happens late in flower
that's a big deal
or
you have you know runoff coming out of
your beds and then you go to make the
adjustment on the um on the blue mats
and they're just really sensitive
so by the time you have a bed that's
running off
it's probably going to keep dripping for
another day and like we don't have
really great
water mitigation i put some like you
know
system underneath the beds to kind of
corral the water which doesn't really
work that well so in my older room with
it when the beds run off it just makes a
mess um
and also i don't like the idea of losing
the nutrients but
the um
yeah i mean you know they tend to if you
get like any air in there at all even if
you fill them up and do everything you
set them properly
sometimes you get a little bit of air in
one and they just don't you know they
don't work there's any air in there
basically a cushion on it so they don't
have the ability to
you know the tension doesn't work its
way through to the actual mechanism that
pinches the little hose um
so we just haven't been able to get it
to be as consistent
on scale
and some of that might just be through
having multiple people in the facility
if you're doing a default or a cleanup
on your leaves if you bump the thing
even if you don't twist the knob
if the if the blue mat itself gets
pumped and it breaks contact with the
soil it's gonna think the soil is dry
because it's got air
so we had a you know a few experiences
like that with runoff
and because my facility isn't that big
um we just hand water and you know i
don't think that's our forever solution
i don't
you know i'm not saying everybody should
hand water larger facilities because
it's a it's a pain in the butt but for
right now it
that seems to be working more
consistently for us than the blue mats
were
yeah so i you know uh i've heard this a
couple times uh it's a little more rare
but the you know it is for some people
it just it doesn't work quite the way
they want it to um
i will say i've worked with some fairly
large facilities that are pulling it off
but the concerns around the air inside
the sensor or the air around coming in
contact with the sensor in the
in the soil itself so like if there's a
big chunk of pumice or perlite right
next to that sensor it could cause it to
um
just over over water like directions so
yeah those are those are definite
concerns um
i think if i was in a larger facility
i'd probably be a little bit more
incentivized to try to figure it out
um because the labor savings would be
more significant basically
um
and i like
i think if we kept going at it we would
eventually figure it out but um
you know i don't know i just
we haven't had we haven't adopted it we
tried it a few times and when they're
working they're great but there was too
many times where it's
you know the nail in the coffin was we
had um one of them clogged from the
inside basically so the hose looked like
it was wicking water and there was
you know there was a we were using the
um
what's that white hose stuff the uh
grip tape yeah the blue foam essentially
soaker hose yeah yeah so it looked like
it was watering
um and it really wasn't and we didn't
notice it and it was like you know week
six and we had two beds that
you know just tailed off hard and
finished really early and that's when we
realized that they just weren't getting
any water
can you explain that because the way
they look like the water is they
actually perspire through the hose
itself so you can see the droplets
coming out of the soaker hose
right yeah i think well that's so the
hose was i mean you know after you use
them a few times they get pretty
you know
sturdy
so you don't really see a droplet
anymore you more just see a film on the
hose
um and i think in this case there was a
biofilm that had sort of formed from the
inside so
there was some water coming out of them
in the in the the actual thing was
pressurized so it was like okay that
when you walk by you think it's watering
and the soil looks a little dry but you
can see a little wetness on the on the
um
on the hose itself and you can you know
it looks like it's watering
um
and so that was a new one we hadn't seen
that one before and i think that one is
extremely rare i i've talked to a few
people about it and they they were like
yeah
that's not that's not a common thing
um and it only happened on you know two
of the beds that run and that was the
only time i ever saw it but
yeah i've never seen that but i i guess
i could see where that could happen we
always uh
clean in between cycles the we clean the
blue mats
and and the soaker hose to make sure
that
you know it's ready to go for the next
cycle but the other thing too that we
typically have people doing is going
around with a moisture meter and just
making sure
that the beds are staying at the in the
range that we want them to
um
because like you mentioned like justin
doesn't have any way of having runoff in
his beds he literally has a little tiny
like i mean it's not much larger than a
solo cup little bucket hanging off the
side of the beds because the way his
facility was designed it was you know it
was an old right chicken factory so he
kind of had to modify it and there's no
drains in the room so
uh
yeah and they've had a couple floods but
overall it's been it's been really
really positive um and worked really
well for him so
yeah i don't know i just thought i just
thought it'd be fun to have a little
discussion around it um the only other
thing i really wanted to touch on with
you is uh you run bare soil you don't
have cover crops in there um
explain i mean i've i know i've been
pretty vocal about my thoughts on it but
what are your thoughts around running
cover crop
yeah i mean most of my thoughts are
probably from taking advice from you
because
you know as far as like learning how to
grow in these large beds and living soil
like you've been the person that i've
talked to the most so
in general like i remember i was really
excited about doing some cover crops
after i got the beds and
you know
your your advice was you know you can
harbor additional pests and stuff like
that and
you know suzanne's always told me the
same thing
and i've always had since i went to the
beds i've had great results with
doing amendments the way i'm doing them
so
i guess my thought is a little bit you
know along the lines of like if it isn't
broke don't fix it sort of thing is you
know the results we're getting results
that we're quite satisfied with and
it is an additional thing that you would
have to manage
um
and
you know i've done some reading on cover
crops
and
you know in indoors i'm not sure that
everybody's getting the the nitrogen
cycling that they that they want and i i
don't really know like it's just one of
these things that i've never i've never
done that um
and i i can't remember but i was reading
something about somebody talking about
doing cover crops um
and how much nitrogen actually makes it
back into the soil
through those crops and
um
i think it's a lot less than and our
people are hoping for sometimes and it
is it's it's another it's another
environment that you're trying to manage
so
you know
today it's something i just haven't i
just haven't gotten into really okay i
thought i didn't know if you played
around with it um i know gold leaf did
and moved away from it um
i wasn't sure if that was something you
would
ever no i at one point i was all i was
all jazzed up to give it a whirl and um
and then i ruined it i think
uh you weren't the only one i mean i
talked to a few people and
you know
it is one of those things it's like if
you if things are going well um you know
it doesn't always make sense to
start trying new things um so
i i still have a curiosity about it
honestly uh but yeah well folks want to
hear maybe i'll try someday maybe i'll
try it again maybe i'll give it a
give the thought process a chance again
now you brought it up yeah it's not it's
not a black and white answer but i i i
definitely fall on the side of not using
cover crops indoors and if people want
to read more about that i have a blog
post that's fairly recent up there on
why
uh at least so people can read my logic
and and then tell me i'm wrong i get
that a fair bit but um
yeah
i guess philosophically too it sort of
made sense to me too because it is one
more variable
and
you know
i was talking with of the other night
and i was talking about
you know like
this organic growing process that really
has so many variables just like um you
were saying earlier is that like this
really is a puzzle that i'm really still
working on and
you know yeah like
adding this thing in or not is like if
if i was going to try it i want to test
it like am i going to bring this in or
not and i'm still
messing with a lot of other things at
this point so i'm always kind of
testing this and that and
um you know maybe i'll get there someday
and it just
hasn't made it to the forefront of what
i've
tested
yeah and when you say testing uh you
brought up a good point you're not just
uh
you're not just doing something across
your entire facility when you say tests
it's it's no
that's not that's not what you do right
yep i always kind of if i'm trying out
something new i bring it in and uh
depending on my level of confidence if
it's if i'm skeptical i do it on a very
small area and if i'm you know more
confident i might try it on a broad area
like the micronutrients like i wasn't
worried that i was going to
ruin the soil in half of the beds
because i didn't you know i didn't even
go for the targets i went for like half
of the targets and
waited for analysis so i'm kind of
creeping up on it um
but yeah i always sort of like try
something and see if it starts making
sense and then kind of scale up on it
you know
actually ben higgins the one you did
with him i had my people listen to it i
was like you know i was sending the link
to my employees like you guys got to
listen to this this is like you know
this is how i think and that's how i
want you guys to think his process of
you know basically bringing the
scientific process into the
into cultivation it's definitely like
how my brain works and to have someone
like really talk about it the way he did
was like really clearly so
um
you know i have the same mindset i do a
lot of
um you know if i if i have a hypothesis
on how something might be better or
uh you know to get rid of a problem i
come up with an idea of how i'm going to
test that thing and then prove it out
awesome yeah and i like the idea that
you started with half of your
what you thought might be your target
just to make sure you weren't overdoing
it because you can always add more and a
lot of people i think yeah a little
carried away on that side of things so
that's and i have found um
yeah on the micronutrients like the
copper um
when i've added that it's basically just
stayed and that's one of the things
that's given me someone else some
confidence in analysis as i can see that
copper and the beds that i've added it
to in a way that really does make sense
um
and then the other ones like manganese
like i've added manganese and it just it
disappears
um so that's when i can see that the
plants are actually uptaking that
manganese whereas the copper sort of
just stays in that bed so if you add too
much copper like you're probably screwed
um
that's kind of
but i've seen manganese really i don't
know if it's leaching out like if we're
having some runoff or if the plants were
up taking it but i suspect the plants
are actually uptaking it because we had
in those older beds there was virtually
no manganese
yeah i'd be a little cautious with it
because i think um it was sam hoffler
from proof who did some experimentation
and he does tissue testing along with um
the soil testing and he does it on a
whole another level
no one's doing as many tests as he is uh
and
graphing them and figuring out what each
analyte is is really amazing um
what he's doing is really state of the
art i got to he gave me a quick little
tour
uh video shot of what he does and one of
the things they found was that when they
were adding manganese they actually
started to cease and toxicities they got
in trouble with it because it was being
taken up
um
so dramatically by the plant so
it would keep an eye on yeah yeah just
just watch that and be careful because
um
you know tissue testing is really how we
figure out what's
actually making it into the plants um
the soil testing we're just making
assumptions that you know the amount of
biology that we have yeah these
nutrients are coming available
whereas the tissue testing is a little
more accurate in that regard but i
actually don't do a ton of tissue
testing but that one i did
and that's one of the reasons that i was
really convinced to go after the
micronutrients too because in the tissue
testing
um they were
basically non-detectable there was like
three or four maybe five micronutrients
that were just like
and and i don't know like they give you
these reference ranges and it's like
okay like how much you're supposed to
have in there and
um but there was a few that was like
okay no matter what the reference joint
this is like non-detectable levels here
um
so and manganese was one of them
oh that's really interesting well i know
we've been chatting for a while is there
any last
you know advice or whether on the
business side or on the cultivation side
um that you'd like to share with folks
um
yeah i guess i mean one of the
yeah i mean just be just be ready for
some failures
um you know even just like about a month
ago
um one of my employees said to me you
know it's a good thing i have a
i think what he said he goes a good
thing you have a really healthy
relationship with failure um you know we
were redoing some of the
drainage system in a couple of the beds
and um you know there was a clog and so
the beds just filled up with water
luckily there weren't any plants in them
at the time we were doing a little bit
of a flush to get some sodium and
chloride down
and um
so we had to basically activate these
beds and it was just like this soup
uh and this whole thing we had spent a
week
taking out these three yards of soil
from these two different beds putting in
this
you know drainage pipe and all this to
try to be able to collect the water in
one location and we refilled everything
and then we had to basically take it all
apart again and it was a mess
and um
you know stuff like that just happens
all the time to everybody so it's like
you know
i don't know it's
it's there's just a lot of failure
involved in it there's a lot of you know
you think something's kind of it doesn't
or you didn't even know something was
gonna bite you and then it does
um so it's just a lot of a lot of
resilience and and knowing that like
you know just because something goes
wrong it's probably gone wrong for
everybody else too so if you
can you know muster the energy to try to
figure it out and call some people you
can usually get through it if you just
like decide i'm gonna solve this i'm
gonna get through this
and
you know that's one thing that's been
really tough about being a small
business owner it's not it's not even
always cultivation
it's you know packaging shipments it's
the whole thing you know
um so just
you know have a healthy relationship
with failure
yeah i think you've done a good job of
creating a sort of a community around
you of resources and then also um
building a good brand to where
you know
consumers know what
what to expect when they walk in the
store and see you know main craft
cannabis and uh
you know generating that interest on the
brand side i think is is
equally as important as growing a high
quality product
yeah
yeah and i have to give my wife emily
credit for all of that you know um when
we were
first getting going with all that she
really
she's pushed me a lot to
you know share stuff on instagram and
even to do podcasts like this like you
know this isn't my comfort zone you
probably know that too but um
you know it's always for me it's always
been
i'm willing to do it because
the former me would still like to hear
what the current me has to say even
though i don't know everything
and then that transparency has really
you know i think it's built a lot of um
trust in in our industry with our brand
and it's really paid off and emily's one
who's pushed me to do that because no
one really wants to make a video about
their aphid problems um
but
you know
the me who was newer would have been so
happy to find the video of the current
me with my aphid problem saying how i
solved it even if it's not
exactly what i'm going to do so
um you know
that
the work she's done on creating the
brand is yeah it's it's especially the
way the market is going in maine right
now like having
having people that can identify your
product is is really paid off um quite a
bit and and that's really through the
communications she's forced me to make
and her own communication through it as
well obviously
yeah i know she's gotten really into the
chocolate side of things too and using
you know premium ingredients and
processes to make a really high quality
product for consumers yeah
yeah i mean our goal in general is to
try to whenever we do something to
do it the best we can so we don't have
like a really wide product line we kind
of figure the things that we make really
well and
um that we can specialize in and then we
just sort of focus on that and that's
you know definitely something emily's
brought to the table as well i'm usually
more quick to be like hey we should get
into this product this looks really fun
other people are doing this um and you
know shows how to refocus me and be like
we don't need to do everything just you
know let's pick the things that we can
do well and just nail those
which
makes a lot of sense
awesome well thanks again for your time
today and i appreciate you doing this
and kudos to emily for uh
forcing you on the show so
okay dad i really appreciate it and i
appreciate the opportunity thank you all
right have a great rest of the day
thanks michael okay bye
[Music]
that was mike wilson and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information
thanks for listening