[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge you
know it's about time that I did a
podcast focus just on lighting this is
not a topic that I'm all that strong on
so it was great to sit down with some
experts in the field and get to ask some
questions to learn more my guests this
week are Travis Williams and Travis
Higginbotham yes - Travis's so it's a
little tricky to tell them apart but
between the two of them we get to hear
about very different aspects of the
lighting industry Travis Williams is the
director of brand marketing and fluence
bioengineering he is passionate about
clean energy sustainability and
controlled environment agriculture his
job allows him to help growers navigate
the challenging and complex world of
horticultural lighting to realize
improvements in crop production
sustainability and profits through LED
technology Travis Higginbotham is the
new director of cultivation support for
fluency prior to working influence he
worked at a state-of-the-art
environmentally controlled greenhouse
covering 50 acres where he was the head
of research and development
they grew annual and perennial crops for
big-box retailers supplying the
Northeast United States his focus was on
rearing beneficial insects IPM protocols
disease testing and trialing new
genetics from around the world he
recently received his master's in
horticulture from Virginia Tech where he
did some work around LED research in
regards to sole source supplemental and
photo periodic lighting this resulted in
equipping irrigation booms with lights
for photo periodic flowering
applications to a controlled environment
where he propagated over 1.2 million
perennials from stage 3 tissue culture
per year he also has a Bachelors of
Science from Clemson University in this
podcast we go over a bit of the history
of lighting as it relates to growing
plants as well as the future of lighting
and what exciting research is currently
done in the industry all right hey guys
I really want to thank you today for
coming out and chatting with me about
lighting well thank you for having us
yep Thank You Pat yeah so I think I get
started
finding out a little bit about your
background now we have two Travis's here
so maybe Travis Williams you can tell us
a little bit more about how you came to
the role that you have now yeah yeah
gladly so I spent about 13 years in high
tech marketing the last three of those
years have been with fluence and then
the decade before that was across
different industries and both high tech
and green tech everything from embedded
systems to alternative fuels all b2b
companies large and small with
accordance assist on efficiency and
really moving the world towards a more
sustainable efficient future with all
kinds of different technologies and then
about three years ago I started to see
the convergence of technology and
horticulture with vertical farming and
different technologies that were coming
online and that's really what spurred my
interest in looking at how to how to
take technology and make it very
applicable to our agriculture industry
and our food supply chain and so I
joined fluence about three years ago
when it was a BML horticulture small
small company back then about there was
about 10 of us and it's been a pretty
wild ride ever since quite quite a
different industry and the horticulture
lighting space than the industries of
the custom - those were very large
established industries with standards
and protocols and this has been kind of
like the Wild West so it's it's been
great to see it evolve even over the
last three years and I look forward to
seeing where it goes over there over the
next decade or so very cool and now the
other Travis came recommended me by
Suzanne Wainwright Evans the bug lady
she said if you want to talk to someone
about lighting she was she had she had
met you and said that you've just been
hired by fluence which worked out really
well since I'd already been talking
about having someone from fluence on can
you talk briefly about what your
background is
sure it would be happy to so the past
five years I've worked in the ornamental
market so like annuals perennials and
flowering crops and what I did there is
I worked for a commercial greenhouse in
Virginia and I directed their research
and development so we did everything
from rearing of microorganisms for bio
controls to using light in multiple
environments controlled environments
supplemental I'm using it on you know
different machinery for photo period and
flowering to introducing new products to
market new genetics new varieties
trialing them in the greenhouse in the
landscape so I wore many hats let's just
say in that regard to to what my role
was they're very cool I I'm new to
lighting this isn't my area of expertise
by any means so I may ask some really
dumb questions I learned a lot at photo
X this past year in terms of lighting
but just for listeners who aren't as
experienced with lighting can we go over
some of this the basic terminology that
people should know when it comes to
understanding horticultural lighting
yeah yeah absolutely and and yeah I
think this is probably the foundation
where everything starts and it's um it's
widely overlooked and it's widely I
think misunderstood in this industry so
most industries you look at people when
they're evaluating something and they're
looking at maybe making a big purchase
or changing something in their in our
factory they physically know the
terminology and they know the metrics
that they're using what I've found in
this industry is that lighting is
largely misunderstood and largely
unknown and so people have been making
purchase decisions cultivation decisions
but without really understanding the key
requirements and so education is a large
part of what we do and I'll kind of go
over maybe about five key terms that I
think it's if some growers could
understand these five things it'll not
only make them you know better in the
garden but then when it comes time to
actually making a purchase decision you
know they it can be an educated one so
the first one I'll start off with is
called par PA are it's an acronym for
photosynthetically active radiation and
that really defines the spectrum of
light that plant to use for
photosynthesis from 400 to 700
nanometers so if you look at light light
is electromagnetic radiation it's
everything from gamma rays to radio
waves and par is a very narrow band kind
of kind of in the middle it also aligns
with the visual spectrum so plants and
humans both use the same spectrum of
light and use a completely different
than plants and we actually perceive it
differently so where our eyes or you
know really skewed towards the green
portion of the spectrum plants use 400
to 700 nanometers almost equally but but
differently and so when you're when
you're looking at light the quality of
light really has an impact on plant
growth in development so you know par is
a type of spectrum so I'm sure you know
a lot of people refer to spectrum and
spectrum absolutely has an impact on you
know plant growth and development so
whether something is heavy in red heavy
and blue heavy in green have been orange
whether it includes UV or far red it
allows really have an impact on plant
growth and development so that's par
that's the that's the quality of light
that you're looking at and then you have
the the intensity of light and that's
defined as PPF another acronym stands
for photosynthetic photon flux and that
is the amount of light within the PAR
region that is emitted by a light
fixture so the total amount of photons
that are emitted between 400 nanometers
that will give you the the PPF of a
light fixture then then the next step
there is to add the the density to that
so you get ppfd
and that's going to help a bro or really
know how much intensity is being
delivered to their crop so that's um
that's measured in microns per square
meter per second and that's going to
tell you the light intensity at any
given point in time in your crop and you
can measure that with a quantum sensor
you can also get lighting designs we
provide lighting design federal gives
growers
of what they're going to be receiving
the other the other measurement that's
important is wattage and I know that's a
that's a pretty sticky topic that we'll
probably get into later but you know
what it is really the measurement of
electricity input it's how much power a
light fixture is consuming measured in
watts a one Joule per second so you know
wattage doesn't tell you anything about
how how powerful or how high-performing
a fixture is in terms of light output
really it's just a matter of you know
what is your electric bill going to be
at the end of the day how many amps are
you going to be consuming for a light
fixture so it's definitely a critical
requirement in knowing from that regard
but in terms of plant growth it's not
going to tell you anything and then the
final one is efficacy that's measured in
Michael Moore for jewel and and I use
the analogy of miles per gallon you know
it's really going to tell you how how
efficient a fixture is so if you're
trying to determine what the difference
is between you know a two lighting
systems from different manufacturers
that maybe both consume 500 watts but
they have different claims you really
want to look at the efficacy of that
fixture and understand you know how
efficient is that fixture at converting
electrons into photons so just so I'd
make sure I understand all these terms
correctly myself yeah when we talk about
ppfd you're talking about light
intensity so how much photons and the
density of those photons or Haiti are
going to be actually hitting your canopy
or your your plant down below and when
the correct when you talk about par
you're looking at spectrum like when I
walk into a hydro shop and see you know
a [ __ ] deluxe bulb or an analog bulb on
the shelf and they have those charts on
the back with the red and the green
spikes that's your power level in terms
of the spectrum that you're getting am I
saying yeah to degree you are you have
you have ppfd down now when it comes to
par in spectrum it gets it gets a little
more complicated because within par you
can have different allocation of the
percentage of light you can have for
example a grower could have a thousand
ppfd
on one section of their canopy and they
can have a thousand ppfd on another but
they can have two completely different
spectrums of lights so maybe one is
influenced in this a broad spectrum it's
more of a white light for the eye and
then another one could be kind of that
magenta color that I think is more
typical of what people think of one I
think about 80 fixtures so the the the
light intensity the ppfd could be the
same but how how that's being generated
in terms of the spectrum could be
completely different so one might be 80%
red and 20% blue and then that's going
to have an impact on the plane
development in terms of the allocation
of the spectrum looking that intensity
okay that makes sense and then watch
just like you said how much electricity
you're using it doesn't really tell you
how efficient that light is so what part
of that process is I understand it is
your ballast is going to be generating
some level of heat or putting off energy
and other forms other than photons which
is really not what we want in most cases
as I understand it so that the more
efficient light is the more of that
electricity is being translated directly
into photons is that correct yeah that's
correct I mean in a perfect world you
would have one electron coming coming
out of the wall off of the grid and
being transferred and converted into one
Photon
right the one the quantum of electricity
one the quantum of light but you know
that would be impossible to do so you're
going to have efficiency losses along
the way in those efficiency losses take
shape and all kinds of manners right
some some efficiencies are lost in heat
through thermal management some losses
are on the on the circuit board and then
you have a matter of you know how a
fixture is designed to cool itself and
some fixtures have active cooling
systems with fans and those fans require
electricity to run right so you're going
to have you're going to have efficiency
losses there so at the end the day when
you're looking at efficiency the goal is
to have as as high of efficiency as
possible so that you can reduce the loss
and then like that makes me think
another
doctor would then be how uniform those
photons are being sent to create a
canopy or a stamp down below the light
fixture itself I was gonna say
unfortunate as a podcast so I don't have
any visuals you know when you start
talking about uniformity a visual is
really helpful for people to see what
that would look like but you're
absolutely right I mean and this comes
back to why I think horticultural
lighting has such a bad reputation and
that you can you can see how complicated
this all can get and then you can see
how you can really play with numbers and
play with things to to trick customers
or consumers into thinking they're
getting something that they're actually
not where if you took a really small
bright light fixture over you know let's
say a four by four and you were able to
get you know let's say a thousand ppfd
well you're going to be targeting that
over say one square foot right in the
middle but your average across the the
canopy is going to be the same as if you
distributed that light nice and uniform
and we all know a nice uniform canopy
it's going to UM it's going to produce
better results for for a lot of
different reason could you give a little
bit of a history in terms of sort of
where lighting is where it started and
sort of where we are now in terms of
these different technologies like metal
halides CMH LED HPS yeah yeah and you
know the history of lighting for growing
relatively corresponds to the history of
lighting in general so if you kind of
look back at the history of lighting I
think in a larger time scale it's
relatively new technology I mean
incandescent light was really formed
around the early 1900s that's and what's
scary is if you look at that you know I
remember growing up it was the same
light bulbs that that we used in our
house until you know pretty recently
that's gonna really inefficient
technology and then you move to
fluorescent lighting which is still very
much used in the in the growing industry
today and that was developed in the
1930s
again the undies were all developed for
industrial applications high pressure
sodium in the 70s and 80s and that was
designed for street lamps mineral halide
in the 60s same thing automotives
streets industrial uses obviously
different spectrum each PS you know has
that orange glow to it metal halide has
that that crisp cool white look to it
and then LEDs started to come around in
the in the 60s as well in the visible
spectrum as semiconductors at large
started to proliferate and and become
more integrated in computers and so
along that way I think if you look at
the history of of lighting in in
agriculture you know I think we all have
to give obtunded credit to the cannabis
industry where for for helping advance
that and and really help set some of the
the operating procedures and and what
what what we're using today we're given
the legislation of cannabis and how
growers weren't able to you know plow a
field and put it out in the open they
weren't they weren't able to you know
build a greenhouse that everybody could
see they were forced into warehouses
they were forced into garages and in
closets and well there's no sunlight
there right so you had to rely on social
source lighting and high pressure sodium
was a great technology for that it was
extremely bright extremely high
performance the efficacy the energy
efficiency was phenomenal at the time
you know fluorescent fixtures were below
1 micromolar per Joule and then all of a
sudden high pressure sodium was getting
up to 1.7 in fact high pressure sodium
was the most energy-efficient highest
efficacy lighting system until just a
few years ago everybody thinks that LEDs
are just intrinsically energy efficient
and obviously over the last few years
we've made tons of advancements and so
it's not even really close anymore but
that's been a very recent development so
you can kind of track the history of
general lighting too
the history of groaning and one of the
one of the things that you know most
people kind of ask well what's the
difference between and grow light and
I'm a regular light that you would use
in your house and until recently with
with LEDs the answer was nothing right
people would take the same HPS lamp that
was used in a street lamp or a parking
garage they'd put it in a in a warehouse
I mean can grow plants with it
LEDs now give us the flexibility to
design custom custom light intensities
custom spectrum for plant growth and so
it's no longer taking something that was
built for a highway and then having to
tailor all of your other procedures
around that light to make it ideal you
know changing your irrigation your
fertigation nutrient schedule optimizing
your HVAC around something that was
never designed specifically for our
plans and now we can take light and
specifically design it for a plant and
so it's no longer kind of that limiting
threshold when I was first starting to
grow I the sin of the industry standard
was metal halide for veg and HPS for
flower and then these so-called new
technologies would show up like Ellie
sees is something I'm seeing a lot of
these days that people are recommending
are using and double-ended fixtures with
HP S is a relatively new idea as well
can you just touch a little bit on what
some of the differences are between
between these and a little bit more
detail for listeners yeah so LEC is a
marketing term that ceramic metal halide
companies used as LED started to become
a little bit more popular which i think
is you know from their perspective kind
of smart right so you had LEDs coming
online which everybody associated LEDs
with new and I tech and innovative a lot
of other people associate them with a
lot of other words right as well in
terms of underperforming high costs all
of that but at the end of the day LED
was associated with something kind of
new and cutting-edge and so to associate
certain McMinn halide with the same you
know they just started coming out with
LEC so the
that's kind of where you get that name
from and then double-ended HPS from from
a growing perspective the the advantage
there is really all around energy
efficiency and higher performance you
know so you're moving from single ended
to double ended where it changed the
cultivation technique quite a bit when
you start to increase efficiencies and
you're able to get higher light output
you went from hoods where the single
ended might have been much closer to the
canopy to get a higher light intensity
so you had air-cooled hoods and then you
were able to move the double ended up
higher than the ceiling you could remove
some of the different HVAC requirements
so it did change it changed the
landscape quite a bit when they
introduced double ended and then when
you look at you know why why growers
were typically using metal halide for
veg and HPS for bloom you know that was
based on I think I'm not gonna call it
rudimentary research but research at the
time that was really looking at spectrum
and so there was a lot of people at the
time associated you know more blue
content a little more compact plants and
metal halide has more blue content than
HPS and then more red and far red
content with flower development and so
that's where you started to see the use
of those two now with with more research
and and the ability to fine tune
spectrum with all these I mean down to
the nanometer we can do research that
we've never been able to do before to
really look at you know is how truthful
is it that that do we makes a more
compact plant and we've done research
before where we've actually grown
cannabis under various spectral light
and I think we ran one that was about
five different samples of different
spectra of light and the plant that
actually was veg that was the had the
longest internode spacing it stretched
the most was the plant that was actually
grown under blue light and so then you
have to start to look at his entourage
aspect of spectrum and how how does blue
light integrate with the other spectrum
of light to get what we see
a more compact plan so it's not just
what we think of as more blue light
because you take blue light and isolate
it and it does the opposite of what you
think you would do so is sunlight still
the king in this arena I hear everyone
say that nothing beats the Sun and I
could see where if we're taking lighting
technologies that are not designed for
agriculture for growing plants and just
using them to grow plants that might be
the case but without getting you know
too far into different spectrums
how does sunlight compare because I know
your light for example is a white light
you know CMH or LEC since they're the
same thing they're they're more of a
white light as well is that sort of full
spectrum or you know rather than going
with these you know more orange red
colors or blue green or purple like the
magenta color you mentioned with with
LEDs what's the what's the comparison
between all of this I guess I will try
to be succinct in answering this so if I
go too long to stop me because it's a
fascinating topic and I think this is
really where you start talking about
spectrum and optimization
we're just getting started not only just
you know we fluence we as a species are
just getting started to really
understand how plants use light and how
we can use light as a tool to elicit
certain responses out of plants and so
you know to answer your question is the
Sun still King I don't know you at the
end of the day we've had customers that
have traditionally grown crops outdoors
or in a greenhouse using sunlight
they've moved to our systems and they
say it's the most flavorful crop they've
ever grown what the Sun does is you know
it provides everything right it provides
every spectrum of light that a plant
could want some of it is good and some
of it is harmful you know when you start
looking at ultraviolet light for example
ultraviolet has some very compelling
tendencies to elicit positive responses
and plans but it can also be very
damaging it's a stressor and stresses
the plant and so if you're stressing a
plant at a time when you want to be
maximizing its growth
that's going to be a negative response
that you're going to want to avoid after
providing for red light at the at the
wrong time the crops development cycle
again it could be it could be
detrimental so I think what we really
need to do is take you know take the
grower and say what are your goals you
know what are you trying to accomplish
with this crop and then take light and
use that as a tool to help them
accomplish it it's it's not a
one-size-fits-all approach it's we're
working with universities and we ran
research with the University of
Tennessee looking at phytonutrients and
looking at different compounds and how
can we how can we take these critical
compounds that can be used in
pharmacology that that natively can only
be you know maybe 0.3% of of a crop and
I think the crop earlier study was bill
looking at a compound for to help people
with vision and it natively was you know
very small doses plant but how could we
use widen so we looked at various social
source spectrum going from really
looking at the difference between 400
nanometers and 405 nanometers and 420
nanometers I mean the differences
between these are are in comprehensively
small but when you look at the results
of what that does to a plant and how
that affects the chemical compositions
of these plants it's quite dramatic the
most interesting thing that we saw was
that you can you can use light to
increase the chemical composition of the
plant target those specific
photoreceptors that are responsible for
that development and increase increase
the percentage of that compound but it
came at a cost of yield so the plants
biomass overall was lower in so that's
that's where I come back and I have to
say what is your goal as a grower all
right maybe we can use light to increase
THC content or CBD content but is that
gonna come at a cost of overall yield
and as companies are moving more towards
extracts and they're starting to isolate
these compounds and identify really what
they're targeting the answer might be
yes or no so again very early stages I
think the most fascinating thing is
right now we're creating these tools
that are going to give researchers the
ability to conduct research that they've
never been able to do
were in fact when I joined fluence 30
years ago we still had a lot of research
partners in academia that we're using
theatrical stage lighting filters over
HPS to conduct this type of research
which is not exactly as precise as you
would like it to be
Wow so I've always been a soil person
and I've always turned to soil as a way
of improving or affecting you know
terpene expression the odors and flavors
of my crop through manipulating minerals
or the biological aspects of a soil but
as I understand it and from seeing some
of your research at photo X and other
places essentially lighting spectrum and
lighting intensity can have an effect as
well on how a plant expresses not just
its growth but also it's it's different
phytonutrients as well is that correct
that's absolutely correct and I might
let the other Travis chime in here too
you know I'll just kind of tee it up
with with you look at the role of
lighting in plants it's there's really
two main aspects that that light impacts
that it's ones in growth and one is in
development and if you kind of take a
step back and say what is what is light
you know what are we talking about here
light has a duality nature to it it's
really two things it's an energy and
it's a particle and so if you look at
the energy of the plan and its impact
that it has on growth that's that's
really where intensity comes into play
so then if you look at the particle and
that's really going to be the wavelength
of light that goes back to the spectrum
of light plants have hundreds of
photoreceptors a lot of them are unknown
and those photoreceptors are all
responsible for different things within
that plant so you might have a
photoreceptor that's that's designed to
take in say 460 nanometers 370
nanometers whatever that might be
and then that's going to trigger that
plant to do something particular with
that with that wavelength of light we
we've been fascinated with chlorophyll
you know if you look at chlorophyll a
and B all right those are probably the
two most popular pigments and
photoreceptors of a plan they're largely
responsible for photosynthesis
and they both align with red and blue
wavelengths of light so that's where you
see this uprising of magenta and pink
lighting the problem is we need when you
solely isolate those photoreceptors
you're neglecting hundreds of other
photoreceptors that are responsible for
nutrition flavor structural development
so going back to your question you know
looking at an intern odo spacing of a
plant and everything else you can you
can absolutely optimize that with light
and it's pretty fascinating so it's kind
of like you know you're a soil guy right
until you're asking is the Sun the best
source of light it's kind of like
looking at soils like well if you went
out and you know dug a hole and some
really rich fertile ground even if it
wasn't say in Salinas Valley or
something is that going to be the best
soil for a plant or could you optimize
it in a way to get a better response
yeah so one of the things about the Sun
as I understand it is over the course of
the summer the the Sun spectrum changes
slightly and people have made the
argument that plants a plant for example
like look if we're talking cannabis in
this case it may be you know half a post
solstice solstice as it starts to flower
and that lighting spectrum I believe is
in the Sun is going towards more of a
red spectrum that because the cannabis
plant or you know all annual flowering
plants would be used to this slight slow
change in spectrum that the sunlight
gives that's our baseline for optimal
and then they try and recreate this with
lighting technology is there any is
there any foundation or research to
support any of that that's if I can come
in now yeah that's a good question um
yeah it's it's interesting cuz you can
you know you can track the plant back to
its native habitat right try to draw
conclusions based on where it originated
to try to figure out how best to make it
flower do whatever you you know if you
would like it to do but at the end of
the day you know there's that there
there's other environmental factors
obviously at play aside from just light
so for some annual crops you can Trump
the photoperiod response for flowering
with temperature right so for example
like with um with garden mums they're
also a short-day crop similar to
cannabis so they flower under short days
and you welcome under long days but
let's say that you're growing them in a
late summer and the days start to
shorten and you would think flower
initiation would go on but you have a
very hot late summer that heat will
delay your flowering no matter to light
quality no matter the duration of the
day the temperature is automatically
trumped your hour initiation the same
can go in relation to light intensity
and photo period so when a short day no
matter the spectrum is supposed to
trigger flowering if you have excessive
light levels but a short day the light
level could trump the response you're
looking for from a short day so I think
there's there's so many other ways to
come at it they're just taking
assumptions perhaps on where it's native
to that makes sense
yeah and that brought up a couple other
questions so one I just want to
highlight when you say photo period
that's a new term that we haven't talked
about yet you're talking about the
amount of the amount of time that the
plant is receiving light is that correct
exactly so I'll compliment on what
Travis said on some of the basic terms
and so when you think about light he
mentions you have three things to think
about you have duration like quality the
spectrum and then intensity so when
we're talking about duration this is the
amount of time that the light is
actually in contact with the plant right
so the amount of time the plan is
exposed to the light is a term called
photo period and photo period is key in
multiple physiological processes but one
of the main ones specifically for
cannabis obviously is vegetative growth
of bulking branching and then flowering
growth so yes
photo period is just duration of light I
brought up a couple other questions that
I've had for years and wanting to know
the answer to so what is optimal in
terms of vegetative growth
I hear people some people say that
plants need a dark cycle I hear other
people and I read an article recently
that showed the benefits
24-hour light cycle have you seen any
research on optimal levels I even saw a
really crazy 13 hour flowering charter
14 hour I can't remember correctly that
someone set up or where Lighting's going
on for two hours and off for an hour
always of supposedly maximizing the
amount of light that the plant can take
in over a given
I think it's D Li daily lighting or
what's the term exactly for the amount
of light a plant can take up over a
given period of time
sure it's called a D Li so a daily light
integral and so this is the amount of
light accumulated during a 24 hour
period and so to go to your question is
there a specific sweet spot for let's
say vegetative growth I would say there
there's not yet you can optimize your
environment to be working 24 hours a day
but it's not just due to the photo
period and it's not just due to light
quality and light intensity all of these
other environmental factors such as co2
humidity soil and root temperature leaf
temperature air flow you know
transpiration ready nutrients all of
these all of these are going to fall
into play in combination or even
complimenting your light levels in your
photo period so the fun thing I see
coming from a greenhouse background now
that we're able to focus in on
controlled environments we have the
ability to have precision over every
single environmental factor and with
that we're going to find multiple ways
to achieve the same thing because like I
said with flowering temperature can
manipulate flowering sometimes just as
much as photo period so I think there's
many different ways to go about it
but in regard to just basic flowering
physiology a long day for cannabis does
help with bulking getting you that that
carbohydrate buildup in order to you
know burst out flowers once it's started
flat our initiation under short days so
but I think that's something not only
can
an abyss but also controlled
environments with you know flowering
crops vegetables we're gonna find
multiple ways with all of these
environmental attributes to get to
similar goals in sad if I could chime in
on this too because I think what Travis
is hitting on is you know kind of we're
hitting we're moving into this kind of
new world of crop production with
controlled environment agriculture and
you can look at things from a business
standpoint from a commercial standpoint
and you look at all the different ways
that you can do something so you know
whether you're using temperature to
control stem elongation or you're using
light you know you really want to look
at what's the most economical way to do
that which one is going to have the
lowest operating cost if they must have
come both accomplish the same thing and
if you look at if you look at lighting
and you were talking about you know the
period of darkness and the spectrum of
light that's where we're we're currently
underway with a lot of research looking
at can you achieve a DLI that is as far
as we know say optimal for cannabis they
say you can achieve a 35 DOI for
cannabis if you could achieve that in a
eight-hour period versus a 12-hour
period could you then have a longer dark
cycle where maybe your HVAC isn't
running as hard or maybe you're using
peak grid energy less so you're paying
less for that energy while you're still
accomplishing the same yield that you
would otherwise and I think that's where
things are going to be fascinating from
a business perspective least our copter
optimized operations and look at how we
can use these these techniques and then
when it comes to spectrum as well
you know there's a lot of research
looking at the phytochrome photo
equilibrium and the read too far read
ratio and what impact that has on
flowering can you trick a plant because
the the photo period isn't actually
controlled by the amount of day that the
plant receives it's controlled by the
amount of darkness that ever sees it so
can you actually you know maybe run your
lights and flower for 18 hours and trick
your plant into thinking that it had
that
night cycle so that you can maximize
yield I think that's where things will
get quite fascinating
now you guys presented some far-red
research last year at the conference can
you just touch a little bit on how some
of these lighting you know more unique
lighting spectrums that are more
specialized and some of the effects that
they're those are having on plant growth
hmm Travis I don't know if you have
anything that you'd want to talk about
I'm trying to think of anything that I
could that I could share right now well
I I will say that before I worked with
fluence or started working at fluence I
worked with them on a project using
different different read too far read
ratios for flowering of multiple you
know perennial generous and what what we
did learn is that you know as Travis
State each plant has you know within
within the understanding of how plants
take in light they have something called
a photo equilibrium and cytochrome and
all these photoreceptors and so certain
photo receptors you know perceive a lot
of these wavelengths that trigger
flowering or trigger certain growth
attributes that we're looking for and so
if I could just say anything on it is
you know the more precise we get on some
of these Sol you know I guess you could
just say pigments that were applying on
the plants we're going to have just
precise growth attributes that we'll be
able to trigger during different
different stages of production if
anything we're learning that and also in
regard to let's say you know leafy
greens and herbs and we could learn from
this industry but they're they're using
you know different different like
quality so let's say red or blue light
towards the end of production to enhance
certain phytonutrients or even using UV
like we stated before to provoke certain
compounds that are desirable but you
don't grow with that spectrum the whole
time during production you just apply it
for a two-hour period every day for the
last week of production so I know that I
know our research team is working on
some things in that regard but you know
all these industries are linked so one
thing we learn they're all plants how
can they how can we bring it all
together at the end so you know although
bond that with what's specific to
cannabis I think exactly what what
Travis descended with is we can learn a
lot from different crops and apply those
same techniques across the across the
different species and but even within
within the same family so if you look at
cannabis we're an AUV trial with three
different strains of cannabis and each
one reacted differently one we were able
to increase the THC content with with UV
light one it didn't really seem to have
an impact and one it had a detrimental
impact and so from you know going back
from a marketing perspective right now
fluid sells UV light but you will not
see us advertising these is like a THC
booster or anything like that because it
depends on your genetics it also depends
on how you use that light and so we
still have so much to learn before we
can start to advise on how to use some
of these tailored tailored spectra to a
list of those specific results so
essentially what I'm getting from this
is that these really specific spectrums
can have a have an impact or a fairly
dramatic impact on the health and growth
of a plant but the research just hasn't
been established enough to really make
any broad assertions about about that
sort of thing at this point does that
sound right it does it doesn't if you
think about how some of these studies
are conducted whether they're you know
with with certain lighting vendors or
they're with the university let's say
that you have you know you have a study
underway in your trialing a certain
spectrum with the same variety but you
have other set points like I said before
of these other environmental factors
that in a commercial setting could be
completely different so even though you
learn something from the study in regard
to the light spectrum you also need a
trial different conditions in regard to
all of these other environmental
conditions to make sure that it could be
a consistent result
yeah they're so they're just basically
hasn't been enough replication of any of
these studies to really draw any good
conclusions because like you mentioned
there's so many variables involved that
it's just really hard to know how how it
will go or how plants will respond under
slightly different environmental
conditions other than just the lighting
spectrum yep yep and I think I think
something that that benefits growers is
to have you know in the horticulture
space what is called grower trials and
this is where let's say a grower would
work with us and we could set up a trial
specific to their environment their
needs and then be able to let's say
recommend something specifically for
their goal because everyone else is
going to have a completely different
environment and now that we can tweak
every single one of these factors that
how you truly optimize
that's really cool I love that you guys
are doing that because I think that's
really what's lacking right now in this
industry is we're seeing a lot of claims
but not a lot of people doing controlled
research - they can we can actually
start drawing conclusions from so I'm
glad that you guys are adding to that
overall body of knowledge that's great
one thing you brought up that I wanted
to it kind of brought up a question and
me was as you know plant stress is is
not necessarily always a bad thing you
know you'll have that grower who always
had the crop that got neglected or got
pests or something happened and it ends
up being their highest highest highest
yielding and or you know highest THC
crop that they've grown and I know in
Italy I read a really cool article about
how the farmers would flood their tomato
fields with salt water at a certain
period during that plant's growth as a
way of stressing the plant creating a
you know forcing it to put its energy
into its fruiting and so that tomato had
you know better flavor in it for example
have you seen any ways or research
around lighting and plant stress in in
terms of optimization or ways that we
can maybe util
is lighting as a way of improving you
know bud quality or our flowers I'll
speak a little to this because I did
work work with you know plant stress in
general for part of my thesis but it's
interesting you know in regard to
flowering or fruiting you know when a
plant is under stress it's going to take
whatever energy it has and just
reproduce you know it's kind of like the
last resort if it's going to die it
might as well just reproduce right so
you can induce flowering through stress
and stress yes can be through lighting
and be you know either from I would
believe like quality and also light
intensity combined you could have
different stressors there but you can
also have you know certain responses
that also have different advantages to
them so like if you were to give a plant
let's just say an exposure of a harsh UV
wavelengths you could produce a certain
compound in the plant that attract
attracts predator insects and I know
there's been work done at Kansas State
Marquardt to this or that you give a
certain dose or high-intensity light
pulse and you can provoke certain
compounds in the root zone to be
resistant to pathogen you know entrance
into the soil so I don't know
specifically and Travis you may be able
to speak to this better than me but I
think plant stress has a place it's just
on how how do we approach it yeah Travis
did you want to add anything else to
that other Travis no I think I just
figured that self of what I was saying
around around UV light in that
absolutely you can use light as a
stressor and like you said stress has
its place in terms of benefits for crops
it's just really when it comes to
lighting we don't know and we can't
prescribe when that optimal time will be
so you know do we want to use it maybe
say during the Scotto period at night
and then watch the plant with some UV
light or do we want to do it during the
main flowering stage those are all the
research projects that
to take place and it's genetics specific
its environment specific we've ran more
trials than I can count where
unfortunately the data comes back
inconclusive because we will be running
say a UV trial to determine if we can
use UV light to you know increase the
quality of cannabis and then halfway
through the study you know the grower
will have an HVAC problem and so for
three days of that cycle their
temperature or their or their diff or
their RH is is completely out of sync
and so the results come back and you say
well are those results accurate or was
that a result of different environmental
conditions and you know get cannabis
flowering alone is you know a couple
months and then you have to add in the
time to cure the plant test the plant
and so each of these trials takes a few
months it takes about three or four
months and so if one you have one thing
to go out of step which typically do in
a commercial growing environment you
have to start all over so unfortunately
the the research process takes takes
quite a while yeah I'm excited though to
see where where this all takes us in
terms of plant stress because you are
opening up the door to for more
pathogens
poor poor growth or potentially less
yield depending on like other Travis
mentioned the types of stress or the
amount of stress it's it's like you're
towing this thin line that you don't
really know what's gonna set it off
either one way or another but I've never
heard of being able to give lighting
spectrum and actually affect the ability
of a plant to attract certain insects or
repel other pathogens I would I would
love to learn more about that well guys
learn more yeah and you know you hear me
talk about this it reminds me of you
know I'm not just looking at it as a
stressor but as a beneficiary outside of
outside of plant growth or development
we did a trial at the University of
Florida
basil downy mildew is probably the
number one issue with basil crop growers
and go use different techniques to help
prevent it and and keep it at bay
I think sulphur is is one of the most
prominent but we actually looked at
using different spectra of light and
concluded that we can use specific red
wavelength of light to suppress basal
down you know that and so when you start
looking at using light outside of just a
tool for photosynthesis or photo
morphogenesis we start looking at as a
part of your your IPM strategy then you
start to you know can start to look at
using light in a multitude of ways are
you guys working with anyone that's
using it right now for suppression of
powdery mildew or botrytis with cannabis
I know I did prior work for Kim
influenced using blue light in reference
to making fungus sports for tea late so
in certain cases some some spectrums
actually enhance you know spore spore
count in certain fungi which is which is
not a good thing and then also we did
work on using UVC to kill botrytis on
contact with certain Harmon goes is just
pulses but I think that research if
anything it's it's just now really
starting to be part of the conversation
market cultivation okay okay that's
really exciting I can't wait to hear
what you guys come up with in the next
few years so that's great I wanted to
get back to some of these questions I
had I'd written out before our talk that
we're sort of sort of basic but really
captured some of my questions from back
in the day and one of them was that I
always thought that LEDs in general were
too expensive and they seemed to produce
poor yields and I noticed more and more
improvements in the LED you know
lighting arena and that technology I
know when it first came out I always
said it was it just wasn't there yet do
you guys feel like we're there yet it
seems like we are can you just talk a
little bit about where we're at with
LEDs yeah so you're right they were too
expensive they didn't perform and you
know unfortunately it's created this
this negative impression for LED
technology in the horticulture space and
I mentioned you know or
not talking about my background I joined
fluence I left a fortune 500 company
where being in the marketing department
at a fortune 500 company it doesn't
matter who your bosses or what your
title was you reported to the legal team
you know everything that you that you
put on paper everything that you said
had to be run through legal and if there
was even one iota of some kind of claim
it had to be substantiated and proven
right so that we don't get sued in the
in the horticulture and lighting space
there was nothing there was none of that
I joined and I did a competitive
analysis and I was appalled at the
claims that these other lighting
companies were making that were
completely unsubstantiated now they we
have competitors that would just
literally put like guaranteed higher
yields and it's like okay well
guaranteed or what and if you give your
light to somebody that doesn't know the
first thing about growing how are you
going to guarantee that our yield you
know everybody I think was the the
highest performing LED or the highest
performing light everybody would you
know you'd have a 300 watt LED system
that would outperform a thousand watt
HPS and it was just it was appalling
then I told my boss Nick the CEO of the
company will never do that you know
we'll never do that we have to build
credibility let's take a different
approach and so it's been it's been an
uphill battle kind of going against the
headwind that led manufacturers created
probably going back to maybe five five
years ago or so where they would come in
and they would the technology was not
there the LEDs themselves were not
efficient enough they weren't powerful
enough the packages and then the people
that were building these quote-unquote
grow lights they a lot of them did not
know the ins and outs of horticulture
and so nowhere on their labels would you
see the PPF would you see the efficacy
would you see par maps that would show
you the light uniformity that they were
getting until you had buyers that were
buying things based off of claims and
hearsay in marketing that was that was
false I think the industry has become
much more
educated people are you know lighting is
continuing to evolve the commercial
horticulture industry is continuing to
evolve and so you're seeing I think more
respectful horticultural lighting
companies come out that are trying to do
things the right way and at the same
time the growing community is becoming
more educated which is only putting
pressure on on lighting companies to to
adapt to that and you're starting to see
more standards being being implemented
the the DLC the design light consortium
who typically have helped to build
standards and regulations in the
industrial space so that when you go to
buy a light for your home that you can
look on that box and it has all of the
critical specifications listed so you
know what you're buying they're now
working in the horticulture space and
they'll be coming out with a
specification that will help bring you
know more clarity to the growing
community so you'll have these standards
and in the lighting companies need to
start playing by the rules and it's not
going to be perfect when it starts you
know they're still going back to how
much is unknown it's there there will be
standards put in place that may hinder
growth if you kind of look at the pace
of innovation in the automotive or the
aerospace industry that is slow it's an
it's it goes at about a snail's pace
because of all the regulations and
standards that they have to conform to
so on one hand it's good because you
have a very high safety rating because
you're not just throwing in unproven
components on the other hand you know
the adoption of innovation is pre-k's
well and so I think horticulture
lighting has been kind of unregulated
just running loose and wild and it's
come at a detriment and the cost to the
growing community so getting some kind
of standards in place will will help us
so I hope that answer your question in
terms of the history and you know about
why we got here and ended to answer your
question absolutely we're here know you
know the the costs are continuing to go
down as tunnel Edie's continue to
proliferate in the underlying technology
behind them continues to proliferate and
then as you know companies like Bruins
start to become larger and we grow you
know the commodity of scale only helps
us reduce our pricing that we pass on to
customers and and I'd be remiss if I
didn't really acknowledge the the
cannabis industry for for fueling that
growth you know the food production
industry right now is is they don't have
the margins that cannabis has they don't
have the flexibility to take risks and
adopt new technology that cannabis has
because if they fail you know that could
be bankruptcy for them whereas the
cannabis industry you know I think
natively is risk takers more
entrepreneurs and they are helping to
adopt new AG tech that as those as those
technologies are proven as those
companies scale and grow and they're
able to reduce their pricing then the
food industry can look at it and say
okay that seems to be proven that seems
to be working and oh now the pricing is
dropping because these technologies are
being adopted on a more wide scale right
which ultimately if we can help the food
industry become more sustainable and
more efficient everybody wins
yeah I agree with everything he just
said I think that's wonderful I will say
that here in Washington and Oregon we're
seeing such a we're at a point now where
so much cannabis has been produced
relative to what's being consumed or
purchased that a lot of growers are
struggling and they're having a look to
look at ways at improving efficiency not
just from a lighting perspective but
from an overall business perspective and
here's where I think LEDs really shine
though there is still a higher cost of
entry it appears than say a double-ended
HPS what's and correct me if i'm wrong
seems to be the closest equivalent to a
well-made LED light but you more than
make that up in terms of the amount of
electricity and efficiency that you're
getting out of the LED fixture over the
life of that fixture is that correct
yeah and I will I will not hide from the
from the price of our pictures in fact
you know fluence is very open about the
pricing we don't we don't play games we
have standard pricing and
our fixtures on day one are absolutely
more expensive than high pressure sodium
the the onus is on us as a company to
make sure that our customers can get a
quick payback on these systems so it
cost me these are these are high-tech
systems right these are new technology
high-tech systems they cost more to
build the amount of people that go into
the research and the support behind them
costs more to support these and so the
price is higher but we look at from a
business standpoint energy efficiency
and lowering your utility bill are
absolutely you know something to look at
and consider the maintenance cost is
something to consider those are all
secondary to helping our customers
improve revenue you know looking at can
we help you increase your yield can we
help you increase your quality can you
help you maintain a better shelf-life or
consistency so that your forecasting is
better so that your your shrink is
reduced you have about you have less
loss crop loss we take in all of these
factors and we don't tell the customer
hey you're going to get 10% more yield
you're gonna get 5% more years you're
didn't get 20% we we don't tell them
that they're going to reduce their
shrink which hopefully Travis you can
you can talk about that as well from
this past company we don't tell them
that what we do is we try to show them
that that is all possible and then we
allow them to say you know what I think
you're right if I can get you know say
10% more light or 20% more light and I
can get these other factors I can reduce
my HVAC cost they plug it in the model
and they do a payback analysis and and
if we can't be efficient at providing a
payback within a time frame that is
suitable for our customers and we need
to go back and we need to adjust it but
I think if you look at the adoption of
fluence and the if you just look at the
ones in the adoption of the cannabis
industry both from home growers you know
hobbyists at home that are using one
light to the world's largest growers
that are using thousands of lights it's
clear that it makes sense for for
everybody large and small yeah you know
it's funny I was joking around when we
first started this podcast and I was
interviewing some
the people that I know in the canvas
industry that I consider to be
influencers like my buddy Jaya Palmer
David Bernard Peron uppity God
Nelson Linsley with poetry plants and I
told her I'm like guys I don't want this
to turn into affluence podcast because
we keep talking about their name when we
talk about lighting just because you
know what you guys are doing is very
innovative and you are doing a lot of
research to support the industry and I
think that's that's amazing I don't want
it there I don't want to sound like
there aren't other companies lighting
companies out there doing good good
things too in the industry and I think
that's important to highlight and I
think people just need to really do
their research and you've kind of given
us some tools here today with this
terminology and other other information
in terms of how to evaluate a light or a
lighting system but in your eyes what
what separates fluids from some of these
other lighting companies out there I'll
speak to that one so when I was on the
other side so I guess you could consider
me a buyer one thing that I did really
appreciate about fluency even though at
the same time I was trying multiple
other other lighting technologies for
one you know when it comes to a grower
that's making a large investment and you
know going through all of these
decisions and building a new new
controlled environment or green house or
whatever it may be when you have
somebody who can help you from from the
start not just in regard to lighting but
every other thing that you need to think
about in regard to photo biology and
plant physiology fluence was extremely
helpful and from that side of it I came
to respect fluence and hits why why I'm
here
as their director of cultivation support
now they care enough to have a whole
division that is meant to help the
grower learn how to maximize these
technologies while at the same time
appreciating and also learning about all
the other factors that influence plant
growth so to me that's of high value
with fluent you know I'll just take you
back on on that and kind of reiterate
you know really I think the intimacy
with our customers
and in our research partners in parallel
kind of having a vision that goes beyond
just having the best product you know if
you look at our products in terms of
their specifications they're world-class
they're great but that's that's short
term right so being able to work with
our customers understand the ins and
outs of their business what are their
goals you know how do they succeed and
how can we help them succeed you know
keeps us focused on moving forward and
not being complacent saying okay great
you know we just created a light that
that works
now let's know it's on them so you know
customer success has been from day one
our key focus you know what got me
excited about your company was the fact
that I heard that a large commercial
basil grower was using your using your
lights the fact that someone outside of
the cannabis industry and that you guys
were working with people in agriculture
was able to be profitable using using
your lighting technology I think is huge
you don't see that with a lot of
companies and the fact that you're doing
all this research with you know Cornell
and some of these other research
universities that are known for Ag is
really what sold me on your company yeah
that Dedham that's key you know all
these plants are connected whether we're
talking about basil cannabis petunias
you know a lot of a lot of what we learn
from one can be applied to the other so
we find about you in learning from
multiple life Goods industries instead
of just focusing on one where let's say
in some cases it could be limited on
what we learn yeah yeah and I would I'd
be remiss if I didn't talk about a study
that we're doing right now with dr.
Bruce Bugbee at Utah State University
he's a meeting plant physiologist and I
kind of talk about you know how much we
don't know right now and you know we
define par going back to the very
beginning of our conversation is 400 to
700 nanometers and the study we're doing
right now is to debunk that we're
actively looking to say is this true is
this knowledge that we are building on
true or or is there room for improvement
and so
by working with the growers and as the
commercial horticulture industry rapidly
evolved due to disruptions in technology
and growing populations at the same time
giving these researchers tools to
continue to you know give us the
knowledge to make them more efficient is
going to be I think radically changing
how people grow plants in the future I I
don't want to extend this podcast too
much longer because I've taken so much
of your day already but I did I did have
a question in terms of it made me think
of plant myths associated lighting so
one of the like we talked a little bit
about optimal veg photo periods and you
guys didn't give me like an exact
general recommendation but you kind of
explained why I'm wondering in terms of
like those green headlamps do plants see
that green light I've always heard that
they don't but does that have the pencil
potential to affect the health of your
crop people are using green lights to go
in during a dark cycle um no I would say
there's not I've not heard of that being
beneficial at all and and to me there
there is there is detrimental yeah that
anything you could possibly be
disturbing the photo period by having
any light on at all depending on your
other factors you know even though we
say photo periods triggered by far red
or red even if you have some other light
if it's at a certain intensity you could
still trigger a photo period response so
if you if you have a dark period you
know and like like Travis said you know
a lot of plants responses are due to
having the dark period as their
photoreceptor key I certainly would not
have any other lights in on during the
dark period yeah that if you if you look
at why people use green lights if they
have to go into a room when the lights
are all that comes from that
misconception that plants don't use
green light you know and so yeah it
that's where it comes from that's why
people choose green it's probably the
least disruptive but it's still much
other said it still would have an impact
especially given the duration and
intensity that you go in there with so
obviously I don't think people are
seeing any death
when they go in there with their little
headlamps but if you were to turn on
high-intensity green lamps in there
during the and this little period you
absolutely would see an impact so that
just kind of made me wonder are there
any other sort of like lighting myths or
sort of established things in the
industry that you guys have found to
just not be very accurate well I would
use this time to simply say watts per
square foot I know that's not like total
biology related but using watts per
square foot to try to determine you know
how much how much light you needed not
accurate so so what should we be using
ppfd okay
one other question that reminded me of
was when I first started looking at
lights people were using the term lumens
but that's not something you guys have
mentioned once in this talk can you can
you touch on that real quickly
Travis I'll mention one thing here so
that it
there's many terms out there also
depending on where you are in the world
on how you how you refer to to light in
general and so let's say in early in the
horticultural industry there they were
fertilized foot candles right and this
was based on what you could see you know
so you made your judgment based on what
you could visually see and what we've
learned with LEDs is we can trust what
we what we see we have to trust in the
technology now because it's surpassed
our our ability to just perceive exactly
what's going on so some of these units
of measure in some ways are I don't know
if you could call them legacy units of
measure but we we've surpassed them with
our understanding so we now use ppfd and
micromoles you know as a common cohesive
understanding of light or light
specifically for biological processes
and plants yep except yeah so we all
need to be on the same page instead of
terminology is what you're saying so
that we can compare apples to apples
exactly that and making sure we're using
the right the right terminology for the
right application so light is used for
many things and if you're trying to
determine you know what lighting is best
for your plants but you're using
human-based metrics for vision things
will be will not go well and you could
just take if you take a ceramic metal
halide fixture that has a really cool
white visual appeal to it and then you
take say our spectrum which has a very
similar similar look to the human eye
they look very similar now if you look
at them on a spectral radiometer in
terms of how planes perceive them
they're dramatically different so it's
just making sure that you're using the
right metrics based on the the
appropriate application that's a really
good point because you're right they do
look very similar to me and I don't
always think about the fact that there's
a lot going on that I can't see so I
guess where I would kind of wanted to
finish up this podcast with and maybe
other Travis I could we can talk again
about some of your background in terms
of environmental controls I'd love to
have you back on to talk more about that
because I know you're a wealth of
knowledge there but where do where do
you guys see the future of lighting
headed I know we've touched on some of
these different things that are
obviously that we're not there yet on
but is there anything else in terms of
where we're going with lighting well me
and Travis have actually spoken about
this a few times and so my understanding
especially after coming to fluence now
is the next step with you know with
light in general for plant applications
is to have you know kind of intelligent
lighting systems right so so every
single one of your factors are all
controlled together and cohesively
Travis I'll let you elaborate more on
that topic yeah I think um you know you
got you have to look at the future I
think I look at it in two different ways
kind of the immediate future
you know maybe within the next five
years and then the quote-unquote distant
future you know five 15 years from now
which will probably become much quicker
than any of us expect but if you look at
the immediate future it's definitely
going to be about continued efficiencies
in the in the platform lower costs you
increase performance really fine-tuning
spectrum as we unlock more research and
and getting the the pieces of the puzzle
built for intelligence so when you look
at you know the Internet of Things and
you look at connectivity and you look at
Big Data you look at everything that
we're doing and are personalized with
computing and smart homes a networking
bringing that into the garden to make
things more efficient I think will be
here relatively soon and then you can
start to automate the garden you can
start to bring a level of intelligence
and sophistication to it that we we've
never had before in our food supply
chain and and so the other Travis and I
were talking about this a couple weeks
ago especially as it relates to his role
which is you know fluence right now is
taking very much an educational approach
really trying to educate our customers
on photo biology and horticulture
lighting and educating our customers
across the spectrum I mean that's
Travis's job is to help out with all
these other factors outside of lighting
the interplay of lighting and I think
soon you know our role is going to shift
from and I think academia and the
industry large will shift from educating
growers on you know how to how to spec
botrytis how to detect a nitrogen
deficiency to how to manage a robot that
does that how to program a system that
can detect that and then maintain those
systems so you're gonna see a whole
shift and lighting will definitely be a
component of that an integral component
of that as more intelligence that's
brought to the department that's
exciting and I love what you guys are
doing so I just want to say thank you
for taking the time to do this I I
really enjoyed this podcast I learned a
lot myself even just chatting with you
guys about some of the some of the
direction the Lighting's heading it's
really exciting so thank you both
Travis's and I would love to do a
follow-up podcast if you're open to it
on some of the environmental controls
around lighting and how important they
are if that if you're open to it sure no
I'd be happy to okay great well thanks
again and I look forward to talking to
you guys
soon I said he didn't appreciate it that
was Travis Williams and Travis
Higginbotham both with fluence
bioengineering manufacturers of LED
lighting for the horticultural industry
their website is fluence dot science or
you can type fluence lighting into
google and it will be the first link
fluence is spelled f l u e and c e you
are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget
that there's more information and
articles available on our website and
blog at WWE and calm as well as links to
the data and information we discussed in
this episode on the podcast page thanks
for listening