[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge don't
forget to subscribe to the podcast and
leave us a rating in review you can also
sign up for our newsletters on our
website as it's the best way to find out
when new episodes and blog post come out
as well as any discounts or coupon codes
our guest this week is Chris Jagger
Chris is the owner operator of blue fox
farm a 40 acre organic vegetable farm in
the Applegate Valley of Southern Oregon
he is also the owner and head consultant
for blue fox agricultural services a
full-service agricultural supply and
consultation company focusing on
ecological solutions for the modern
farmer both his farm and his
agricultural services used living soils
as a foundation to scale farming
operations efficiently and affordably he
rounds out his involvement with the
agricultural community by hosting the
living soil symposium each March the
symposium is an interactive conference
for farmers interested in regenerative
farming techniques to exchange knowledge
and gain insight in a peer-to-peer
environment all right thanks Chris I
really appreciate you coming on the show
today thanks dad yeah I wanted to start
off giving listeners a little bit of
your background sure yeah
my wife and I have Blue Fox farm in
Southern Oregon and we grow a variety of
mixed vegetables on about 40 acres we
have about 15 acres in production the
last couple years and we've been down
here for about 16 years now and we've
got two kids that were raising as well
two boys we really we focus a lot on
direct sales to the customers that we
have through farmers markets directed
co-ops and that kind of stuff and then
also I've the founder of the living soil
symposium that were in our third year
this year
and that besides a couple other side
projects that I have kind of take up
most of my time so how did you get into
farming before you moved to Oregon I we
talked a little before the podcast and
you had started out in California
mentioned yeah we started in Santa Cruz
in the late 90s that was right at the
very beginning of when organics really
started taking off and the local
movement was just starting to you know
gain its footing and so we started
interning on farms there and just
working in the fields picking
strawberries picking beans you know just
that that grind doing the work and then
we ended up moving to Colorado and
interning there on a couple farms and
then my wife and I ended up managing one
of the farms that she hadn't turned on
for a couple years and that really gave
us our chops as far as how to how to be
managers not just farmers so then you
moved out to Oregon and I know you
bought some land there and expanded and
have kind of gone through some growing
pains can you talk a little bit about
your background with cannabis sure yeah
my background with cannabis it's it's
been a very loose relationship over the
years I haven't actively been a grower
but I've been surrounded by a really
strong community here in Southern Oregon
of cannabis growers and I've always been
supportive of what they're doing and
we've all interacted with each other
over the years and kind of shared tips
because it's all agriculture so we've
all wanted to figure out what we can do
to help each other that's that's really
my my relationship has been as a support
to that industry as it's grown and
changed yeah and you brought up
something that I know we're both big
proponents of which is that cannabis and
agriculture are should be one in the
same in a lot of ways that we can pull a
lot of great information and Technology
and stuff from the farming community and
from agriculture that already exists we
don't need to reinvent the wheel here
and Brae yes you know cannabis is a
special plant in a lot of ways in terms
of its medicinal values but that doesn't
mean that we can't cultivate it in some
in a similar fashion I know that
you mentioned to me off air that you've
started you had your first year growing
hemp which is in a lot of ways similar
to cannabis can you talk a little bit
about that experience yeah for sure that
was really exciting to take that project
on I looked at it as really a proof of
concept my approach for it was to try to
grow the hemp crop exactly how I would a
vegetable crop so I been working on
building my soil fertility in my soil
biology up over the last several years
working this ground and I I had a
special spot that I knew I wanted to put
the crop in just it's the area that I've
done the most work on and I I said well
I want to be able to grow this just like
I grow a kale crop and I want to see if
I can have success from that and I also
wanted to grow it without having to put
a lot of hand labor into the plot I
wanted to be able to just grow it on
scale just as a way to look at how we
might scale up production so we did all
of the work with as far as bed prep goes
with our tractors the same the same
bedding system that we use in a kale
crop we use the same fertility program
that we use with our kale crops we
transplanted it mechanically with a
waterwheel transplanter and we set it up
in a way with a bed system where we were
able to cultivate with our tractors
throughout the entire lifecycle so we
had an empty alleyway between the rows
where then we could cultivate on either
side once it got taller and bigger and
we started with an overhead irrigation
system and we irrigated overhead all the
way up until the second week of flower
and then we transferred to a drip tape
after that and so it was just really
interesting to watch the season progress
and see how amazing these plants are
growing and how how effective they are
at at just pulling off like this amazing
growth in such a short period of time
and at the end of the season the biggest
cost to us was the labour of harvesting
you know that was our biggest bottleneck
was then you know getting the plants
down and
into our barn to start the drying
process and that that really was the
only area that took a large amount of
hand labor everything else was done in a
way that we would do any other vegetable
crop it was it was really amazing to to
watch it grow did you face any
particular challenges with it and
related to like say pests and disease
that you didn't face with your other
crops uh no not really and I I think
there's a lot of ways we could look at
that it was a very dry fall here in
Southern Oregon we had a really long
summer and so that was an advantage we
have strong winds that blow through our
valley every afternoon so as far as any
disease pressures that we might see in
vegetable crops we didn't see any any
problems there at all and we had the
plants spaced out enough that they
weren't compacted in so they were
planted on six foot centers out in the
in the beds the pest pressure the only
pest pressure we really saw was right
after transplant was cucumber beetles
we've got cucumber beetles here that are
just rampant they're just it's amazing
how strong of a population they have and
so the way we dealt with that was we
covered the plants right after
transplant with insect netting that we
use on like a lot of our Brassica crops
to keep flea beetles off of and that
worked great like once we got the plants
up to a healthy healthy size and then
they were just starting to crank they
could grow out of any pest pressure
after that and we did we constantly
monitored throughout the season or any
kind of mite pressure of any sort or any
other disease pressure we were
constantly checking the fields just to
just to observe and see what we saw but
other than that it was it was a pretty
straightforward season so you didn't
spray anything on the crop other than it
sounds like overhead watering yeah
overhead watering we did a little bit of
supplemental foliar with fish
hydrolysate but other than that yeah it
was just a let it rip wow that's great
and did you notice anything else in
terms of the crop itself any any changes
different than say when you've seen
cannabis I was ham very similar in all
respects or were there anything that you
notice that was project
different you know honestly everybody
that walked through the field throughout
the season didn't believe that it was a
hemp crop it just has such a similar
structure to cannabis
they were definitely couldn't believe
that that was hemp and I I think that
that you can attribute that to the fact
that the high CBD hemp crops that are
specific for that they've come out of a
breeding regime I am assuming from the
cannabis lineage you know it's a little
bit different than what I think of as
far as like a fiber hemp would be but
yeah other than that no it was it was
really straightforward the structure is
beautiful we had on average I'd say the
plants varied between 6 and 10 feet tall
at the end I liked the more compact
smaller plants they definitely were more
manageable and the the density of the
flowers were were better on those
smaller compact plants what cultivars
did you run and did you do any testing
afterwards how did the plants finish
yeah they were they were all cultivars
from the boring hemp company in boring
Oregon and they were all Auto - that's
the OTT OH - crossed with a variety of
other genetics and we did do some
independent testing after after the fact
and you know I I didn't I didn't really
have much to compare it to so for me
it's going to be going forward like what
I what I can see as far as improvements
from season to season you know I'm I'm
no expert on the crop itself I was just
growing it out more than anything - just
as a starting place to see what I could
learn so what are your future plans
around him really depends on what the
marketplace is like I think that we're
quickly seeing it moved into being a
commodity crop and so it comes down to a
matter of scaling properly and whether
we want to do that or not
so I've had a lot of other farmers
vegetable farmers especially you know
called me up and say hey should I grow
of em crop and my answer to them always
is like as long as you have a
marketplace for it because we've seen
the market place's is definitely
challenging and flooded already so I'm
encouraged by the future of it all I
think I'm just going to wait and see how
it all develops once kind of the the
madness of it all
of this first couple seasons kind of
dies down do you think there's going to
be more of a market for these high CBD
plants that are grown organically as
people will start using them more for
medicine do you see this side of the
industry growing just from your own
experience yeah I think so I think it's
a matter of the two schools of thought
of whether full spectrum full spectrum
material as opposed to an isolated
material which is more beneficial right
now a lot of times that isolated
material is more easily
I think distributed nationwide that's my
understanding at least and the full
spectrum material is something that it I
think stays more in state right now I
think I think the industry is very young
right now and it's going to be
interesting to see how it matures but I
would hope from what I hear from people
that are more knowledgeable in that
arena than me from what I can hear is
that there's a lot more public
acceptance each year and people are
finding real intrinsic value in using
using those high CBD materials you know
to their advantage for their health and
I think that as science gets behind it
more and can prove more so it's just not
anecdotal understanding that we'll see
wider and wider acceptance yeah my
father is actually dealing with a rare
disease called syidp that's the chronic
neuropathy and he uses cannabis that he
infuses with coconut oil as a way of
topical to help treat a lot of his pain
and it's been life-changing to help him
because before that they had him on
super high levels of narcotics that was
really really tough it was changing his
personality it took away all his energy
it actually didn't help deal with the
pain over time so I'm I'm really helpful
in the medicinal side of this so I'm
glad to hear that there's farmers like
you out there growing happen and
exploring the CBD aspects of cannabis so
thank you yeah and I did want to change
topic a little bit since we were talking
about the demand I know this is a little
bit topical right now I've read more
articles about the massive amount of
excess cannabis in Oregon and I since
you
surrounded by these farmers what are
what are you hearing regarding this
topic are people worried about next
season or are they yeah I guess where
are you at with that yeah I mean it's
yeah the Southern Oregon is a hotbed for
for the industry the rec industry right
now and the others massive concern among
a lot of folks because it I think it
changed faster and scaled larger and
quicker than anybody could assume that
it would and there's been no real cap on
the number of licenses as far as I
understand and so it's just been race to
the bottom almost for most people and
that's really disconcerting for people
that have put their entire savings into
building these brands and now they don't
have anywhere for it to go just because
there's just not the there's not the
population base here in Oregon to
support that so yeah it's it's pretty
scary you know and it affects all of us
down here not just the people directly
involved in the cannabis industry but
all the support industries and even just
the local economy here is there's a lot
of people that are being very cautious
with if they expand any of their
businesses or how they're going forward
people are being very cautious because I
think we can see the bottom drop out
pretty quickly now does that mean that
it won't recover no I don't think so I
think that it's just part of the growing
pains of the industry I just don't think
that people expected to see it shift so
rapidly yeah and I think the way that
people are going to survive is by
becoming more efficient in the way
they're growing and reducing their
expenses and you love you know a lot of
the things that we talk about on this
podcast in terms of using using
methodologies and ideas out of the the
farming or AG community so we'll see or
differentiating your product by being
yep you know organic or craft or having
some something that makes you unique
from someone that someone's flowers you
know just down the road yep I think
differentiation is going to be that's
the that's the hot item that people are
trying to figure out right now is
differentiating is the thing that needs
to happen it's just a question of how
you know yeah
stuff because you have guys that are
farmers you know they're not they're not
marketing companies and they don't know
how to build a brand necessarily they
may be growing great high quality
cannabis that's organic but in terms of
getting that information out to the
consumer that's a whole different skill
set and it's a big challenge I think for
a lot of people and so I'm hopeful that
some of this will come out as the
industry evolves but that's that's a big
concern for me yep I agree so one of the
things that I was really excited to talk
about with you when I found out that you
were coming on the podcast was because
you've been farming vegetables for so
long and you have this this level of
experience I wanted to talk a little bit
about some of the mistakes that you've
made over the years because I know for
me a lot of the biggest lessons I've
learned and the biggest improvements
I've made have been from screw ups you
know the gas get a lot of money so I
love to hear some from your perspective
what are some of the mistakes that
you've made that you that have really
improved your farming yeah there's been
a lot and you know that's what I always
tell people is that if if you're a
farmer just getting into farming and you
go to an elder farmer and ask hey what
what can I do to be successful
generally the farmers that are being the
most honest will not tell you what you
can do they'll tell you what not to do
and so that's that's definitely what I
talk with younger farmers about a lot
for me the things that if I could do it
all over again I think I would have I
would have invested in the proper
machinery and tools to scale up more
effectively earlier and I think that I
would have focused even more on training
my people and having a really good
business culture or like on farm culture
like focusing even more on taking care
of my taking care of my crew from the
beginning and not that I never not that
I didn't take care of my crew but just
focusing on the culture surrounding what
the work days and really looking at how
you can encourage people to keep going
because you know farming is not easy
work and so you get in the middle of the
100 degree day in August and you see a
lot of people's productivity really dip
and so I've learned over the years tips
and tricks that I can pass on to my
field managers to kind of keep the work
ethic and the and the whole vibe of the
crew up you know those are the biggest
things is because the people really are
the glue that keeps it all together and
another thing that I've learned is once
I was able to afford a full-time tractor
slash irrigation slash maintenance guy
onto my crew that was a life changer for
me too because then I could focus on
being the farmer and he focused on the
nuts and bolts of keeping it all
together but but some of those things
you know that that comes with time as
you scale and as you grow so those are
the biggest things that I've I've
learned you know there's also micro
fails that I've had as far you know just
a little things of like getting the
proper water on transplants as soon as
you put them out there and not waiting
and just having little failures here and
there but that that kind of just comes
with the territory on a day to day basis
yeah I think going back to what you
mentioned about your staff I think
that's really important and one thing
that I learned pretty quickly is that I
can't expect an employee to have to work
as hard as I'm willing to work that's
not their business yeah you know they
may have a passion for farming but the
other day like you mentioned you're in
hundred degree weather and it's it's
brutal and it's it's a different
mentality so building that culture and
finding ways to incentivize and support
your staff is so important and then
getting the right staff in place I've
had the issues where I've held on to
staff members that may be necessarily
weren't the right fit but it kept him on
longer than I should have you know
because we do believe in the people it's
like it's like family at a certain point
yeah well and and one of the things that
like a big mental shift for me was
several years ago I had an older friend
that had been farming for a long time
and he said to me he said the sooner you
can realize that you work for your
employees and not the other way around
the better your your farm culture is
going to be and I took me a while to
understand that but then I started
realizing like
that's my job is to make sure that my
employees have everything they need and
so if there is failure on their part
it's because I haven't trained them well
enough and so once I started approaching
it like that man things got so much
easier because any time a problem would
come up I'd be like okay what am I not
doing here effectively to teach them and
that doesn't fix the problems of you
know somebody that just doesn't care and
just doesn't come to work because they
have a horrible work ethic but on the
day-to-day I found that when I started
focusing on what I could do to make it a
great work environment for them things
got a lot easier that's great and you
get a lot of feedback from your
employees in terms of ways to make
improvements around the farm and things
like that yeah I do I I have a very open
door policy with what's going on and we
also understand each other to the point
that if somebody comes and says hey I
see it like this and I say well from my
experience that just doesn't work but I
appreciate your feedback then they know
that I'm not just shooting them down to
shoot them down they generally will
trust me from a point of experience you
know and I try to be open and
communicate that clearly yeah that's
great I always encourage my staff to
speak up but then also if they do notice
a problem to try and get me a solution
as well when they come to me with that
problem they don't they don't have to if
they're not able to come up with one but
a lot of times I find though they'll
come to me and say hey we're having this
problem
say with an animal enclosure and this is
what I think we need to do to solve it
and I can just turn in them and say
that's great
let's do it you know because they're
taking ownership of the land and of the
business and making good decisions that
are helping all of us have a better
experience so again yeah I can't say
enough good things about that yep that's
the way to do it and then in terms of
equipment I know I've bought equipment
that was either underpowered or not
suited for the right job in my file my
farm I have have you made that mistake
in your process or do you have anything
regarding purchasing equipment or using
equipment that you'd like to touch on
yeah generally all I mean this is I
guess it sounds like a really classic
American response or whatever which is
always buy the biggest machinery that
you can afford and I don't mean just go
overboard with
but I found over the years that anytime
I've bought a I'm like well I can afford
a six foot disc or if I if it hurts a
little bit I could buy an 8 foot disc
and just the efficiencies that come with
the proper sizing of those things and
looking at the long term payout if
you're spending you know 20% more
initially the long term payout is going
to give you a 50% return well then you
should do it you know those are the
biggest things for me is just properly
sizing the equipment and that came from
just asking experienced farmers you know
what they've used so I I can't encourage
people enough to reach out to people
that have more experience than you yeah
that's great and I think encouraging
people to get to know your neighbors
because that's where your pest pressures
are coming from they may know the
history of your land they can give you
experience with what grows well in your
area ton of benefits there yep I agree
100% so any other advice to new farmers
people that want to get into farming
yeah the the things that I I've been
asked that question a lot over the years
and the things that I always tell folks
are number one is learn how to be a
business owner like farming is actually
pretty easy I mean it's tough but it's
way easier than running a business and
so if you can't find that bottom line
then you're not going to stay in
business very long so that's the thing
that that I've learned over the years I
think the modern farmer is way more like
an entrepreneur than the classic idyllic
vision of what a farmer was you know
when our grandparents were we're young
so that's one thing is learn how to run
a business and then the second thing
that I always tell folks is be okay with
leasing land you don't have to own the
farm at least not at first
and if I could do it all over again I
think my wife and I probably would have
found a small house somewhere on a small
piece of land and leased ground to get
used to growing in our area especially
where we moved into this area and then
you're just not tied to that piece of
land because like our home property that
we originally bought it's good land but
it's nothing like the ground that we
have our production acreage on now
and so that that's something that I
think that people get caught up in the
idyllic vision of like oh I have to own
my own farm to be be able to be a farmer
and that just isn't true because the the
amount of land available out there is is
unbelievable and it's growing every year
you just have to figure out smart
contractual agreements with the land
owners to to make sure you protect
yourself and it can take years to bring
back poor soils and so it's you bring up
a good point in something that actually
Steve Solomon talked about when he first
started homesteading in Oregon is he
wishes that he had bought better land
because it took him forever to bring
that land back yes didn't look at it
closely enough Lee was first purchasing
yep yep that's that's where we're at I
mean once we started growing on our
production piece that we have the soil
was at least a hundred times better than
the property at home and so we just saw
our yields go through the roof with not
any extra work of what we had been doing
before so that was just a really eye
opening for us yes so in terms of
growing on your lands
you're obviously planting directly in
the ground I do see a lot of cannabis
farmers planting into containers yeah do
you have any thoughts on growing in
containers versus growing directly in
ground yeah I mean that's like a whole
other podcast on its own I guess I I
think that the jury's still out on if
one is better than the other as far as
the end result of what what you get out
of it I think it depends on your
approach your methodology you know I
feel like container gardening allows
people more control and it probably
mimics mimics the world of like the
classic hydroponic style more just
because you you get more nutrient flow
through and more water flow through in
that case and if you're working in
native soils you'll see that the
frequency of irrigating is much less and
there that that comes down to your your
personal ethics and approach to farming
as well as what kind of resources as far
as irrigation water and you know that
you have available to you I prefer like
here in Southern Oregon I mean we have
some amazing class ones
oils and I've seen some cannabis farmers
pull off amazing crops just going right
into the native soil but they've
definitely had to change their growing
approach and it's really hard when
you've been growing in a in a certain
way for you know 10 15 years or more and
then you all of a sudden have to get to
where maybe our only irrigating once or
twice or three times a week at the most
so that's a farmer has to be willing to
make that shift you know yeah I'm a big
proponent of planting directly in the
ground because owning a retail nursery
you can see the difference when you
allow a plant to have as much root space
as it wants it gets much larger I have a
great example with our mulberries where
we have some in a container that are
about two feet tall now after two years
and then I have one in the ground that's
over 80 tall same that was brought in at
the same time yep and like you mentioned
the ethics involved with using less
water you're going to keep the root zone
temperature down which is probably good
in your area because of the heat yep
there's so many benefits now you're not
just planting in a native ground I'm
guessing you're probably doing some soil
testing you want to talk about that a
little bit oh sure yeah yeah I mean it
really depends on your specific locale
you know I mean there's a lot of the
ground that people have been growing
cannabis on for years have been these up
in the hills properties and so you find
heavy heavy clay content up there which
could be a real challenge to grow in
without doing some serious soil
remediation down where I am in the
bottom of their River Valley a lot of
the cannabis farms that that surround us
down here you know those are Class one
like super low me silty loam soils some
of those there's little that needs to be
done other than say liming or some pH
balancing through that and some
mineralization and then just adding in
fertility into those into those soils
but yeah soil testings really where it's
at that's it's something that I'm still
on a learning curve with I am no expert
with understanding the intricacies of
the full the full world of soil testing
I'm learning every year but since I've
actively done tests on my veggie
ground over the last 10 years my my
understanding of my individual soils at
the farm have grown immensely and it's
been really exciting to watch how it's
changed due to what what kind of
amendments we put down and and even
these like little nuance differences
between one soil on this side of the
property to another soil type on the
other side of the property and how they
respond differently and it is a balance
to like I I just don't have the time to
spend countless hours like really
digging into all this because the
margins in the vegetable world are so
tight you know at the end of the day I
spend more time just getting product out
of the field so that's the beauty of the
cannabis industry is that it's always
seen better margins so people have been
able to focus more on that and that's
something I've always been a bit envious
of is the ability for the cannabis
industry to really dial in and look at
specifics surrounding soils yeah you
bring up a really good point around soil
testing and that it's it's simply just
another tool like a shovel or a tractor
it's another way of gathering data that
you can use to make more informed
decisions about your land yep and you
also brought up some other points that I
thought was good so there are times when
it's not necessarily great to plant and
land directly into the ground like when
you have very high clay soils I'd also
mention if you had a lot of real heavy
brewing pests like rats or moles or
things like that then a container might
make sense if you're in a floodplain
where you dig down and your water line
is really high close to the top surface
of your soil then you may want to go
into container so yeah oh and if you
have really bad heavy metals or you're
on remediated land so yeah those are
just other things I want to throw out
there now let's talk a little bit about
how you do fertilize your crops so you
mentioned that you have different
programs for different crops where are
you were you getting your fertility yeah
so fertility for us comes from pelleted
fertilizer
it's a from the chicken manure world
pelletized that's our pre plant
fertilized it's kind of like our broad
spectrum what what we put out on the
fields we focus a lot on cover cropping
as far as fertility
so sometimes nitrogen fixing cover crops
sometimes organic matter building cover
crops combos of both and then we also
use a fish hydrolysate that we put into
our irrigation systems either overhead
or through drip and then those are the
main fertility drivers for us and then
we also look at mineralization and our
mineral mineralization program has been
pretty like we haven't fine-tuned it to
each specific crop because of honestly
just because of cost you know we just
have to keep cruising forward so we've
kind of had this general overview
program you know using glacial rock dust
and azomite and other trace minerals
like that and now actually my my
education curve on the whole world of
mineralization has really been growing
over the last several years and so
that's something I'm starting to dive
into a little deeper but I I'm no expert
on that yet but I can see the the value
of that going forward are you doing
anything from a biological perspective
uh yeah I mean we we've used different
inoculants in our transplants in the
past and we've made tees in the past I I
haven't really and and what I always did
with T's in the past and I've kind of
scaled back on on tees because I there's
kind of like a lot of a lot going on in
that world right now that I'm just kind
of the jury's out you know for right now
but what I did for a long time just for
for more than anything food safety
reasons just to keep my certifiers happy
was putting biological T's out on our
cover crops and feeding the feeding the
cover crops instead of the food crops
and just with it the concept that the
biology would be there and inoculated in
those soils and then when we had those
soils turned under then we could come
back and follow with a food crop just
because there's a lot of there's a lot
of debate over the world of using that
T's and like foodborne pathogens and all
that kind of stuff so that's that was
our approach in the past and the last
several years I've found a really good
point of I get I don't know if I guess
I'd call it
like I think of the biology in our
fields is really healthy right now and
I've just been watching that and we're
having to fertilize less and less each
year and we're just kind of going off of
the bank of fertility and the biology
that's there and we're still seeing
great results from the crops and I know
I'll have to shift that at some point
but that's kind of been our approach for
right now so it seems like we have a
pretty good stored Bank of fertility and
we just keep observing now when you say
teas are you talking about aerated
compost Peas yeah I mean I've gone I I
messed around with aerated compost teas
for a while and then I kind of got into
just doing more of compost extracts like
a real quick extract where I wasn't
actively bubbling and I'd kind of mess
around with with everything whether it's
been worm based teas or compost based
teas or or whatever but I honestly I
never really dove into it deep just
because again a lot of what I end up
doing on the vegetable farm it comes
down to cost and time of how much energy
I can put into it it's been an
interesting kind of like
shoot-from-the-hip kind of project sure
that makes a lot of sense
now you mentioned either use some cover
crops do you have some favorites in
terms of actual actual varieties or
anything like that yeah definitely and
what I always tell folks what works here
in Southern Oregon may not work where
you're at and I think that's really
important you just kind of have to
experiment that's what I did
specifically the valley that we're in
here oats and peas work really well I
can plant oats and peas as late as
December first and still get a nice
stand before the spring it really
depends on when I'm going to be
harvesting or you know chopping that
that crop down in the spring so if I
have more time to let it grow and say
I'm not going to take a field out of
cover crop until May or June then I can
get a really nice stand so that's my
overwintered go-to is oats and peas like
a Cayuse oat and a Austrian winter pea
I've done Ryan veg in the past there's
one of the things I learned the hard way
was a and the annual rye is the thing to
use and not a perennial rye I learned
the
hardway on that one and and then during
the main growing season I've had great
success with su decks
like a Sudan cover crop for organic
matter building and weed suppression and
then I've used buckwheat a lot I really
like buckwheat as a crop because it's so
fast to grow it's like up and down in
like six to eight weeks and a nice
little phosphorous boost as well and
then if you can let it flower out before
it really goes to seed it's a amazing
attractor for beneficials those have
been the main things I've worked with
I've tried some understory planting of
clovers and vetches that's really
challenging if you don't have your weed
seed bank under control in her fields so
that's something that I would like to
work with more in the future the last
three or four years we've really focused
a lot on making sure that we're removing
our weed seed bank out of the soils and
so making sure that none of the weeds go
to flower anymore and that's making a
huge difference so once we get that
under control I probably will start
experimenting with more covers during
Maine season is that a manual process
where you're actually going out and
physically plucking the weeds sometimes
it is it's also about what we call bare
fallow where we'll have a block that
we're not growing in for a certain cycle
that will go ahead and irrigate that
block and then germinate the weed seeds
and then we go through and do a light
cultivation nothing deep or aggressive
just a light cultivation on the top to
knock those weeds out and we may do that
for you know one two three cycles you
know will irrigate grow them up knock
them down grow them up knock them down
and then we'll plant a cover crop into
that area and let that grow up and then
chop and drop it that has been really
good for us as well but but then yeah
it's also out in the field when we have
veggies growing just making sure that no
the weeds that do come up and make it
they ever go to seed yeah that's great
and so you're you're actually telling
these crowd your cover crops back into
the soil then before you plant your next
crop yes yeah we usually will use a
flail mower just to really pulverize and
the soil to eat that cover crop up
quickly you know it depends on what kind
of turnaround you want out of the field
because the the smaller that we can make
the residue the faster the soil can you
know like eat it up you know and so
that's that's kind of been our our
process yeah that makes sense you're
increasing the surface area for the
microbes to be able to consume that
great so let's talk a little bit about
some of the advocacy work you're doing
so you have this upcoming living soil
symposium that I'm really disappointed
I'm gonna be out of town for I want to
go I know my buddy jaya palmer has been
a speaker in previous years and he raved
about it i have a lot of friends that
have attended can you talk a little bit
about some of the the goals around that
and what what it is oh yeah sure
so I founded the living soil symposium
three years ago it really came out of
then I just saw the Greater agricultural
community online talking about a lot of
these techniques to take our farms
beyond organic like what these next
steps would be but I also saw a lack of
depth to community as far as the
communication goes online because
there's only so much you can do with
thumb typing your response you know you
just don't get as deep and so I said man
we just really need to create a venue
for a lot of people that are similar
minded to get together and really go
deep on some of these so that was the
real premise for why I created the event
originally was just to get people
together and have these interactive
conversations and we've always
encouraged it to be a two-way street as
far as the audience interacting with the
presenters and vice versa instead of
just being talked to by a you know in a
PowerPoint presentation by no means do I
have the the structure of the symposium
completely figured out yet every year is
a is another permutation of what the
previous year was and so we listen and
observe what the community at large is
saying and are trying to bring in a
diverse set of presenters each year and
so like this year we we've really
expanded out into a lot of different
traditions of farming whether it's
whether it's permaculture or grazing or
orchards or vineyards and hemp and
cannabis and even vegetable production
we're just really trying to widen our
reach and let the community realize that
there there's a lot of people out there
talking the same message even though we
might have a different crop that is our
you know that's our income crop so I'm
hoping that there can be this
cross-pollination between these
different methodologies of farming that
we can find the commonality and then
come out of it being better better
growers all together so that's the main
idea of what what I was trying to to do
with creating the symposium so the
symposium this year is being held in
Portland it's starts on March 23rd
through the 25th and it's not a cannabis
symposium correct but you do have some
cannabis yes some cannabis related
speakers and fest I see a good friend of
mine here David Bernard Peron is going
to be one of your yep one of your
speakers for the weekend session yep is
there anything else you want to
highlight any any talks that you're
really looking forward to this year
people you haven't heard before um oh
yeah I mean there's several folks that
um I I brought on because I wanted to
see how they would bring into the fold
there's Zakk Lok's he does he wrote a
book called the permaculture Market
Garden I'm really intrigued by what he's
doing where he's doing like a market
scale vegetable operation but with
permaculture design in mind a portland
local Peter McCoy he has radical
mycology I think that we're gonna see
what an important place fungi play in
agriculture going forward so I I wanted
to bring his voice in and I I think the
overall thing that I really want people
to understand is that I tried to look at
the symposium as a curriculum a weekend
curriculum as a whole so we're hoping
that there's some there's some synergy
between one presenter and another
presenter that one presenter can fill in
a piece of the puzzle and the next
presenter can fill in another piece of
the puzzle so like our friend Sam from
soil sand biotics he talks a lot about
mineralization and then I have
this fella Dan Kitteridge who's part of
the bio nutrient Association and he
focuses on nutrient density and crops so
I'm hoping that there can be a
continuation of education between those
two guys presentations that that Sam can
talk about the science and the specifics
behind mineralization and the importance
of it and then Dan can connect the dots
to how that translates to the food that
we're actually eating or the cannabis
we're actually consuming so I'm I'm
working hard on that and the one thing
that I'm I know is kind of the most
out-there idea that we're hitting on
this year is I have a group of folks
that are we're going to be actually
looking at the social like we're the
social permaculture of the event so
basically I have folks that are going to
look at the design of the event and
they're going to be observing the event
as if they were visiting a farm to
implement a permaculture design onto
that farm so like what what is the
cultural structure of our event and what
can we do to improve it so it has the
proper way the proper flow with systems
management you know and that's it's kind
of this esoteric and out-there idea that
I had but I think it's really worth it
to look at the culture that's driving
the event is just as important as the
information that we're getting out at
the event so that that's something that
I'm I'm really excited about as well I
think that's a great I mean one of the
great things about permaculture is since
it is design system you can really apply
it to anything and people are applying
it to the technology industry to just
about just about anything you can
imagine so I think it's wonderful that
you're looking at the social aspect
there yeah I'm really excited that
you're putting on this event and I think
it's still something in the industry
that's been needed needing to happen and
it's definitely gaining traction so I
hope people will definitely go and check
it out if they haven't heard of it or if
they haven't gotten their tickets yet is
there still room available oh yeah their
tickets are available yeah they're going
to be available the tickets closed March
17th
because we do serve lunch both days we
kind of need to know our numbers so the
sooner that people get their tickets the
better for us just so we know how many
people took
and we can prepare accordingly but yeah
the tickets are out there you can get
tickets for there's a Friday farm visit
to a farm right outside of Portland
that's more of a hands-on practical
experience those tickets are limited to
just a hundred tickets available for
that and then the Saturday and Sunday
sessions you can get a ticket to one or
both sessions you know so it's just
really whatever people can fit into
their schedule I highly encourage people
to come and be part of the community
discussion that's something I've been
focusing a lot on is making sure is that
the audience is stacked just as strong
as our list of presenters because that
is really important to me because it is
a it is a dialogue between the entire
community and so the stronger we can
make the entire the entire group of
people the better I feel yeah Jaya came
back super energized from from the last
one that he attended talking about how
it's just a wonderful group of people
and especially the audience itself
having like-minded people in the same
room they've been able to share all
their ideas because everyone has a story
and everyone has experience so that's
that's really great now was there
anything else he wanted you wanted to
cover before we sign off did you want to
talk any more related to farming or the
symposium or anything else no I just I
just want your listeners to know how
glad I am that you're doing this podcast
I think it the more people that can do
podcasts like this to really get the
message out about about what we can
what's really possible for us going
forward in agriculture it's really
exciting to me so I just applaud you for
the work that you're doing Ted well
let's follow up again maybe after the
symposium and see if you can share some
of the things that you learned at the
symposium and some of the exciting new
in new things going on in the industry
so I'm this podcast has been great for
me I really enjoy it it's open doors in
terms of meeting new people like
yourself and yeah I really appreciate
that so I'll get this podcast up right
away for listeners so that they can sign
up for the living soil symposium this
year and I look forward to talking soon
yeah sounds great
have a good one Ted all right so Chris
I'm having you back on the show today to
talk a little bit about the living soil
symposium
you know when we first recorded the show
we were talking up the symposium and I
was so excited for what you guys were
doing and then some things happened and
the show was canceled so I wanted to use
this as a platform to talk a little bit
about that process sort of what happened
and let listeners kind of into your
brain and what's been going on oh yeah
for sure so yeah thanks for having me
back on Ted I think it's really
important for me to you know relay the
message and kind of things that I've
learned after the fact now that we've
had to cancel the symposium really it
came down to ticket sales for us we had
we knew that the ticket sales had been
low but the previous two years they'd
been low until the last two weeks we had
previous two years we had sold a large
majority of our tickets in the last two
weeks but this year once I checked in
with my team I saw that they were just
not there this year and we were watching
how fast or slow they had been going and
started kind of doing the math and said
man there is no way that we're going to
be able to reach our break-even point in
the next three weeks so at that time we
had like three weeks of ticket sales
left I think it was because we had a
cut-off date seven to ten days before
the actual event so we could get plate
counts for the meals for both days so we
said there's no way that we're going to
reach that that number in the next three
weeks it just it just won't happen and
so it was a matter it really came down
to a business decision of sorts it was I
could cancel the event
now which has been about a week ago as
you and I are talking right now and I
can lose the money on all of my deposits
on all the event space and and the extra
costs that that I had already invested
or I could try to see if we could
weather the storm and really make a move
to sell tickets but even then if I
didn't find that break-even point then I
was going to lose about another twenty
thousand dollars on top of what I was
already losing and so for me I had to
make that decision and
eh I just have to call this this is just
not this is just not going to work and
and that really comes down to it was my
own personal financial responsibility
and so I had to make that decision from
my standpoint because I didn't have a
backer on any of this at all it's just
been you know my own my own money to
bootstrap this whole thing from the
beginning so this was your your vision
this symposium and it was something that
you put together out of your passion for
this style of cultivation and farming
and when you say you were your ticket
sales were low I know you and I talked
we're not talking you know 10 or 20
tickets we're talking hundreds of
tickets low so it was a yeah it was
really a financial decision on your part
to cancel this show and I know it wasn't
an easy decision for you yeah I'm sure
it's been you've gotten some feedback
I'm sure I've seen some both positive
and negative feedback on your Instagram
page setup' then do you want to talk a
little about sort of the emotional
process you went through with this and
have any comments to the people who left
both you know positive and negative
feedback on there oh yeah yeah um well
first of all I would say I listened to
all the feedback and I don't think that
I don't think any of the feedback was
out of line at all really um you know I
I'm really good at critiquing myself I
mean being a farmer you kind of have to
be good at critiquing yourself there was
a lot of things that I I took chances on
that I shouldn't have we thought that
there was a greater a greater capacity
for the event this year and so we found
a bigger space that could facilitate a
larger a larger group of people and that
meant that we had to move up to Portland
because I didn't find a space down here
in Southern Oregon where I'd had it the
previous two years that could hold that
number of people that was a mistake on
my part this the move I totally
understand that the added cost of of
having a bigger space meant that my
upfront costs were more so I was more on
the line for for making sure that I sold
X a number of tickets I definitely
realized in the world of running an
event like this once you start
baling up it becomes more challenging to
do it with a minimal number of sponsors
and not having a tradeshow I think that
and that was something that I was trying
to avoid was having a trade show that
brings in money and having a lot of
sponsorships that brings in a lot of
money I was really trying to keep it
into a symposium atmosphere of of really
critical thinking about being clouded by
sales of products or trying to pitch
products or whatever and so that was a
big lesson for me that doesn't mean that
if in the future if I was going to do
something more that I would I would
definitely have a trade show and have a
ton of sponsors I just think that I
would look at a different a different
format probably those were some of the
things the other thing that I saw as far
as comments were that it was too
expensive those that that cost that I
was charging for the event for the two
days was basically a break-even cost for
us because I didn't have a ton of
sponsorships and because I didn't have a
tradeshow and the fact that we were
working really hard to pay all of the
presenters properly this year and in
years past people had done it for free
and even though a lot of people still
wanted to do that we were trying you
know to pay everybody fairly to present
and it wasn't a lot but it was like but
once you have the amount of people that
we had presenting this year once you
multiply it by that many people it adds
up to a chunk of a chunk of cash to get
people there so that was really the
reason for the increase in the ticket
price this year and I know that the
state of Agriculture right now
especially the cannabis industry I had a
lot of people reach out to me and say
hey man we came last year but we just
can't afford to come this year because
the financial state of the cannabis
industry especially here in Oregon right
now is really on rocky ground and and so
and that is a big part of my demographic
is the cannabis community and I get it
where they're coming from I'm seeing it
all around and then there were there
were the people outside of cannabis that
were just in agriculture together that
just said you know we're kind of burned
out on
on conferences and this to them it just
seemed like another conference and that
was probably our myself and my team's
fault for not not putting the message
out there stronger as to how we were
going to differentiate ourselves and so
that's something that I'm learning from
as well that just allowing a conference
or symposium like this to grow
organically it worked really well in the
first two years just word of mouth but
as we were kind of growing up I think
that we probably should've earmarked a
much bigger chunk of our budget towards
pushing posts to people paid advertising
paid marketing out to the out to all the
people and that's something that that I
am looking into for the future how I
would approach things differently
because honestly in the last year a lot
of the algorithms in the world of
Instagram and Facebook have changed and
I don't think that we were as we're as
aware of that as we are now just that
the organic reach is just not the same
it was a year ago so all of those things
together I think were major contributors
and there were you know smaller other
other factors too but it's like that's
it's like there's like the overall
takeaway is that the ticket sales were
just low and that's that's kind of where
we're at yeah I love the idea that being
in Portland since I'm up in the Seattle
area being able to bring people down
from Washington out of the 502 market -
yep be able to attend as well I think is
amazing you touched on a lot of things
there that I think are all really
important one thing I know I had talked
with some with some good friends in the
industry about doing it something
similar to what you were doing like a
symposium and there are all these
challenges and even with this podcast
I've avoided having advertising on here
or anything because there's so many
issues around that in terms of what
products that you personally support or
feel are you know created ethically and
that you would even want at a tradeshow
and once you go that route it's really
it's a slippery slope when when money
starts coming in and saying no to some
people and yes to others I think is a
real challenge so I commend you in that
in
staying with that symposium forum and
I'm really hopeful that next year we can
generate enough interest and I'd love to
you know come on board and help out as
much as I can from the outside in
promoting what you're doing because I
think it's so important that we get this
information out to the wider the wider
audience both in cannabis and in farming
yep yep yeah and I think it it's I think
that that's something that I'm taking
away from this is that when you are
trying to trying to put a message that's
this big and this diverse out there
which really I mean honestly the living
soils moniker was really just saying
nature you know like we're just all
trying to find our own pattern
recognition of nature so whenever you're
trying to take something on that big
like it's gonna take some time and I
think that that's something that I'm
realizing is that this is this is a long
path that I'm taking and it's not like I
I don't think that I took that as
seriously as I should have as far as
like how much work it takes to affect
culture in a healthy way and so that's
something that I'm I'm taking note of
it's like we need to keep pushing
forward with this this educational
message and I just have to be patient
you know like I really view this as a
hiccup in the road and other than the
fact that it it it kind of sucks for me
financially in the short term in the
long term I know that the that the end
result is is and can be a really good
thing I just have to be patient with
that well I'm glad to hear that you're
still moving forward with everything and
not too discouraged by this and I hope
that listeners and people that were
attending you know attendees were
open-minded to the greater situation the
perspective here in terms of what you
you're going through and the energy
you're putting into this and what it's
costing you financially for you and your
family
one thing you touched on with the
symposium that I think is really the
coolest thing about it is that you're
when you say that living soils is just
is just nature we have and this is
something we talked about off-air we
have all these different ways of
cultivation and farming you know in our
community
terms of you know Korean natural farming
permaculture probiotic farming you know
you have all these bio dynamics all
these different styles or methodologies
that are all slightly different but all
organic and all looking to looking to
promote ethical and sustainable
cultivation and farming and what I love
about your symposium is it's getting all
these people together to where if you're
an open minded human being an individual
there's something to learn from every
group you know each one is going to be
slightly different but each one has a
really powerful message that we can
share and all learn from each other so
that maybe we don't have to have all
these separate groups that are divided
tribes but rather just united under this
idea of trying to save the environment
and trying to grow sustainably yep I
agree and I you know the analogy that
I've been using in all of this is like
I've I just view it as speaking
different languages and then you have to
get everybody in one room it's kind of
like when you see the United Nations
kind of get together and meet and you
see all these people with different
headsets on that have their the
translation is happening like that's
really what I viewed the symposium to be
was a place where people are speaking
different languages but at the end of
the day we're all basically speaking the
same language it's just how we're going
about presenting it you know and so
that's that's something that I keep in
mind in all of this very cool well was
anything else you wanted to cover in
terms of the symposium itself or
anything else you want to say to
listeners regarding what was going on no
I mean nothing other than some folks
have already reached out to me with
brainstorming ideas of how they would
like to see things go forward or what
their ideas are to to make things
continue this educational path continue
and I so I just encourage people to keep
reaching out to us with their ideas and
I also encourage people to take it into
their own hands if they see that they
can create a group of like-minded folks
are open-minded folks in their own
communities that you should start
creating events small micro events
yourselves you know and that's one idea
that I've really really resonated with
over the last week as several people
have said well I'm just going to start
my own event here and then maybe
we can meet up at the symposium each
year to kind of share our regional ideas
and I'm like yeah that's great that's
like so if if nothing else maybe this is
a this kind of like bump in the road is
a catalyst for other folks to realize
that they can take you know take that
power in their own hands so sort of like
a TED Talks thing with tax yeah exactly
kind of like a you know doing their own
their own because that's the thing is
like what we realize is that all of our
farms are different you know and so and
that could be a regional difference too
and so like there's folks in Colorado
that said we're going to start a small a
small gathering out here of folks and
talk about the same topics that you'd be
talking about the symposium and then all
of them would love to come to get
together in a yearly celebration of what
they're learning and share it with
others you know something like that I
don't know it's it's it's it's all about
brainstorming together as a community
that's that's brilliant I love it I
would love to I'd love to talk to you
further about that and maybe we can I
mean you're down in Southern Oregon I'm
up here in Washington it would be great
to have something up here too you know
our smaller events so wonderful
um well again thanks for your time today
I will add this on to the podcast so
people can get a little more perspective
on what was going on and yeah thanks
again I'll let you get back to the
farming I know you got a lot of work to
do out there thanks dad
all right have a great day
[Music]
that was Chris Jagger owner of blue fox
farm be sure to check out the upcoming
living soil symposium @ww living soils
symposium calm and Chris's farm website
at www.archives.gov/calendar smore
information and articles available on
our website and blog at WWE
as well as links to the data and
information we discussed in this episode
on the podcast page and if you enjoy
these podcasts please take a moment to
leave me a rating and review on itunes
or whatever platform you're listening on
and send me your feedback and
suggestions through our website contact
page or ta d at kiss organics calm
thanks for listening
[Music]