[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is dr. ad ray dr. ray is
an NIH funded neuroscientist who has
been studying cannabis opioids and their
interaction for her entire career she
has a strong publication record in
chronic pain addiction and harm
reduction dr. ray is currently an
assistant scientist at Legacy Research
Institute in Portland Oregon and holds a
joint faculty appointment at Washington
State University her multifaceted work
ranges from synaptic physiology to
clinical pain management dr. ray is
long-term academic research goal is to
define the harm reduction potential of
cannabis in the opioid overdose epidemic
as a co-founder of smart cannabis ad
leverages her knowledge of pharmacology
to enhance consumer well-being and
support craft cannabis producers smart
cannabis is a portland based consulting
and research firm that empirically
identifies the world's most enjoyable
cannabis now on to the show hi ad thanks
for coming on the show today you bet
thank you so much for having me bad yeah
well I had such a great time meeting
Steph finally in person down at photo X
and she said you'd be the best one to
talk to you on the show so let's just
dive right in can you give me a brief
background on your research and how you
got to well the place that you are today
you bet so you know I've been studying
cannabis and cannabinoids my entire
adult life I wrote my first grant to
study cannabinoids in the laboratory in
2004 and my hypothesis and my academic
work is that we can use cannabis and
cannabinoids to reduce our reliance upon
prescription opioid drugs for pain
relief
so I've studied this problem from a
number of different angles you know all
the way zoomed way and down to how the
neurons
the brain function in the presence of
these drugs all the way out to you know
now we're clinically managing people's
pain using cannabis so and a lot of
other things in between
so we're where I fit right now I still
have a very you know large I'm not large
I guess but I have a very active
academic research program but as you're
aware the federal constraints for
studying cannabis are pretty tight so we
we have to get creative and how we're
answering some of the most burning
questions that we have about cannabis
and its effects on people so one of the
one of the projects I'm the most excited
about in pretty much all of my life is
the work that I do outside of academia
with our company smart cannabis and
really the the cool thing about this
project is that we get to answer some
really fundamental questions about what
does cannabis do in human beings healthy
human beings and the way that we've
structured it we can answer these really
exciting questions in a way that doesn't
violate any laws and doesn't get us in
trouble so you know a lot of academic
researchers in the cannabis field have
had to get very creative and how they do
their work in order to answer the kinds
of questions are interested in so for
instance I have a colleague at
Washington State University Kari Cutler
and she does essentially psychometric
testing she gives people you know
computer tests to do over zoom because
that way she can have this person do a
DAB / zoom instead of illegally doing a
dab inside her laboratory so this is
this is what I mean with being creative
and and how we're answering these really
interesting questions so so yeah at the
moment you know I've built my academic
work up you know over the years NIH
grant by NIH grant and and now I do sort
of tandem projects both inside and
outside of academia so what drew you to
cannabis in the first place this is more
just out of personal curiosity it sounds
like
a lot of your focus initially was on the
medical side but now you're looking at
sort of its affects both medically and
recreationally is that is that right
that's pretty fair yeah and I would say
that my draw initially like really
really early in my career as an
undergrad was pure scientific curiosity
you know I was looking at these two
drugs opioids and cannabinoids both of
which were used as pain relievers and I
knew that if you use two drugs together
at the same time often they amplify one
another's effects and that was true and
continues to be true for both of these
drugs but you know I came into it as a
skeptic you know I was a straightedge
hardcore punk rock kid and I was like
super anti drugs and alcohol and I I was
really interested in addiction and it
wasn't until I saw all the literature
for myself and produced some of that
evidence myself that was like huh
there's really something here and you
know sure enough you keep following the
evidence over you know decades and it's
a very compelling story that this is
this is clearly a safer drug compared to
opioids when it comes to pain relief and
and even you know if we're talking about
from a pure you know altered state of
consciousness perspective altering your
consciousness with cannabis is arguably
more safe than doing so with alcohol so
so yeah
follow the evidence to understand both
the therapeutic value and the harm
reduction value that cannabis poses and
so that's where that's where I sit now
I'm looking at the relative safety of
cannabis compared to other things that
we put into our body both were a
therapeutic purpose and for a purely
personal reason and it really is true
that this is a relatively safe and occu
a substance that that most healthy
adults can use for a variety of things
and you know the way that you ask the
question kind of pits medical youth
against adult use as a binary
choice but really I do see this as a
spectrum and one individual can fall
anywhere on that spectrum even multiple
times a day they can fall in different
places on that spectrum so you know the
the ability of this plant to produce
such wide different kinds of chemistry
matches up with the ability of the human
to use many different kinds of plants
for many different kinds of purposes so
yeah I do I do very much see it as a
spectrum and that's kind of where all of
my work is is based on now yeah I think
that's a really good point you brought
up it's really the legislation that has
created this medical versus recreational
sort of binary path when when you're
right there are all these outcomes and
effects that people experience with
cannabis that it's not really accurate
to just split it so so black and white
in yeah I think it's funny but oh go
ahead well I was just gonna say that's
even been recently reflected in the
scientific literature you know we've
seen that if you go into a dispensary in
Colorado a recreational dispensary and
you ask people why they're there 60 or
70% of them will say either I'm here to
get something to help me sleep or
relieve my pain and that's in the adult
use market so you know like it's we see
it also played out in Oregon where you
know for a long time we had the oh mmm P
the medical marijuana program and the
numbers of you know participants in that
program have been dwindling over the
years and it's not that those patients
are going anywhere they're just not
using the medical program anymore
so that's the other thing about cannabis
is that it is a very self empowering
tool so you know and we we tend to find
that with any kind of patient when they
feel like they are responsible for or at
least they're they're in control of
their own health that that tends to be a
good thing so the ability of people to
you know take this medical tool into
their own hands and use it to the degree
that suits them you know that's kind of
a
win-win you have empowerment and you
have a personalized approach to medicine
yeah now we're kind of on opposite sides
of the industry I think it's really
interesting cuz I came to cannabis sort
of like you did in the sense that I
wasn't that wasn't a big user I had
never even tried cannabis till I was 33
I think for the first time and I was I
was so afraid I had I went hiking in the
woods and took one little puff and I
didn't know what what sort of
experiences I would have because I was
just I was a control freak and I didn't
like the idea of this but I think it's
interesting that like Michael Pollan
highlights the the fact that we all
every society every culture human
culture attempts to alter their
consciousness in one way or another
through the use of plant-based medicines
and plants so I think that's really
interesting but the thing that interests
me most about your research from a
personal level is that I have I find
that I have very different effects with
cannabis than a lot of my friends and
other people in the industry which is
one of the reasons my focus has always
been on like cultivation and providing
you know safe clean flower that that to
me is the most interesting aspect of it
but at the same time like I know these
effects are so important and like for me
with effects I if I smoke most flowers I
will get I'll get sleepy but I won't
fail to fall asleep my brain will just
race a million miles an hour and then
I'll just eat everything in sight and I
seem to have that effect across a
variety of different cultivars to where
it's not as appealing to me as you know
maybe other other things like like you
mentioned alcohol which I agree is way
worse than cannabis in those cases but I
know that everyone has different sort of
effects when they consume cannabis and
this is sort of one of the things that
you guys are discovering and researching
can you start to share a little bit
about some of that research yeah
absolutely I'd be delighted to but first
I want to recognize you know like thank
you for sharing your story I think that
it is extremely common amongst people
and very frustrating so you know I and
exactly our process through the
cultivation classic is designed to
support exactly this thing that you're
describing which is that engaging with
cannabis
is a risky behavior and what I mean by
that is that you are taking a gamble you
don't necessarily know what's gonna
happen you know you can follow your bud
tenders recommendations and you can go
based on your previous experiences or
maybe you have a friend who you know
well-versed in things but when you're
making a buying decision at the
dispensary counter for the most part you
are not really guaranteed whatever kind
of experience you know you think you
want so so that's exactly what our
process is designed to support we want
to make it a less you know less of a
gamble you know maximum enjoyment at
minimum risk and so you know the
wonderful thing about the cultivation
classic is that you know not only are we
really focusing on organic like
regenerative kinds of flower which we
know is best practice right we the
cannabis industry isn't gonna exist 20
years from now if we burn out the planet
or if we burn out the people who are
using the plant so you know that's why
you know this this particular cup has
always been focused on you know plants
that don't use salt mineral fertilizers
but you know and we really reward
cultivators who are you know minimizing
their carbon footprint and producing
sustainable cannabis so in Oregon what
what the competition looks like is that
you know we accept entries from
throughout the state last year we had
roughly 50 cultivators and a total of a
hundred and fifty flowers which we've
then put through a very rigorous
analytical chemistry panel so we you
know use one laboratory the best
laboratory we can find
last year it was Cascadia who
unfortunately is no longer in the Oregon
market but they're doing great work in
California so we've got a nice list of
all the cannabinoids and all the
terpenes then we take that flower and we
distribute it to our consumer
ambassadors our judges and we do this in
a double-blind randomized fashion so
what that means is that I don't know
what flowers
my judges are getting and they don't
know what flowers they're getting either
they're just in you know jars with a
four-digit number the next level of that
process is that first of all they take a
tolerance break 48 hours before they
start engaging with the plants in their
kit our judges get about 10 flowers per
kit and they've got 30 days to use them
now that is really important and that's
what you know that this is a key
distinguishing factor from other kinds
of cups you know it's kind of widely
known that other you know competitions
if you want to call them that you know
there's a bunch of flowers that get
consumed around a conference table and
it's not exactly an objective evaluation
of which flower was the best so this is
an extremely rigorous process we want to
make sure that our judges have the time
to mindfully complete an assessment of
the flowers that are in their kit so you
know we give them a nice long period of
time to do so
so at the end of that what we've got is
a very valuable data set in that we've
got high fidelity plan information
double-blinded assessment and
specifically the feedback tool that
we've designed you know that our judges
log in to our tool and they provide
their answers to you know a survey
digitally and we can really delve into
questions not just like you know I want
to scale one to ten how much did you
like this but was the experience
desirable was the aroma desirable you
know what are your tasting notes how did
it make your body and your emotions and
your cognition feel we delve into all of
those deeper questions so that we can
really get a more granular idea of
exactly what effects these kinds of
flowers had in healthy human beings so
you know this is the this kind of
process takes a lot of effort and time
and I think that that's you know that
kind of investment is uncommon in in a
lot of those other events that are out
there yeah so I just I want to start off
by saying I bended the cultivation
classic twice now maybe three times it's
wonderful I love what you guys are doing
there I want to get more involved with
it personally I've been talking with
Steph about that hopefully for next year
but it's a great program and a great cup
and I do think you are doing the best
you can at sort of controlling as many
variables as possible one question I had
around that though was do you have any
recommendations for people consuming at
the same time of day or same day of the
week or like I assume people would have
a different effect if they had just you
know won the lottery and then smoked one
of the flowers versus if they had just
broken up with their girlfriend and
smoked one of the flowers you know so is
there any way to account for those sorts
of fluctuations as well or is it just
it's a little too hard to control I
don't know what do you think yeah yeah
those are those are excellent questions
and as a bench scientist those are all
the exact kinds of variables I would
love to be able to control but I have
learned that this is the reality we live
in people consume at different times a
day they they consume for different
purposes they have different kinds of
you know schedules and they have
different routines and that is going to
be the case no matter how small or how
large you know the the cannabis industry
is or or our sample sizes so what we
want is to capture naturalistic behavior
so you know there we do ask a few things
to try and standardize you know to the
best of our abilities so we have some
important questions you know when our
judges first register to try and level
the playing field a bit but in general
you know like there it is a fact that
people's experiences and routines are
different their expectations are
different and we have to capture the
reality out there in the world so yeah I
do agree that under ideal laboratory
kinds of conditions we might have you
know smaller noise in the data might be
able to detect patterns a little bit
more easily if that noise is less
prevalent but in general you know we we
have to we have to live in reality
sure and I think just to be clear this
isn't a problem that just exists in
measuring effects of cannabis this
exists across all health research or
anything involving a human subject where
you can't put them in a vacuum and
expand and test so that's why you just
it's a it's a matter of collecting so
much data that you have you know a good
standard deviation you can create a good
mean effect and then throw out all that
data that you know all that noise that
you mentioned that's just skews things
so you can you can get nice graphs down
the time over time if you collect enough
information I guess is what I would say
around that that is exactly right that's
exactly right so let's talk about some
of your findings this I thought this was
really interesting do you want to start
talking about THC in general or would
you like to cover some of the findings
more specifically you want to talk about
this whole indica versus sativa thing I
know there's a lot we could we could
start off with okay yeah well yeah let's
let's start off with what I think is
probably the most impactful finding that
we came across last year was that you
know so when we're assessing we're
digging through all the data that we get
at the end of our you know data
collection period and we can make a
composite you know sort of enjoyment
score essentially and you know if we if
we look at how enjoyable a flower is and
then we rank them all from the most
desirable you know all the way down to
150 it's least least desirable and zoom
in on the top 10 so the top 10 most
enjoyable flowers in Oregon what we
notice immediately is that only 3 of
those 10 had more than 20% THC so that
tells us that when you take the you know
the label off of a jar and you just give
a human an ability an opportunity to
enjoy the flower they tend to report
that they like some moderate potency
flowers the best I think even our number
four or number six best performing flow
we're only had 6 percent THC so you know
this this is incredibly important
because it highlights the legacy of
Prohibition namely potency so right now
you know from the retail intake manager
to the consumer to the producer there is
this like perpetuation of potency as the
number one value in cannabis you know
and and I don't I don't blame people for
chasing this because historically it's
the only information that we had that
you know quote-unquote the dank was
always related directly to THC potency
but what this data shows us is that
enjoyment and intoxication are different
so you know we we know that THC potency
is correlated with intoxication for sure
that's been demonstrated in the lab it's
common knowledge you know you can go
home yourself and do an experiment on
yourself and know that more potent
flowers mean more intoxication however
more intoxication doesn't necessarily
mean more enjoyment so there's this you
know mythology that the more potent
flowers are the most valuable flowers
but the more potent flowers are the most
enjoyable but this data shows that
they're not so you know I think about
potency from the perspective of an
addiction researcher and what we see in
all illicit drug markets whether it is
opioids or alcohol or you know in the
days of prohibition with cannabis
prohibition promotes potency and that's
because smugglers are trying to pack as
much of their stuff into the smallest
package possible because they have to
move it around
that's where potency comes from so
despite the fact that we have beautiful
legal markets and somewhat functional
cannabis economy we're still dragging
around this legacy which is completely
irrelevant
so you know I think about it a a really
nice comparison is with moonshine you
know like yeah moonshine is incredibly
potent and you know it was easier to
move around than other kinds of alcohol
because it had so much alcohol you know
in in the smallest package possible but
but we're not in the moonshine base and
when were as you know as a consumer
going to a dispensary counter I could
make the moonshine decision or if I were
given the opportunity if those products
existed I could choose you know a nice
glass of cab sauce or a fine eye hazy
IPA or a farmhouse ale or you know a
barrel aged whiskey so there's so many
other experiences that are possible if
we go if we dip below the intoxication
level that moonshine provides us so I
have a couple questions but I want to
start with the first one with this
enjoyment score now does that taking
into account like when we talked about
medical some of the therapeutic benefits
is that sort of factored into that
enjoyment score as well what sort of
know things look at that yeah so the
enjoyment so we steer very very clear of
any medically relevant questions other
than maybe asking about you know
undesirable side effects which you I
guess could argue that a racing cart is
a you know an adverse outcome but you
know we're really trying to see you know
like what is what is enjoyable and
what's least likely to produce you know
something undesirable so now we're
steering clear from medical utility
because if you're doing a double-blind
randomized you know if you're assigning
products to people in a double-blind
randomized fashion and you're asking
them medically relevant questions you're
conducting a clinical trial and
currently that is not legal
because it seems like you could down the
road look at this and say okay this
particular flour
you know reduced my pain on a pain scale
by this much versus this other flower
but I that makes a lot of sense now so I
I get it and I'm yeah and as a pain
researcher there is absolutely nothing
that I would be more delighted to do
then asked that very question of these
two products which of them made your
pain better you know that that is that's
something that myself and my colleagues
would would our longing to be able to do
so if I'm understanding you correctly
basically what I'm hearing is that one
this idea of THC being sort of a marker
for evaluating cannabis is something
that we should hopefully as a society
will stop stop doing and that we need a
better tools for evaluating cannabis and
that's sort of what smart cannabis and
your your company is looking to
accomplish for people is a way for them
to better evaluate the effects of these
flowers before they before purchasing
based on the amount of available data is
that that's on right yes absolutely we
want to empower the consumer to be able
to make choices that promote enjoyment
and that are and we know at least from
this data that enjoyment and THC don't
necessarily go hand in hand
so one of the other really interesting
data points from this year and actually
we've seen this for a couple years in a
row now is the importance of aroma so we
saw you know we have really nice
correlation between the aroma of a
flower and the effects that are produced
by that flower and so what I mean by
that is you know if we look at you know
the how how much a person enjoys a
particular flower then that is likely to
be correlated with how good that flower
smells so the the better a flower smells
the more likely it is that a consumer is
going to enjoy the effect you know we
also saw a correlation between the aroma
and euphoria
so euphoria
and enjoyment are two different things
from our perspective euphoria is a mood
state how do you feel emotionally happy
yes or no and then the other one is a
preference do I like this so yeah it
kind of makes sense that if you're happy
you're gonna like it but we find that
that is related to the aroma of the
flower so you know in the cultivation
community and your listeners will
probably this will ring very true to
them there's that old saying the nose
nose and so you know at our at our award
ceremony in May we have the nose nose
award for an exemplary cultivar that
smells great that produces a really nice
psychological state in our people and
makes them happy yeah I want to talk
about more of your findings but a
question popped in my head while you
were talking about this that I was
wondering so along with the challenges
of sort of identifying these variables
and and creating this these graphs
around these flowers how do you account
for variability among a given cultivar
so like when we talk about like a chemo
of our expression something that I know
Jeremy plumb is really passionate about
and talking dives into do you see this
becoming like the wine industry where
the 2017 oh gee coach that was grown
outdoors on this farm was sort of that
you know created this one experience and
then next year it may be a different
experience altogether because they may
have changed something in the soil
profile it might have perceived more
water or more sunlight you know all of
these different variables right you're
absolutely right and this is a tricky
question which I think will a we're
working on it and B it will take some
time to really fully develop and it'll
need some consensus among the community
because you know from my perspective
like the most conservative thing is to
say that you always have a novel
cultivar no matter if you put the same
you know name on it or not you know it
is even under very tightly controlled
growing conditions you know artificial
intelligence controlled greenhouse stuff
like you know even under those type
controlled conditions with genetics that
are identical harvest to harvest we have
genetic drift you know we have
environmental changes that very
profoundly affect phytochemistry and so
from my perspective every single time we
produce a certificate of analysis for a
cultivar it's a unique thing it's a it's
a totally new thing every single time so
I don't think you know unlike wine I
think it'll be much more difficult to
you know routinely produce the exact
same chemistry time after time after
time I think that we're getting closer
to that and I do think that you know
Jeremy is a prime example of you know
the the level of rigor it takes to get
those harvest harvest really really
reproducible outcomes but I'm again like
I'm okay with this you know this is the
world we live in we have a lot of
variability in that plant because it is
crazy sensitive to its environment so if
that's the case then great but I do
think that there is work to be done in
creating rough categories of kheema bars
so that is you know we have our types 1
2 &amp; 3 or THC dominant and then hemp like
you know flowers and then within those
be there probably is some further you
know chemo taxonomy that's related to
the terpene expression but even you know
we're looking at hops and we're looking
at other you know agricultural products
and we know that a lot of the aroma from
hops doesn't necessarily come from
terpenes it comes from other molecules
that don't currently appear on anyone's
certificate of analysis they're totally
not on the radar so you know this is
this is something that you know I think
that it's going to be this is what's the
most exciting thing to me about cannabis
is that it's like the Mariana Trench
both in terms of the chemicals it
produces as well as what those chemicals
do in the people that are consuming the
plant so we have many many decades of
discovery ahead of us but but yeah we're
currently working on a project we're
using this data set from the cultivation
classic in partnership with some
colleagues in California to see like
okay
if we can model different chemo types
you know what kinds of buckets of
cannabis are there and then can we
create a predictive model which will
then you know fit these new you know
cultivars that are coming out and put
those into those different you know
chemo taxonomic buckets that's that's
really interesting so you mentioned you
mentioned smell and we talked a little
bit about genes and I know you have some
chirping data and one of the things that
I learned I wasn't aware of was that you
know cannabis for a long time was Merce
mersin dominant primarily and now we're
starting over the last few years we're
seeing more variability in that can you
talk a little bit about what you're what
you're seeing in terms of the
variability now in terpenes and what
effects people are reporting related to
that data yeah for sure
you know the effects thing is tricky
because our data set would tell us that
the mindset of the person is the most
predictive thing the mindset and the
aroma are the most predictive things so
if this person expects it to have an
indica like response then it's that's
what it's going to do for them which is
not that surprising if we look at
cannabis essentially or THC being a mile
classic psychedelic and if you look at
all the other classic psychedelic drugs
some mindsets prior to ingesting the
drug is a huge component in the ultimate
outcome so if you have an expectation
that this product is going to do this
for you it's kind of a self-fulfilling
prophecy so you know with with the data
that we currently have it's not
sufficiently large enough to detect
these patterns not to mention the fact
that you know we're not just looking at
the effect of mere seen we're looking at
the effect of mere seen in combination
with all of this other huge host of
chemicals that you know polypharmacy is
a completely different ball games and
you know just taking mere scene on its
own so you know if we look at what we've
seen in the data this year compared to
last year one of the things that's
unfortunate is that
you know we see a lot of plants that
tend to be more similar to one another
compared to you know a different from
one another and we would really like to
see all the freaks we would love for
people to submit flowers that are very
unique and very special but what we have
seen is that you know compared to last
year we have way more turpentine
dominant cultivars so you know this is
you know for some of the old-school
folks out there Dutch treat the smell of
Dutch treat that's the turpentine
dominant aroma this tends to be also a
very potent aroma intense so you know
like a lot of people can detect oh I'm I
don't know you know a lot of different
types of weed from one another but I can
smell turpentine it's a very distinct
aroma same thing with citrus something
has a citrus aroma that tends to be
really distinct in people's minds and
you know like five out of seven judges
can easily detect a citrus aroma you
know they don't have to be trained in
sensory evaluation to go yep this smells
like citrus so so yeah and I think that
that speaks to you know trend you know
just like perfumes we have you know a
number of years ago sandalwood was
really popular and there all these
perfumes on the market that smelled like
sandalwood and then dude it was really
popular food oil was very popular and so
many perfumes out there that had food as
their you know primary aroma and so you
know I I can suspect that if we allow
the market to be driven by the sensory
experience of Canada's that we would see
very similar trends that things would
wax and wane over time chirpin almond
might you know to pennilyn might have
been hot this year but maybe next year
we'll have pining dominant you know cult
the viruses are frontrunners who knows
oh that's really interesting yeah so you
also found research around gender - if
that if that's right what I remember
from the presentation with Steph welcome
matter No yeah I mean so gender is a
social construct and specifically the
question we asked was biological sex and
the reason we asked the question that
way is because we know from
the scientific literature that cannabis
affects biological males and biological
females
differently you know there are different
rates of the development of tolerance to
th see there are different effects on
our hormonal systems so it was important
for us to see you know it can we
actually detect a sex difference and are
there kinds of cannabis that are
biologically better suited for men and
women our biological men and women and
so you know we were able to you know use
all of the data to find you know a
cultivar you know we thought we found
cultivars that were like equally amongst
men and women these are like outstanding
flowers that one for whatever other
reasons that they want but we were able
to find you know one standout flower
that produce a really nice effect and a
very desirable aroma for women but the
men were kind of like oh that's one that
we we deemed that one that was the
ladies Choice Award so that that was
that's a beautiful flower and it just so
happens to be my personal favorite as
well so it's a type 2a you know roughly
6 percent THC it's a lovely lovely Cold
War thank you for correcting me on the
biological versus gender differences
thank you I appreciate that yeah it's
important to highlight that and then I
realized the way that came across so
yeah that's I think that's important and
personally for myself the the one flower
that I really enjoyed happened to be a
type 2 flower called kava that was grown
by up here by a company called gold leaf
so these type twos yeah the type twos
have very I think that this is where we
have a lot of promise in the future of
the industry is with these type twos you
know like this like you were saying your
personal experience with cannabis is
that yeah like you might feel sleepy but
your mind is going crazy and to me
that's very indicative of a frankly a
THC overdose so what what's possible
below that threshold of intoxication so
if you you
there's two ways you can do that you can
slowly dial back from 20 20 and 30%
flowers and see what you feel or you
could work your way up from hemp you
know starting with a heavy hunt product
and then you know especially for a new
consumer who has an intolerance you know
the the easiest way to not have a bad
time is to not consume too much THC so
so yeah this is where I think the type 2
flowers are really valuable because one
they're balanced with CBD which is you
know experimentally been shown to reduce
the paranoia and anxiety that's produced
by PhD so if you're consuming them in
roughly equal amounts great you're
protecting yourself from that paranoia
to begin with
you've got enough THC on board to get
yourself into the therapeutic window and
what I mean by that is if we look in
medicine every drug has a therapeutic
window where you have to take a certain
dose where the patient feels it but if
you take too high of a dose then
negative side effects start to happen
and this is exactly the same with THC
but if you take it out of the context of
medicine and just look at enjoyment you
got to get up into the therapeutic
window so that you can feel it but you
can't take so much that now you have
racing thoughts racing heart dry eyes
dry mouth blah blah blah blah so you
know these type 2 flowers have an
immense potential to have wide appeal
across many different kinds of people
for many different kinds of purposes
because they're just less risky I like
that and that fits with me one of the
things
Jeff lowenfeld said he was asked you
know what's the most potent flower
you've ever tried and things like that
and all these questions and basically
what he what he said around it which I
thought was a good point was like hey we
don't need to go stronger and stronger
like that's that's not the that's not
the solution like you can always you
know take another hit you know you can
always have a little bit more let's stop
trying to get this you know like I said
like these 25-30 percent THC dominant
flowers and yeah it sounds like your
research is sort of supporting that
concept so you actually have some data
to support that now and I guess what I'm
wondering is how
how does this impact growers so let's
talk a little bit about that so as a
grower how can I use this information to
better you know cultivate and sell my
product ma'am this I love this question
so much and thank you for asking it I
want to start the answer with an
anecdote so one of our judges is also a
cultivator in the cultivation classic so
and and he's been involved in this
process since the very beginning
he's always submitted flower and I think
he's always been a judge he might have
missed a year um but in one of his early
years you know we gave him his feedback
we revealed at the end hey these were
all the flowers that you liked the best
and he was shocked to find that some of
his most favorable responses were to
flowers that had a really high CBD
content and he was kind of bummed
because he had absolutely zero CBD in
his garden so what did he do he went
back and he introduced some CBD and some
more balanced phytochemistry into his
garden and you know their business was
doing really great he's got wonderful
wonderful products on the market but
it's not all that surprising so if you
ask these cultivators like what is your
what is your most treasured flower that
you're producing a lot of them will say
man I've got this purple girl who's like
14 to 17 percent THC she smells like you
know Flintstone vitamins and it's just
the most beautiful thing best experience
it's transcendental I can't sell it
because it's less than 20% THC so the
cultivators already know this and the
consumers if they're if they ever have
an opportunity to try and moderate you
know potency flower they often will also
say yeah I can only take one hit or
wouldn't it be nice if I could take two
hits like you know cuz I really enjoy it
I like the taste of it I like the
experience but you know those potent
flowers just that it's not fun for me so
the customer often knows it sometimes
they don't you know there's still a ton
of THC hunting out there but the
customer you know is is
to realize that you know potency is not
necessarily the best so the cultivator
knows it and the consumer sometimes
knows it but there's a really critical
sort of choke point at the intake level
at retail intake so I've talked to
retail intake managers in Washington who
literally tell me my boss won't let me
buy any flowers that has less than 17
percent THC those flowers have literally
been cut out of the market
so those ones that fit so beautifully in
the therapeutic window that are so
wonderfully produced in the full Sun
with a rich terpene profile and moderate
potency those flowers that are the most
enjoyable are ironically the ones that
are least likely to be found on the
dispensary shelf it's a real shame yeah
I think it's a big problem so how do we
address that as a society how do we
educate consumers to select flowers that
are you know going to be more enjoyable
for them over time how do we move away
from this sort of THC dominant thought
process yeah I think that it requires
this is a big problem that doesn't have
one solution I think we need to address
the problem from multiple angles
you know we clearly need widespread PSA
level information like hey you're too
high on a billboard but we also need you
know bud tenders and and and intake
managers who have the education as well
to be able to pass on that knowledge
directly at the counter where when they
have a consumer who comes in and says
what's the most THC I can get you know
for my six dollars a gram then the
budtender could say well you you could
take that moonshine route and why don't
you also try this other thing because
you know like yeah that'll get you mess
up but we have this other thing which
might actually be more enjoyable so I
think that it is you know a multi-modal
approach we need to have bud tenders who
really
not only you know get this information
but they experience it for themselves
you know the intake managers are open to
producing higher values monetary values
for type 2 flowers and flowers with
moderate potency and of course you know
like a widespread you know public
education campaign about you know like
THC and all it's cracked up to be
I told Leah Gris I hope that I hope
you're right my concern is is it from a
growing perspective as a cultivator you
know it's risky to try and cultivate a
flower that's under 17% that may not
sell sell on the on the shelf is it
possible to use this data as a consumer
facing approach to where this could be
near the flower or out by the flowers
and people could say hey we're seeing
these responses on this flower give it a
try yes
absolutely and that's one of the huge
benefits from our processes that we're
able to take this data and feed it back
to the cultivator and feed it back to
the consumer so our judges at the end
you know they get access to all of their
you know we unblind them and tell them
what they liked the best and they go wow
I had no idea just like you know that
cultivator anecdote that I told you
earlier so yeah I would love to see that
deployed at a larger scale level and we
have some projects that we're working on
that are moving toward that you know
really enabling that consumer to have a
personalized experience but you know is
is based on their own experience with
different cultivars of cannabis and yeah
you're absolutely right that this is a
risk like you have to all of the you
know decisions wholesale and retail
level are currently being made on
historical data right we're looking
backwards to see what sold last quarter
and a quarter before that and the
quarter before that and that's where
we're assuming that the future is a
hundred percent dependent upon the past
when really what we need is to not ask
you know
what do people think they want to buy
but really what do people actually need
so it's less looking backward to see
what sold previously and more looking
forward about what people will be buying
in the future because it's a more
enjoyable experience and that's
precisely what this what this project is
aimed at doing yeah so what do you see
for the future of this industry I know
we've kind of touched on it a little bit
but was there anything else you wanted
to add to that in terms of what you're
seeing or how you what direction you see
is going for sure you know I think that
what we have learned from other
agricultural products is that you know
as things happen with corporate
consolidation there's this trend toward
monocropping and producing an
agricultural product for yield and
producing a product for yield at scale
is like the entirely opposite thing that
our data reveals which is that these you
know craft types of artists and flowers
are the ones that tend to be the most
diverse and terpenes the most
interesting and and desirable smelling
and the ones that produce the most
enjoyable experiences so you know I
would hope that this industry would take
an evidence-based approach as well as a
practical one in that we need to have
sustainable products that aren't you
know pulling resources out of this earth
and we need to be putting products into
our bodies that don't burn out our
endocannabinoids systems and put us at
risk for cannabis use disorder and
hyperemesis and all the other health
risks that are associated with potent
THC products I completely understand
where how we got to the place we are
where everyone is trying to push their
certificates of analysis up to that 30
percent mark but the reality is that
when you give people a chance to consume
cannabis in a blinded fashion that's
just not what they want so I think it's
going to take some growing pains and I
think it's going to take some leaps of
faith it's gonna take you know a small
part of the garden dedicated to you know
a nice moderate potency flower and just
kind of cross your fingers and see what
happens with that guy but I think that
there is a moderate path here you know I
don't think it makes sense to completely
just like flip the market overnight
where all of a sudden you know noe is
growing 25% flowers anymore but the slow
introduction of you know more diverse
products is why because we have more
diverse people than ever before using
cannabis for more diverse reasons than
ever before so you know it if you think
about your 4th of July barbecue you know
you've got kids in the pool and the
barbecues on and every adults in the
yard is standing there with a beer in
their hand and at any point something
happens with one of the kids in the pool
you know any adult can drop the gear put
the kid in the car and get to the
emergency room but what is the
equivalent of cannabis right what what
what kind of cannabis is that I I can
still drive and I can take my kids to
the emergency room kind of cannabis what
is the you know Sunday afternoon hike
what is the 6 a.m. yoga before I have to
go to work and be at my desk at 9:00
a.m. you know there there are lots of
different kinds of people using cannabis
for more reasons than ever before and it
would make sense to produce lots of
diverse products which would fit all of
those diverse mean yeah one question I
forgot to ask you that I was thinking of
is did you see any difference between
outdoor versus indoor grown flower on
these scales or is that something you
tracked and I know you haven't looked at
organic versus conventionally grown
cannabis but is that on the radar at all
either no honestly we don't really have
any interest in looking at
conventionally grown cannabis because we
believe that organically grown cannabis
is the right thing to do we believe that
you know this is better for the earth
it's better for the human so I don't
foresee that we're going to be looking
at conventionally grown cannabis we have
definitely looked at light
but if I go back to those that the top
ten you know the the most enjoyable -
least enjoyable I believe the majority
of those were cultivated with
supplemental light so the way that we
ask the question is you know like this
could be any supplemental light so it
could be in a greenhouse with with some
light but you know with a greenhouse we
also or a hoop house you often still get
the full spectrum that you know a Sun
only flower would get so that's how
that's how we differ things but yeah I
mean people like both indoor and outdoor
ones you know equally it seems I can
tell you from a phytochemical level we
we see the most diverse you know we tend
to see them the widest array of terpenes
expressed by you know flowers that are
produced in the Sun that makes that
makes sense
I could I could see that just based on
the spectrum analysis
you mentioned cannabis and I'm gonna
mispronounce it hi Piper menses how do
you how do you say that word yeah hyper
hyper emesis have you seen any research
to support what is causing this I've
heard people correlated supposedly with
as interacting a name and a variety of
other things I've heard people blame it
on oh I can't remember there were there
a variety of things theories have you
seen any actual reason yeah on this yeah
this is a very active field and I can
tell you 100% it comes from over
stimulating the endogenous cannabinoids
system with cannabinoids it is not
related to toxins it's not related to
pesticides it's not a side effect of
mean you know that that theory you know
kind of went viral and it was very
widely adopted for a long time but you
know in looking at you know both of
zooming in to the receptors where
cannabinoids bind you know that's a
molecular level as well as everything
that's you know reported by physicians
in the emergency departments who are
treating these people who have hyper and
all of the evidence is pointing toward
this is a cannabinoid mediated effect
interacting with the endogenous
cannabinoids system so it seems to be
causing people that are extremely heavy
users is it something that it builds up
over time and then think it can hit at
any point or is there are there things
that are triggering it for certain users
is it's not cultivar specific or related
in any way or anything like that you
know I these are all excellent questions
that I think we have some evidence to
support that yes you're absolutely right
this this tends to happen in heavy users
you know people who use very frequently
for very long periods of time we don't
know exactly which molecules may be
contributing or or that is you know
which team of ours or cultivars of
cannabis are contributing to this effect
but you know it makes it makes sense
that a lot of these heavy users are
using very potent products and it's very
very likely that it is a THC mediated
effect and you know what how you could
balance that risk with you know a more
diverse both of are a type two cultivar
that had more CBD totally unknown at
this point and frankly it's going to be
a long time before we understand that
because we need the federal guidelines
to you know turn around so that we can
do that kind of research and collect
that data you know in a controlled
manner great well I'm glad we got to
touch on that too because it's something
that's been in the back of my brain for
a while so it's good to hear some real
information on that but yeah I really
appreciate you coming on the show today
and sharing a lot of this cuz I think
that I hope this is the direction of
cannabis consumption in the future and I
think we need these science-based tools
to really make informed decisions I know
here in Washington we're not allowed to
even smell the flower so you really
don't even know we can't make that
correlation between smell and enjoyment
like you mentioned so yeah was there
anything else you want to share with
listeners before before I let you go for
the day yeah I mean like I you know
briefly I think that what you've just
mentioned is a huge problem for
consumers you know here we have data
telling us
that this is the most important
indicator of an enjoyable experience an
aroma and yet you're completely
depriving the consumer of the ability to
make an informed decision and you're
forcing them to make a decision based on
potency which we know is bad because
potency promotes all of the health risks
so you know I I would love if your
regulators in Washington and in
California and in all those other
markets where you know consumers aren't
allowed to stand all the products you
know we need to be able to pass this
information on and say hey like this is
a really important biological
decision-making factor that it's not
fair to deprive the consumers of I mean
I would agree with that wouldn't be the
first time regulation got in the way of
things that made sense right yeah and
you know you mentioned odor and odor is
another whole nother topic I feel like
because it is so complex and you
mentioned that there are even terpenes
that we aren't even measuring at this
point potentially or understanding like
with your allusion to hops
yeah and and not even necessarily
terpenes you know there are other
aromatic compounds that produce aromas
that are not terpenes you know so we
have aldehydes and ketones and other
molecules that are present in hops and
in grapes and in roses and in cannabis
you know we have those other molecules
that produce aromas that are not
terpenes or terpenoids and nobody is
nobody is looking for those so and
you're absolutely right that you know
the sensory component is a whole other
you know sixteen minute episode in and
of itself you know like what smells are
there and in what intensity and who can
who can differentiate between them and
who is sensitive to these smells and who
isn't and what is what is that more
rigorous relationship between the aroma
and the experience this is yeah it's a
huge area of opportunity for exploration
well I'm super grateful to have you on
the show I really appreciate your time
today
I hope maybe I can get you guys back on
as more research you know comes out in
what you guys are studying and we'll go
from there so thank you yeah that sounds
great tad we've got a lot more projects
planned for 2020 so it would be a
pleasure to come back and share our
updated findings and yeah I will see you
guys at the cultivation classic at the
very least I plan on attending have we
have you set a date for 2020 yet yeah
the last weekend in Mays was after
Memorial Day okay and people can go to
cultivation classic dot CC to check out
that website I'm gonna put all the
information relating to this website and
maybe even some of the data if you're
open to sharing it I can put that on the
website podcast page - awesome sounds
great
all right well thanks I will look
forward to talking again soon all right
that was dr. eighty ray and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey don't forget to check out our
website at WWE is organics calm for more
information and resources and links to
topics we discussed on the show today
and while you're there please sign up
for our newsletter on our website
homepage so you can stay up to date and
give us a follow on instagram @ k is
organics thanks for listening
[Music]