[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is dr anna paltzeva
as an international urban soil scientist
and assistant professor
dr paltzeva's mission is to educate
communities about the critical
importance of soil health in growing
nutritious food supporting healthy
ecosystems and helping to reduce harmful
greenhouse gases
her expertise is in helping people
identify and remediate soil
contamination in urban gardens she has a
passion to help others to understand the
impact of heavy metals on the health of
soils and the best way to improve soil
quality
in addition to her appointment at the
university of louisiana at lafayette she
is taught at new york university cooney
brooklyn college and the new york
botanical and brooklyn botanical gardens
this has led to her creating the delta
urban soils laboratory at ull that
provides soil testing services and
informal education to communities and
businesses across the country now on to
the show
hi anna thanks for coming on the show
today
hi i'm so glad to be here and share what
i know about soils and hopefully get
excited people excited to test their
tools and learn more what's in their
soil
absolutely absolutely so i found out
about you through bryant mason of soil
doctor consulting he had mentioned you
to me in regards to heavy metals
but can you just give you know listeners
a little bit of background into uh who
you are and what you're doing
of course so i am dr anna beltwa i'm
also known
by anya which is russian nickname
i grew up in russia in the south of
russia in my parents garden i used to
play in
this dirt when i was a child
and this
childhood game became my career
eventually but both of my
parents are agronomists and they taught
me how to
take care
soil our land and grow our own
vegetables
and food
so i brought my family trade to the next
level
by
conducting research in urban
soil in
urban agriculture and i got my doctorate
degree in earth and environmental
sciences
at the city university of new york
graduate center
a couple years ago
and basically since then well for the
last seven years since i started my phd
i focused on urban agriculture urban
soil contamination
and soil testing which also led me to
open up recently my very own delta urban
source laboratory at the university of
louisiana at
where i'm currently an assistant
professor in environmental sciences
that's so wonderful and i i think your
area of research is just really
fascinating when we talk about urban
soils
you know trying to grow food in the city
uh is really challenging and the big
issue is is content soil contamination
related to
you know things that we're dumping into
the soils things that are leaching into
the soils and these heavy metals
can you talk about
some of the research that you did around
around heavy metals
of course yeah so the
starting well when is yeah started like
2013 when my phd advisor offered me to
do a test
on
studying bio accessibility of web and
back then i didn't know what by
accessibility was but basically now i
can easily define it as a fraction of
harmful contaminants or metals like lead
that we determine in soil in order to
understand how that particular fraction
uh can affect
human health
so
basically what
we find is that not all
metals are harmful
and not all total concentrations are
harmful so let's take a lead for example
if we find uh with a standard method
that
there is um
like 1000 parts per million of latin
soil it's a very high number but it
doesn't mean that all of this one
thousand parts per million is going to
be harmful for humans or plants it
really depends on what form the sled
exists in soil and this form
will determine the bioaccessibility
it can be low or it can be high
depending on the chemical state of this
metal if it's let's say um
lead it will combine with organic matter
with the phosphates it will be very
stable thereby accessibility will be low
so let will be present still in the soil
but it's not going to be uh harmful or
at least a much lower level
harmful to plants or humans but if it
exists in the form of
like lead carbonates it may be more
soluble in the environment thus more
harmful so my research started with
assessing different methods on
um
specifically on the accessibility of
lead
and it led me to develop two
different methods in collaboration with
the
columbia university research group and
university of bolasea in italy research
group
on how we use instruments to
by accessibility of lead in soil using
um x-ray fluorescent analyzer machine
and another one was visible near
infrared spectroscopy
this uh method allow us to
quicker assess the harmful fraction of
the soil not just total concentrations
uh
and uh be able to test more soils so
samples at a shorter period of time
so
so what you're saying is
it's really important to look at how
bioaccessibility in that how
easily can the plant uptake
that particular heavy metal and um one
of the factors that you mentioned is the
the form that that heavy metal is
in the chem the actual chemical form of
that of that heavy metal in terms of
what it's bonded to
um what are some of the other factors
like i just off the top of my head here
i'm thinking that um plant selection
would play a big role ph
um the
hydrology or the amount of moisture in
the soil
how do all of these sort of come
together in terms of determining um
you know if you can grow a safe crop in
the in a given soil
that's a great question and all of those
factors it did have a huge role in the
availability of metals and soil
and uh we found that a plant type is
actually a more important uh
than amendment type that we tried to use
to remediate soils because plants would
react differently some plants would take
up more lead and arsenic that we studied
some of them would not or it would be
more susceptible to
get contaminants on the leaf surfaces
for example like leafy greens spinach or
lettuce from splashes from surging areas
or
dusty positions
so really plant selection plays a huge
role which also means that we can grow
some vegetables in
moderately contaminated soil
uh
if those like we grow tomatoes or
eggplants or squash something that will
be growing further from the surf surface
of the soil because plants have
physiological barriers inside of them
like food vegetables and if they grow
further from the soil then it will not
have a
splash from surrounding areas
and then it will leafy greens and then
root vegetables will be of course more
susceptible to this level contamination
another factor like
ph that you mentioned which is really
huge is that
most of metals will be least available
at ph close to neutral so
like slightly acidic to neutral ph
metals will be least available while
nutrients will be mostly available
so nature is smart as i like to say it
makes nutrients available and metals no
but once it drops ph drops to very
acidic levels it can make
lead and arsenic for example more
available for
plant uptake or human impact so it's
really important to keep ph close to
neutral as possible organic matter is
another one that's really important to
mention because it burns lead
or some other metals and forms organic
mineral complexes which are more or less
stable
and it will take time for organic method
to degrade to release those metals again
so we found it to be an effective way to
remediate soils by adding compost to
contaminated sites
and on top of that it also has a
dilution effect when we add the extra
volume of compost or any other organic
amendments to the soil
it dilutes the over concentration of
metal in that soil plus vegetables that
grow in that soil will typically have a
high yield as would be larger in size
so
it also creates a second dilution effect
in a let's say tomato food
um
or an eggplant
so compost is really great way to
remediate contaminated soil
another factor is also you mentioned
moisture indeed it's good to have a
moisture in soil especially with if it's
the summer and it's very
very windy or
it's like it's a
area that's susceptible to erosion so
moisture helps to reduce dust and
redistribute contamination so it's
really good to have it
another factor is a
soil composition is it centrosol or clay
soils
clay soils may hold more contaminants as
much as they hold nutrients while sandy
soils more permeable and that consists
of cords and cords doesn't really hold
uh hold on much
of nutrients or contaminants on their
surfaces so there will be more leaching
happening in san diego compared to clay
soils
that will act like a sponge
you're referencing the cec or cation
exchange capacity of a soil and the
higher the cec the higher the ability to
retain heavy metals in that soil
yes there are cations the positive
metals yeah yeah and then what about the
anions though
in a higher c
soil would you still see more anion
retention
they
there's a possibility they will be leach
out more
okay in the ground like arsenic is more
leachable for example than
lead light will stay in the soil it's
not very mobile but arsenic that
typically in a negative form the arsenic
arsenide will uh susceptible to
leaching and moving down in the soil
profile
so um
you mentioned compost now i think of
compost as a source of soil
contamination in terms of heavy metals
as well depending on
where that compost is sourced because
i mean frankly locally a lot of the
municipal composts um
aren't really doing good testing and
they're composting some some uh
you know i think
somewhat uh mixed material where
people are throwing stuff into their
yard ways that they shouldn't be
essentially um so
how
how does one evaluate compost
to know if what they're adding is
actually going to be decreasing their
heavy metal load or or potentially
increasing it
great point and we also found that the
some compost that were buying for our
research
contain elevated concentrations of
metals that shouldn't be there
and of course we didn't use them for
research but it was a really interesting
discovery
to answer a question basically testing
is important you
should
periodically test samples or bags of
compost or any other amendment that you
buy in the market
and it's a really good investment if you
want to make sure you're not adding
additional heavy metal concentrations
uh you will still get some of the metals
because metals
you know they present in plain tissues
but they should be at a low
concentration
unless those composts are made from
contaminated manure or from trees uh
leaves from the trees that grow next to
road
um
other type of compost if it's like you
make your homemade compost it's going to
have very minimal
metal concentrations it shouldn't be
harmful so testing is really important
to understand what levels you add into
the soil so you don't create
accumulation of this metals and i think
that that's the answer you either make
your compost yourself and you know what
you put on the compost or you test what
you buy
and you know so for one of the things i
want to talk about with you is the fact
that um
i agree testing is so important but it's
been it's been not affordable for people
it's been way too cost prohibitive i
know when i first got
my soil mix tested a potting soil
to make sure that we were meeting the
requirements of a fertilizer because of
the amount of nutrients we're putting on
it's a much higher requirement so if i
were just going to sell potting soil i
wouldn't have to test it for heavy
metals and that's what 99
of the industry does right now um
and so we we don't really know what
heavy metals are in our potting soils
because no one's testing them and no
one's testing the vegetables if you
register as a fertilizer it's a higher
requirement anyway long story short the
cost to do that was a few hundred
dollars it was quite expensive um
and then i get a guaranteed analysis and
then i can put this gets publicly
published um
but i i agree with you this is really
important but as a homeowner i also
wanted to test my
soil in my backyard because i wanted to
grow vegetables but being that it was a
suburban area you know i didn't know
what construction had been done on the
property before i before i bought it and
you know i didn't know if things had
been dumped here by a previous homeowner
or things had leached so
talk to me about this this lab testing
that you're doing and you know the
pricing and just how amazing this is now
is a way for people to test their soils
yes you brought up really great points
it's important to know
land use history land management
history of your property
and if it's possible to find those
documents or maybe look up on some epa
websites they always have really great
uh
tactic maps or information on the area
so you could get an idea what
potentially could be in your soil and
see the proximity to
highways or form industrial sites at
least get an idea what could be found in
your soil
the in terms of testing in the labs
of course commercial laboratories
they would charge certain amounts of
dollars for their testing typically
university labs are much more
affordable
from my experiences working at
new york and brooklyn college and here
it's lafayette
we
not doing it for profit it's not for
private organization really we use this
lab
expenses or cost
to cover um
the materials
uh we used to to test the soil
and really support students so
the method we're using for example to
test ex
heavy metals is an express technique uh
it's actually called exportable x-ray
fluorescent um analyzer instrument
that we used a lot in new york and we
have here in lafayette and it's uh
reduces the cost because the machine
itself is much
less expensive than mass spectrometers
that uh commercial labs typically use
and those mass spectrometers of course
provide high accuracy and precision but
modern xrf uh machines they have
actually um
good results they're very reliable a4
are properly prepared
and the way we achieve this uh relative
accuracy is by
um let's say you send me soul sample we
will analyze it by first
dry in the oven reducing the moisture
condition like get rid of any of the
moisture then sieve it to two millimeter
size to create the homogeneity of the
sample and then measure this uh soil in
special cups with a special film that
does not have impurities on it
on this extract machine and it's a
result that give us close
proximities to the mass spectrometers
and this reduces the cost because the
instrument is much less expensive than
mass spectrometers and it requires less
time to prepare and analyze soils
because when you do a mass spectrometer
analysis it takes a few days when you
have to prepare the sample like dry it
save it through then you have to weigh
it very small
numbers like
0.2 or 0.3 grams and then you have to uh
add
different assets to it so
you have to put it in the microwave or
in a hot plate and then they have to run
into mass spectrometers so it will take
several hours then you have to process
the data so all of this will require
more time and of course
more it becomes more expensive when you
have to pay for
the time of the lab technician assets
for machine spms maintenance maintenance
is quite expensive so
what we have been using here is this
extra portable machine that allows
much faster results and
less time
to process the
salt soil samples it can be also
fertilizers it can be
different amendments compost some sort
of
solids that we can
analyze
in those
xrf cups that they call the small
plastic cup that we use for the machine
and we need typically
at least like one centimeter depth of
the material to analyze it
so if i understand you correctly you're
saying that the methodology that you use
is
uh
not maybe not quite as accurate
as a mass spectrometer but it correlates
well so it'll give you within a a fairly
good standard deviation of what you
would get from a mass spectral
spectrometer but the method itself is
dramatically less expensive and much
faster
so um
it's just a huge savings in both time
and money so
we've been using your labs now for a few
months
testing uh you know formulations for uh
fertilizers as well as our so our
potting soils
i haven't tested any actual soils with
you yet
but that's something i'm looking forward
to in the future too but
you have the ability to test all of
these things
correct yes and also the good point to
to notice that
this procedure is like having it
um
slightly less precise and accurate than
mass spectrometers but you can test more
samples with this uh
for the same amount of money you could
test more samples and it will resemble
variability of your soil or potting mix
or whatever you're doing
because the
soil typically is very ortho mixes very
heterogeneous and soil in general is
super heterogeneous at your property
your soil on the lawn versus soil next
to foundation of the house or under a
tree or in your vegetable garden might
be very different
so it's better to test more samples as a
slightly lower accuracy
but get a larger number of samples so
you get a better understanding of what's
actually happening in your soil and
unless you're doing analytical chemistry
it doesn't matter if you're
um i don't know if you got like 25 parts
per million of lead versus 20 parts per
million applied you know so it's um
it's really important to detect the hot
spots of contaminants and compare them
to guidelines to see if they're higher
or lower
and i think for regard for an average
gardener that's more important to test
more samples to understand what's
happening in the entire property than
just test one representative sample
on the
expensive machine
versus have multiple samples tested
that's a really really good point and
from a statistical perspective by
increasing your end value the number of
samples that you're taking you know i
could probably take eight eight or nine
samples for the price of what it would
have cost me to go with the mass
spectrometer
i can i can graph those and and plot
them and then come up with a more
consistent value across
all of those that would probably be as
accurate or even more accurate of what's
actually going on in my soil or in my
fertilizer than you know one one sample
so
that's that's a that's a really good
point you brought up there
yeah and this is the something that the
labs university labs i have noticed for
reading research not just in the united
states but in some other countries as
well start using more and more there's
my ref method it's uh there are epa or
usda methods uh
how to use i think it's epa
um
protocol so it developed to just follow
the procedure how to prepare a sample
and analyze it which also a discussion
also allows to
test soil
in a
natural environment like outside
of course the result may be less
accurate because if it's moist or it's
more heterogeneous
but still if you go around
the sheet or even the
garden we can detect the hot spots of
high levels of metals and collect those
specific samples
um
and it's really good to understand
variability in the garden or in the city
like this is what i'm aiming to do in my
research is to analyze
soil in lafayette and see how metals are
distributed here
and this instrument allows us to do it
in a real-time
setting when we go around we analyze it
we get the data within 90 seconds and
then we can collect samples from
highly contaminated areas and bring them
to the lab
for further more accurate analysis
now in your research how are you finding
uh soil depth or compaction influences
heavy metals like are the heavy metals
more at the surface of the soil because
i know you were talking about dust and
things like that or are you finding them
further down like could i grow a crop
that's a deep rooting
crop as a way of of potentially helping
remediate them or am i less likely to
have contamination growing
you know something like a lettuce that's
a very
low rooting yeah so it's typically
closer to topsoil or on top of the soil
if you don't add compost to your soil
just say it's normal soil
you will see it's a closer to the
surface or
really like top soil that most likely
contaminated from all these deposits
over the last um i don't know like 100
years that lead has been used
uh where other metals been used and
deposited from industrial sites from
highways from lead paint
if you add something like your compost
over and over every year then of course
your bearing burning your contaminants
under
which is another remediation technique
by the way with burning contamination on
the compost layer
uh so we ask top soil is most likely
going to be contaminated uh surface soil
compared to
subsoil and dust and splashes is
something to be concerned about if soul
is contaminated and if there are any
children around it's really important to
make sure
kids are not playing in contaminated
soil
that's a really good point so even if
you don't plan on growing vegetables if
you live in an urban environment this
would be a very simple way to just make
sure that your yard is safe
for your kids to play yes
it's even more important than for
vegetables because vegetables
as i said like they pick it they can
some of them can grow
well and safely some of them like
carrots should not be grown in
contaminated soil but for children it's
imperative to test
soil the backyard to make sure the kids
are not exposed because the primary
pathway of heavy metal exposure for
people is actually
ingestion and house does
so
children who are playing in the
backyard on a bare soil they would touch
fingers and then lick their fingers
ingesting potentially contaminated soil
and this should be avoided and to do
that first test the soil see what the
levels you're getting and then
plant some lawn on top or put some some
sort of fabric some protection layer so
children are not exposed to bare soil so
definitely parents who have small
children should test their soil just to
prevent potential exposure
yeah that's a great point i as a new
parent to a two-year-old i am always
thinking about this as someone who
thinks about soil a lot and right now
we're living with my in-laws and they
live on a golf course and i watch the
chemical applications that are happening
onto the grass on the golf course
and i don't want my daughter to lay
anywhere near that grass
for a lot of those reasons so
you know i think as parents that's
something we definitely want to be
thinking about and i know i've seen
research that shows that children uptake
these
chemicals and and i'm assuming these
heavy metals quite readily uh
even sometimes
more so than adults
so
i i think that's a wonderful point for
people that live in cities or in areas
that have been contaminated
i'm thinking of oklahoma just because i
do a lot of work in oklahoma and
i know there's a lot of contamination
sites there
so you know parents please do consider
getting your soil tested and we'll list
all the ways to uh
or the method to go about getting a hold
of anna and submitting samples to her
lab on on the podcast page
so people can get that information and
absolutely get a hold of you for this
um
so let's and we have also practices how
to remediate soil in case it's
contaminated i will share those
resources as well that was my next
question so let's say i send in my
sample to you and whether i'm growing
cannabis vegetables i just want to
protect my child and know
the ground safe
it comes back with high levels of
arsenic or high levels of lead or
cadmium
what do i do
yeah so it will depend on how high those
levels are but uh
and where the how big the distribution
is it's the whole garden or just a
vegetable plot
so some of the basic techniques to
remediation
is
adding compost
or some sort of organic metal like mulch
or something else that will help to
dilute the soil
and um bind metals with this organic
matter
another option um
is to put lawn on top
uh there's some sort of grasses though
they'll to
cover uh bare soil so there's no dust
there's no erosion happening
reducing the potential runoff of the
soil
we can uh
so plenty of vegetation adding compost
or some sort of organic amendments you
can try and change uh chemistry of these
metals by adding a phosphate amendment
or phosphate fertilizers
although we found it
would be tricky for
an average person
to figure out how much to add and how
long it will take to break down there
are some studies that uh did successful
job with the
change in your chemistry of lead and
converting it to program work it's a
stable plus a light phosphate mineral
but for an average person it can be
tricky to add i and someone
sometimes
if it's possible you can bring a new
soil and you clean a sediment um from
if it's some organic methane of course
for nutrient content from another area
some people
take it from
maybe like a farmland they know it's
clean or in new york for example there's
a program that's called the clean soul
bank when actually distributes a glacier
sediment
um
of two community organizations it's
mostly sand but it's clean it's pristine
because it's uh was
collected from
deep layers when the foundation of a new
building is being constructed
and that glacier sediment in the
community garden let's say can be mixed
with the compost to provide nutrition
value
and successful plants can grow and of
course it's
much much safer for children so if there
is a way to bring a new
soil it's a possibility
using raised bed soil
or build a raised bed on top of
contaminated soil it's an option if you
don't worry about children if you don't
have a
small kid and you only want to grow
vegetables and you don't want to do any
amendments or any compost additions then
grow tomatoes
they
found to be
um at the monthly grown well in the
modern contaminated soils because they
have physiological barriers inside of
them that prevent
metals to be uptaken uh to foods and
they're further from the surface that
tall plants and they don't really have
uh
splashes from surrounding areas so those
will be very simple
techniques
uh probably least expensive of course
you can excavate it and bring absolutely
new soil but it will be more expensive
so so we've been talking about soil as
the primary
source of contamination
but can we talk a little bit about
where this is all coming from it's not
like that soil started out contaminated
um
where where is this contamination coming
from and how do we limit that in you
know not just our gardens but also our
homes
uh good good question so
one thing to know that the metals
naturally occur in soil from parent
materials such as rocks and minerals but
those levels are typically very low
and they're not harmful to people
because they're natural sources
hello we do have anthropogenic sources
of metals which in most cases is
industrial sites it's uh roads cars
vehicles and
paint
leaded paint of course it has been
banned since 1978 but lead paint is
still on some old houses
so it's important for people to know
what kind of pain they have on houses if
they if they live
in them
and they know they're
before 1970 so the most likely will have
some
lead so it's really important to know
that part and then do testing of
surrounding areas if possible you can
even test paying cheap these days as
well
so it's important to reduce the house
dust so especially if there are children
in the house
by doing a cleaning just like you know
with a
some
wet napkin or something for the so they
could to bring down the dust that's just
one of the
main sources inside of the house and
this dust can come from you know from
windows from open doors from shoes that
people work outside or walk just outside
and bring this dust and dirt into the
house so to avoid this leave shoes
outside
uh or change shoes when you walk inside
don't bring
dirty
instruments from the garden into the
house and do um
wet cleaning like wash floors and wash
window ceilings
uh so yeah those are basic
recommendations uh to reduce
contamination inside of the houses um we
cannot change land you do use history of
locations where we live you know they
had some industry industrial sites in
the past but we can
control our environment inside of our
homes by just doing good cleaning
periodically and testing
what's um
surrounding our houses and knowing the
history of the house or at least when it
was built
that's it that's a good point and one
other thing people i want people to
consider when we're talking about edible
crops and food crops is everything that
those roots or that soil is coming in
contact with so if you're going to build
a garden think about the material that
you're using to build with
even with fabric pots i've saw some
research some pots coming out of china
that showed high levels of lead so when
those roots hit that edge of fabric that
fabric pot they're being exposed to that
lead and they could potentially be
taking it up so
there's just a lot of things you have to
really think like a scientist or like a
detective when you start thinking about
read labels too yes yes so
um well great i want to kind of change
directions here um
we've been talking about heavy metals
related to gardening and urban soils um
since this is a
cannabis cultivation podcast and i know
your experience is not with cannabis i i
wanted to talk a little bit about
heavy metals that you know some of the
how that might relate to cannabis and
get your thoughts on some of this so
one of the things is in certain states
now they're testing the flower
for
arsenic cadmium and lead and
at fairly aggressive thresholds
and cannabis appears to be
a fairly
good at uptaking not just nutrients but
these heavy metals
and we are seeing some failures in
certain states based on uh the
methodology that people are using um
you've already talked about ways to sort
of reduce
heavy metal exposure
you know we're not testing vegetables
like this do you think that down the
road
policies might change in terms of how
how we're testing like maybe cannabis
might be
sort of an example for how we may
eventually test
vegetables
that's a very interesting question i
think uh
part of the answer here would be
to understand that cannabis is not a
simple plant it's hyper accumulated
plants and that plant basically
is capable of
uptaking metals from
soil and i think this is why
policy is really forcing on
measuring
cannabis
not so
all vegetables have taken up metals at
the same level so each vegetable of food
or berry or tree versus grass they have
their own capabilities how much they can
or willing even to uptake metals and how
they tolerate it
some can be
more susceptible
than others some plants may be
affected by
even low toxicity levels others can be
much higher some of them prevent
contaminants going into their tissues
like tomatoes so there's no
need as much as cannabis to test tomato
plants so it's really um
important to understand what type of
plant that is
and when it comes to hyper chemical
plants or plants that we know
can take
more metals than the average plants then
it needs to be
more vigorously
regulated
i'm not a policy person but like from a
science point of view that's how i see
it
i i mean i would love to see i would
love to go to the grocery store and
eventually have their be you know
conventionally grown organically grown
heavy metal free
you know have some of these new labels
that would allow me to make choices
because i would pay a little bit more to
know that what i'm buying is
is free of of certain contaminants
beyond you know just the organic
certification
um but
who knows that's a great point and i um
yeah
i don't know the answer to the question
but i think it's definitely more
interesting and it comes back to
uh testing and pricing for testing right
because we have to test everything
everything then every batch it will be a
lot of data a lot of processing a lot of
labs and a lot of delays
uh but i think having more vigorous food
testing is good and i know fao recently
was bringing it up that they were
collecting data from scientists around
the world on
i think it was mercury and fish they
wanted to see more data on it so i think
it is moving towards
uh food
safety testing um and metals and perhaps
other contaminants as well but it you
know it takes some time to
be able to test everything
so
can i share with you some of what i've
found in in cannabis um
related to heavy metals and please just
correct me if anything i find seems to
say seems odd or wrong or
inaccurate um
but since
since we've been we've been diving more
and more into this this heavy metal
thing because
we've had a few growers fail and you
know as someone who manufactures soil in
addition to this podcast
and the fact that we do organic soil and
organic amendments
you know there is always going to be
some heavy metal load in our soil and so
we're always looking at how to reduce
this because we use things like rock
dust which as you know contains
levels of heavy metals
and soft rock phosphate um
you know any mined product or
in my experience contains some level of
heavy metal so it's all about heavy
metal management we can't reduce it to
zero
but we want to make sure that we're not
overloading it and then
beyond that
keeping our ph a little more alkaline so
i like to run my ph higher than
traditional um
agronomic recommendations
um
probably closer six eight to seven range
rather than you know six four six five
like i see
like i see in a lot of places
um
it's sort of the sweet spot for me in
terms of having in terms of reducing
heavy metal risk but still allowing for
good nutrient availability
in terms of exposure so um you know i
just want to throw out there no one's
failed just using our soils we've always
found other sources of contamination
that were more significant
and really contributing to a fill
rate um
some of these were
water sources people thought they had
clean water but they were from a well
and they actually were bringing up
ground water in this case it was arsenic
i had another one in the facility that
was an old building in oklahoma city and
they were doing a lot of construction
and they were kicking up dust and that
dust was falling onto the leaves and
causing contamination
so that was a little bit of a tricky one
to figure out
even things like uh
sump pumps or
metals that are in contact with water
for a long time like in a reservoir or
through an irrigation system we found
can increase a heavy metal load
too um
so it's it's it's a challenge and you're
always trying to figure out what it is
and then
um
i i guess
one thing you brought up was phosphates
which i thought was really interesting
and how they might bind up um lead
you know one of the things that we find
with um
i've been trying to find a good
phosphorous source that was
vegan or not animal based and it's it's
really really hard um
all the ones i find are also bringing in
uh heavy metals
um i sent one sample to you of a soft
rock phosphate and it came back with you
know lead levels so how
one do you know of any great phosphate
sources that are going to be lower in
heavy metals
and then um
can you talk a little bit more about
this phosphate
binding
yeah also
that's a good question
on
sources one thing that came to my mind
is the
fish bones but it's not i mean you said
that you wanted it to be vegan or like
not animal products
but then yeah it's appetite uh it's a
traditional uh
rock mining you know mineral which is
running out so we need looking uh look
for other phosphate
um
sources but
yeah fish bones would be
non-vegan uh stores which might not have
as much heavy metals as anything else
otherwise i don't know it's it's hard to
think um
i have to think about this one and get
back to you if i find the resources
yeah it's
um typically
a fungi would help to release phosphorus
that's in the environment making it more
accessible for plant uptake
so
maybe there will be some mixes with
fungi that could be you
now i developed more uh
dr allison justice actually sent me a
paper a couple years ago out of italy
that showed uh with hemp increased
heavy metal uptake into the hemp biomass
with the addition of mycorrhizal fungus
which
makes sense to me because mycorrhizal
fungus increases
the nutrient uptake you know it's most
notably phosphorus
but um other nutrients as well and so
they saw higher levels of arsenic with
um
uptake with it which
which i just thought was interesting
research
um
so i i guess it may be my question
arsenic becomes more arsenic becomes
more available with phosphorus addition
while lead becomes less available with
phosphorus addition so that's a paradox
when both lead and arsenic are present
in the soil
yeah i didn't know that phosphorus might
not be
yeah so phosphorus might not be
the best solution if
soil is contaminated with most lead and
arsenic
when we did a test
for heavy metals
in
our research in new jersey we tested the
soil that was contaminated with lead and
arsenic
and we
added the different platforms
fertilizers and we added different
compost
and we saw that arsenic was more
available
did not
was not fixed by phosphorus obviously
because they start
competing
and arsenic becomes more mobilized but
compost was a better result for us and
so though
basically yeah it was more successful as
a remediation technique compared to
phosphorus fertilizers
that's that's really interesting um
now one thing you mentioned was that
arsenic is more leachable
than lead how
realistic is it for someone to
flush their soil or their their their
media as a way of reducing arsenic
levels is that going to make a
significant difference
oh that's an interesting question that
i'm not capable to enter fully because i
know there is such thing as an
industrial washing when like you know
they do it on a large scale and they can
wash soil
uh with water or maybe some other
solvents that help to remove
heavy metals but i don't know for
if it's sufficient for a person to do it
i just not something i've seen in
literature because i never was curious
about it until now
that's fair i i appreciate your honesty
i would think it's not
very super leachable just because we
still see it in areas that have heavy
you know fairly significant rainfall
right if there was a you know
exactly precipitation and natural yeah
so they maybe needed some technologies
to do that um
yeah to make it more effective
um
if it was like nitrates for example then
we would we would know fairly quickly it
would just disappear into our water um
yeah i wonder if there's a microbe down
the road that someone will discover that
will allow us to tie up these uh heavy
metals more efficiently that would be a
really cool invention or uh discovery i
guess we would say
yeah i think there are there are
research um research studies related to
that and
it looks promising to
just to find some microbes that are
converting
metals into less available forms or an
also fungi help to
convert lead to
paramorphic and you ask me earlier about
this
conversion so what basically happens is
when lead
is exposed to available phosphorus it
combines into paramorphite but you would
need a lot of phosphorus in the
environment to combine this light
efficiently and it will take some time
sometimes maybe a few years it depends
on the climate and the zone where the
site is located but the idea here is
that just lead becomes lead phosphate
mineral and it's very stable
and it's not
or
not by accessible or has very low by
accessibility so it's not really harmful
uh to people if it gets to human body so
like let's say a child consumes it it
will just go through the system and
you know just the child
poops it out
and not being
dissolved in a bloodstream compared to
other source or other forms of
lead
so paramorphic is really
good mineral to have but it
takes time naturally to form it or
artificially to form it if you want to
play around in your garden and try to
make this conversion yourself
so when we get a lab test back
that's not going to tell us the actual
form of
the arsenic or the lead so we won't know
how available this is to our plant we'll
just know that it's it's present
in some form
so good question uh there are different
methods how it's tested
metals can be measured in total
concentrations and
phytoavailable concentrations for plants
and in bioaccessible concentrations
total concentrations
it just gives us total numbers of how
much in total lead or arsenic or cadmium
in soil
phyto available those methods are using
extractions
to
see how much potentially can be uptaken
by plant or how much is available at
least for a plant
uh and it will be lower than total
concentration typically not all of it is
going to be available
this can be found in labs a lot of labs
testing for
[Music]
phytoavailable nutrients but also metals
and another question is bioaccessibility
i've seen only few labs around the
country who test
for that
for public it takes
more effort to
to do that method and like do sample
preparation and
the method is still there are different
methods how to use it there's an epa
method there's like european methods
different authors came up with the
different methods so they're um
hard to say which one is the best
and it's still a
tricky uh in some ways to assess the by
accessibility because when we do those
extractions we try to mimic
uh gastric solution in the lab condition
and it's really difficult to predict
what the human gastric system is
and you know like
our
chemistry of gastric solution changes if
like before we eat after we eat it will
respond differently potentially on the
metals we would consume and it's very
difficult to mimic this in the lab
conditions that's why there's some
methods that exist out there and the
labs don't really
not many labs offer those tests
to public if you get a chance to find a
lab
that
test for by accessibility you should do
at least several samples for you to get
an idea what numbers you're getting
okay so it's not very uh cost effective
necessarily or realistic for the average
person or grower to
to find that out yeah i don't know the
prices
yeah i don't know if they're like what
are the prices for them they're just not
as publicly available tests as i
seen like not every laboratory offers
that
okay okay
um and while you were talking about that
it got me thinking about one other
variable that i meant to mention that
we've kind of touched on is uh
not just uh crop selection in terms of
uh
variety but also
our species but also
um
cultivar selection so the amount of
genetic diversity we see in cannabis is
is
huge it's it's much larger than any
other
you know ornamental vegetable crop that
anyone would grow
so
we found that certain genetics
will uptake heavy metals much more
efficiently than others so just because
one genetic fails doesn't mean that
other ones will fail in that same soil
so that's just one other factor i mean
there's so many variables here when it
comes to heavy metal uptake that you've
that you've touched on um
it's just it's alone in the future
yes it is it's complicated
yes
so um
is there anything else that you would
like to share before we sign off in
regards to um your research or upcoming
research that you're really excited
about
well
uh currently i am working on the soul
survey for heavy metals in louisiana but
i always welcome samples from around the
country it's really interesting to see
what people are getting in their soils
or amendments or fertilizer so lab is
open to
other
people from across the country to send
the samples to us
i continue studying heavy metals in a
different form and shape and my current
research also involves
using uh magnetism so magnetism to
understand how that may correlate with
heavy metals and also
find the way to
make methods even
less time consuming even more affordable
so we're still working on developing the
best methodology possible and hopefully
in the future we'll be able to
offer the by accessibility tests with
the xrf so we are still working on that
to make it through portable technology
so yeah basically if people want to send
their soils to the lab feel free to send
them to our website
or just google delta urban sales
laboratory
and they will find information on how to
collect their samples and where to mail
them to
um and if they want to
look at my research i also have my
website it's
um annapeltsava.com my instagram soil
under school expert i love chatting with
different people and i'm always
responding my instagram so i'm really
pleased to hear
what people experiences in their gardens
and homes around the country
absolutely i'm glad you brought those up
because i was going to list all of those
things and i'll have them in the
introduction as well and on the podcast
page because
it might be a little tricky to spell
your last name for people unfamiliar um
but but i highly suggest people uh
do check out your social media you're
quite active on there
and you just recently posted i i saw a
story where you were showing exactly how
you do the testing on the heavy metal
analysis which i thought was fascinating
it's wonderful to actually see what's
happening
in a lab
and
you're just you're very interesting mix
of
you know fashion and soil science which
you don't typically put together um so i
think it's a lot of fun and people
should definitely
check you out
thank you so much i appreciate that you
reach out to me invited to the podcast
and i'm excited to
collaborate more different projects test
more of your samples and be engaged with
the audience
yeah i i we definitely will be sending
you a lot more samples as we try to
discover
not just we're testing we're in the
process of testing all of our soil
amendments and fertilizers right now to
make sure that they're we know the heavy
metal levels and know that they're safe
but also um we're working on formulating
and all the time trying to come up with
new new formulations that are going to
lower heavy metal
risk um for growers on the organic side
so um you're
what you're doing is a huge resource and
we're very grateful for it and i thank
you for coming on the show today show
today thanks for your time
thank you so much
[Music]
that was dr anna paltiva and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey i'll post pertinent links on the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast thanks for listening