[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is dr. Allison justice
Allison graduated from Clemson
University with a PhD in plant and
environmental science during her time at
Clemson Allison taught greenhouse
management to undergraduate students
where they focused on organic methods
and production Allison's dissertation
involved investigating the effects of a
beneficial Michel type organism piriform
of spora India where she learned that
organic sustainable growing can be easy
cost-effective that produced
aesthetically pleasing plants when done
properly through research Allison is
elevating the standards of cannabis
cultivation both indoors and in
greenhouse settings allison has worked
for outcault a vertically integrated
cannabis company in San Diego for the
past three years
Alco was one of the first companies to
integrate LEDs on mobile racking systems
this decision was backed by rigorous
experimentation conducted with fluence
bioengineering allison has made a recent
move from San Diego back to South
Carolina where she is focusing on hemp
allison is a co-founder of SC botanicals
large-scale CBD extraction facility in
South Carolina and the hemp mine
Allison's 40-acre family hemp farm dr.
justice has been appointed to the
California industrial hemp advisory
board through May of 2020 she was also
named one of the 40 under 40 in cannabis
by marijuana venture magazine I'm really
excited to get her on the show today and
share some of the research that she's
been doing in cannabis all right hey
Allison thanks for coming on the show
today yes thanks so much for having me
why don't we start off by giving
listeners a little bit of a background
into into your life and how you got to
the role that you have now
absolutely so I guess it all goes back
to being a child and kind of having
being born with a green thumb so my
grandparents are cotton farmers in South
Carolina I grew up on a large ball and
burlap tree farm in Georgia you know
every summer every holiday I was busy
playing with plants or you know digging
holes picking vegetables that sort of
thing and when it came time to pick a
degree absolutely
it had to be horticulture so I did go to
Clemson
I received bachelors in horticulture
after that it took a couple years off to
kind of figure out what I wanted to do
and also worked for our family tree farm
I started out very quickly but I wanted
to get back into the science you know I
wanted to discover more and so I went to
grad school for a plant environmental
science at Clemson as well to see my PhD
and I actually did a direct doctorate
after my PhD I started a consulting
company where I was mainly consulting
for IPM for large greenhouses across the
US and you know my grad student studies
were mainly on looking at organic
methods mainly looking at a in the fight
performance for an indica and how it
helps ornamental greenhouse plants take
up nutrients you know how it has the
potential to fight off disease and even
promote oxen for Reformation and
cuttings so you know I decided I wanted
to do some consulting to help these
companies implement microbes of
different sorts and actually develop a
system of rearing beneficial nematodes
because the nematodes as an organism are
very very good you know there's
different sorts of nematodes you know
starting NEMA carpet KC
starting with OPI that all attack
different insect pests
and so you know the way that you're able
to get these nematodes today are
basically in a brood and dried
concoction and what a lot of the studies
were showing is that nematodes reared
inside of hosts usually wax worms were
more effective at fighting off different
paths yeah so I was teaching farmers how
to rear their own nematodes versus
buying them you know in a dormant frozen
basically form you know as I was
consulting I eventually started getting
asked to consult for cannabis companies
which at the time you know live in South
Carolina I didn't necessarily consider
cannabis as an option absolutely
supported it but I just the career path
for it was not clear to me and still
isn't for a lot of people here in South
Carolina which is why I did develop an
internship program which we can talk
about later if you'd like but it started
getting you know questions from cannabis
growers started consulting and so very
quickly that you know it was a rising
industry and an industry that needed
science and that was very very
interesting and so eventually I was
asked to come out and visit out Co in
San Diego and was offered a job I really
had no intentions to move but it was a
good offer and just just the science
that I could I could achieve very
quickly with cannabis just seemed so fun
honestly and so I did move to San Diego
I have actually just moved back to South
Carolina
but I was in San Diego for about three
years as a vp of cultivation there I I
still actually am vp of cultivation for
outcault but in the meantime you know
during those three years about a year in
South Carolina passed the bill to grow
him and so my family being all farmers
already having land and
green houses I encourage them to apply
for a planet and they actually got one
of the first 20 licenses given in South
Carolina to grow hemp and so that was
exciting and you know we went down the
road of cultivation but then you saw
very quickly well there's no one here to
extract and the people that are coming
in state and offering extraction
services 99 percent of them were
basically shark and you know saying oh
we'll give you $5,000 an acre for your
crop you know we'll buy it right now
when in reality they should be making
you know at least a hundred thousand
dollars an acre so outcode being
vertically integrated you know already
had dr. Marcus Rogan a brilliant chemist
we decided to build an extraction
facility here in South Carolina for CBD
for hemp extraction and partnered with
my family's company outcault and as well
as an investor of course and Bill I see
botanicals and so we extract they're not
only my family but other farmers across
South Carolina and you know as a part of
that extraction service you know I'm
here to help with a lot of the planting
because if we're growing good plants
with high potency everybody's wedding so
here I stand back in South Carolina and
now with a lot of different things going
on it's it's absolutely been an
interesting three plus years but I can't
tell you how much I've learned what
would this point single plant that's
that's so interesting because I was just
recently at that soil scientist meeting
I told you about and Ron Turco with
Purdue University was talking and he was
talking about how everyone was getting
into hemp right now and his big question
to him was what are you gonna do after
you've grown the hemp like how are you
gonna extract it there's no there's no
one there's no infrastructure for that
in a lot of these states so I think
you're gonna be filling a really
important need there at SC botanicals
that's great absolutely yeah a lot of
the states where we stand at him
you know it's already been in production
for a number of years now like Oregon
and Washington you know it is the
starting plants and it is the extraction
that's the bottleneck you know there's a
lot of good farmers out there but
propagation specialists so our
extraction specialist is is kind of
where the need is and so building those
companies is I think important right now
I told Leah gree I think it's great what
you guys are doing and I have to say
I've been I big a big fan of your work
now for a few years I actually heard
about you long before I met you because
of an article that was published talking
about how you were able to reduce
outcodes
expenses on the nutrient side by moving
away from essentially what we're calling
bottled nutrients or you know a branded
marketed nutrient line that's specific
for the cannabis industry would you be
willing to talk a little bit about that
process when you came into outcault and
how you made those changes yeah so you
know when I first got to outcode they
were already in operation and so the
good first few months in my time was
just simply investigating what they were
already doing and comparing to you know
methods I had been using previously with
non cannabis crops and the first one
that really stuck out to me was these
giant vat of liquid nutrients you know
with names of company companies I'd
never heard of with silly pictures on
the front and basically you know
fertilizer labels that didn't make a lot
of sense so as I start digging through
it there's a lot of as you know there's
a lot of magic and special sauce that
fertilizer companies like to put into
their bottles but at the end of the day
you know the plant needs its essential
nutrients that's it so over time you
know through experimentation through
research you know I found that cannabis
is
a plant of course as we know but it is
it's a special plant but it's a plant
that also is a plant and needs it 16
essential nutrients and you know as I
developed our own fertilizer recipe you
know what I found is it's very similar
to point-seven tomato with a few tweaks
and you know it took me about three
years to to decipher what's going on but
I think as of this week I've just kind
of put together all the facts so I'm
gonna I'm gonna give you a little bit of
my conspiracy theory of what's going on
with my bottled nutrient and you know
the idea of levels of nutrients that are
needed so first let me just say you know
I did run through an experiment where a
controlled experienced experiment where
I'm looking at two different commercial
fertilizers very popular one every
everyone listening has known or used or
at least heard of not learning mean
names because I don't want to be that
person but you know when you actually
look at when you're able to compare
their recommendations versus what's
actually in the bottle it's it's really
flatter gasping what they're having you
apply one what I found was in the bottle
one didn't match the label and two you
know compared to other plants the amount
of mineral nutrients we're putting on is
just outrageous I mean it's it's just
plain horrifying and you know because of
this I think I think the organic side
you know with what you're doing actually
has more knowledge and more even though
it is extremely complicated when you're
getting you know lots and lots of
organisms involved it's it's complicated
because a lot of cycling but
I think you almost have a better grasp
on what's going on than a lot of the
people that are using mineral nutrients
which is kind of backwards but I think
it's a push from the fertilizer
companies so and then I'll get back to
that but you know looking at my
experiments nitrogen for a regular plant
should be you know 50 to maxing out in
the low 200s well one of these companies
specifically during the you know week
six or so they're getting up to about
400 parts per million nitrogen double of
what any other plants possibly sees all
right and then you know with these
results I'm correlating with leaf tissue
samples and so with a nitrogen even
though you're applying twice as much as
what normal plant needs when you look at
the results the amount of nitrogen
nitrogen this took up in the plant is
not double it's absolutely the same as
our control fertilizer which is 150
parts per million it's exactly the same
so where is that fertilizer going at the
bottom
same thing for potassium same thing for
phosphorus phosphorus specifically is
you know very very bad for the
environment absolutely great for the
plant but the amount we are applying I
would say at least eighty eighty five
percent is going right at the bottom of
the pot you know some of the ways that
growers deal with this high EC is by
flushing and it's just not necessary the
reason you're having to flush is because
you're applying so much nutrients and if
you didn't your plant would absolutely
die that's obviously I say that's really
it's really interesting because I know
when we talked at photo X at that time
you were thinking it was primarily
phosphates that was leaching which is a
huge issue
like you mentioned and something we've
discussed on on this podcast before from
a sustainability perspective but now
you're seeing nitrates and potassium as
well and it sounds like it's everything
it's everything to send these
fertilizers you know compared to what
our control plant needed and compared to
other fertilizer recipes every single
thing that's being applied is at least
three times too much and I think it's
twofold one the growers are putting
themself in a bind because they have
this idea that they need more
phosphorous and so they're applying
phosphorous and once you get over about
you know hundred parts per million
phosphorous you're also precipitating
out your iron link and possibly calcium
and so you know if you're if you're
increasing your P you're also having
increased those others and so it's this
back and forth you know increase of
nutrients that's just not necessary and
the whole reason being because you've
put too much and you're it's not being
able to be taken up by the plant yeah
that's that's really interesting because
we have this perception as growers that
the more we put on the bigger our plant
will grow and so people have this
tendency to continue to add nutrients
and a lot of it dates back to this
concept that plant that cannabis plants
need nitrogen for veg and phosphorus for
bloom leading back to a really popular
cannabis book that came out I think in
the 80s and so this this sort of myth
has carried on for years and I do see
that what you're saying here around
especially around phosphorus being over
applied it's a really common problem
with cannabis absolutely and so you know
I was trying to figure out what is the
reason what is the reasoning growers
think that they need so much phosphorus
with any other plant you know the low
would be eight parts with the high being
maybe fifteen parts per million and you
know with looking
these commercial fertilizer
recommendations they're putting on
upwards of 200 and the plant literally
cannot take up that much and so it's
just being wasted and so I'm not gonna
take claim of this find but you know
we're talking with dr. Roy Heinz brine
core and Jim Barrett they found a study
from 1977 which I have no idea how they
perform the study in the United States
but it's called responses of greenhouse
growing cannabis to nitrogen phosphorus
and potassium and so you know it's an
interesting study but I'm worried that
this is what's fact this whole
phosphorus push you know if you're
reading it quickly and not necessarily
doing the math it looks like okay well
you need 150 parts per million applied
to your plants and you know the the
normal person would think okay well
that's every watering well if you dig a
little deeper which their materials and
methods are are pretty inadequately hard
to follow but you know what it's
actually talking about 150 milligrams
per kilogram of soil not 150 parts per
million per watering and so if you do
the math further it's actually equaling
about 15 parts per million each watering
and so looking at their study they're
going from 15 parts per million being
the high application rate and keep in
mind that cannabis liquid fertilizer
companies are recommending about 200
parts per million
phosphorus their medium range with five
parts per million and their low was zero
and so as you would imagine when you
look through the data yeah they're
getting higher higher yields and flower
and biomass they're getting higher THC
content which was only points Arts
Project but
know what strengths they're growing but
it's really low anyway but if you're not
doing this math you're thinking wow wow
it's a really really increasing on
phosphorus I'm gonna get higher
everything but it's only 15 parts per
million and so you know by by reading
that study was it being the only one out
at that time you know that could have
started started this crazy and there's
no doubt phosphorus does increase
flowering and freedom but what you know
how much do you have to use to actually
get that and then the next thought is a
lot of plants out there will turn purple
when there's phosphorus restriction that
was one of my studies in grad school was
looking at some patients and saying okay
well instead of applying plant growth
regulators like fundamentals ornamental
growers do very consistently instead of
using PG ours
can we just apply less phosphorus not
inhibit flowering and get a smaller more
compact plant and so what we found was
if we use three parts per million the
plant would be very stout not you know
long gangly which is great for our
little plant it did not inhibit
flowering but it was very very purple
you know it supposed to be a green plant
it was very purple and so did that
matter
well once we applied adequate phosphorus
that ten parts per million it green
right up and then it's flowered normally
and so I wonder if I've heard lots of
people say this you know when the stems
are turning purple or yeah well
understand the turning purple so it's
got to be a phosphorus deficiency and
they need to add more phosphorus when
one that's probably not the deficiency
sign and and so you're actually just
adding more salt and probably making
your problem worse simply it just being
a stress maybe a stress just responds I
think some just earned naturally for
well could that be also related to
temperature I've seen purpling stems
most common commonly correlated with
cold temperatures which would allow less
as I understood that less movement of
phosphorous and that's what was sort of
making that show up but are you seeing
other reasons for purpling and stems you
know I've definitely seen purpling
increase with cold temperatures me this
is a flower of leaves of stems
everything I'm specifically talking
about times when me that the plan is
just stressed in general and growers
will just automatically associate that
with a phosphorus deficiency because of
that purple color
not necessarily with coal temperature
but yeah absolutely plant the plants do
turn purple one if you drop the
temperature the one I hear the most is
any time you see any chlorosis in the in
the leaves like in travail no chlorosis
or anything like that it's always calm
egg and then they're always adding
cal-mag because that's what's causing it
is that one that you've you've heard of
or seen a lot of - or well the cow
magazine kind of throws me off a little
um you know because cal-mag it's it's
not one nutrient right it's it's usually
maybe calcium chloride and magnesium
sulfate and so you know when I see in
Trevino chlorosis yeah I think it's a
magnesium deficiency potentially and so
I would want to you know do some
increase of epsom salts but yes I think
the general term people throw around you
know if cow mag is something that we
should think about you know are you do
you need to increase that calcium and
you need to crease the magnesium and you
know we should be a little smarter and
be able to diagnose that and imply apply
the right nutrient versus just some
bottle of you know to mixed different
molecules that's a good point it's
probably not calcium and and Magni
and as I understand it cal-mag isn't
even typically the right ratio for what
plants need at least from what we're
aiming for on the organic side is a
ratio between calcium and magnesium so I
think that's exactly what I think that's
a great point but one thing I wanted to
get back to was when you created your
own fertilizer can you talk just really
quickly on the economic benefits of that
for outcault when you guys made the
switch oh absolutely absolutely and so
when we originally switched we were
actually saving twenty four times the
cost which is this you know if anybody
knows you know one of the biggest costs
is fertilizer I mean so you know just
paying for a brand is absolutely
ridiculous when you can go down to the
local agriculture store and get you know
all of your ingredients that are tested
for heavy metals and pesticides and
whatever else she might be worrisome for
for absolutely pennies and I guess my
skeptical scepticism comes from one grad
school when you know we're it we're
asked to question everything but also
you know being raised on a farm when you
know you don't have money extra money
just to throw around because you know
it's this the crate you need to have
reasons behind all of your choices and
you know not that everybody has the
capability to you know to mix their own
fertilizers but there are absolutely
agricultural shops that can assist you
with making shorter decisions on on what
you're applying because at the end of
the day like I said the recipes aren't
that much different than then what
tomato farmers and influence that
growers are using absolutely I agree
100% with this and it's something you
know I've I've been pushing as a
platform now for five or six years I
gave a talk at Kanak on one year on how
to get off bottled nutrients we're
essentially the my big push is look at
the ingredient list for starters so see
what what they're actually claiming on
the bottle
and then look and see if this product is
being used outside of the cannabis
industry that's a red flag if it if it
isn't and then lastly if they say
there's anything proprietary about what
they're doing
walk the other way even even if it's the
most amazing product in the world
because it if we're gonna grow a plant
that's gonna be combusted or it's gonna
be consumed as an edible we need to know
everything we're putting on that plant
and if we can't trust these companies
they've already proven it there's been
too many stop sales and other issues
around the cannabis industry that we
just we should not be putting our trust
in a manufacturer it's just it's too
risky especially for a commercial
facility so I love that you were able to
switch out Co off of a program like that
onto one that in my opinion is not only
more affordable but a lot more
sustainable for for the plant itself
even so thank you for that yeah
absolutely absolutely and so you know
coming from grad school where I did
focus on basically microbes in the soil
and how they can assist you know and
we're gonna sound like a skeptic here
but at least talking about growers who
are growing hydroponically you know a
wine as we're talking about fertilizer
companies I questioned some of the
microbe companies as well it's
specifically growing hydroponically and
because this makes me think you know if
we're applying such high rates of salts
you know making your EC and your and
your root ball very very high are we
actually just adding one problem on top
of the other so your EC is very very
high and it's this microbe application
actually benefiting the plant because
you're applying one more set of watering
which is actually it's not necessarily
the microbe that's helping the plant in
general it's the flushing its allusion
of that EC that you already have in your
media that's helping
or is it potentially you know you have
such a high e C we know microbes help
mainly with phosphorus and zinc uptake
is it potentially helping you
during this high stress high salinity
environment as microbes do but if we
were smarter about our fertilizer
applications from the get-go you know
would these microbes be showing that the
results that they sometimes do some
growers so just so I understand this
you're speculating that what we're doing
with some of these microbial
applications in a hydroponic environment
due to the salinity is is really just
putting a band-aid on a wound that we
created so in theory you could lower
your salinity levels and get your EC
down and maybe receive achieve the same
results that you're getting by over
fertilizing and applying microbes
absolutely that's really interesting and
it kind of brings up another another
point that I wanted to touch on now you
and I have had discussions off air about
organics versus let's chemicals or
synthetic or mineral salts whatever you
want to call them as as two different
methods for cultivation and you know I
grew up being a hardcore Ganic guy my
parents were organic but as I've gotten
as I've gotten older and learned more
about this industry I've kind of opened
my mind a little bit towards not so much
organics versus conventional but more
about sustainability so it's very
possible to be organic and unsustainable
in terms of what you're adding in terms
of heavy-metal levels and other issues
potentially with organics but I think it
is possible to grow more sustainably
using mineral salts and the added
benefit from a research perspective of
reducing all the variability that you
see in organics I think it would be very
very difficult to perform a study on
living soils versus using a hydroponic
setup where you can control all of those
aspects so you really only have one
variable that you're looking
can you I know you mentioned that
growers have giving you a hard time in
the past for being for not using
organics as your methodology can you
touch a little bit on that so I
absolutely believe that sustainable
growing is is the answer
especially with not even having the
opportunity to V USDA certified organic
there's many many scenarios where if you
were combining synthetics and organic
methods that you truly are being more
sustainable than if you were only doing
one or the other you know if you think
about let's say silica and in calcium
chloride so if you're adding a lot of
silica and calcium chloride to your
foliar mixture to your to your nutrients
you know you are getting the benefit of
pest control by adding those non organic
inputs and you know one having a better
crop because of less insect damage but
to maybe not applying other pesticides
that could be a little more damaging and
like you said you know overdoing
anything is not a good thing over
applying salt is not a good thing over
applying manure with lots of lots and
water on top of that you know that's
still a pollutant so combining a lot of
these sustainable methods you know it is
absolutely in my mind okay you know
there's there's a downfall to each side
absolutely but I think you have to
combine them it's hard not to
specifically an indoor growing
controlled environment growing you know
if you're not able to
we use your your pots or or your soil
mixtures or you know remediate each year
your outdoor crop soil environment you
know it's very hard to to do only
organic methods specifically fertilizers
and when we look at it from a plant
perspective I mean the plant doesn't
doesn't care if the nitrate it's
receiving is from a mineral salt or from
a nutrient cycling process where it took
something like fish meal and broke that
down into nitrate by the bacteria
archaea you know protozoa and everything
cycling that nutrient to the plant it
doesn't really make a difference which i
think is an important distinction that
we that we discuss now to be fair I am a
purely organic person and I see a lot of
issues with not just the cannabis
industry but conventional agriculture
around the concept of sustainability
like we discussed but I also realized
that not everyone is going to make that
choice or choose to grow organically and
what we really want is everyone to be
growing sustainably no matter what
methodology they choose and part of that
I think is what you mentioned here is
moving away from a lot of these bottle
of nutrient programs that have you over
applying a lot of these macronutrients
and figuring out exactly what the plant
needs but for a lot of growers that's
really challenging I mean a lot of them
don't have access to leaf tissue
analysis or even basic soil testing and
the one advantage of these bottled
nutrient programs is they give you a
feeding chart and they give you a
product and you know you're going to get
a certain result so how would you
address that for someone who has less I
guess less educational background around
horticulture and maybe less access to
testing facilities right so with the
hemp bill just passing I think our
opportunity to have the sample or you
know leaf and that office done at
university is gonna be here within the
next six months I know there's some
like here at Clemson that will already
do it so that the specifically leaf
samples of hemp you know obviously if
you have a cannabis sample the leaves
aren't going to have the secondary
metabolites that you might expect on the
same intent but it would be okay I think
the other thing to realize is that
you're not locked in to only working
with a hydro store anymore there's
companies out there that have been in
production for a hundred years in
agriculture that can help you develop a
fertilizer program that is sustainable
that does work for cannabis and you know
can guide you through that so for
example in San Diego there's a company
that I work with called grungy toes you
know they for 50 years plus they've been
working with avocado growers and other
fruit and vegetable growers and they
have the capacity to make whatever you
want and so you know I was able to go to
them after singing out our recipe from
individual salts and they made you know
my mixture into you know a premix ready
to put under the dosatron slurry where
they weren't where my guys weren't
actually mixing the individual sauce
himself just because you know there can
be human error and not and whatnot and
did it in bulk did it in concentrated
form and it was still 23 times less
expensive than the bottled nutrients and
you know that was with me having a
recipe ready but these companies I mean
they they already know what a canvas
plant needs and they're very this is
just in San Diego but there's our
culture of stores everywhere in every
state and you know these are people that
have been working with plants their
whole life and they can help you figure
out what your plant needs just like a
grand Jace grand gee toasted
that's great I don't want to take away
from the fact that we're still learning
a lot about camping about cannabis and
what optimal nutrient levels look like
in these crops because the research is
just starting to starting to happen I
think we're gonna see a lot in the next
few years hopefully but I think I don't
think we should count on the fact that
the nutrient companies that exist in the
cannabis industry have really figured it
out a lot of ways and I think that's
what a lot of people are counting on
that
you know the recipe from general
hydroponics or from botanic air is
optimized for cannabis Wow we just I
think that's something that we need to
go back and revisit as we learn a lot
more about this plan I agree
all right well let's change subjects
here because there's a lot of other
things I want to talk to you about in
terms of aspects around cultivation one
of the things that you mentioned to me
was some work you've done around this
concept of lolli popping can you talk a
little bit about that yes so when I
joined outcault you know they they were
stripping the bottoms of the plants and
you know week three they were stripping
almost all the leaves off the top of the
plants and I was just I was so confused
why did what's happening
and started doing some research and
found you know okay it does make some
sense you know it's the same idea of
what peach growers do you know they will
either spray some sub substance or have
growers go out there and knock off half
of the peaches and so yes they have less
quantity but their peaches are bigger so
it's all about where are you wanting to
allocate your resources and so you know
that concept made some sense the concept
of better air flow made sense for
botrytis or powdery mildew but at the
end of the day I still struggled with
well yes these are further scepters and
are we actually hurting the planet by
doing this re lowering our yield
and so I had dr. Mike Jenkins come out
from Rubisco consulting and we've done
some work together before but he has an
actual like or meter and what this does
is measure photosynthesis and so we said
okay well let's let's put some numbers
on all these theories that that growers
have and you know try to figure out and
understand why certain methods are done
well you know he spent a couple days and
grow room taking measurements and he
he's actually coming out with a paper on
his saw but all the details hopefully
you'll be able to read shortly but long
story short what we found is that the
leads that receiving less than 200 micro
moles so the intensity of 200 micro
moles were not so to synthesizing
efficiently basically those low release
and to give you an idea you know our top
leads we're reaching anywhere from 900
to 1100 micromoles so much much higher
so you know okay well the lower leaves
are not doing anything meaning they are
not creating food meaning they are a
sink more interesting than that what we
found was that they were transpiring and
so being an indoor grow double stack you
know one of the things we really
struggle with is taking the humidity out
of there
well we have found with data every time
we lollipop or even defoliate the lower
leaves it's easier to control that
humidity and you know this data point
helped us make prints of that well
you're getting rid of these low releases
I'm not photosynthesizing that are
taking nutrients from the other plants
and are just acting as a sprinkler
system and so what we learn
is there is absolutely sense and and
lolli popping and getting rid of the
leaves that are receiving less than 200
microlitre so in theory if a grower had
a light meter they could go around and
and sort of get an idea for what leaves
are getting approximately what light
levels in the canopy and then remove
anything below that that 200 micromo
level yeah yeah and so we did not
correlate that with a yield but for us
it was an important point because we
struggle with humidity control okay so
your your research is is right now based
around humidity control you haven't I
think that's an important point you
haven't done the correlation with yield
yet what about in in relation to plant
stress or or disease because I do
realize that you're talking about
essentially stressing the plant by
removing these leaves in a lot of ways
what would you say to that well this
plant is absolutely shown to have
positive results and whether that's just
positive results from increased
secondary metabolite production from
stresses so you know I I think if this
deformation happened specifically early
on just in theory I would say there's
not a negative effect on yield a flower
it is so when when were you removing the
leaves just just out of curiosity this
was at week four okay
I'll be interested to see if other
people do more research around this to
see if there's a you know a different
time point in the flowering cycle that
might be more optimal but I think that's
wonderful and I would like to see some
more research around stress response
because like you mentioned cannabis does
seem to be highly adaptable and able to
deal with stress and there is plenty of
research in you know the plant world
showing that stress targeted stress
stressors can result in you know up
essentially a better tasting fruit or a
better fruiting response I haven't seen
anything around cannabis with that have
you have you seen research on that at
all own cannabis itself no I have
absolutely seen in papers where water
stress salinity stress can increase
secondary metabolites with Basel but
cannabis not necessarily and that
actually kind of brings me back to the
fertilizer input you know it's in
general you're applying well over the
amount of phosphorus and potassium that
is needed you know think about what a
lot of growers do at weeks five six and
seven is they apply more PK on top of
that and so K controls your EC and so
you know is it the benefit of more
phosphorus potassium or are we applying
a stress of salinity by increasing these
to increase potentially a cannabinoid
content I like that that's really
interesting because a lot of people just
make these assumptions that it's the
nutrient but if you look at it from
another perspective there are other
variables that could be causing the
response we're getting and that's
something that that's why I think
science is so important so I really like
that
now just to change subjects again you
would mentioned that well you presented
research actually a photo X a couple
years ago around a lighting study is
that the lighting study you're
referencing talking about today yeah do
you want to go ahead and describe that I
remember seeing that research when you
presented it was I thought it was really
really interesting I've actually talked
about it a little bit on this podcast
before but I would love to hear hear it
in your words sort of what you found and
what you were testing so you know what
again when I started at outcault you
know one of the rumors that I was
hearing was we can't flower under LED
and you know every person I would ask
why was
you know he didn't have a really good
answer for me or they tried it once and
it didn't work
and you know I do agree you can't
necessarily give an answer off of one
one time trying with LEDs it's the sort
of thing you have to change some of your
growing habits to produce a good crop
under but the blunt fact of it just not
working is this very country and so Josh
Arabic who was the plant scientist Sarah
fluent at the time contacted me and said
hey do you want to do some lighting
trials together and I said well
absolutely you know what let's see
what's happening here
what prove or disprove this and so we
set up a study with one cultivar which
you know I want to be very honest with
that it was one called cultivar and
others could act very differently we
looked at different light intensity so
400 600 800 and 1,200 micro moles per
meter squared per second but then we
also had a HPS at 700 micro moles more
or less of the control and so we
collected a shoot fresh way shoot dry
weight flour dry weight trim weight and
secondary metabolites and I office you
know basically what we found is that
what one yes you absolutely can flower
under LEDs and to you know when you're
looking at this you have to dig deeper
than just yield you have to look at
potency you have to look at your ROI and
so that's what we did in a study you
know so looking at basically pounds
perlite there was a direct comparison or
correlations between intensity and yield
and so we did receive the highest yield
with the highest wattage and also
highest ppfd and
we D at two and a half pounds per light
and then the lowest obviously was the
400 you know it wasn't enough for myself
or for the owners of the company to just
say okay higher yield let's go with it
you know we had to dig a little deeper
we had to say all right well if we're
considering X amount per light if we're
considering coverage of this light how
much were paying in power which in San
Diego it's very expensive you know what
is this far oh I'd look like and so you
know what we found is that cost of you
know the amount we were getting per
flower - power it's actually the LEDs
that were winning and this was not even
considering HVAC or that thing which you
know we talked a little bit more about
later but that was one of the biggest
issues changing to LEDs was was the HVAC
but you know end of the day what we
found is that we were making a much
greater roi from the LED lights than the
HPS lights considering power and also
cost a fixture because that's one of the
biggest problems with LEDs is that their
price per fixture is just you know
compared to the outrageous so if you're
looking at 800 I'm sorry at 660 what LED
you're looking at 1,200 bucks maybe
higher HPS you could probably get it
under $400 and so you know especially
when you're first designing a room you
have to think you know is this worth it
and so in our study what we showed was
that no under one year you're able to
pay back that investment simply because
of the the power savings plus increase
of yield plus increase of secondary
metabolites which was minimal but what's
there
the other thing that was really big for
outcault was that because of some of the
local walls we were not able to expand
like we had planned to and so we were
limited in space but we did have really
high ceilings and so because they're
LEDs you're able to stack and so we were
able to immediately say r8 will can
flower under LEDs we need to also
increase our footprint let's stack and
so we partnered with tip and you know
almost immediately doubled our our
footprint so that you know that's great
in all that increased our overall yield
by two point eight times but you know
it's not it's not perfect there were
other things we had to work through and
so you know being one of the first that
upgraded to the the double stack we had
to figure out alright well honey should
get water up up to the top how do you
how are you able to move these benches
with with getting water to them how do
you use the air within these canopies
and so there were a lot of tricks we had
to figure out that was fun but also
frustrating at time one of the things
that we expected maybe not as much as it
is about being was the humidity control
and so you know because they are LEDs
are cooling was enough but the humidity
removal was not and so you know you have
twice as many plants your hat you have
twice as much transpiration and so you
have to remove twice as much water from
the air and so we absolutely had to
increase our dehumidification the other
thing that I would just suggest all
growers do and they're using LEDs is
think about you know even though the
temperature in the room might be the
same that does not mean that the leaf
temperature is the same and
so I would highly encourage to get an
infrared sensor to look at leaf
temperature compared to HBS which does
have a lot of radiant heating the least
in certain be up to five degrees cooler
under LEDs and so if you have high
humidity and you have much cooler leaf
temperature that's the special sauce for
botrytis and so you know increasing room
temperature as well as something that we
had to ultimately end up doing that's
interesting so you the solution was to
increase the room temperature to address
the lower leaf temperature relative to
LEDs exactly
okay and I want to go back a little bit
on this this study that you did so just
to clarify for listeners it was one
cultivar and under a variety of
different light intensity and you were
looking at ROI so return on investment
for people who aren't familiar with that
term but essentially what you found was
that the 1200 micro moles was not the
most efficient use you had the highest
yield but relative to the amount of cost
associated with running your electricity
that high I believe you found one
thousand was optimal for your facility
is that correct or is that that changed
almost Ulmus so the 1200 PP SD fixture
which was the thousand watts so that was
actually just a prototype to achieve
ppfd that high but when considering the
extra power input it and then the yield
and potency it was actually the 800 ppfd
and that's average of course but the 660
was so it was the spider X that was
optimal okay and that's going to vary in
terms of ROI based on your cost of
electricity so if you're in a different
area where electricity cost a lot less
or lost a lot more you may find that
that number may change a little bit
which i think is is something to
consider great well let's uh we have a
kind of a wide variety of topics here
that you have listed talked about can we
move on to curing yes and so curing is
something that I've especially became
interested in because I think even more
than chemistry or cultivation it's been
a little bit ignored and I think in
terms of an art it's been figured out
quite well but in terms of what's
actually going on I don't think we know
very much well you know this really
isn't my area of expertise so I'd be
curious to hear what you have to say
around around caring or what you found
out
so dr. Marcus Rogan and I tag-team us
because it is a combination of plant
science biochemistry and then of course
just chemistry in general so we had a
good time trying to guess what's going
on and then comparing it to some of the
industry guesses you know what is drying
hearing and so drying of course we have
to do it to prevent spoilage curing
though you know when you stick it in the
bucket what is that and why do you need
to do it so we set forth trying to
search the literature search other
plants and figure out what might be
going on and so when we're comparing it
let's think
all right well fruits and vegetables you
know they are plants that are picked and
stored for a while cut flowers maybe
even more so relevant they're picked and
they're stored and the science behind
that is just out of this world compared
to what cannabis has right now and then
there's the transportation of unrooted
cuttings so instead of just fruits
veggies and flowers that are meant to
basically just be put
pause and then killed the transportation
of unrooted cutting is appalled but then
a continuation of growing and so looking
through all this literature you know the
big things we see are alright well we're
trying to delay death trying to preserve
we're trying to delay ripening but not
yet do we want to speed up ripening you
know in how's this done well cool
temperatures inhibition of ethylene and
I think ethylene has been very much
under studied in cannabis because it is
you know a ripening agent that every
other industry struggles with to remove
or in case of ripening fruit maybe even
use and then humidity and then of course
we have to think all right well it's not
just this one organism cannabis that
we're working with there's others that
like to creep in at certain optimum
temperatures and humidity as well such
as botrytis so we looked into you know
what's going on in the industry right
now anywhere from sixty to forty five
Fahrenheit for for drying and forty to
sixty for humidity is about standard and
then you know we we wonder go and this
was of course at the beginning you know
how do you decide it's time to pull a
plant from the dry read2go integer and
you know when I started the answers I
was getting was well there's a crack in
the stem and at the time of very
confused how that the metric that we're
using is a crack because I wasn't
familiar with what that crap was
supposed to sound like and I wasn't sure
how I was going to write a SP for other
employees to be able to you know make
sure we're pulling the plant down at the
right time by a crack found and so you
know looking into what people in coffee
lets you know drying roasting coffee
looking into let's say beef jerky you
all of those are food items that has to
be dried and you know there's a known
stopping point well what what is that
device used for knowing when it's time
to stop drying well that's called a
water activity meter and so this is not
actual moisture content of a food item
it's the actual available water for
microbial growth and so you know if you
look through the literature there are
set water activity numbers that will
tell you all right well this species
strain of bacteria yeast and mold will
not grow under these certain water
activities so we purchased a water
activity meter and that is how we now
determine when it's actually time to
pull the plants from the room and to go
to cure and so from that and from
looking at the literature where it is
shown that botrytis will not grow under
a water activity of 0.8 we can be very
comfortable with drying fast enough for
botrytis and other microbes not to grow
but also slow enough where all of these
enzymatic activities which we don't
actually know which ones are happening
now but we can postulate that it's the
conversion of starch to sugar the
breakdown of korah field etc so we can
have the water activity high enough to
continue these enzymatic activities but
low enough to not grow botrytis so we
wish I had the graph in front of you but
basically what we do is from day 1 to 3
we drop the the water activity very
quickly so down to 0.8 that way botrytis
is not growing and then it's a slow dry
until 12 to 14 days at that point it's
dropped down to about point 6 which is
consumer preference but in between
you're still a high enough water
activity to where a lot of these
enzymatic processes can happen
that nut is so cool that might be the
most interesting science related
cannabis thing I think that has been
shared on this podcast to date the fact
that someone could take a concept that's
been more art than science really around
curing and set a quantifiable point
using a meter so that growers can know
exactly when to harvest something or
when did I guess I said essentially when
did how you should be drying something I
think that's that's awesome thanks for
sharing that completely so anything else
around caring that you would touch on
that you found by using this methodology
absolutely and so once we were
comfortable with our drying procedures
you know we just we just wanted to do
what was happening in the Cure in the
bucket and and what the heck was a
burner and so we set up an experiment
with make controls and legacy they
actually made us small data loggers
which measured co2 relative humidity and
temperature and so we were able to put
these into five-gallon buckets just you
know the regular old food grade plastic
ones but I would say most people use for
curing and we had a control and so this
was a bucket that was kept for two weeks
with no burping so just stay close the
entire time we had what we called the
out cupboard and so this was for the
first three days the lids were removed
for about 20 minutes so our turns and
then returned to their position and then
industry births where we took the lid
off daily for an hour and turn the flour
and so we were able to graphically see
what was happening with these different
metrics we looked at so looking at co2
what we found is that in general over in
general over these two weeks do two rows
okay and so somehow it's being produced
within the bucket no matter the type of
birth all right the second thing that
was interesting is that you zoom in to
one specific day within those two weeks
no matter the burp style what you're
seeing is a huge decrease in co2 after
the birth which makes sense and then a
very fast increase and so when we looked
at the times of when all this was
happening
well the birth would happen about 7:00
a.m. when people would come in to work
and just keep in mind that these
containers were kept in a room where the
trimming was happening so there are a
lot of people coming in well the the co2
would increase until about 5:00 when
everyone got off worked and then it
would slowly decrease when I left work
so he saw that obviously the co2 is well
the co2 that the humans are producing
are is causing the increase in the
bucket so the buckets are not gas tied
at least ok so just the amount of humans
in the room was raising the co2 in the
bucket so what kind of I guess
generalizations can you make based on on
your findings here if any it's yeah it
it was very surprising honestly you know
I'm these plants at such a low water
activity I just couldn't imagine any
sort of respirations happening is there
any sort of fermentation happening I
I've discussed this with a quite a
number of folks and it's still very
confusing what's going on but at least
having some data a little bit of insight
of you know what might be going on it's
a good start I mean there there's so
many follow-ups to these experiments we
need to do but yeah that was just
interesting to see as well but you know
looking next that relative humidity
because one of the answers I would
always get with you know what's
happening in the Cure is oh it's
releasing moisture on what it was that
mean releasing moisture
and so this was regardless of the type
of bird - the control so you know the
the out cupboard and the industry Birds
what would happen is when it's closed
it's a very stagnant line and you know
that about 50 percent humidity and then
when the burp happened the humidity
would increase or decrease and this
would happen in correlation to what was
in the range so if the room had 30%
humidity and we did a bird it would drop
for about 30 minutes to about 50 percent
humidity and then go back to exactly
where it was and then the same with the
inverse if it's very humid in the room
it would pop up very quickly during the
bird and then go back to where it was so
there is no per se release of moisture
it's just it's accumulating whatever's
happened or not accumulating but it's
that it's acclimating to whatever is
happening in the race so that was
interesting
but I think I think the only thing we
truly proved in this study we did have
interesting findings but the only thing
I think we truly found was that the cure
is a homogeneous ation and so the birds
dry from the outside in meaning that the
outside of the bud least their moisture
first and then eventually it comes out
the inside and so this was proven by at
the beginning of curing taking lots of
water activity samples and what we saw
is there was huge variance between the
samples and this makes sense because
there's big bugs big but big behind
small buds all sorts of buds and they
had very different water activity all
right once two weeks passed we took this
water activity samples again and so what
we found with children to interesting
things one being the variance was much
smaller meaning whether it was a small
bud or a big boy
they were very similar in water activity
the other thing that was interesting is
that overall the water activity
increased and so this doesn't mean that
the buds were getting more wet this
means that the moisture that was inside
or the moisture that was you know within
the the deep crevices of the big bud was
going to the small bud and they're all
having a very similar water activity
moisture content so it was homogenizing
so by putting it into a bucket or
container like that you're allowing all
of the moisture in all the buds to sort
of homogenized this is sort of what
you're getting it yeah exactly
so there is the advantage to putting in
these buckets to homogenize the moisture
but you couldn't draw any conclusions
regarding - burping is in terms of it
being beneficial or not no conclusions
we do know there is a a wild exchange of
gases you know we did have an ethylene
sensor but it was borrowed and it was
not working very well and so I really
wanted to measure the ethylene that was
being produced and I wasn't able to
correlate it but I can conclude that the
amounts of ethylene was just out of this
world I had never seen numbers that high
and so I can't tell you if that's good
and we want to increase uh saline or if
we want to decrease it but I can tell
you it's there and it's very very high
and so so much more research needs to be
done but this was just kind of a first
babble just trying to see what's
happening in there but yeah like I said
lots more to be done yeah I didn't I
never really have thought about cannabis
in relation to ethylene I mean when I
think of ethylene I think of bananas or
apples and like you mentioned how we use
ethylene or try and modulate ethylene in
those industries because it does have
such a ripening effect on fruit so
essentially what you're getting at is
that we don't know if ethylene is good
or bad or if the burping by you know
lowering the ethylene is going to
improve the quality of the cure
or we want to not burp it all and raise
ethylene levels sounds really
interesting I would speculate that we're
removing the ethylene when you burp and
that is potentially beneficial just
based on what the industry is sort of
you know anecdotally moved towards but
we really don't know it sounds like yeah
we really don't know or is it a good
thing and is it is it helping to speed
up the ripening process which you know
is that is that making the bud sweeter
is that getting rid of the Corso or it's
not the grassy I really can't say but I
think it is be investigated that's
really interesting yeah I I can't wait
to see more research on that and thanks
for sharing that so sure moving on from
curing the last topic I wanted to cover
really quick was sort of this concept
around myths and I know we've kind of
touched on a few things already but is
there anything else that you've seen you
know coming out of your you know having
this degree coming into the cannabis
industry with your background is there
anything else you're noticing that
really stood out to you is sort of a
sort of a crazy methodology or anything
that we're doing in this industry that's
just that's just really unique or
different yeah you know a lot of it
always goes back to fertilizer for me
but the concept of Flushing's that's one
I'm still questioning you're the only
research I've seen put out is from I
can't remember the name it was from a
master's degree dissertation in Canada
where they were looking at Flushing but
all they really measured was the amount
of nutrients within the flower and so
not not form of nutrients but just
elementals basically and so what they
found is that with flushing whether it's
one week two weeks that there was no
decrease in elements which makes
complete sense because you know you hear
you're flushing you're flushing the
nutrients out of the plant well that's
not assignment possible you might
manipulate the form that the nutrient is
in but you're not just gonna yeah for
some remove parts that have developed
into the cells of these plants so you
know that that stays showed that no
you're not removing nutrients you know
fact but that doesn't mean that you're
not change that restricting nutrients is
not changing potentially you know the
form and also you're not speeding up
some of those post-harvest processes
that are beneficial so you know maybe if
you are causing nutrient deficiency then
maybe the plant thinks it's time to be
harvested it's the fall and you know
speeding up some of these ripening
procedures like the starch to sugar or
core so degradation that could in fact
yield a better quality post-harvest
flower I'm not sure or you know it's
flushing beneficial because we are over
fertilizing the plants and this is
actually a break for the plants to you
know to not be does not have salinity
stress and it's actually an opposite
stress very quickly done to the plant
two weeks before I don't know and I
don't have any of those answers but you
know I get frustrated when people just
generally say oh you're getting rid of
the nutrients and the planet you know
it's it doesn't make sense I think we've
got to strive to ask more questions and
not be stuck on just carrying around the
myth that you know other growers have
said I think it's I think it's okay to
say we don't know I think it's okay to
try these things on our own
and and figure it out together yeah so
essentially it's very well established
that you're not removing nutrients from
the plant when you flush and that's just
basic plant science but possibly by
removing the nutrients from the media we
may be in
like speeding up senescence or creating
a stress response that allows for
potentially altering the the quality or
quantity of our final crop yeah
absolutely
okay that makes sense anything else
around the myths that you wanted to
discuss or other concepts that you found
don't just just haven't played out in
real life
you know as I think we covered them
mostly the main ones that I have in mind
and that you know I've been able to
touch on somehow through research even
it says you know again those inclusions
but at least the starts yeah I think
that cannabis has done a great job you
know conducting throwing and and and
doing things without being able to go to
your Extension agent or you know take a
class it's it's pretty amazing how its
progressed and it's just exciting to to
help put some of those data points on
you know successful growing techniques
well I appreciate you sharing all this
information I know that a lot of time
and money goes into creating these
experiments and the fact that you're so
you're so willing to share this freely
with other growers I think is quite
remarkable and I really appreciate that
and I really thank you for all the great
work you've done already in this
industry and sort of bringing science to
the forefront so that we can learn a lot
more about this plant and really draw
effective conclusions as to what's going
on absolutely it's my pleasure all right
well thanks for your time today Allison
I can't wait to hear what you what you
learn and come up with next and I really
appreciate you coming on the show today
that was Allison justice without co and
SC labs if you're in South Carolina and
in need of extraction be sure to reach
out and don't forget to leave our
podcast a good rating and review on
whatever platform you listen on it's
these reviews and support through our
website that allow me to keep producing
these podcasts and bringing on great
guests thanks for all your support and
happy growing
[Music]