[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge don't
forget to subscribe to the podcast and
leave us a rating and review you can
also sign up for our newsletters on our
website as it's the best way to find out
what new episodes and blog posts come
out as well as any discounts or coupon
codes this week's podcast is especially
important to anyone making a living off
of farming or cannabis cultivation too
many people today using the words
factory and farm in the same sentence is
nothing short of sacrilege in many cases
though the same sound business practices
apply whether you're producing cars or
cannabis benef Department has found that
incorporating the best new ideas from
business in newest farming can
drastically cut out waste and increase
profits making the farms more
environmentally and economically
sustainable working smarter not harder
also prevents the kind of burnout that
startup farmers or growers often
encounter in the face of long hard
back-breaking labor Ben and his wife
Rachel own and operate clay bottom farm
in Goshen Indiana where they make their
living growing and selling specialty
crops on less than one acre their food
is sold locally to restaurants and
cafeterias at a farmers market and
through a CSA program in 2017 Ben was
named one of the 50 emerging green
leaders in the United States by Grist I
took a long shot reaching out to Ben I
know that cannabis cultivation can be
off-putting to many traditional farmers
I was honored that he was willing to
come on the show to talk about his book
in the concept of lean farming I cannot
stress enough how important this book
can be in changing your business for the
better I've been telling all my friends
and growers about it and made some
massive changes on our farm based on the
principles outlined in his books without
further ado though here's this week's
interview
well thanks Ben I really appreciate you
taking the time to come on the show
today hey you're welcome thanks for
happening thanks for having me
yeah so for my listeners I heard been at
the focus on farming conference that was
local to me this winter and heard about
his book and the concepts have already
had a huge impact on my farm and I don't
want to get into all the details of the
changes we've made because of your book
but we made some pretty major financial
and philosophical commitment to these
concepts okay and I think every farmer
needs to read your book so I want to
start off by giving listeners though a
little bit of information about your own
personal history yeah sure I grew up on
a northern Indiana 500 acre corn soybean
farm and our farm was just down the road
from Earl Butz who is Richard him
Nixon's secretary of agriculture and he
was made famous for saying get big or
get get out that's how you're gonna make
it in agriculture and so that is the
mindset with which I entered farming and
so we might when I got married we
purchased a five acre property and it
was my thinking that is a stepping stone
property and we eventually you know
whose expanded ten acres and 20 acres
and then and then work her way up from
there
because when I was growing up the
metrics for success that you're a
successful farmer in northern Indiana if
every year you got a bigger tractor
every year you rented or grew on more
land every year you put up another grain
bin and if you didn't then something was
wrong with your farm and so that's the
mindset with which I entered farming and
to my detriment because we had we what
the type of firing I want to do was
small skill and local vegetables we were
selling direct to customers and it was
labor intense and it didn't take us long
before I realized I just constantly
expand being just wasn't going to work
on a number of number of levels first it
meant that we were having to find more
accounts further away from home and
drive to Chicago drive to Detroit or
Indianapolis to find accounts for food
and so is stretching the definition of
being a local farm
and then also just from a psychological
standpoint it was just constant stress
and it kind of hit home
I hit home one afternoon and actually
only I tell you a story here of how I
tell you how I greenhouse ended up on
the roof of our barn is every year we
used to have what we call pizza and we'd
party and it was a name that we cleverly
chose to lure college students how to
our farm and weed our we did greenhouse
or two and then we'd feed him pizza
afterwards and so one app so this one
about ten years ago we're getting ready
for a pizza and we'd party and we'd set
out all the tools and we rich and I
wanted a house for a break and then it
was a light breeze in the morning Howard
by mid afternoon the winds starting to
pick up and eventually the slow wind
turned into a gale force wind and we
heard Rachel heard a thunk and she ran
to the window and she said Ben you
better come see what's going on here and
so I ran in oh and saw the green our
greenhouse had landed on a roof and had
it the bed the ball or not block the
greenhouse it would have ended up in
northern Michigan or Canada I don't know
but and it was because we had in felt
part of the lean system you're supposed
to ask the question what I five times
whenever something goes wrong to get at
the you know you want to get at the root
of every problem and so what is the
reason I greenhouse ended up on the roof
first we when we the first time we asked
that question well I we say well is
because there's a high power wind how do
we ask that question enough times it so
you ask it again the second reason is I
thought it was under engineered and he
asked well what's the reason and what
then well it was it under engineered
because I was in a hurry bill in the
greenhouse anyhow by the time he asked
why five times the root cause of the
greenhouse being on the roof of our barn
I was was simply that I was overworked
and working too fast trying to expand
the farm too quickly and after that
happened we realized hey we need to
maybe think about our business model and
maybe there's a different way of running
and growing a business and and that's
where the lean says
and our thinking can you talk a little
bit about what it lean manufacturing is
so people kind of have a foundation of
what where you started this idea of lean
farming uh-huh and just I want to back
up just a minute just that clarify kind
of who we are at this point we us how we
raise organic vegetables and we do it on
in less than an acre of land and all of
our accounts are within a mile and a
half of our farm so we're kind of an
uber local micro farm and we're make a
comfortable living over a hundred
thousand dollars a year doing that um so
lean what lean manufacturing essentially
amounts to is putting on a set of
eyeglasses and notice then you read a
lot about seeing and vision in the lean
literature but essentially you're
noticing when am i adding value for the
customer in other words when am i
touching my product and causing the
value of my product to go up and then
when am i contributing to muda which is
a term we roughly translate as waste
however it's essentially any activity
that's that is happening on your farm
that's not directly adding value for
your customer and the Japanese very
precise culture and they identified
seven specific types of mutas and now
they've added three or four new types of
mutas um and we just have one forward
for muda in English we just call it
waste
however it's like how some cultures they
have 600 or more words reindeer or
whatever the Japanese have thought more
carefully about non value-adding process
than we have and so essentially what you
want to do is maximize the amount of
time and effort going into value-adding
activities and minimize or better yet
eliminate all the waste activities yes
so before hearing you speak in reading
reading your book I had I had heard of
lean manufacturing in fact one of our
main people at our farm was telling me
about how we should incorporate this
into the farm and I was familiar with
Toyota and all you know some of what
they had done and to me there was a huge
disconnect I wasn't able to in my brain
go from what Toyota does in the
manufacturing facility to all the
different aspects and things going on in
my farm it felt like there were too many
variables
uh-huh so what your book really does is
connects the thought between that lean
manufacturing and then this thing this
concept of lean farming which is that
something that you coined is this your
term and actually no because it farms in
Asia Asia in in Scandinavia have been
using lean systems thinking for several
decades it's just new to North America
here um and I to clarify - they say lean
came from manufacturing how are the
first workers at Toyota in the 1930s
were rice farmers and it's these rice
farmers who brought this lean way of
thinking to the factory floor and I
think that's part of the reason that the
seven types of weights that they
originally identified at Toyota these
are ways they're ubiquitous on farms and
one has to wonder if agricultural
thinking then influenced Toyota and and
wasn't one of the reasons why Tod
eventually became eight point times
eight times more profitable you know
than GM and Ford and and I think farmers
especially in 17th and 18th century
Japanese farmers they just had to be
shrewd and they had a they had to farm
farm you know or else they weren't going
to make it there are a lot of historical
sociological reasons for that but anyhow
so that's a stay it's actually
originally at as much an agricultural
system as it is manufacturing system I
didn't know that that's really
interesting can we dive in a little bit
to the five basic principles of lean
before we talk too much about muda and
you have some great examples here in
your book starting with is it ciri uh uh
yeah you mean it for the five s process
yes yes okay
and so lean is can roughly be thought of
as a series of there are four basic lean
concepts that fit most appropriately in
agriculture and the first is to apply
this 5 s organization system and the
second is by is identifying value from
your customer and then getting rid of
the loop is then the fourth step would
be continuous improvement and so we can
begin by talking about that first step
which is which I think is the place to
begin for most farms is to use this five
s process and essentially there's five
steps to getting a
workplace or organized according to the
lean system and it all goes back to when
am i adding value when am i contributing
to a waste and so the first step of that
5s process is called Siri or sort in
essentially that means as you go around
your property and every object on that
on in your work environment you ask a
simple question which is did you add
value for a customer in the past and for
cannabis say in the past and growing
season
did you add value for a customer whether
it's a fork or a hoe or you know planter
container or whatever and if you stir if
you struggle to come up with an answer
if you have to think it over then it's
probably time to get rid of that item
okay and so I tell you they're very
ruthless about the only items in the
workplace where those that are being
used on a daily basis for adding value
and we do this twice a year on our farm
we go around every object and some say
you should actually physically touch the
object we don't physically touch
everybody we salute we at least come
close to it physically close to it and
we ask that question dude did this row
cover to this hoe did this tractor
implement add value in the past six
months and if the answer is no then we
get it off the property and we've been
pretty ruthless about this I don't like
to have stuff on our property and we
farm with enough tools that would
fitness a small sized pickup and EXO as
you're doing this you want to choose
tools that you want to farm with a few
tools that add that add a lot of value
that perform many functions and so we
love for instance a hoe that can be a
grubbing hoe that's a strong hoe for you
know flipping soil if you need to and
yet it has a fine point so we can use it
for finer cultivating or the Beast BCS
working swap out multiple implements and
can perform a lot of functions more
we're always on the lookout for how can
we farm with fewer tools and get more
work accomplished now that kind of leads
essentially the next the next one which
is set in order because when you say
fewer tools you are removing tools but
you're also putting the tools where
they're most useful and even duplicating
tools can you touch on that a little bit
uh-huh yeah so we used to hit for
instance we used to have a
nice tool storage areas toolshed like a
lot of farms would have and the first
thing we did at lien consultant came out
and said you really need to take a stick
of dynamite to that toolshed because
it's adding a lot of muda to your
process and the reason is for every
process we had to do say prune tomatoes
we'd have to walk two hundred three
hundred paces to the tool shed grab the
pruners then walk back to the greenhouse
and prune the tomatoes then return the
pruners we put in as much work going to
get the pruners and returning him as we
did actually pruning the tomatoes and so
what we started to do in the lean
systems has to do is you want to hang
your tools at eye low high level
locations as close as possible to their
points of use and so now we have magnets
spread out across the property that hold
knives and rumors that we use on a
regular basis and every green how
they're for greenhouses everyone has a
tool set up and the tools we need in
that greenhouse are attached to the
greenhouse somewhere I got to say that's
a huge one for me a little light bulb
went off because I know for a fact like
some projects I would I would spend
15-20 minutes just looking for a tool
because it wasn't replaced it would be
on the entire other side of the property
from where it needs to be and the idea
of having an extra set of pruners or
extra sets of shovels or whatever
implement tool I'm implementing in the
location where I'm going to use it can
save not just my time but my employees
time which I'm paying labor on and yeah
that was a big one so we're working on
on getting all of the right tools in the
right places and I know that's going to
save us a ton of time awesome
and I think it's okay to duplicate tools
we say if a tool costs $50 or less we're
going to probably duplicate that tool
and so for instance every greenhouse we
on probably 15 or so knives that we'd
harvest with even though we only going
to use three or four nine seven time but
every greenhouse has a couple of them
attached to the greenhouse so that for
the reason that they're physically
closer to where we're using them and
that small investment is paid off now we
don't buy a tractor a separate tractor
for every greenhouse you know there's a
limit to tool duplicating but the point
is the keep your tools close to their
workstations yeah I'll put up some
pictures you also have some mobile
workstation examples in your book that
are really interesting to the
show that you can you can move the tools
around with the worker so that they're
easily accessible and easy to see when
you're getting low on supplies as well
uh-huh yeah and Darrin Darrin volt
Vollmer an excellent farmer up in
Wisconsin he would have more workers and
we have several dozen workers during
peak harvest season and what he does is
he would have a five gon bucket with an
organizing basket attached to it and so
every worker gets a bucket with
precisely the tools they need and they
carry that bucket around with them and
they're responsible for those tools in
the bucket but the the point is that to
not it said to make sure tools are where
they belong or in your hands they're
either in their place or in your hands
there's no third option that's great and
that leads us to our next concept which
is shine uh-huh yeah so like I said
there's a lot of language about you read
a lot about vision and seeing in the
lean literature and idea behind the
shine concept you want to clean your
tool your your work spaces with the
tooth tooth brush and make sure they're
well lit your most used tools workspace
should be very clean and the reason
behind that is you want to see when
waste is creeping in and so with with
cannabis production you want to think
about when are the steps in my process
when there's the most defect happening
the only near cleaning or we may be
submitting or whatever you want to make
sure those spaces are very clean and
very well-lit to seeing so you can see
your work and the a principle here too
is you want to perform site so in short
high frequencies birds and instead of
long low-frequency let me explain the
difference short high-frequency means
that every time we're done you know
watching a hundred pounds of lettuce in
the processing area or hosing a hundred
pounds hundred bunches of carrots we're
going to restore that processing
processing area to zero well that means
we're going to take it all the way back
to clean so it's clean condition and we
hang pictures up in our processing area
so that there's no ambiguity about what
zero look
like in that processing area and so
every time we're done working in there
you know every every hour 90 minute
chunk at I know we're done working we're
going to take it back to zero is the
language we use and will used to do the
long low frequency method would be to we
just junk up the farm from say March
until Thanksgiving and then we thought
hey we'll have the entire energy all
winter to clean it but we never did it
it always just every year just got more
cluttered and what you which which
happens so when it comes to these first
three steps sorting saying in order and
cleaning the thing I tell people is that
you don't have to do it all in one week
and we did actually about a week we just
we got several wagon loads off of our
property several tons of John literally
off our properties we didn't one big
push however you don't have to what you
can do is just make sure that you're
headed in the right direction because
the trajectory that your your euro land
is ultimately the most important thing
because trajectory is a very powerful
psychological force is the most powerful
force in the world I think because if
you think about ear your farm is headed
in one of two directions you're either
getting more cluttered every growing
season or you're getting more
decluttered you're only headed in one of
two directions and you just want to know
you're headed the right direction yeah I
think this is a really important step
and it's one that we are taking baby
steps on ourselves
you know I mentioned to you before we
start the podcast I've actually brought
in some really large dumpsters that we
filled we got rid of a whole bunch of
plastic pots that we were been storing a
whole bunch of other other just
literally just junk that we need to
remove off the property or things we
weren't using and the psychological
effects of this has been really big the
staff is has a cleaner space to work in
they have take more pride in their work
it's not there's a there's a
psychological impact and that was
something that I learned from you was
that I didn't realize the psychological
impact of having a pile of junk the
amount of stress they created in the
fact I had to keep thinking about it
over and over again but once it's off
the property I can let it go emotionally
and that was a big deal absolutely
I'm reading a book right now called deep
work and I'd highly recommend it for any
wants to delve deeper in these concepts
but that idea is that we're actually
happiest and we're the most productive
when we have just what we need in front
of us and no more an especially in
itself uh in the smartphone right they
say the average office worker I
experienced some sort of disruption
every 15 minutes it's an on the farm
that what that happens to and whether it
be your disruptive because you can't
find the tool you're looking for or your
shrub because your cell phone goes off
or just constant interruption constant
disruption and we need to get into what
lean language lean would use is we call
a flow we need to get enter into a
workflow in order to achieve maximum
productivity this means we're working
for about an hour to 90 minutes without
interruption and once you get to that
point you can repeat a process of
getting into a deep flow it's a fun it's
been phenomenal on our farm how much
more productive we are yeah that's a
great point
you know I've always being interrupted
and it is hard to maintain your train of
thought and there's good studies out
there that show that we're not able to
multitask as effectively as we actually
think we are uh no or not so that's that
is a big deal and as we continue to
disrupt our work it actually changes the
neural pathways in our brain we actually
change how we think it becomes i we can
do long-term damage to our brain and
make it long-term more difficult to
enter that state of deep flow so I think
it's very important and something that's
overlooked often we think that
multitasking is often hair is often
Harold it is a something you want to
work towards like the open office
concept that I googled new offices are
just totally open and Facebook too would
have open offices and all right but the
reality is that you you open yourself up
to a lot of dis rack distraction in
which is definite all ultimately to the
bottom line yeah I think that's a really
good point and the other thing you
mentioned that I wanted to touch on was
the idea of how using photos and this is
a brilliant idea because the amount of
time it takes to explain and train
employee on what a space should look
like or the amount of time for them to
read all the every step if you want to
write things out is is pretty
detrimental compared to them being able
to just look at a photo and say this is
what it looks like now this is what it
needs to look like and make those
changes uh-huh
and that's a good segue in I psych way
into the forced up of the 5s process
which is standardization and so when you
perform those first three steps sorting
sliding an order in shining you want to
do it the same you want to repeat the
same steps especially with signing and
so photos really do communicate a
thousand words much much more efficient
so like I said we hang photos of what
our clean hosing station should look
like and then I don't have to tell
workers every time they set these crates
over here and I set these boxes over
here mop the floor we just say hey make
it look like what the picture is yeah
that's great
and then let's touch on the last one
there sustained uh yeah so it sent what
Toyota used system means you want to
make sure that these this 5s process is
part of deep is deeply ingrained into
your workplace culture and there are a
couple ways of doing this what Toyota
used to do is literally send someone
around each workstation and give a
numerical rating based on how close to
the workers were using the 5s system and
then give them bonuses I think one of
the best ways to sustain the practice on
a small farm is through hanging lots of
pictures up around the farm and asking
people keep the farm looking like what
those pictures look like and it's also
sometimes helpful to have a third person
say not you as the farm manager owner
but have a worker give inaud it give an
occasional audit maybe once a month or
something you could do once a week even
I just do a quick walk around and give a
numerical rating - how close to your
using the 5s system so your discipline
yourself to make it happen that's great
let's jump into the next section which
talks a little bit about what value
means and how you identify that for your
for your customers and I love that story
that you you told at the conference
regarding the toyota employee uh-huh so
we have this thinking in the u.s. anyhow
that we know more than our customers and
Steve Steve Jobs use this it was famous
for not listening to customers and users
say I know what my customers want more
than they know what they want and that
might be true and specially tech
industry there might be some exceptions
however for most businesses especially
agriculture though but the best phrasing
I've heard is from Jim Womack you wrote
the book lean thing it says you want to
start with the customer customer and
work backwards from there just so begin
with the customer work backwards from
there and so the customer is the only
force that is allowed to identify about
you in the lean system and so you want
to be very precise about identifying
value which means you want to listen
very very closely to your customers and
the Japanese have this tradition called
gun cheek and boots boot which means up
close and personal observation to
thoroughly understand a situation so can
she can boots and so was one of my
favorite stories of gun chicken boots
sue in practice is in 2004 it was there
Toyota said it's time to redesign this
sienna and Toyota was not they were not
the first in in the minivan market they
were kind of trailing behind however
they quickly took over the in a minivan
market because of what this one engineer
did and so they sent him over to North
America their primary market he told him
to drive him van in all parts of Mexico
Canada in the US and he spent better
part of a year doing this closely
observing how we're using the vans over
our vans over here and so he noticed
that in Santa Fe New Mexico for instance
he had trouble turning they needed a
tighter turning radius than those
current Sienna had and so he called home
and said we need to tighten the turning
radius by 15 degrees to get up and down
the alleyways in Santa Fe New Mexico and
so they did it they tighten up that
turning radius and then he noticed in
western part of the u.s. that we drove
long distances and we were eating like
four-course meals in our vans and this
wasn't a cultural tradition in Japan and
so he invented this beautiful flip up
console that this current Sienna has and
he put something like five
our cupholders in there there's no
excuse not to have I not to be drinking
while you're driving and then my
favorite example is he went to Ann Arbor
Michigan a couple hours north of our 4
and he went to the parking lot of a Home
Depot and he didn't go in he just stood
in the parking lot and observed and what
he noticed was that people were trying
to stuff for bait sheets of drywall or
plywood or whatever into the van and
they just couldn't quite get it in and
so they bunted the back hatch or try to
strap it to the roof and they became
very frustrated and so he called home at
that point and said hey from that
parking line he said we need to get a
four by eight sheet of whatever in the
van the next plan that we produce and
sure enough if you own a minivan
produced after that point in his history
then the odds are very high that you can
get a 4x8 sheet of plywood in it and
then Mather wise to it or hunter or gene
or Ford everyone followed suit but my
point is that notice how closely they're
observing their customers this is close
personal observation and then acting on
those observations and their level of
observation very my new very precise and
in Raich and I had to admit we heard
stories like this when we start looking
into the lean system Budi I'd admit we'd
never come close to taking our customers
that seriously and so one of the first
things we did after we'd clean up the
farm using up 5s system was to perform
this against you can boot due process
with our customers and really get to
know what they wanted so here's the
three questions this I'll summarize the
whole process with three questions
essentially you ask number one what do
they want what specific products are
they asking for number two is when do
they want it and the third is how much
and what amounts do they want it so with
very simple questions what do they want
what do you want how much and yet most
people in in most cannabis producers
most vegetable growers corn soybean
farmers certainly are not taking the
baby step it would take to get good
precise answers to those questions and
it really hinders your business yes so
basically what you're
hanging out there is what ad how do you
how do you identify value and then what
adds value and then what does not add
value and then you're essentially trying
to focus on ways to raise raise the
value or do more activities that add
value and less activities that don't add
value can you give a concrete example of
something you did on your farm that was
a change based on customer response or
customer feedback uh uh waiting for a
number of years ran a CSA which means
Community Supported Agriculture and what
this means is customers paid us the
beginning of the growing season and then
we gave him a box of food every week and
at first we said you had to come out to
the farm pick it up and we gave a couple
hours on Friday afternoons and we began
as prices we asked those three questions
to our customers and and those questions
obviously helped us determine what to
put in the CSA boxes how big to make
those CSA boxes and we altered the
amounts and me items that went into
those boxes however that we heard most
feedback was that we loved actually what
you're giving us however is inconvenient
to come pick up Friday afternoons at
your farm and so we started using pickup
locations around town and so they won't
have to make that ten mile trip and so
at the end of the next growing season we
asked those questions again and they
said we love the pickup locations
however it's hard to get there just on
Friday afternoons and so the following
growing season the third growing season
we installed coolers at those pickup
locations and so they could pick up
whenever during the week we told we're
going to deliver Friday afternoon you
come get it winters can be and then at
the end of that season we asked the same
questions and they said we love the
coolers that makes pickup much easy or
however it's just actually still kind of
hard to go to the groceries to grocery
store and then go to your pickup
locations like we're doing our groceries
in two places and so what we did is we
asked our customers where do you most
lower to most you do your grocery
shopping and then we partnered with that
grocery store to use them as a CSA
pickup location is their local food
co-op and so that our customers could do
their grocery shopping get their CSA
boxes in one
trip save a trip and then we ask those
questions again and we and and and now
what we're hearing is we love that being
able to pick up that this at the
supermarket saves our trip you're giving
us the right amount we love the
ingredients that are in in there however
we want more i we need some help with
cooking in the home we just don't have
time to cook everything and so now we're
partnering with the deli department of
our coke of our co coop to create a sort
of local blue apron option in which
we're going to put a whole meal package
together it won't be mostly our
vegetables how are the deli would maybe
bake a loaf of bread or add some
condiments and put a whole recipe whole
several recipes to put a whole meal
together and it'll be a blue apron model
form anyhow so the point is that's how
we retain CSA customers mo CSA's lose
more than half their customers on an
annual basis and there are a lot of
external reasons for this a lot more
competition a lot of more places to get
organic food than there was 20 years ago
and CSA is the beginning however there's
a lot of there are internal practices a
farm can do to keep your customers not
that's that's one of them you know I
learned this lesson the hard way
literally tens of thousands of dollars
I've wasted in I started off with an
edible nursery with all these
permaculture plants that are really
really awesome plants
unfortunately no one in my community
really cared they didn't care that I had
all these really cool plants that I
thought was really fascinating or some
of my friends thought was fascinating so
they sat on the farm I had to water them
I had to care for them people came in
and bought the same things blueberries
apples you know stuff they knew and
occasionally I would sell some of these
other plants but I had to lean down my
nursery to what was actually selling and
I didn't even really know this concept
at the time it was just something I
discovered in addition we were growing a
lot of these really cool rare vegetables
and heirloom plants but again no one was
buying them they were they were going to
waste because uh-huh I wasn't looking at
what the custom was valuing I was taking
my values and trying to impose them on
the community and so you know having
thousand pounds of organic habanero
peppers doesn't do any good if there's
no one in the area that wants to eat
habanero peppers so
uh-huh absolutely.i I've made this
mistake year after year and so I'm
really excited that we've kind of been
forced into this process as we've
learned the hard way what not to do and
I'm hoping other people can avoid making
this mistake so don't don't necessarily
grow the planet that you want to grow
grow the plant that your customers are
going to value and want want you to grow
so now we're growing some Tulsi Basil's
that are holy Basil's for the local
Indian community as well as some some
certain eggplants that they've requested
so we're going on asking them okay what
we can do to support them rather than
what week what they can do to support us
there we have it
yeah another way to say that is to that
the customer is the only one who defines
up you and I they call that owner
Distortion owner of a distortion via the
technical term for what happens in a lot
of businesses were your own fascinations
get in the way of profits because the
customer should be out ahead pulling you
along one thing we try to do is get all
our orders before we even purchase our
seeds at the beginning of the year sit
down with all our chefs and and map out
who's going to purchase who's going to
eat every single you know crop that we
produce and then we'll get our seeds
ordered and go from there that's great
and I'd like to use that as a transition
into our next our next topic which would
be muda which i think is the most
fascinating aspect of lean and you list
10 tools for minimizing waste which is
essentially what what muda means can we
talk about each of those just touch on
them briefly starting with the idea of
minimizing your movement yeah so one of
so like I said the Japanese identify
these types of waste in a production
environment and motion waste is the
sixth type it's not first on the list
however it's prevalent on every farm and
the idea behind motion waste is you want
to actually count the number of times
you touch your product and like I said
you want to achieve what they call
smooth flow and so you want to touch
your product as few times as possible in
the grocery industry they say you're
allowed three touches
for instance selling a box of kicks I
you unload the kicks from the wholesale
distributor put it on the shelf customer
picks it up you check check out so you
in the customer checks out so they say
it's a grocer or you're allowed three
touches and if you touch it if you can
get by with just one touch then you're
making money if you touch it two times
then you're probably breaking even if
you get to three touches you're probably
losing money I think on farms we're
allowed probably five or six touches a
few more however not many more touches
than that so the first tip I would have
is to just count and you know map out
your process you know what steps are
involved in production and then how many
times did you touch your product before
it got into the hand of the customer and
try to get it down to four or five
touches yeah can you take me through
that process like with a carrots or or a
tomato or maybe lettuce to kind of
describe what that looks like
uh-huh and so yeah I'll use an example
of head lettuce what we used to do we
say we have two hundred heads of lettuce
that need to be picked and processed and
sent off your customer I'll tell you our
old process as we would harvest those
200 heads of lettuce someone would
harvest and then take them up to the
processing area so there's a touch not
someone else to pick up the each head of
lettuce and clean each at a lettuce it
strip off the bad leaves there's a touch
and someone else would pick it up again
and dunk each other lettuce and wash it
so we're up to three touches and then
someone would pick it up again and in
wrap plastic around it or tie a band
around it and then someone would package
it put in the final packaging for the
customer and then put it into the
walk-in cooler so we're up to five
touches and then someone would take it
out of the walk-in cooler and put it in
our delivery vehicle and drive to town
six touches and then unload it from the
vehicle deliver to the customer seven
touches okay I'm being ultra being very
specific here because it's really
incredible how much more profitable we
are after we wrapped your mind around
this concept so lien would suggest using
what they call a single piece flow
process in other words could we so we
had seven touches that added value to
lettuce every time we touch that and
it's a gained
in value and what lien says to do is add
as much value as possible to the product
in your hand before you set it down and
one way I like to word it is to harvest
as market ready as possible and so on
the example of our lettuce our current
process is someone cuts the head and one
as the in while the lettuce is in their
hands they strip the bad leaves off the
lettuce and then they dunk it in a
bucket of water that they've taken out
to the field with them it's still in
their hand and then they give it a
little shake and they'll tie a twisty or
wrapping plastic out in the field and
then they put it in the final container
going to the customer out in the field
we have I we have what I can set up so
that final containers aren't you know
touching the ground in their harvesting
and placing it in the container and so
we've got we're just down to we're just
still on our first touch we haven't set
down the head of lettuce and yet we've
added volume for different process these
and then the person we've stopped
actually using a walk-in cooler instead
we back up a refrigerated delivery
vehicle to the location the item is
harvested and we're going to load it
directly in a refrigerated delivery
vehicle and within an hour it's off to
our customers okay and so one of the
reasons we want to get rid of the
walk-in cooler was motion waste because
there's a there's the extra motion of
putting it in the cooler and taking it
out of the cooler it's two touches so
for most of our crops we're getting away
with three or four touches instead of
seven or eight touches and it actually
has increased your profits by almost
twice as much because we're spending
half the amount of effort it doesn't
sound like a big change when you when
you list it out it sounds so stupidly
simple stupidly simple and yet it does
small changes like that make us such a
big difference
yeah and over the course of the year
we're talking hours and hours of savings
in time uh-huh you use the example I
believe in your talk of putting a letter
together a folding ceiling an envelope
and in my mind when you mentioned it my
first thought was well you'd have three
people and the first person would put
the letter in and hand it to the next
put it down the next person would pick
it up and seal the envelope with with
water or lick the lick the adhesive and
then put it down the last person would
put the
stamp on and that would be the fastest
way but it's actually way more efficient
for one person to do all three of those
steps without sending the letter down
absolutely and I've done that when I
have when I have enough time with groups
I'll have a I have one person come out
front and do the single piece flow
process with the letter and then I'll
have someone come up and do a batch of Q
system which would be that where you you
know fold a hundred letters and then you
stuff a hundred letters and then you
stamp 100 letters and it's amazing how I
have never that the single piece flow
people are consistently at least twice
as quick as the batching queue people
and yet it's counterintuitive we think
that it's more efficient to work in
large batches but it's actually it
actually isn't yeah and I think it's
better for the employee because it's
more interesting to do multiple steps
and I think it also reduces the amount
of fatigue or risk of injury because you
are moving around more and you're not
doing just the same repetitive motion at
least as a repetitive so there's a ton
of benefits to it and I love that idea
you also under minimize moves you talked
about spaghetti diagrams and drawing up
a picture of everywhere that you walk in
a given space doing a task can you touch
on that real quick
yeah so this is another very simple
technique that farm can use to quickly
shave a bunch of muda off your process
and and so what you do is pick that one
or two hours when you're the busiest
when there's most motion happening and
then have someone stand in a corner of
the room or you know on a balcony where
they can oversee the whole farm and just
have a blank sheet of paper and just
trace motion when did people move and
wind it a product move when was there
motion on the farm and after about 45
minutes or an hour its kind of look like
a plate of spaghetti noodles and then
what you can do is have everyone huddle
around and ask three questions of that
plate of spaghetti noodles number one is
how could we have shortened some noodles
number two how could we have
straightened some noodles if you see
curves and the third is how could we
have eliminated some noodles and ideally
you eliminate a bunch of noodles and we
use this process we're actually setting
up a new farm right now and we use
spaghetti diagrams to
I'll define where buildings should be it
helps set up our processing area so we
did several rounds of pretend to
harvesting head lettuce for instance and
determine the shortest routes for the
head lettuce the straightest lines and
what actually ultimately led us to is to
build one large building a home in which
we have our house or processing area
garages storing your storage area a
potting shed we got a bunch of functions
that are in one building to eliminate a
bunch of noodles and then that we kept
our growing areas very close to the
processing area so there's there's
there's we've eliminated as many lines
as work as possible now there's more
types of muda and tools for reducing
them I don't want to give away
everything in the book because I think
it's important to visualize it and read
it so I want to keep this moving along
since I know we have a little bit amount
of time can we talk a little bit about
the idea of continuous improvement how
this process never really ends for you
and what that looks like
uh-huh yeah and especially when it comes
this is a little bit heretical with
farming nearly every farm book you read
our video course or whatever everyone
thinks they figured it out they figured
out the best way to make compost or the
best way to grow tomatoes or whatever
and they are going to sell you all their
secrets and I actually don't I am my
second book gives you all of our
production secrets it tells you where
we're at in the lean process with with
producing tomatoes and peppers and
everything else however at the point is
just to give you inspiration for your
own lean thinking because there never is
a perfect perfect way to do something
it's always about continuously improving
your process there's always a better way
to do something though let phrase they
use in lean is no problem is a problem
if you think you have no problems then
that's that's your problem anyhow so
essentially what you essentially what
continuous improvement or Kaizen means
is you perform the first three steps the
lean system with more precision every
year and so you get more decluttered
every year so the first step is out 5s
and orgonite so you get more organized
every year get more junk off the
property and then number two you get
more
I see identify value from your customers
every year you get to know them deeper
and you deliver more value to them every
year and then third is you with mutas
you'd get rid of even more of the
Buddha's every year there's over
production waste waiting lease
transportation waste over processing
inventory waste there's always going to
be muda in your operation and every year
you just [__] a little bit more off of
your farm so I like this sculpture
analogy it's my favorite analogy for
lean is that you're it's like your farm
is a big log and every year you choose a
little more waste off the farm until you
have a very beautiful sculpture that's
pure value you've chiseled all the way
stuff but and you just keep keep honing
it and polishing it yeah I remember you
mentioning that even at Toyota they had
they had managers that got in trouble
because they weren't changing and
updating the standards consistent
constantly they weren't continually
looking with a really fine eye to be
improving the process so this is a
never-ending process of improvement like
you mentioned I think that's an
important factor there yeah or they used
to mandate that once a month the
processes had to change at some some way
so they mandated change mandated
continuous improve but yeah I think
that's great and can we talk a little
bit about how this lean process affects
your staff in the morale around the farm
uh-huh sure I what the thing with a
Kaizen or continuous improvement is it's
often you want it to be an all staff
project and the reason is your workers
are as close to the waste or sometimes
closer to the waste as you are and so
there's no reason-- about that to not
let them help you root out the waste and
what TG Ono at Toyota helped design lean
systems Yoda uses he used to say that
workers come to Toyota to think not to
build cars okay just think about that
they're in a manufacturing plant you're
often repeating tasks over and over
again but he said ultimately people come
here to think not to build cars and so
what it means is that you have engaged
staff people who are not just picking
tomatoes or stuffing envelopes
what they are doing is thinking
they're working and what we do is we
keep a list of the waste list of the
mood is in the center of our processing
area and we instruct our workers we say
hey we want you if you see one of these
types of ways we want to be the first
ones to hear it we encourage them to
kind of ruffle her feathers and to think
of a better better ways of doing things
which is countercultural and our culture
workers are trained and specially in
agriculture to just go out and pick and
there they're not thought of as as
managers and everyone should take some
management responsibility to make the
process more efficient yeah I think
that's great and it gives people more
ownership a feeling of ownership of
their space and their job and what
they're doing and the importance of it I
think it for us I'm finding it's
improving morale because people are
excited to see these changes as we're
making them around our property ok
and awesome one thing I wanted to touch
on because most of the people that are
listening to this that are cultivating
that are doing it commercially so this
is their business it's much easier to
cut costs than to grow your profit
margin so like you mentioned it's a lot
easier to reduce a thousand dollars
worth of expenses than it is to sell two
thousand dollars worth of new product so
you can maintain your sales which i
think is something you said you've done
over the years is maintain your sales
level but reduced your expenses and then
that's all money in your pocket
sure so to grow more up to Bruce more
product involves muda we're going to
have the mood of construction of another
greenhouse or mill at creasing that your
infrastructure for growing system you're
going to have the muda of training new
workers there's just a lot of effort
that goes into producing more and you
can grow your business also by trimming
out costs and wastes and then you don't
have to deal with all those mutas you
can just save money and add your
bottom-line so at the very simple secret
of our farm is that we've been making
we've been a grossing six figures for a
while however we haven't always I netted
a whole lot so we had started to do is
every year we print out an expense
lecture and we say we ask the question
hey where's the five percent
in others how could we trim 5% off of
our expense ledger and still produce
this same or more next year and who
couldn't you know scour the expansion
ledger and come up with 5% and so if you
do this over a course of ten years which
we have then you grow your business by
50% which is a very respectable rate of
growth you grow your net profit by that
much and you didn't have to produce more
in the process and so as pure Girish
pure profit and I think that at some
point all businesses need new customer
need more customers need to expand it
just has become it becomes a it becomes
an addiction in our culture and there's
another way to grow a business which is
to cut out the Muto's and get more
precise on adding value it is to so
every year we try to replace low profit
items with higher profit items and and
give our customers more value so that I
so that our we charge more for our
products and we're getting more from our
customers for the same amount of effort
yeah that's a great point
one concrete example for me was also
working with the people that we buy
things from or that we work with so for
me changing or renegotiating my merchant
service rate on credit cards made a
difference of almost fifteen thousand
dollars in a year and you know that's
money that I get to put back towards the
farm towards my employees not into the
pocket of a merchant service provider so
expenses are huge and I think that's one
place that we need to look at it and I
love how thoughtful you are before you
make a change on your farm because a lot
of times we're running around so crazy
we don't we don't take the time to
really give thought to the process or
even to buying a new tool or a new piece
of equipment we just are constantly
trying to move forward without
evaluating do we need this is this the
best tool for the job is this adding the
value all the questions that you're
asking in your book are just so
important now one thing you mentioned at
the end the book that I think is
interesting is that lean is a style of a
style of cultivation or an attitude
towards farming but it can be taken too
far can you can you talk a little about
what that looks like and what you meant
in that section well I think in
particular like let's say you're getting
your
you're an animal you're your protein
producer you you raise animals and I so
what one of the core tenets of lean is
you want to maximize your fixed cost and
so fixed costs for me would be a
greenhouse or processing a fixed cost
for a hog producer B be a hog house and
and so what lean would suggest is that
you want to stuff as many hogs as
possible and into the hog house and I've
seen lean use this way in agriculture
and with milk production and you want to
get as many gallons of milk as that
animal as possible and you're going to
maximize the investment you have in the
animal and I think there are just some
ethical considerations you need to use
and in farming if you're going to use
the lean system and I would also suggest
that farmers who try to stuff as many
hogs as pasta another hog house are not
probably applying a value analysis as
lean would suggest they should in other
words how are they act are their
customers actually wanting them to do
that is that the process their customers
want and lean says like I said start
with a customer work backwards from the
customer and so that be one one example
and on with food for with vegetable or
grain crop producers I think there are
all kinds of ways to I use more fossil
fuels on our farms to increase
production and again I think we have to
ask is this what our customers are
wanting this is what our the process our
community wants
anyhow you can't take lean too far on in
an agricultural context I totally agree
in fact an example of this on our end
would be you know choosing where we
source the ingredients that we put into
our soils for example because we
manufacture soils and knowing to me I
know our customers value using
high-quality ingredients so if I were to
go out and source a cheaper ingredient
in that mix it wouldn't be providing
value even though it would be lowering
my expenses because it might lower the
quality of my actual product so it's
really important to look at that and
like you mentioned ethics is so
important here we're you know we're
trying to protect the environment we're
trying to come up with sustainable
methods and conventional agriculture
isn't necessarily all that
sustainable and I think that's where it
falls down in relation to lean
manufacturing concepts
uh yeah cost-cutting is not necessarily
lean cost-cutting can be very unli if
it's not the type of does not if it
doesn't secure your cut business in the
direction where your customers are
winning yeah so the last question I had
for you was as I mentioned to you this
is a cannabis cultivation show and I
know you're not able to cultivate
cannabis but there is anything you'd
like to add or touch on on the topic
before we sign off for the day I would
say that it be great if Indiana would
and actually we've been working on it
and Indiana is they're talking about
some legislation now that would make
medical marijuana available but I think
that the process that lean system is a
universe saying you lean system is a
universal system in that the types of
wastes are Preval and so there's no
reason you can't use lean with and even
if you grow one marijuana plant or if
you have tens of thousands of plants the
lean system is applicable no matter what
size business you have how many workers
you have or who your customer is there's
something you can gain from and you can
become more profitable and you can
create a more pleasant work environment
first oh yeah I think it's so important
because we want to spend our time doing
other things like this allows you more
free time to spend with your family and
more time to spend doing things that you
want to be doing not that you don't love
your work but finding ways to reduce
your expenses increase your bottom line
and make yourself make your life more
efficient I think is a win all around so
I just wanted to say again Ben has two
books out I'll put links to both of them
on the podcast page and as well as some
photos and other things but I highly
recommend people check out your books
and I really appreciate you taking the
time today to come on the podcast and
chat with me about lean farming hey
thanks thanks for having me
that was Ben Hartman author of the lean
farm and the lean farm guide to growing
vegetables I can't recommend his books
enough and I hope listeners will
incorporate at least one aspect of lean
farming into your growing practices as a
way of becoming more efficient in
reducing waste you're listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget
that there's more information articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
well as links to the data and
information we discussed in this episode
on the podcast page and if you enjoy
these podcasts please take a moment to
leave me a rating and review on iTunes
and send me your feedback and
suggestions through a website contact
page or tad at K is organics calm thanks
for listening