[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
this week i had the pleasure of chatting
with samuel hilfer sam is a 10-year
cannabis industry professional and
current head grower of proof cultivar
sam is finishing an agronomy degree at
oregon state university and focuses
primarily on nutrient management
irrigation techniques and cannabis crop
production
sam has created a novel cultivation
model at proof cultivar while building
one of the most advanced and informative
data sets on cannabis nutrient values to
date sam's long-term goals include
establishing optimal nutrient ranges for
cannabis creating an open platform for
industry professionals to share
knowledge and to continue pursuing a
lifelong passion for researching
cannabis cultivation now on to the show
hey sam thanks for coming on the show
today
absolutely thanks for having me happy to
be here
yeah i'm excited we get a chance to talk
i know i got to come down and visit your
facility a few months ago now and see
you guys in production but uh
let's go ahead and give listeners a
little background into uh who you are
and what you do over at proof
yeah absolutely so my name is sam
hoelsler i'm currently a head grower at
proof cultivar in portland oregon
we're pretty large indoor organic
cannabis facility and my background with
cannabis is a little over 10 years now
grew up in pennsylvania and was
introduced to cannabis pretty early on
and started to grow almost immediately
they've kind of bounced around the
country you're operating a number of
different facilities from working with
penn state and tissue culture and
greenhouses there to
southern oregon and large 50-acre
cannabis and hemp operations and
mushroom cultivation down in southern
california and
i bounced around and ended up at proof a
little over a year and a half ago
and have been working ever since to try
to revolutionize and overhaul the the
cultivation model that was going on
there and
have since landed on a new program um
part of it uh due to kiss organization
yeah now in portland oregon and
having a blast and operating one of the
greatest facilities i've got to work
with
yeah this facility is uh
quite technologically advanced in a lot
of ways and yet you guys are also facing
some other challenges um
because of the way the facility was
generally laid out
i was going to get into this later but
since you mentioned the technological
aspect let's just you want to kind of
describe some of those things that you
have at proof and how
you know how they've been either useful
or not as useful as you would have
thought when they were originally
installed years ago
yeah that's a really um interesting
topic proof kind of started out with
this really grand ideal of being able to
take cannabis cultivation to the next
level of scientific production and
technological production and so there
was a lot of automation
early on back in the day from
custom-built robots that lift trays up
and down and move them along transfer
line systems to
auto pot washers and auto dirt fillers
auto planters kind of
the whole purpose was to be able to
stage plants get them in a room and then
the automation kind of takes care of the
rest and
for all the ambition i think most
cannabis growers that have grown for a
number of years know that it's
really hard to automate a human touch
when it comes to cannabis cultivation
and being able to produce
really great craft quality cannabis
automated just isn't something that's
always worked out and so we've
slowly and quite painfully over the year
kind of ripped out all of the initial
automation and gone back to just
hands-on labor and hands-on process and
at this point in the grow everything is
done by hand everything from propagation
to
about half of our watering to
transplanting and pruning and topping
harvesting weighing
packaging trimming everything is done by
hand
there's really
not a lot of automation that goes on at
all i think the
the little bit of you know technology
that we do utilize now is
is more for data collection and trying
to
control
everything around the plants rather than
the plants themselves so we work really
hard to use some custom
operating systems and softwares for our
climate control to
to deliver
accurate climates and set points
to the rooms themselves and then to
collect some really high-end data
regarding irrigation and try to bring
some of these new crop steering
principles and merge them into an
organic methodology
and make them work so it's this really
interesting blend of
starting out at high technology and then
kind of working our way backwards to
really where the basics are at and
trying to utilize some of the
the basic agronomic technology that's
been around for a number of years things
like tanziometers is super important in
the program that i've that i've designed
and
just
automated irrigation as much as possible
through trip lines and climate control
and being able to track those trends has
been really impactful versus
you know things that i haven't
found to be worth the money or you know
the auto fillers the auto pots
things that
try to automate the labor aspect of it
for you it's really difficult to
to eliminate that from your program i
found
yeah you're one of the few facilities
i've seen that's kind of gone the other
way where you you started like highly
technologically advanced and actually
have moved the other direction as you
guys have tried to pursue better craft
cannabis which is really interesting and
um
the other thing that i would possibly
highlight is you know a lot of the stuff
that's used
horticulturally
as technological tools don't necessarily
translate as well to cannabis um
it seems like uh
some of the plants and and you can
correct me on this if i'm wrong um
cannabis seems to be a little bit more
sensitive in terms of how it's handled
versus some of these other uh you know
ornamental ornamental crops that we're
mass producing for the
you know in these greenhouses and
industries what
what are your experiences with it right
yeah that's
it's more
difficult to
uniformly take technology and just apply
it to cannabis you know with with
ornamentals and these mass-produced
crops in greenhouses there's
kind of this one-size-fits-all
method to technology you come in and you
just create a uniform environment across
the entire space
and you're able to do all of your
processes without really having to
change much versus cannabis is very you
know every plant is is unique and alive
and growing and individual and the way
you shape it and form it
and work with it over its life cycle
really impacts the product on the on the
end
and it's actively changing in its
climate i mean the climate change from
propagation to veg to flower to mid
late and early flowers just
it's really different all the way
through and so
there yeah you're right there's not a
lot that you can take from
maybe these mass-produced industries
that have been around for much longer
and try to adopt that technology and and
furthermore it makes it a bit of a
challenge because
these days most large companies whether
it be ornamentals or other
you know mass-produced farms they're
trying to
focus on the the money side of it first
they're trying to be as economical as
possible and it's really hard to take
that and apply it to an organic
setting you know i've run into this
issue with
trying to adopt volumetric water content
measurements and
things of that nature to
kind of a container-grown soilless media
for cannabis it just doesn't always work
out the same and so there's a lot of
adoption and adaption that has to happen
whenever you
try to take something from another
industry and apply it to cannabis
yeah and let's be clear your
your yields are are still quite good i
believe you guys are the top producer in
oregon i think is what jeremy was
telling me um if i remember correctly
yeah
we're still pretty good it's been a up
and down roller coaster for 2020 we were
the largest indoor producer by volume
like how much we produce for the
majority of the year and
it gets a little difficult late season
when all these outdoor farms start
coming in and mass producing crops but
it it took a long while maybe a little
bit of history about the grow as we we
didn't start out organic we started out
as a mineral two-part fertilizer you
know 52 gallon pots on a single tray and
it wasn't good
and then jeremy um brought in a
wonderful cultivation design jeremy plum
for those wondering
and
created a really awesome organic program
and it took about two years to just to
reach this point where it was
extremely dialed in and record-breaking
and hitting just massive number output
from our rooms and really happy with it
and
we're kind of diving into another topic
here but we we went through some pretty
massive changes in 2021 that were forced
upon us that
is inevitably how we ended up in this
new program to
to
really have to work our way backwards
and try to reach those numbers again and
it's been extremely difficult but
really happy with where we're at yields
are
are doing really well and um yeah happy
to kind of walk through that transition
that we had to go through if you want to
dive down that rabbit hole
yeah i think that's a good segue i do
want to come back and talk to you about
what technological uh tools you found
are most useful in your grow so i i just
want to shelve that one but
i remember jeremy reached out to me
towards the end of last year a little
bit panicked like hey we need soil right
away um
we were fortunately able to get you guys
what you needed at the time but
basically and i'm not going to name any
names here but you had been working
with a bottled nutrient line and
apparently they changed their
formulation during covid without telling
you
and as i understand that created very
high levels of chlorides
uh in the in the soil or in your in your
solution and that um you want to talk a
little bit about what effects that had
on the plants for people who aren't
familiar with
uh chloride toxicities or yeah yeah
it was
it was a really interesting situation um
like you said we have been using the
same program for about two or three
years we were using basically an inert
media that was cocoa and peat paste
and then we were using
bottled nutrients
and at the same time you know peak
demand was just through the roof and one
of the really big key producers in
canada had a bog fire
heat supply was just massively low and
they were scraping the bottom of the
barrel and the product we were getting
in was just like cake flour it was
powder there was just nothing to it that
was allowing good growth and we put in
an order and they basically canceled it
and said sorry we can't supply you and
we only had eight weeks of supply left
so
soil media kind of being the foundation
of the program it was really difficult
to take them back okay we have to build
something new within eight weeks it was
a really scary endeavor which i think is
you know when we gave you a call and we
started to really pursue all those
options and
yeah at the same time i had been
tracking for about six months before
this implant health issues seeing really
just
necrotic tissue starting to form
yellowing leaves that just died back
just rapid
burning browning of the leaves that get
super crispy and it was really scary and
at the time i'm taking tests and i'm
doing
soil tests and sap analysis and tissue
tests and
i i was seeing ppm levels of chloride up
in the six seven eight thousand ppms in
the tissue
and the plants were just dying back
massively and it was terrifying to deal
with and
i tested everything from our nutrients
to our supply lines our recipes our soil
every single cultivar our plant sap
soil solution saturated paste or you
know an m3 test i went down a rabbit
hole of tests i even tested you know the
piping between our rooms to see
what is being
scraped away from potentially metallic
pipes and stuff and
circle back around and conclusively
prove that the issue was with this
fertilizer that we were buying and i
reached out and they just you know flat
out denied it and and six to nine months
later come back around spring of 2021
we're kind of faced with this issue and
jeremy and i ended up meeting with some
of the executives of that company
and showed them like hey this is a
really big issue and they confided to us
that they did in fact change their
recipe and
they didn't really think it was going to
affect growers and
lo and behold it had a massive effect on
our output and the value of the company
and and how everything was going so we
ended up in this position of
of having to completely change our
program from soil to nutrient and
fertilizer and do all of it in about two
months time period and we were coming
off our biggest year ever just a
record-breaking year from 2020 and
having
you know incredible output really happy
with where we were positioned in the
industry and now suddenly our whole
program just like crumbled in our hands
and we um we kind of took a step back
jeremy and i and we had a
i remember one day we were sitting in
the office and we had a really great
conversation about you know what is the
future of proof and where do we want to
take this brand and and what are our
core values and we agreed upon that we
wanted to stay organic but
in in this day and age i think jeremy
and i both agree that organic is never
really enough we want to move in a more
sustainable
model a a more advanced method it's
there's so many brands that just tack
organic onto their their label and it
doesn't really
mean much it doesn't mean it's you know
ecologically what's best for um
the planet so we
we definitely
decided upon early on that we wanted to
go with living soil and we talked to a
number of different people and we called
you and had great conversation and
really happy with the soil and
i think one of the biggest issues that
came up is uh
you know the first challenge was
container sizes our our facility was
designed for two gallon pots and
the program that we had been running for
three years was three gallon pots and
now we're forced with this issue of
living soil which you know we're being
told should probably be grown in you
know 20 30 30 gallon pots or beds
ideally and
i think that was a really difficult
situation that we just kind of had to
trust our ability to figure it out and i
know you're curious about that container
pot issue as well and
yeah it's been a long road and now we
settled in 10 gallon pots with a really
interesting
method of kind of using traditional
fertilizers still through drip injection
and
how they kind of match the depletion of
the soil with what we're putting in and
it's been a very
fascinating process i can
you want to talk about that or if you
want me to go back and
yeah
think i think we can go right into that
i will just add that
normally um well so let me give a little
more context here um just from and
correctly if i get this wrong uh one of
the one of jeremy plum's big goals with
proof it was to create consistent
uh
consistent chemo type expression so if
you were a medical patient walking into
a store and you wanted
to and you let's say you had really good
results from this particular cultivar
that proof produced
you know jeremy would be able to
confidently say that he's going to have
the exact same result every you know
batch after batch and that that tends to
push you away from living soils and
towards uh you know a bottled nutrient
or a program where you can control every
aspect of the plant's fertility whereas
with living soils we're giving up a
little bit of that control um and
counting on the microbes in nature to
sort of handle that for us so that's
that's a little context as to why proof
was growing the way they were growing
and normally too you know jeremy and i
talked about this and sam you and i
talked about how
you know this wasn't the ideal way to
make a switch over into another
production system normally you'd run
trials
you you know you run one room and see
how it performed and collect all that
data and then look to improve it make
sure the workflows make sense and sops
for your current staff
but um
you weren't able to do all that you kind
of had to make the make it yeah
did we jumped right off the deep end i
mean we were
we didn't even really have time to do
many trials or really any trials we kind
of we initially tried to sneak a couple
into some production crops to trade here
or tray there and we we're just like
yeah this isn't really working and it's
like you know we have one crop left of
our old soil of our old program like we
have to make a decision now and exactly
what you said yeah jeremy um his vision
with proof was always have a very
consistent product for the end consumer
and that's still really important to us
and
i would say we're still able to hit that
even in the new program and it's
been one of probably the most difficult
um
things to really target is just to
balance those minerals and that
nutrition for the plant so that the end
product you're getting is
really really accurate with with what
we're saying it is and just the
consistency is there every single time
so
yeah it was a big leap of faith um but
happily we've we've worked through it um
and so we went from
an old inert
you know three gallon pot highly liquid
injected inline injection drip system
where they're just getting
a lot of organic
liquid feed to using a 10 gallon pot and
we
we ran the first crop we threw the
plants in and we're like okay you know a
10 gallon pot
as much as we want to do water only it
we know it's probably not going to last
on nutrients for the size our plants
grow and so at what point does it start
to deplete and at what point do we have
to kind of lift it and pick it up with
these fertilizers and that was a really
big question for us that we just didn't
have the answer into and so we kind of
crossed our fingers through a whole crop
into the pots and
immediately the plants love the soil i
mean they just started out looking
awesome and
i started taking data and collecting
tissue and soil samples and just
recording this all and plotting it all
in crafts and
and really keeping an eye on it and then
about that same time frame we reached
out and we're talking to bryant mason um
soil doctor and had
really great conversation kind of
triangulating between you
jeremy and i and him
and
we kind of just established that let's
get away from the bottle nutrients let's
kind of go go way back to just the basis
of fertilizer from
organic products and just and using
powders and you know every single one of
these bottled products come from these
raw sources anyway so
let's just skip the whole liquid
injection and shipping this you know
massive weight around the country this
massive freight you know shipping carbon
footprint around the country and just go
back to the basis and use this
fertilizer so
we went back and now we use pretty much
everything attached to the sulfate you
know gypsum
epsom salt just
really basic stuff and so
when we switch to this new program with
the living soil we're doing 10 gallon
pots and it's working phenomenally and i
think that's something that's really
unique and rare for an indoor
grower especially in an organic setting
to use a 10 gallon pot in a living soil
with minimal fertilizer inputs and have
it work as well as it's working for us
i really started by just observing
where our depletion was at on specific
nutrients on specific time frames so
in my program i track and trace every
single analyte you know whether it's
calcium and nitrogen or potassium
phosphorus manganese iron
i track every single element
in every cultivar in every room
basically every single week and then i
plot those
on a graph and i have rolling averages
that i that i track and trace and the
dashboards see
how we trend on a weekly basis and then
you know i've
grabbed what sufficiency ranges exist
out there for hemp and i've kind of
adapted them to cannabis and then set
some of our own to really
establish where we want to be at for
those ranges
and then
the hardest part was you know how much
do we put in to kind of either step
these nutrients up or step them down
based on the trends of of what the plant
needs
in its specific lifestyle cycle phase so
you know as the plant goes through flour
you know it may start to need less and
less nitrogen it may want to use more
mag it may up take more mag so how do we
not only balance what we're putting in
and our concentrations and how much is
going into the soil but how do we
balance what's being depleted out of the
kiss already and that was
a pretty big challenge for me and a
massive learning curve as i kind of work
through those problems and we're
about
nine months into the program now and and
about five percent lower on yields than
we were in the old one after three years
so extremely happy with where we're at
product quality is just
through the roof our thc scores have
gone up from 19 to 27 on average
a lot of new genetics that we're working
with just really happy with the program
but it is entirely
novel and new in my opinion what we're
doing i've
i talked about this a lot at work that
we've kind of just grabbed from so many
other
methods of cultivation and made it work
in one
i'm kind of getting back to the
technology side of things i think
it's
really easy to focus on technology when
you're doing hydro and when you're doing
cocoa you know mineral fertilizers going
in i mean there's a number of companies
out there these days um
that are just focused on volumetric
water content and crop steering as a
whole and they're really precise and
just watching your ec and your dry backs
and doing all these really accurate
measurements
and when i first started looking into
that you know i was like okay this is
really great information but does this
even work in organics and
from what i found the principles of it
do but the sensors and the data that you
need to actually drive and make those
decisions are not the same so
piggybacking off of kind of some of the
initial stuff that brian introduced to
us we we went way back to just original
orometer tensiometers and
we go we use those to really
match our attention in our to our
drybacks rather than volumetric water
content you know with our soil we have
to pay attention to our matrix potential
and
and really
play up you know keep an eye on that
data and play a pivotal role in when we
want to trigger certain developments in
the crop cycle
when we want to trigger them to flower
when we want them to bulk when we want
them to finish and the maturation the
morphology we can control a lot of these
things based off tension alone
um and then
you know how much water we have to put
in in order to hit those specific drive
backs with tension rather than
volumetric water content so
we've kind of
had this original automated facility
that we switched to a living soil that's
all hand crafted
and we're using you know outdoor quote
unquote technologies like ten theometers
indoor with small containers 10 gallons
and using classic powdered fertilizers
with a batch tank mixing system and
it's this
very crazy model that we've been able to
build and work and
not only just get to work but
hit record-breaking yields again hit you
know record-breaking thc levels just
greatly improve our quality from a
program that was so well-defined before
and do it all within
about six months
it's been really incredible so
so so sam take me back a little bit here
um
you're talking about
using uh a tensiometer so you're
measuring the moisture tension of the
soil
and then you're you're utilizing that
data as a way of intentionally
uh
stressing the plant at certain stages of
growth can you can you kind of explain
that a little bit a little bit more
yeah absolutely so um the you know the
idea of tension you know is mature
potential is that the
[Music]
the soil particles are essentially
holding onto the water and roots want
that water and they have to overcome a
certain level of tension in order to
take that water away from the soil and
so
a tensiometer essentially measures you
know how hard those roots are having to
work in order to take that water away
from the soil particles and uptake it
and that's a really
you know
very uh
non-descriptive method of of what is
actually happening on the from a
scientific standpoint but essentially
that's what is the basic principles of
it and so
when you think about stress there's just
been this idea in cannabis cultivation
for a very long time that you know
there's good stress and bad stress and
obviously nobody wants bad stress on
their plants but there is ways to use
stress on a plant to influence
how you want that plant to grow and some
of these principles have been adopted
from um
crop steering and some of them we've
just kind of had to create on there on
our own so
as far as using the tensiometers i think
what's really important for us is to
limit that stress and have almost no
stress and vegetative and then during
flower there's a few different methods
people kind of tend to go two different
paths when it comes to flowers some
people like to stress early in flower at
the flip to kind of initiate
budding and then they go back to low
stress during bulk to really put the
weight onto the plant and then they
stress again late flower
to finish out the maturation period and
get them to really finish and that's
what i kind of adhere to that
methodology but then there's other
people that kind of do the opposite and
they want low stress when you flip the
flower and then stress mid-flower and
then no stress late flower so there's
kind of the inverse of each other but
what i found to be true is that if we
can hit a specific tension
but
before we water every single time so
for for instance vegetatively in our
soil and this is going to change
depending on what soil we're at and
kind of how you want to grow your plants
and at what rate
i like to let my veg plants get above 10
kpa and then
not any higher than 15 kpa and that
sweet spot right around 12 is where i
want my
vegetative moms watered every single
time because it gives them enough dry
back that oxygen is you know getting
into those pores it's getting around
those roots it's helping that plant to
breathe
and then you water again and you're
replacing that oxygen with more water
but if you wait too long you're
stressing that plant because it's it's
starting to think that it's not going to
have enough water to
continue growing at the rate it's
growing and start starts to limit its
own growth
versus if you water it too early not
enough oxygen is replacing the water in
the pores and you're
not getting enough aeration in your root
zone
so trying to time it at this perfect
interval has been really important for
me in how we drive plant health
and so for vegetative we try to hit you
know between 10 and 15 kpa and that's
been really big for us and then for
flower
we kind of do the opposite the method
you know the the principle behind that
is that when you flip the flower you
want that plant to
have just a little bit of stress just a
just a tiny bit of stress so that plant
knows that
now i'm not supposed to be growing at
max potential i'm supposed to be putting
energy in the bug production so we do a
little bit of stress right when we flip
the flower by letting that drive back or
that tension increase a little bit
higher maybe to 20 25 before we water
and then after that stretch period of an
you know early flower and they're done
stretching and the bud sites are already
there it's not going to be flipping back
to vegetative at all
we want that plant to start bulking so
around week two and week three
we start going back to kind of that
vegetative irrigation where we're
letting that tension stay pretty low in
that 10 to 15 range and so
we're letting that plant get just enough
dry back that the roots get oxygen that
um you know it's happy with that dry
back and then we're hitting it with
water again
and we're doing that every single day
and the and the trick is to
give it just enough water to get you
through to that point so that the next
time you need to water the following day
you're at the proper amount of tension
and this will change based on
climate factors how big your pots the
soil types how vigorous your plants are
growing everything kind of goes into
this but
we found it really impactful to kind of
hit these specific times when we're
watering do multiple irrigations a day
hit very specific tension measurements
from those tensiometers
and
hit it accurately and consistently you
know if you have inconsistent watering
you're going to have inconsistent flower
as just a
very loose correlation there
so tensiometers have been really
impactful for us
in how we shape the plants if you want
to
limit stretch and limit growth you can
increase tension between waterings to
limit how much they're able to stretch
if they don't have that water available
to the plant they're not going to be
able to put
a ton of energy into growth or they're
going to be focused on reserving that
energy but if you
give them low stress low tension and you
give them just you know adequate amounts
of oxygen replacement in between those
waterings and that plant has
no reason to stop growing you're going
to see
incredible growth
from your plants in both veg and even
early flower or bulking if you really
want it to so
there's other factors like lighting that
come into it when you want to
design you know the height of your plant
and and how you really control that
from a light intensity perspective and
your internal density um in the overall
stretch of the plants but
yeah tension has been
really important for us in
soilless mixes and when you start
looking at hydro it's something that you
just nobody uses tensiometers really in
in rockwool or even cocoa that much
because the matrix potential just it's
not there it just doesn't exist it's not
something you really have to worry about
too much
that's that's really fascinating and for
listeners to save you the time from
looking things up um if you're familiar
with millibar ratings the kilo pascal is
just a
a tenth of that so a
a 10 kpa kpa would be
100 millibar
which is which is interesting and at
some point you know you and i haven't
talked about this
previously um so this is a little bit
new to me too but uh
you know some of the people that we work
with like justin for example runs
much lower numbers so much wetter soils
he'll run in that 60 to 80 range or six
to eight kpa
whereas you're letting things get a lot
drier
and in general running things a lot
drier so um
i think that's really interesting and i
think uh one component of that we have
to look at too is also um your
environmental controls how you're
running temperature and humidity in the
room and what your vpd is as a as a
relationship to all of these other
numbers in terms of how fast yeah just
transpiring so it's it gets complicated
it's definitely oh oh it's very
complicated i was just i was this
morning i was down at the willamette
research center talking with uh
um dr nackley down there and one of the
conversations we love having when we're
talking about hemp is just like you know
in a research trial you try to control
everything you can like
like we just want one variable that we
can focus on but there's never just one
variable and when it comes to designing
a program it's just there's so much
going on it's it's impossible to try to
control everything so you just kind of
try to control as much as you can but
you're absolutely right i mean the
numbers i
throw out are not going to be
directly
able to be taken and applied to another
system
because
one of the trials i've done over the
past two months is
you know for a soilless high organic
media you can't exactly send it off to a
lab and get your water depletion curve
calculated you know it's not just
sand silt and clay making up your soil
there's so much organic matter
and so in order to have that depletion
curve one of the things i did was just
to physically map it with data so i took
a tensionometer that's digital
that's just take take measurements every
10 minutes and then i took two
volumetric water content probes
and i put them at very specific levels
within the
pot
three inches from the bottom and then
five inches from the bottom and then
that two inch ceramic tip on the
tensiometer
at that same range the bottom of it is
at that three inch in the top of it is
at that five inch and i charted our own
water depletion curves on the soil and i
did this with you know kiss oil straight
out of the bag i did this with
kiss soil that's been used for two
months after a plant we had you know had
called and it's just completely
compacted and it's so root bound and
there's just like no pores left and it's
really interesting to
to be able to you know read something in
a textbook about how poor size changes
you know your water holding capacity and
field capacity and your tension and
things like this and then go physically
measure it with sensors and to have that
data correlate
exactly to what you're reading about so
absolutely you know for for justin um i
i don't know him personally i haven't
been up there yet but i know that they
reuse their kiss they amend it they're
doing all these things and so over time
that media is going to change your
porosity is going to change your pore
size is going to change so i would yeah
absolutely i would expect them to be
running different numbers because
even
in our system just the difference of two
months in a pot
changes
kind of those target set points so to
speak of tension that we're trying to
hit
the available
water your volumetric water content at a
specific tension is way higher in the
kiss when it's fresh because of the
large aggregates the porosity is really
fluffy than it is when it's
more utilized you know when we start
getting into that stuff that's more root
bound lower pore space more root density
it becomes really hard to accurately
water your plants
and i have this great uh presentation i
gave to you my watering team about this
to kind of
drill it into their heads is you know
when you have
this fresh soil and a low root density
plant the water the soil can hold so
much water but it can also hold oxygen
so your window for irrigation you know
maybe
12 hours right if you accidentally miss
and you wait eight hours you water that
plant it's probably not feeling a ton of
stress there's like i measured about a
30 percent volumetric water content
difference before there's a
3 kpa difference in that soil when the
kiss is fresh so it can go from 45 vwc
down to 25 bwc and it'll only move from
about 6 kpa to 9 kpa
so there you have a ton of water there
like it's a really slow curve and then
when you start looking at things that
are highly compact your low pore space
you know really high root density
that soil is starting to break down and
there's just not a ton of water holding
capacity after it's been used for months
you may drop five percent you know from
30 down to 25 volumetric water content
and you could have a 10 to 15 kpa
difference so it's really
it's really about just trying to
see how much stress your plants are
having to utilize to get the water they
need and then what their water reserves
are and how long they have before it
runs out and in that you know the
biggest factor i tried to drill into the
heads of the watering team is that
when you have an old compacted plant
like a mom that's been around for two or
three months you know you may start to
water it and you're starting to see
these over watering symptoms and it's
not necessarily because you're just
you're giving it too much water it's
because the water holding capacity is so
low that the only
time it has enough water
to actually keep the tension high enough
so that the plant can take it in is at
the same level when all the oxygen is
displaced from the media
so there's this
change that happens to a point where you
can no longer give enough water to the
plant without completely displacing
oxygen from the soil and it becomes
really difficult to water plants after a
specific point so container size is not
only important for available nutrients
but how
dense your roots are going to get and i
say we're
right on that threshold with our
flowering plants you know after eight
weeks of being in that 10 gallon pot
they're pretty
i wouldn't quite say root bound but root
dense
and we can't really go back that past
that you know eight to nine week
maturation cycle without running into
some issues but thankfully we you know
we female hunt and we select cultivars
and we kind of build our program to be
designed around a
you know an eight week
to eight and a half to maybe nine week
maturation cycle
yeah you brought up a lot of good good
points there um and i think for folks
that want to start playing around
with this
in their facilities i think this is
definitely something that people should
be looking at and kind of figuring out
based on the media that they're using um
what
what works
in their rooms because
you know watering cannot be
um understated it's it's something that
i see over and over again as
the biggest variable in terms of plant
health
and
a lot of times the deficiencies that i
see people are dealing with is a lot of
it relates back to improper watering so
dialing in your watering is just
critical and one of the things that you
brought up that is a similarity across
both of your facilities and we'll get
you up to justin's here sooner or later
uh to check it out but
uh you know consistent watering
i mean they're using blue mats so
they're getting water all the time but
this idea of increased water frequency
uh like what you what you mentioned is
something that's very consistent across
both facilities um
and then staying within a given range
you know whatever that defined range of
watering is so that you're not getting
those
big wet and dry cycles that uh
well we used to that you would you might
be more likely to see in hydroponics um
oh absolutely i mean yeah like you said
irrigation just it can't be understated
it's
actually this a couple days ago um
because i didn't mention this in the bio
but i do go to oregon state for uh
agronomy and
we were talking in one of my classes
with faculty and the question came up
you know like what is the the most
important climatic factor in crop
production and it's a really difficult
question right because there's just so
much that goes into it you know you have
your your temperature and your light and
you know ph of your soil and available
nutrients and all these other things and
i guess you know i settled on i was like
well it's water you know it's it's to me
water is always going to be the most
important factor when it comes to crop
production
and cannabis tests those limits right
because there's just so much else that
goes into it but water to me is always
kind of the foundation you start with
your media you start with your nutrients
you start with your water and then
everything else kind of comes comes
behind that you you work on your climate
your temperature your rh and then at the
very end you kind of focus on light
intensity is like the last lever to pull
and that's something that uh jeremy has
helped to instill into me is every time
i want to go pull a lever for light
intensity we we have to circle around
and make sure that you know everything
else is going good and
we don't run you know we we have leds
that we put in this year we're almost
entirely led in our facility that's one
of the really big efforts we undertook
this past year but
we don't run them you know as high as
the hydro guys or other facilities we
keep them
relatively lower than i would say most
facilities and i think part of that is
just because we
we don't see a need for luxury
consumption of light
in our plants so
yeah there's just so many factors but
irrigation just it can't be understated
and and super important and
yeah i want to make sure i covered all
those technology topics you wanted to to
circle around upon i i think
tensiometers is probably the most
important thing for us
some people
were wondering i know i've talked to in
the past you know why we don't use
ec sensors or media sensors
and part of it is we just we don't
we i've i've calculated what goes into
the media well enough that i don't
really worry about
how it's sitting in there and staying
over time so that is a little bit
backwards to how some people work with
cannabis like in cocoa or or hydro when
you're actually getting lychee but in
our new program we don't have any runoff
i mean what we put in water and mineral
life it stays there we don't have
anything that comes out the bottom of
the pot which has been a really awesome
thing to happen when we think about you
know wastewater and waste streams and
you know pollution that happens from
really big cannabis facilities using
liquid injection fertilizers and whether
it's organic or not i mean we
we really try to give them just enough
so that they're hitting the point of
what they need without crazy luxury
consumption of these nutrients and in
the perfect amount of water so that it
evenly saturates and has the right
amount of dry back
it's a really tough balance it's really
tough balance
yeah what uh real quickly what ppfd
levels that canopy are you guys
currently using
um so we hit
so we're between 900 and a thousand um
typically i mean we're not there's a lot
of people with the new leds that want to
push
higher i mean i've seen stuff as high as
oh wow and a lot of people average in
that 12 to 1400 range is is pretty
common um
but we run our
lights pretty low i mean we
we get up to that range of that 900 to
1000 pretty quickly
and then it it kind of stays there on
average we're not running any higher
um new moles in our leds than we are
with
you know the couple of rooms that we
still have on hps they're
they're relatively the same i think what
we get
is dimming control better
significantly better efficiency
um and just better spectrum in my
opinion
yeah that's great so um
do you think you you will start to turn
the dial on lighting and up lighting
intensity or do you feel like
like like you mentioned not offering
luxury levels do you feel like that's
the level
sort of where
you guys are comfortable in your
facility in terms of your yields and
output and pushing the plant any harder
won't necessarily
offer enough benefit to offset the
amount of wattage or electrical
consumption that you'd be getting
yeah i mean i think
i think if there's potential for
increased yield um
there's always that one drive to want to
push for it and something that's been
ingrained through
um my education with agronomy is that
just because it's higher yield doesn't
mean it's always worth but worth it um
you know sometimes your inputs just
creep up higher than
that extra little bit of yield will get
you and so i think there's there's
definitely room to go higher but i think
there's room to go higher at specific
intervals so
higher light intensity at specific times
to control morphology to control stretch
to increase no density
but i would say on average i don't
really see us going above
1100 or 1150 you know even when we're
doing peak um
yeah like peak absolute best cultivation
and part of that is just facility design
right so one of the reasons people run
higher light intensities is because
they're not doing
trays like us so we have like an even
canopy through the whole room we don't
get
side lighting on the plants we don't you
know we have one really even canopy
across the entire room versus a lot of
people running hydro or rockwool or
thing you know greenhouse they're doing
like benches like uh rows table rows
where they only have one plant on each
row
going you know maybe 100 plants long and
so
their light intensity has to be good
enough not only to hit the top of the
plants but also
down the sides of the plants and try to
get those lower buds at all as well
versus
our cultivation model we pretty much
strip
everything back i mean we we go very
heavy on our prune and then we just get
a really big even canopy all the way
across the top which is one of those
ways that we also control consistency
at proof is just to
try to avoid the vertical growth as much
as possible from you know top to bottom
and just having an even canopy that's
kind of on one level all the way
throughout the room
can i ask a little bit about like what
your pruning schedule is
or philosophies
yeah for sure um
i'll try to
give as much info as i can without
divulging too much but so we we do two
prunes and we do them pretty early on in
flower we like to do one
pretty much at the flip and then a
couple weeks into flip and the first one
is kind of just to get rid of some of
those lower growth top the plants kind
of shape them a little bit we don't we
don't do too much and then the second
one we cut out
and this is really specific for facility
design right because i would not
recommend our printing style to someone
that's
growing in a tunnel or greenhouse or
doing hydro that you know has side
lighting and stuff because they're
they're going to want to leave all these
lower branches on but we strip
a ton back kind of in the second
to third week of flower
and
leave
pretty much only the top 20 to 25
percent of the buds on there
if not less and just really create an
even canopy and we want just great
airflow through that bottom of the
canopy
and kind of being pulled up through the
through the canopy as best as possible
but um
yeah yeah i think that's probably as
much as i can really no that was good
without giving an actual class on it of
course and describing pruning is a tough
thing to do on a podcast so i understand
uh yeah well let's let's change topics
here i want to get over because um
when i came to the facility one of the
things that you guys were doing was this
uh
tank mixing
an application of various sulfates so
essentially i mean you guys are doing
more testing than any other facility i
know um i know when i first saw all your
tests i was like yeah do we need this
many tests like you know
and and you know we kind of went back
and forth on that and
um
i i think it'd be you know you're so
collecting data for the sake of
collecting data is pointless but
collecting data that you can use to
allow you to make good decisions is is
priceless and that's something that i
think
jeremy's told me about you is like
you're very good at taking that data and
then using it and um
creating a program around it and and
that's where i think would be
interesting for listeners is sort of
one like what you know you touched on
briefly some of the tests that you're
taking but then how are you taking all
these tests and then creating a program
that allows you to
target these different you know trace
trace elements because one thing
you know just as background like for me
and this is something that bryant and i
have philosophically like it's a minor
difference honestly um brian's great
i tend to focus more just on the macros
um as long as i feel like the micro
the the the micro or trace minerals are
there then i feel like we're we're
probably good unless they're like crazy
so my ranges are a lot bigger
um
and i tend to not fiddle with it but you
guys you and you know and from working
with brian you guys are really targeting
those um
yeah just talk to me about it
yeah so i think uh first just kind of
giving a little context around this is
gonna be super important because i don't
wanna i don't want to give advice for
people and then they take it and run
with it so to speak so
i completely agree for your situation
when you're building soil that is like a
baseline for so many different types
grows and people and situations yeah you
just want to focus on kind of like these
wide ranges getting enough of those
macros and then micros are pretty easy
to supplement on like the facility
um scale you know
so
in my situation absolutely agree i
probably do more testing than anyone
else or any other facility i've come
across i mean i've i've put a lot of
faith and time money and effort into
testing
and it kind of just evolved
naturally when we're when we were
building this program
i
there was a lot of feedback internally
and externally from people that kind of
like the old method of growing i'm going
to say old method of growing for
cannabis where you just kind of
observe the plan to keep an eye out for
quote-unquote deficiency symptoms
showing up in the leaves and then you
kind of just like self-diagnose and then
you
add more or less and that's never been
my preferred approach i am very much a
numbers guy and
i want to quantify everything and i want
it to fit within this certain bracket
and so when we were building um
the program from scratch we always knew
that we were going to start out with
just a ton of testing
and then slowly
back off of that over time and now
here we are you know
six to nine months nine months is
probably when from when we ran like the
first crop and we had no idea how it was
going to turn out versus
six months from when we probably ran the
first crop with a
actual new fertilizer program that we
were like running for the first time to
see how it went so so a little ways out
from there
now i only test
a couple times a month and
i still probably test every room and
maybe two cultivars from every room so
you know i still probably send out 30 to
45 tests a month that include both
tissue and soil versus before i was
sending out
30 a week so
there's a large difference there and
that will continue to dwindle over time
to the point where we may only send out
at key intervals in the maturation
period but you're absolutely right data
for the sake of data is
really fun but not very practical
especially in a production environment
so
when i first started taking the data
i
did not have the knowledge i knew now
and i was relying heavily on brian in
the lab and another consultant at the
time and just like
like how do i even take this and
interpret it and i think that's a
situation that a lot of cultivators and
farmers really end up in and my
education around agronomy and just
working with this day in and day out has
really helped you kind of evolve my
understanding of it but
when i started taking these tests you
know i got the first test and i'm like
okay great you know like i have
some very rough sufficiency ranges that
were you know published from various
universities around the world on hemp at
you know the week before flower
that i'm gonna try to correlate to this
but how do you take that and correlate
it to veg and the you know the
pre-flower and then early flower
midflower late flower you know how do i
kind of track this over time and
those trends i i just kind of had to
learn and graph over time but um when i
first get the first data set you know
i'm like well this is great i see this
point in time that this is where my
plants are at and now i can take this
and i can
make changes up or down and in the
beginning of a nutrient program you can
kind of make pretty big changes you know
if you're just like bottomed out on
nitrogen right you can up your nitrogen
or you know if your calcium is at like
one percent it's pretty easy to make
that change and add more calcium but you
know as your program goes on
it's harder to make changes almost
because you're trying to move them
really
minut
ways you know really really small ways
and there's a lot of nutrient
interaction going on so
the first test comes in i get it and i'm
like great point in time then the second
test comes in you know i only have two
papers side by side but then i get the
third and the fourth and the fifth and
like i'm in a month into this you know
i've got like
a hundred data sample tests like all
spread out around me and i'm like i have
no idea how to take this information and
like
try to keep track of it and watch the
trends of everything so
i developed a
tracking model kind of just out of
necessity where i take all that data and
i put it into a table form in excel and
i do these really basic graphs you know
to kind of track stuff and i
i was i was tracking information like
strains and data samples and plant
health and you know where all those
values of the analytes are at and then
using graphs to kind of track that on a
day of maturation cycle and
even still that was um good but it got
convoluted when i started getting up
into having you know
six to ten thousand different data
points in a in a single data set you
know like for my soil i think i have
like
10 000 data points at this point for
tissue probably a little bit more than
that so
wow at after time you know i end up
having a hundred different tiny little
graphs that only attract individual
cultivarism
it it got to a point where
there's a couple different things you
need from your data you need to know
what an individual crop in an individual
cultivar in an individual room is doing
when you have multiple rooms right you
can't just take that one room and try to
apply it to everything but at the same
time you need to change a
feed program that affects everything and
so you need both the macro and the micro
picture of it all and so recently about
right before christmas vacation i filled
out this new dashboard which i don't
think i've had a chance to show you but
you'll you'll love it
it takes all of those data points and
all those data sets and has them in
singular tables and then queries them
into this dashboard and i can see and
observe
any specific analyte i want on a single
dashboard over a average week of
maturation for any specific cultivar any
specific crop any specific room and i
can visually just see how those analytes
move over time so
i can see where we start with calcium at
the start of flower and you know i know
that's a combination of what's already
in the kiss versus what i'm putting in
and i can see that trend line rise and
fall from week 0 to week 1 to week 2 to
week 3 and have a trend line that
actually maps that average across that
period and at the same time on that
graph i can
i have the sufficiency ranges that are
um you know there's there's not great
publication down on sufficiency range
for cannabis in my opinion there is some
out there that is the best that we have
but i don't think it's conclusive at all
yet um
but i took those and i ran with them
that kind of
moved them based on what i thought is is
best and what i've observed from a plant
health and recorded from a plant health
perspective and so i have this dashboard
that like you said it has to be
practical that data and i i study this
data daily and weekly now to the point
where
every single time i add a new data set
it's this self-learning
data model that just continues to evolve
over time i can see how we went from
having
a ton of our nutrients you know
deficient or toxic or out of whack
during week five initially with the
program to now
i would say
pretty much all except maybe one or two
elements are just exactly where we want
them to be i mean they are dialed in and
i even had a call last week with client
where we're just
i call them up and we're like well you
know at this point it's we're pretty
stable it's like maybe you adjust
something here maybe you adjust
something there and so it's been really
fascinating the past six months to just
dive into this nutrient program take all
this data you know convert it to
something useful go apply it back to the
plants and then see positive results but
a massive learning experience and
undertaking and
and i'd say you know my goal is that by
the end of january here that the
nutrient program is finished and
stabilized and
it is basically automated to the point
where
i can go and focus on other things now i
can start focusing on dialing and
pruning i can dial in our lighting i can
dial in our vpd and all these other
variables you know that you have on the
table but for the past year
nutrients have been the you know the the
biggest limiting factor when it comes to
yield and
thankfully we're pretty much over that
hurdle and we're back to hitting
record-breaking yields and we'll just
we'll keep moving along but
i i completely agree there's
there's no like
there's no great training manual on how
to build a
facility specific
data set and how to
take these you know everyone recommends
oh go to go get a soil sample oh get a
you know tissue sample but short of
having a full-time consultant how do you
take that as a grower as a cultivator
you know whether your home or a large
commercial operation
and collect that data and correlate that
to yield correlate that to plant health
and to influence your decisions and have
proof of why you're doing this
throughout those changes
and and guide your program along the way
it's it's not something that i think is
easily understood in the in the cannabis
space
oh i totally agree and one thing i want
to highlight that you mentioned is this
idea of waiting until you see a
deficiency in your plant well at that
point really it's too late you've
already stressed your plants so yep
and
i'll be the first to admit i need to
learn a lot more about tissue testing it
wasn't something that was traditionally
available to cannabis growers and so
it's something that i need to
educate myself on here
so that's great you're able to you're
able to work with
with that data and a lab to get that
testing um
out of curiosity
what sorts of trends did you find with
our soil for people who are listening
and and maybe use our soil in terms of
things to watch for
um
yeah being in containers that they like
it's very bad
yeah so it's it's really interesting i
mean so i don't we kind of touched on it
but the whole premise behind the
container thing is like
living soil will work in any container
but
obviously the bigger you go the less
additional fertilizer you have to put in
because there's a bigger reserve bigger
bank so if you if you do a 30 gallon or
40 gallon or whatever size you go up to
right you can do a water only program
for the most part and not really have to
put anything in but for a 10 gallon
container
it wasn't a question of if we would or
we wouldn't run out of nutrients it was
more question of when we would and what
ones we would be running out at first
and and you mentioned you know as a as a
soil builder your focus is kind of on
those macros and most of the micros are
kind of just there naturally from some
of the inputs that you utilize but
micros is important really important in
media that buffers high
ph i think one of the things that was
really beneficial is we brought
a close associate and not too long ago
because we were seeing like manganese
uptake like really high
and we were using just like a tiny bit
of manganese but not anything like that
we would you know bat an eye at and
i was really confused i'm like and like
i pulled all the manganese out of the
program and it's like okay i just won't
put it in anymore and we were still
getting this this issue and i was like
man i'm just like scratching my head and
turns out um that
it's it's one of those things where you
wouldn't be able to just like
look at a leaf and know what is going on
because the plan is showing manganese
toxicity right and manganese toxicity is
this very interesting
like camouflage purplish reddish brown
like very very unique coloration that's
going on
kind of this distorting whirling of the
leaves
and what's happening is that with the
soil kind of buffering around a 7.0 ph
6.8 to like a 7-1 it's pretty high but
a good range in my opinion but iron
oxidizes it at that point it
precipitates out um you know it
essentially becomes rust in your soil so
it's not readily available to the plant
so whenever that plant runs out of iron
availability it starts taking up that
manganese in replacement of it and we
were just getting a huge
flush of manganese into the plants it
was just like running into it
and so one of the ways i changed that is
we just we added iron to our weekly feed
program before i was adding micros at
the beginning of flower and then hoping
that they would just like there would be
a reserve of them to kind of last
throughout that whole cycle
but iron was just precipitating out
immediately and manganese was becoming
hyper available and just getting taken
into the plant so now i push iron
weekly two times a week and just low
concentrations like in the 10 to 15 ppm
range in solution
and it just it keeps it available to the
plant at all times and i don't see any
iron issues the manganese issue has gone
away but you know specifically with your
soil i think it's amazing it's really
great like you can take a plant put it
into it and it's immediately happy and
then there's some small optimization you
can do from there there's a great amount
of calcium so i you know if people are
trying to take your soil and then throw
calcium nitrate at it i probably
probably not the right path to go
but uh
calcium is is great in it it buffers
kind of on a higher ph so those things
that do have limited availability at
high ph range just take a peek at those
and kind of see how your plan is holding
up but
we really don't have to supplement a ton
you know those first three four weeks of
flour
we do input some stuff but it's mostly
uh
luxury feed and it's putting it into the
soil so that by the time
what's available and the kiss runs out
around week four
um the stuff we've been putting in for
the past few weeks is becoming available
and it's starting to be taken into the
plant so there's this kind of handoff
from
what is in the kiss to what we're
feeding that has to happen about halfway
through flower and it's such a pivotal
point in time but um
iron iron is super important the other
micros
i don't have to worry about too much i
honestly don't really put
much of anything in other than iron
magnesium is something that when you
have super high calcium in the soil
and we also add you know you know
sulfate of potash so we're adding in
potassium as well that that mag can kind
of become a little restricted and we've
seen really great results with just
pushing either magnesium foliars and veg
or just by adding
a little bit of mag into that that
feeding program and kind of boosting
that so
wow we haven't talked about this until
uh on air here so some of this is new to
me it's really interesting yeah until
now
yeah i gotta show you the dashboard and
some of the the data i've been
collecting it's really
really fascinating but overall i mean
like
for someone that wants a soil that they
can use a
large pot or a large container or even a
bed or something like that and just put
a plant into it and
it it does 95 of the work for them yeah
just kiss organics all the way i mean
it's amazing
our facility is in this really unique
position where
we're just restricted by container size
and we kind of have to pick up a little
of the work halfway through flowers so
but yeah
well i appreciate that it's been great
to work with you guys
the iron thing is really interesting the
magnesium thing is
not unexpected to me
because of the high calcium levels uh i
could see where magnesium could be you
know potentially optimized by adding a
little bit more
um you have to be careful with magnesium
because it will raise your
your ph if you're if a lot of the ways
that people are adding it because it is
a cation too so
um
yeah there's so many it's such an
interesting all the dynamics and the way
these minerals uh work together with
biology and the physical properties of
the soil to optimize plant health
yeah and i hope people will start
looking at this and utilizing testing
one of the things that you brought up
that i think is
important is you know people get stuck
because they're like okay well i can go
get a soil test but then what the heck
do i do with this thing like
do i have to pay someone else to look at
it and give me results and you know
there's a lot of people doing that with
varying
abilities and quality um
you and i are both you know friends with
and fans of bryant mason over at seoul
doctor consulting um he does have a
yep he does have a course um i'm gonna
get him back on the podcast but he does
have a course where he teaches you how
to evaluate a soil test that you can
sign up for and i think there's a
actually a coupon code
if you put in the kiss organics you can
save a i think 100 bucks or something
200 bucks off the test stuff the course
yeah and i
completely stand behind that but you
know both jeremy and i have
gone through that course and looked at
it and i've had a ton of conversations
with brian and you know for anyone that
is kind of in that position of like okay
you know i do get a soil test now what
definitely utilize his course and also
utilize his
you know consulting he's been immensely
helpful and just
kind of building a foundation for us and
then circling back around and just kind
of giving it's really difficult to like
build a program almost by myself and
then be like okay you know
i should probably get a second opinion
on this and and talk to someone else and
verify and every single time we talk
it's just like
really confirming for
the work we're doing and moving forward
and and so can't say enough about him
he's an awesome person and highly
recommend him to anyone listening
yeah so you can you can get a test
through logan labs send it off to bryant
he'll give you a result that is a great
option for people
um who don't have the time or energy to
you know want to learn all of it
themselves um
and i don't want this to turn into a
you know shameless plug for kiss but if
you are using our soil we will customize
a nutrient pack for you um for free if
you send us a logan test test of your
soil and if it's our soil we offer that
as a service but um we're not doing
outside testing uh just due to i don't
have the time to do it and and bryant's
already doing a better job than i could
at it so uh
i don't need to reinvent the wheel
but getting back to uh
this this testing stuff so i do want to
ask you you mentioned you're adding iron
you mentioned you're adding uh magnesium
um you mentioned doing a lot of these in
sulfate form can you talk a little about
how your you know what products or i
guess not products but like what
amendments are you using to
raise these particular nutrients
yeah that's been um
it's been really fascinating we've just
kind of taken like a
i don't know a
30-year step back because obviously when
you go to
any other farm production right i mean
there's
if you go to outdoor ag or you know any
kind of vegetable or produce or anything
people amend their
fertilizers with you know raw products
they amend their fields and stuff with
raw products versus cannabis has this
very interesting
um
hierarchy of nutrients where it's like
you know cannabis nutrients there's over
100 different brands of cannabis
nutrients and they all pretty much come
from the same place you know they're
they all use the same
raw ingredients the same base
ingredients and so
one of the things that
i i definitely adopted from
bryant and completely agree with is like
just stop
paying to ship water and to have someone
else you know build this nutrient for
you when you have so much more control
using those raw products yourself so
pretty much everything i use other than
two products is going to be attached to
a sulfate they're all omri certified
they're all
um
you know just just base ingredients so
pretty much everything other than
nitrogen and phosphorus is uh is coming
from a sulfate form so you know calcium
we're using gypsum calcium sulfate
magnesium you're using epsom salt
iron sulfate sulfate of potash manganese
sulfate
everything is basically sulfate attached
the only you know raw powder that we're
not would be like
sodium borate but
we i have no need to add boron pretty
much at any time we're always at a grid
level so
i also don't like putting sodium into
the soil so i just i never really use
that every the main ones i use we
honestly don't put it much i use um the
nitrogen we use is like the fertile
explorer the powdered based soy protein
um
powder it's good you could also use like
crow or secret it's pretty much the same
thing
and then
i use chipsum i use a little bit of mag
for like full ears i use sulfate of
potash and
yeah some some cfos for phosphorous and
that's pretty much it in iron iron
sulfate but other than that i mean i i
think i only use
four
of the products out of you know i have
every single one on hand in case for
some reason that something pops up on a
specific crop but the only thing we use
actively is gypsum
epsom salt
fifos
ferticell explorer
and iron sulfate and potassium sulfate
so it's
really basic and the way i have like you
said you mentioned that we use a batch
tank system now which has been
a big change for us because we used to
do inline injections so we have a batch
tank that
we
mix everything in and then for
simplicity we only mix one recipe a day
i have this schedule built out so that
you know mondays and thursdays we have
one recipe tuesdays and fridays we have
one recipe wednesdays and sundays we
have another recipe and then saturdays
is when we introduce like
biologicals like microorganisms and
stuff into the into the soil so
i i really only use three recipes one of
them is just kind of your your nitrogen
and iron another one is your
calcium and potassium and the other
one's mag and they just get that at
varying amounts whether they're in veg
uh pre-flower early mid or late flower
and i just kind of manipulate the
volumes going into the soil
and track where that data is
on the soil test and in the tissue and i
can kind of i don't even have to change
the concentrations of the feeds i just
change how much volume of the feed is
going into the pot
on an individual crop or a whole
facility-wide basis and it makes it
really easy to control
that's yeah that's really interesting um
i'm just trying to think if there's
anything else
we could share for
uh you know a facility
that's listening that wanted to try and
embark on this path of collecting more
data and then using it to make some of
these actionable decisions is is there
any advice you would have because it is
pretty daunting to think about i mean
you're kind of through the worst of it
but
um yeah where do you start
i think
yeah that's that's a great question
because i
you know
for
everything i've learned over this past
year i don't have
20 years experience working with these
nutrients so it's um it's been a lot
really fast and for anyone listening i
would say
start like first off just don't guess
right i mean if you see a deficiency on
a leaf you don't don't just guess and
apply something testing has a really
important place in agricultural and
production and just
utilize the experts around you whether
that be bryant whether that be your
local university obviously here in
portland i go to oregon state oregon
state
has no affiliation with cannabis but
they are able to work with hemp and
there's a lot of universities around the
country that are able to work with hemp
and so
most of that data
you know correlates to each other so if
you're having questions about
nutrients just utilize the resources
around you like you said you can do
testing through logan lamps but they
also offer you know recommendations
based on their own test brian
has really great advice and he has his
own course built around nutrients
not entirely for cannabis but you can
use everything in it for cannabis
and so it's there's just a massive
amount of resources there but they're
they're often hidden i mean
the nutrient industry in cannabis is
so overpowering
none of the nutrient companies are going
to tell you like oh yeah you know you
just go just go pay you know 10 percent
of the cost of our nutrients by buying
the raw product and being able to
control calcium individually rather than
having to put in you know five nutrients
at a time like it's that's not
mainstream in the cannabis industry
these days so trying to read between the
lines utilize local universities utilize
university research utilize crop
consultants
utilize labs utilize people like you
that are building an awesome product and
kiss soil so it gives you a strong
foundation
and then
know how to organize your data
like you said data for data sake is
never really
good in a production model so take that
data and have a way to track it and
trace it and to correlate it to other
things i'm talking with you know suzanne
wayne wright evans the
amazing entomology just you can
correlate these
mineral concentrations to pest pressure
you can correlate it to
you know yield obviously you can
correlate it to plant health you can
correlate it to how much you water you
can correlate it to all these different
factors but you have to have that data
organized digitally in a table in a
spreadsheet you have to be able to to
use it and to manipulate at your will so
don't just save it on paper and put it
in a folder and put it in a box and
stash it away and try to remember it all
it's really great to take the 20 minutes
to just
transfer it to a digital file
catalog it organize it and to use it to
track your program overall
yeah and i i guess i've
got it got me thinking um
but one of the things i was going to say
is
uh be sure to take some pictures of your
plant too so you can have a visual
representation of
what this test
actually uh
actually correlates with visually so you
can go back and look at your crop and
then um
if you are doing working with an
agronomist
make sure they're familiar that with
soilless media because a lot of people
are growing in essentially peat based or
cocoa based soils which is
very very very different than actual
sand silt and clay soil so
yeah a lot of agronomists aren't
comfortable and a lot of the tests don't
correlate well like uh bryant did a
great instagram post the other day
talking about how we can't we can't look
at cation exchange capacity the same um
that number isn't really relevant on a
malik 3 test for example so
that's just something to be aware of and
then
the other thing i was going to say on
this is uh when it comes to tissue
testing you mentioned that there were
some sufficiency ranges that were
already published is that something that
i'd be able to share on the podcast page
when we put out the podcast
yeah so um there's some great ones out
of north carolina north carolina state
north carolina university i believe
and yeah i can i can share those and
they're
good foundations but i won't say to
entirely rely on them bryant also has
some really great
ranges
from from his experience that i believe
are in his program that are that are
awesome to utilize so
all the university ones out there just
remember that
they can't touch cannabis right now so
it's with hemp and most of them are
doing
testing that is either not tracked in
the maturation cycle meaning that it
could be done in veg it could be done in
flower it could be done pre-flower it
could be done at any of these times
they're also testing a wide variety of
hemp genetics and
one of the things i remember reading in
one of those publications is that you
know the max deficiency range for one
cultivar was below the minimum
sufficiency range of another one for
i think it was either nitrogen or
calcium so there's there's a really wide
range that's genetic specific
um so i'll yeah i'll try to get those
over to you and um
see if i can kind of give you some of
those base values to go off of but yeah
it's definitely something you have to
kind of figure out for your own facility
and take up or down don't don't just you
know double your calcium because some
university growing hemp says that it's
the proper amount to grow calcium at the
end of the day you know your plant's
best you know when they look healthy
you know when they're yielding the best
so if things are yielding well and the
data is just slightly off you don't have
to change something if you're getting
good results
yeah so all the more reason to collect
data for your own facility and your own
genetics and then also when you do have
a good you know
bumper crop you know your best yields
make sure to take a test so you know
what your targets are for that cultivar
and what you did in that room so that
you have you know essentially you've
essentially created your targets in in
in a certain respect so
that's a good way to look approach it
from the other range it's not always
about a deficiency sometimes it can be
about a optimal target
so
completely agree that's one of the
biggest things i hear from crop
consultants all across the country it's
like you know like people come running
in terror whenever something is wrong
with their facility and we they talk to
us once or twice we give them a couple
of suggestions and you know their plans
start to look healthy again and like
okay yeah i got this now and they just
like they disappear again and then they
come back four months later panicking
when things start going wrong it's uh
it's really important to
take note when you're doing things right
if not more important than when things
are going wrong because obviously you're
never trying to mimic when something is
going wrong you want to always you know
have that target set point for when
things are going right so great advice
there
yeah and just one thing to end on for
people is at the end of the day it's not
the goal of all of this is not
the perfect test or the perfect tissue
test it's it's really about
yields it's about healthy plants so
don't don't drive yourself crazy if your
plants look good and your test is a
little bit off
sometimes it's better not to tinker
so i just want to leave that as a
thought for people in the back of their
heads too because
yeah i mean there's sampling errors
there's
there's a variety of reasons that test
result might not line up but at the end
of the day your plants
your plant health is what we want to
look at so
um yeah
well this you know i like jeremy i could
talk to you for hours here so um
right we should probably wrap it up but
was there anything anything uh partying
you wanted to add regarding uh
anything we talked about today
i think we pretty much covered a good a
good start yeah i completely agree we
could end up talking forever and ever
but there's probably enough information
there for people to digest and
really appreciate you having me on and
having a chance to talk and kind of
share some of this information and can't
wait to kind of show you some of the new
data and dashboards and info we got
going on down here it's been a little
bit so we got to catch up
that'd be great and i i look forward to
seeing where you guys are you know say
even a year from now because i know
you're always
you guys are always moving forward and
uh improving things so uh
yeah we'll talk soon thanks again sam
absolutely
all righty thanks dad
[Music]
that was sam hoeffler and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey i'll post pertinent links on the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast thanks for listening
you