[Music]
Welcome to the Cannabis Cultivation and
Science podcast. I'm your host, Tad
Hussy of Kiss Organics. This is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and draw top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge. Before starting
the podcast, just a friendly reminder to
check out the podcast page at
www.kisorganics.com. Just click on the
learn tab, then podcast. And if you want
access to podcasts as soon as they are
recorded, along with additional content
and video, we do have a Patreon account.
We also do book clubs, hangouts, and
have a private Discord channel for
members. The Kiss Organics website also
offers consulting, a variety of soil
amendments, lighting fixtures,
beneficial insects, and the highest
quality commercial soils on the market.
We carefully research all of our
products that we offer and manufacture
to make sure that they are science-based
and meet our standard of quality. My
guest this week is Saul Alba. Saul began
his agricultural work in vineyard and
winery operations on the central
California coast. After deciding to
focus career on crop protection, he
moved north where he managed IPM
programs at Monterey Mushroom Company
and Jacob's Farm. This work led to a
position as IPM manager at Harborside
Farms where he directed their
biointensive greenhouse cannabis IPM
program. Saul now works as a technical
sales representative for Biobea.
coming on the show today. Hey, Todd.
You're welcome.
Yeah, I'm I'm excited to have this
conversation with you. Um, you know, I
met you years ago now when you were uh
working at another insectory. Now you're
with BioBe, which I'm really excited
about because I get to work directly
with you and also with Kelly Vance as uh
our sort of our technical support guys.
Can you talk a little bit about what
your your current role is with BioBe?
Yeah. Um the title is uh let's see
technical sales representative. So I
work obviously getting reaching out to
get more customers but my job is really
consultative sales which is uh working
with the customers to help them design
IPM programs and um you know ultimately
the goal is um move their IPM to fewer
sprays or more compatible sprays, more
more compatible practices so that our
products can be integrated and um they
have success with them.
A and along with that too I would add uh
proper application rates of beneficial
insects and proper timing of application
rates with beneficial insects as as you
know then just to share with the
audience uh if we apply beneficial
insects earlier in the growth cycle um
you're going to have more success with
them and you can apply lower rates in as
a general rule. So um I know from
Suzanne we've had she's given me
instances where people have been
massively overapplying beneficial
insects which hurts your budget makes it
hard to stay in business. Uh and then on
the other hand um applying the wrong
insect or applying um levels inefficient
to actually control the target pest. So
yeah you have a really interesting
position. I'd like to add um that we at
BioBe with my team um I like to say
we're kind of we're a solutions first
approach. Okay, the sales important but
it'll it'll come. So, you know, you you
you
uh show success of your products with a
customer, they will buy in. Then they'll
also say hey you know they'll tell their
you know their friends that you know hey
try talk to this guy or go through biobe
right um and what do I mean by success
um with bio control that that's super
important to me that to define um
success not only means you know um our
products
helping increase your yields by keeping
pests under control keeping them at
under an economic threshold. It also
means keeping it within your budget.
Okay, that that to me is um is basically
goes handinhand with you know crop
protection within your budget. Okay, so
um I think sometimes other companies
uh they devise programs that are you
know shotgun type um programs. You know
throw all of this into your crop and you
won't see pests. Yeah, guess what?
That's probably true. If you throw every
biocrol or excessive biocrol
um or multiple
uh biocrol agents that are going after
the same pest when you may not
necessarily need that many. Um I think
that's a way to win, but you don't win
on the budget side, right? So that's
super important that we figure out how
to balance that.
Yeah. And one thing I want to touch on
is, you know, when I think of certain
target pests like two spotted
spidermite, my braid immediately goes to
pimileis or fungusnats, I think of, you
know, SF nematodes. But it's not as
simple as just
um combining, I guess, a beneficial and
a pest. Every, you know, one thing
Suzanne's really taught me is that every
facility, every grow space, every
greenhouse is different. Can you talk a
little bit about what those differences
are and how that goes into determining
what the best option is? Yeah, so you
know it it's the reason you're you and I
set this up is because you know that my
primary crop that I work with and the
crop I know the most about crop
protection is cannabis. Um and so I work
with um a greenhouse primarily um but
lots of indoor smaller indoor operations
and and um uh also outdoor you know um
fields. Um so that's what's cool about
that is you you get to understand like
what the pest complex is really like. Um
what I mean by that it's like what
really becomes an issue for different
growers in those different settings. And
so, for example, outdoors, grasshoppers
might be considered in certain regions
the most important pest to control,
whereas in a in a um indoor setting,
you'll never see grasshoppers. Um,
but rude aphid can pop big in a
hydroponic indoor facility, whereas root
aid is not an issue outdoors. So, it
really does kind of depend on lots of
things. Um, climate being one. um you
know um and uh and and yeah, that's
that's going to be that's going to vary
um based on you know your your
particular operation. Some some really
really low tech green houses don't have
the option to um to like heat and use
use a dehumidifier. So their betritis
is, you know, harder to manage than, you
know, like a Dutch style greenhouse
where that's all designed into the
plant. So yeah, environment I think has
the the most to do with it. But that's
not all. Um practices, growing practices
also have a lot to do with it. So, um,
grow where
you tightly pack the the plants in the
grow space, um, are going to usually be
more difficult to to manage pests
because a it's harder to find the pests
in a thicket and b sprays don't
penetrate well into, you know, if you
need to use sprays. So both of those
things, you know, it's a lot harder to
if you if you have plants tightly
tightly packed, it's a lot tougher than
if you do proper spacing and for example
do a lot of leaf removal where it's
necessary, you know. So it's it's just
everything. It everything can affect it.
Um living soil, you have a lot of living
soil customers. That's a particularly
challenging setting. Okay. For from what
I've seen. Um, so everyone has their
their different challenges and like I
think what I'm grateful for is that I
have a chance to work with, you know,
the kind of the gamut.
Yeah. So when you see when you walk into
a new grow facility or grow space, uh,
what are you sort of looking for? What's
your mental checklist in terms of uh,
IPM specifically?
Yeah. So, usually we start in
propagation. That makes sense. You know,
go from the least likely to be infested.
Um, and then as through each stage, you
know, basically take notes on what their
primary pest is. Um, and what and then
find out what they're doing, what
they've have been doing, and if they
think why they think it might be failing
or why they think it could be better or
why they think it's doing a great job.
Um and then
um you know obviously um listening like
at least in the first visit lot a lot of
listening and note takingaking
um that's that's important to me. Then
then you know then I I look for things
where number one to me is um the signs
and symptoms of pest presence. Okay. And
so for example um if it's an indoor
operation under lights with uh you know
like those the
the I don't know what they're called the
trays um where you have a drain one side
you have a a decline declin whatever
it's called the slope and then you have
the drain on the other side that's a
great place to go look for for root
aphits. Um you don't have to look in in
in substrate. a lot of them crawl out
and as you irrigate the water pushes
them down to the drain. Um so that's
that's kind of one really quick, you
know, you know, that's a good pointer.
Yeah. Inspection. And then um you know,
leaf damage. You can if you look around,
you'll find either thris or spidermite
damage. That's super important. Um you
know, basically quick scouting when I
come into a room if they'll let me. I
try not to like go deep into the crop
until I know that they're not infested.
um just not just so I don't carry out
any any pests or move them around the
grow. Um so yeah, that's that's more or
less what I do. And then I then what's
super important to me is a follow-up.
Like my goal is to get a follow-up email
to the whoever it is that's, you know,
responsible for the IPM um within a week
because things have to stay fresh in
their mind. What we discuss, I have to
and then reiterate them, right? So
that's kind of my my approach.
Yeah. And when you write a
recommendation to a grower, it's not
necessarily all beneficials either. I
want to clarify that for folks because
I've seen, you know, your
recommendations for growers that we work
with that you've sent um after maybe
visiting the facility or talking through
their some of their challenges with with
pest control. Um can you give me a
sample of what something might kind of
look like for someone who was listening
to the podcast and is unfamiliar with
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. So, one big one
one big question I have is what kind of
monitoring are you doing and are you
doing it properly? Because what I'm
interested in knowing is if your
population of pest is to a point where I
would you would be throwing money
away to start with bio control. So, for
example, a common practice in veg is
spraying. Um, and it's probably 75% of
the people I deal with prefer to spray
for for pests in veg. Um, and that's all
well and good. There's very few of them
that are implementing bio control. It's
it's something you really have to learn
to do for the entire cycle. Um, but you
can start integrating it slowly into veg
so that you can reduce your your sprays
because sprays may not be ideal all the
time. So, I may need to know, okay,
what's your thrifts population like? And
they might say, well, I don't know. It's
a lot. I'm like, okay, what are your
yellow cards telling you? Um, I'm not
doing yellow cards. Okay, you need to
start yellow cards. What about your
fungus net? Are you doing yellow soil?
No, I'm not. Okay, you need to do that.
Start on that right now. Let's go with a
chemical approach until you get me some
data. We need to know when we need to
speak the same language. I have a much
better I I can communicate with you more
because I'm not going to be able to
visit your grow you know weekly or
whatever.
Um, if I have data from like from like
yellow cards or if I have for example
counts of spidermitites or counts of
spidermite eggs per leaf, you know, that
kind of thing, then then you know if
it's if it's something that I I believe
biocrol can't catch up with, then of
course the strategy is, hey, let's get
this down to where bio control will do
it so that you can reduce your sprays.
And that that might take a few sprays.
Um, and so I'm I'm fortunate that um, in
part of my career when I was first
getting into biological control,
um, I decided that I wanted to learn all
of the organic sprays that I had
available in California, all the
materials. Um, so I knew when to use
them, um, or what I could use and then
try them and see how well they worked
and basically got familiarity with a lot
of these materials and a lot of these
techniques. Um before jump diving in
head first into biorol I went into it
slowly so that by the time I got into
the cannabis greenhouse um I had I had a
good background on sprays but I also had
a background on starting with bios. So,
you know, um I was able to integrate.
Yeah. So, essentially if the So, first
off, you need to know what level of
prepest pressure you have and you need
to be able to quantify that. I think
that's essentially what you're saying
and that's really important. So,
scouting, you know, I I know we could do
a whole podcast on that. You had
mentioned um it's a pretty indepth thing
to consider in your in your facility and
your grow. Um but then if if the pest
pressure is above this threshold where
it's going to be able to be controlled
by beneficials, then we're talking about
bringing in um you said chemical
solutions, but what you're referring to
there, not necessarily uh synthetic, but
it could be like an organic solution.
We're talking soaps and oils, um, or
maybe botanical, some sort of spray
option to suffocate, neurologically
disrupt, um, kill essentially the the
target pest to get them down to a level
that then the beneficials could
potentially control them, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Number one, most of the states
that have legalized um, they won't allow
you to use certain materials, right?
It's almost all organic materials. I
can't I can hardly think I can't think
of anyone even organic sprays that are
like neurotoxins like spinads aren't
allowed in the majority of states. Um
and some states are so strict that they
don't allow you to use an EPA registered
organic material. So um you know it's
it's a challenge but I'm lucky because
I've focused my pest management to
organics and that's almost all I've ever
done. Uh the first job I worked in, we
did use some insecticides, some real
insecticides, but it was the goal there
was go towards organic and then after
that it's been all organic. So I know
the sprays well, I know the materials
well. Um I don't actually know, you
know, the the real poisons well and uh
I'm lucky not to have to ever use them.
So yeah, you can do it. And not only can
you use them, but you can actually
integrate them if you know what you're
doing. Takes some guidance, but that's
what I'm here for.
Yeah. And then on the flip side, an
example where you maybe not don't need
to do sprays because I hate spraying.
It's just the the labor to, you know,
fill a
sprayer, m tank, mix everything, go in
the room, spray. I just I hate doing it.
Um it's not something that I enjoy. So,
uh for me, I had I had a thris damage
thris that came into my room on my
clones. Um, as you know, they can I
believe pupate inside the leaf. Is that
correct?
So, I I didn't see um or lay eggs inside
the leaf. Sorry. I didn't see any damage
um on my plants until they had grown a
little bit, but the grower I got them
from noticed Thris's damage a couple
weeks after I got my plants from him.
So, he's like, "Okay, you need to start
treating for this." So, I did some dips
and sprays um to try and get them under
control. And then I did a a release of
beneficials after, you know, my after
after a couple rounds of sprays. And
then the next cycle, I had very little
thris damage that cycle. But the next
cycle in that room, I just
preventatively released uh some SF
nematodes into the soil because the room
had been empty for a couple months and I
didn't see any thris damage that next
cycle. Um, you know, I do like to treat
plants when I first bring them in. But I
guess my point is, um, if you have a
very low pest pressure or maybe your
last round you had a little bit of pest
pressure, that's where I think
beneficials really shine, I guess,
especially early in veg because you
don't have to buy a lot of them
necessarily. And, um, if you know,
spraying, like you mentioned, can't get
everywhere, whereas these beneficials
are eating and working 24/7. uh and
they'll work their way into all the
little nooks and crannies of your of
your canopy to really get your target
pest.
Yeah. I mean key there in um the way to
make bio control successful is to
realize that it is much much better as a
preventative tool than than it is as um
a curative. Um there are some biocontrol
agents that actually can essentially
cure a problem or bring it down so that
it's so low that um you know that it's
nowhere it's not going to hurt you. Um
like SF nematodes being one of them. Uh
you can take a a a a greenhouse that's
just loaded with fungus nads and if you
use the SF nematodes properly, it's
going to be a bit expensive at first.
you can get it down to where, you know,
they're not an issue anymore. But that
is an
exception. Okay. Most of most biocrol
works, you know, and should be used
preventatively. What does that mean?
That means at the first sign of pests is
when you is when you really start. Um,
if you have the budget to get just get
them in there before you've even seen
any pests, obviously that's even better.
But most growers are going to say,
"Well, I'm not going to do make an
action until I know they're there."
Right? And that's fine as long as you
know when they when they are at a very
low population. So what's that mean?
Again, you know, I I told you earlier my
mantra is scouting is the basis of of of
success for biological control. So
knowing what you have, what pest you
have, where is it, and how much of it is
there. Um that's like key to having bio
control succeed. And I don't think I
don't think um a lot of I've noticed I
have my experience is that compared to
other greenhouse crops like ornamental
and food crops and and and foliage
crops, the cannabis
grower might miss that concept, might
not might not have that ingrained. Um
and why?
likely because they they were growers
during the black market days, right,
before it was legal. So, you could just
take Avid and wipe out your spidermite
issue with one spray or keep it low. So,
they're kind of used to more like, okay,
curative, curative, I can cure this.
Biocrol won't do that. Organics
materials won't do that either. They're
very rarely curative. So, it's kind of
switching that mentality to I want to I
need to do this preventatively based on
scouting.
Yeah. I remember 20 years ago, and this
is probably a pretty common story where
I didn't really think about pests. I
mean, I wasn't being around I wasn't
around any other cannabis grows. It was
just my own grow in my garage at the
time. And uh so I figured I was pretty
safe, you know, if it was just me going
in the room. And then I didn't catch uh
I end up I ended up getting thris
somehow. They got into the space and I
didn't catch it right away because I
wasn't scouting as carefully as I I
should have at the time and I didn't
really know how to deal with it. Um and
so I I got I got a little too late to
the game and I hadn't even heard of
beneficials 20 years ago. So, that was
all um I had a lot of learning to do,
but um man, I'd forgotten about Avid and
Eagle 20 and some of these horrible
chemistries that people used back in the
day. Um I'm glad that we have better
solutions now, even if they're not
systemic, which is sort of the point of
it. It's not going to end up in your
final flower. Um
well, let's talk a little bit. I want to
change directions here and talk a little
bit about
um russet mites, hemp russet mites. I've
been hearing and seeing more issues with
russetss. Okay. Uh as of lately, I mean,
I know they've been a problem for a
while, but um what are some of your
options for russet mites
or recommendations, I guess? So, first
off, I I want to like make an
announcement on biological control of
russet mites. There are anecdotal
reports out there that certain predatory
mites that are commercially available
can help you. Okay. My actual experience
um and actually if you talk to Suzanne I
think she's in agreement that there is
no reliable con convent commercially
available predatory might. Some folks
have mentioned um the Anderson might um
but again it's all anecdotal. um it may
be there but if you look at it you'll
see failures with anderson but you'll
also won't be able to find any
scientific literature basically not much
at least showing that anderson can help
you with with arrestmite and there's
very little lit or if any on biological
control of hemp reset might okay now
this is going to sound like a commercial
but it's something I'm excited about um
began production of a predatory might.
It's in the same family as all the rest
of the predatory mites. That might is um
commonly known as the western predatory
might because it's in all of the western
states.
Um the scientific name is galandromis
oxididentalis. Among us we call them
oxies.
Um this
might is primarily going to be used in
certain crops in outdoor crops. there's
a demand for it. Um
but it is known to
be more of a generalist predatory might
if I can say that. Um so what I mean by
that is um pimileus would would be a
very specific predator that focuses on
two spotted spidermite. It won't even
feed on and control may feed but it
won't control certain species within the
same genus as the two-spotted spider
might. It it's a it's specifically
focused on that might. It it co-evolved
with that might is what I understand.
But then you have neelis calapernicus.
So I'm sort of people have heard of
which will also feed on for example
broadmite and might help you manage
broadmite and there's literature showing
that and the two spotted spidermite and
can also feed on you know pollen. So
it's more of a generalist if you get
what I'm saying. Um
gallandroxalis the way I like to
describe it is that it's a like a like a
the most generalist of the predatory
mites. Okay. And so we're excited
because in nature
um it will feed on the area family which
is the family of pest mites to which
hempresses belongs. So you you have it
recommended by like the University of
California as the go-to for certain area
feed species like for example tomato
russet might um which is in the same
genus as hemp russetmite. So our hope is
now that we have it to be able to
basically debut it in cannabis to see
what impacts there are. So if anyone is
interested and has an existing hemp
breast my problem, we're just about
getting ready to launch this, but we
have some production going where we
definitely want to see it feeding and
would like to to um to get video of it.
U my colleague already has video of it
feeding on hemp rust. It might so it's
clear that they'll eat it. Controlling
it yet to be seen because it's never
been tried. So that's my bio control.
just want I'm I'm putting it out there
because we want to get the data. Um,
currently though, very
um effective way. Go ahead. I'm sorry.
So, Salt. Yeah. Before we get into uh
the current your current recommendations
around hemp russet, I wanted to touch on
this a couple things that you just
mentioned that I think are really
important. one uh this is a really
really big deal because I I remember
talking to Kelly Vance about this uh
years ago actually and um I know he's
been pushing for it and one of the big
reasons that you and him I think ended
up at Biobe was because you were so
excited for this might and access to it
and what it may offer the the uh growing
community.
Um so the other thing so I just want to
throw that out there this is a big deal.
Uh the second thing that you had also
mentioned um is control versus feed and
I just want to highlight that too. So
you know russet mites live in the in the
bud within those tricoms. They're very
hard to um that area is very hard to
navigate. It's sticky. It's you know
same with tomatoes sort of thing. And
so, um, this idea that like I think you
mentioned Anderson may feed on russet
mites, um, you know, in a petri dish or
or something, um, but maybe not able to
control it and navigate that space as
well as a russet or effectively enough
to control in the sense of keeping
populations low enough not to have uh,
economic damage to your crop. Uh so
you're we're we're hopeful you're
hopeful that Galandrois will be able to
do that based on the literature and what
you guys have seen. But um I think
that's an important distinction between
something that's able to feed something
and on something and something that's
able to feed on it so effectively that
it's able to control it below an
economic threshold.
Absolutely. And it's something that
Suzanne preaches and I'm very glad she,
you know, highlights that just because
an animal can feed on another animal
doesn't mean it would control an
infestation. Um I don't know if you've
seen the videos, but
[Music]
um there's a video of an of a deer
eating a
bird. Literally just sticks and needs.
These are herbivores. They're not
supposed to be doing that. I don't think
that you would buy a deer to to get rid
of like I don't know a bird pest problem
in your on
your right. You're not um that's the
same thing we and and the the tricky
part is that it it is often crop
dependent and also um dependent on other
factors. But you know just because it
can control something in this crop
doesn't necessarily mean it'll control
that same pest in another crop. Um, and
then just because it'll it has been
shown to control a pest in your
particular crop doesn't mean it'll do it
in every case. And I'll give you the the
primary example for that um is um
amblyas cucumber. So the cucumber might
which I'm sure people are aware of an
inexpensive might probably the least
expensive predatory might out there.
used for thris management, very
successfully used for thres management.
Um, but also successfully used for
broadmite or cyclon might in
strawberries. There's a lot of
literature showing
that.
However, it does not prefer
broadmite. It would rather eat thris.
So, what happens when you have a thris
infestation along with a broadmite
infestation? You may not get biorol
unless potentially you just inundate it.
So that now the cucumber is like
everyone wants to eat you know the steak
not everyone gets the steak. Somebody
has to stay alive you have to eat the
broccoli.
Yeah. So they they may be preferential.
And with the um gallendrois I know you
had mentioned to me that they also like
two spotted spider mightites. So if you
have a twospotted infestation along with
a russet mite infestation, your
hypothesis was that they would probably
control the two spotted first just
because they're larger
um and maybe more delicious in the eyes
of galandrois.
Yeah. I mean if you if you think about
it um so just some some research if you
look at what Cornell University has to
say about galendronosis oxidant talis in
certain crops like like uh uh palm fruit
and and um stone fruit they will feed on
the you know the respective russet might
of those crops but those crops also get
a a a bunch of other you know other pest
mites from the tetranic family, which is
the same one that two spotted spider
might belongs to, and several other non
tetrronicid larger mice that are
potentially more nutritious, right? So,
if you have that infestation going on,
it could fail for the russet might in
your tree. But if you have a clean if
you're if you've got a clean crop with
no other like preferable food, there's a
better chance that it can help you with
rust at night.
So my thoughts on it
is, you know, getting
your populations of twospotted
spidermite as low as possible or um your
thris population as low as possible,
then there's a better chance that gallon
oxidant can help you with rustite and
that you know say as cucumber can help
you with with broadmite
and that's why we need people like you
to offer, you know, technical support
for this sort of thing because it's a
lot to know about and there's a lot of
research that goes into it and expertise
that, you know, people like myself even
don't have. I pick up all that I can
from you guys. Um, but at the end of the
day, if I need a if I need a
recommendation, um, or I have an
infestation, I'm going to come to you
and get get some advice. And so on that
note, uh specifically, let's just stick
with russetss, uh since we've been
talking about them. What would be a more
traditional recommendation for russetss
knowing that uh there has not
historically been any biological options
that control rustites?
Yeah. So,
um back when I started at Harborside
Farms as IPM manager, this was this was
2017, I believe. I can't remember. Um I
walked into a russet might wildfire and
I did not know that pest. I was from
organic herbs. Never dealt with an area
of feed.
Um first thing I did is what are your
scouting reports about this? What do you
mean scouting? Um okay well do you have
scouts? Well we have people that
reported this. Do they carry loops? Um,
this was at the point where we were
where we didn't have anything like what
is set up for example in an ornamental
greenhouse. Um,
so you can't see them without a loop. So
immediately busted out my loop, started
looking, found them. Okay, I know what
rust might like. Okay, what have you
been using? Well, we've been using this
soil and this oil and this soil, but
it's not doesn't seem to work. Okay, let
me dive in. Dove into the its closest
relative. Um, that's that is a pest in
another crop is a tomato russet
mightite. All right, what are they
doing? The go-to for them was elemental
sulfur sprays. All right, so if it works
for them that relative, it should work
for us in cannabis. Um, so that was the
first first sort of step to in the in
the direction. Um, what we didn't know
at the time was how concentrated your
spray had to be and what frequency you
had to apply it. Okay, because there's
negatives to spraying sulfur. Um, but
eventually came around to figuring out
exactly what the rate and frequency of
the sprays should be to manage and then
other techniques that I learned
subsequent to that to help to have you
manage um, hempressescent might
relatively easy with elemental sulfur
sprays. I still believe that if it comes
to a spray, and I think that probably a
good 90% of the cannabis community would
agree with me, at least those that have
battled it, that you're better off with
a sulfur spray than you are with an oil
spray. Um, and there's disagreement, but
I think I what I run into more is
success with using elemental sulfur
sprays, but there are drawbacks to using
sulfur. There's a a few really important
drawbacks.
Well, let's talk about it. I know we we
originally recorded this whole podcast
and I think 15 or 20 minutes of it uh
turned into talking about the pros and
cons of sulfur. Uh, unfortunately we
lost the recording uh due to technical
issues, but let's let's let's do a
little bit of a pros and cons around
sulfur because you you and the last time
we did it, you took the pro side and I
took the con side and we kind of talked
about what those were because I've heard
some I've heard from Suzanne why she
does not like sulfur as much as you do.
But, uh, it is very effective in certain
instances dealing with certain pests. So
let's dive into it. What are some of the
advantages and disadvantages of using
sulfur? And let's talk a little bit
about uh burning sulfur which
technically I don't think is allow legal
in any crop. Um but people do it. So
let's let's have a a short conversation
about that just knowing that it's
happening. Um and then
alsible sulfur sprays. Okay. So on
burning sulfur, yeah, like you said, it
it was very commonly practiced. There's
still devices for it um in green houses,
but at least in California, um I guess
the whoever whatever agency is the in
charge of like fires and you know,
whoever manages the fire departments at
the top of the state um said no more.
It's way too risky to leave these hot
lamps in a greenhouse. we've had too
many instances. So that's actually the
reason why it was um it was um outlawed
at least here in California was very
effective for powdery mildew. So that
forced the growers to go a different
direction. Um I believe if you want to
be
compliant in most states you can't burn
sulfur. Um but again that's a big if.
Some people don't care about being
compliant. It's a different story. Um it
is more it's probably more efficient to
use it to burn it than it is to spray
it. It's you know it's in a vapor form.
It covers the entire um greenhouse. It
may be less effective, more efficient
but less effective for a number of
reasons. Um so that's my take on burning
sulfur. As far as pros and cons of using
sprayable sulfur, I'm going to start
with the cons that I think are
legitimate cons. Okay. Um, so number one
and most important to me is we don't
know what impact the uh the sulfur
residue has on the ability of biological
control agents to hunt for their prey.
It could be disruptive because it is
volatile and a lot of these predators
use alactory cues to find their prey. So
it could interrupt us and that's a very
legitimate uh concern. Another one is go
ahead. So, so let's let's just uh
clarify that. So, you're saying after
spraying sulfur uh and waiting I don't
know a few days or whatever week, you
bring in your beneficial insects, you're
saying there still could be some
volatizing sulfur in the coming off of
that leaf surface that may make it hard
for those beneficials
to track down their predators because
they use their sense of smell. and this
sulfur is still creating an odor. And
then um we don't have any research to
know either way on that. Yeah, nothing
really legitimate yet, just anecdotal.
Um and it's not that it can stick around
for a few days. It does stick around for
a few days. And in fact, in my pros, I
will mention why that's important. Um in
my anecdotal experience where I've seen
it
used seen sulfur used I have
encountered a very robust bio control uh
management. So, in my experience, it
didn't seem to impact the predatory
mites we were using and the parasettoid
wasps we were using or the lace wing.
Um, aphids and and thris and
spidermitites were being managed by
predators after a sulfur spray. Um, now
what does that mean? Does that mean you
have to go in with a higher number of
predators immediately after a sulfur
spray or a more frequent release until
that sulfur dissipates? Maybe. Maybe
that's what it means. Um, and maybe not.
Um, so that's my take on on that. It's a
legitimate concern. We don't have the
research point saying one or the other
yet. Okay.
Um, I do know that the recommendations
from those that have done research like
to say wait 4 days before releasing
predatory mites um I don't know where
they got that um the four days from it
but it is based on research and I think
it's less about can it um can it hunt
properly more like do you put them at
risk if you release between four within
the ne within four
Um, so yeah, that's what I have on on
that. Um, so that's what that's a
legitimate concern for me. The other
concern that's really important is using
oils is effective. A lot of of of pests
in cannabis um not desired in certain
stages. For example, maybe week three of
flower, now you're talking about
something that might be hurting you more
than helping you. Um, so like I said,
maybe a good 75% of of the cannabis
growers I've worked with do use oils in
veg. So using oils in veg is effective.
There may be some drawbacks to using
oils. You know, some some growers
believe that they block stamata, so
photosynthesis is um reduced, so growth
is reduced, plant health's reduced. Um,
then there's also the possibility of
phytotoxicity using oils. This is where
another legitimate concern is with
sulfur. If you look at most sulfur
materials, they do not recommend using
an oil
spray next to a sulfur spray that you've
got to give it a 30-day wait. In my
experience, that's been more like a two
week wait. And now that pe that folks
are using lower rates of sulfur, um it
could even be less than. but that it
does complicate the use of oils if
that's a practice that you already
comfortable with.
Um, another con which you brought up
last time which is very legitimate is
that all of the EPA registered
uh midocidal fungicidal sulfur products
have a 24-hour restricted entry
interval. In other words, c the growers
and the workers can't go into the
crop for 24 hours after a spray and that
interferes with some operations. And
also the the available products can only
be used once a week according to the
label. So that is another another con.
Um again to all of these cons I have
ways to clear the hurdle.
Um let's see what else. It's good it's
good to mention both. Um
yeah so REI or restricted entry
intervals are very important to follow.
Um they're created for a reason. Now do
we always understand those reasons? No.
I think you brought that up last uh last
conversation. But um as a facility with
liabilities and just health risks, it's
probably best to stick to those. Um yep.
In theory, there's research to support
that. Most states, including California,
have whistleblower laws. So if an you
get a disal employee that that shows you
that learns that you're not following
REI
um that they could they could cause a
lot of problems. They could get you
fined um you know because there are
whistleblower laws. So employees in an
agriculture operation are protected by
by the state if they you know report
lapses in you know the way you handle
pesticides which is a good thing right.
Um, it's also why you need a pesticides
license as a as an applicator in
California specifically. Um, yeah, all
these things exist for to for worker
safety. Mhm. Yep. Um, one other one
other con since we're on the con side
still, uh, I wanted to bring up was you
already talked about residues. Um,
sulfur is an essential mineral for
plants.
um it creates those
uh esters and alcohols that sort of that
skunky smell in in cannabis. So, we know
we need sufficient in our soils. Um
however, I worry about heavy metals
potentially spraying heavy metals onto
our flower. So, even if there's just
trace amounts, let's say two to five
parts per million of uh lead or arsenic
or cadmium on in that sulfur. And again,
I this is
I'm not saying this is the case, but
it's worth researching your your product
source because if you fail for heavy
metals because of a residue, that would
be that would be awful, you know, on a
crop because you sprayed sulfur or
anything that you're spraying really.
This doesn't apply specifically to
sulfur. This applies to anything that
we're applying to our crop seaweed or to
our soil. Seaweed and uh anyone using
shrimp kiten um all of those are there's
a risk of metals, mercury in particular,
right? Um, yeah. So, it's a legitimate
concern. It is another one. You beat me
to it. Um,
it it was brought up by Suzanne that she
had a customer who reported who failed
for metals, tested their sulfur product,
and found that it had had them. Um, so
here's what I have to say about that.
again. No, I'm going to go into the the
the the pros afterwards, but yeah, that
that could be a risk of your particular
brand of sulfur having a um having heavy
metals in it. It is a risk. That all
being said, I've never experienced that
with any of my customers, but it is a
risk. Um and I can tell you why. It's
probably that I haven't experienced it.
Um, so another con I can think of is
most
states have laws as to what materials
you can and can't use.
The the
majal
sulfur p wetable powder products that
are available
to crops, all different kinds of crops,
including organic crops.
um are EPA registered
and there's none that I know of in
California that are allowed if you're
trying to be compliant. So that's a huge
issue there is okay if if you're using a
traditional sulfur elemental sulfur
product you are and something that's
used by for example strawberry or grape
grape growers um you're likely going to
be non-compliant by using it. Uh so you
know yeah that's big. It is if you want
to be compliant you know uh there's no
testing for sulfur that doesn't mean
that you don't want to be compliant. Um
you know until those laws are changed
based on research. Um you know you want
to be compliant. You want to be able to
sell to the legal market. That's that is
a con.
All right, let's talk about the pros
because you uh you're a sulfur guy. I
am, but I should preface everything. And
if if Suzanne, if you're watching
this, always remember this
preface. I am not a sulfur guide. I
would I recommend it used only very
limited circumstances because of all of
the cons. Okay, not all cons, because of
the majority of the cons.
Um, that being said, I'm convinced it is
the best treatment for russet mites and
broadmmitites in
veg. That that I can say. I don't
believe in using it unless you've got
rusted might or broadmite.
However, several of the growers I work
with have
anecdotally
reported health benefits to sprays the
sulfur sprays. It it is my understanding
it can be absorbed by the foliage.
So now the other pro or the first pro
um I believe it's superior to oils in
many regards because oils are a
contact only um kill. Now there there's
some herbal oils that are also also have
repellent repellency but mainly the mode
of action the main mode of action of
sprays is contact. If you don't get the
oil to contact the pest, you won't kill
it because it'll dry and that's it. One
and done, right? Um,
which is harder on these two particular
pests because of where they live.
They're tiny. They can get in the
crevices and something so tiny, unless
you're using some kind of
a effective aduant to thin out your
spray, they can even be protected by,
you know, um what's the word? The the
hydrophobicity or the um the lack of
ability to spread in these tiny crevices
or underneath tricoms, right? So the
oils are hard. It's hard to contact them
and they don't last very long. Whereas
sulfur what few are aware of is sulfur
is used routinely in grapes and I used
to work in in wine industry. So I I
learned about sulfur. I learned about
its mode of action um some time ago and
it has actually a two-fold mode of
action. It's contact. Okay. And it's not
that it suffocates the way oils do, but
it's also um residual or
um the vapor form of of of sulfur also
is toxic. This is the powdery mildew. My
belief is that if you perform a sulfur
spray and you miss a colony of russet
mites, but the residue is there pumping
out, you know, the the volatiles,
um the gas attack can actually have this
residual effect and that's why it's so
effective. Even if you don't contact,
which is a kill, the gas can still kill,
right?
So, something to really consider, oils
can't do that for you.
Um, one of the back to oils, one of the
pros, you might say, well, what about
the phytotoxicity risk, the 30 days or
two weeks you have to wait between
sprays. All
right, that is true. Okay, and it's on
the label and I've experienced it
myself.
Um, however, subsequent to me being in
production, growers have figured out
some strategies on how to reduce that
time. And the best strategy I've seen,
which is
um really cool, is actually to spray
your sulfur and wash wash it off
afterwards. Of course, then you're
before an oil spray. You're limiting the
residual if you're doing that right to
the the time that you the time between
spray and when you wash it off. but
you're also removing it so that
effectively removing it from the leaf
surface so that you can come in with an
oil spray and less less risk of burn.
Um, the other thing that's been learned
more recently is I was using it at rates
that were effective based on what I
learned and researched, but it turns out
that growers over time started using
less and less less lower rates down to
half of what I was using were some some
growers are having um an impact. So,
less sulfur residue, easier to wash off,
less even less risk of burn.
So that's sort of my how I clear that
whole issue. You have to time it
properly, right? You have to do the
right thing so you you can avoid the
burn or at least reduce the risk of
burn.
Um what else? Um how do I clear the
hurdle on of heavy metals?
Um first off, again, in my experience,
it's never happened. And in the
experience of Suzanne, she said it
happened. I've asked for the name of the
product so that I could do a little dive
into it. I haven't gotten that
yet. What makes you suspicious of of
sulfur being actually a source of heavy
metals is um back in the day sulfur was
mined. Okay, we know there are metals in
the in the earth. Sulfur was mined um
and then purified in whatever process.
And so the risk there is there. It's
very clearly there. Nowadays, my
understanding is the majority of sulfur
that's used in agriculture is actually
distilled from some other source. What
does that what does distillation mean?
You cannot easily
move how can you get to the vapor point
or the gas stage of mercury? You
probably need to be on the surface of
the sun to do that. So distillation
probably removes a lot of that metal
potential metal contamination. And if
the majority of sulfur products have
that have are are distilled, then maybe
you're, you know, it's not such a
terrible con or a risk. Um, but what you
can always do is take whatever sulfur it
is you're using and submit it for metals
analysis on a regular basis and confirm
to yourself that yeah, in fact, this is
clean or even contact the company and
ask for like a lot analysis and they
can't. they oftent times will test for
metals. Um, so that's my hurdle there.
The hurdle on the
REI, that's a weird one. It's a really
weird one because the fungicide and
midside products that I mentioned, the
EPA registered are 24hour, but there are
some elemental sulfur folure sprays that
are not through the EPA. In other
words, they are not pesticides because
they're being used as nourishment,
folure nourishment.
Um, it's elemental sulfur. This plant
can use sulfur in its metabolism, right?
So, there are some materials that don't
don't qualify as pesticides. Now, why is
it they don't qualify as pesticides?
could be all had to do with the inactive
ingredients. What else is in the
pesticidal sulfur that is not in the
folure feed sulfur? Um, and the folure
feed sulfur actually have lower REIs.
Okay, that doesn't mean that it's safer.
Okay, but for whatever reason, the
governing body has determined the REI
is, for example, as short as two hours,
right? Um, still, you know, why not wait
if you can, right? U, there's no no law
that says you have to go in after two
hours, right? But there's also the
possibility that
um the research is done for the research
was done to find that a combination of
the active and the inactive make it
you're probably safer to go for the 24
hours. I don't know. Okay. I just have
that to say. I just have to that that to
throw out. Um what was another Go ahead
real quick. First of all, I know you had
mentioned that one of the things that's
really important to look at is
application uh frequency, but also
application rate. What is your
recommended rate based off of what
you've seen in facilities? All right.
I'm not going to make a recommendation.
All right. Okay. I'm going to give you
my experience. All right. Okay. Fair
enough. with with a compa with a comp
um with a product that I used which
was about 80% elemental sulfur so 20%
inactive at the
time I was using 20 grams per
gallon and I was applying twice a week.
Okay. All of that was in compliance with
the product. All
right, that was working for me when
again when I had a rust that might pop
up. All right.
Um, now subsequent to that that time,
like I said, growers have figured out to
reduce that all all the way down to 10
grams per gallon, although I think most
growers are using about 15 grams per
gallon with an
80% elemental sulfur product. So, you
can translate it however you'd like.
There are others that have lower sulfur,
whatever.
Um, what was I going to say
regarding these sprays? It'll pop up. It
was an appropriate time to say it right
there when we were were just talking.
I'm sorry for interrupting you. Um, I
know what it was. Go ahead. So what was
key for me again this is my mantra is
the monitoring having good scouts that
can identify russet might as early as
possible. What does that mean? I had a
scout who I would call her the russet
whisperer. All right because she could
practically smell I swear she could
smell where russet might was. And
sometimes I get a text and she'd she'd
say, "Hey, um, I want you to look at
something." I'm like, "Uh, no. You I
know what you're I know what you're
telling me. You you've smelled them
out." And sure, she could look at um
leaf
color in very young leaves and find
russet might infestations very early on.
You have a better chance of getting rid
of them faster when it when it's just
started. Unfortunately, you don't know
when the infestations are just starting
because usually the effects the the
symptoms of the plant don't pop up until
after you have a sizable infestation.
But that was that showed me the
importance of monitoring and having good
scouts that are trained to ID these
these symptoms as early as possible.
Then when we found it, it's like, okay,
all hands on deck, track and trace
because we know it's in this clone and
we know that it in this strain and we
know that it came from clones from those
moms over there. So the first thing
we're doing is going to look at it, look
for it in those moms. Okay. And the
second thing we're doing is any crops
that are were for example cloned and and
and propagated before this particular
crop and are farther ahead including
potentially even in flower are probably
might have it. So let's focus on what
just like they did in covid time track
and trace where did this come from who
did you talk to who did you meet who
were you around who subsequently before
you ID it before you
got diagnosed who also may have may have
spread it to so that's was super
important and then you start really
intense scouting identify the plants
that have it mark them and then do a
sulfur spray because you want to come
back within a few days literally kill
was often
within 24 hours percent of the
population had been reduced. That was
amazing to me. Um, but if you can, you
need to continue to go back and scout at
those plants until you're sure you got
them all because again, you're not going
to always get them all. Um, and and
you're not going to get you may not get
the eggs with sulfur. They it may not
kill the eggs. So you need to go back
and um usually in my experience again
this was way back when I'm sure growers
have gotten better but within two weeks
I was of sulfur sprays I was in good
shape with whatever infestation I found.
So that's super key.
Yeah. I want to I want to mention
something that is important on the
scouting side. So and this is maybe this
will help folks because this is a recent
story. We had a guy reach out to us that
thought he had a fertility issue. And so
we started digging into this and uh
basically what we found was this problem
was happening at his facility, but it
was also happening at his his uh
partner's facility and they cultivate
different ways. So the chances of that
being a fertility issue versus a pest or
pathogen is less likely. It's more
likely that there's a pest involved or a
pathogen. In this case, it turned out to
either be russetss or broads. I have I'm
waiting to get um an image to really
determine that. But um one of the other
clues that we had was is this across all
of your plants evenly or is it is it in
one place specifically? And basically
what we found was oh it's worse over in
this area. And yeah, they were they were
doing living soil beds. So there's a
chance that you know the fertility was
different across there. But most likely
if you're treating all your beds the
same and you have a what we call a hot
spot, um it it's it's most likely a pest
or pathogen issue. And so then we want
to we want to dig into that a little
further. So if you see it just with um
you know across multiple genetics or in
one part of your room or in one room
versus all of your rooms um and it's
spreading uh it's more it's less likely
that it's fertility. And I just want to
bring that up as some clues for folks.
Yeah, you need to know how to identify
russet mites for sure. And in, you know,
a future podcast, hopefully we can do my
presentation on signs and symptoms of
common cannabis pests, which includes
the russet might, you know, signs and
symptoms, but you really do need to know
how to use them. And there's a method
that I developed. I didn't develop it.
It came from a cla a pathology class um
that makes scouting for rusted broad
rusted and broad mites a lot easier. Um
but it it's something that some of the
growers I've worked with have have tried
and they like it. It makes it fast for
faster scouting, but I'll go over that
on a maybe on the scouting um podcast
when you want to do that. Um unless
anybody wants to reach out, I can I can
talk to them about it. But um but yeah,
that is that is key. What's interesting
about russet might is um you know the
the they don't they're not great movers.
They're little carrots with feet, right?
To them for them to move from one plant
to another is um it's it's tough. But so
you'll often find one plant that is just
loaded with them and the neighbors
aren't have a few of them, right? And
they're because they're touching. That's
that's I've noticed that it's um and
then that spot does grow. Okay. and and
it can grow fast but that's often a case
where you find one plant. Um, one key I
want to I want to I'd like my
observation for monitoring um rustmite
is when you get
into
flower it in my experience tends to hit
those really lower flowers down you know
even sometimes down on the trunk of the
plant before I see them up above. I
don't know why that is, but you start I
start to see the symptoms, particularly
the the leaf curl, you know, the the
taco or whatever you want to call it, um
the canoe, um down there in those little
teeny flowers. Um so, might not be a bad
idea when you're scouting through a
flower when you see those to take a look
for those symptoms down there. It might
alert you to where it is and possibly
that it's just starting,
right? So, yeah. about sorry a con that
I forgot about sulfur is most growers
don't want to use it in flour and I
don't recommend it. So making sure you
come in clean into into flour with no
sulfur is smart. It's it's critical and
some growers will use a sulfur spray
right before they flip or right when
they're done with their um two weeks
into before the flower primordia. Um,
and it's not a bad idea. If in fact, if
somebody's going to just use what we
call calendar spraying, that that would
be the one spray that I would say,
"Yeah, that's a smart move where you're
you're you're giving it one last shot."
Now, luckily now, if all goes well,
hopefully some growers will help us do
it. We have a biocrol agent, which is
attractive to use in flour, um, which
which is not going to taint the flavor
of the of the of the product, um, with
gallon drumalis. So that would be super
cool. If russetss get past you in veg,
maybe there's a non-spray solution in
flour.
Yeah, I just wanted to mention one other
clue for us. And the reason this one
threw me was because I hadn't seen a
plant this far into flower with this bad
of an infestation. I just hadn't come
across it yet. Uh but we had flower buds
that were um that looked awful. you
know, they were displaying every sort of
what could look like a deficiency. Um,
you know, the the tacoing, the
discoloration in the leaf, some
necrosis, uh, premature browning of
pistols, uh, poor development. Um, but
the fan leaves looked great, normal. So,
the fertility on the fan leaves looked
really good. The buds looked terrible. I
put a picture up recently on my
Instagram um, of that and and most
people clued right in on russetss uh, or
broad mites. And I I sent it to Suzanne
and she actually was leaning towards
broad mites, but um I have yet to get a
positive idea. It could potentially be
either. So, you have a scope.
They did not have a scope. So, that was
a lesson learned for them. They're both
locations now are are getting scopes and
they're hopefully going to send me a
picture. So, I'm waiting on that. But,
yeah, we uh we got them a a
recommendation for, you know, sort of
what we talked about here as a way to
address this moving forward. But um
yeah, it's a powerful lesson of why it
is important to scout so you can avoid
getting that far into flower
and you know to a point where you can no
longer deal with it and now you're
facing crop loss or significant crop
yield loss.
What in my opinion is
the most dangerous arthropod pests of
cannabis being russet
mites and the fact that you can't see
those with the naked eye and unless you
have some experience it's they're
difficult to find with loops. I don't
see why every cannabis scourge doesn't
invest a 100 bucks on a microscope that
can help you ID russet mites and broad
mites. I can't see it. It's literally
you can get them for 100 bucks. Um
yeah, since we're doing video here, and
I know not everyone can see it, but I
have my I have my Dino Light, which
unfortunately is significantly more
expensive than $100 nowadays. Um I also
bought this like cheapo Amazon uh hooks
up to my phone and takes photos. Uh and
this works good enough to get uh you
know to see hempress it. It's not as
high of a quality image, but yeah. Oh,
you got one, too. It looks like the same
one even. So, yeah, I think, you know,
and mine at the time was like $30. So,
they're really is no excuse for not
having something some sort of microscope
that you can you can take images with. I
totally agree. But yeah, I like this
little thing. Um, it's obviously not
the, you know, Cadillac dinoite. Um, I
recommend if you can afford it. You
know, there are some affordable dino
lights, too, that are probably better
than the $30 one that you and I have,
but this is more than sufficient. Okay.
And and also train yourself because you
can see them with loops. I I I know how
to It's not tough if you just train
yourself. Um yeah, there are some
strategies on how you can see them
better with loops, too.
Well, S, I feel like we covered a lot
today. Hey, I'd love to get you back on
because there's so much more around the
insect world to talk about. Um, I'm
really grateful for the relationship
that we have with Biobe and the ability
to, you know, work with you guys. And so
when we do sell insects to our growers
and we we ship direct from insectory um
directly from you guys to the grower um
which I think is important uh we we can
always turn to you guys or put growers
that work with us in touch with you as a
way of getting that sort of support that
extra technical knowledge. Um and
there's no extra cost to that because
that's part of that's literally your job
which is so wonderful to our customers.
That's what we offer. um our c your
customers are our customers.
Um again, it's that's just part of the
deal. I may not be able to visit all the
time. I'm based in California, but I do
make it up to the Pacific Northwest. In
fact, I'm there at the be at the end of
the month. Um although I'm there briefly
in Portland. Um, but there are times uh
when I'm up there more frequently and I
can actually do visits. Um, and any of
your customers in California obviously
easier to visit. I already visited one
of them in is it Long Beach? I can't
remember. Um, yeah, down in Southern
California. Um, it's it's to me this is
fun. I you could probably tell I can
talk about this for hours. Um, and you
know, and then there's nothing as
satisfying really to me than giving
advice to a grower, having the grower
work with me to integrate it into their
program, and then getting the the report
back. Hey, guess what? This solved it.
This did it. Why? Because it validates
that, you know, I'm not just giving BS
information out there. Um,
yeah, absolutely. I feel the same way on
the fertility side when we're able to
get growers off of, you know, bottled
nutrients or a multitude of products and
simplify it with soil testing um and
save the money and and produce a high
quality flower. Yeah, that's that's why
we do what we do. So, yeah. Well, we'll
definitely catch up again soon. Super
grateful for this time and uh thank you
again. Yeah, Tad. Thank you. Anytime.