[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is my good
friend Suzanne way wght Evans also known
by many as the bug lady she's an
ornamental entomologist specializing in
integrated Pest Management suzan has
been involved in the green industry for
more than 25 years with a primary focus
on biological control and using
pesticides properly she is a graduate of
the University of Florida with degrees
in both entomology and environmental
horiculture Suzanne has been on the
podcast multiple times and I highly
suggest folks go back and listen to some
of our other podcasts if you haven't
already her website is buglady
consulting.com where you can find links
to other podcasts webinars and
information as well as how to contact
her for direct Consulting now on to the
show hi Suzanne thanks for coming back
on the show hey Tad it is great to be
back and to talk with
you yeah so before we get started I did
want to mention that you and I have been
working in the background along with
Adam over Collective elevation and his
team to throw a conference next year so
I want people to mark their calendars
we're still working out a lot of the
details but on September 5th
2025 we're going to have uh a workshop
with Suzanne as well as talks so the
5ifth through the 7th so the 5ifth and
the 6th will be the conference at
Collective elevation in Boseman Montana
and then the seventh is going to be a
some sort of tasting event with the
living soil Alliance
Montana group that will be um included
for folks going to the conference and
then uh open up to the to some some of
the public as well and that's the plan
but I want to get a lot of the people
from the podcast to the conference uh to
speak a lot of my favorite guests and
I'm really excited for it so I wanted to
start with that anything you want to add
Suzanne well I am super excited too
because a Montana B Montana I uh I
always love going to Montana um also um
I've been out to collected elevation and
um they've always been super awesome so
um I think it's going to be a lot of fun
a lot of good education um I'm excited
to be giv the opportunity to actually
teach a workshop more interactive with
the Cannabis scowers because often times
I'm just doing a presentation but this I
want to be a bit more interactive that
we're going to do on Friday so I think
it's it's going to be great and I'm
really looking forward to
it awesome awesome well as we dive into
this podcast I know uh there's a we're
kind of going to jump around a little
bit on topics one of the things I wanted
to touch on briefly because I in my
indoor garden this year I've never had
an issue with um I've been calling them
isopods but we should probably touch on
that too these uh woodlouse roly poly
armadillo like creatures I'll let you
pronounce the scientific or the Latin
names um but because of the amount of
organic matter in my soil and I don't
use I I'm in raised beds and I'm not
using a cover crop or a mulch and we can
touch on that as well too but I posted
about them and I saw a whole list of
comments replying to them everything
ranging from you need to feed them
separate from your plants so they don't
attack your plants but this seems to be
a problem that's pretty common among
living soil Growers from time to time uh
typically the ones that I see having
this problem are ones that have mulches
or cover crops I don't see it as much
with people like myself who just have
bare soil and are not using those
practices but um yeah some of the
suggestions were everything from you
know squash or pumpkin or beer traps to
kind of Mast trap or collect them in one
spot or feed them separate from your
cannabis plants um other people are
putting sticky tape or wraps around the
stock of their plant is a way of keeping
the plant the insects from walking up
the plant or girdling the stem um so
we've seeing a bunch of different
suggestions around how to deal with them
one one of the suggestions was a pyganic
5.0 which is a pyin and I definitely
want to talk to you about
pyrin um what are your thoughts okay
well first of all they're not insects um
you know to be an insect you have as an
adult six pair of legs um um anteni
where if you look at this group which
they are a kind of isopod isopod incor
incomp
incorporates um a lot of of different
animals out there um but there are some
specific families that these I'm going
to call them generic rly py because
there are a lot of different Regional
names for them uh just like how some
people call lightning bugs and fireflies
different names um that it's the same
kind of thing that there's a lot of
different names um you know woodlouse is
often used a little more I don't want to
say scientific um than Ry poly um but
they get their name Ry poly a bunch of
them because they can roll up and that's
the
group um that you have the armadilla
daier um which it makes sense because
they roll up like armadillos um and so
um that is
uh kind of where they rest and I I did
do a little checking cuz I am not a rly
pulley expert cuz you know I work more
with insects and mites and
nematodes um but it looks like none of
them are actually native uh to North
America and when I say if you look up
isopods of course there's native isopods
but um the genuses of the ones that
Growers are using or a lot of them that
are found Outdoors are not native they
have been either a brought in
accidentally um with uh soil um from the
Mediterranean region from Europe um
other parts of the country or by people
buying them and then um them escaping or
people dumping out their soils when
they're done with a crop um you know
it's it's a tough thing because a lot of
them now have been here in North America
for you know quite a long time and so
they are kind of established in the
ecology so they are kind of indigenous
but they're not actually native but uh
you know I get real squirly about you
know moving animals around um without
the proper permits and without the
research that's been done proving that
it's okay to move them around because
historically a lot of mistakes have been
made um today to get perits from the
USDA is a multi-year very painful
process and pretty much from you know
the spectrum that I the side that I
worked on with the biological control
we're not getting anything new into the
US um unless it's it's a species that's
here already um that that's been well
documented here so um as far as
management goes I don't think anybody's
really surveyed to know exact
which species are causing
problems um in them because I'm going to
guess it's not just one species of roly
poly out there because of people coming
from different regions and again I know
some people buy them and release them um
I've had numerous Growers contact me and
as as you mentioned there seems to be
that common denominator of of the heavy
mulching um because I think that
provides a perfect environment you know
you go outside you whatever you pull up
your mul
um you can find rly pulley down under
there um um because they are they
basically are decomposers and you know
that's what mulch does on the bottom
it's it's it's decomposing between the
media um and uh the actual mulch layer
itself and so I mean it does create a
perfect habitat but the problem is is
with anything too much of a good thing
is not a good thing um and the numbers
can get out of control
and I mean i' I've actually seen them um
beat on tomatoes um as well as cannabis
and as far as control honestly I mean I
hate to say it the Growers I've worked
up we've kind of ended up vacuuming a
lot out um I mean I kind of understand
the idea if you provide them an
alternate food source that they'll feed
on that and not so much your crop but
you that's a gamble because you don't
always know again what species with the
environment is and what they prefer on
and providing them a perfect habitat
with a lot of food for reproduction can
just really boost their numbers even
higher which could create a bigger
issue um if you're a homeg grower and
just have a few plants and you can put
sticky collars around the base of your
plants for for trapping that can work um
I will tell you that we've had when
people have used products like tangle
foot it creates a moisture layer and uh
we've seen where the plants has have
tried to grow roots out in that area and
it looks really weird um but also um
when you start getting into trapping
like that it's non- selective and you
can you know you can you can catch good
things as well as bad things um and you
know if you're relying on um you know
predatory mites to be able to run up and
down the stocks your plans and things
like that you may end up trapping uh
some of your beneficials there um on
it yes can I can I touch on something
so the way we're talking about these
roly py right now is that they're
they're a pest and they do have uh they
are classified as a a pest of minor
importance by um you know some of these
uh
universities and such but really do have
a lot of benefits to soil health so I
want to acknowledge it in the healthy
ecosystem a lot of times you will find
them in you know proper quantities or
concentrations they're not out of
control and they do uh like you said
they do have a very a decomposing sort
of behavior where they'll eat dead plant
material shred it break it down further
which allows microbes to better access
the carbon and such in there so it it
they will help mineralize soil and
mineral ize um organic matter so there
are some benefits to them um it's when
they get out of control in these indoor
systems I think that we have problems
like I I would
be I would be surprised to see a lot of
issues outdoors with these with with
roly police but maybe maybe it does
happen it does happen um also um where
you can in times of drought if you have
again crops with water content in them
and they're looking for moisture to feed
on um that sometimes can drive some
unusual behaviors
um in nature when it's outside you have
predators of them to keep them in check
and this is again it's a numbers game
which you know everything it's it's it's
keeping numbers in check and this is
true with anything I mean like hey an
aspirin's great for a headache but if
you eat an entire bottle it's G to kill
you
um and so the same thing like with roly
poy to have the proper number around but
you're taking them out of their ecolog
that complete ecology and force them
into a very artificial ecology and I
think what's tough is people are trying
to create Outdoors indoors but they're
missing a lot of the key elements um
where you don't have the Predators you
don't have frogs you don't have lizards
you don't have and I'm sure there are
some I guess they technically wouldn't
be inop pathogens they would probably be
armadil
di
pathogens um that keep them in in check
um even flooding oh you know some of
them die because they've drowned or
drought and and the people are trying to
cherry-pick just a few things from the
ecology they think are going to be good
for their soil because we've been told
they're good for the soil but there's so
many pieces of the puzzle we're missing
and so it it it the wheel doesn't run as
smoothly as it should um I you know I
often think about how important wind and
rain is for plants outdoors and when you
bring them inside you don't get that
natural every time it rains you know
kind of leeching the soil out and
washing the soil and adding that um
because you don't have that in an indoor
environment and I can appreciate and
understand the direction and what
Growers are trying to do
and I I get that I just think we need to
think bigger
about not just cherry-picking a few
things and throwing them in and being
like yeah now you know we're going to
have this you know healthy soil with
missing a lot of the
pieces yeah I I've talked about this
with other people on the show and I've
and on my social media this idea of
biomimicry that we're trying that people
are trying to create indoors
and it frankly it's a it's it's a lovely
idea that I resonates with me
emotionally but like you said ecology is
very complex biodiversity is so complex
so us adding in you know 10 more plants
in the form of cover crops into our
indoor garden does not suddenly create
an ecology that's going to match what we
would see outdoors and part of that like
you mentioned is we don't have the same
pathogens that are helping control some
of these you know insects or roly py or
other other biota that we have in our
soil so I think that's a really good
point that you brought up there um let's
talk about pyrans because I was trying
to remember in my head I'm thinking I
know they're dered from crysanthemum I
know that you don't like them therefore
I don't really or you don't usually
recommend them you it it is I it's not I
and I have recommended them for the
right usage
and the thing is is I think with
cannabis because of their limited access
to pesticides for the legal Growers um I
think pyrans just have been overused
because of lack of access or not not
access but the legality of using other
chemistries um and I I also think people
you know have this idea just because
something comes from a plant it's safe
um and we all should know better than
that so the so is the issue with
pyrin mostly uh overuse in the sense of
pest developing resistance to it or
there other potential risks or
non-target organism effects if you were
to use them for like say drenching the
soil because I did find one article
talking about um isopods showing
avoidance behaviors to soil that was
contaminated with pyin versus a soil
that was not but um I wasn't able to
find anything directly saying that they
would
kill uh daop Poots so as you mentioned
you know
pythons do come from um chrysanthemums
that's kind of how this all got started
they
are basically they affect for ins their
nervous system this is where most of the
research has been done on insects um and
it's it affects their sodium channels
what affects their nerves so they lose I
mean if you watch an insect die after
exposure to pyrin you know they get kind
of Twitchy because their muscles just
kind of fire and then they just kind of
die now humans um you know discovered
this this is like such a cool thing and
at the time I mean it and you know I'm
not going to knock pesticides I mean you
can argue that they've been completely
bad but also everybody enjoys having
cheap food today and you know a lot of
our cheap food system um has to do with
the development of pesticides and
allowing us to grow a lot of crops um
but pyrans themselves growing enough
chrysanthemums to extract the pyrin out
is very expensive so that's why humans
developed synthetic py roids um and
those are the products you get in things
like
bifenthrin um which are used a lot for
Structural Pest Management um if you
live um or if you grow plants in the
Southeastern portion of the United
States Texas up towards I think we're
now hitting up to Virginia um and you're
going to transport plants you have to
incorporate um bifenthrin which is a or
one of the synthetic pyrethroids into
the media because synthetic pyrethroids
are really good
repellants this and this keeps the fance
from going into the pots and it repels
them out they do it in the Pacific
Northwest to keep weevils out of of
containerized plants too why they use it
a lot for Structural Pest Management
around windows and doors is because an
insect walks up and they're like Boop
don't want to be either that and and it
repels them away so the this this the
pyin pyrethroids yes there's definite
repellency qualities to these
chemistries but when humans developed
the synthetic pyth roid compounds and
they started in all the homeowner
products Turf people used them nurseries
used them everybody used them resistance
happened very quickly and so there's a
lot of resistance to to this group so
and this is something that it's very
important to understand with resistance
just because you've never used a
chemistry that doesn't mean the insects
or mites you have have not been exposed
to it so it's very possible for you to
get you know never have used a
pyrine and you spray it and it didn't
work that's because the the insects you
have gotten um have a history of
exposure even though you haven't exposed
them one of the very famous problems
we've dealt with in the United States is
when we got um U bmia uh White fly here
in the United
States um and it was resistant to many
many chemistries and it wasn't because
of what was sprayed in the United States
um in Spain because they have large
Greenhouse systems there they had used
uh the synthetic
pyrethroids um I'm sorry sorry they used
the neonic noids very heavily and when
those white flies made it here from
Spain they were resistant um so the
resistance we have can come from other
countries and other regions um but again
with the pyin
pyrethroids pyin are the natural pids
are the synthetic version um they've
been cheap they've been used for decades
so there is so my concern one is
resistance and it's not something you
can just spray over and over and use
over and over in your facility um
because it it you would definitely will
develop resistance that's number one
number two they're definitely
non-selective um that it it doesn't you
know it's not like the chemistry is
Ascension being that would be like hey
you know might or hey aphid or hey
ladybug are you good or bad because I'm
only going to kill the bad one you know
it doesn't do that um they're very
non-selective um then my next concern is
persist
distance I've actually you know talked
to the researchers that um have worked a
lot with the natural pyre renss and they
talk about how quickly they break down
and I asked like under what conditions
and what they've looked at is outdoor
row crops you know in the sun in the
rain where it does break down quickly
when I started asking about well what if
it's you know indor grows and you don't
there's no irrigation and it's sub
irrigation and there hasn't been it
seems like a lot of work on that um but
I did uh get some information like when
it it's used in stored grains to keep
stored grain pests out in cooler
temperatures in the dark like that it
can persist for months um I do know
indoors in cannabis um we have done some
Leaf tissue analysis where um pyrin were
sprayed and we tested and even three
weeks out um there was still very low
but there were still detectable levels
of uh pyrin on the
foliage wow are there any health risks
or Reis associated with pyin or
pyrethroids absolutely um they all have
Reis because they are registered
pesticides and that's something that
concerns me um sometimes with the
Cannabis industry cuz um not all
cannabis Growers carry um pesticide
licensing and I think to me what's
important about the pesticide licensing
is learning and understanding how to
read um pesticide labels understanding
Reis um post Harvest intervals what PPE
is required you know a lot of people are
like oh it's you know big government you
know trying to take control and blah
blah no they're trying to keep you from
killing yourself because these are
pesticides I mean they they can kill you
um they can I mean that's what they're
designed to do they kill things and it's
again it's a dosage thing now if you're
spraying pyrans you know is it going to
kill you no um but the thing that I
think about is the long-term lowd dose
Expos exposure of constant exposure to
these things if you're again outdoor in
a rad crop environment where you've got
rain sunlight microbial like to be so
many things are going
on things down when when you go into an
indoor grow environment which is not
like outdoor everything changes and I
don't think we fully understand how
chemistries break down in those
environments how they persist in those
environments um it's just we just don't
know yet and I would not say not to use
it if if it's something that was the
right use you followed the labeled you
wore the right PPE you waited the proper
REI the re-entry and AAL before you
entered back in or your employees you
know that's fine but I wouldn't just go
using pesticides willy-nilly
you brought up two things that I think
are worth spending a little more time on
and and I didn't I wasn't aware that
makes a lot of sense about how things
would break down much slower indoors
than outdoors and how that might
increase exposure or even even
potentially contamination on the leaf
tissue itself of the final cannabis
product in this case but the two things
I wanted to talk a little bit more about
was REI which is return entry interval
and when we're we're talking about that
uh what that is it's on a pesticide
label telling you how long you need to
stay out of that space before you can go
back into it without PPE um after
spraying uh pesticide is that correct Su
correct me if I yeah yeah yeah it's it's
the re it it's it it it and this is the
crazy thing
this you're given these Reis um and it's
for your employees to stay out this is
the one of the problems I have with this
rule is that it doesn't imply it doesn't
apply to
non-employees so if you've got a garden
center and you want to come in and spray
a product with like a 4hh hour
REI your employees can't go back to
those plants for 4 hours but your
customers
can so um yeah and that's I I that's
horrible I don't know I'm going to guess
you know there was probably some weird
lobbying or something because you know
for for the public and this is why
there's been some of that where you need
to put the law the signs on your Lawns
posting that this was sprayed with a
chemistry kind of thing because I think
people need need to be aware but that
that doesn't apply in all areas and
sometimes that you know is something
that has to be
requested um that you know that you get
notification um of of it every every
state is different on on that
notifications for those outdoor
applications um but that or REI is very
important because again that's that's
what the government has deemed is safe
for your employees to go back in now
it's interesting
because in the United
States a lot of the newer stuff has 4our
Reis on it um older chemistries you'd
see uh Reis as long as 48 Hours um most
my most of my
ornamental Growers don't want anything
more than 4 hours 12 is really difficult
because that means their employees can't
go into that facility for 12 hours
and um
I I think with cannabis um because of
just the hands on
nature the way people grow I think
sometimes those Reis are overlooked and
I think it's from lack of understanding
um on the
label yeah I had reached out to you
because uh someone in a Reddit Forum had
suggested a product at another you know
organic uh supplier and I wasn't
familiar with the product and someone
said oh just apply this and it'll fix
your problem and I I want to make a a
video around this here so I don't want
to give it all way on the podcast but
essentially I sent it to you and you
said oh yeah this this has been around
forever uh but it has a 48h hour REI and
I guarantee I mean because these guys
sell stuff mostly to Hom Growers I
guarantee most people either don't know
that or they're not waiting 2 days to go
look at their indoor plants again um no
hom grower I know of does that so uh you
know it's it's scary to me to think
about what people might be exposing
themselves to
unintentionally uh and so yeah I look
forward to working with you on maybe
clarifying some of these label terms in
a you know a short series or something
video series in the future yeah and I've
got to go back and reread that label
because again I mean that product's been
around for decades and it's just never
gain traction because the long long RI
but I it may require a respirator um for
application cuz a lot of um pesticides
you need a a respirator and the
government now you need you need a a
respirator that's custom fit to your
face um so you don't get leaks in it and
um because it's all about keeping the
stuff out of your your lungs and and
your body and I don't know of any homeg
grower that is custom fitting
respirators um the green houses and
stuff I work with they they have you
know checks where they check the
respirators to make sure they fit they
have training
classes um on how to teach people how
to train to to check to make sure that
these respirators fit and everything and
again this has kind of been a big driver
for more bio control because you don't
have these respirator requirements
and as more products get longer Reis
even though again new products tend to
have shorter ones if you go up to Canada
Canada is just not even giving things
shorter than really 12-hour Reis anymore
just because they don't want anybody in
there for 12 hours after a products um
appli the United States is pretty
liberal and we have some pretty short
Reis compared to um other countries um
out there um
but you know it's really important to
protect your lungs and yourself because
again even though they come from plants
some of these are synthetic chemistries
I mean they are they are
pesticides great and I just double
checked on the US EPA website and on
this product and the um the REI is 48
hours now when I go to the website for
the product it says oh it's uh food safe
insecticide mde that provides fast
andure biochemical control for a wide
range of problem pest it's as safe as
soap it causes no skin irritation to
humans livestock or pets uh you know if
you get in your eyes just flush your
eyes with water it's it's like getting
soap in your eye this is the faq's on
their website but when you go to the EPA
site a 48 hour hour REI is kind of scary
to me there's a there's a big disconnect
between what they're putting on their
website and what looks it's like a
totally safe organic EPA certified
product versus what's on their actual
label and and I will say sometimes when
products come to market for the first
time they might have an R High REI but
then if the the product more research is
done they can come back and come back in
with a lower REI on it um that I have
seen that happen but again I've known
about this product uh it's been 20
something years and if it's never been
lowered in 20 years it's I there's
something about it I don't know what it
is about the product because again if I
can't no one I know will use a 48 hour
product um no one and it's weird I
honestly I didn't even know this was
still on the market um I was kind of
surprised when you contacted me that it
had it had resurfaced um again um but um
the only place I could see a 48 hour REI
is outdoor row crops because you got the
tractor it will go out and spray it and
you don't have to worry about people
being out there working because those
crops will grow for weeks if not months
and nobody's out there but if you're in
a a greenhouse a nursery a Canabis
facility someone's going to be in there
in in more than 48 hours and just
because we were talking about um pyrin
um Panic which can be a very good
product um in the right situation that
one does have a 12-hour I so if you are
going to use
Panic you have a 12-hour re-entry
interval um after applying it before you
your employees can you should be back in
there great so the other thing I want to
touch on that you had brought up was
essentially non-target organism effects
so this idea that when we apply any for
any pesticide anything side that kills
something that it's just going to kill
our Target Pest and not other beneficial
or innocuous organisms in our systems is
is flawed
so like for an example one recently was
uh I saw people using mustard meal for
example to mustard seed meal to kill
fungus Nets and I started looking into
it yes it will kill fungus Nets but it's
also going to kill other organisms that
may recycle nutrients that have other
benefits in your soil as well uh so I
kind of want to just touch
on non-target organism effects now there
are some things that are very targeted
that we can use too I think of like
Bavaria for example in this regard as
being a little bit more targeted than
say you know some of these
broadcasted things like mustard meal but
what what are your thoughts so and and
this is this is a challenge in a way um
for people that want to be
sustainable and care about the
environment because the newer synthetic
pesticides that are coming to the market
um uh saltan is a very good example from
BASF it is very targeted it only kills a
few species of spider mites spiderm
mites are a family it doesn't do
anything for broad mites it doesn't do
anything for russet mites it it it it's
the way it works is very targeted so it
is one of these newer chemistries that
we can use over top of predatory mites
and has no impact on the predatory mites
I mean other than the water washing
action if you were going to spray but if
you were to spray a leaf put the
predatory mites pimus cucuma sski they
all just can go on and live their happy
lives um just like again the broad mites
would because it doesn't affect them it
it the the the chemical companies are
really dialing
very specific targets there's like
Endeavor is another synthetic chemistry
and it affects the mouth
Parts on um white flies and aphids
because their mouth parts are kind of
like turkey baster bulbs you know
simplifi oversimplifying but it stops
that muscle from being able to work so
they can't feed so again it's very
targeted on those groups things that are
that that are more from nature the
pyin Soaps and oils even they are non-
selective and they will just come in and
kill everything um Bavaria even though
it can be more targeted um so Bavaria
basana is is a fungus um we consider an
inop pathogen because it does kill
insects but if you start looking at
labels you'll see there's numbers or
letters after them because we have
different strains just like with
cannabis there is with these fungi and
the different strains can affect
different pests differently and
different insects differently um and
even though bavar basana GHA is the most
common found one will not kill
everything when you apply it it will
kill some of your beneficials like it
will kill
orius but it's considered much safer
with predatory mites as long as use the
wettable powder formulation and this is
really getting into the deep into the
pool because then you have to start
looking at formulations and how they
affect things but generally stuff that's
approved for organic farming is is
they're non- selective they kill good
and bad where when you're looking at
sustainability and being very targeted
and killing specific pests some of the
newer pesticides actually
um are going to they're better for your
bio programs and to preserve your
ecology now most of these what I
consider designer pesticides cannot be
used in cannabis but they are being used
in ornamental and vegetable production
because we can keep our beneficials
going come in Target with these products
um but yeah sadly um again pyrethroids
um or pyren the natural ones are
non-selective and they will wipe out um
the beneficials that you do have um the
BTS which have been around for decades
now uh BT stands for basilis
thuringensis and same thing with that we
have multiple species there's Israeli
insus there's zi uh there's um uh garia
and each of these
is very targeted for groups the Israeli
insis is very targeted on flies and
that's what we um have commonly used for
fungus net management and it's something
that we can use to Target fungus Nets
that can work fine in conjunction with
beneficial nematodes soild dwelling
predatory mites and things like that um
where uh the chawi uh cawi um is used
for Caterpillar management but just like
everything else you use it too much and
there are resistance issues with it so I
mean
if you know it's it's this fine line
because I love beneficial insects I mean
that's no big secret I've committed my
whole life to this but sometimes um it's
these these synthetic targeted
pesticides are actually are I think from
a sustainability option um a targeted
Choice than going in with a
broadspectrum
pyin that's going to kill everything but
sometimes you're okay with killing
everything because you need to do a
reset you just want to kill everything
and get back in pretty
fast yeah so something like that where
you go and knock it's called a knockdown
spray or essentially trying to get
levels back down to a point where you
could come back in with beneficials or
something that's a little bit gentler so
if you notice if let's say for example
you weren't scouting in your indoor
space and all of a sudden you realize
you have spidermites and they've gotten
out of control you may want to come in
and do and we're not too far into flower
I have to set all these different
parameters uh then you could come in
with a knockdown spray and essentially
suffocate or kill a lot of them and then
follow that up with a beneficial
application of the right beneficials to
um potentially deal with all the little
ones that you weren't get and then move
forward with your with your crop cycle
yep exactly it it's it's um yeah just
doing that knockdown spray
because it is very difficult today and
I'm sure there's going to be push back
when I say this to manage pest just with
spray programs um because you don't get
the spray coverage
and if you're doing just a spray program
obviously it has to be done regularly
but you're just keeping your numbers in
in check um with that um but even with
that if you use the same mode of action
repeatedly with there are a few
exceptions typically we don't see
resistance issues with soaps oils or um
Bavaria basana um things like that um
but again uh pyren BTS if they you're
constantly using those you definitely
will develop resistance to repeatedly
using those and then your program can
get out of check your problems get out
of control then you want to come and do
knockdown spray but your product's not
working
[Music]
anymore that was part one of my two-part
podcast with Suzanne way Wright Evans
and you are listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast don't
forget to check out the podcast page at
www.k organics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and if you want
access to podcast as soon as they are
recorded along with additional content
and video we do have a patreon account
we also do book clubs Hangouts and have
a private Discord channel for members
the kiss Organics website also offers a
variety of soil amendments lighting
fixtures beneficial insects and the
highest quality commercial soils on the
market we carefully research all the
products we offer and manufacture to
make sure they are science-based and
meet our standard of quality thanks for
listening