[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge don't
forget to subscribe to the podcast and
leave us a rating and review you can
also sign up for our newsletters on our
website as it's the best way to find out
right away with new episodes and blog
posts come out as well as any discounts
or coupon codes in honor of our guest
this week in his field of expertise I'd
like to offer 10% off on all of our
humic acid and EMA products just enter
the code humate that's H um a te into
the coupon code box our guest this week
is dr. Robert Faust who is the president
of bio a dr. Faust attended the
University of Delaware College of
Agriculture his major with entomology
and applied ecology later he received a
Bachelor of Science degree from the
University of the state of New York an
accredited university in Albany his
master's of sciences in agronomy whereas
thesis was field research on the use of
ecological and organic methods for crop
production and the use of humates and
bio-based fertilizer in large-scale
production in Idaho he received his PhD
from Columbia Pacific University dr.
Faust lived in California for many years
where he was a licensed pest control
advisor and IPM specialist who advised
organic farmers on soil and pest
management conducted contract bio
pesticide research and was a commercial
sales manager for safer incorporated a
company that produced and sold
alternative pest management products he
also conducted organic certification
inspection and consulting with the
organic farmers in Hawaii
dr. Faust is a leading expert in agro
ecology providing integrated services
throughout the world including the
United States Egypt Belize Jamaica and
Mexico to assist in reducing dependency
on chemical fertilizers and pesticides
using new biotechnology and foliar
fertilizers to increase crop yields and
create sustainable systems I'd like to
welcome to the show thanks dr. Faust for
taking the time to chat with me today
and I'd love to dive right in with a
little bit of your personal history in
terms of how you came to work with humic
acids and a little more about that well
I come from Southeast Pennsylvania and
you know my family had a farm and it's
it's I grew up in the city I went to the
farm on the weekends my grandfather's
farm so I was highly influenced by being
around it I guess I just got on the
organic movement I was like one of the
first people involved in bio dynamics
and organics was me back in the 60s but
I went to the University of Delaware and
studied entomology and applied ecology
and just about every other science they
offered that was back in Vietnam days so
we wanted to stay in as long as possible
so I grew up in Wilmington Delaware
which is the chemical capital of the
world and I didn't want to go that
direction I wanted to be the alternative
to toxic technology so I started farming
while I was still in finishing college
running our family farm and started you
know be an organic grower a member of
the biodynamic Association trying to
understand biodynamic farming which of
course relies on houmous so through the
years my whole goal was to provide
alternatives to toxic technology because
I saw what damage could be done by
synthetic pesticides and herbicides and
relying on that technology you know and
which is unsustainable so at one point I
decided to move west this was in the
early 70s and I bought a small piece of
land in Montana Flathead Valley and I
wanted to improve the soil because it
was over grazed it was hard
you know I wanted to raise purebred
sheep and so I was looking for a way of
improving that soil and I noticed a
little ad in Montana farmer Stockman
magazine and it had an advertisement for
clod Buster soil softener supreme it's a
human and so I called him up this is
before the internet so yeah I did call
people and it was magazine type articles
of course I was describing organic farm
and garden magazine that influenced me a
lot but I talked to the supplier of this
so-called clod Buster humate and I'd
never heard the term humate I know what
houmous was but I didn't what Hugh made
was so they sent me a small sample maybe
a couple ounces and I set up took some
of my soil put it in pots I had a little
greenhouse and I dope and I set up test
plots with sweet corn with and without
you know putting a pinch of course we
didn't even know how much to use then
putting a good pinch on an honest four
inch pot they didn't and then planting
corn and then having control untreated
control and the results were dramatic
within two or three weeks germination
was quicker the shoot the plant itself
the corn was bigger I mean it was
outgrowing the control the root system
when you wash the soil off was extensive
I said well this stuff does something
okay so that's where it all started a
little sample overall humate
from New Mexico you started out with
essentially learning about humates from
trying out this product where did that
research take you had you already done
your doctorate at that point already
does oh no no no no no that's a long
time after I wasn't until 1986 this was
like my first experience with humates
wasn't like 73 74
and actually it got me into the next
level you know a master's in agronomy
and then a PhD in biotechnology and
agroecology so it sort of fed my
scientific curiosity because here's a
product which the university system says
nothing about never mentioned and if you
did mention it to an academic I saw wow
that's that can't work you know you're
not putting on enough per acre that it
could do anything and you know that's
snake oil
but I knew different because my eyeball
I use the scientific method here's the
experiment it's doing something so don't
tell me it isn't my eyeballs tell me and
the fact that the negativity surrounding
humans or humic substances in American
academia just stimulated me more because
I knew what it was doing and the fact
that they were suppressing that
information or actually you know
negative going negative on it made me
even more interested what's going on
here you know so I went to the next
level because I was working with with
farmers in the seed potato industry you
know I was involved in seed industry
they seed potato seed beans as an
agronomist as a advisor pest control
advisor so I had a client to grew seed
potatoes and these are very sensitive to
everything you had to produce it's got
to be disease-free certifications and
all that so we bought a truckload 20 ton
24 tons of this humate material from New
Mexico and we did test plots 20 acre
test plots 20 acres with 20 acres
without on potatoes seed potatoes okay
now what I saw right to the RO and I
still have the pictures of this which
I'm going to present at a conference
this fall American Society
Arata me and what happened there was we
had a lot of leaf damage the feeding
activity on the untreated potato plot 20
acres and then right to the row I mean
where we applied the humic acid humate
product there was little if any insect
damage at all I mean plants right next
to each other one row over no insect
averages back over to the right you know
lepidopterist defoliator holes like
Swiss cheese in these plants and then of
course the plants were more vigorous and
the treated side and they yield higher
okay so that obviously got me interested
I mean as an idealistic young guy who
wanted to provide alternatives to toxic
technology I saw something there that
was amazing I put this stuff on I don't
know what it is
and somehow the insects
it provided a level of resistance to
potatoes I mean this could be an
incredibly important thing for the
organic industry so is the pest it's
like a pest control advisors dream you
know you can put this stuff on the
ground get better growth resist insects
and get higher yield Wow
you know but nevertheless the folks
Montana State University who I knew you
know they they just discounted it oh no
you know how much you using per acre and
of course those days we were using a raw
humate product unprocessed dusty kind of
messy and we're using - 200 pounds or
more per acre - to - up to 400 pounds an
acre and so they're saying wow there's
not enough houmous organic matter in
that to do anything so based on their
limited knowledge really since they
couldn't really wrap their minds around
how it was working they just denied it
that it could do anything you know like
well there it is there's a result well
buddy
can't work because it just okay but
bottom line is I knew it did and things
just progressed you know and we were
involved in many other crops a lot of
potato crops a lot of bean seed a lot of
vegetable crops and I was growing giant
squash in Montana I bring the County
Extension agent over to look at it and
he just stand here with his mouth open
and and I said well what do you think he
says well you're growing stuff that
really you shouldn't be able to grow
here in Montana so I just got more and
more involved you know and then I moved
to a larger agricultural area a major
agriculture area where I set up a farm
services consulting program testing
organic certification and an formulation
of products an application of products
and so we started using humates in
combination on a lot of crops everything
from sugar beads to barley to potatoes
dry beans corn so a full range of crops
and at that time I started doing more
formal research and my research was in
what are the limiting factors what are
the limiting factors that hold back the
yield of crops in other words once these
crops have a genetic potential far in
excess of what you're actually seeing
done so what's holding them back and so
my research over the years has been crop
limiting factors and that was part of my
master's thesis in agronomy and you know
on beans potatoes barley things like
that common crops
okay what's holding back to you you know
so we get up to yields like 237 bushels
an acre on corn which was really big
time in those days 100 and over 120
hundred 60 bushels barley on and on and
on and I talked to older farmers that
farmed there and Twin Falls Idaho and
when it first opened up
it's irrigated flood irrigated farming
forgetting farming and they talked about
45 sack beans and now the problem was
the the bean yields have dropped to 15
sacks 10 sacks from 45 sacks and that a
good yield was 25 24 25 well what
happened to the 45 sacks that the
original farmers in that area had so
there must be a limiting factor what is
it and so over the years we found out by
leaf analysis soil analysis and trial
and error that the limiting factors were
well not only trace elements but root
growth itself the lack of root growth
and there was reasons for that part of
it was the use of the herbicides they
were using other parts was this is a
desert soil and you know that kind of
farming oxidizes the organic matter and
the organic matter gets down to below 2%
so with the experiments that we did we
found that humic substances apparently
are the limiting factor a major limiting
factor and of course since then there's
been a lot that's 40 years ago since
then working with other scientists from
around the world in doing pretty big
formal trials and tests we found that
the main limiting factor on any given
soil is activated humic substances or
human compounds and mono silicic acid so
when those substances are depleted and
organic matter of course is unstable it
oxidizes it leaches blows away the
yields come down because it's just like
when people migrated to the west they'd
move into the Midwest Ohio let's say
Indiana clear the forests and that was
hardwood like oak and birch in various
hardwood species
he's on they would clear that and then
they plant and they'd get high yield for
a few years and then the yields would be
reduced and then they'd move west so it
was a constant moving West soil mining
and West westward movement and so my
whole concept is we either figure this
thing out or you know agriculture
becomes unsustainable and it's just
relying on chemical inputs and you know
more and more disease issues and
resistance issues problems with
production you know a new spray but my
background in as a farmer my family had
been farming in Pennsylvania since 1733
and so you know we had basic grasp of
organic methods going way back you know
using compost having livestock systems
where you compost manure and put it back
on crops so you could grow corn to feed
your livestock that kind of mixed
farming scenario so we knew the value of
human compost and then the biodynamic
people tried to put some science to that
like Pfeiffer dr. Pfeiffer and Steiner
and people like that it influenced me so
we knew you know I was already kind of
sold on the idea of organics because I
kind of grew up with the Amish and
Mennonites and so the results were
obvious matter of fact my first time I
use maxi crop kelp on corn was on
suggestion of an Amish neighbor and you
just couldn't deny him they knew what
they're doing but so over the years you
know the humane thing I got more and
more deeper into it including many many
trials in greenhouses and in field crops
row crops specialty crops and tried
different deposits from around the world
okay so we found out that some of those
deposits don't do anything you know
you'd be disappointed but you didn't
know why you know how come this one
doesn't work it's got the same humic
acid content as this one let's say from
New Mexico versus Wyoming let's say or
another location within New Mexico or
Utah and as far as we knew based on the
only testing available was just for
humic acid which isn't really even a
real thing but there was adequate
differences either sometimes no results
sometimes negative results so we're
looking at a why what's the difference
here they all analyzed humic acid some
of them are higher in humic acid like 80
percent or so but didn't provide the
results on actual plant growth where
there's some of the products that were
as low as 25% humic acid had spectacular
results so there's a lot of mysteries
involved at that at that point dr. Fox
can I pause you for a second for our
listeners could you give a quick
definition of the differences between
humans humans humic and fulvic acids so
that people have an idea of what those
differences are you know well humans you
know what's gonna form under on let's
say an undisturbed forest it's under the
Duff layer you know which is sort of the
leaves and the bark and so it's a
decomposition of organic matter
specifically leaves bark twigs you know
the stuff that falls from the forest and
is decomposed by fungi okay and it's the
same as what would happen in a compost
pile you know it's a range of
microorganisms
really dominated by fungal organisms
that can
take apart cellulose and produce an
phenol and lignin lignin is a big factor
in lignans in bark twigs leaves like oak
oak as a high tannin lignin and so some
of the best soils word evoke and that's
what we see here in the Willamette
Valley - okay so you have microorganisms
breaking it down so the definition of
human is the raw undecomposed organic
matter that you'll find you know next to
the soil in the upper profile just a so
the definition I've heard for houmous is
that it's the decomposition of organic
matter to the point where under a
microscope you can't tell the difference
if that was originally a peat leaf or a
dead animal or some other remains and
that he mistakes time so it's not
something we're gonna get in a compost
pile in a period of a few months would
you agree with any of those statements
oh absolutely absolutely
because you have different levels of
humic acids see and then that's where
these different definitions are like
fulvic acid humic acid human h um i n
that's an insoluble fraction so it's one
of the only substances or chemicals
defined as a fraction so humic acid is
not a substance it's not a chemical that
you can analyze and this is humic acid
no humic acid is defined as the alkaline
soluble fraction of organic matter or
houmous and fulvic acid is defined as
the acid soluble fraction okay so these
can be separated by alkyl and extraction
and acidification and so you have the
humic is black and and gray dates in two
different shades of brown and then
fulvic oh you still there you broke up
for a second there so you said the the
humic acid is black yeah it's black or
brown it can gradate from brown and the
full the gas
it is go over yellow but here's the
story on that it's about molecular
weight the low molecular weight is the
yellow stuff the gold the fulvic
so-called fulvic acid acid soluble that
has got a low molecular weight okay so
that can be absorbed by plant roots that
can be absorbed by cells it can be
absorbed on a foliar application the
black stuff can't it's a high molecular
weight and so plants can't directly
utilize that and in fact it's got a
colloidal structure and if you put it on
too heavy it tends to plug the roots up
it globs on to the root system and kind
of plugs it up and you can get negative
effects so only the golden fulvic
fraction is actually going to be
absorbed by a cell and it really is a
cellular phenomenon so the black stuff
can be utilized by soil microorganisms
and fungi and it does have effect on
matter of fact the last paper I
published which was last year in Japan
at the iMix substance Society was the
effect of these products on soil
structure and Bach bacterial versus
fungal dominance so you can take a
burned-out soil like we have here in the
laminate Valley it's been over farmed
hardest cement or turns into muck clay
you know and when it's wet and my
experiments applying a humic and fulvic
acid to the soil in pots and in
greenhouse incubating it for different
periods of time and then looking at
sending it to local labs here that do
fungal you know do do soil food web
analysis so what we found in there is
that the controls went were totally
bacterial dominant and you know hard
pretty much unproductive and when we use
treatment so the humic substances and
then in 60 days different intervals
testing you see
that it reversed everything so the soil
went from bacterial dominant to to more
fungal dominance and that's really what
you're looking for so is that because of
the additional carbon and the chelation
that you're getting with the humic acid
molecules well that's part of it it's
actually way more complex than that you
know there's a certain amino acid for
instance another thing that we've
noticed is that and farmers would would
report this over and over and over is
once we use the humic acid products on
the soil they start to see earthworm
activity they hadn't seen in years
you see castings on the surface they'd
see earthworms when they plowed you know
and that impressed them okay so what is
it that's causing it so a small amount
of humic substances per acre it's almost
nothing two or three hundred pounds of a
a cur
with our newest products of course
they're activated concentrated and
they're effective it you know thirty
pounds I think or even ten pounds I
think but it has substances like certain
amino acids like TOC which are a
requirement for earthworms and it's got
a fair amount of complex biochemistry
that isn't totally defined okay but
there are these are requirements for
fungal fungal propagation and and so
forth in other words humic acids are
even effective at increasing mushroom
growth you know mushroom media you know
I'm not sure we're really there you know
but it's it's it's you know it's like we
didn't know what caused scurvy either
but they found out that lemon juice or
lime juice would prevent it but we
didn't know what vitamin C was at the
time so I see these humic substances as
the vitamin C scenario of modern times I
mean it's a requirement to prevent
diseases
and provide optimum growth and we know
it works just like they knew that if he
ate lime she wouldn't get scurvy but
they didn't know about vitamin C so they
are there are components in there that
we just have not we're not there yet
what the specific components are they do
that but they're there it's a cellular
your thing it's essential for for
cellular life we know that on a broader
scale humic substances are protein
acceptors and protein donors so you know
at a higher level of cellular biology
they have the ability to increase
acceptance of electrons and protons
that's been published research pretty
recent so it has a very basic effect on
some very basic properties in nature of
life and it's hard to say it's cause the
chelation or this or that it's much more
complex than that it has to do with
molecular genetics as it turns out I'm
jumping ahead 40 years now yeah let's
let's talk a little bit about that
chelation benefit just because that is
something that is most widely known
about humic substances and for those of
you that may not be familiar with the
term chelation it's really just a fancy
word for bonds with essentially the
minerals in the soil and helps you can
expand on this helps make them more
plants available well it has a buffering
effect okay so if you make a nutrient
solution and you try to make a
concentrated nutrient solution you know
you're gonna have bonding you're gonna
have like phosphate tying up with
calcium or iron you're gonna have
nutrient interactions it's hard to keep
that those elements as individual
elements in solution you're gonna
they're going to react they're going to
combine you know into an insoluble
precipitate
okay the humic substances prevent that
in other words that's sort of the
chelation effect in other words so you
take zinc zinc by itself if you add to
the soil and of course it's crucial zinc
they can tie up with iron you can tie up
with manganese you can you know excess
phosphate can tie up zinc in the root
system and you get all those problems
now that's that's that's part of the
reason the agricultural decline because
it lacks buffering substances this is
what humic substances do so you take
zinc like zinc sulfate and you combine
that with the humic substance you have
something called zinc full-volume 8c so
you've created you you've put the zinc
in an organic form you know slash
chelation chelated form in other words
it's it's part of an organic complex and
now it's not going to combine with
something else and this would allow you
to use lower concentrations of zinc
sulfate then for example oh absolutely
because otherwise you have to use a huge
amount because it ties up so fast yeah
and and so these elements are mostly in
the soil anyway but they're already
insoluble precipitate you've already
combined so use of humic substances on a
natural soil tends to reverse that so
for instance humic substances fulvic
acid are really big-time responsible for
phosphate availability in the soil and
as the organic matter is depleted the
humic acids complete it depleted
phosphate availability is reduced and so
the farmers respond by huge amounts of
phosphate because it's gonna get tied up
almost literally within days so you know
they're using high doses every year and
you can't tell them otherwise okay but
my and this is a big part of my work
and I know and in other places I'm
telling the farmers no wait a minute no
let's test the total phosphate levels in
your soil because this use of excess
phosphate is tying up zinc and now
you're having like reduced maturity
reduced growth because you're causing a
tie-up of zinc because of the excess
phosphate and when you flood your again
you're forming phosphite which is toxic
it's causing problems with the root
system okay so we'd actually test the
soil for total phosphates and because
high as 10,000 pounds an acre
I mean they've been putting putting it
on for so long you know but the soil
organic matter depleted to less than 2
percent so they weren't getting
availability and so you know we would
put humic acids on and do leaf analysis
and you're good
matter of fact in decades of me doing
this kind of work I've never seen a case
yet where the phosphate didn't come up
to optimum level without adding any
additional phosphate so it's a matter of
humic substances maintaining
availability this is particularly a
phosphate but also trace elements
well biological activity good diversity
and bioactivity help as well in dealing
with with remediation in situations like
that yeah because you know biological
activity is what's producing natural
humic substances in the soil to begin
with okay that makes sense
so when you use a human product it's
like priming the pump none other words
we put it on in the spring and the
organic matters 2% or less like 1.5
percent phosphate levels by the
availability scale would be 5 or 6 ppm
and then by fall after a human
application the organic matter
inexplicably could come up 2 percent you
know so 4 percent you know three and a
half percent and the phosphate
availability would be good the entire
growing season based on leaf analysis
petiole analysis so you had a very rapid
effect
but why how could it possibly increase
the organic matter that machi you're
talking about thousands of pounds per
acre of organic matter and you've only
used it the most let's say when we use
the raw stuff 200 pounds an acre it's
impossible okay but what's going on
there is you're stimulating root growth
you're stimulating fungal biomass
big-time so then you have a mic mycelial
mass for them in the surface okay and
then that becomes organic matter so so
that'll test as organic matter in other
words you stimulated a lot of activity
and and the fungi can break down raw
organic matter like straw
roots and dead root systems you know
plant residues and and then that soil
test will show an increase in soil
organic matter but it took that priming
the pump with the humic substances to
kick off you know that activity and of
course I'd also advise them on different
tillage methods no we're not gonna plow
deep we're not gonna plow the good
organic matter deep in the cold soil you
know organic matter humans forms on the
surface that's where a fence post rots
right on the surface that's where the
activity is so we had to change tillage
methods tilling a surface you know
keeping the organic matter what we call
managing to decay systems so that we do
get humic substances so that's pretty
much what's going on you're stimulating
oh and of course we didn't have a soil
food web analysis then like we do now so
now we can look at these things and see
what's really going on and that's what's
going on the fungal biomass increases
and just forms a mycelial mat you know
within the whole soil and forms crumb
structure because you know it tends to
form a stable crumb structure because of
the mycelium activity and sort of forms
in the soil so you go from a slimy soil
that sticks together to one that it has
a crumb structure and part of that is
the colloidal effect of the humic acid
which tends to coat the soil particle
with it so it's a it's a living layer
between the dead mineral of the soil and
the living plant root so and it also
state causes formation of crumb
structure and the soil so this this is
really crucial stuff I mean the humic
acids are humans in the soil is you know
the only difference between the earth
and the moon
okay now I studied soil formation when I
lived in Hawaii matter of fact I
developed all these products that I sell
now in Hawaii when I was working with a
range of industries in Hawaii because my
specialty was declined at that point in
my life you know I had worked as a
researcher okay why do we have macadamia
decline why do we have avocado decline
what's happening to the trees what's
going on with citrus why what's decline
systems why why do they orchards go the
other way so I looked at South formation
in Hawaii you can see everything from
fresh lava that's 2,000 degrees to 150
foot tall rainforest depending on the
age of the lava flow so how can you get
six feet of soil of what they call
histah Sol's
or organic soils form over sterile lava
rock kind of important information well
it all starts with with with sterile
rock it's pretty highly mineralized
though and then you have you begin with
lichens that start to grow on that rock
and then you get higher plants like
grasses lichens break down and and
houmous again
it's all about humic substances or humic
acid formation it's a gradual process
and as a succession progresses you know
from lichens to grasses to brush you
know and the soil layer gets deeper
thicker and then trees start to appear
and then they start dropping leaves and
bark and then you know then the soil
gets deeper and deeper you know and then
people come in cut down the rainforest
plant coffee or whatever macadamia or
whatever it is pineapple and then over
the years the soil just goes away it is
oxidized this now you're right down on
lava again basically the Hawaii and
Native Hawaiians
before Europeans knew how to handle this
they knew how to be sustainable on that
in those conditions we didn't we were
just soil miners that came in and
wrecked it but bottom line is nature can
make you know deep very rich very
balanced soil starting with sterile lava
and there's so what we're doing is we're
just speeding that process up by taking
mind mind materials yeah so that brings
up a couple questions for me we because
houmous is caused by the the composting
process or the breakdown of organic
matter if I had a compost pile and I
think every every gardener should and I
wanted to increase that decomposition
rate in terms of in terms of making my
own houmous you know that we'll have
that humic acid and fulvic acid fraction
should I be applying any of the humates
to my compost pile in addition I assume
things like aerated compost teas could
also help in increasing that biological
activity and helping speed up
decomposition it sounds like I should
use a lot of things that are high in
lignin for example you talked about
because that'll write it down into that
that humic acid fraction what what do
you recommend in terms of optimal
composting
well I've different compost achieving
that because we can go right back to
biodynamic compost preparations which
influenced me back in the 60s we didn't
know what they were but it was this
black powder you know and you added that
to your your raw materials and
composting yeah that's called the
biodynamic preparations what I have now
our product like full humic and all that
basically our modern biodynamic
preparations but you see if you compost
with deficient organic matter in other
words you're taking organic matter
whatever it may be straw or whatever it
is off of deficient soil well you're
gonna have deficient compost so I mean
you can't make a silk purse out of a
sow's ear that's what my grandfather
used to say it's pretty hard to find
like virgin materials to compost it
would have the right balance of trace
elements there's always a problem there
so we've done a lot of trials at em7 and
of course in compost tea we've done all
kinds of analysis and bike microbial
testing same thing you get the increase
in fungal biomass and then what are the
best things for compost well you know
it's kind of interesting what that is
municipal wastes in other words right
here in Oregon and in Washington you
know they're taking like leaf all the
stuff they they rake up in the city you
know all the leaves the fallen leaves
all the wood waste and stuff and then
composting it and that's got lignans
tannins you know it's oak leaves it's
hardwood broadleaf leaves and bark and
twigs
that's your best stuff now now I do
agree with you that leafmold compost is
some of the best and I love collecting
leaves and also you know all their
softwood and a combination of softwood
and hardwood woodchips but our municipal
compost up here in Washington I found is
is really not all that good because it's
one processed very very quickly in uni
the couple runs and so it's it's a lot
of time not even finished it's still hot
that bacteria is highly dominant and
still creating a lot of thermal energy
and I don't know if my neighbor or
someone down the road used you know high
levels of herbicides or pesticides on
that leaf surface that may end up in my
compost right exactly and that's true
that's very true the compost they sell
and there's we have a couple sources
here yeah it's hot it's not done it's
not finished I mean if you go back to
biodynamic theory you don't want to use
a compost until it's well rotted that's
the term they use well rotted okay now
it also you don't want to use a compost
until it's got critters in it okay so in
other words earthworms insects little
things crawling around right see so it
has to be you know go through its cycle
you know the heat and all that the act
any of my CDs and all these things and
then it goes into a fungal stage in
other words I actually grew up around
the mushroom industry in Pennsylvania
and I've been a mushroom grower so these
folks know more about composting than
anybody you know because you have to
push this compost through all these
stages to where it's a media for fungi
and that requires it's it's a lot more
elaborate than your municipal compost
for sure
and it takes time
in other words on the conventional or
let's say classic bio dynamics you might
the composting process might last two or
more years before the compost is cured
and that is contains you know little
critters running around and inside of it
I think that's a really important point
that you bring up static composting or
giving the compost time to really break
down is something that's really lacking
in I'd say 90% of commercial composts
that are available so if you want to
make your own you really have to
dedicate time to it just like you would
a fine wine or a whiskey or anything
like that absolutely and then you have
to keep aerating it because if you let
it go anaerobic there's toxins there
that roots will touch that and stop
growing if there's any clumps of
anaerobic stinky stuff I call it yeah
and then the compost should have that
good rich smell - not a rotten smell not
a soured on a septic but a rich houmous
any good Pennsylvania Dutch farmer knows
with what I mean okay
or any good farm really well I don't
know about that but yeah so these
municipal compost products they're just
the beginning stage I bring that stuff
in here i truckload and yeah and and
then I recom post it i reformulate it
pilot aerate it and you sit out here for
a year or two before i'm gonna use it
you know and i add other stuff to it
like calcium sources to balance the pH
because that's crucial I mean in other
words for the get the right fungal
activity you gotta have calcium you
gotta have the pH reasonable the high
level so they can mushroom compost you
had a lot of gypsum lime let's say and
other substances to it because we're
really trying to grow fine JA here and
so there are negative like for instance
a lot of compost and potting soils they
use bark fir bark okay this is a problem
like if you use more than ten percent
fir bark in something there are negative
effects okay this is because of the
breakdown of that bark dust and it forms
phenolic compounds and other substances
that are negative to growth and
microbial in other words it's sort of
like disinfectant and then there's all
kinds of breakdown products that are
negative 2 root growth of plant growth
so you know bark I'm talking about
softly you know pine fir and all that is
negative more negative than let's say
oak but bottom line is it needs to be
all broken down and cured and you'll
start to see fungal activity in the
compost
you know you'll notice fungal activity
especially under a microscope now you
have a stable compost and the ammonia
levels are gone they've they've the
microbial activity that is converted the
ammonia to microbial protein and then
the fungi actually it's a pretty complex
thing composting right but you can cause
yourself a lot of problems using what
they call compost which is really really
kind of isn't yeah we talked about it on
another episode that I did the idea that
a lot these potting soils have fir bark
but it's also known as forest houmous or
it has it has a bunch of names that make
it sound like it's an beneficial
ingredient but you already discussed
some of the detrimental effects that and
potential it can have in all right
products I mean they use they use bark
because they have it it's cheating they
have a lot of it yeah cheap but it but
and they use a lot more than 10% we know
that more than 10% is a problem I mean
there's there's people out here using
you know 40 50 percent I mean I see it
all the time I would never use a bark
fir bark in any of my pot I make my own
potting mix you know and it's pretty
much I'm gonna start doing it
commercially
it's gonna be sort of a real premier
brand you know it's just gonna be sold
locally but it's quite sophisticated and
we've been doing a lot of testing here
with it and it's basically re composted
municipal compost we either get from
McMinnville or south of here by
Corvallis whether it's a big composting
operation so weary compost it and we can
we we amend it and then we combine like
humic substances at a pretty high level
and then and then actually we use steel
slag which is a high source of calcium
and alyssa Cassatt and trace elements
and it's also super cheap so you're
talking about you know people are
spending too much for come for some of
these potting mixes and they're really
inferior I mean I've done a lot of tests
come growth tests comparing my simple
you know mix it's all local stuff versus
some expensive potting mixes which I
won't mention the brand names and you
know I can get about double the growth
out of it out of my mix so yeah there's
a lot of people wasting a lot of money
on some of these potting mixes big time
of course if you take a look at what
we're doing here you'd be a believer but
yeah it just goes back to real simple
biodynamic concepts in good old organic
farming and gardening magazine you know
it's just good basic stuff that you know
that farmers have been doing for
hundreds of years probably thousands of
years see so it's not like we don't have
a you know a model you know that we
don't know what's sustainable
I mean I've studied sustainable and
that's part of my PhD thesis by the way
his studying sustainability in other
words which cultures were sustainable in
terms of agriculture and how did they do
it
and I always thought people would read
really interested in this and I've given
papers on the subject like one of them
was called ancient Hawaiian Agricole
as a model for sustainability there's
some real meat in that but very very few
people were interested in that because
it seems like ancient history like no no
no you know that's all that's all hat
you know we're up to date we're mod and
we're scientific you know and so you
start talking about ancient agriculture
as a model for sustainability they've
got you know you get a lot of well
there's just not a lot of interest in
that concept but here's the here's the
bottom line on that these folks for
farming for thousands of years we've
been farming for maybe while here in
Oregon 150 the u.s. maybe 200 250 let's
say but the Native Americans that were
here before us including here in the
Willamette Valley we're farming for
thousands of years sustainably not
necessarily farming either they managed
an ecosystem for instance the Indians
here the Native Americans here in the
Willamette Valley they were managing an
ecosystem they didn't actually for him
but they were very effective and what
they were doing now the Hawaiians
actually farmed and so did the Mayans
and I've been in Belize I've studied
I've been with the Mayan Indians I know
what they do I've been in Egypt I've
been in all over the place
studying you know ancient agricultural
techniques because they did it without
chemical inputs and they did it for long
periods of time and we talk about
sustainability you know that's the goal
sustainability sustainable agriculture
blah blah blah how many years does it
have to be sustainable to be sustainable
I mean how many years are we talking
about
to qualify for sustainable you know
because we happen to know that there
were cultures that did farm sustainably
for thousands of years and we're only
you know we were only here maybe it's
the most 200 well I think we are seeing
this now I mean there's a big movement
now around Korean natural farming the
one straw revolution by Fukuoka has
become really a pillar
I met him I met him in Santa Cruz hit a
conference really oh yeah I was highly
influenced by him I set up raised beds I
tried all his techniques a mixing CD
pelleting seed scattering it all
together oh yeah you bet
yeah he was one of my examples one of my
studies was was what he was saying and I
did manage to meet him at a sustainable
AG Santa Cruz that UC Santa Cruz one
year in person
so those quite a breakthrough but again
he was you know people were skeptical of
him
you know the establishment in Japan and
yet he proved it he did it but so that's
what we need to be looking at you know
like real examples of sustainability not
just like what we think based on the
conditioning from the you know the agro
chemical industry I mean they were
saying oh you don't need compost you
don't need manure you know I just use a
chemical fertilizer you can grow one
crop after another no problem yeah
except soil turns to cement you know
it's totally not sustainable absolutely
not I mean I live around you know I see
it daily where I live and boy it's a
hard time to get these farmers to listen
to you you always get something listen
you know some that succeed
but the rest don't even want to look at
that you know because their worldview
just they're just not there
so you know we need to look more in
organic technique well you know there's
a demand right now I mean I just came
back from a few more months or two ago
to Salinas Valley right so all the big
buyers like Costco Walmart all these big
produce companies their customers are
starting to demand organic so the the
public about 86% of the buying public
would prefer organic produce
so we've we got that that is really
coming on strong so now the big players
that buy a lot of produce are starting
to demand organic production from these
big big growers like in Salinas
you know that girl lettuce and spinach
and grapes and you name it strawberries
and all that so a lot of our products is
being used down there right now and so
we're seeing a big change I've been
waiting for a long time for this believe
me a long time so we're seeing a shift
towards organic even within the Canon
well even within the cannabis industry
but you know we have quite a quite a few
people growing cannabis organically an
outside Sun grown like the Oregon's Sun
grown growers guild and people in
Washington you know Eastern Washington
and as far as I'm concerned the quality
factors are there just like an organic
produce in general flavor
you know nutrient content all that so to
me organic approach is just superior in
so many ways it's not even funny
so my thought would be that the four
people that are growing organically and
want to incorporate humic acids into
their into their application schedule
with cannabis applying humates
or humic and fulvic acids to the soil
would be a way of helping increase I
assume terpene production by helping
make some of these trace minerals more
plants available yeah and more and more
than that because the way these humic
substances work for as the fulvic acid
this really gets interesting
it has to do with transcript profiling
and the expression of genetic expression
in other words there are specific
components within the lignans tan and
poly phenyl groups that switch on
genetic pathways now this is something
we've only known in the last couple
years two or three years from German
researchers at Humboldt you
versity in berlin that I work with they
have tested my products in fact we've
tested our products in the aeroponic and
hydroponic labs at Humboldt University
of Berlin Germany and the results are
just short of spectacular but
additionally they found out that how
these products are working it's such
minut amount is that they're actually
tripping genetic pathways and they know
which genes are being tripped and these
are pathways for growth regulators
resistance pathways other pathways like
insulin like pathways on and on and on
so this is a motive act action that we
never had a clue because we don't even
have the science of molecular genetics
we didn't know about substances that
turn on switch on resistance and all
that so this is the kind of stuff that's
going on really I mean it's it's on a
cellular level you could determine it
with a single cell and so you need a
stable form of humans to do this in
other words we're back to that business
of a long term composting and curing of
the compost so that these precursor
compounds like lignans can go through
the you know the changes you know to
polyphenols specific town and specific
known components that affect genetic
expression this is new stuff big-time
big-time new stuff is not being done in
the US so if I was a cannabis grower and
I wanted to use fulvic acid in my you
know in my regimen how would I apply
that would I apply it in conjunction
with things like the seaweed extract
powder or on sulfur blackstrap molasses
or with other higher nutrient content
things like bat guano's that are soluble
or is it best applied by itself and
those having those ingredients or
nutrients already in the soil well yeah
it's best to start with a soil that has
the basic nutrients in the basic right
mouths because humic substances
provide nutrients they provide in crease
uptake nutrients because they stimulate
root growth they make the cell membrane
more permeable so the plant can absorb
more nutrients and they have effect
chelation of phosphate but you know is
it doesn't supply nutrients so to get
the optimum results and believe me the
optimum results can be enormous more
than most people imagine especially with
cannabis
you've got to have the nutrient pack get
your present see and then the humic
substances just stimulate the uptake and
in the cellular metabolism the protein
proton donor acceptor concept and all
these cell division is increased the
mitochondria are our power energized you
might say so you really gotta think
cells its cellular it's a cellular thing
okay so what's molasses gonna do well
that's just gonna turn into alcohol or
an organic acid you know in the soil
itself I mean it's just like you take
some grapes and juice them and just let
it sit out well it's going to turn into
wine because yeast are present and
they're gonna take that sugar and
they're gonna convert it to alcohol or
they're gonna convert it to vinegar
depending on what microorganism you're
involved with so you know things like
molasses and all can provide a little
bit of trace elements and it can provide
energy for for microbes but it's not
really gonna do much for a plant well
wouldn't that increase in biological
activity in turn increase your nutrient
cycling because I found on sulfur
blackstrap molasses to be one of the
best food sources our balanced food
sources for you know bacteria archaea
fungal hyphae well we know sugar sugar
is an energy source short for for
something footage
a matter of who who's an energy source
for lay friendships for fungi a better
energy source for fungi like we use in
the mushroom industry is oil vegetable
oil that's the energy source see for
fungal biomass not sugars sugars can go
you know like I say it most of the time
it's gonna be yeast that's gonna utilize
the sugars and and fast pretty rapidly
yeah but then the yeast is producing B
vitamins and that could stimulate funds
fungal biomass it's very complicated but
like in a hydroponic media you don't
need it you absolutely don't need it
like a lot of our work was done with
aeroponics where you just have the roots
it's hanging down there and a mist and
then we could just you know add the
basic nutrients as per hydroponics you
know your NPK your face element as a
control and then we'd be adding like tm7
SCYTL plus which has got kelp or the
straight fulvic acid and then then
determine the results statistically so
where are we getting our best results
just the fulvic acid because that's the
low molecular weight that's the only
fraction or part of humic substances or
gaming acid you can actually be absorbed
by the plant root so anything else can
be negative so humic substances which
are the black stuff and aeroponics or
hydroponics if used excessively can
reduce plant growth so we know basically
what works and what works is keeping the
levels of fulvic acid at about 15 parts
per million or so so and that's all the
time it's like from the time that first
that seed germinates you know we use it
for cloning too for root cloning is
terrifically quick effect on root growth
but in fact the only substance in nature
I mean natural organic they can
stimulate root growth is
click acid low-molecular-weight with the
right you know chemistry in that now
we're getting into variation between
deposits this is very important
information that you cannot generalize
about humic acids or the deposits that
they're used to formulate them we've
done tests on eight different humic acid
deposits in the US and it it's just
amazing the differences I mean some of
them will stimulate root growth but not
shoot growth some of them will stimulate
shoot growth but not root growth
some of them do nothing some of them
have a negative effect some of them or
two of them to stimulate both root
growth and growth so there is a gigantic
difference in these products and that is
really a big unknown why that was
well we've determined now the reasons
you know has pretty arcane pretty
complex chemistry
it's about functional groups like the
Russians know which are the positive
functional groups present and what are
the negatives and then they score by
subtracting the negative from the
positives and they come up with a number
like 86% bioactive and those are the
humates that are bioactive that are
effective or they're characterized by
high aroma sisty air obesity in other
words have a high level of aromatic
groups and then specific carboxylic and
phenolic compounds so this is all new
information to the humates aren't just
humates you even even within a given
mine you go a little deeper or a little
bit off the deposit and the results can
be you know you have a product it
doesn't do anything so you that's why
it's so important the brain you know who
you're dealing with the brand that
you're dealing with or or do your own
testing and again we're still back to
using corn sweet corn
I mean I started 40 years ago with sweet
corn and bottom lying all these new
tests that we're doing with bio assays
and trying to functional groups and
trying to correlate them with shoot
growth root growth and all that stuff
still comes back to sweet corn you know
the only way you can tell is by what a
plant actually does the we don't have we
can we can kind of do very expensive and
complex organic functional group
analysis and and kind of you know narrow
it down a little bit but it really comes
down to it to to actually that simple
plant test you know where I'd soak the
seed and different concentrations of
different products and you could tell
right pretty quick you know what the
root growth was because only like the
only little stimulate root growth is
folic acid like you wait if that doesn't
happen you don't have it and in fact in
our all our aeroponic and hydroponic
tests pure hydroponic pure arabic you
only need the fulvic acid there wasn't
any benefits from the tm7 from site open
there was benefit oh yeah over the
control yeah big time okay but as far as
the best results you you pretty much got
the results just from the gold stuff or
the folic acid alone and nothing else
was really good system it's a different
system than hydroponics so the the in
the soil the humic substances can
actually degrade down to phobic
substances and that's what happens in
composting over time the black stuff or
the humic further degrades you know by
fungal activity to lower molecular
weight fulvic acid so that's really why
it's so important you know the whole
idea of well rotted or aged or cured
compost because there's your time factor
that's what takes the time that
downsizing of the molecule the molecular
weight and and so you just add that
basically our product is one to two
hundred two hydroponics all the time you
keep it in there they want and through
the whole see the whole process because
we know that that is absolutely
requirement for normal cellular cellular
activity and plant growth it has to be
there all the time it's crucial it's
it's the living bridge between the dead
mineral and the living plant root you
know because basically hydroponics is
using dead you know using salt chemical
salts yeah most of our most of our
growers are gonna be growing in soil
hopefully is my goal because I think
it's a more sustainable option long-term
and we're really fortunate here in
Washington to have good compost sources
like the one that we use is a two to
three year aged fish compost which I've
been pretty happy with but before I
forget one thing I wanted to go back and
touch on oh well another thing I should
have wrote this up vermicompost in all
these trials we did with eight different
humic substances one of the the the
substances we use in these trials is
vermicompost now you could see parallels
there the vermicompost had the similar
effects to the best humates so they
personally for my own growing I have a
vermicompost bed out here you know and I
throw stuff in waste materials in there
and I had like on a crop this year I
used that vermicompost that have been
out there for six or seven years you
know in the results we have are just
fantastic so you you can make your own
humic substances you don't really need
to to buy them from me
you know earthworms are definitely play
a part in all this and vermicompost is
yeah
that that's that's a crucial factor of
course if you stimulate earthworm
activity in the soil you're gonna get
that anyway you're gonna get it so just
like I mean the whole idea of earthworms
I mean you can't you can't discount that
how crucial that all is you know then
and that's why I say once you see
earthworms in the compost then it's
ready to use it's funny that you
mentioned that because worm castings is
something they're vermicompost thing has
come up in pretty much every single one
of my podcast episodes so far everyone
wants to talk about them because of all
the benefits that they have I think
that's really important but one thing I
wanted to touch on with you before we go
any further we talked a little you
talked a little about compost teas and
one of the things that I found so I did
some experiments using humic acids and
in compost teas where I had a control
using compost and distilled water and
then I added some of these humic
substances I tried I tried your tm7
and then I tried some of the products
from Terra Vita if you're familiar with
them they're SP 85 and they're L C 10
plus 7 which is sort of a liquid chelate
version of the TM 7 and what I found was
I had I had a tough top the control
actually had higher microbial activity
than the ones that I added the humic
substances to and I don't know if you
remembered but I was talking about this
one said Kanak on in a presentation and
you came out to me afterwards and said
something along the lines of yeah that
didn't really those results didn't
really surprise me but now in this talk
you're saying that the tm7 you found
increases microbial activity and T's and
I'm just curious what your what your
thoughts are on it I guess well it's
about concentrations in other words tm7
in a solution is alkaline so it can have
as it stands you know
and in its format you get it and it's
got a pH of over 10 C because it's an
alkaline form of humic substances so
that can affect you know an important
factor in in that culture in other words
the pH you're increasing the salts right
people tend to overdo it these things
are effective in other words we don't
recommend a solution any stronger than
what's looks like iced tea okay so
that's like one gram per gallon
you see so so what it's not so much how
much you use but what the concentration
is C so you're in the neighborhood of
about up to 3 grams per gallon and so
you know it's not black it's not you
know in other words these substances can
take things to two different way in
other words a lot of the German work now
on these humic substances is is has to
do with well you know health benefits
longevity effects and all that okay it
they use the term core basis okay so
humic substances are a poison at one at
one level and a tonic in another that's
the concept before mesas that the stress
provided from a small amount of a poison
stimulates a lot of things I so so don't
disagree with you I just think that from
my experience and then yeah you're gonna
see a decrease in bacterial activity
that's exactly what we showed in the
tests I did last summer in the
greenhouse with soils absolutely we
start out with the control and controls
versus and in the bacterial levels drop
way down and the fungal that will go
away up so yeah I mean that's what
you're looking for you want the
bacterial activity to be reduced they're
not reduced you just want to see fungal
activity is dominant because bacteria
can't take apart cellulose or anything
like that they don't really have much of
a chelating effect or anything it's all
about
yeah and the metabolites produced by
fungi and their ability to digest
organic matter whereas bacteria don't
can't they need the help of fungi first
you know they can take sugars sure you
know bacteria can directly utilize
sugars fungi can produce sugars from
carbohydrates from you know lignans and
carbohydrates and just cellulose as far
as that goes you know the right fungi
can produce sugars from cellulose so you
know yeah I mean you're gonna notice a
decrease decrease in bacterial activity
I guess I didn't see that increase in
fungal activity though either at least
in the t's themselves now I'm not
suggesting that humic acids or human
quemic products don't have a ton of
benefits like you've said like you've
already mentioned in this talk I've just
found personally I've had better success
applying them separate from my compost
teas in well it could be there's a lot
of things that can be going on there you
know it's kind of complex how that could
go down you know depending on what raw
materials you're using just the whole
range of things whole range of issues it
just gets very complex and then really
and until you put that compost tea on
the soil and then a whole bunch of other
things are going to happen once it's
added to the soil and and you know
changes actually you know what you're
talking about
humic substances or organic matter and
soil microbial activity that's the most
complex chemistry in nature it's
extremely complex you know that in humic
acid or so-called humic acid this is
recent researchers just a paper
published last fall using the four tier
exchange electrospray you know some new
technique of determining you know
particular compounds in something okay
so there's over 800 different compounds
identified within I mean
let's say dots on the electrospray graph
I mean we don't know which what their
names are
you know they fall within you know
polyphenols and phenols and with you
know carboxylic sand all that but you
know there can be as actually as many as
8,000 different compounds so it's
extremely complex so you know when
you're talking about a humidor fulvic
acid you're not talking about a specific
substance at all
you're talking about a fraction an
acidic fraction that may have several
thousand different compounds you know
because you know all the things that are
claimed all the benefits for humic acid
fulvic acid how can one compound do all
that well it can't you know you have
substances there that are key lehder you
have some that are micro antimicrobial
you have some that that did stimulate
different genetic pathways we're just
you know we're just at the beginnings of
this but we know there's thousands of in
see what they used to for years I used
to try to determine what is the formula
the molecular diagram for humic acid or
fulvic acid they spent years trying to
figure that one out and now they're down
to no no no no no it's it's that's not
it it's it's actually a soup and it
varies tremendously so there's thousands
of individual compounds so to be able to
say that this thing did that or this
thing did that I mean it's a level of
complexity that is just overwhelming
you know that's why we stick to like in
hydroponics just the fulvic acid because
that's the low molecular weight that's
absorbed by plants that's not going to
interfere with anything else it's a key
later in itself you start throwing humic
acid in there the black stuff well
that can combine with other things it
can have an a that can have methylene
groups
that's stuff that's associated with oil
and coal methylene that's toxic okay and
this varies so you know you you're not
necessarily sure what's going on here
see and so that's why I say okay the the
part that has the bang the biggest bang
for the buck is is the so-called phobic
fraction which is our product called
full power so and we have the first
label on the west coast and here in
Oregon they finally allowed us to call
it folic acid because a new test method
has been developed and approved by some
different regulatory bodies and now
accepted by Oregon Department of Ag and
you know hopefully the rest of the
states will follow suit so we can
actually even define is only in the last
year we could actually define fulvic
acid let alone all the goodies that it
has in it so we're the only one that's
been able to do that actually get a
label you know actually get through all
the testing requirements you know heavy
metals all the things that they require
to register and as do with molecular
weights and all that kind of stuff so
when you start getting into something
that has 8,000 as many as 8,000
different compounds in it that vary
tremendously it's hard to predict what's
gonna happen exactly you know and then
concentrations are crucial like I say
it's toxic at one level and beneficial
at another level well my hope is that
people that listen to this podcast will
take away that if they're growing in
hydroponics they should just try the
fulvic acid if they're using soil like
most of us are they can also incorporate
humid city mates and humic acids they
can make their own by
managing their own compost pile and
taking care of their soil and hopefully
realize that they need to try
high-quality products and brands like
yours for example they're not just
sourcing these things on eBay because
they're not going to contain the same
constituents and properties and then
lastly that we're just really fortunate
to be in an industry where there's so
much left to learn and everyone should
be doing their own trials and and
scientific method to find out what works
best for them with their soils so yeah I
mean this isn't a guessing game you know
I see a lot of people try to grow that
way you know they all I think it needs a
little amino acids today I think it
needs all of this you know like what you
think is meaningless
you know it's what the plant wants it
counts you know and that's why you have
to look at control you know okay let's
try this on the control versus a
treatment see see what's really
happening you know I mean all this fancy
science we've got now you know it's it's
developing I mean we're not there yet
okay but it still comes back to like
getting some seeds and soaking them in
the stuff and seeing how quick they
germinate I mean we did stuff here with
Oregon State University seed lab okay so
where we just take fescue seed treated
at different rates of fulvic acid and
then and then then they they run it ok
what's the speed of germination okay so
it 1 to 1,000 dilution of full power we
get statistically significant increases
in seed germination ok well that's
definitive fulvic acid so I mean you can
literally just soak some seeds in a one
to one hundred one to one thousand and
if you don't see any difference between
the control and the treatment well then
you don't have anything and and that can
be just take a week or so let's say so
you know you let the plant tell you the
plant needs to tell us we can't really
tell the plant what it needs it tells us
what it needs you know and so reading
the plant the color the bigger
their root development like for instance
without using humic substances or fulvic
acid the root system is what I call
stringy
it's a stringy root system that's the
morphology it's just stringy okay so and
you use the folic acid real fulvic acid
the morphology of the root is fibrous a
lot of root hair development and it's
dramatic okay so you can do your own
trials and just you know wash the roots
off you know use a potting mix it
doesn't have humic substances you know
like pro mix or something like that
something's inert pretty much and and
you know you either gonna have it or
you're not I mean it's either gonna if
you have a stringy root system well I'm
sorry you know because the real thing is
going to give you a fibrous very very
dramatically fibrous root system and
then of course the chute growth will be
better
most people just notice that they don't
really good but you need to wash the
roots off take a look at that but you
know that's that's still the bottom line
on how to determine whether these things
are effective or you can take it to the
lab with that idea of the soil food web
analysis and take a look at that but
when you add humic substances the black
stuff you know well what we call full
humic full humic is a soluble powder
that has the whole range it has the
fulvic the humic avec Olmec all the
various humic substances and minerals
nothing's been removed see these other
products they'll just dissolve it an
alkali and then settle it and then and
then you know you get you just get this
that one humic fraction but our product
yep nothing has been removed okay
so it's the full spectrum okay so that's
what the soil needs because the various
microbes can utilize that they can you
know start to break down organic matter
and form more
substances forms a colloid that affects
soil structure
the biggest most important part of what
humic does that's the black stuff is
soil structure super-important it's the
difference between a brick and friable
soil so I mean that's not an issue that
it's an issue in hydroponics obviously
so but it's crucial in any kind of other
you know growing activity in soils
because once the structure is gone it's
time to go to town and get a job you
know you've got cement limit valley is a
good example of that but so these
substances have a range of benefits you
know in soil structures in other words
the first humeid I used was called clod
buster
soil softener supreme that's that's
their logo soil softener supreme and we
didn't know how it did that and now we
saw our product called full humic s-- we
sell it to municipal use like sports
turf like these football fields golf
courses some of the big universities
here use it on their you know football
fields and and the guys are saying wow
yeah the ground softer you know when we
fall you know it's we're not bouncing
you know the ground this is softened and
all that so you really want to think
about that you know is the the humic
feeds the soil the fulvic feeds the
plant well I I really appreciate that
and I want to thank you again for your
time today I think we covered quite a
bit and I'm hoping people will go out
and and try using some of these humic
substances in their gardens and see what
sort of effects they get well yeah I
mean it's it's almost a formula that
that's gonna work every time you know
assuming you know but the important part
is to stick to the label and that more
isn't better you know I mean that's the
problem farmers may have you know they
see a result and they
more is better not in this case more
ain't better there there is a curve
we've developed that curve we know what
rates what concentrations will get us
you know to where we want to be and then
we know that it'll reach a point where
you don't get any more benefit and it
plateaus off and then you use more and
more and more it starts to go on the
other way so you know it's almost
homeopathic yeah because you're talking
about things that affect cellular you
know response molecular genetics does
not require you know more is not better
it's not like like adding nitrogen or
something where you just get more and
more growth you know and I learned from
Jamaicans I also studied in Jamaica
because there is a pretty good example
of sustainable AG some of those folks in
the cockpit country that real Rasta
people they're very you know they're
they're particularly effective but they
consider on cannabis okay on ganja they
consider chemical fertilizer okay this
is this is a quote makes the plant mad
see so you ask them what's the best you
got what's the best stuff you got coach
[__] that's actually a term for
high-grade cannabis in Jamaica goat [__]
because the highest quality cannabis is
grown using goat manure or or bat ratbat
you know bat guano
now use chemical fertilizer it makes the
plant mad which they mean it makes it
you know a lot of top growth I mean
vigorous you know male energy right and
so you just get a leggy tall plant but
it doesn't give you what you're trying
to get you know so that's learning from
people that have been doing this for
quite a few years and that's something
to think about you know if you're
considering using chemical fertilizer it
just makes the plant mad you know and
you want to use
organic methods you know plants only
need a little bite everyday you know
it's two uses some of these hydro
formulas and some of this stuff people
are doing with commercial fertilizers is
like feeding a man all he can eat on
Sunday and then then then then he
doesn't get anything to eat till next
Sunday when it was really they just need
a little bite every day that's the key
that was dr. Robert Foster bio egg their
company's website is WWII AG com don't
forget to use the coupon code humate
that's hu ma te for 10% off all humic
acid products for a short time following
the release of this podcast you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey stay tuned for more episodes
where we discuss exciting new concepts
and interview some of the top experts in
our industry thanks for listening