[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge this
week's podcast is with plant pathologist
Chris Hayes Chris began his journey into
biological while working on his PhD then
continued in the field while scientist
at Cornell University at Cornell he
worked on the strains of Trichoderma T
22 and G 41 that would ultimately become
the active ingredients in Richfield plus
he left Cornell approximately 25 years
ago to help start Bioworks
for the past quarter century he has
worked at various areas within Bioworks
with the ultimate goal of helping those
interested in using biologicals to
understand the do's and don'ts to
maximize the effectiveness of
biologicals and programs to help prevent
plant sickness and loss now on to the
podcast hey Chris thanks for coming on
the show today thank you for having me
tad yeah Chris can we start off talking
a little bit about your background and
let people know kind of who you are and
then go from there I sure can hello
everyone out there my name is dr. Chris
Hayes and I hail from the farmlands of
central Illinois and always had an
interest growing up looking at
alternatives to using synthetic
chemistry's to try to grow healthy
plants and I pursued that that idea in
both undergraduate and graduate school
and when I was graduating with my PhD
from West Virginia University last
century I was looking into pursuing the
idea of alternatives to synthetic to
protect plants and so I accepted a
postdoc at the New York State
Agricultural Experiment Station which is
governed by Cornell University so I
to work at Cornell University in upstate
New York in their field areas working
with different microbes mostly fungi
that attack hosts to see if they had
applicability to commercial agriculture
and so again back last century in the
late 80s to mid 90s I worked at Cornell
in the area of biological control and we
developed some pretty interesting
microbes that a decision was made back
in the mid 90s to leave Cornell and help
start a company that we now call today
bio work so got about 25 plus years of
experience actually out there promoting
and placing biologicals into commercial
horticulture agriculture and now the
medicinal plant market yeah I'm very
familiar with your company we actually a
lot of the growers that we work with are
using a lot of your products I think you
guys do a great job and I want to circle
back to some of the products that might
be best for for cannabis here in a
little bit but before we do I kind of
wanted to talk a little bit about
trichoderma and mycorrhizal fungus and I
know that one of the things that you and
I talked about off air last week was
just best practices and some of the the
differentiation between different
strains of Trichoderma so could you just
kind of talk about what is Trichoderma
and what is what are some of the best
practices from an agricultural
perspective Trichoderma is is a genus
filamentous fungi
found in the soil that has evolved for a
purpose of suppressing or possibly
protecting plants against pathogens and
all 12 more upon that in just a few
minutes but user filamentous fungi that
are found in just about all types from
around the world and their role is to do
one of various functions within the soil
some of them may just
grow throughout the soil taking up space
others may grow throughout the soil
producing metabolites that may be both
beneficial or harmful to both the plants
and other microbes in the soil still
they're very diverse these these tractor
dimmers there
the name Trichoderma is very familiar in
the growing of plants because there's
been a lot of publications for a number
of decades on track and Irma's and
they've been isolated from suppress the
soil soils that seem to have suppression
certain pathogens scientists have went
out and dug up different strains of
track and urban different species and
have been able to identify some that you
know have the ability to help plants not
hurt them so what I'm hearing from you
is that when we're talking about
trichoderma it's it's a numerous species
of fungi and so we actually have to be
very specific when we're looking at a
particular product or talking about a
particular trichoderma and I know I know
one product you guys carry is called
root shield can you talk a little bit
about how that product came about and
what that particular strain is is it is
it strain or species with fungus I've
always thought of it as a species but I
want to make sure I'm using the right
nomenclature
try to dermis brains Trichoderma strains
are like different family members some
are really strong and good and some can
be a little bit naughty so depends upon
the strain of praça derma how strong or
how weak or what they can do of any
value or have no value at all because
the the group the genus Trichoderma
they're known for their abilities to be
found in soils around the world and
they're workhorses out in the soil but
again sometimes they do good things and
sometimes not so good so if they are
very strain dependent and we took that
concept to heart at Cornell University
when we obtained a grant we were looking
at can you produce a hybrid strain of
attractive derma that may be able to be
used as a bio control agent in a
commercial agricultural use so with this
grant at Cornell and the lab of dr.
ferry Harman hybridization studies were
conducted now these are asexual fungi so
protoplast fusion was used to mimic what
happens out in nature to produce genetic
variability and so strains were selected
from various areas in the US where
disease suppressive soils have been
identified and what I mean by that is
farmers report record yields high yields
in their soils but their neighbor across
the street using the same inputs the
same genetics inputs having the same
basic soil profile did not have the same
success and scientists will go out and
collect samples from these different
soil types and try to identify something
that may be unique in these suppressive
soils and that was done and a couple of
different strains were identified from
suppressive soils hybrids were made
using a process called proto Pass fusion
and then time was spent to look at these
different hybrid strains to see if uh
the superior hybrid could be identified
that may have commercial attributes
so that's where the field came from the
the t22 strain that you yea manufacture
yeah that the actual numbered p22 of the
strain its string number is called 12
19-22
strain 12 was in red line was was fused
to string 95 and many many different
hybrids were isolated dozens and dozens
and dozens over a hundred and it was the
22nd hybrid so isolated to the
microscope when we took it for further
testing had the bear the greatest
attributes to attack the greatest range
of pathogens it would grow on the entire
root system it would grow in soil pH
soil temperature soil moistures that
were highly variable so this strain had
attributes that made it pretty strong
out there in the environment against a
range of issues in a variety of
environments and because the parents
were chosen from suppressive soils were
synthetics were used the strain had a
high degree of compatibility many
chemical fungus I didn't develop
resistance and so this is the original
strain or active ingredient in our
product root shield but being scientists
you always look for what else is out
there that can help being businessmen
you you always want to have something
interesting to talk about you always
want to try to improve your products to
offer more efficacy to the farmers and
the growers out there in the real world
and so we had some single line isolate
strains that were pretty strong and had
attributes in excess of what the hybrid
strain t22 had one of these strains was
classified as g41 it was attractive
derma viren's and it had the ability to
grow in very wet soils and it like to
attack pathogens found in the group on
the oh oh my seats including pet diamond
Phytophthora and downy mildew so visa
that this other strain was mixed with
the t20
two hybrid strategy 41 strain and we
introduced a product a couple years ago
called root shield plus the name root
shield was pretty good the name root
chill plus we thought we'd keep it so
you now have two different strains in
the same package and and and they
complement each other and in fact we
were granted a patent on the synergy
between these two strings which means
they act better together than either one
would alone they're a heck of a couple
yeah so you mentioned some effects
against oh my SETI's which I'm not great
at pronouncing either what are some of
the attributes of these particular
strains in terms of the root shield Plus
that people in cannabis may see benefit
from you mentioned downy mildew for
example and I want to talk about the
mildews later in the podcast what are
just some some general attributes
associated that you found from these
particular strains well these strains
are what we call rhizosphere Raizel
plane competent they like to grow not
just in the soil not just near the roots
but they grab onto the roots and
actually coil around them most
importantly root hairs so when we use
the name root shield we're truly talking
about shielding the roots blocking
entrance in the root tissue by pathogens
so that's one of their strong attributes
they cling on very tightly and so you
know if you're growing clones either
from cuttings or seeds you know you want
to protect that newly emerging root
tissue and these trichotomous found the
roots your plus will do that we have a
wet amol powder you can drench with we
have a granular you can incorporate or
even topdressing water down because they
grow so these are little microbes fungi
that will colonize and protect that root
and that's a pretty good thing shielding
it in addition these fungi produce
enzymes
the the t22 string produces an abundance
of what we call chitin aces and many of
your fungal pathogens that try to attack
the roots contain chitin as a sugar
moiety in the cell wall other pathogens
do not contain as much chitin in the
cell wall they contain a sugar moiety
called a glue can and I don't want to
bore your audience with the chemical
structures but they're close but a
little bit different a little different
spin on a glucose molecule and this glue
can we have that additional strain the
g-41 that produces an abundance of glue
kinases so it attacks different
pathogens by dissolving the cell wall
and feeding on it than the t22 string so
together they produce these enzymes
these chitin aces and glue kinases that
will attack the sugar moieties and most
fungal cell wall so these these tractor
nerman is not just cling to the roots
but they'll actually attack pathogens
that get near the roots and stop them
from entering root tissue and in fact we
have seen studies on fungi that produced
survival structures called sclerotia
Sclerotinia is one and our friend
powdery mildew produces sclerotia and
these these excuse me boat rightists
produces sclerotia my point is these
fungal pathogens produce survival
structures in the soil that allow them
to hide from synthetic chemistry's with
the tract of dermis can sense where they
are they'll grow to them rapid random
and start to digest and feed upon him
so these Trichoderma fennel root co+ can
can lower pathogen levels in the soil
and that can be advantageous because if
you attack pathogens especially are
those that may grow out of the soil and
attack the foliage if you suppress them
in the ground you'll have less potential
when they surface out of the ground to
possibly attack the foliage and flower
buds yeah now in a healthy ecosystem are
you seeing persistence with these
Trichoderma extreme Trichoderma strains
are they lasting or is this something
that needs to be applied on a fairly
regular schedule if you're doing
intensive cropping like you would be
with cannabis well I know out there
people listening would love to have
something that lasts forever but the EPA
says that's a no-no we mean we don't
want to you to release something that's
invasive that will take over so what we
see with our tract determines is that no
colonize the root tissue and a
protective level for 8 up to 12 weeks
depending upon the organic level of the
growing media organic levels tend to
encourage these praça dermis to persist
but after 12 weeks we see these levels
begin to drop in by 16 weeks there's no
appreciable protection with these
strings of trichoderma found in root
shield Plus so it doesn't last forever
and the other interesting point is that
they have compatibility we know with
mycorrhizae dolly back in the 1980s late
1980s and early 1990s we were doing work
with the USDA dr. Bob Lumsden who was
able to show that our strains attracted
Burma had no negative effect or little
or no negative effect on micro raisa and
dr. Mary house back from Michigan State
University also published it saw less
than a 10 percent or about a 10%
reduction in micro Rosie concentration
when I'm using these strains of private
area which is not significant so we
don't always know why they're compatible
but when we place them together they
they seem to not have a negative effect
on each other so that's a good thing but
I like to say that doesn't hold for all
the different strains and all the
different species of crocodilian that
may be offered to you out there like I
said a lot of these strains may produce
metabolites that are have a negative
effect on plants or may have a negative
effect on mycorrhizae that's why some
people say you can mix trichoderma
mycorrhizae the others say I don't know
others say you can't it depends on the
strain and that's very important to
understand not all strains
tracted Irma are the same not all humans
are the same so it's important to
understand the strain and ask the
questions
hey company do you know what your
strains are compatible with I'm glad you
highlighted that because this is
something that you and I talked about
last week as well off air and for me one
of the challenges I see is I see these
commercial products and you know I know
here's one that I'm just looking at the
label it has 83 propagules per gram of
Glomus and Terada sees it Globus ma CA
and then 313 313131 spam of trichoderma
so you have a preponderance of
trichoderma in there at concentrations
you know exponentially higher than the
amount of micro rise in the product you
know even though the product is marketed
as a mycorrhizal product and you know
the company claims that these things
play nice together
but we don't really know you know it's
an end user without seeing a lot of
research to support it so I just want to
caution listeners to do their homework
and realize too what's on the label
isn't always what's actually in the
product - that's a whole nother
challenge that we're finding the Oregon
Department of Agriculture has been
testing a lot of products and finding
that with microbials you don't always
get what you think you're getting when
we're talking across the board here but
you know I have I have tried routes
yield before I think I think you guys do
a great job with your products how does
that work in terms of shelf life with
the root shield and root shield Plus are
people able to walk into a store
purchase it I know I ordered online and
had it shipped directly from you guys to
me and this was this is quite a few
years back but how does how to shelf
life and those sorts of things stability
come into play with a microbial product
like this well just to make sure
everybody can find this information on
their own please check out our website
WWE have compatibility information shelf
life and storage information
if you want to treat ten plants or
10,000 acres we have small volume and
large volume calculations for you we
have a very high quality expertise staff
so ask the expert area on our websites
and then your questions give us a call
we have a lot of PhDs we have under plus
years of expertise and experience with
some of the people we have on our
technical services and our biological
program managers along with our people
like myself are biological solutions
advisors we we throw a team effort of
trying to give you an answer but to
answer your question quickly you know
with our products it's temperature
dependent most Trichoderma today are
temperature dependent so if you stored
at room temperature you can get six
months in the refrigerator
you'll get longer in the freezer it
stores even longer so we have a shelf
life table based upon temperature can
you walk into a store and buy our
products there is a chance you can
however we typically try to direct
people through our distribution channel
and again on our homepage
if you click at the top or if you go to
the top there's a button where to buy
into the state enter the country because
we're in multiple countries and you will
see a listing of our distributors and a
way to contact them so we try to do it
that way we do have a retail site we
have a couple of retail outlets
Johnny's Lexi's barbacoa and others that
you can order from so we try to make it
easy to get it from you or get it from
us to get it to you we try to give you
shelf-life information tables that you
can print off they're all PDFs we've got
compatibility with other biologicals
fertilizers agilent's and other
synthetic inputs I mean here are fungi
that you would expect not to be able to
be mixed with chemical fungicides but
they can be there's many you can because
the premise behind biologicals roots
you'll + and anything else is you want
to prevent you don't want to try to cure
and in cannabis and him your toolboxes
are limited and what you have available
and so you want to prevent and not have
to go to that tool box for a hammer
because you don't have a lot of hammers
but prevent and not only preventive from
a root protective aspect or prevented it
from a foliar aspect you know things can
get out of hand real fast above the
ground and if you don't have some
preventative out there you're gonna lose
some plants
you're gonna lose some flowers that's a
good segue into the next part of our
conversation but before we do I had one
last question about Trichoderma
specifically the ones that you are
offering do those have offer any
assistance in regards to the microbial
loop or nutrient cycling
in terms of plant health or plant growth
beyond the disease resistance potential
how much time you got to that oh we
published a paper at a station called
solubalization and sequestration of
inorganic nutrients by trichoderma
strength e22 don't ask me to say to you
and they answer your question not just
hat just yes but heck yes these are try
consumers have the ability to solubilize
insoluble nutrients we would take
culture filtrate from strain teen 22 we
put rock phosphate in it put it on a
shaker over and I come back in the next
day and it was gone somebody stole the
rock no they didn't it was dissolved
because our track of nervous retreat
produced reducing agent chelating agents
they're part of the recycling of food
back to the root tissue in addition and
this is a published paper in addition
another paper was published out of the
lab up from a scientist visiting from
Taiwan again last century and they were
able to show that utilizing our
attractive derma strings as a soil
drench that they could inhibit viral
uptake by the plant tissue I got a paper
in front of me right now I'm taking a
look at called practicer my heart
t22 induces induces systemic resistance
in tomato infected by cucumber mosaic
virus we're seeing these tract of dermis
can turn on what's called induced
systemic resistance within that plant it
helps produce things like phyto alexinnz
which are the antibodies of a plant it's
quite fascinating in fact we did a study
again a while ago at Texas A&amp;M on cotton
seedlings out of the strings and with
t22 we saw a tenfold increase in phyto
Alexan production in the roots and again
the plight of alexinnz are one of your
plant hormones that are produced as a
response to a problem in infection there
the so called antibodies in a plant they
move from the roots up and so to answer
your question yes we there's a lot of
publications on this I if you would just
a search solubilization or or michael
parasitism or induced systemic
resistance and t22 you're going to see a
lot of papers popping out
so there's a lot of publications we try
to make sure that we have data support
what we say that's that's great that's I
love that I'm gonna put some links up on
the podcast page to your website as well
as some of the publicly available papers
you and I can talk about that after the
podcast and we can put some of those up
and then I'm excited to put you in touch
with dr. Ben Higgins to it and start
maybe doing some research on cannabis
here with some of these things because I
think that's really exciting what you
guys are doing - Jenna head we I've been
talking to scientists around the country
we want to set up studies to see how
metabolite production is enhanced
reduced altered using our inputs out we
look forward to having that data we look
forward to those studies so please
anybody out there we want to work and
have data we we've strive for many many
decades to offer information so you
you're not guessing you're using facts
and figures to guide your programs
yeah that's I totally agree with you on
that I think that's wonderful what you
guys are doing
you had mentioned some of the
above-ground challenges which was
something that I was really looking
forward to talking about with your
background in pathology so one of the
big challenges in cannabis is powdery
mildew can you talk a little about a bit
about what it is how it relates to
cannabis and how we might be able to
better treat and prevent it well Padme
mildews uh it's tough I mean in a tax
cannabis powdery mildew is just a
general name for many many different
genera that are included in the grouping
powdery mildew thirty-plus and they're
finding more all the time so it's a
pretty broad spectrum it typically
occurs on the upper leaf surface as a
white powdery kind of - little hairs and
and so it's it's unique in that it's an
obligate parasite so it likes living
tissue to grow and develop it it's
unusual in that it doesn't require free
moisture to germinate you know things
like Bo try this the free moisture -
thank you go crazy quickly this thing
doesn't need free moisture you can
actually pull moisture out of
atmospheric water we actually call
humidity so it can get out of hand
it likes to thrive between temperatures
of 60 to 72 if you can raise the
temperature in your greenhouse or your
atmospheric control unit to about 75 it
just doesn't thrive real well it's
interesting in that powdery mildew needs
an open wound or a cut or a stoma -
inner leaf tissue it differs them you
know botrytis and downy in that they'll
make enzymes and dissolve their way
through the cuticle and the epidermis of
the leaf tissue powdery mildew really
doesn't do that so you know you can use
certain products certain contact kill or
certain hammers
and some people will even say that's a
curative effect well powdery doesn't
enter quickly so I don't know if its
curative you just happen to whack it
before it got into plant tissue so it's
a it's an interesting fungal problem to
control it yeah just get the humidity
down get it down to 45 percent if you
can I know that's pretty low but that
really discourages powdery mildew that
or get the temperature in your
greenhouse around 75 to discourage it
you know with any pathogen out there tad
that may harm a plant it's always good
to find the best genetics available and
I know there's a bunch of work being
done in cannabis on genetics because
resistant varieties you know that's that
there's nothing that coating resistant
but more if you can lower pressure
significantly than some of your contacts
and biologicals may be all you'll ever
need to keep things from getting
seriously out of hand if you use them
preventative ly so it is a very common
problem powdery mildew I mean Dolly the
multiple generate can probably attack
over 1500 different types of plants so
it's a very common problem so I've a few
questions here let's start with the do I
need to worry about my the powdery
mildew on my comfrey or the powdery
mildew on my squash infecting my
cannabis plant in my garden if I was say
in a greenhouse or outdoors or is there
is there a specific species or strain
that's affecting cannabis that's that's
different than what we're seeing on
these other vegetables or other crops or
do you know well sometimes they can jump
from one crop to the other it just
depends upon the strain of the of the
pathogen you know some of these
pathogens are more crop specific some of
them aren't so it's always best if you
if you got other plants in there with
this powdery mildew it may not be a bad
idea that the tree
those plants but again it just it just
depends so what I see you know as
someone who grows a fair number of
vegetables with my squash and stuff when
I start getting the colder nights I'll
get like I'll have like a really hot
sunny day and then the next day it'll
it'll rain or I'll have a really cold
night some sort of water event and then
I'll start seeing powdered mildew a day
or two later popping up and the spore
pressure just seems to get really high
and I can spray that that pumpkin plant
or squash plant with an oil-based
solution that will you know kill that
powdery mildew but it doesn't it seems
to just keep coming right back you know
four or five days later
I've got powdery mildew again and with
cannabis I know you can't you can't
spray a lot of stuff and flower I want
to talk a little more about the humidity
and temperature thing but what are your
thoughts in terms of treatments so when
we're contact killing powdery mildew is
it because of the spore pressure and the
air that we're just seeing we're seeing
more pop-up like do we need to control
that or is the plant just damaged at
that point it has easy access and it's
just gonna keep coming back once we've
seen it on a plant does that make sense
pathogens pathogens are like the IRS
they never go away
they're always out there they're always
wanting to do something it just takes
the right environmental trigger to turn
them on and powdery mildews can survive
up to three years in plant debris so you
know they they they have persistence
others can survive for decades but other
pathogens but battery mildew can survive
in overwinter plant debris and survive a
couple of winters up to three years in
plant debris so it's always out there
it's good to use as you said some of
these contact hammers especially when
the environment as you described starts
to favor the occurrence because you know
under certain environmental conditions
and triggers a couple of days later it's
happening so
that trigger hits let's get out to
prevent it as you mentioned oils oils
are a great contact we have an oil I
will mention it it's called self oil ex
the only reason I mention it that if
you've ever used an oil that looks like
milk that self Oil X it's an emulsified
oil to give it charge so it will react
with water and it has some attributes
from that aspect but other things you
can use besides oils for these foliar
pathogens or soaps soaps can be
effective but be careful
they can weaken the cuticle and do other
things and then you have we have a salt
based chemistry called Mill stop it's a
potassium bicarbonate that will defecate
and not allow fungal spores to either
germinate or grow very well because of
the desiccation properties and also the
pH alteration properties of this product
you know I've also done some experience
with there's an enzyme in milk raw milk
apparently too that has some efficacy I
know that there's some specific
biological fungicides as well you know
products like actinovate but I haven't
had amazing success with like
streptomyces and some of those other
ones
personally I don't want to say that they
don't work but for me a lot of these
other applications well the milk
shoot it dries and it looks like powdery
mildew on your leaf surface which to me
was it that was a deal-breaker but the
oh the the streptomyces I felt like I
had to apply it like every few days like
I wasn't getting very strong suppression
personally and this is anecdotal purely
anecdotal in my experience the oils all
worked really well I haven't done
anything with potassium bicarbonate but
at the end of the day I find I'm still
it's nothing completely wipes it out
once I see it on a plant I feel like I'm
battling it until I crop have you had
any success or any other experience with
people having
or success with that and then if we're
cloning that plant what are the risks
associated with besides let's just say
being a weak genetic line or poorly
resistant to powdery mildew are there
any other risks of Rhian occu lating it
or bringing it back into our into our
controlled environment yes there's
always risks when you take that's why on
your mother plants you should do your
best people sometimes think our mom's
fine I don't need to worry about her
well mom needs to be taken care of too
and so you know before taking settings
that encourage people to put some some
one of these products down you know salt
soaps oils and you mentioned
streptomyces dad have you ever made use
of products that contain a bacillus
different species but Leppa sila
subtilis these bacteria had have you
ever used a bacillus before I have there
was one I got from beasts from Wilbur
Ellis back in the day and I'm trying to
remember the name of it the commercial
name maybe it'll come to me while we're
all shouting oh that was bacillus I'm a
little liquify seeing or what heck
anyway I milk that product I'm trying to
remember - sorry we're both having a I'm
having a senior moment you're just but
and and what I like to talk about is and
I'll make mention now is I like that the
hammer residual concept I like to mix
these salt soaps and oils with a
biological that may have some residual
activity based upon its mechanism of
action and so you know you are right
some of these you know hammers the oils
Reuther and salts they they got to be
reapplied because they don't last a long
time that's a good thing or a bad thing
but they don't have a lot of residuals
so why not mix it with something with a
residual and there's some Sbisa bacillus
based products out there we happen to
have one called fils it's a bacillus
subtilis strength USP 713 for those of
you that want to know that
and compatibility got shelf-life info
and these bacteria in general pad their
their mechanism of action is to produce
metabolites that we call them sometimes
cyclic lipopeptides n' and
biosurfactants sodaro for is there's all
sorts of names but these metabolites
have the ability to make holes in cell
walls and cell membranes and cells can
bleed to that they can collapse and
those metabolites can have some reason
that can have some residual activity on
the foliage so you mix ah in a lot of
our programs you'll see us recommend
mixing our bicarbonate mil stop which
will help spread and stick the
metabolites with cease which hasn't but
tab like so you get a quick direct kill
on contact and then you get a residual
activity from the metabolites fantasy so
you know that's where you can start
putting these biologicals together in
your programs for a quick kill and a
residual activity so you don't have to
come out so often so I looked up the
product it was it was called Sonata
it's a bacillus band a Puma less I'm
turtle it I'm terrible
Puma liver okay but one thing I wanted
to jump back to you was regarding
powdery mildew and temperature and
humidity so one of the one of the
challenges you know traditionally people
would would grow cannabis during the
flower cycle and just immediately drop
the humidity down into the 40's for that
very reason that you mentioned because
the the molds and mildews just don't
don't enjoy that level of humidity but I
find what we found and again this is
this is still fairly anecdotal but by
using you know a vapor pressure
differential in raising the humidity
relative to the temperature the plant
seems to be more resistant to these
particular mildews than
prior problems so we've had some
cannabis growers that have rather than
you know their traditional dropping the
community they've actually raised the
humidity level in the rooms and raised
the temperature and by doing so they've
been able to reduce the amount of
powdery mildew that they beans
they've seen expressed on the leaf on
the leaf tissue in cannabis I think
that's a great idea and I've seen people
do that too here in Florida when I go
visit and elsewhere and yeah because as
you raise the temperature the humidity
changes but the most important thing is
about 75 were hired pattering just
doesn't like to grow well it just
doesn't so raise it up a little bit even
if the humidity goes up because the
temperature is still not conducive for
this problem to get out of hand and if
you remember the pathogen an insect and
pest triangle you need the host you need
the problem and you need the right
environment and so raising that
temperature even if the humidity goes up
it's still okay because you're not going
to allow because of warmer temperatures
to power degree to get out of hand so
I've seen that work too I agree with you
so we've been we've been starting with
the higher humidity and then slowly
tapering it down towards the end of
flower to help prevent botrytis because
it seems like as the plant is starting
to senesce is we're getting later in the
crop cycle were more at risk for
botrytis as the flowers are developing
and it seems that if we don't drop that
humidity towards the end of the cycle or
we're going to still have some botrytis
challenges what can you tell can you
talk about botrytis and sort of how it
relates to powdery mildew and some of
these other things because one of the
issues here is we can't spray a lot of
stuff on cannabis flowers in flowering
cycles and even though microbials are
really challenging because some states
are testing for microbials but they're
not differentiating between you know
different different types you know
gram-negative bacteria or all these
different things just microbial biomass
is all they're looking at and so there's
a lot of challenges around testing that
just
from a legal perspective make it really
hard to treat these things if we don't
get ahead of them early on oh no
question about it two ads no question
about it
and they'll do a total microbial foam
fungi and mold and things and they've
made that's why you know with some of
our microbial living products we
recommend stop applying you know before
you know harvest the flowers because our
goal is to ultimately go to these
testing labs and set up primers and
assays to allow distinction of what's is
there so you can negate the use of some
of these beneficial biologicals because
they are darn good tools that offer you
know nothing negative to the plants just
all of my products have exempt from
residue tolerance levels so you don't
have to worry about anything they
produce as being toxic to you the
environment or the plant all of my
products have at least one formulation
organically certified I mean if you were
growing something you could pick and eat
tomatoes and then apple we have zero
pre-harvest intervals with our products
because they don't crews anything toxic
but they're still testing going on to
look at total microbes so that's where
you may want to make use of some of your
your nonliving biologicals some of these
oils and salts and soaps you know before
the because what happens is when the
flower closes upping it's nice and dense
it holds moisture in there and that's
where problems can get out of hand
inside that flower and I know you can't
use vials so before it closes too tight
maybe means one of these other inputs
that could be that could be helpful but
you know the thing with botrytis is it
different from powdery mildew both Rytas
needs free moisture to germinate so it
likes it when it's wet out so they'll
try to you don't want to water plants at
the end of the day and leave them wet
all night you'll have no try to popping
up the next day you don't want to do
that so you want to you want to keep
your plants dry so I know people that
have issues with botrytis will space
plants a little more so they can dry
others will turn on fans they
drei plans now you don't want to do that
with both rightous because Petridis is
dispersed by the wind
so when but try to sporulate on the soil
surface and you turn fans on all you're
doing is spreading it so you got to be
careful with airflow and botrytis
whereas airflow can help them powdery
mildew and other issues it's not good to
have good airflow because it can cause
spore dispersal with botrytis a booked
riders so they're just a little bit
different but try this will produce
chitin aces and lipases enzymes that
allow it to penetrate right through the
leaf surface and not have to worry about
finding a an opening available to it so
it's not a it's a tough one
well practice is different from pottery
in that you know there's there's
multiple species but rightist is the
genus name but there's multiple species
fortunately enough these species are
more host specific so as I mentioned
with your powdery mildew you got some
cucumbers or something near some some
medicinal plants I wouldn't do that
there's a chance not always but there's
a chance less of a chance with poke try
this because they're more specific but
you've got one certain species but try
to cinerea
and I got eleven years of college on tad
so I can pronounce these names pretty
well I better be able to it's this book
try to cinerea you know it's a beggar
out there you're gonna tackle over 200
different plants both monocots and
dicots so if it's a gnarly one and you
you know you buy strawberries and you
put them in your refrigerator right why
because I want to eat them in two three
weeks
well you can't do that there's some
something gray growing on that that's go
try this we call it gray mold and you
know even the refrigerated temperatures
of 46 degrees Fahrenheit it can grow
after time so it likes it cool it likes
it moist so it differs in powder you
won't see powdery grow it in your fridge
I can't imagine so it's a little bit
different but
and on a good side boat ride it doesn't
survive for three years like powdery
does but try to you know a couple of
weeks to a couple of months maybe a
little longer but it's and this is a
neat one in but pritus is related to
Sclerotinia it's in the same family and
they they form these survival structures
in the soil and you know what corner we
used to do studies looking at how well
these sclerosis could be colonized by
our different strains in rural plus and
they did a pretty good job of growing on
them and knocking them out so that's
where I talked about earlier to suppress
the nature of these strains to suppress
pathogens in the soil before they can
service and do foliar damage so can you
explain to me sort of the the physical
mechanisms associated with botrytis and
also you get yarn you touched on this
lifecycle a little bit here can you sort
of explain how it survives and and
exactly what it does to attacking the
plan well the survival structures are
called sclerotia there's these little
they produce hi-c and other materials
that encapsulate the survival spores in
this the surviving cells inside and and
when the right environment is is there
again it can be you know they thrive
from about sixty to seventy-five degrees
Fahrenheit so they thrive it about the
russain temperature ranges powdery but
they can survive in much cooler
environments and again you get enough
moisture a good rain and you got these
temperatures in the soil they're going
to come out of hiding they're gonna grow
to the soil surface the boat Rytas is
going to sporulate the spore is going to
be
windblown and that's how they move
around and in their in the environment
but krytus also as I mentioned will go
directly through the cuticle through the
epidermis into the the plant tissue but
especially but try to cinerea they
actually produce small RNA molecules
that can affect the plants immune system
so
some of these pathogens when they attack
they'll turn the plants defense system
off and they have free reign at that
time so did I did I answer the questions
had like you yeah so I've seen botrytis
spread really quickly like oh yeah
takeaway Twitter and I've seen people
attempt to treat it in a variety of ways
from everything from hydrogen peroxide
to cutting off and wounding that
particular bud and taking it away from
the room but at the end of the day they
all feel like losing battles
once you've spotted it you're kind of
you're kind of in trouble it seems like
what would be the best way to address it
and how quickly can it really spread it
seems like it just it spreads like
wildfire in my experience once it's
established in a room but can you touch
on those those things a little bit yeah
I mean if you got free moisture in the
right temperature the right environment
in eight hours it can germinate in eight
to twelve hours so in half a day you got
the right conditions it's germinating
it's growing and it's producing enzymes
going right inside the the leaf tissue
so if you can't get it with contacts so
that's why when you you either have a
history or you start to see a few plants
having issues that's when you got a
quarantine that problem and it with some
some contacts also there are some
biologicals that are available again mix
some of these hammers these salt soaps
and oils with something living again our
C's product is helpful but we brought in
a new fungus from New Zealand Australia
Regent at a couple of years ago and
started testing it it's a unique
biological and that most biologicals
either attacked a host or produce
metabolites that are detrimental to the
target or other things this this fungus
in its technique called ulocal a diem
odo Montse strain you three because the
name u2 was taken and this particular
strain
of fungus is called technically an
antagonist so when cells semester die
they rupture and they release moisture
nutrients and pathogens and insects can
since sometimes these volatile in and
move or grow towards these compromised
cells
well this fungus will actually grow on
those compromised cells this this
product and we're talking about
controlling both rightists and our
parking is called bo tree stop so I
think you know what it controls into its
an antagonist that outcompetes Mik
occupation of ruptured cells so as a
preventive or as a quarantined
preventive you spray this out on the
foliage and it will call and ice and
grow however too close to harvest it may
continue to grow so we tell people and
again we have programs for cannabis
production on our website called bio
works cannabis program and you'll read
about when we tell you to stop applying
these microbes based upon microbial
testing that's being done but this is a
real good tool in the toolbox to control
both Rytas and other foliar issues by
sheer competition for niche occupation
so once we have once I spot botrytis on
a on a bud in a room can I safely assume
that the spore pressure in that room is
is already fairly high or can i
potentially catch it early enough and
just remove see when you remove the bud
you're wounding the plant and I guess
creating potentially other issues you
know another place for pathogen and
disease but what what do you think I
mean for people who can't apply
microbials and can't harvest immediately
what other options really are there if
any for you know preserving your crop
depends on I've been in facilities no
names but I've been in there where I saw
a little bit of
boat ride is starting to creep up and
they cut it out and had no issues with
that plant you know sometimes people
will come back with some of these
contact materials to help protect that
wound kind of like a temporary band-aid
that can be done I like to tell people
if you can and it's small enough try to
cut it out if it's getting out of hand
remove it didn't ask yourself do I have
a lot of air circulation here in this
room if I do and the problem is about
try this I may have spread spores I
better get out with some sort of contact
preventative and again salt soaps and
oil I don't know but I think they'd be
tough to detect and testing for for you
know I just don't I think they would be
okay again
I we're trying to as a company work
closer with some of these testing labs
to be able to give you a clearer answer
on when these things can be applied
when's the last time they should be
applied so again I know you're gonna
damage our maybe hurt a plant by
trimming it but if you can trim it a
little bit maybe come in with something
to protect out like an oil that wound
you could save that plant but it's
scouting that tea answer tag to
everything is scouting don't get lazy
get out and look at your plants and I
know in cannabis there's a lot of people
out there and a lot of ice so your whole
entire staff should be trained to go out
and scout if they see something funny
report it just don't ignore it so yeah
and I want to highlight the important of
good genetics too I mean I've seen
plants covered in in botrytis and
powdery mildew next to plants that don't
even seem to care because they just have
that innate resistance in them and you
know some people they're like this is
just the best cultivar of cannabis I've
ever grown you know it's the one that
everyone wants at the end of the day if
if it gets botrytis every single time I
probably wouldn't grow it and a lot of
people get stuck in that world of sort
of that market need to grow something
versus what's practical in their
environment so that's a challenge but
genetics
such a big role at the end of the day it
really I think gets overlooked in a lot
of ways people are always trying to
treat potentially plants that are
genetically weak and then trying to keep
them healthy and that's a real challenge
oh I couldn't agree with you more I
think I said earlier tad that you know
with the proper genetics you really
won't have too many issues but if you do
your biologicals will work well because
the pressure didn't get out of hand so
rapidly and I like you have been in
facilities where there's different
varieties side by side one getting ate
up by something the other one looks
beautiful I'll say I can be not growing
more of this and well this one what
everybody wants and I said we'll send it
to your sister facility you guys should
concentrate on this variety because you
know how to grow it well I mean yeah
genetics are so important and you're
gonna see so much research being done on
genetics in the next couple of years it
it's gonna be so nice so I wanted to
jump back to powdery mildew I had
another question from a plant pathology
perspective we see lately you mentioned
fans and airflow and a lot of growers
are removing quite a few quite a few
leaves families as a way of allowing
better airflow through the plant which
in general I tend to agree with now my
question is sort of in terms of
spreading powdery mildew you mentioned
that with botrytis those spores are
riding in the air
what's going on with powdery mildew and
what's in a you know how much leaf
tissue should we be removing in a given
environment or a given canopy as a way
of optimizing our plants chance for
success against these against these
pathogens because when when I see a
space that's like when we get too many
leaves are too dense of a canopy in the
dig into that canopy not only can you
not scout it but you do see that's where
the powdery mildew wants to want to live
you know the areas that aren't getting
good airflow so what kind of
recommendations would you have around
sort of airflow and these pathogens
why again but pottery airflows important
I mean and and so the leafing can be a
technique to help reduce the ability of
powdery mildew to get a foothold so I
believe in deleting again how much
should you do well doing nothing you
know you're getting good airflow number
one number two is belief enough that you
know you can scout in the middle of
something you know easier than having to
crawl in there so I mean the leafing
offers a couple of advantages so uh but
powdery likes to spread more by water
splashing on people's clothes it's not
blown around it's not wind dispersed or
air dispersed like like poke try to so
that's an advantage of keeping that air
flow up but again with patterning
temperatures importance get it up there
we talked about that at seventy-five a
little higher if you can and and you
know powdery doesn't need free moisture
but pritus does patterning chin you can
get good airflow and stop it from
getting a foothold the botrytis it'll
help disperse it so there's no easy
solution or answer to that it's just
what's your biggest problem you know
play around with air flow watch over
fertilization I mean you know too much
fertilizer can alter the metabolites
being produced by these medicinal plants
but also it can weaken and stress a
plant we know that an ornamental plants
the flowering plants you know if you add
too much nitrogen Pythium can attack the
roots more effectively white flies can
sense a plant is stressed and attack
more effectively in fact you know and
you guys have all heard about this some
of these so-called plant nutrition
products offering the ability to reduce
plant stress when plants get stressed
they give off volatile and these
volatiles are
gases ethylene is one that plants give
off ethylene when they're stressed and
issues can sense and detect that
ethylene emission and especially insects
and go and attack that plan so we be
cautious of too much cutting too much
damage to a plant there are we have a a
plant nutrition called on guard and for
a lack of better terms this this this
amino acid based plant nutrition with
a500
for lack of better terms I'm going to
throw this out there is I call it prozac
for plants it reduces plant stressed and
in addition it is what I also call an
uber it helps transport nutrients inside
the plant more effectively and
efficiently so you can utilize less
nutrients save money and not have salt
built up so there are ways to try to
reduce stress in plants and I know that
University of Florida hired biostimulant
specialists a couple of years ago names
dr. schinsky Yaga Hara and he is working
on the use of bio stimulants because if
you can reduce plant stress plants are
capable on their own of fighting off a
lot of diseases and pathogens and
insects number one number two is they're
not producing volatiles that help entice
problems to come in faster and if you
can uptake nutrients more effectively
both your macro and your minor nutrients
the plants going to be healthier less
stressed and it can fight off a lot of
problems on its own yeah I'm glad you
brought up over fertilization because I
have seen what your what you're talking
about there and relationship to nitrogen
and have you seen that sort of research
done in an organic system where say that
nitrogen maybe have been applied in the
form of oh I don't know fish meal or
feather meal or some other form that's
not immediately available or key
lated where the you know you're waiting
for the microbes to break it down into a
plant available form are are you seeing
I mean I've seen where over application
of those products will cause bacterial
blooms which and also raise the
temperature of the soil which plants
don't like obviously but are you seeing
the same challenges around over
fertilization in organic soils I guess
or have you seen research on that I've
seen some research research is
continuing and there's a great deal of
research out there on organic production
because one of the limiting factors in
organic production is the availability
of good organic sources of nitrogen that
are either too available or not
available and and your other needed
elements so work is being done I I can't
sit her and quote you on any of them
because a lot of it's still being
conducted I know here in Florida in the
southeast in general I hang out a lot
what I'm not in Mexico doing work is
that there's more and more interest in
some of these organic based inputs and
in fact we started a line a couple of
years ago of biological fertilizers we
call them where your nutrients are not
readily released by moisture temperature
like a control release fertilizers you
literally need a living soil with good
biology to release the NPK because they
are released by microbes feeding on
these dried granular materials and not
by moisture and temperature like a lot
of control releases are so there's a lot
of interest in this area we as a company
have interest in this area we'd like to
develop specific plant nutrients for you
the cannabis needs and a lot of work is
being done in this area there are a lot
of products out there to add there are
more products I mean
darn when I go to shows I see a lot of
stuff out there and when I start asking
specific questions I don't get specific
enough answers I get a lot of features
and benefits but not a lot of science so
I will say
there needs to be a whole lot more work
than before we'll know what we need to
be doing as far as proper plant
nutrition both in organics and in
cannabis production I can't agree with
you more there are a lot of products out
there like you said the new ones coming
on the market every day and it's it's
really hard one of the things that
Suzanne and I have had long discussions
on and what she had me come down to the
biocontrol conference to give a talk on
was specifically how do we how do we
evaluate or vet all of these products
you know what are the questions as
growers or end consumers do we need to
be asking these companies to know not
only that what we're putting on our on
our plants is effective but that it's
even just as a low bar just safe for the
end consumer because there have been
some companies in the past that have
been less than honest with us about what
they're putting in their product and so
there's some challenges around that too
but yeah this fertilizer thing I think
is really interesting so I'm excited to
see more research on the organic side
come out in relationship to optimal
nutrient levels associated with cannabis
and what those effects are on some of
these things like like you mentioned
like botrytis and powdery mildew and I
look forward to the day we can do more
research to see how our products and
other types of biologicals like ours
affect metabolite production because I
think that that is something that needs
to be understood and measured yeah well
Chris I know I know people are gonna
yell at me because you're you're a smart
guy I'm sure I didn't ask all the
questions I should have asked I'd love
to get you back on here at some point to
follow up but I really appreciate your
time today and you're explaining some of
these different microbes and pathogens
was really helpful so thank you you're
welcome sir and it's been an honor to
talk with you and hopefully I've helped
a few cannabis growers out there
understand a little bit better about the
confusion that's going on there's a
whole lot of products out there being
off
- you just ask questions check them out
I mean there's a company we have over 25
years of history and ornamentals an
edible production and I'd like to say we
got all the answers in cannabis and hip
production but we don't we have
questions we want to work with those
that would like to work with us to
answer some of those questions and
that's the only way we're going to get
things done and as importantly tad we
need to make sure that we we have some
sort of system in place in the future to
certify or just to say these products
have been shown to help these haven't
good like you said there's a lot of
products out there there's a there's a
lot of fermented products I don't want
to see anybody get harmed by people
coliforms or any anaerobic organisms so
be careful understand what you're doing
it may make sense to you the person
presenting the the product may have made
sense to you but ask around see what
people are using check out check out the
company's websites he would take an
offer if they can't answer a whole lot
of questions I'd have a whole lot of
concerns about working with them I think
that's great advice yeah I appreciate
that and people I will put links to your
website like I said in some of the
information that you mentioned on the
podcast page so people can check it out
there and thank you very much thank you
sir for your time
[Music]
that was Chris Hayes with Bioworks and
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'm your
host Todd Hussey you can check out the
Bioworks website at WWE
and don't forget to check out our
website at www.kppc.org/keeps