[Music]
thank you
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics the this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guests this week are two
awesome cannabis researchers Paul coxon
and Patrick veezy Paul has been on the
podcast before on episode 59 talking
about his paper on cannabis deficiencies
be sure to check out that episode if you
haven't already just click on the learn
tab then podcast I also recently had
them on together to talk about their
phosphorus research and they are back
this week to talk about magnesium
Paul has been working in the hemp world
as a researcher since 2018 and in plant
science research since 2016. he has a
background in Horticulture agroecology
and floriculture from his time at NC
State currently he is pursuing his PhD
at the University of Kentucky working
with Industrial Hemp Paul's primary
research focuses on rhizosphere
management and bring strengths in plant
mineral fertility plant hormones and
growth Regulators substrate research
General Diagnostics and Greenhouse and
growth chamber expertise in addition to
a strong Greenhouse background Paul is
also literate in field level agronomic
processes Paul's passion is for
mentorship and sharing the research
process with undergraduate students when
not doing research a Paul and his dog
Groot can be found hiking in local state
and national parks
Patrick veezy has been working in the
hemp world as a researcher since 2019
and as a plant science Reacher
researcher since 2018. he has a
background in Horticulture and Flora
culture from his time as an
undergraduate researcher at NC State
currently he is pursuing his Masters of
Science at North Carolina State and is
focusing on Greenhouse substrates for
cannabis and other floriculture crops
Patrick's primary research focuses on
plant mineral fertility substrate
research and general Diagnostics was
super excited to talk to them about some
of their latest published research on
cannabis and hemp now on to the show
all right hey guys thanks for coming on
the show today
thanks for having us tell me again I
know you guys have been on the show
multiple times now but uh can you just
give a quick bio uh each of you and what
you're currently up to and uh then we'll
dive into these papers
uh Paul you want to start us off
sure yeah
um I'm Paul coxon um I'm currently a PhD
student at University of Kentucky
um I got involved pretty early on with
Dr Brian whipker at NC State
um doing hemp research cannabis research
um and ever since then it's kind of been
a fun Wild Ride of just exploring uh
this Avenue and that Avenue but most of
our work uh coming out of there the
Patrick myself and Dr Whitaker did was
related to fertility and mineral
nutrition of cannabis so but currently
I'm at University of Kentucky and we're
exploring germination and establishment
with some Industrial Hemp so a little
bit more of the Grain and fiber side
and you Patrick
yeah and I'm Patrick veezy I'm a first
year Master's student at NC State
working under Dr Brian whipker and
worked under Paul as an undergrad
most of my research is focused on
Mineral fertility of different crops
including cannabis now moving a little
bit more into the substrate realm of CBD
hemp and other crops as well awesome
well I appreciate you guys coming on the
show and the the main purpose of the
show today was to talk about this paper
that you were both authors on that uh
that Patrick did a lot of research on
here it's entitled magnesium's impact on
Cannabis sativa is it baox is that the
name of the cultivar or how do you
pronounce that uh bayox
bayox okay and silver haze growth and
cannabinoid production awesome but
before we dive into that paper there was
a question I got an email from a
listener that I thought was interesting
and I kind of wanted to talk to you guys
about it and just kind of expound on
that so the the email is sent the the
gist of the email was why don't
researchers partner with Farmers or
Growers that know how to grow plants to
get you know really healthy happy plants
for these trials and I think this was in
relation Paul to one of the papers you
did and the plants in the paper not
looking quite so hot so can you kind of
explain
um
just a little bit more around that
process and and yeah just yeah I'll just
leave it with that and take it out take
it away
yeah for sure
um well first off I'm actually really
excited that people are commenting and
uh you know challenging and and giving
feedback because it's it's important in
this industry that we're all
communicating together and sometimes
that means
um asking those hard questions or
expressing some uh frustration in
constructive ways but um I guess I'll
kind of answer that twofold the first
part is um actually the very first paper
that we did on the survey with Hunter
Landis we partnered with a local grower
that was where we started with our
foundation so
um given that Dr Brian whipper has an
extension appointment we really do value
and try and partner with Growers
whenever possible but the challenge
sometimes is especially with larger
grants you're often required to partner
with Growers but this industry at least
on the scientific side is so new and
we're still breaking into it that a lot
of those Federal funding and larger
grants are just now starting to roll out
and so most of us were having to do solo
work I'm trying to kind of figure some
stuff out on a smaller scale which
sometimes makes it difficult to involve
Growers but definitely moving forward um
we're all in this together and we only
get better together so uh yeah
definitely Partnerships are the way to
go
because you know we're scientists we're
really good at science but sometimes you
know we're still doing it well also I I
want to touch on the fact that the point
of research is not just for research
itself but actually to further
knowledge for Growers and farmers in the
agricultural sector so that you know we
can grow better plants so we can better
understand that process so you're not
doing science in a vacuum but you're
doing it hopefully with the goal of
impacting Growers
yeah and that's a really good point um I
always laugh because Brian uh Dr whipker
he has a saying um he does a lot of
nutrient deficiency work and he always
says his motto is we kill plants so you
don't have to and uh you know I think
sometimes you know we as scientists
we're we're almost looking to fail or
we're looking for that failure point
because we're trying to fail and figure
out you know what's wrong so that we can
inform the The Growers in the industry
and what not to do and the other thing
is just a little bit about the the
scientific process itself
um you know when you're designing an
experiment you have a very specific
question in mind and so you're kind of
streamlining all of your variables and
you're trying to eliminate anything that
can impact that question so that you get
kind of a pure answer at the end and so
if something goes wrong in the middle of
an experiment sometimes you can't fix it
because if you do try and fix it you
don't know if maybe what you did to try
and fix and auto correct your trajectory
impacted the results or if it was truly
your experiment and so you know early on
when we were still kind of trying to
dial in with the phosphorus work our
plants didn't look too hot but we knew
that we couldn't correct that because we
were very specifically trying to study
phosphorus and uh when we came to this
next round of experiments that Patrick
headed up with the Magnesium work we we
definitely changed a few things here and
there especially with the fertility
regime um then it really showed through
in this experiment that we also learned
from our mistakes yes so so once you
have your methodology in place here in
your hypothesis you really can't make a
lot of changes at that point you're kind
of committed is that essentially what
you're saying
oh and Patrick you had something you
want to add to that
yeah so
we did experience some magnesium
problems in Paul's study
but kind of looking at that we saw the
problem and while we couldn't correct it
for that that's kind of what
springboarded us into this next project
is that all of our work kind of built
off what we had done and the problems we
had seen so even though once we were
committed to only playing around with
the phosphorus rate and that first
experiment
we adjusted and actually sprung board us
into this completely other direction for
a new experiment to look at magnesium
so while problems do occur early on as
we've gone through this line of
experiments the plans have looked better
because we've made these minor changes
all the way along and we kind of
document that with our research
that makes a lot of sense and I
appreciate you guys explaining that and
uh
it is great to hear that research is
partnering with
Growers and farmers and that's the main
purpose of it one other aspect to that
though too as as someone who works with
a number of cannabis facilities
they're not really set up to do research
in a lot of ways because you can't set
up a protocol that you know won't give
you the highest economic uh gain so you
can't you can't set an experiment where
you know you're going to lose some
plants or your plants are going to yield
lower because at the end of the day your
bottom line is what's keeping you in
business so that's where you know having
another location working with
researchers and giving input is really
important because you just can't do it
in a working facility
so I just want to add that to that but
let's let's just dive into this this
magnesium paper
um
Patrick uh do you want to go ahead and
just uh explain a little bit of what the
goals of the paper were and you know
start taking us through it
yeah so this magnesium paper really
started off as a problem that we were
seeing with our plants and a lot of
other growers in the southeast
so magnesium
you can get a lot of it from your water
supply if you're on a well where your
ground water contains a lot of magnesium
this is pretty common in the Upper
Midwest where a lot of their parent
materials contain the Magnesium so it
winds up in their water however here in
the Southeast especially North and South
Carolina
we were seeing a lot of magnesium
problems because our water really
doesn't contain any
so like with Paul's research
when we're mixing our fertilizers if you
use a Triple Tin it doesn't contain
magnesium and sulfur uh
so moving along into that we'd we saw a
lot of Growers have this magnesium
deficiency going on especially late in
the bud set
so we wanted to determine if we can find
that magnesium fertility rate that
Growers can Target
in order to not have that magnesium
deficiency especially later in the
production cycle
so moving along with that we set up this
experiment where we looked at six
different magnesium fertility rates
of zero
see
zero twelve and a half twenty five fifty
seventy five and a hundred part per
million magnesium
and we held them constant throughout the
entire experiment and we looked at the
uptake in the plant growth at three
different stages a vegetative stage
pre-flower where we're only a couple
weeks in a Bud set and then at the end
of flowering of so 12 weeks of total
growth or eight weeks of reproductive
and just looked at you know how much
magnesium was the plant taking up and
what the impacts on the growth in
cannabinoids were
so that was kind of the Baseline for the
study and why we did it
now you you guys what was your um what
was your media for this because I when I
think of magnesium I typically see it
coming in a lot with compost
um so it's part of my media already in
in many cases I tend to never have to
add magnesium even though it's not in my
water just because we get it when we mix
soils but if you're growing
you know purely using mineral salts I
could see where that could be a little
more challenging what were you guys
doing in this case
so for this one we utilized the 70 30
peat perlite volume to volume substrate
so and we custom Blended that so we know
it didn't have a pre-plant charge
so this rate that we're sort of
recommending as your baseline or
Cornerstone to modify from there
this is with nothing coming in in the
soil as well as everything is supplied
through liquid feed
so like you're saying a lot of it can
come in with your substrate your water
or many other things here's just what we
were looking to recommend is what should
your Cornerstone bead kind of look at to
avoid the deficiency and then you know
if it is coming in a lot in your
substrate or in your water you can kind
of take that away from the rate
so uh and your decision to keep
magnesium the same throughout the cycle
in terms of how much you were feeding
what went into that
sort of sort of that conversation
so looking to keep it constant versus
altering it it's
mainly that magnesium's a mobile element
so if the plant needs it it'll be able
to translocate it so we wanted to see
just by giving a constant feed
you know will the plant take it from the
lower leaves whatever it's not in
reproductive and move it to the new and
developing foliage or into the buds when
it's developing we didn't really want to
alter it we wanted to kind of see if you
held it exactly constant throughout how
the plants new sinks and sources were
really going to influence
how much was needed
okay now before we go into the results
can you uh could one of you guys give me
a little overview on magnesium I feel
like maybe we should we should have
backed up and started there uh in terms
of how how it works in the plant and
what a deficiency may look like
um relative to other nutrients and if
there's any antagonistic
relationships with other nutrients like
the on the motors chart for example
so magnesium deficiency which we have a
pretty good photo of
um in the article it initially will
appear on that lower one third of the
plant the oldest leaves
and then it'll start as this intervenal
fold uh intervenal chlorosis and it
starts right in the center of the leaf
and kind of spreads outward to the edge
of the leaflet and then as the uh
deficiency becomes more severe it
spreads into that middle portion of the
plant and then we saw in many severe
cases it can be throughout the entire
plant
now once that intravenal chlorosis has
really developed we begin to start to
see necrosis forming and then leaves
dying and falling from the plant
so it is also Mobile in the plant
so once it starts in that lower one
third of the plant the plant's actually
taking the new the Magnesium that was in
those lower leaves and translocating it
to the upper portions of the plant to
meet the new developing needs of the
plant so especially when we put that
plant to flower and reproductive it's
going to take all those nutrients that
is stored in the bottom it's going to
shift them up to the buds
so it's kind of essentially a magnesium
piggy bank in that lower one-third of
the plant where it's going to kind of
hold it
and then once it's needed for that bud
production it's going to move it to the
upper portion
and that's kind of one thing we wanted
to look at is how much is needed to not
see that translocation
and keep it constant throughout
but just because your lower leaves are
efficient that doesn't mean your upper
leaves are deficient because it's moving
it throughout so that's why it will
initially appear first in the lower area
and then in terms of antagon
antagonistic effects with other elements
magnesium is antagonized by
potassium and calcium
however it's synergistic or we see an
increase in uptake when phosphorus is
high or nitrogen
so uh really looking at your nnp to see
if we really increase that nitrogen rate
or really increase that phosphorus rate
you will see an increase in that
magnesium uptake
um so for what we looked at here
we had 150 Park million in uh constant
feed so if we did increase this uh to
you know 250 300 Park million in but
like we have seen some Growers do you
may need to alter the rate that we do
provide uh because when you increase
those two elements you're going to see
an increase in magnesium uptake as well
yeah and I'll just jump in here real
quick and and provide a few comments so
um the the figures that we have in this
paper that Patrick were referring to
that's figure three and figure four for
kind of the initial deficiency stages
for magnesium and then kind of the
advanced with figure four and another
figure I'd like to highlight is sticker
six where we're looking at 25 per
million magnesium
um so it's a composite photo with both
nayox and severe Haze showing kind of
that uh the Tran reallocation
that Patrick was just talking about and
essentially it's pulling it out of those
older leaves and funnily and into the
new reproductive I think
um but uh as Patrick said
um phosphorus magnesium is synergistic
with phosphorus and if you actually look
at the fertility rates that we utilize
we had 30 parts per million phosphorus
and if you'll kind of cast your mind
back to the the previous episode that we
had where you know we were kind of
recommending you know start at around
the 15 parts per million rate given we
were going so high with the magnesium
and given that initially on the
phosphorus study we saw some magnesium
deficiency that's kind of what sparked
the the interest that Patrick had in the
study so we increased that phosphorus
because of the synergism with the
Magnesium knowing that we would probably
have an effect there but as far as the
importance of magnesium
um in plants so in the chlorophyll
molecule it kind of uh sits in in the
middle of this ring and it's important
in a chlorophyll production and
chlorophyll health so it's directly
correlated to photosynthetic health and
we all know that you know the healthier
the photosynthetic Machinery the more
photosynthes and the healthier your
plant will be and the more resources it
will have to funnel into those buds or
those you know seeds
come the induction of the critical photo
period so magnesium is definitely
extremely important
element
given its its role in photosynthesis
that's that's great I really appreciate
you guys explaining that can we dive in
now to sort of what your your findings
were on this and I'll I'll link to this
paper and these these diagrams
or figures on the on the podcast page
itself so people can go back and look at
these as well
yeah so our findings uh
for this study was
we noticed that
it was slightly different for both
cultivars so uh first
bayox
we didn't see some of the magnesium
deficiency at some of the same rates
that we did for savier haze
so we actually saw more of an impact on
savior Haze plants compared to bayox
when we had that low magnesium fertility
uh savier Haze is a bit more of a bushy
grower and a lot more aggressive grower
than baox
so what we did notice is that there's a
big colesfar dependency here
so when we we're going to make this
right recommendation of 50 to 75 part
per million mg
however one of our big things that we do
want to highlight is a takeaway
is that this can kind of serve as a
Cornerstone for a grower however it is
not
exactly the recipe for a grower so while
we can say it's in this range one of the
big things I do want to highlight before
getting too deep into this
is that this will vary based on what
Coles fire you're looking at if you have
a very aggressive grower you may need to
look at a slightly higher rate compared
to a smaller plant or if you're keeping
them smaller
and additionally
um magnesium had a negative impact on
plant growth at the lowest two rates of
zero and twelve and a half per million
and that's when we're seeing the plant
being deficient
in the Magnesium uptake
in terms of once we start to move up the
ladder 25 to 50. it was also very
dependent upon what stage and growth we
were at at four weeks of growth
25 and 50 for baox were fairly similar
however as we begin to move
into
the later weeks we begin to see that
difference grow much more in terms of
overall plant growth metrics so later
into the production cycle and that plant
needed more magnesium it really turned
into 50 to 75 produced
better growing plants and more yield
another thing to really highlight is
that we looked at this range of rates of
six of them now at the lower rates of 0
to 12 and a half
we completely expected to see a decrease
in plant growth but one of the other
things I want to highlight is when we go
to the far end of things
so if you supply a plant with too many
nutrients
you will actually decrease your plant's
growth and here we really saw that for
both cultivars starting even initially
at eight weeks of plant growth for bayox
plants that received a hundred par per
million phosphorus
showed significantly less growth
compared to those that received 50 to 75
and we saw the same yield as plants that
received Zero part per million magnesium
so it's really finding that key balance
for a grower you don't want to over
Supply your plants with magnesium but
you definitely don't want to undersupply
them as well
so that's kind of where we get these
rates as the Cornerstone of 50 to 75
part million mg
and really
looking at
um
the finals growth stage
we saw that there wasn't a real big
difference in budweight overall
so it's
um for bayox there was no differences at
all and when we look at magnesium plants
that received zero or a hundred parts
per million mg exhibited significantly
less Bud weight overall
compared to plants that were in that 50
to 75 Park billion mg
so your magnesium rate can directly
impact your yield and even if you're not
seeing magnesium deficiency
we you will see a decrease in Bud
production because of a over
accumulation of magnesium in your plant
so that's kind of the really big things
we want to highlight from the plant
growth perspective now one of the main
ways that a grower can determine uh
magnesium
concentration in a plant is through Leaf
tissue analysis
and one of the things we saw is that
as you begin to give the plant more and
more magnesium it's definitely going to
take that magnesium up looking at all of
the different nutrient analysis that we
did on both cultivars
and both cultivars uptook magnesium in a
linear fashion so the more you gave it
the more it took up
now granted we also saw that decrease in
Bud production so kind of one of the key
things to highlight is that a greater
magnesium concentration does not mean
better healthier plants we're kind of
looking at a sweet spot here of about
1.15 to 1.3 or a percent magnesium in
the leaves
uh was kind of that 50 to 75 part per
million what it turns into concentration
in the plant
so we didn't see an actual plateau
that linear increase continued all the
way up to 100 PPM and G and maybe if we
increase the rate further you know to
150 200 par per million magnesium
we may see an actual Plateau occur where
the plant just won't take any more up
however up to 100 PPM and G which is not
hard to obtain we did see an overall
Plateau or we did not see a plateau and
uptake but we see a plateau in growth so
looking at those uh if you do conduct
nutrient analysis making sure you look
at those values and understand that more
is not better is a key thing to kind of
take away from this piece of work
if I can add something real quick to
that um just one click clarification for
bayox regardless of the Magnesium
concentration we didn't see much
differences in the bud weight but for
severe Haze we did and those differences
were seen at the 50 parts per million
rate compared to the zero
but then once we got up to those higher
concentrations like Patrick said we did
see a decrease in that total Bud weight
so again just kind of
to kind of I guess uh parrot something
that Patrick said earlier it really when
when looking at this research and trying
to figure out what what does this mean
for my operation what does this mean for
me
um recognizing that there will be Cult
of Articles of our variety or variety
differences that you're seeing and so
using this as kind of a starting point
and a guideline to conduct your own
research in your own facility because a
lot of you know other abiotic factors
what type of Lights you're using how
often you're irrigating your vapor
pressure deficit will impact you know
how those plants are taking up and
utilizing the nutrients as well
so just wanted to you know
reiterate what Patrick is yeah just so I
understand it too you said that with
bayox you didn't see a difference in Bud
weight but then when you got to the
higher
higher concentrations you did
so did you or did you not see difference
in overall yield I guess or are you
talking about the actual buds size and
weight just comparing a like a single
bud but that was my confusion in that
yeah yeah so um if you look at table 10
and table 11
um from the paper you can see that total
Bud weight
um there
um so we took a sub sample composite if
that's if I'm remembering correctly
Patrick or did you uh this is
all of the buds on the plant and looking
at uh table tin which is bayox
for any of the examined magnesium
fertility rates we don't see a
difference however savior Haze
we do see a difference between that 50
or we see a decrease in total Bud weight
produced by those that were zero uh part
per million mg and 50 and then we also
see a decrease on the other end of the
spectrum so plants that received 100
part per million mg produced
significantly less total Bud weight
compared to those that receive 50.
um
so that really ties in that cultivar
difference between
cultivars will react differently
different differently based upon the
Magnesium fertility rate so in some you
may see a significant decrease in but
production in others you may not
so
to kind of summarize Tad in one cultivar
we saw no differences regardless of
which magnesium rate we're seeing in
total budweight so no correlation
between Bud weight and magnesium however
in the other cultivar we saw that we had
lower Bud weights at those lower
concentrations and it increased up to
that 50 parts per million magnesium and
then it then decreased when we got to
that 100 to be less okay so as the big
takeaway is that genetics can play a
huge role in magnesium uptake because we
have such diversity in genetics and
and what people are growing perfect
um
some of the other I guess big points
that you would you would highlight
um are
uh sorry I have to go back now and
recollect my thoughts um
[Music]
actually I'm going to come back to that
so the first the thing I want to touch
on was lighting because you mentioned
lighting um
you were growing in a greenhouse in this
case right and you mentioned magnesium's
role in photosynthetic um
activity do you think if you had pushed
uh your
your you know your pdfd levels higher or
more consistently across like like say
with an indoor indoor facility you know
it
1200 ppfd or somewhere around there you
would have seen increased magnesium well
I guess you you couldn't see increased
magnesium uptake do you think you would
have seen
um
you know deficiencies or maybe have
needed more magnesium
um
in those instances relative to what you
actually saw in in this study
I think by pushing the plant by
increasing you know ppfd
to once you're pushing that plant to get
bigger faster comparatively to uh we
were growing with natural DLI with night
Interruption and this started off in
uh early spring and transitioned into
later in the spring closer to mid-april
so we weren't in you know what we'd
consider the maximum ppfd or DLI for the
year
so by adding more lights and other
things and you're really pushing that
plant pushing the photosynthesis
increasing mass flow of other nutrients
I think you would have needed a slightly
increased magnesium fertility rate to
help compensate for that plant growth
that you're really pushing
um additionally when you're really
if you're increasing the photosynthesis
and transpiration and everything else
magnesium is going to get drawn up more
because the plant's utilizing more water
so you could potentially need to
increase uh your magnesium fertility
rate as well to compensate for that
increase in plant growth
or vice versa if you're going to try and
slow the plants down
and not need to irrigate nearly as much
between intervals
then you could potentially lower this
magnesium fertility rate as well but
definitely lighting if you're going to
push the plants potentially looking at
tinkering with this Cornerstone that
we're kind of providing you may need to
up increase it depending upon
your setup as well
great and did you see
um
did you see diff can't calcium or
potassium deficiencies as you increase
magnesium up to that 100 PPM level on
visually with the plant or with tissue
analysis
um neither visually nor uh so Paul did
the original Cornerstone that y'all
highlighted of nutrient values for
cannabis deficiencies
and we were only playing around with
um about 100 Park million mg so we
really didn't see that much of a
difference compared to our 150 Park
million in modified Covenant solution I
think if we really would have started to
increase the Magnesium you know 150 200
we could have started to see a little
bit more of that interaction
um you do slightly see some of that
interaction playing out in savier Haze
but we don't see nearly two deficient
levels
um but there is just a little bit of
that interaction occurring where you see
as we go up in magnesium you see
slightly lower calcium levels in some of
them
okay okay so uh the high level things
just getting back to that are that it's
really important to have sufficiency in
magnesium but it's uh you can't you
can't have a luxury amount that has
antagonistic effects so there is a limit
to how much magnesium you want in your
media or being uptaken by the plants
it's going to be affected by all your
abiotic conditions your environments
watering habits
all of those things it's a mobile
nutrient
and
um genetics plays a big role are there
any other high-level things that I
missed
and kind of recapping some of this in 50
to 75 PPM was The Sweet Spot in the
study for these genetics uh based off
what you saw
uh yeah
um that's all correct the other high
level thing that
we kind of wanted to point out is we
didn't see a any influence on
cannabinoids
um so
from our current understanding is
at these levels we weren't seeing that
interaction with the cannabinoid
production pathway
um now potentially if you
are running a different system or or
running different genetics as well you
may start to see a difference
however we did not see a difference
based upon the Magnesium rate for our
setup
now as
go ahead Paul
oh How can I jump in here
um so if you look at tables 14 and 15
from the paper it kind of highlights
what Patrick was saying here and what we
essentially did is we kind of reiterated
this point that genetics plays a huge
part because you can see that you know
while magnesium didn't necessarily
impact the cannabinoids
and we did have quite Stark differences
between the two cultivars and the type
of cannabinoids that they were producing
across the acidic pools as well as the
decarboxylated pools so again just kind
of driving home the point that you know
this is a starting point and based on
your genetics and your environment you
know you can kind of use this as a
guiding star but you'll have to make
some fine tune adjustments and find out
what works for you and your operation so
yeah so as someone who works with what
people are calling living soil these
days which so essentially soilless media
with compost organic
inputs
where the nutrients or fertilizer that
we're adding is not immediately
available to the plant like like it is
in in the
in in this study that you're running I
tend to aim for lower levels of
magnesium
on my soil tests because I know that it
can tighten the soil
it raises your pH pretty dramatically
relative to other cations and
[Music]
um
it's harder to flesh out relative to
some of the other cations so for me I
aim low and then
um as an organic grower I use magnesium
sulfate Epsom salt as a way of of sort
of feeding magnesium as needed but
typically I'll wait until I get a you
know some sort of visual
clue of a deficiency but one thing that
your research is showing and correct me
on anything I've said so far if if I if
I misspeak in your eyes um
you're saying that potentially just by
waiting for that visual deficiency on
magnesium I may be
possibly impacting overall plant health
or yield
is that is that correct
because you found differences based off
of
um doing your Leaf tissue analysis that
showed
essentially a decrease in yield
um prior to visual plant deficiency is
that
is that a Pharisee
yes
um
all that you're saying with
in a living soil system magnesium
can be very problematic both with ph
locking up the soil and everything else
um
but
you're also kind of holding it there
to kind of it's already incorporated
into your soil
um from what we're kind of viewing is we
did see
decreases when we didn't add any
supplement because we did a constant
feed so
I can't answer that if
you're making an adjustment as you see a
visual deficiency if you're negating the
deficiency with your supplement of Epsom
salt
um
we're kind of only saying that if you
see the efficiency and you don't
supplement
uh you will see a decrease for the two
cultivars we looked at but we can't
necessarily make a statement if if you
see the deficiency and you make an
adjustment
the lease will still look deficient but
that new growth is likely going to take
it up so I assume you're negating it to
a certain point but I can't necessarily
say that you are going to see that
deficiency if you add later because it's
a mobile nutrient those lower leaves are
potentially nutrient sinks at that point
um especially in an indoor facility
where they're getting a lot less light
so you're saying it may not be as
impactful
yeah the the plant's not gonna go back
and prioritize those lower leaves uh
it's even if you add Epsom salts those
leaves will still look deficient and
show the deficiency symptoms but the
additional magnesium sulfate you applied
will be prioritized to your new growth
which would be your uh your bud or your
new developing shoe tip which is your
economic portion of the plant
go ahead Paul
and oh oh I'll jump in real quick if I
can here and kind of highlight something
um that this paper shows
um and and kind of going back to the
figure that I referenced before where we
had the two mature plants I had 25 parts
per million magnesium that we're showing
those deficiencies I think it's
important when you see a nutrient
deficiency a lot of times you tend to
freak out you know it's like oh no
something doesn't look right my plant
isn't totally beautiful and you know it
doesn't look right well understanding
the life cycle of the plant and when
that deficiency may start naturally
occurring because of that reallocation
can also kind of help you because you
know if you're within the sweet spot for
your operation you've done your research
and you've looked at your 50 parts per
million but you know that with your
genetics and your setup you're gonna see
some magnesium deficiency about four
weeks in to um you know bud set
it may be okay because that plant is
just reallocating and so if you're
trying to correct that at that point you
may be throwing money away because if
you know that the final product you're
getting even though you're seeing that
magnesium deficiency in those leaves
because it's relocating you don't want
to put more money into the system
when you know that your cannabinoids and
your bud is still going to be good at
the end of the season there for you so
you know it's kind of like the the
classic you're driving by a cornfield in
the fall and plants look like crap
because they're dying and finessing but
that's actually a good thing because the
plant has taken up all these resources
and it's reallocating it to the sink and
you actually want to see you know that
reallocation because it means that
you've actually done your job you've
dialed in your precise nutrients and
you're reallocating what you've already
given yeah that's a good point you both
brought up and and Patrick especially I
want to highlight something you said for
folks and that's that um
it's important to know if a nutrient is
mobile or in Mobile and if a nutrient is
mobile
then we're really focused on that new
growth the upper the upper portion of
the plant and not only are those leaves
you know down at the bottom not ever
going to look good again but uh that's
okay and that doesn't mean that we're
necessarily going to impact
our overall plant health or the economic
value of that plant so
um it's something we take for granted
because people do you know like like you
said Paul people freak out when their
plant uh starts to show any issues at
all
it's so funny because I'll have people
and they'll be like oh my plants
finished so well they looked great and
then they send me the photos and I'm
like oh my gosh like how did this plant
even survive
um it looks terrible and then other
people are like oh man I had a terrible
run and then they send me these plants
and I'm like dude you crushed it like
these look great like I would have been
very very happy with these results so a
lot of it is subjective in that regard
but I do think that we can um
uh we we do need to look at Mobile
versus immobile nutrients and also just
understand that that these are living
organisms they're not designed to look
like
um what you see on social media all the
time across your entire facility and all
your plants so that's a that's a very
good point to make
um
what else did we want to talk about in
regards to magnesium did you guys have
other things to highlight I probably
have a couple more questions but I want
to just kind of open the floor here and
see
um
what your thoughts were
yeah it's uh one of the big things is
kind of something we took away from this
was making sure what your magnesium
levels in your soil are to start off
with
um we've looked at a handful of
commercial substrates and some come in
with a major pre-planned charge
in very high magnesium at that so
understanding what's coming in in your
substrate and Then followed up by what's
in your water if you're on City Water
this may not be a concern for you if
you're on well water this you may
already have a significant amount of
magnesium in your water source
um so as we start to play around with
you know what magnesium rate works for
your operation it's kind of taking all
of these factors into effect and both
looking at your substrate before you uh
utilize that in your operation as well
as water quality those impact a wide
array of nutrients just not magnesium
but magnesium is heavily impacted by
those two it's kind of what we've seen
that's one of the most common nutrients
that come in in people's water and
substrates
that's a good point I wanted to add to
that in the sense that um
I think everyone should test their water
everyone should test their soil and
don't assume that the test that you
receive from the Municipal Water company
from the commercial soil producer is
always accurate especially because most
of these potting soils like ours used a
fraction of compost and that compost as
much as we want it to be consistent it's
there's always room for variability and
that can lead to
uh you know your overall potting soil
having variability so it's just
something that people need to be aware
of and account for
um interestingly enough so I'm on a
municipal water system in this house
that I moved into
here in Washington state and I reached
out to the water provider and what they
do is they Source from a number of Wells
to get a more consistent water supply
they only test for heavy metals so when
I asked them you know from a gardening
perspective like what kind of cations
are coming in in my water they they said
that those are all considered secondary
elements in in their eyes or variables
and they don't even test for it so I had
to send in my own test to find out uh
you know what levels of calcium and
magnesium and sodium were in my water
which is as you know very important
because we see we tend to see at least
the water test I see the biggest issues
I see are usually heavy metals and
salinity so sodium
I haven't seen super high magnesium
water but that's just I think the areas
of the country that I've happened to
work with but it's it's absolutely a
concern so
um Paul you're nodding your head too do
you want to add anything to that
oh no I'm just saying if you want to see
some high calcium and magnesium come on
over to Kentucky I'll show you some some
test results so with that Limestone base
but yeah no you're absolutely spot on
it's not something that Municipal uh
water facilities will often test and
also it can vary so for example here in
Kentucky
um you're just based on where your water
is coming from and you know the the flow
of the groundwater itself you can have
variability over you know weeks or
months so you know you may dial in and
then test your water three months later
and your calcium and your magnesium
could be completely different and so
that can impact your acidification so
yeah test early test often yeah and for
those of you that are in
uh the soilless potting soils or living
soils they're making your own soil I
tend to not even add a magnesium
input like I don't I don't like to
necessarily use Dolomite lime I don't
use
silpo mag kmeg whatever you can call it
there's a lot of um inputs I mean you'll
get a little bit of magnesium from a lot
of different organic soil amendments
already and just with the compost
fraction you probably have some level of
magnesium sufficiency just based on this
the number of soil tests I've seen
and again since it's it's probably the
easiest organic supplement to add you
know since we do have access to uh
magnesium sulfate or Epsom salt it's
just it's soluble it's it's just it's
really easy so I it's something that I
feel like I can always add to my soil
but like it's much harder to subtract so
I just want to throw that out as sort of
an ovary for people that are like myself
you know more on the organic living soil
side of things
good
um
well guys uh
I feel like we've really covered
magnesium quite a bit
um
do you have anything else to add on
magnesium or do you have any future uh
research that you're excited about right
now that you're working on or what are
even just your future plans
professionally for for both of you guys
um Patrick you want to start us off yeah
I'll lead into it
um you know him hemp work wise uh been
playing around with some other nutrient
work
um looking at micronutrient uptake
looking at some amendments to soilless
substrates and then playing around with
some different Aggregates and looking at
substrate ratios is kind of the
direction that I'm playing around with
right this moment and that's been it's
been very interesting uh hopefully
looking to build off that more in 2023
and take that for research we've done
and take it to the next level
um
but then it's just all been soilless
media looking at different blends for me
uh starting to move more
into uh how to make good soilless
substrate and look at how to be more
renewable with it
um is kind of the direction that I've
been heading for the 2023
um and then I know Paul's been looking
at a lot of different him things as well
well uh before we we go over to Paul
um Patrick if you ever want to look into
uh living soils and reamending the soils
and treating them like an agricultural
commodity from a state of sustainability
perspective I think it's it's really
exciting from a science perspective I
think it's really interesting but it's a
little bit more challenging especially
on the IPM side as I'm sure you guys
know
um I want to ask you what substrates uh
you're experimenting with right now
because from a sustainability
perspective I would love to eventually
move away from coca-core and peat moss
as sort of the dominant media options in
our industry
at least on the organic side obviously
rockwool is
horrible environmentally
is there anything there because I've
looked into a few different Medias uh
option or substrate options and I
haven't found anything
that will perform anywhere near the
levels of what I can get from from peat
moss right now
I'm still using peat moss as my base
um
an individual you may want to look into
his research be Dr Brian Jackson with NC
State he's done a lot of work with wood
fiber
so just looking at using pine trees to
completely replace
p and all the other Aggregates and they
have looked at a lot of different peat
Blends and other wood Blends
um
in order to try and dial that in he has
done some work with him Paul could
probably make a little bit better
comment on his hemp work
um but he does a lot of wood fibers and
alternative substrate to completely
replace Pete
um but that's
probably the most prominent one that
I've heard of completely alternative to
Corn Pete
I I've looked into that a bit I've been
a bit stymied either on uh price or on
I get I guess growth metrics but I I
haven't given a pope I I feel like
there's something there's something
there but
um yeah I would love to I would love to
talk to him down the road I think you
guys in did an introduction so I need to
follow up on those emails and see if I
can keep pestering them to get him on
the podcast
yeah uh how about you Paul
well I'll go into my future here in just
a sec I wanted to make one comment that
um I think part of the reason why
um coca-core and Pete has become a bit
of an issue
um is kind of the
The General
a general theme in agriculture is we
tend to find one thing that works and we
tend to just use it use it use it use it
and use it and if you look at um true
sustainability you know like a
diversified Network it's kind of like a
good Investment Portfolio you want to
have a diversified portfolio you want to
have a diverse product and diverse
products that you can build into the
system and and that goes with pretty
much anything you know fertilizers
substrates Etc and I think that really
where a lot of the future research is
going to have value is finding those
things that won't completely replace
something but are going to help move us
towards a diversified portfolio so that
we start alleviating stress and start
moving these industries to be more of a
sustainable consumption
um you know and obviously moving more
and more towards as sustainable as we
can get but just wanted to add that as
well so you're saying even if we just
added 20 wood fiber to our
our substrate recipe that's going to
have a dramatic impact
um in a beneficial way towards our
overall sustainability even if we're not
completely replacing Peter core
I'm not a substrate specialist so I mean
I'll let Jackson come on here I'll let
Jackson come on here and answer that
question but yes theoretically from a
conceptual thing if you're even
replacing just 20 that's 20 before
that's that's fair you scientists are so
so good about not speaking out of your
lane
yeah yeah well that's that's why Jackson
has so much value so what what's in the
future for you
um are you getting close to uh to
graduating
yeah so right now I'm slated to graduate
fall of 2024 or spring of 2025.
um obviously in the research world
nothing is ever a hardcore perfect set
um timeline you know you could have a
bad ear you could have a crop failure
especially when you're doing field level
stuff
um but as far as uh for me you know like
I said focusing more on germination
establishment rhizosphere metrics so
right now really what we're doing
heavily is looking at roots and trying
to image those roots and figure out how
root phenotypes and how they're actually
growing to help us with the rhizosphere
management
um but um as far as what I want to do
for the future
um you know I I love research I've
always been insatiably curious
um you know and I love being able to
take that research and not just have it
be some sort of
data that sits there but actually
turning it into a meaningful and
applicable story for people
um and one that's actually going to help
the industry and Growers so for for my
future I don't know if that's industry I
don't know if Academia but I know that
definitely that that Outreach
um with with Growers and with the
industry and and specifically research
and development would definitely be an
Avenue that I'm that's the exciting
thing about this crop right and I think
that's the reason all of us are here is
because
we feel like there's so much more to
learn and we don't have all the answers
um like I think corn would be really
boring now like the research has been
done like we're on a new frontier here
and I think that's so exciting
um
yeah well and Grain and fiber too I mean
I know that you know that's not your
your focus necessarily here Tad but like
you know don't don't underestimate the
value that those could have as a
launched commodity
um as well and again it will just add
more research dollars and more value to
this industry in in all of its avenues
that would be an interesting topic
because I don't really know a lot about
the fiber side of things it just hasn't
been a focus and I'd be curious to know
where what opportunities exist in that
industry as infrastructure for
processing the fiber grows as demand for
the fiber grows
yeah I think that would be I think that
would be really interesting
so maybe that's a future podcast topic
uh all right so last question before we
sign off have you guys done any work
with biostimulants so looking
specifically at microbes and their role
in uh nutrient uptake in the rhizosphere
um is that something either of you have
a an interest in or have done any
research on
or see future research
so
as as far as the work that was done at
NC State
um there there we did not look into
biostimulants or bio additives
um um so that was some research that um
a few a few companies that expressed
interest in
um but it just you know sometimes the
Stars don't align as far as the the
funding or follow through so you know
it's just
it it's definitely an area that needs to
be studied there's a wealth of knowledge
out there that shows just how much value
these these microbial communities can
have not only to the plant but also to
the network to you know the the
rhizosphere to you know nutrient cycling
nutrient availability and everything
something that you know you live and
breathe Tad with you and your company
and the excellent work that you guys do
but uh who knows maybe uh future I I
believe it's the future of agriculture
in a lot of ways as we hit Peak
phosphorus as we see limitations in
supplies we need to figure out ways to
better utilize the nutrients and
elements that are available and that's
where I think you know these microbes
are so complex it's really daunting to
try and study it because they have a
synergistic effect you can't just
isolate one and expect to understand it
fully and
it's a bit of a
yeah it's it kind of hurts my brain to
think about it or even begin to try and
construct a a reasonable research study
around it but I do think there's
something there even if we can't fully
understand it at this point
so
yeah
yeah I couldn't agree more well uh I
just want to thank both of you for your
time today for sharing your research for
doing this research and the impact it
has and benefits for Growers you know
like myself that are always interested
in learning more so I hope we can stay
in touch and continue to to share this
information so Growers can do a better
job in their Gardens
wonderful thank you for having us yeah
yeah
thanks for having us we uh we all only
get better together so the the work you
Do's had on on the podcast and
everything it really really does make a
difference thanks for having spec
[Music]
that was Paul coxson and Patrick veezy
and you are listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram if you want to support the
podcast check out our new patreon for
some unique benefits or the wide range
of products we offer on our website
ranging from soils amendments beneficial
insects LED lights soil test analysis
and Consulting you can also sign up for
our newsletter on our website homepage
to stay up to date on the latest
research and information thanks for
listening
foreign
[Music]