[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of kis Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
organic growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge today we are
honored to be interviewing Steve Solomon
all the way from Tasmania Steve is the
author of numerous books most notably
gardening west of the Cascades and the
intelligent Gardener can we start off
today talking about your own personal
journey and how you came to write the
intelligent Gardener which focuses on
soil remineralization and nutrient
density you know you're asking me to
tell you about my whole
life
uh and uh there's uh not enough time to
do that so I'm going to uh condense
things as as best I can and if I wander
you stop me so I I wanted to live a life
where I worked as little as possible and
I conceived the idea that if I could
produce as much of my own stuff as I
could and I wouldn't have to earn money
or pay taxes on it and I might have a
much better lifestyle so we moved from
Los Angeles sold the business bought
five acres in Oregon that looked real
pretty to us I knew because I read all
the organic gardening literature I had
been subscribing organic gardening mag
and I've read their books and I knew
this was the truth uh that I could take
any Oak Clay Pit or gravel Heap and uh
uh turn it into a garden of eaten as
long as I put enough compost into the
ground and maybe some
lime so I found this beautiful green
Hillside in Oregon in the springtime and
uh uh I could afford it and was just 5
Acres of bare land with some little
Douglas gr trees self seating on it and
enough that was flat enough that I could
put in a garden and uh moved on to it
and I put in a big garden and started to
eat out of it and then one thing after
another happened and uh a few years
later I found myself in the seed
business uh not knowing how to do it uh
not knowing how to make any money at it
it took me uh two years of being in the
business before I learned to make a
little bit of a profit well I basically
taken every every bit of money I had
left which by the way was
$113,000 okay now you're referring to
territorial seed there that's right
territorial Seed Company yeah it got
capitalized with all the $113,000 that I
still have yeah it's a highly
successible Seed Company yes yeah it
became that but in the first few years I
had no idea how to run a seed business
and uh how to charge for the seed or you
know I had to learn but I tried to do it
honestly so so I put in a trials ground
uh if you find a seed company doesn't
have a trials ground go the other way uh
they're
just um not somebody i' want to uh
admire or do business with I won't use a
lot of other language so there I was uh
with a business that was not making me
any money truly the first year I made
nothing uh took nothing out of it
because everything everything I just
needed everything to try to do the next
year the next year I actually managed to
take $4,000 out of the business and
pretty much lived on that
$4,000 and the year after that I took
$7,000 out of the business and then it
got better then it went 14 28 you know
40 I started doing well but uh in the
beginning uh it was pretty difficult so
what kept me going was the trial ground
now I had a a lady friend at that time
uh who became Mrs Solomon her name was
Isabelle Moser and she ran the Great Oak
school of health and she was a
naturopath who practiced medicine
without a license and had always avoided
going to prison for for any of the uh
crimes that she was committing uh like
practicing medicine without a license or
having somebody with cancer who was
dying and sent home to die by the
doctors come and stay with her and try
to recover and they died anyway and then
you know there's manslaughter
charges uh and there's all that sort of
thing I don't know if you're aware of
how health Alternative Health is
suppressed in the United States but she
was a very brave Outlaw and Isabelle
told me that I would be a lot healthier
uh the more vegetables that I ate and
that the fact that I didn't have any
money and had all these trials was
really a great opportunity for me and
all I really need to do was learn how to
live on vegetables almost completely and
the more I did that the healthier I'd
become oh well that seems to make sense
so I did that and the more I did that
the more unhealthful I became
and um Isabelle uh came and moved in
with me uh and she started eating the
same vegetables and the more she ate
them the less healthful she became
although she was extraordinarily healthy
woman uh she began to experience uh uh
brittle hair and uh uh thin fingernails
that sort of stuff and I started to have
uh teeth that got a bit wobbly sort of
had off days and felt grouchy and lost
energy and things started seemed
difficult and life seemed stressful so
after about four years in the business I
was making enough money and things were
organized well enough that we took off
six months and I just didn't do trials
that year and we went away at the
beginning at the end of the spring and
didn't come back until after Christmas
and uh went to Fiji and that's where I
had this uh illumination where we just
started eating the fruits and vegetables
in the market uh in Fiji in sua and uh
we didn't go to the tourist Fiji we went
to the capital city of Fiji and lived
with the Fijian people and did what you
do in subba it's not a place most
tourists went the market there had all
the usual um European vegetables uh as
well as a whole lot of tropical stuff
and uh we ate all that stuff including
we found it all tasted really good uh we
started eating okra too and we ate
plenty of beans and and and they had
green we had cook greens of various
kinds we anyway we ate more or less the
same kind of diet we'd always been
eating and my teeth got tight in my jaw
on her fingernails got hard and her F
hair got beautiful and we had much more
energy and we felt much better and uh I
wanted to find out what was going on so
I I made some inquiries and found out
that all those vegetables that we've
been eating came from the Singa Valley
which was an hour and 20 minutes drive
out of subba so we rented a car for the
day we never had a car there and we only
had one for the one day but we rented a
car for the day and drove up to the
Singa Valley and I rung ahead and booked
myself in to have a visit with the
research station that they had up there
in the valley and uh they showed me
around and told me how the farmers grew
vegetable crops and and that they never
used fertilizer and that they'd grown
vegetables for 75 years in that Valley
uh European type vegetables and they'
never used any fertilizer in 75 years
but they did use lots of pesticides
uh and I think he said the reason they
had to do that was that when you grow
European French beans snap beans you
call them in the United States uh in the
tropics so there's a lot of things that
want to eat them you know but they were
grown without fertilizer the reason that
it worked is is that the The Watershed
of the Singa River has is an area of
extraordinarily highly mineralized Rock
uh of a type that's called Ultra basic
ous Rock and it basically means it's
just ch choco block with plant nutrients
cat I with calcium and magnesium and
pottassium and iron and zinc and
manganese and
copper it's just loaded with all that
stuff it makes soils that tend to be
neutral to slightly alkaline which is
why they call it Ultra basic ous rock
well that stuff comes down the Singa Riv
River as silt and about every three
years there's a Cyclone or what they
call a cyclone there or would you call a
hurricane and uh the sing singota floods
and it covers the entire valley floor no
one has a house on the valley floor
except the government research station
which is up on a sort of a
mound um everybody who Farms There lives
on the little bit on the slopes outside
the valley anyway it deposits a Sil and
every 3 years or so there's a large
deposit of freshly ground rock dust of
the most mineralized sort you could ever
want want to have and uh during the
Rainy it has a two- season climate
there's a dry mild season when the
weather is like beautiful mild spring
day a mild summer day in Washington you
know and it's it's 78 degrees and the
sun is shining and you know uh the only
difference is that in the dry season
there the kns would never go down below
about I don't know
65 something like that they're always
mild and shirt sleeve weather then it
gets rainy and hot and humid and it gets
so humid and so hot that all those
vegetable crops die of disease and the
fields get taken over by weeds and the
weeds grow mid chest High uh for about
five months and then it stops raining
and they get in there and plow the weeds
under and they decompose rapidly and
that's the organic matter and I think
the decomposition of the organic matter
also helps release minerals out of the
rock dust and uh they plant their
vegetable seeds and they grow beautiful
crops and it tastes really good and made
us incredibly healthy despite the p
pesticide residues and I had to figure
that out because I believed in organic
stuff I was a believer in all that rale
[ __ ] so so Steve let me pause you so
just to clarify the soil where all the
vegetables that you were eating at your
time in Fiji was grown in a particular
Valley where no fertilizer was being
used whatsoever but that's right a
variety of chemical pesticides that uh
did not fit with your current organic
Dogma or ideals that's right and my
belief system at that time would have
told me that those pesticides were bad
for me and that there's no way I could
possibly be healthy if I'm eating food
with pesticide residues on and I came
away from there with a different opinion
which was after I thought it over and
you asked me about it a few years later
I think I would have told you and a lot
of
audiences that and I came up with a
wonderful line that I used to use when I
lectured I said the problem is not that
there's residues of pesticides in our
food the problem is uh uh that there's
only residues of nutrition left their
our Foods so you're not claiming that
pesticides are necessarily good but
rather that the level of mineral content
in our vegetables is so
depleted because our soils are so
depleted that um it's affecting our n
Nutri our nutrient levels and our health
way more than these Trace Trace elements
of of pesticides that may be left on the
vegetable itself yeah well the trace
elements wouldn't hurt us but the
pesticides the residues of the
pesticides yes they are an insult to our
body they are poisons okay and our
bodies are designed to deal with insults
and poisons uh and uh the better
nourished the body is and the healthier
the body is the better it is at handling
that sort of stuff so a very
well-nourished body would be much less
affected by pesticide residues generally
speaking on an average and we're talking
statistics here not about any individual
case sure so just to bring it back to uh
your time in Fiji so you you discovered
this knowledge and then uh winter winter
came and you had to head back to Oregon
at that point that's right and how did
that guide your gardening or your uh
your experiences moving forward after
you left Fiji well it didn't really nail
home for about a year because we came
back from Fiji and we felt really good
we were enjoying life I mean uh we were
we were youngsters we were your age or
not much older you know we still didn't
have much sense and uh so we just went
back into it and Isabelle was an athlete
she did triathlons and got in endurance
a Athletics and I got back into my
business and writing and after about a
year we noticed that her fingernails
were getting soft again and her hair was
deteriorating and my energy level was
dropping and my positive attitude was
harder to maintain some days uh and my
teeth were starting to worsen
again and I said [ __ ] you know it's the
food we're eating it's it's that trials
ground that we're eating off of what's
wrong with it you see I didn't really
know I had been using uh sort of like a
primitive approach to complete organic
fertilizer at that time uh I had already
evolved that uh and there was a a ratio
of limes I always I I wanted to have a
ratio of calcium to magnesium that was 7
to1 so I tried to put in a mixture of
dolomite and agim to come up with about
7 to1 because I didn't know anything
about soil testing I figured well the
best thing I can do is put it in at 7
to1 sure and not put it in too fast uh
you know and I I I did I got a lot of
information I started doing research and
I mean if you want I can tell you about
all the mistakes I made along the way
but well what what I would like to maybe
focus in on then is so you started
researching this and I know from reading
your book more than one time actually
that uh you focused on some of the work
by Price yeah and the the dental records
which I think is really fascinating and
then you also started looking into
remineralization with um some of the
work by William albrech maybe if you
could touch on both of those findings
briefly that would be wonderful yeah and
just let me just sort of put a warning
out there that um I write this book
called growing vegetables was the
Cascades and it's been through seven
editions and every one of those editions
except one has been a complete rewrite
it's a totally different book every
single time it comes out with the same
title okay and so uh some of the earlier
editions have versions of complete
organic fertilizer or make assertions
about the nature of the soils or what
you should do that today I would
consider incorrect so I I contradict
myself from book to book yeah so I I
just don't want people to uh uh get
stuck uh if they've got an older book or
believe something that I said back in
198 888 or
1992 uh I mean that was only from a very
limited partial understanding of the
whole thing it took a long time before I
got it all worked out sure I would I
would say that's one of the things that
I really appreciate about you as an
author is that you are open-minded to
learning new things and changing your
mind on subjects as you become uh more
experienced or more educated on a
particular subject thank you um I think
that's one of my strong points too or
weak points anyway the older I get the
more I realize I'm not so damn smart you
know so can you tell our listeners a
little bit about what you learned from
uh price in particular Western price
gosh his book nutrition and physical
degeneration is in my opinion the most
important book that was written in the
20th century and I'm I mean you can even
put Einstein in their top 10 or all
those any other book you come up with
because see price did something for us
that's absolutely Priceless he
documented the existence of groups of
people that no longer are the way he
documented them in the
1930s there still were places on this
planet that were so isolated that the
people who lived there completely ate
the food that they got there and they
didn't bring in any food they were poor
usually and very simple they lived in
hard to get at places that nobody wanted
uh you know little remote Valley
somewhere someplace we had to trekk in
Pakistan through passes that were frozen
and ice snow 9 out of 12 months of the
year you know and go up so thin you
could hardly walk with the danger of
slipping off the edge and dying every
300 meters you know on a really
dangerous Trail for a couple three days
of this to get there places like that so
price had heard about these places and
he was interested in Dental Health from
the point of view of preventative
Dentistry he spent his whole life trying
to work in there he had failed
completely as as a research scientist he
never could figure out how to prevent
people from having bad teeth he'd see
occasional people who had bad really
good teeth but why is it just their
genes is it where they grew up is it was
it their diet there was no way to know
and he said the only way we're ever
going to sort this is if we have a
control group and we don't have a
control group but maybe these people are
a control group he says I hear that
these people in these remote places have
extraordinary good health and almost
perfect teeth all of them let's go and
have a look so he and his wife organized
these uh basically TRS into remote
places with the assistance of the local
medical authorities usually because
price was quite well known globally uh
as a medical you know Dental researcher
so he went and visited these people and
he did this over three years uh very
extended uh trips by ship of course to
different continents and then Journeys
to these places and he went with I don't
know how many people he went with I'd
really do I'd love to know the det
details of who how how how he organize
these things but he took a lot of
photographs very high quality black and
white pictures he had a lab with him
where he he didn't analyze the soils
they had only primitive knowledge of
nutritional aspects of food but what
albre did know how to find out oh excuse
me what price knew how to find out was
the mineral content of the food vitamins
were just being discovered they weren't
sure what they were exactly you know
their chemical formulation was not known
all the B vitamins were just sort of
lumped together and I think they were
called B vitamins because they were
water
soluble um but they didn't know one from
the next but price was able to Ash the
food he could take a sample of food and
he could heat it up until he burned off
all the carbon and all he had was some
Ash and then he could use Simple
analytical chemistry and say in that Ash
there was so much potassium so much
phosphorus so much calcium so much
magnesium
and that's what he did so he collected
that data from several dozen groups of
people and took photographs of often
quite old people with all the teeth in
their jaw and obviously in good health
and documented all kinds of anecdotal
evidence and looked at questions like
are the people in this remote place so
healthy because they have special genes
and not like the people down in the
valley who don't have those genes and
that's why they have good teeth and the
people in the valley have rotten keeth
no that's not what happened actually he
got documentation of young people from
the remote place with perfect key so
went down to the town to have an
adventure and stayed there for three
years ate the food down there and came
back home with a mouth full of
Decay and then he'd find in many of
those people that the carries the dental
cavities actually had healed and uh had
scarred over with naturally occurring
enamel but it was obviously scar tissue
and the body had healed those cavities
isn't that amazing all up uh those
people were
intaking two three four times the
mineral nutrition of the average
American in the
1930s so basically the the quality of
the food that they were growing from a
mineral perspective was much higher and
therefore their own health which was
reflected in their dental records and
their Dental Health was much higher as
well so they didn't have a lot of the
tooth decay and problems that you were
seeing right in other areas of the world
at that time another way to say that
would be that the designer of the human
body designed it so that if it was
adequately nourished it would keep all
of its teeth for its entire lifetime and
they would be in perfect condition and
they would be tighten the jaw and the
only thing that would affect them would
be uh eating a whole lot of abrasive
stuff that wore them down in which case
they also had the ability to replace the
hard coating on the outside if you're
well alert nourished enough which is how
those cavities heal or else you played
Sports you know and you got a few teeth
knocked
out but other than that that's the
body's design you see it's it's how it's
made the body is made to last uh I don't
know 110 years okay let's say on average
which means that if we all had perfect
nutrition for a few Generations because
just one generation all of a sudden
starting on perfect nutrition does not
make perfect babies the actually the
nutrient density of mothers has to
increase and it takes several
generations for a line of females to
develop sufficient nutritional reserves
that they can then form a perfect fetus
and then nourish it with you know with
breast mil that fetus would then go on
to have an average LIF span of 110 years
probably Steve just to uh bring this
back to plants obviously
remineralizing soils is important from a
nutrition perspective in terms of our
own human health what are you finding
though in terms of the health of your
and growth of your plants by adding
these minerals back into your soil I
started intentionally remineralizing a
year before the intelligent Gardener
came out so that was I mean kind of like
where I was dealing with Trace elements
and really with the kind of
remineralization that I'm advocating
these days so ever since then my food
has tasted better every single year year
on year and it's still happening not all
of it but some of the crops uh sometimes
of vegetables the flavor improved a
great deal uh for the first few years
and then it sort of
stabilized uh and it's very nice that'
be stuff that's shallow rooted crops
like lettuce cuz I got the top soil
remineralized first you see but the
trouble is how do you remineralize the
next 6 in down the nextx foot down
because vegetables will put Roots down a
lot further than most people realize if
they can and if they don't encounter a
lot of nutrition down there they don't
do as well this is especially true of of
root crops like carrots and parsnips and
beetroot these crops and all the chores
they all feed in the subsoil chies you
know are a root crop that just makes
edible leaves in the same way that
parsley is a root crop that makes edible
leaves the chicken chory let me tell you
what happened with my
chory we like to eat Indi but it has a
problem it tends to be bitter and it has
another problem in the winter time in
the humid weather and the cool humidity
of our autumn and winter uh it develops
a leaf disease that tends to cause rot
spots and and it can get worse and worse
until it rots back to a stump and get so
spotted with these things you don't want
to eat it anymore and it'll kill it
eventually in a wet winter doesn't
happen anymore I thought that was the
nature of endog you know and it was hard
to grow in the humidity of the winter
and you put the plants further apart and
you do everything possible to increase
air circulation and it doesn't rot as
quickly but it in a wet winter you're
just going to lose it I thought that was
a nature of Endive now it doesn't happen
anymore now it just laughs at that
disease doesn't happen anymore because
when the Endive starts to try to feed
down two feet down it's finding
nourishment now it just took years to
leech it down there so you're seeing an
increase in disease resistance
essentially huge at the same time
there's another problem with mve right
it's
bitter well at the same time that the
endives stopped having problems with the
spots on the leaves it stopped being
nearly as bitter and started actually
being so sweet we can eat it like
lettuce so improving the quality of the
flavors and odors of your given crop
essentially a great deal people who eat
with us are just Gob smacked at how good
our food taste they don't have a clue
how good vegetables can taste until they
taste my vegetables or how satisfying
they can be and how much less inclined
we are to eat other things than
vegetables because the vegetables are
just so so rich I don't know how to put
it sure everyone has had the experience
of eating conventionally grown or
hydroponic tomato from a grocery store
or going out to a real farm and picking
one off a Vine and and the difference in
the in the flavor is
dramatic right now if you could go to
that farm and walk the rows of a variety
trial and taste 30 different kinds of
tomato all at the same time okay you'd
find there was a lot of difference and
some of them had a lot better flavor
than others but if you could take and
put a couple of parallel rows with the
same varieties and you fully
remineralized one row and you didn't
with the other the plants might not look
call that different but you would sure
notice the taste difference in the same
variety from the two different soil
circumstances another thing that happens
with remineralized food it doesn't mold
after you harvest it you know if you
just let it sit out on the counter uh it
doesn't grow mold it just sort of slowly
loses moisture and shrinks a little bit
it stops being quite as crisp it just
sits there you know it it stores a whole
lot better if you put it in the fridge
okay so can you can you touch a little
bit on how grower or a gardener would
use some of these principles in terms of
adding these these minerals back into
their soil so I know that in your book
you talk a lot about soil testing can
you describe that process to someone
that would be new to this subject yeah
but I want to back up one step and I
want to talk about targets what are we
trying to accomplish the soil test is
just the tool that we use to accomplish
it with but uh I think we want to start
talk about what it is you're trying to
do albre worked out the basics of this
stuff he worked out roughly the
relationship the levels of calcium and
magnesium and pottassium and phosphorus
that a plant needed to produce a lot of
protein and to be very healthy such that
the livestock had ate it would also be
very healthy but he didn't finish the
work he probably didn't because the soil
testing procedures available at that
time uh weren't sophisticated enough to
do soil testing inexpensively it would
have been a it would have cost a great
deal to determine how much copper and
zinc and manganese and stuff there was
in the soil or
Boron you know in those days it could
have been done I think but it uh now
it's easy now for $14
us and a little bit of postage to send
60 gram of soil to a lab in Ohio uh I
can get an accurate reading uh of the
levels of all those elements in the soil
now are you referring to Logan Labs with
that no actually I'm not I'm talking
about one called Spectrum analytic okay
loog Logan is $25 for their standard
soil test I believe Logan's um
presentation the way they give you the
information is probably a little more
friendly to an amateur otherwise there's
not a lot of difference I mean they come
up with roughly the same kinds of
numbers they may differ but if they
differ it's all because all the numbers
from one will be 10% higher than all the
numbers from the other and in
practicality it doesn't really matter
what really matters is the relationship
between all those numbers and they'll be
the same from both Laboratories it took
the work of a whole lot of really smart
Farm advisors who sort of took alre as a
springboard and uh they developed a
philosophy of fertilizing soil called
base cat IR balancing the idea is is to
bring the levels of the plant nutrients
up to a point and a balance that
produces Optimum Health in those that
eat the food and at the same time
produces a very big yield and very
healthy plants that don't have as much
trouble with insects and diseases and
all that stuff which is all very good
and also you don't get that kind of
result unless the land is healthy so
part of the process is maintaining
enough organic matter in the soil okay
so it's a sort of generative or positive
sort of Agriculture where you're
building real soil fertility uh and
better health of the entire ecosystem to
produce a result in the crops that you
want the trouble with that approach is
it it does not appeal to a greedy
selfish farmer who just wants to make
the biggest bottom line they can because
the economic logic of the farmer is is
their profit is result of how much they
can shortcut the inputs the more they
can reduce the cost of input
the more money they can make so these
soil tests traditionally are focused
around minimums for yield isn't that
correct to where they're not talking
about necessarily looking at their
recommendations are not necessarily for
optimal plant growth or health or soil
building but rather minimums to allow
for no plant deficiencies yeah the the
the word is
sufficiency okay there's two
philosophies here about how to fertilize
there's the economically rational
philosophy and then there's the uh
ethical philosophy you might say so the
economic rationalists they just want to
make sure that there's enough of all the
plant nutrients that the crop will
produce a lot and enough is defined this
way putting any more in will not result
in any increase in yield that is anyway
relates to the cost of putting more in
so other words we put it in until the
yield Peaks out and then you don't put
it anymore because it's not economically
rational you're better off to use your
money for something else so they target
lower levels than somebody who is being
ethical about their food would want to
Target they want to make sure there's
enough copper there that the plant isn't
obviously copper deficient in having any
gross copper deficiency symptoms but the
idea that having 10 times that amount of
copper in the soil might do something to
the total balance of nutrition in the
crop more protective substances more
phytonutrients more of the stuff that
the plant uses to protect itself against
insect and diseases that then when the
human eats the plant helps us protects
us against diseases and things you see
they don't think about that stuff sure
now most of our listeners are uh
cannabis Growers now you have a high
value crop here to where you can put
more into your soil and you can build
your soil so uh how does that influence
uh your say your recommendations or how
you would treat the soil knowing that
you can afford to put throw throw a
little bit more at the crop in terms of
minerals and nutrients well listen
you're just very lucky in this respect
that you asked me this question because
now there's no way that I could talk
about me growing cannabis here in
Tasmania because it isn't legal sure but
it just so happens that I have a friend
who has a license to grow
hemp and we are growing hemp here in
Tasmania now and it's a burgeoning
industry uh that the government is
actually trying to forward um they have
a certain problem with it in the um they
also want to have total control over it
and want to make sure that nobody does
an extraction from hemp and gets CBD oil
out of it without them calling it
medicine and having it in their
system but in any case he asked me uh if
I would do some soil testing for him and
make recommendations about what to do to
grow a good hemp crop and I've done that
so I got some idea the kind of nutrition
hemp would need if you were thinking
about it from the point of view of
farming it you know raising it by the
acre and planting it like wheat so hemp
needs hemp first of all it makes a lot
of fiber plants that growing
vegetatively like him they probably need
twice as much potassium as most
vegetable
crubs and they take a lot of it out of
the soil if somebody were to be growing
it in the same place they would have to
and we're actually taking the the
material out of the field then they
realize they're taking a lot of
potassium when they when they take it
out of the ground hemp uses a lot of
manganese for some reason it just draws
a lot of Manganese it helps the plant be
more healthy it uses a great deal of it
that brings up an interesting question
for me Steve y well it's sort of a two
point two-part question so my first
question is traditionally uh people on
these tests aim for p to equal K uh
phosphorus and and potassium be equal
now uh you're suggesting with cannabis
sort of fits what some of the findings
that I'm having as well saying that we
want to run potassium possibly a lot
higher than we would with phosphorus
that's right do you have any other
comments on that yeah I would think
that's right there's one thing about my
experience that may be different with
the can with scrollers all right and
that is I'm talking about growing stuff
in the soil in the field where uh you're
about several feet of growing media
beneath your feet uh a lot more root
Zone than you can put into a small pot
if you start putting plants in synthetic
growing medium in in indoors now you're
dealing with a medium that doesn't have
any exchange capacity
usually and this is an interesting
conversation if you're growing in
something that has no buffering capacity
do you use that term buffering
capacity a little bit this may be
getting a little technical for some some
of the listeners but yes so the the
soils that we we manufacture here at
kiss Organics they range in Cc or cadine
exchange capacity I I'd have to look at
a test I don't have one in front of me
but I think they're around anywhere
between 20 to 30 that's quite high in
fact I would like it very much if you
off off later if you'd share with me
maybe on another day even what it is you
use uh to get that kind of exchange
capacity in a synthetic medium I would
imagine youd use vermiculite and
charcoal and really good compost but I
can't think of anything else anyway if
you can load up your exchange capacity
uh in your growing medium with the plant
nutrients that it needs then I'd say
you'd want it to test kind of the same
way as soil that you'd want to grow
tomato plant in with the exception that
you'd want potassium up a bit higher and
then with another exception too if
you're not feeding the crop mostly with
soluble fertilizers you see if you if
you got a growing medium in a container
that has no buffering capacity and
basically you're you're growing in
Hydroponics yeah even if it looks like
soil even if you've got living compost
in it even if there's you know an e an
ecology living in it if most of the
nutrition the plants are getting is
coming in the water that you're you're
feeding the pot with then it's
Hydroponics I'm not totally sure what
the proper levels would be to try to
duplicate that with dry fertilizers and
the kind of stuff we use out in the soil
see see out in the field we have another
thing or in a pot maybe that if you have
a large container with a growing medium
that has an exchange capacity over 20
then you could mix the nutrients into
the medium and they would then go onto
the exchange sites and sit there waiting
for the plant to draw them off that
would be a much better way of going
about it I think the plant would get
quite stable nutrition that way so I
would fertilize that stuff more or less
like I'd fertilize the field so you
would top dress with these uh dry
amendments or nutrients uh over over the
course of the plant's life like you
would in your garden is what you're
suggesting yeah I put as much of it as I
could into the soil without making it
too hot and then uh add more on the
surfaces the plant grw from what I know
about growing cannabis you actually want
to feed the crop quite differently
depending on whether it's flowering or
whether it's vegetating when it's
vegetating you want to feed it lots of
nitrogen and lots of potassium and a
fair amount of phosphorus and all the
trace elements oh we'll get into this
when we talk about fol your feeding and
all that sort of thing anyway you really
want that heavy and then when the plant
goes into bloom it's not making a lot of
vegetation anymore Growers need to
understand that mostly what nitrogen
gets used for is to make chlorophyll
chlorophyll is is a protein uh it's
nitrogen Rich so when the plant's
constructing leaves it needs a lot of
nitrogen and then the leaves are nice
dark green and they have a lot of active
chlorophyll in them and they make a lot
of sugar and they do a good job when the
plant starts to
bloom uh you know it stops making leaves
it starts making flower Mass this Mass
doesn't have very much chlorop and theol
cannabis Growers are try to breed the
leaves out of these flower structures as
much as possible because they're they're
less harsh uh when you smoke them they
talk about don't they talk about a ratio
kind of of like CX to leaves and that
sort of thing they they want lots and
lots of stigmas and lots and lots of
seed bracks but very little in the way
of leafy
structure or am I wrong toad yeah
essentially what they want the most
valuable part of the crop in most cases
which is uh not the fan leaves you know
we want yeah they want Tricom density
but then when we're looking at that
plant growth uh you know bud formation
and things like that there are nutrient
certain nutrients that are tied to this
but in addition to just these macro or
major nutrients that we're talking about
right now that nitrogen phosphorus uh
potassium calcium sulfur one of the
things that I think that you have really
promoted is adding in all these trace
minerals so oh yeah by by getting these
rock dusts into the soil we're going to
increase the the tpine levels the triome
density the the quality of the final
crop while also increasing the overall
health and yield of the plant yeah now
actually Tad there's something that you
could do that it wouldn't be free for
you to do it but uh you could answer a
really major question for me okay
because you are using Rock dusts okay
I've always had a lot of reservations
about rock dust when I lived in Oregon
there was a quarry into the old Cascades
Bessel and it was located right along
Interstate 5 between Cottage Grove and
crestwell Oregon and you could see it
when you went up the highway they M bass
salt for road base and things like that
Crush Rock and you could get dust if you
wanted you could just go there with
buckets and at the base of the conveyor
belt the dust Rock Dust just piled up as
deep as you wanted to shovel it up and
take it away and they were just as happy
to see you do that so I tried it and
used a whole lot of it and didn't seem
to do a great deal didn't seem to make
much difference that I could tell and I
got an analysis of it it actually has in
it all the trace elements that you want
but when you analyze the parts per
million and then think about how much
you're actually spreading and if it's if
I'm spreading a ton of rock dust and uh
it's three parts per million zinc well
in a ton there's what is that is that a
million a million grams anyway I think a
ton is something like a million G so if
it's three parts per million it means
that in a ton of that stuff I got three
G of Elemental Z you see in a ton now
when I Sprint zinc sulfate I want to SP
spread like seven pounds of Elemental
zinc on an acre and that's soluble see
so that goes out of zinc sulfate and it
goes into the soil solution and then it
attaches itself under the cat IR
exchange capacity if it's not
immediately picked up by a plant and uh
it sits there as available zinc to feed
the crop and I put 7 pounds of available
zinc basically into that field uh into
the fural slice into the top 100 top six
Ines of the soil and if I put out a ton
of rock dust I'm putting out say three
lounds of potentially available dink
someday when the stuff completely breaks
down whenever that happens so how much
unavailable zinc would I have to put out
to actually make S pounds of zinc
available on the exchange sites when you
start to ask that question it starts to
look like we're talking 15 20 30 40 tons
of the acre I I think I can give a
little bit of input on this so one thing
I want to distinguish before we go too
much further is that when we put out
rock dust or we add Alfalfa into our
soil uh we're not directly feeding our
plant but rather feeding these uh
microbes that are in the soil that are
cycling these nutrients into a form that
the plant can uptake so another
important aspect of gardening and
growing and farming is the is the
microbial populations that we have in
our soils and that's where high quality
compost becomes really important right I
knew you were going to say that by the
way that's also the uh party line of the
rock dust people who are pushing rock
dust and saying it's a solution it's how
they explain it and I've always had my
doubts I mean I just I'm I'm from
Missouri man you got to show me so what
I'm saying Tad is you could show me you
there is a way you could show me it's
real interesting all you got to do is
have some tissue testing done take some
of the nice leaves from some of your
cannabis that you've been growing with
this rock dust in the medium
and send them off to a lab that does
leaf analysis and find out uh if the
levels of copper and zinc and manganese
and Boron and that and uh in the leaves
are what you'd want unfortunately here
in Washington there is no uh tissue
testing as far as I'm aware of that's
legal for for cannabis um I believe
maybe in Oregon it's possible but it's
not that's not something we can do yet
oh that's right if you can't you can't
send the leaves to Oregon can you not
legally yeah we definitely can't mail
any anything right so it's just not
maybe possible to really answer this
question you well well I think it is so
to give you a little more information
when we mix our soils we're putting in
around 100 lbs of minerals and nutrients
per yard of soil so very very high level
of amendment that that soil is going to
actually heat up and thermally compost
for at least two weeks yeah uh but while
we're turning it and keeping it evenly
moist before we can it'll even cool down
to where we could plant into it so uh
we're putting in very very high levels
of a lot of these of these nutrients for
in our soil well this container so if
you put a plant uh in 50 lers of this
material that's a nice big pot right not
a 12in pot say you put it into a 14inch
pot yeah something with a good volume of
soil is there enough nutrients in there
that you can go plant from one end to
the other on just nothing but water we
found a sgon container is probably the
minimum and that that's going to vary
based on how long you're uh vegging your
plant before you flip it into flour but
we are finding that yes you can go the
full cycle now in a smaller container
like a 7 gallon we have a nutrient pack
which is essentially the dry amendment
that we put into our original soil mix
that we will Top dress the pot and
scratch into the surface at the end of
the first and the end of the third week
of flow just a/2 cup to a cup per plant
as a way to help it get those nutrients
by the time it's ready to finish what
we're finding is Growers that are doing
raised beds indoors or giving the plant
more soil as we discussed are able to
yeah are are able to grow uh larger
healthier crops because one thing you
may not be aware of is that in in the
Cannabis industry traditionally what's
happening is a grower is bringing soil
into into an indoor facility they are
maybe it's basement maybe it's a garage
maybe it's an actual warehouse and then
that soil is uh well soil or perlite
whatever their media is I guess is then
uh fed with either bottled nutrients
that are organic or ones that are ionic
salts or you know conventional and then
at the end of the cycle that soil that's
typically grown conventionally with
excessive nitrates and excessive
phosphates is then put outside and
disposed of because the salt levels are
way too high they can't reuse it not
without substantial leeching I imagine
anyway yes so then that that soil that's
primarily you know let's say cocoa based
or just perlite based is then dumped out
and leeching into our groundwater which
is a whole another problem and then
they're having to buy and bring in new
soil new bottled nutrients and start
over again so what uh myself and others
have been working on is essentially
creating a living soil indoors over time
by re amending these uh larger
containers every cycle in place so we
don't have to move the soil and out of
the facility and uh we have some Growers
that have been using the same soil up to
5 years now by just adding back organic
matter and adding nutrients back similar
as you would find in nature right so if
you did some soil testing on these
containers at the end of every crop and
got an idea of what was there already
you could then use sort of like the
intelligent Garden approach and figure
out what you needed to put in there to
bring them back into balance yes though
we do find that the uh the intelligent
Gardener one doesn't allow for that
higher potassium and a few other things
that seem to be more specific to
cannabis what we do have uh lab tests or
soil tests with Logan that show how
these levels are varying every crop
cycle based on the nutrients that we're
putting in at the beginning and at at
the beginning of the cycle so we can see
more or less what the plant is taking
out of the soil over time so I I can I
think yeah start to address your rock
dust question uh in that regard yeah you
can you can clear that up for me
because being an organic Gardener I
can't I don't feel comfortable adding a
lot of these uh sulfates so things like
uh zinc sulfate or copper sulfate um I
can't I don't think I can add them into
my soils according to NOP standards um
because they're not considered organic
same with manganese sulfate I would love
to know uh a good organic form of
manganese for example what is NLP uh the
national organic program so it's sort of
the standard NLP I misund Mard here in
Australia Organic certification agencies
will allow the grower to use sulfate
salts of Trace elements if a soil
analyst has determined by soil toast
that these things are deficient that's
the same law here but as someone who is
a making soils from container media um
it's not something that I want to get
into adding into my soil initially
because of the fact it isn't considered
you know completely organic yeah do you
know of other sources for some of these
I know Kel meal is one that you you talk
a lot about and how would you feel about
using Keel Trace elements that instead
of being copper sulfate or copper
gluconate people who use them say that
you don't need to use much more than
about half as much to have the same
result is that the biomin copper that
you're referring to yeah that's sort of
biomin biomin Trace elements you know I
haven't looked into that product I
believe it is Army certified though yeah
so you might feel okay you and your
client base might feel okay about using
that stuff if it would be acceptable
theoretically I think you should
experiment with it and see what it does
for you if anything now do you know of a
good source for manganese besides
manganese sulfate while we I know we
touched on that a minute ago not unless
there's a biomune form of Manganese I
don't know that's another difficulty
that I have you see where I live I'm way
out at the end of a long supply chain
and Australia is way out at the end of a
long supply chain so you people in North
North America have a lot more materials
and possibilities available to you than
we do down here as far as I know I don't
have any choice if I want to add
manganese I need manganese sulfate so
just to sort of summarize what we've
been talking about a little bit here for
a grower to test his soil or test his
his container growing media find out
what those levels are based on a soil
test they can then go back and amend
their soils properly to bring any levels
that are low or bring everything into
balance yeah let me let me I got stop
you here a little bit going backwards a
few minutes you could use the levels
that are recommended in the intelligent
Gardener to grow cannabis with the
exception of potassium so you could
still use the the targets that the
intelligent Gardener generates you see
for all the other elements it's just
that you probably want at least twice as
much potassium as inell as the
intelligent Gardener calls for I totally
agree with that we're finding the same
thing with our trials as well here so
that makes a lot of sense to me yeah but
the amounts of nitrogen if you think
about cannabis as a high demand crop
during the time that it's in vegetative
growth and then as a very low demand
crop when it's blooming and make sure
that during all of that time you see
because low demand crops don't demand
lower levels of Trace
elements or calcium they just really
mean lower levels of nitrogen because
are not making chlorophyll they're still
growing fast they're still building a
lot of mass just to clarify so what
you're getting at is essentially that
because cannabis is an is an annual
plant an annual crop it's going to
naturally want to sesse or complete its
life cycle and that's what that the
process of forming uh buds or flowers is
and during that process it doesn't need
as much nitrogen because it's not trying
to put on any vegetative growth that's
right in fact it might need a third as
much nitrogen or even a quarter as much
nitrogen as it needed while it was
growing new leaves now on that subject
one thing that Jeff lenells talks about
in in his book teaming with microbes is
that the plant is really in control of
this process based on uh the exudates it
it's putting out into the soil to
control sort of the the nutrient cycling
in microbial Loop um what's going on
there in the in the area around the
roots yeah do you have any any thoughts
or comments on that um it's just a sort
of gut level feeling and I hope you take
this the right way tab but see people
who want to believe in Organics and I
say want to believe in Organics then
they uh adjust things so that they make
a good story it's a good narrative okay
and that's what I think you're hearing
there and it there's some truth to it
and it does happen I've been learning
all kinds of things about how plants
talk to the microbes in their root Zone
get a collaborative relationship going
on I wouldn't even mind talking about
that it's really quite exciting
information I've been finding out how to
wind my plants up another 25 or 30% more
than they ever were before by fol or
feeding them the same kind of elements
that we've been talking about I've
discovered that plants cannot obtain all
the nutrients that they could use if
they could but get them not out of the
soil it doesn't matter what you put into
the soil it doesn't matter how
concentrated the soil is the plant could
use more of certain things at certain
times and if it gets them there's a
dramatic Improvement in the way that
plant grows the way you uh do that is
with fold of your feeding you see that
sounds really interesting Steve I would
love to uh do another segment talking
more about that now that the Growers
have a little bit of a foundation into
your philosophies and why this process
is important U I think it would be
wonderful to have you back on to talk
about that we'll go there another time
time you could write another book I
don't think so you younger people are
going to work this stuff out I'm 74 now
you know I'm just happy to get up now
and feel good today and go out there and
grow a few veggies sure I really am not
out to try to learn the whole thing as
much as I've already done I'm kind of
content at the moment so what what kind
of loose ends if we leaveing dangling we
must have not finish all kinds of things
in this conversation where would you
like to go boy you know I think we
covered a lot of it I would love to
follow up with you in another talk to
talk a little bit more about sort of the
connection between microbes and the soil
food web and this idea of
remineralization and how those two camps
have sort of been um butting heads uh in
in terms of their philosophies for for
many years and then I would love to talk
to you again about this foler feeding
idea that and how what your findings are
with that as well and I would like to
see a Logan leb's report on some of
these deep soil bits that you've been
running for five years and see what
Logan says they look like I can show you
a bunch of tests on that I think you'll
find it really interesting I would enjoy
seeing that t I'd like to talk to you
about
that thanks Steve appreciate you taking
the time to chat today all the way from
Tasmania don't forget to check out
Steve's latest book The intelligent
Gardener it's available on our website
at
www.k organics.com or on Amazon as a
digital download you are listening to
the Cannabis cult cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
stay tuned for future podcasts from
leading experts around the industry
don't forget that there's more
information and articles available on
our website and blog at
www.k organics.com and if you enjoy
these podcasts please take a moment to
leave me a review on iTunes and send me
your feedback and suggestions through
our website contact
[Music]
page