foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Brandon
Hudson Brandon is a second generation
cannabis cultivator with over 35 years
of direct experience with this amazing
plant
building on fundamentals learned as a
child Brandon has applied a controlled
approach to cannabis cultivation
starting with his first glance his
freshman year of college in 1986. he
currently works for kiss Organics
providing Growers with everything from
customer support to assistance with
nutrients and soil tests a well-rounded
and passionate organic grower Brandon's
real passions in soil chemistry most
recently Brandon was the director of
cultivation in one of four founding
members of a minority-owned hemp flower
farm in South Carolina he provided Sops
and oversight for all aspects of
cultivation from propagation to harvest
and cure including daily operation of a
large Nursery facility
in this role Brandon also performed
several federally funded hemp trials for
hbcus as well as research projects for
nutrient producers he is a proud dad and
husband who spends his free time
outdoors with his veggie gardens and
chickens this week's show is a bit
different as we get a lot of the same
questions at kiss Organics and thought
it would be fun to do a show covering a
lot of the most common ones now on to
the show
hey Brandon thanks for coming on the
show
hey Ted great to be here
yeah I mean I know we talk all the time
but I want to do this show kind of
talking about all the questions that you
get asked on a daily basis You Know
cover helping out with the phones and
doing a lot of the Agronomy and solo
analysis
um let's just start off right off the
bat talking about soil health
you get asked a lot about how to reuse
the soil kind of take me through sort of
what that process looks like with kiss
yeah so it really you know it's like
anything you you want a little bit of
background on their cultivation practice
are they in beds are they in pots that
sort of thing but after we get
information about you know how their
growth setup is
um it's all kind of similar uh or the
same across the board and so whether
they're in pots or in large Beds which
we prefer for various reasons
um at the when they're approaching the
end of around three weeks two weeks it
really depends on how organized they are
and how quickly they can you know get
things turned around do they have the
usual suspect list of amendments that
they'll most likely need on hand that
way they're not waiting to you know get
their test results and then order
amendments they can usually you know
about two weeks out take a soil sample
if they're in beds they could take a
couple of samples from each bed mix
those together homogeneously send off
two cups to Logan Labs if they're in
pots they can either dump all that soil
mix it together thoroughly which is kind
of my preference but that's a lot of
Labor to get that back into pots or they
can take samples from you know
representative pots mix that again again
send that off to Logan labs and get
their soil reports back
and so now we're armed to do the mineral
nutrition side of their soil so we'll
get that soil report back and we'll send
them a detailed recommendation of what
what amendments they need to get in and
that's that's pretty much it as far as
the the mineral side of it it's very
straightforward you know we're doing it
you know and you and I talked about this
the other day how incredible it is that
we can use metrics we don't have to
guess and so um I'm a big fan of the
soil reports and getting those
amendments in and then you've got the uh
biological side of the soil and then
you've got the physical components of
the soil that you need to deal with
physical components you know we're
mostly worried about compaction
over over time after a couple of rounds
we've got the organic matter breaking
down and we're starting to compact a
little bit and so every couple of rounds
for me it comes down to every four
rounds but everybody's different and so
I'll I'll add you know maybe six to
eight percent aggregate back into my
soil I prefer pumice
um you know I just escaped the the east
coast and the swamp and um I can say on
the East Coast it's almost impossible
unless you're ordering from the west
coast to get hummus and so a lot of
folks I recommend lava rock
um even hydrogen
um
hydrotton however you say it um but you
want to get some aggregate back in there
and perlite is not
a good choice perlite
um I used it for years
um I just I don't like it it's
eventually going to all float to the top
and end up in the floor and you're just
going to lose all of your aggregate so
it's just not a really good choice for
you
and then you've got to deal with the
biological side and that's all about
quality compost
um that's that's you know when people
are making their own soil you know East
Coast folks that can't afford shipping
who you know want to get a nutrient pack
from Kiss to get balanced new mineral
nutrients
their their Achilles heel is always
trying to find good compost and when you
get a compost not all composts are
created equally there's a short little
checklist you want to know the pH of
that compost just to make sure it's not
way out of range the carbon to nitrogen
ratio obviously if it's above 18 to 1 I
would I would find a different compost
you know the the carbon to nitrogen
ratio heavy metals those are the real
blockers
you know I want to look at sodium I want
to look at the cations as well but once
they have a suitable uh uh compost every
couple of rounds you can add that or
alternatively you can be getting your
biology through teas so
that you know there's there's some
options to do that but every couple of
rounds I do like to get some more
compost back in there
okay so just to highlight a few things
and add a little bit
um there's three big things that we're
looking at when we're reinvending soil
we want to look at the physical
properties of the soil which is
gas exchange aeration
moisture retention you know if you're if
you're buying potting soil that should
already be optimized or close enough to
optimize and that's just a matter of
maintaining it every cycle
um you mentioned the biological
properties of the soil you know if
you're on the west coast I'm going to
give a shout out to the New England
compost I've seen samples of it and
talked to them over there I think they
have a really nice product so if you're
out there you know checking check in
with those guys
um and if you don't want to bring in
compost to add organic matter because of
the risk of fungus gnats or other pests
things like that you could look into
making a compost tea or a compost
extract as a way of getting beneficial
microbes back into the soil or you could
use a specific microbial inoculant
you have some options there
and then when we talk about the mineral
side
which is where we really like to
emphasize and target for reament
um two to three weeks out you said two
weeks that might be kind of a little
close with a few uh a few facilities in
turn if they're further away and they
need to get amendment to order after
seeing analysis
but if you they already have all the
Amendments on hand and you know they're
doing this all internally then two weeks
worth great it's just really important a
couple of things I want to point out
with this is it's important to always
take the samples the same way and take
them correctly you can do one sample for
an entire room if you're treating the
room homogeneously and then if you have
any outlier beds that are performing
differently for some reason you could
always sample those separately but you
don't need to sample every bed I'm
Bryant's Mason Soul doctor and I've had
multiple conversations about this and uh
the tests always come back close enough
so it saves a lot of money you know
being able to test per room or per area
versus every bed
um and then the last thing around the
testing uh just to mention the folks we
we did partner with Logan labs and now
we are offering the testing directly
through kiss for those of you that work
with us and
we do an analysis for 35 of the complete
soil test and then if you buy the
Amendments that we recommend through us
you get a credit towards
uh towards those amendments so
essentially making the consult portion
free so that is an option for folks that
do use us but anyway I don't want to
focus too much on kiss I want to keep
this podcast uh you know as educational
and non sales pitchy as possible Right
brand agnostics I want to share that
no I was just going to say one other
thing about soil that that gets left out
once you look at the mineral physical
and biological is the IPM side and so
it's it is really important to keep that
soil healthy you know we talk about
folks that have to flush uh between
rounds because their sodium is too high
you know it's really important
um once you've removed those plants
which is a portion of the immune system
of the of the soil to get something
aggressive whether that's trichoderma or
lactobacillus but some productive
biology in there because you know like
we you know I'm always saying that we've
probably got pythium on our faces when
we're talking you you're not going to be
able to exclude that but there are some
things that you can add into your soil
to out-compete it and then there's the
the insect side of things where you
could be putting Bavaria and beneficial
insects like SF nematodes or you know
other insects into prevent fungus gnats
whatever pest pressures you have and so
that's that's one last piece of that
puzzle that I like to just at least
start the conversation with folks
okay well since he brought up Flushing
uh the couple things I want to mention
around that so we typically don't
recommend flushing in organic soils
unless you have an excess of nitrates or
mineral nutrition in general
um
or if the you know prior to harvest now
after harvest if you have excessive
levels of nitrates potassium or more
specifically sodium which we do see when
you don't have any runoff potentially
build up over time it's not an essential
plant
plant mineral and it can cause issues
and raise your overall soluble salt
level
people say flush but then they have
questions about how do I do that can you
take us through what the flushing
process would look like to reduce sodium
yeah yeah that's that's one that we just
see repeatedly with this style of
growing sodium's highly mobile but with
no runoff there's no place for it to go
so what we need to do is if your sodium
is creeping up you know anytime I see
somebody hit a hundred ppms uh I start
talking to them about you know let's
let's plan for a flush but I've seen
some pretty scary numbers 344 parts per
million stuff like that and so like you
mentioned the the overall soluble salts
and related osmotic stress is going to
go up exponentially and then sodium is
going to block your productive cations
specifically potassium and it can
actually replace potassium in the plant
plant which is not good so we want to
flush that
the easiest way to do that first and
foremost is to make sure that your water
is not bringing in extra sodium so if
sodium if the contamination is coming
from your water obviously you need to
solve that before you do a flush because
pumping more sodium Laden water into the
beds not going to fix the problem
but if you have clean water
low sodium you want to flush
approximately 10 percent by volume you
know so a 4x4 is typically you know with
a 12 inch side 10 inches of soil is is
almost dead on 100 gallons of soil and
so if you flush that 10 you want to get
10 gallons of runoff and most facilities
are not set up with this in mind and so
you know if you don't have
a way to capture your runoff if you
don't have a valve you can open on the
in on the bottom of your bed or
something like that you'll have to get a
little more creative I've got you know
some Growers who will catch it in a five
gallon bucket and when they've got two
of those full they know they've got 10
gallons out and so you know we're
Growers we're resourceful and we'll
figure out a way to do it but you need
to get 10 runoff through that bed to
essentially cut that sodium or that
nitrate in half and that's typically
what we're shooting for
um you can bring in an EC meter and you
know take your EC right when runoff
starts and it'll typically be very high
and then you could continue to flush
until that EC is cut in half and that
will give you a more dialed in approach
to it but we have really good success
with just the 10 so that's normally what
I do and then the last little bit I try
to that's where I'll add
trichoderma or lactobacillus just to
make sure that I'm getting a really nice
biology
prophylactic approach to keeping that
that soil safe
yeah we don't like to do this type of
heavy flushing when there's a plant in
the bed this would be after harvest and
just to get people some numbers so if
you have a yard of soil it's
approximately 200 gallons you're putting
20 gallons of water through it coming
out the bottom
um right right okay so it might take
more than it might take 30 or 40 gallons
it just really depends on how dry their
soil is
um you know so the the runoff Target you
want to collect that 10 and so if you
can you know so
it might take more water than you know
10 gallons in a 4x4 it might take 15 or
20 to get get 10 gallons to flow out of
it but that's what their target is
great Yeah you mentioned uh Bavaria
changing topics here we're going to
bounce around a lot this podcast
um and I wanted to talk about some
things that we learned about Bavaria
last week in a meeting with uh one of
the large major producers of it in North
America
and I want to just share a little bit
that but I do hope to do a whole podcast
this number very because I think it's
really fascinating but some of the
highlights from that meeting that I
would share was that every species is
different and will have slightly
different results within that Target
class of pests that Bavaria works on so
uh you know the particular uh hearing of
Bavaria that
you know is sold through bioworks is
going to have different results than the
one from certis and you know on and on
down the line so uh that's not to say
that one is better than the other but
that they're just going to have slightly
different results across the species
that Bavaria works with because they're
all different strains and they were uh
all captured naturally from different
areas around the world
um which also means that they'll have
different storage conditions so some may
store in the fridge for
six months and not have any any Spore
loss whereas others uh won't have that
same storage life which I thought was
really interesting
um I have a couple other things but did
you want to add anything
about Bavaria yeah Bavaria is one of my
you know one of my favorites I like
Horticultural oils I like Bulgaria
um I thought the conversation was really
interesting just the whole concept of
these biology biological
um helpers have been evolving for
Millennia along with
their their targets and so if you get a
like you know if you get a Bavaria
strain from Chile or one from Northern
California they're going to have
different efficacies on different
insects because they've evolved with
different insects and then just the the
complexity of like you just mentioned uh
storage you know what temperatures
um there's a different PH range that you
want to apply
um there's the timing as well so like
with any IPM product for insects
um
the timing is is really important you
want to get that all you know usually
when it's an early molting you know
stage where you can you can have better
efficacy against the insects but it's
just really important to make sure that
you're you know in the fly fishing terms
match the hatch you want to make sure
that
you've got the right strain for the
right target insect and that you are
taking all the environmental factors
into into account you know temperature
uh pH those sort of things the same way
you would want to do that if you're
deciding between cucumbers or swarsky
you know you want to look at the
environment in your greenhouse and so I
was just I was really Blown Away by how
complex these bavarious strains are and
how specific they are
um and then I really thought that the
you know because we're trying to lend it
um
how wet the plant gets even in veg the
conversation about cold fogging Bavaria
was really intriguing to me because I
that's never occurred to me and that's
that's something that for a propagation
room or a veg room
would really free up a lot of Labor and
get you the coverage you need
yeah one other thing that I'll have
another interview later today with
Michael brownbridge at biorex talking
about isopathologist and he's going to
talk a lot more about Bavaria and these
microbes in general but um one of the
things that he's discovered through
testing that I hope to get him to
elaborate on is that some of these
Brands and I'm not talking about
you know these the major brands like
bios but some of the people even in the
living soil game that are selling
Bavaria have levels Spore counts so low
in their product that you can't even get
any sort of efficacy with them it's not
it's just not possible for that to have
any any actual effect on an insect
because of the Spore count so you may be
wasting your money as a grower if you're
buying some of these products and this
is not unique to the living soil game
there's a lot of there's a lot of
companies out there in the AG world too
that just have poor quality product in
that regard so don't assume that all
Bavarian is going to perform the same or
is of the same quality and then the
other thing is that other product labels
have actually had claims of sport counts
so high that it would not be
physiologically possible to fit that
many spores into that given volume so
their labels are just completely
inaccurate too so
um
it's an interesting topic when we start
thinking about marketing and how it
comes into play and what people are are
claiming around Bavaria so you just I
guess Barbie wear when it comes to that
sort of thing yeah exactly buyer beware
it's the same thing with mycorrhizae
where you you'll see a product that
lists you know an endo uh form of
mycorrhizae but the Spore count is so
low that
you know it's it's a marketing blurb but
it's there's no efficacy at all so you
definitely want to do your research and
and use trusted products
yeah since you brought it up one of the
questions that we get is you know is
there mycorrhizal fungus in your soil
and uh the reason we don't add it to our
soil mix is because uh it would strictly
be a way of just getting it on the label
it wouldn't actually have any sort of
efficacy because it's impossible to get
a high enough Spore count to make any
difference when adding it to your media
uh you really need to add it
specifically to the root Zone write a
transplant time
um if you're going to use it at all
stuff that that's a good point so when
you see it read the label and then
realize that the label might not be
accurate
um because of storage conditions uh
inaccurate product management and a
variety of other reasons
these microbes get tricky
um
moving on though
since we are talking about microbes uh
let's talk a little bit about
aspergillus because we've had a few
people bring that up uh bring it to our
attention uh what can you tell me about
aspergillus uh we've had a we've talked
to a few people who have failed for it
in their growth how do we manage it most
effectively
yeah so in this will dovetail into a
another conversation about root ball
removal
um and why we like like that but um we
can we can come back to that in a second
um fungal pathogens aspergillus
specifically there's a lot of things it
starts with cultural controls you know
all of your
pathogen control starts with cultural
controls and so you want to make sure
that you're moving around your facility
always from the head house Downstream
you don't ever want to reverse that and
go from a flower room back into your
your veg or your mother room
um it's it's a really good idea to wear
some sort of protective clothing whether
that's scrubs or a Tyvek suit or you
know something like that just you know
most of the folks that work and grow
facilities have a plan or two at home
you know they're they're passionate
about it most of them and so you don't
want whatever might be going on there to
come to your facility and so if you
sealed them into uh into some scrubs or
something hopefully that doesn't get
loose in your facility so that's just
one more layer of protection I really
like bleach mats
um when when you took me to Gold Leaf I
I was really happy to see that they had
bleach mats at every every door
I really like the idea of having a spray
bottle with 90 rubbing alcohol in every
room so that you know as you enter you
can spray your yourself down from the
forearms and hands uh the other option
is to use nitrile gloves but I don't
like to use all that plastic if I don't
have to
um and then keeping your tools clean you
know make sure that you're you know
you've got at least two pairs of shears
per person so that they can rotate those
out into a bleach solution or something
between plants and then it's going to
come down to labor constraints you know
you don't want to stop your workers
every 30 seconds so they'll they'll
always be some potential
cross-contamination
but then the other thing is really
controlling your environmental controls
aspergillus likes a hot humid room it it
really likes to have
um
microclimates you know little uh hot
moist areas and so defoliation and good
fan air movement throughout the room is
really good and then that's that's a
weird Catch-22 because if you look at
powdery mildew it needs moist high
humidity
to spread but it also needs dry air
to sporulate in the first place and so
you're kind of damned if you do damned
if you don't you know you want high air
movement to prevent pm and to prevent
aspergillus but if you've got fusarium
you don't want a lot of cfus moving
through that room because it's just
going to destroy the whole room and so
again like we were saying with
um insects or anything you really have
to get a definitive
ID on what you're dealing with and so
you want to know is this aspergillus is
this some other fungal pathogen but
those are the cultural controls that
that you can do for that there are some
products and I know like you just said
you're going to talk to Michael
brownbridge Dr Michael Brown Bridge
later and he and I talked about some
products
um
one of those being trichoderma that you
can get into the soil they also have
some other products that could be
beneficial for dealing with aspergillus
and then you really want to make sure
that you're cleaning your rooms as
thoroughly as possible between rounds
and so you could get in there with a
good oxidizer and get the floors and the
walls at the very least
um
you know I see people doing things like
running trim machines in a grow room or
you know they'll they'll Harvest and
hang their plants in in the same grow
room and that's just the opportunity to
really inoculate that room and so you'll
see people who pass pass and then all of
a sudden they fail and it's just those
four counts are just building up
building up and then eventually they
take over a room and and you'll lose it
and so those are those are some of the
main things you can do you want a really
good air exchange so you don't want to
just be pushing the same room around or
the same air around the facility you
need to get the old air out the heat
humidity out and you need to get fresh
air in there
um I don't know am I leaving something
out I think that covers it pretty well
uh you know I just want to say
aspergillus is everywhere
um it's going to be at differing levels
depending on your media and and soil
especially if you're you know if you're
using a compost in your soil
um
we've seen it in a variety of different
potting soils from different
manufacturers and it's All About
Management like you mentioned so
just something for people to keep in
mind uh and really it probably involves
a deeper conversation around their
specific facility or grow space
um but those are some you know good
Basics that everyone should be doing in
for IBM in in any space
uh yeah and the reports I've seen the
white papers I've read is that they they
find aspergillus in every soil every
potting substrate and so you know it's
just good to know what you're up against
and so you can take the proactive steps
and
keep your facility clean get good
biology into your soil and you know it
is everywhere the exclusion is is
difficult and so we want to you know
meet it head-on
yeah okay I want to uh switch directions
and talk a little bit about heavy metals
there's a few things you know we've done
podcasts now on heavy metals uh you can
go back and listen to my one with Brian
Mason Soul doctor
uh there's a few things I want to just
bring to to highlight for folks because
we are hearing more and more people
having to deal with regulations around
heavy metals
um
do you want to cover why don't you go
first Brandon and just mention a few of
the highlights and then I have a list
here of things I want to add to it okay
and and kind of something I left out on
the aspergillus that that comes into
this same conversation is getting rid of
the root ball we're seeing that heavy
metals accumulate as well as viroids in
the root material and the recent
research has has proven that that's
that's where we're getting the heaviest
um rates of accumulation whether it's
heavy metals or viroids and so we are
heavily recommending that folks remove
their root ball so that they can get
that out of their soil
and then that that just goes back to a
con uh comment I meant to make about the
aspergillus is that
indoors folks that leave any sort of
detritus
um and this and this includes cover
crops and mulch
um that's a perfect breeding ground for
aspergillus if you wanted to grow
aspergillus you would leave all your
dead leaves on the surface and so it's
really important to keep those beds
clean if you are going to try to do that
you want to make sure that you're
incorporating that organic material
below the soil surface
and again I still just I would rather
just remove it in an indoor environment
but with heavy metals again we want to
remove that root ball there's
so many potential contaminants it could
be dust from lead arsenic that's been
sitting in your neighbor's field from
the 70s you know these are persistent
they're not going anywhere it could be
in your water
it could be in your compost you know we
see that frequently so there's so many
uh ph up and down products can bring it
in and so it's really important to get a
test for anything you want to add to
your soil because you're not going to be
able to get those heavy metals out so
you've got to prevent them from getting
in there
um you can try to control it with a
higher pH we've seen some really
interesting things with biochar tying up
um heavy metals I've seen some
interesting Research into silicon being
able to out compete heavy metals for
accumulation in the plant and so there's
some things we can we can try to do to
mediate a bad situation but we really
want to prevent it and that all goes
back to testing your products making
sure and if you contact a producer and
ask for a heavy metal test and they blow
you off or they won't send it you can
look that up I believe California has a
registry for you know all the organic
products but you can you can look them
up but honestly if they don't send you a
heavy metal test that's a red flag for
me just to keep keep looking
yeah and I never have a problem with
people asking us for uh additional
testing or they want to test the product
themselves I think that's important
um but just the Highlight some main
things again uh heavy metals are
everywhere
uh typically when water or soil comes in
contact with metal that's a
contamination risk for heavy metal
uptake uh
we have seen high levels of uh certain
heavy metals in PH down specific
products from pretty big name brands so
do your research there and test
we don't know what levels in soil will
cause a plant failure we can't say that
this PPM of arsenic in soil is going to
cause or in your media is going to cause
this level of PPM in your plant because
there's so many variables between your
VPD how are you watering what your your
ppfd is on you know light intensity on
that plant
um what sort of biological activity and
nutrient cycling do you have happening
what is your pH all of these things are
going to affect uptake what is the
genetics that you're running that's a
huge one
um different cultivars are going to be
more efficient at pulling up heavy
metals than others
and and honestly if you need to pull
heavy metals out of your soil
unfortunately have been cannabis are
probably the best plant for that too so
it is a challenge so so the key for for
us what we try to do at kiss at least is
we try to start at a level that we know
we're gonna pass regulation
um below whatever that regulatory
threshold is and then we know that we
have a removal rate because we we know
there's going to be some heavy metals in
our soils we just need to keep them low
we need to manage them and then when you
go to harvest your crop you're going to
be pulling out small amounts of heavy
metals what we have to do is make sure
that that level is going to allow you to
pass and then the next round will be
reament we're reamending with less than
you pulled out so we're always moving
the direction of removing heavy metals
and
um interestingly enough we did a test
with gold leaf soil oh I think it was it
was a couple years ago now so they're
probably six years into that soil we
actually tested it in the Michigan
Market
um sent a sample over there and it
passed undetected for heavy metals which
was awesome and so I know that it's
possible with this method to grow and
and and passed but you do have to be
diligent and where we see people get in
trouble is when they start adding other
products and maybe they haven't tested
all the products and they just assume
from the manufacturer that it's safe
um
and and that's where we start to see
people fail it and the more products you
add the more variables you have to go
back and test which can get very
expensive down the road and that can be
teased that can be uh microbials that
can be uh just about anything like we
said PH down so uh you really do have to
do your research there and that doesn't
even get into uh I just saw a pot a
webinar the other day
um
by Patricia Atkins she I mean I might
have to get her on the podcast he's with
uh antilia scientific
and what she was talking about with
heavy metals is the laboratory side and
how many fail points there are in the
laboratory from the type of water that
they're using to how clean the facility
is to if they have metal furniture in
that space to the gloves that they're
choosing to use actually have heavy
metals on the gloves and levels of zinc
and other and other things so
it's challenging
um yeah and when you're looking at when
you're looking at levels that low the
margin of air you know that small 0.02
parts per billion or something like that
the margin of air is as the unit gets
smaller the margin for error
exponentially gets bigger and bigger and
so you know with heavy metals
um there's there's it's it's really
difficult it's just really difficult so
you want to manage everything up front
by exclusion and test and everything and
then another thing is RO water and we
can talk about RO water because I get a
lot of calls about that but RO water is
hungry water there's no ions in it and
so anything it passes over it's going to
grab ions from so if it's going through
you know cheap uh plastic if it's going
through
um a brass spigot if it's going you know
any metal plastic anything that that
water is passing through or over could
very well grab heavy metals and deposit
those into your bed so that's that's
another thing you know you want to make
sure that that water is buffered before
you get it back into your beds or pots
yeah absolutely
um I had something else on heavy metals
but I'm blanking on it at the moment so
I'll have to I'll have to come back to
it oh I just remembered so the other
thing with heavy metals too is they uh
they appear to accumulate more in older
tissue so if you can send in a I think a
younger part of the plant as well as
less stem in that plant that is probably
going to test slower I'd like to see
more research around that but that's
just sort of the direction I would head
based off of
what uh what we've been learning about
heavy metals still want to pass that
along
so uh moving on to a new topic you know
I know you get asked a lot like what's
what's the secret sauce what's that
special product that's going to make
your
grow
I guess special
um
but what do you have to say about that
man after 38 I'll have 38 years of
cannabis under my belt in May and I've
done
you know I drove for 18 years Organics
for 20 years
um
I've tried every kind of setup that you
can imagine and
the kiss system and again I don't want
this to be a kiss ad but just a simple
organic living soil with testing and
amendments with Safe products
is the easiest workflow I've ever had
and so
after trying you know the Frankenstein
approach just every product you can
imagine
um
the most simple sop has given me the
best yields and the best quality
cannabis and so
it all comes down to managing your
environment making sure that you have
adequate
nutrients available to your plant and
the secret sauce is time and patience
and paying attention to your plants
listening to your plants observing your
plants taking data you know getting in
there doing scoping defoliating looking
for pests and pathogens
um
that's really the secret sauce is the
folks that spend
um spend more time in their Garden
have better grows because I could give
you know 10 different Growers all the
exact same inputs cultivars whatever and
they're going to have dramatically
different results
and a lot of folks you know and it's not
their fault a lot of Growers are burned
out it's a growing is it can be
monotonous it can be you know it's a lot
of hours I know that for a fact you know
you can easily burn a 80 hour work week
on a farm and so a lot of Growers get
burned out and they come in they check
make sure everything's watered and they
just want to get out of there and and I
don't fault them for that but
the the thing that you need to do is
spend more time and so if you can
automate your watering so you're not
doing that by hand and get more time you
know that's a that's a dunk just for the
return on investment uh side of things
but anything you can do so that you can
free up your grower
especially your higher end grower so
they're not on you know holding a hose
or something like that
that's what's going to get you better
uh results and and then the next thing
would be if you want to try a special
you know secret sauce if you want to try
a product
you need to start off with uh you know
like we always tell people to start off
with just water only for their first
round and they're like well but you know
if we add this or we add that
well if you add anything you do not have
a base data set and you really really
need to get get a base data set so you
can make decisions moving forward so if
there is a product that your buddy's
using or you read about or saw in a
podcast and you really want to use it
you need to set up a control so that's
the only thing you're adding and then
you have other beds or pots with the
exact same ppfd CO2 you know all the
environment is the same and then you can
determine at the end of that round did I
get a you know a statistically relevant
bump on
on my return for the money I spent
because you know if you're a if you just
got a 4x4 tent
you can go crazy because you just really
can't spend too much money and and so I
think that that's a lot of fun to to
play around with different products and
that kind of stuff but on scale you
really have to take a scientific
approach to it because you just can't
afford to to spend or waste I should say
that that kind of capital and then
there's a lot of products out there that
you know
are are marketed to Growers
that don't really produce you know
um and look to look to traditional AG as
well that's one of my mantras I'm always
begging people to you know cannabis is
very special to me it's it's it's
very special to me to my family
um
it's not special in agriculture and
there's no corn or soybean guys spending
six grand on aloe water or you know some
of these products that you know there's
a place in time and a small uh in a
small operation where that might work
but for Growers on scale you need to be
spending time with your plants you you
really have to check in Daily and
um that that would be my my soapbox on
all that
yeah I have I have a couple thoughts on
this too so one I I agree that there's a
lot of I see a marketing all the time on
Instagram and even stuff like
that's pushed forward as education
around how to grow but it's really just
product based or just pushing products
on you and it it frankly drives me a
little crazy and I don't know how to
combat that
um
and at the end of the day it's a lot of
hype around product and and if you think
about it or at least how I how I
approach it is like you said you want to
control for a variable test one thing at
a time get a baseline but add something
and if you do get a result try and
figure out think about why you got that
result it means you had some sort of
limiting factor growth at that product
addressed whether it was nitrogen
whether it was nutrient cycling through
microbes whether it was you know
whatever micro macronutrient at the end
of the day that's what you want to
consider when you're thinking about uh
product from a non-marketing perspective
and and then the other thing about this
and I really I really love this about uh
Nate over at Gold Leaf so for him his
secret sauce is his soil because he got
soil over eight years ago now and
that soil has been in his facility he's
been managing it in a very specific uh
microclimate that's unique to him and so
the expression that he's going to get
from his genetics is going to be totally
different because of that microbial
succession
and ever and co-evolution between his
cannabis plant and his soil that's been
happening over the last eight years you
know cycle after cycle that's what
probably 40 40 plus Cycles now in that
soil and so for him his secret sauce is
his soil that's that's his uh that's his
Special Sauce because it allows him to
have you know unique terpene expression
um you you know different unique
cannabinoid levels and so I think that's
kind of a better way to approach the
secret sauce ideas just realize that as
a as a grower that soil that you're
managing if you are reusing it it's
going to become unique to you it's not
you know it's it's no longer a name
brand soil it's now your
under your ecology habitat that you
created and so that that can be special
and can be a marketing tool down the
road for Growers depending on your
market so and I and I I think that that
uh that's super important and I
um couldn't agree more
um when Allison Schaefer just got
interviewed for uh their local paper
that's Justin McGill's lead grower for
the high-end Mako Farms
and she said the exact same thing she
said our either she said either their
secret recipe or there's you know their
secret weapon is their soil and it just
goes back to the same thing they've been
running kiss soil for a number of years
um you start to you know obviously
there's no humic fraction in a potting
substrate but you do start to approach
something similar to where you've got
nutrients just flowing into solution and
then you've got the microbiology that's
going to be completely unique to your
environment and your grow and whether
that's
driving trichome production or driving a
different uh terpene profile
um that that is what's going to set you
aside and so some of the things we were
talking about earlier as far as like how
you manage your soil keep it healthy
that's going to have everything to do
with your final product and so again you
could give four different Growers the
same cultivar you know and put it in
their soil and one's going to definitely
come out on top one of them is going to
have you know a better expression just
because of that soil
yeah and I want to change topics again
here and talk a little bit about no-till
um
I I you and I are going to agree on this
because we've talked about it multiple
times but I want to I want to kind of
share some thoughts around it and you
know I met Steve Cantwell Greenlife
Productions down in Vegas uh face to
face for the first time uh last month I
think it was at the living soil Summit
where we were both speaking and I got to
hear him speak and I gotta say I have a
ton of I I mean I already had a ton of
respect for the guy but um I love what
he's doing I love his thought process
and The Innovation that he brings to the
community is amazing
um now Steve's a cover crop guy Steve's
a no-till guy
um Steve's came up with the idea
bottomless pots which I think is
potentially very brilliant I can't wait
to do some trials with it
um so I I share this twofold one because
I have I'm going to give you my
reasoning for why I don't do those
things in uh the facilities that we work
with or I don't recommend them some of
them still do it and that's fine but
also that we're all a community here and
at the end of the day like it's this
Innovation that pushes us forward and
and when we become dogmatic in the way
that we grow we are open to what other
people are doing or what other people
are sharing I think it really limits us
um and you know people try and act like
we're we're against each other on this
sort of thing and while we have
differing opinions
um Stephen I get along great so I just
want to throw that out there there's no
drama there but
I do want to talk about why we don't
recommend cover crops indoors and why I
don't really like the term no-till
indoors as well so
and and this is a complicated topic
um cover crops uh potentially one
they're another crop you have to manage
uh two they are habit an ecology for
pests and pathogens potentially and
three and the biggest reason for me even
though those two are huge is that I want
to mix my nutrients back into my soil
down into the Rises there I don't want
to top dress it because of our short
flowering cycle I want those nutrients
available immediately and having cover
crops in there makes it impossible or a
much more challenging for me to do that
um and we have this term no-till which
when we amend indoor beds we're not
truly tilling anyway we're not running a
tiller we're we're shoveling it which
does not have the same impacts on
biology that uh tiller would and we're
not creating a compaction Zone like you
would with a tiller if we're using a
shovel so uh the other advantages of
this just to highlight are you're
removing the roots which would
potentially lower your heavy metal
content in that soil for the next cycle
you're getting your nutrients directly
into the rhizosphere
and
um there's this other there's this
disturbance hypothesis that uh Dr Ben
Higgins talks about uh that I I might
need to do a an episode with him on this
but essentially the idea is that we have
we have ecological systems starting with
our primary systems which would be like
right after a volcano erupts and you
just have a rock right you have bare
rock and then slowly Life Starts to come
in those are our
beginning successional systems all the
way through you know then you have
grasslands temperate forests all the way
through to our old growth forest like
the Redwoods that would be our
considered an apex or climax ecosystem
where we have the most biodiversity
and in theory where cannabis would most
like to grow is really in the middle
there it's not in these Apex you know
no-till
climax ecosystems it's it's where we
have the most biodiversity is is through
disturbance and that disturbance
um allows us to sort of maintain
a little bit more ecological diversity
and biodiversity in theory I don't know
how anyone would ever prove or disprove
what I'm saying just because we don't
have the technology to truly measure
these things
um because of how rapidly these
microbial communities are changing
um but I do feel like that's really our
sweet spot and why we see the results
that we do is there anything you want to
add around no-till or cover crops yeah
no I'm on the exact same page I I am a
no-till person but no-till doesn't mean
no-till because you know like I always
say I always bring up phosphorus it's
only going to you know phosphate's gonna
move a half an inch in your profile on
its own so if you're not you know
scratching in three or four inches down
to where your roots can get to it you
know your plants are going to be super
slow
um top dress is a super slow release the
biology can't get to it and make it in
you know available in an ionic form for
your plant and then you're potentially
creating an impermeable
um layer on top that would love to grow
fungal you know spores of some sort some
good some bad
um
and then um
I love what you're just saying about Ben
you know we're not trying to mimic
nature we're trying to do better you
know we you know there's lots of loss in
nature and we're trying to prevent that
um but yeah so I think that that you
nailed all that
yeah this idea of
you know doing what nature does
is I think a little bit of a fallacy
because nature doesn't have weeds nature
doesn't select for one crop species over
another and to the exclusion of others
and you don't see the level of Health in
nature typically that you would
especially across a for vast
quantity of plants which is what you
need to do when we grow cannabis and you
don't see monocrops in nature you're not
going to see you're not just going to
walk out into an old growth forest and
see a field of you know homogeneous
cannabis anywhere you know
um and so
that's you know we're doing we're doing
something different I shouldn't say
better we're just doing something
different
um
and so you know some of the things that
some of the natural processes are not
beneficial to us in a controlled
environment
yeah and I do love cover crops mulches
those sorts of things outdoors so I want
to or even in Greenhouse environments so
I want to make that clear uh but the
other thing too
is just that while uh
while we don't see monocrops in nature
we uh
we we do see
I guess what I want to add to this is we
do see healthy plants in nature and and
the biodiversity is important but adding
you know a five or seven crop
cover crop is not really increasing our
biodiversity anywhere near the levels
that or that we would see naturally so
to me that's that's still monocropping
pretty much yeah and it it just makes me
so nervous to add a cover crop indoor
you know what what's the advantage so it
helps with your moisture retention I'd
much rather set up a blue mat system and
automate my water so I'm not having to
worry about that you know it can prevent
erosion and I always joke that if you've
got erosion indoors you should try an
instrument that maybe growing is not the
thing you should be doing because you
know how are you you know creating
erosion indoors so that shouldn't be a
factor
um and then it makes you know we're
already adding in the nutrients based on
you know very tested targets so we don't
need you know any nitrogen fixing in our
in our beds
um and then it makes it so next to
impossible to till in your nutrients
you're gonna have to tear up all that
um organic matter and work it under the
soil and it goes back to the aspergillus
conversation you know if if you've got
cover crop and you know you get a pest
or a pathogen in there it's you're going
to have hell to pay on that it's going
to be really tough
and Steve talks about how he's growing
in a desert in Nevada and so his pest
pressure is very different than what a
lot of us face in other parts of the
country
um he doesn't have a lot of crops being
grown around him from what from what I
understand and he is downright militant
about who gets into his who gets into
his facility and who gets into his
flowering rooms yeah he instead in his
talk that there's a lot of people that
work in these facilities that have never
seen his flowering spaces because they
don't need to and that's the sort of IPM
that allows you to do the things that
he's doing I think
um because he's really doing a great job
of keeping pests out of away from his
plants an office facility you know
you're not allowed to grow if you work
for him you're not allowed to do a lot
of those those things that lead to
problems so yeah a lot of respect for
Steve
yeah yeah and I and I love
um that that you're always
open to
um conversation and even being wrong and
um yeah I'd love to keep the
conversations and and keeping our minds
open and that's how we learn and how we
get better and you know like that's one
of my favorite things about cultivation
is I learned something every single day
I was joking with somebody the other day
I was like sometimes I learned that I
was wrong and that's that's exciting you
know it's um you know everybody's got an
ego some some level of it and so it's
humbling to be wrong but man it's
exciting because you get to you get to
go off on a whole other area of learning
and um so I'm very grateful for the
folks who
have differing opinions but uh the folks
that bring it to the table respectfully
and in a genuine sincere desire to learn
more and to help other Growers so that's
that's I love that that's part of the
conversation just keeping everybody's
Minds open and we're all on the same
team you know we all want to push the
needle towards sustainable
um
and and we've all you know every path of
the organic
uh sustainable movement has stuff to
contribute
so one other question I get all the time
especially since I started doing the
plant trivia posts on Instagram was uh
diagnosis
so people send plant photos of of you
know some issue or another they're
dealing with their plan how do you
approach diagnosing a plant
that's uh yeah so diagnosis in person is
difficult and so for me to diagnose
you know from across the country over
the phone is really difficult
um but we do have a systematic approach
to that and you know we've got the
dichotomous key on on the website that
folks can look at that will give them a
really good Fighting Chance at figuring
out what what's going on
um the first thing you really need to do
is determine if it's a nutrient issue
and so one of the easiest ways to do
that one of the the tried and true ways
is to look at your individual ranges and
any range would be you know whether it's
a bed or a group of pots but when I say
range I just mean a uniform cultivar and
feed schedule
and then uniform environmentals
um
and if you look at that and that whole
bed is showing some symptom it's all
yellowing or something you know then if
the entire bed is affected you can
usually safely assume that it's nutrient
now it might be a nutrient issue because
the whole bed got over watered and
there's been root death and so it's
showing nitrogen issues
um but if you can see a consistent uh
across the the entire range issue then
you're pretty safe to assume you need to
go down the nutrient path pests and
pathogens tend to jump around and so
you'll have one plant tanking and then a
plant right beside it that's doing fine
um that that's time to get out the scope
look at Roots maybe do some testing
um but if you if you see something
uniform you want to inspect the range
and you want to look at the plants and
what the first thing you want to notice
is where is the problem starting don't
even worry about what the issue is where
is it starting on the plant if it's
starting on the bottom of the plant then
it's a mobile element and so what's
happening is the apical growing tip
you know the plant is is trying to
reproduce itself it's just doing what
biology does it's trying to make progeny
and so it's going to sacrifice those
lower leaves and and flowers to the top
of the plant to make sure that that's
healthy and can receive pollen and make
seeds for the next round
and that's what the plant wants to do to
preserve itself
um and so if you're losing nutrients at
the bottom you know it's new a mobile
element so you can
you know kind of break that down pretty
quickly you know it's either nitrogen
phosphorus potassium or magnesium and
that's that's pretty easy magnesium is
is probably the easiest one to diagnose
it's just that inner venal chlorosis
potassium is chlorosis you know that
stays on the margin and then rapidly
goes to necrosis
phosphorus the the whole plant will get
dark but the bottoms the tips will start
to burn and the leaf will go necrotic
nitrogen you just the whole Leaf goes
yellow goes chlorotic and then you'll
have lethal decision where the leaf will
just pop off before it goes necrotic you
can just pop it right off or it'll fall
off and so then if it's not at the
bottom then you know that it's a
immobile element
you know and that's where I see most of
the misdiagnoses a lot of folks will see
burning at the top and assume that it's
nitrogen they've got too much nitrogen
um
when in fact that's almost always a
Calcium deficiency
there's a couple that will show across
the entire plant like sulfur the entire
plant will go kind of light green
um and then there's things that happen
at the top of the plant like like iron
consistently and every grow I've ever
seen you know the very top of the plant
is a little bit of lime green especially
where the petiole into the of the leaf
and that's iron and it just grows out
you know repeatedly over and over again
and so just using a dichotomous key to
see where on the plant it's starting
will limit what nutrients you're going
to look at and then there's very
specific
um
uh symptoms that come with that and so
you can get out the nutrient
deficiencies and bedding plants that
book is a great book because you could
go around your yard
and look at every single plant and you
know because that dichotomous key is not
specific to cannabis it's it's designed
for cannabis with cannabis illustrations
to to help Growers but you can apply
that to to grasses to flowering plants
and so it's practice that's that's the
thing is you can't just get that
overnight you're gonna have to practice
and so you're going to have to look at
that dichotomous key and you're going to
have to run through your plants and you
know
practice on on what's in your garden
that's not cannabis practice you know if
you go to a friend's house look at their
plants
um don't drive them crazy with diagnosis
but you know just the more times you can
repeat that process where you know is it
nutrient is it a consistent symptom
throughout the range where on the plant
did it start and then based on where on
the planet started start looking at the
individual symptoms and then it's it's
pretty straight straightforward to dial
that in
um I guess the other the only other
thing is just to
don't neglect environmental changes if
you've got our differences if you've got
a great a big greenhouse and
everything's planted the same you might
have a corner that's shady and so it's
you know accidentally getting over
watered it's just not getting the same
growth rate that sort of thing I think
everybody's first initial instinct is
it's nutrients and it might be nutrients
but it might be some environmental
Factor that's preventing it from getting
into the plant as well like calcium you
know if your VPD is off it doesn't
matter how much calcium you've got in
the soil it's just not going to get into
the plant
yeah I think you covered it I don't
really have a lot to add there other
than
um when people send me their photos I I
try to give a diagnosis but it's always
a challenge so just keep that in mind
I'll do my best but uh
yeah like you said it's impossible to
tell just from a food yeah and if they
can if they can give you that
information because a lot of times
people will send me a picture of a leaf
and they're like what's going on with
the plant and if you could send me a
picture of the leaf send me a picture of
the entire plant like backed away from
it that and then some information has to
you know when it started
where did it start is it homogeneous
throughout the rain you know is it only
one cultivar you know like um
you know Justin McGill has one of the
most amazing growth facilities I've ever
seen it's like a surgery room the floors
are are Polished in um it's the cleanest
place the nutrients are dialed in
they've got one I think it's their white
star dog
it always presents some deficiency at
the end of the round and so as long as
you
are okay with that then the the
nutrients across the board you know
there's always going to be certain
outlier cultivars that are super heavy
feeders super light feeders and so that
could be an issue as well so always
always consider the cultivar in the
environment as well
yeah Justin's facility is great in the
sense of uh
the
the staff and how they they care for the
plants keep things clean it does have
just if people go online and look at his
the pictures on Instagram he does have
old life he does have old Peck in there
but they still grow consistently really
good plants because of
all the other reasons that you lifted so
I just want to throw that out there uh
just in case people do go look that up
and check him out um which they should
he's a great grower and he's they're
definitely a facility to follow along if
you're interested in this style of
growing
um okay last topic uh in in under five
minutes because we're almost out of time
you said you get asked a lot about white
ash
um
do you want to go ahead and touch on
that and then we'll uh sign off on the
podcast for today yeah I'll make this
really quick
um bottom line for white ash is it
should not be a driver for why you're
selecting your cannabis there's all
kinds of myths that it's heavy metals
it's pesticides it's not flushed
properly for hydro soil Hydro grows
um
there's been a ton of research you know
you can go on the forums and get let
down all kinds of Primrose Pathways but
if you if you go back like I said
earlier go to traditional Ag and look at
the research before you you know spend
money on something
um with white ash there's tons of
research it's been done we don't need to
do it again you know you could look at
the tobacco industry they're kind of
responsible for the whole white white
ash mythology
um but also forestry services both here
and in Europe fire departments you know
the study combustion science that's not
new you know there's 200 years of of
research that we can look at
and Ash color
has nothing to do with pesticides has
nothing to do with heavy metals has
nothing to do with mineral content Ash
color is determined by carbon
and whether all the organic matter all
the carbon-based
material has been burned off and
combusted converted to carbon dioxide
and it's left the building it's gone now
and if all the carbon has left the
building then you end up with a
perfectly White Ash and the only thing
that's left behind or the mineral
constituents a lot of sodium magnesium
um
but you know so when people say it
wasn't flushed and that's why I had too
much nitrate or something like that in
the in the plant that's not why it's
burning
um Salt and Pepper or dark uh you know
because in perfect White Ash the only
thing that's left behind is the mineral
content
um there's there's a a chemist who did a
bunch of experiments on it
um
but it all comes down to moisture
content you could you could have the
best herb in the world that's not
perfectly dry and burn it and you're
gonna get a dark ash and then you could
have heavy metal pesticide Laden
horrible swaggy brick weed and it'll
burn perfectly white if it's super dry
because all the carbon's been burned off
so at the end of the day I just don't
want people to you know that's a myth
that if we don't get it out of cannabis
you know how do how do they get
cigarettes to burn perfectly white well
they spray products on that and I don't
want tobacco ethics or sprays in my
cannabis experience
um I don't I don't want anything to do
with that and so my incentive for trying
to stomp on this one particular myth is
because if we don't stomp on this one
eventually we will have cannabis
producers you know for spraying their
final product with additives so that it
will burn white if that is a driver
um you know like THC you know is is a
huge driver if you go into dispensary
that's what they're going to tell you
this is a THC level on this this and
this but we know from blind tests that
people are picking their cannabis based
off of the terpene profile more than the
THC and so when it comes to drivers on
why you're paying what you're paying and
what the experience is you know if
aesthetically it does something special
for you to have white ash in your pipe
or on your joint
um then cool go for it but as far as the
science behind it and studying
combustion science there's there's no
validity to the White Ash myth at all
just zero
um
it all comes down to temperature and you
know you can go ask a fireman probably
the average fireman could do a much
better job of explaining this or you
know somebody in the Forestry Department
but the things that would prevent
um one or one finished flower from being
white versus another one would be the
moisture content and the resin content
and then a really interesting side note
on this is that
THC to CBD ratios may have something to
do with it because the way that the THC
molecule it it's a 2d two-dimensional
molecule it lays flat CBD is a
three-dimensional molecule and so
when you decarboxylate that
um you have the protonation of a carbon
group that has to leave but then there's
a there's a a proton has to
um
come in for that to happen
with CBD because it's three-dimensional
that second ring is blocking that proton
so it slows the decarboxylation and so
could that be another part of the puzzle
as to why you know those ratios it
certainly could but bottom line end of
the day is White Ash has nothing to do
with the quality of the of the finished
product
okay I don't have anything to add on
that topic as you know but uh I
appreciate you sharing that for folks
and uh thanks for taking the time today
to do this no thanks I enjoy it always
fun
that was Brandon Hudson and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Tad
Hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on Instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information thanks
for listening
[Music]