foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Bryant
Mason Bryant is a certified crop advisor
who specializes in organic cannabis
nutrition he has spent the last four
years working to combine Precision
laboratory techniques with data science
in an effort to unravel the complexities
of cannabis soil and crop nutrition
along with his work on soilless media he
also helps outdoor cultivators around
the United States with nutrient
management and cover cropping if you
would like to do soil testing help with
interpreting a soil test or interested
in an online course on these subjects
his website is
www.soildoctorconsulting.com now on to
the show
hey Brian thanks for coming on the show
today
thanks for having me Chad
yeah absolutely
um I know you've been on the show
multiple times here and people are
listeners probably familiar with who you
are and what you do
um so let's just go ahead and Dive Right
In we had talked uh before the show
about one of one of my recent podcasts
with Paul coxon and Patrick veezy
talking about phosphorus and that was a
topic that kind of sparked some interest
in you
do you want to share some of your your
feedback or some of your thoughts from
from that podcast
sure well first off I just want to say
that whenever I see any
research related to cannabis nutrient
management I'm thrilled because it's
just so many decades behind that and and
there are so so many questions and uh so
if you answer scientifically at least in
the research research literature that I
just love seeing that kind of content so
I did listen to it I loved it
um I think my dominant takeaway is and
I'm sure you share this is a little bit
of disappointment in the fact that all
the nutrient research in cannabis
production that I've seen is
um
non-organic and that changes things so
dramatically the target nutrient levels
that those researchers were taught
researchers were talking about were so
much higher than anything that I ever
see in organic living soil systems so it
was tough for me to use their target
numbers to ascertain any information
about you know what we're seeing in
organic soils
um so that was my first thing and all
the research that I've been reading is
mostly in Hydro Solutions it makes sense
from a research standpoint because
they're able to control more variables
using soilless media and ionic nutrients
um but it's a little tough to to pull
numbers from it they were applying
hundreds of PPM of of soluble phosphorus
in one of their studies and and the
interesting thing I remember hearing was
that they weren't seeing any uh negative
they weren't seeing a negative yield
from huge whopping amounts of phosphorus
which I've sort of observed that as well
I don't recommend super high phosphorus
levels but I haven't seen really
elevated soil or tissue phosphorus
levels create any zinc iron or manganese
deficiencies at least not very clearly
so that did add up to what I've seen
working with Growers
now when you look on Mulder's chart for
example which shows sort of the
antagonisms and and such associated with
various nutrients you'll see that that
phosphorus does have uh an antagonistic
relationship I believe with iron and and
zinc I think and a couple other elements
but yet
um I've heard you talk about how it's
it's sort of a luxury
uh nutrient in that we you're not seeing
those sorts of issues with high levels
can you kind of expand on that
yeah you know Mulder's chart has always
been a source of Fascination for me
um because
I've always wondered
how it was developed what crops they
were using because there are certain
antagonisms that show up very quickly
and very aggressively in different crops
um and not in others so for whatever
reason uh cannabis doesn't seem to
exhibit these types of antagonisms as
quickly and as easily as something like
maybe a corn or soybean crop wood so um
I think that probably explains the
difference with the molars charge kind
of depends on how it was uh created
usually and I've seen this in other crop
types I've I've seen zinc deficiencies
that are from excess phosphorus
application
um but like I said I just haven't
necessarily seen that in in cannabis now
there are other reactions too that may
happen in the soil so for with calcium
calcium phosphate is a classic insoluble
precipitate that can happen with with
really elevated levels of of phosphorus
but in organic systems most of that
phosphorus that we're applying is either
through compost soft rock phosphate or
bone meal so um it's not in these highly
soluble forms that are going to
precipitate out
um in the soil as easily and that's why
on a standard soil test you might see a
pretty large amount of phosphate but
you're not going to see as much in the
solution solution the only time I see
very elevated soluble phosphorus numbers
is when people are using phosphoric acid
to usually to PH down their water
or I just want to add on that if they're
using fish hydrolyzate or something
that's stabilized with phosphoric acid
I've also seen that and then the last
time I've seen it is in soil mixes that
have a lot of bat guano high phosphorus
baguano which you and I were talking
about
um
prior to the show starting so
yeah you can see in Organics where
what's causing it and that that to me
always really stands out when you have a
really high available phosphorus number
on your saturated paste but
on that note I consistently have Growers
with quite low available P you know like
0.5 for example on the saturated paste
and yet we're not seeing P deficiencies
necessarily in the plant at least
visually and yields seem seem to be
quite good still
um what are your thoughts on all that
yes that's a fascinating one I've always
uh
found that phosphorus is one of the
least accurate nutrients to manage based
on soil test results it helps to have
the standard tests and the pace test in
the case of phosphate I actually put a
little bit more weight on the standard
test when it comes to looking at
phosphorus because of phosphorus
Dynamics are very biologically driven so
the general theory that I work off of is
if you can have a large enough reservoir
of phosphorus in your soil
microorganisms are mineralizing
phosphate and delivering to the plant
delivering them to the plant root pretty
efficiently and so it's very rare in
natural ecosystems and in Agro
ecosystems for soluble phosphorus levels
to accumulate to very high levels the
other issue is in a new soil it's been
sitting in the bag a lot of that
phosphorus is mineralized and so you
might see three or four parts per
million on the pace test but as soon as
you water it and as soon as those plants
start growing it usually drops and
without supplemental feeds yeah 0.3
0.4.5 is usually what you see on the
pace test and I've seen very little
correlation
to what ultimately matters which is the
plant tissue and so as long as levels
are sufficient on the on the tissue test
that's all I care about so really you
know
I have a range of phosphorus on tissue
and as long as it's in that range and
ideally on the high end of that range I
have no concerns whatsoever I will say
that there is a correlation between
sufficient tissue levels and what's seen
on that standard test in pounds per acre
of phosphate so I really like to keep I
like to slowly build phosphorus levels
in soil until that number is sufficient
well my next podcast that I'm actually
recording later this week is with Dr
Carrie Peters over at Jack's fertilizer
she's the chemist over there talking
about tissue testing specifically so
we'll definitely dive into that more for
listeners here really soon which I'm I'm
excited about
um but I want to I want to talk to you
about the the uh
phosphorus number on the standard test
on the Malik 3 test
um how is that tied or is it tied to the
exchange capacity of the soil and then I
want to kind of dive into
CEC TCC and sort of
what what those challenges are with um
you know what we're calling living soils
soilless media versus actual soil
yeah great so
um most phosphorus in a peat-based media
is not on any exchange sites a lot of
it's tied up in compost and so as
microbes slowly decompose that compost
it's released it's also tied up in rock
phosphate minerals and different
animal-based meals like I said fishbone
meal or just standard bone meal and
usually agronomically the traditional
um
CEC definition is
more focused on the soil's ability to
hold cations and phosphate is actually a
negatively charged anion so it's it's
not usually very related to the CEC
um so the CEC cation exchange capacity
is the the interesting thing about CEC
on a soil test especially on peat-based
media is it's actually a calculation
it's not a direct measurement so what I
mean by that is is usually if you're if
a soil test comes back they're directly
measuring how much calcium and nitrogen
and zinc are in that soil they're using
a machine called an ICP and they're
directly measuring the parts per million
of that
nutrient
and with Tec or CEC they're sort of
synonymous
it's actually a calculation that's
adding calcium magnesium potassium and
sodium together the cationic uh
macronutrients and making some small
adjustments for
other bases and hydrogen but but it's a
it's a calculation that's summing all of
those cations extracted in the melee 3
solution and so the Malik 3 has a pH of
2.5 it's dissolving those into solution
and the lab just adds them all up based
on what the the numbers of nutrients are
and the reason that this is a problem is
because usually in traditional agronomic
calculations you apply more nutrients to
a higher uh CEC soil so in a peat-based
media you're gonna see higher CEC when
you have more cationic nutrients and so
you
will apply more nutrients and you keep
applying more and more and all of a
sudden you've over applied so it's a bit
of a positive feedback loop so that's
one issue
um so how I look at the the CEC
measurement is more of a more of a of an
almost like an EC measurement but just
for the cations
if that makes sense because usually CEC
was developed for for mineral Topsoils
and especially acidic Topsoils about any
excess mineral salts and these cations
are are essentially binding to to Clay
particles the negatively charged site
sites on clay and so
um when you add all of those together it
gives you a pretty good sense of of all
of those sites in the soil but in in
soilless Media or in peat-based media
that's not really how it works most of
those cations exist in compost or
minerals or just floating around and in
the in the media Matrix
foreign yeah so I have some questions
about that so
um
anecdotally when I see a high exchange
capacity I'll see
um
I'll see higher levels of our cations
you know calcium magnesium potassium
sodium but I also tend to see higher
phosphate and sulfur levels is that just
because on average when Growers are when
we're seeing those High cation levels
it's just Growers are probably over
applying p and S2 they're not actually
tied in any way mathematically to that
calculation you nailed it so
um you know when you apply to get high
calcium or to get high magnesium
or pet potassium you they're usually
applied in the form of you know gypsum
or potassium sulfate or even just
compost right that brings in all the
nutrients in a package so nutrient
levels tend to be correlated because in
organic production we're we're sort of
applying then
um together even if it's just gypsum
it's still calcium and sulfur together
so you'll see both of those levels climb
simultaneously but you're you're right
on with the the math is not connected
Tec in any anion is not connected
okay and then the way I've always
thought of CEC is like uh a giant sponge
so like what's the soil like when we're
talking about actual soil here like sand
silk Clays ability to retain
nutrients cations and so the higher the
CEC the more clay in there uh the more
nutrients it's going to take for that
soil to be saturated and have a lot of
like plant available fertility so
there's there's pros and cons to high
sea soil a low sea soil let's say like
Sandy soils in Florida for example
um you're going to be constantly
applying low levels of nutrients because
it's not it doesn't have any ability to
retain those nutrients for the plant
however if your CEC in actual soil is
quite High you may have to apply a lot
of nutrients just to move the needle a
little bit and maintain
fertility is that an okay way of
describing anything you would change or
tweak in that sort of Layman's
definition I think that's a pretty good
way to think about it
um a sponge is a good analogy I've also
often seen like a dinner plate you know
and you can like only hold so many ions
on that dinner plate and the dinner
plate is representing a clay colloid
um I think I think Brandon or someone
who works for you in an email to me uh
referred to them as docking sites which
I really liked there's only so many
docking sites on a clay mineral and
these cations can attach and once all
the docking sites are full there's
nowhere for these ions to attach and so
they'll Leach out of the soil over time
and that's why
agronomically you really assume that
there's no excess ions in the soil that
don't aren't cations that aren't
attached to a docking site because
they've all leached out and so if you
extract all the cations and add them up
then you have a really good estimate of
how much how many docking sites there
are in your soil and so I think that was
a good explanation and I think um it's
just a tough thing to apply to
peat-based Media because those docking
sites don't exist it's just a matrix of
peat and compost proper core
aggregate minerals and and so they're
not actually
exchanging in the traditional sense
that that makes sense so it's really
just a measure of your fertility in a
lot of ways it's not actually
um telling you what this there's no real
CEC there
um exactly but one one thing I don't
quite understand then is if the way the
lab measures It Is by measuring by
adding up all these cations
essentially to give you that number how
do they how do they determine an actual
soil what a CEC is because a soil may
have a high CEC but have very little
cations in it right at a given point in
time
how do they determine that
so
they they do the same thing they extract
all the cationic nutrients and then add
them up
um and they adjust for atomic weight
they divide by other bases and
exchangeable hydrogen so they're
accounting for a few other things but
the point is they add it all up and they
estimate the CEC but if
um when you incorporate all of the
cations that we mentioned the nutrient
cations and hydrogen
um a soil with a
lows a high CEC with low nutrient levels
um will be acidic that's that's because
all of those exchange sites will be
occupied by something and if they're not
occupied by calcium
magnesium potassium or sodium it's going
to be hydrogen and so that soil will be
acidic so in a high CEC soil without a
lot of nutrients you're going to see a
lot of hydrogen ions but something is
going to occupy those exchange sites
that that makes a lot more sense to me
most of the soils that we work with are
pretty close to neutral so I don't see
that as
as much but uh that that makes a lot of
sense so let's talk about that really
quickly because there is that
exchangeable hydrogen uh that people
will see on the standard test and
you know it only shows up when you have
obviously acidic soils uh what does that
number really tell us it doesn't
honestly I've asked Logan to get rid of
it it's a it's a source of confusion
it's 100 correlated to pH so it'll be
zero with Pages above seven and it'll
tick up with ph's
um below seven and so it's really just a
different way to look at pH and there's
no useful value to the percent
exchangeable hydrogen on the soil test
awesome
um
let's let's move on to organic matter
yeah and how that relates to a soilless
media versus actual soil and what what
Target should be
great so organic matter does involve a
direct measurement unlike CEC and the
measurement is is a is taken from a
technique called loss on ignition which
um estimates organic matter based on the
weight change
of the soil after they heat it up to a
really high temperature I believe 800
degrees Fahrenheit so almost as hot as
you know a combustion flame
um and at that temperature there's a lot
of oxidation of of
organic matter and so they weigh the
sample before they weigh it after and
essentially they're they're weighing how
much carbon is lost that
at 800 Degrees in Topsoil that carbon is
primarily organic matter
I believe organic matter is 58 carbon so
it's an inexpensive and it's an accurate
enough technique to be widely used in
soil testing it's really the best method
at scale for testing organic matter and
soil or at least estimating organic
matter and it's it's pretty accurate
in actual soil and mineral-based soils
if you go out in your backyard or
whatever
um in peat-based media there's two
problems here the first is that the
carbon that is oxidized in in a
peep-based media is not real organic
matter it's primarily peat moss or
coca-core or immature compost those
things aren't technically organic matter
um
in the same sense that it is in a real
mineral topsoil they're carbon based so
they show up as a big matter
they just behave differently is
essentially what you're getting at right
yeah I mean they are organic matter
they're being that yeah it sort of
depends on how you define organic matter
but in in most I mean most soil
scientists would characterize organic
matter
um at least what we're trying to get at
with organic matter is a long chain
carbon compound that has taken a long
time to form and is fairly recalcitrant
meaning it's it's doesn't decompose very
easily or very quickly and it provides
nutrients and a very sort of diverse
microbial habitat and so by that
definition peat moss doesn't really fit
because
um it doesn't have it's kind of a nerd
it doesn't have many nutrients it's not
it's like a totally different carbon
chain than like I mean the the
this is sort of an Antiquated word but
humus you know is is this substance this
magical sort of jet fuel in the soil
it's totally different than that so yes
it's organic in nature in the sense that
it's made out of carbon but it doesn't
give us all the the plant health and
agronomic benefits that true long-chain
organic matter does in the soil
um it doesn't give us all the benefits
when it turns over and when it changes
form
um so it's just a totally different
species of carbon
so
when we look at the organic matter on a
peat-based media
um it's not it's really just kind of
showing us the weight loss and that gets
to the second issue which is the
measurements highly correlated to bulk
density because if your soil is super
fluffy right out of the bag it's going
to have it's going to show a higher
organic matter
um but as we all know that bulk density
changes over time you know that's why
the that if you grow in a pot it looks
like the soil sinks two to four inches
in the first round
um that bulk density is increasing so
organic matter is going to jump all over
the place based on bulk density and they
make an assumption with topsoil uh bulk
density assumption that's usually pretty
accurate but in peat-based media it's
really not so usually a new peat-based
media is going to see you know show high
organic matter and high CEC right out of
the bag because it's fluffy and it's
full of nutrients but those numbers are
going to jump wildly so those are two
issues there's two more issues I can
kind of stop there
um actually I'm gonna I'm gonna just
present one more which is that
this may be the biggest issue in my
opinion it's not the technical nature of
how they tested and blah blah blah it's
more around what do you do with the
number because the purpose of testing if
you're going to pay money to get a test
it's it's to determine some kind of
action you can take as a grower and so
if there's no management action that you
can take with 40 organic matter or
thirty percent then to me that's the
biggest issue with any metric because
the purpose of these soil tests is to is
to take some kind of valuable
information and then go apply it via
action
so it's not tied at all to the CEC
uh directly at least
they're totally the measurement is not
okay totally separate that's good and
yeah there's very little correlation uh
between those two numbers
so so the bottom line is ignore organic
matter percentage if you're not testing
actual soil yes
now if you are testing actual soil how
does the application of compost come
into play in affecting that organic
matter and giving us an accurate number
of what our percent really is because I
could imagine if I applied compost
earlier in the season tilted in or top
dressed it I take by sample some of it
ends up in the sample the sample
remember is only half a teaspoon of
actual material when we're talking about
the Malik 3
what's that going to do
yes so and that's a great point because
this the first problem I talked about
which is that we're testing pmos or
immature compost and not
organic matter in the traditional sense
that problem exists Outdoors too where
loads of composts have been applied so
you apply compost your organic matter
jumps from two percent to ten percent
you're super proud of yourself right but
that's just measuring the carbon from
your compost
which is good it's it means that your
your carbon inputs are high and that is
one of the many variables that leads to
the formation of stable organic matter
but it's not true organic matter by the
traditional definition so
um that too is an issue and I worked at
a lot of
um small organic vegetable Growers and
they use large amounts of compost and
their organic matter is very very high
on a soil test and
it's also you know when when compost
is applied it goes through a multi-year
decomposition process and so that number
is going to jump all over the place and
so that the organic matter number gives
you a little bit of information like you
know this soil has been cultivated it
has high organic inputs but it's not
necessarily something that should be
managed very closely even in a uh you
know conventional broad acre cropping
system
the organic matter number should be
looked at over I would say a five to ten
year Horizon and not a year-to-year
number
um because to your point there's organic
matter variation in soils as there is
and just everything in nature so
um you are going to see a little bit of
fluctuation you shouldn't see large like
full percentage points but you'll see
maybe tenths or even at a half of a
percent fluctuation year to year so you
really should be looking at added over
you know a five or ten year Horizon even
in real topsoil so it's a very crude uh
measurement it's very important we all
know that organic matter is one of the
most important things
um for organic Agriculture and for soil
health and for plant Health but it's a
it's a really tough thing to measure
accurately
when
your soil test costs 50 bucks
yeah so we're really looking for Trends
is it trending in the right direction is
it moving up is it moving down correct
that's I think I think that's the key
there okay but in a piece based media
just to just to be clear I wouldn't I
wouldn't even worry about the trend
yeah I've seen it jump all over the
place based on the sample so I don't
I I tend to ignore it too
um
well uh you know sticking on the topic
of uh
nutrients
um we were going to talk about uh ratios
sort of versus levels because you get
these ratios of what what your cations
are made up of how much of it is calcium
how much is magnesium how much is
potassium how important is that relative
to
just the actual values in pounds per
acre of calcium magnesium potassium in
terms of sufficiency
yeah so there's there's sort of ratios
the racial conversation is fun because
there's
people throw around a lot of ratios and
it depends on uh
the kind of tests you're taking so for
example I look at ratios on both a
tissue test
and a soil test I look at ratios on the
standard test like base cation
percentages as well as on the pace test
so the ratios that I think matter the
most I I am um I've always really looked
at calcium to potassium as a ratio
um and I look at that primarily on the
tissue test I also look at iron and
manganese there's another very popular
one that I don't necessarily put a lot
of weight on which is nitrogen to
potassium
but I think what you're asking is
probably around the standard test based
cation saturation ratio ratios is that
right
yeah and also the soluble cation ratio
okay great great so yes yes the the soil
tests
um
a very common sort of like Albrecht
based approach is to look at uh what I
call bcsr and it's the percentages of
cations extracted by the Malik 3 and
all over the internet on all kinds of
different websites there's these
percentages that generally fall between
like 70 68 to 80 percent calcium uh 10
to 15 magnesium and three to seven
percent potassium I uh look at those but
I don't put a lot of weight on them
because I prefer when managing a
peat-based media for cannabis production
I like looking at the saturated paste
test and in that regard
um I do look at the percentages
um because what those percentages are
telling you is balance and so my general
approach to nutrient management is you
have to achieve sufficient nutrient
levels and then you want to work toward
balance between those nutrients so you
can have a perfectly balanced
um you're going to perfectly balanced
cation nutrients let's say on the pace
test but it doesn't actually matter if
there's just not enough
food in that soil for those plants to
eat it doesn't matter how balanced it is
and so the first thing I do is I have
sufficiency levels of nutrients
and then the next thing I do is I look
at those percentages and I really like
um to see calcium generally at about 50
percent magnesium at about 20 and
potassium at about 20. and
um for those who are doing the math that
leaves 10 to be allocated elsewhere
oftentimes that goes to sodium and
sometimes it goes to one of those other
nutrients just based on fluctuations or
you know how you like to run your your
soil and
what I've found is that that's that is
by far most important it's the most
correlated to the actual tissue tests in
general it's correlated too to those
those standard tests bcsr ratios which
are usually you know that
what sort of translates is usually about
seven percent potassium on the standard
test
um I do not like to go above 12
magnesium on the standard test and I
always want to be above 60 ideally well
above 70 on calcium and usually if you
can usually those will lead to the right
soil solution balance but I don't try I
don't manage for that standard test
percentage because it's sort of the tail
that Wags the dog I go right to the PACE
test and I look at sufficiency and
balance on the pace test
okay and I want to reiterate uh what you
what you just said there I think that's
really important
um if the soluble salt level on your
soil your EC is is low like let's say
you had 200 PPM on soluble salts that
soil uh it doesn't matter if it's
perfectly balanced you're going to run
out of nutrients relatively quickly
versus a soil with a much higher EC or
soluble salt level so
um but I think that's important because
I've seen some soil tests from from
folks where you know everything looks
balanced but at the end of the day if
that if the amount of fertility is low
it doesn't it doesn't really matter
you're going to run out and you have to
add nutrients and those aren't going to
necessarily be balanced anyway so
I think that's a really important point
you brought up um
also uh as you're as you're looking at
this
um when we talk about hitting uh
sufficiency first
um
just switching topics here one of the
things we talked about was
um sort of luxury nutrients where do you
get concerned about
um sort of excesses and toxicities when
we talk about our major uh cations and
ions you know versus say things that you
know you're not too worried if you see
high levels of
sulfur for example yeah great
okay so
um every nutrient by the way is is sort
of
a separate topic and so they're all very
different and how I look at each one how
I look at each one on the soil test is
they're all different yeah it's so
But to answer your question
um the worst cation to have
in excess is sodium it's not an
essential plant nutrient and it's simply
it it puts undue pressure on
the electrical conductivity in the
osmotic
pressure that it exerts on on Roots so
if there's in a perfect world you'd have
zero PPM of sodium there's just no
purpose
um but that's impossible in organic soil
based systems so sodium is low as
possible that's the worst thing to have
in excess luckily it's very mobile so
you can leech it out
um or flush it out of your soil
if it's not in your water I want to
highlight that because some people have
sodium in their water or they're using
conditioners to their water that's
adding sodium so Flushing High sodium
soles with sodium water doesn't work
yeah yeah it's one of them yeah for sure
I mean the one thing about high sodium
water how you can manage it a
traditional method is you accept it this
is the water we've got
elevated in sodium we can't filter it or
whatever
so you just water water and then you
flush because what happens is the water
evaporates leaves the sodium behind and
so the levels start to accumulate and
you so you can theoretically flush that
out even with your high sodium water but
it's it's never going to get it low it's
just going to revert back to whatever
your water level is but yeah to your
point you can never get it you can never
manage to zero if it's in your water
um so the next one though I want to
bring up which is a tricky one an
organic uh peat-based media is magnesium
and magnesiums
magnesium is is uh
often High often excessive and it's
antagonistic and it's not needed in
nearly the quantity that calcium and
potassium are in the plant tissue and it
gets in the way and it can can really
create sort of this gentle antagonism
that you're not initially going to see
visually but it's slowing down your
plants and reducing yield and crop
quality
so
um magnesium is a tough one to manage
my Approach is
I
like to set a minimum sufficient level
for magnesium and then I have a an
optimization algorithm that changes the
level of calcium and potassium if
magnesium is high to just try to
maintain balance because those are
always competing for one another and so
I'm looking at both the pace tests the
percentage on the pace test and the
percentage on the on the Malik 3. and
like I said I I never apply any
magnesium If the percentage is above 12
because what tends to happen is when you
apply gypsum it opens up and and
magnesium flows into solution so
magnesium is one of the more complicated
things to look at and manage
um and it's not as easy when you have
excess magnesium I still think you
should Leach your soil you'll see those
levels drop especially the soluble
levels but you're never actually going
to be able to pull it all out the key is
you just try to minimize the inputs with
high magnesium I never I sometimes very
rarely I'll recommend a little dolomitic
lime in a real topsoil but never in a
peat-based media and
um so really the only source the only
two sources of magnesium I'm ever
recommending might be a little bit of
um like uh potassium magnesium sulfate
it's an organic mineral
um
as the mineral name but there's
different trade names like kmag or
sulpomag
um yeah
and then
otherwise I think Epsom salt as a foliar
is a great way to just give small
amounts of magnesium to your plant as
needed
um based on visual symptoms or tissue
tests and you're never applying it to
the soil to push those levels up so I
like running that a little bit low and
maintaining plenty of sufficiency and
and more of a weighted balance toward
calcium and potassium
yeah I mean I agree with everything you
said I always run magnesium low in our
soils because I know it's so easy to add
via episode and affordable exactly and
all will actually you know on occasion
do Epsom salt drenches just like a
tablespoon per gallon of water when we
see that magnesium level
drop I like the foliar idea too
um but uh yeah no that's that's really
interesting I wasn't aware of something
being something you could really flush
very effectively and I assume if you did
you're also going to have to add a lot
of fertility back in because you
probably you've absolutely flushed the
more mobile nutrients out to like
phosphate nitrogen potassium things like
that sodium yeah and every everything on
the pace test is going to be mobile
because it's just it's floating it's not
real so it's a good point when you when
you leech heavily because you have an
excess of something everything is going
to go down it's sort of like a hard
refresh so
um for example like
yeah when I when I see something sodium
maybe over 45 parts per million on the
pace test the soil doctor tool will
recommend or my you know my
recommendations will recommend leeching
your soil and that'll flush everything
and then you're going to reset re-test
and reamend
um
and that over the long term is a far
better approach to plant Health than
just continuing to push now sodium some
strains and in some operations sodium is
okay it's not like it's not toxic
it's just going to create excess osmotic
stress on the plant so you're getting a
more you're getting more efficient
metabolism
um when it's lower
the plants having to work harder in that
soil to access nutrients essentially is
what you're saying correct and there is
um in certain crop species like a
substitution effect that happens where
it starts using sodium instead of
potassium Which is less efficient
metabolically
I wasn't aware of that that's
interesting
um
well then let's let's uh let's move on
to a couple of the other touch on some
of the other minerals here you've talked
about magnesium and sodium so far
what's uh
what's another one that uh you've talked
about two relatively you know
antagonistic ones that we want to
monitor
um
what's another one you wanted well and
the other thing just to mention on these
cations is a lot of them are influenced
by more than the levels and the balance
they're influenced by evapotranspiration
and irrigation technique and root size
and so I can't stress enough that it's
really really really valuable to to
use tissue testing to validate
because oftentimes you can have enough
calcium but you don't see enough in the
plant and it's a different issue you
need to address entirely like watering
um or maybe your relative humidity or
your VPD
so tissue testing is really a good way
to to make sure that there aren't other
issues with nutrient uptake
um but to talk about other nutrients I
mean I nitrogen is a fascinating one
um
in the sense that I do think
um of all the nutrients I I generally
recommend maintaining fairly stable
concentrations that's the goal in
organic production
um you know there's a lot of things
happening the microbes are breaking down
amendments and releasing nutrients the
plants are uptaking them nutrients are
being sort of leached to the bottom of
your beds
um when you water so there's a bunch of
different things happening but the goal
should be to really try to maintain
consistent levels sufficient levels
throughout the entire round of most
nutrients but nitrogen is a little
different in the sense that
um
it's going to be taken up quickly and in
high quantities by the plant and
generally speaking
I like to have
you know high but not excessive levels
through veg and I like nitrogen levels
to draw down through veg
um to sort of
to change the carbon and nitrogen
balance in the plant with the theory
that you're sort of optimizing quality
or terpene expression with lower
nitrogen levels it doesn't doesn't mean
zero nitrogen at all because you still
need nitrogen for plant metabolism and
protein synthesis and flower development
but a lot of that nitrogen is actually
being moved from
from the plant's existing tissue so
there's already a lot of nitrogen that's
taken up through the plant cycle that
the plant is then using in flour and so
nitrogen uptake really goes down and uh
you can you can
create some issues by running nitrogen
too hard too late in flour and so that
is that that one is interesting to me
because
um I do think
that should be measured and it should be
managed a little bit differently by not
necessarily maintaining this the same
concentration through the entire cycle
yeah we do see that you know when you
have high nitrogen you'll see uh you'll
have very like larfy
plants that just won't yield and they'll
be super dark green
um
we we do see it uh but rarely because
most of the time we can control nitrogen
through flushing so if you do have too
much nitrogen it's pretty easy to lower
it
um but one question I did have for you
uh that we didn't we didn't answer was
for people who do want to flush how much
water do you recommend by volume
um
to run yeah an average soil
well so one thing one thing about
flushing is it's I don't think it's
great to do in the middle of a round
sometimes you have to if you have a
really good draining soil
um
then go for it but I also think that if
you it can create more harm than good if
you if your soil doesn't necessarily
have high drainage capacity I like to
wait until after you harvest to leech
um
and there's no magic way to do it I mean
one way to do it is you just water your
beds your pots and you just measure the
EC of the runoff and I generally say
just wherever your aec is keep watering
until it's 50 of where you started
that's one method the other method would
be to I just say like water until like
six inches or 12 inches run on the
bottom of the pots or the beds it really
depends on the severity of what you're
dealing with so if you if you are you
know you failed for heavy metals or if
you just have if you have 150 PPM of
sodium on the pace test and you just
want a and like I said a hard refresh
then
um
just just really go for it until you get
a foot of runoff or something
um so it really kind of depends on the
severity there's no magic number that
necessarily it's really really depends
on on what you're trying to do
yeah I guess for me the situations where
I may want to leech mid-round is where I
get a soil test back from a commercial
grower who's you know mid flower plants
aren't developing I see on this test
they've got
300 PPM of nitrates in there
um
I I feel like
and then I'm gonna have a conversation
like Hey we're gonna get a yield but
it's not going to be the yield that you
want do we stress the plant by over
watering it where it's going to you know
you're you're potentially impacting the
biology of the soil you're killing some
some root hairs
um you're causing plant stress but
you're going to lower that nitrate level
what's better I guess is the scenario
there and what would your thought be
with a hypothetical like that you know
I think if you
it just totally depends on the
composition of the media
if it's like a horizonal system or
something that just I don't know
something that's not well that's not
true if it was a horizontal system I
would still
what I would probably recommend
mid-round is to do a slower leaching
event so to do like multiple
pulses that are sort of pushing the
water like this but still pulling air
into the profile between each leaching
event so instead of just one like you
know four hour irrigation set I might
just say water to run off six times in a
row
um that's one idea
I don't know one day yeah
okay are are many people doing a
horizonal system honestly I don't we
don't work with anyone that grows like
that I know it's somewhat popular online
but I feel like the challenges with
watering like you mentioned and and
fertility
sort of move me away from it
I know that several people who have
received soil recommendations for me are
using it but I'm not
um
actively engaged having conversations
with them on a weekly basis but yeah I
think I mean I've heard a lot of people
doing it
um I also just think like
I've mixed media doing tests that is
extremely porous and I've mixed media
where I incorporate five or ten percent
of my top soil from my farm and change
the drainage dramatically so yeah I mean
I think you can reach I just get a
little bit nervous about it because
um everyone has a different situation
but I think in pots when you have a true
peat-based media and pots I think
drainage is fine you just water until
you get heavy runoff and there's no
issue whatsoever but I think it's
something to be aware of I just want to
mention it
no that's a good point I think uh just
for listeners like if you're if we're
talking about Pro mix that's a very
different conversation than talking
about something that's
oh I don't know like you said has actual
topsoil in it and is some sort of
horizonal system that's not going to
drain the same that you're going to have
some perched water challenges and other
things with water movement through the
media potentially
yeah
okay well enough on that let's move on
um was there anything else I know we
could probably do a whole podcast just
on nitrogen but was there anything else
you wanted to touch on besides the fact
that uh nitrogen really needs to be
managed and you can absolutely have
too much
um wow there's a million things we talk
about uh
amino acids are interesting
um to me from a nitrogen standpoint
um
and I just think that that the only
other thought I wanted to throw out
there for folks is when you're when
you're using organic nitrogen amendments
all of them including amino acids have
to go through the nitrogen cycle
um I I think maybe even on the last
podcast here for the last several years
I generally
thought and I had been told
um from
other experienced agronomists and
Consultants that that amino acid uptake
is much more metabolically efficient
and it saves the plant an enormous
amount of energy because the plant
doesn't have to convert nitrate back
into amino acids to create plant tissue
which is uses the amino acids directly
and my thinking on that has actually
evolved quite a bit and I don't actually
think that plants are uptaking
amino acids in significant quantities at
all because
um the well I've reviewed a lot of of
the research on amino acid uptake and I
actually think most of it's getting
converted into ammonium and then nitrate
plant takes it up and then it gets
converted back into amino acids so it is
true that theoretically you get a huge
metabolic savings if the plant uptakes
amino acids but my belief is that the
microbes feed first in the soil and so
they're going to take that those amino
acids and convert it into nitrate the
reason I like amino acids is because of
the particle size either they're in
liquid form or they're in a powdered
form that you can feed and they're
they're very quickly available and so it
really gives you more control as a
grower when it comes to nitrogen
management
um and I also want to mention that all
organic amendments are Amino based
they're all protein based so they're
enzymatically broken down into amino
acids
um and so even when you apply alfalfa
meal that is a sort of amino based
source of fertility it's just a much
larger particle size that takes longer
to break down in the soil microbially so
that's sort of an interesting thing to
me I I think more about particle size
than I do about uh the source of the
nitrogen whether the label says amino
acids or whether the label says soybean
meal for example
um and so my my thinking's evolved on
that a bit
I don't know where I was going with that
other than oh the nitrogen cycle so
the other thing I think Growers need to
think about is when you apply a huge
amount of amendments
um organic amendments that microbial
action that breaks those amendments down
is consuming a lot of oxygen so the
reason that
it's usually pretty intuitive and pretty
uh well understood that you should let
your soil cook before planting
um is because all those amendments are
turning into ammonium
before they turn into nitrate and
ammonium is really not a preferred plant
available source of nitrogen so that's
the one thing but in that process
those microbes are consuming a
tremendous amount of oxygen and that's a
huge challenge for Growers because
people are trying to flip you know into
the next round as quickly as possible
and sometimes you don't have three weeks
to let your soil cooker let those those
amendments break down and so
honestly if you can never let your soil
get so depleted that you're applying
enormous amounts of those organic
amendments that's the best solution
um you're just kind of constantly either
top dressing or feeding
um nitrogen as the plants need it and
you never let your your nitrate get to 2
PPM and have to apply like massive
amounts of any of these amendments
because once you plant into it those
young plants are not going to like the
high ammonium low oxygen environment
that's interesting because the way I've
always described it and correct me if
I'm wrong on this but my understanding
is as we add a lot of
uh nutrients you know in this case we're
talking about nitrogen
um one I've noticed that different
uh nitrogen sources will create
different microbial communities and
different sort of bacterial blooms
um certain things are seem to be more
balanced from a microbial perspective
like alfalfa meal versus some of these
other amendments but I've always
described it as
um sort of like the you add all these
nutrients you've created this Feast for
all the bacteria archaea fungi protozoa
in in the soil it's a the bacteria is
sort of an exothermic reaction they're
generating heat as they reproduce and
that's creating this you know it's
essentially thermally composting your
soil and plant roots also don't like a
lot of that temperature and they may not
be able to access the nutrients as
efficiently like you said the microbes
feed first so even if they're sufficient
fertility in that soil if the bacteria
is actively like reproducing at high
levels then those nutrients aren't going
to be available to the plant and you
could see
um deficiencies expressed in the plant
even though well probably due to like
you said excess ammonium root hair death
from soil temperatures a lack of oxygen
so a variety of factors potentially
affecting it so what we try to do is
like you said you you have high
fertility in the soil you go to reament
and by having a larger volume of soil
like in a bed when you go to reament you
don't have to add as much nutrients as
you would to that same volume of soil if
it was grown in like a seven gallon pot
so we don't have to it's not going to
heat up it's not going to go through
quite those extremes and it doesn't need
to sit as long too in in my experience
yeah yeah definitely
um Okay cool so uh just to keep things
moving along here
um
what are some of the ones that you you
aren't concerned about you know I had
mentioned sulfur as sort of a luxury
nutrient
um what are some other ones that you're
like okay there may be a little too much
here but I'm not too concerned yeah well
if I had a magic wand I would reduce
sulfur
um just because again it's okay putting
on new pressure on EC but there's no but
besides that I have no issues with high
sulfur and I actually just think it's
um okay
if you if you're if you in order to get
high calcium and high potassium you just
sort of have to use you're going to see
high sulfur and that applies to compost
too like you're just a lot of compost
you're going to see high sulfur so it's
a bit unavoidable in most organic
systems and it doesn't create real
negative effects in the plant but like I
said if I could just wave a magic wand I
would reduce it because it's it's uh
it's in luxury levels and it's putting
upward pressure on EC
I
let's see other nutrients I mean I
really like
high levels of calcium I've always liked
running high levels of calcium
um I've never seen real negative effects
from that I
have always
liked
um I don't wanna I don't wanna
say high levels of any micronutrient
because that can you can run into issues
but compared to other crops and
um other just sort of Target levels of
nutrients I generally like slightly high
manganese and when I see luxury levels
of Manganese I'm not too worried about
it as long as it's not surpassing iron
and as long as the tissue test isn't
showing anything super out of whack
um
luxury levels I mean potassium
can be pretty high without concern
especially
um again as long as the calcium levels
are high enough on the tissue test in
week two of flower I think having pretty
high potassium levels is not a problem
whatsoever
um
I think that's about it I don't think I
want anything to be too excessive and
even the things I just named can be
excessive I literally just looked at a
soil test and I recommended
um
leaching because potassium was too high
so I'm I'm sort of putting my foot in my
mouth but I think those three nutrients
generally I like to see in pretty high
levels that cannabis plants generally
respond well to high concentrations
so some are just more concerning I guess
um in terms of their detrimental or
negative effects at high levels versus
others that you're like okay it's high
but you're still going to get a good
crop out of it absolutely exactly
exactly and obviously we're talking
about like it depends on how high but
yeah I mean there's a pretty big range I
guess is my point that
um the plants will do pretty well in I
think the
yeah I mean it's not like chloride or
sodium or
um copper
I saw Copper at 60 parts per million I'd
be really worried
that makes sense
um well let's let's talk a little bit
about
um
let's do some let's talk about uh some
of the stuff you have going on here
because you know we've given out a lot
of information here you have other
resources available through slow doctor
Consulting
um what are some of those things that
people can utilize you for
yeah thanks so
um pretty much my two major offerings
the things that I obsess about every day
and think about all the time
um
last year I put together a course called
become a cannabis soil expert and it
includes it's a course that includes
over 12 hours of self-guided video
content that details really everything
about organic nutrient Management in
cannabis so Growers can come become more
self-sufficient in managing their
nutrition in-house and so I've put a lot
of time into that there's a number of
different modules and dozens of videos
that really just dive into the
fundamentals of techniques and soil
targets and plant tissue targets and how
to amend soil and essentially write
their own program
taking control and having the confidence
to do all this stuff organically
in-house with data and precision which
is something that I think has been
lacking in the industry for a while the
other thing that I've been working on
obsessively every single day is this
soil doctor tool which is a it's a it's
a digital
I'll call it just a tool that's intended
to sort of be a digital agronomist for
nutrient management and cannabis so
Growers enter a few pieces of
information about their their grow along
with soil tests and the tool spits out a
Precision organic nutrient
recommendation to assist in making a
decision about what to apply to your
soil and in what quantity and it uses a
fairly complex mathematical model to
really determine the rates
I want to dive into that but I don't
want to gloss over your soul course I
want to talk a little more about that uh
before we move on because I've I've
taken the course
um
I think it's probably the best online
tool for cannabis Growers that want to
understand
how to properly amend your soil how to
soil test
um
what the different amendments are and
how to utilize them in your soil uh you
give a lot of information in there and
the ability to comment on the modules uh
all the all the short videos I was able
to do it over a period of a few weeks
I'm just kind of diving in and watching
a video here and there when I had time
kind of letting it mull over and process
and then coming back to it asking
questions and things like that so
yeah I I don't want to just skip over
the fact that this is a pretty
comprehensive course that you've put
together I know it took
as someone who's working on putting
together like a botany course and some
other tools I know how much work went
into that uh to create so yeah thanks
thanks for your thanks for your positive
words the positive feedback I've gotten
from you and other Growers has been
really humbling so I appreciate it
yeah are you adding to that at all or
what are some of the things that you've
I know you've gone back and made some
changes as you're learning too which I
think is really cool
um yeah
yeah I added a
topsoil module so there's there's
there were originally five modules
um probably 10 hours of content and I
added a sixth one on on outdoor
cultivation
and so which really was my bread and
butter
um years ago and so I just kind of go
into the different tools techniques
cultivation techniques irrigation
techniques and and ultimately nutrient
management methods for outdoor topsoil
and that was the biggest addition in the
last year and then I also go through and
I yeah I update things as I learn more I
change some of the target levels as I as
I go I try to do that on a six-month
basis and I only update the course when
it's codified I'll change things in my
um my agronomic model or my Consulting
practice a little bit and I'll let that
run for six months before I update the
course so the course is sort of the
encyclopedia and I try not to update it
too much but I'm on there constantly as
soon as someone if someone asks a
question or if there's any conversation
happening I'm on there
um
that day within 24 hours so the updates
happen usually on a six-month basis now
I would say for I'd be curious to hear
Tad for listeners on a scale of one to
ten what what is the technical nature of
the course would you say
10 being very technical very Advanced
Growers only one being beginner Growers
who have their you know are in their
first cycle in a tent
that's a great question I think it's a
sliding scale a little bit so like the
first section of the course to me was
sort of information I already knew
um and no offense but it was you know it
was it was fairly basic in nature just
to give you a over line or an outline of
of sort of what these different
amendments are
uh you know what are your options for
nitrogen what are your options for for
phosphorus passing these sorts of things
and then as you get further into the
course it gets you know it gets sort of
as technical as you want it to be
um in a lot of ways um the audience that
listens to this podcast is is pretty
Savvy and pretty technical like I
I you know I've interviewed geneticists
neuroscientists and you know people like
yourself that are experts in their field
and so I I feel like
um
I'm kind of dancing around the answer
here uh I think this course is for
anyone who's really passionate about
soil science and wants to understand the
why because it's one thing to be able to
um
you know take a soil test and send it
off to a consultant or plug it into a
calculator and get a result but it's
another thing to kind of understand
what's actually going on so that you can
make
actionable decisions so
um I throw it like I guess overall maybe
a seven or an eight so
where I think it makes sense is either
you're you're a hobbyist and you're
super passionate about soil science and
gardening or if you're a commercial
cultivator that's using Organics and not
working you know closely with an
agronomist or consultant or a company
that can do those things for you then I
think this is knowledge you absolutely
have
and uh
I think that's my answer I will add that
it's you know it's not uh
it's not a low price point um of Entry
it's an expensive course because of the
amount of time and energy and research
that goes into it not just in creating
it but learning the material to be able
to teach it
um but I think that's very affordable
when we talk about a commercial
cultivator
for a tent grower it may not be uh it
may not be in the budget unless it's
something you're really really
passionate about does that kind of
answer it
yeah no I appreciate that I I I'm I have
that Curiosity because I don't know you
know
what level it's at to other people but I
also think I asked that just because I
wanted
maybe to highlight the that yeah it's
for it's for passion and Growers
it's not it's like it's not necessarily
a dabbling course I don't think
um maybe the first module is like you
said
no not at all like I think you're I
think you're right on it is
um it is challenging it makes you think
it's like taking a a course in sort of
soil science with an emphasis on soil
testing and I think uh soil is media in
a lot of ways so if if you wanna if you
want to understand why
the local agronomist doesn't give you a
good recommendation for your cannabis
grow because they're looking at you know
a Logan soil test and trying to
understand why your potting soil is
performing differently well this would
explain it to you
yeah great
um yeah and it covers you know like
liquid feed recipes and foliers and
various subtopics but really the the
basis and the meat of the course is
organic
soil base or I guess we should
peat-based uh cannabis cultivation so I
think people often ask like people
people often ask is it would it benefit
me if I'm if I'm not an organic grower
and
the answer is I some of the principles
the principles absolutely
but
all of the targets and the general uh
approach is definitely an organic
approach
um I don't really talk about your rears
or you know polymer coded
fertility it's just it's it's very much
an organic based approach so anyway
that's that's a good point yeah
um okay well I'll let you move on to
explaining the the tool now oh yeah okay
so the tool is another extension yeah
the tool is an extension of this General
philosophy that that comes from the
course too which is test don't guess
um you know my my Approach with the
course and with this tool
um is to recommend only what's needed to
improve plant metabolism so this tools
you know you enter information about
your grow
um your soil tests and it it does this
complex mathematical calculation
um to determine Amendment rates and it's
the opposite of the traditional kitchen
sink approach in which we throw every
biostimulant enzyme ferment microbe and
nutrient at the plant and hope for the
bed the best so you can still Growers
can still do that you can apply your
special sauce whether that's a fungal
compost extract or a high-end silica
foliar or a micronized calcium
or k ferment whatever in addition
to the Amendments from the tool but the
tool is really supposed to hit the the
low hanging fruit
and it does so with data and precision
because this the industry has always
been so full of like you know blood
Blaster RX for terpenes or bio catalyze
for microbes or whatever fulvic biochar
sprouted cow mag foliar so you know I I
do you know I I do a lot of things in my
When I grow cannabis and in my Orchard
that are Beyond just the bare minimum I
had I love a lot of that stuff but I
guess my point is you have to start with
the fundamentals first you have to make
sure that nutrients are sufficient
available balanced
um before all of that other stuff and so
this tool is really intended to make
very accurate recommendations to make
sure that all of the macro and
micronutrients essential for the plant
are in your soil in the best way
possible
foreign
yeah that's I think that's I want to go
back and highlight what you just said
because that's so important I see
companies marketing product based grow
methodologies all the time you know like
add this product add that product
um and you can absolutely do that and
like you said you can use all of these
ferments and and other things but at the
end of the day if you don't have
sufficiency in your major your your
major nutrients uh it's not going to
matter that that's going to be your
limiting factor growth so I always start
with what's my limiting factor of growth
and if it's fertility I want to figure
out what cation or anion it is and then
if
you know you apply some sort of pumpkin
extract and you get a plant response I
want to figure out why rather than
continuing to buy a product that's you
know mostly liquid and probably
overpriced I want to know what what is
in there that's making a difference
because it means you have something
that's limiting your plants health or
growth
um and so I start with sufficiency start
with a good foundation like you said and
and something that's interesting because
when I first started I started off using
these Soul calculators the the initial
ones were based off of
um
and getting uh nutrient density so not
necessarily optimal yields when we talk
about cannabis but just an overall
sufficiency of or are not even
sufficiency but higher levels of of
nutrient fertility to make sure that
that grown edible crop is going to be
healthier sort of the Steve Solomon's
approach essentially
when it worked it works okay it works
fine and you get you get some good
information from there and those
calculators you know are not bad and
then there's I've seen other calculators
come out for cannabis too but for me
there's more information I want than
just what's on a soil test when I'm
evaluating a garden and trying to make
Amendment recommendations and you know
the the tool that you put together
uh has other variables
associated with that and and so can you
kind of talk about what those are and
why they're important
yeah sure so when I think about I just
want to step back and when I think about
photosynthesis I think about light
think about CO2 water temperature and
nutrients and this tool
is only focused on the nutrient part of
it helping Growers
understand and apply nutrients in a
better more precise way
to focus on that bottleneck of
photosynthesis so if your environment's
off this tool isn't necessarily going to
help if you're not watering correctly
this this doesn't is it's not going to
address that and I think that you've
been really good
um
at pointing out that this isn't a
Panacea for growing it's not like an
automated you know it's not going to
solve all your problems but the idea
here is it's focused on nutrient
management so the variables when you go
into the tool you set up an area
and you choose whether you're indoor or
outdoor because that matters you also
choose your cycle length because the
tool changes nutrient levels slightly
depending on if your plants are going to
be in the soil for less than 12 weeks or
longer than 16 weeks so for example the
nitrogen Amendment quantities are
increased a bit for a long-term or
full-term crop versus a soil intended
for like a nine week flower I'll add
that the difference here is relatively
small because like I said I like to
maintain
um
concentrations as opposed to trying to
pre-load too heavily
but there's a happy balance that the
tool is trying to achieve there it also
it also asks you for your soil volume
which is a big deal as anyone who's
grown in a seven gallon pot versus a 30
gallon pot
um there's a difference there
and the tool actually out takes your
soil volume and it outputs the quantity
of amendments for your entire soil
volume as well as per just a you know a
cubic yard of soil so you can kind of
choose
um which which way you go there
and then it also when you're setting up
an area asks for uh your compost and
this is an interesting conversation that
we've had to add compost might be the
biggest variable in living soil nutrient
management because all composts are
wildly different so the tool asks for
the nutrient levels on the compost
um from a compost analysis which most
Growers don't have and that's okay and
if you don't have it it asks for what
the compost is made out of so at least
it can make an estimate it can model the
nutrient numbers based on the feedstocks
of that compost
foreign
I just want to add to that because one
of the things we're going to talk about
with soul recipes but I I don't think we
have time but the one thing I want to
highlight there is that uh I see people
in forums still all the time saying oh
I'm gonna run Mike's mix or John's Bloom
mix or whatever
um
but really all of these online slow
recipes are going to be somewhat
inaccurate just because they're all
going to be sourced from different
compost so if you really want to
formulate a soil or you know a potting
soil or a media correctly it needs to
start being formulated around what
fertility is in your compost so it's one
of the 300 yep 100 a combo is made out
of fish and hardwood aged for a year
versus a compost made out of yard waste
turn six times in six weeks in oh yeah
Middle America versus a compost made out
of lobster waste on the East Coast the
the nutrient profile between those three
is striking the difference the
difference in the nutrient profile is
striking so yeah
um
and then and then the only other thing
that you would enter in the soil doctor
tool in the area section is is that your
preferred nitrogen sources so Growers
get to choose up to four nitrogen
amendments that the recommendation will
use
um our default is usually to use four
soybean meal alfalfa meal granular
poultry manure and blood meal to
optimize nitrogen release rates and
microbial diversity but it doesn't
really matter honestly like I think the
most important thing is for Growers to
do their own research and choose the
best sources of nitrogen for their
operation and for their values
um and there's very subtle pros and cons
of nitrogen sources but the point is
that people can customize
um
the output a bit based on their
Amendment preferences
um so yeah I mean the inputs to the
model are taking as many things as
possible that influence nutrient
management and trying to account for
those and trying to change the
recommendations and trying to model the
entire nutrient system in an organic
way and use data from both the standard
and paste test to spit out a calculated
recommendation as a guidance tool so I
always I'd like to tell people that the
recommendations are guidance it's like
okay based on all the information I have
here's the best advice I can give
um and you get a fairly comprehensive
recommendation with notes about the soil
and precision you know recommendations
and a bunch of tips about how to apply
the Amendments the report is is pretty
awesome and so that's kind of what I've
been working on and honestly for it's
like five years in the making because
I've been
I've just gone so deep into this that uh
there's just a lot of you know
dozens of conversations and I think I've
looked at like 5 000 peat-based soil
tests and done calibration experiments
and
um taken just classic agronomic
um
research and all tried to incorporate it
into this this one tool for Growers to
use
yeah I looked into doing something like
this years ago and frankly I just
realized I didn't have the brain power
to uh calculate for all the variables
that I really wanted to in a
in a tool and you've gotten more in
there than anyone else I've seen it's
pretty it's pretty impressive honestly
um
that you're able to pull that together
yeah and I will say like
um
you know when I when I sit down with a
grower or Brandon who works with me um
on that we'll look at you know
because because we're having a
conversation with the grower we can we
have them send us photos and we look at
videos sometimes with their grow space
or we'll look at
um you know can we look at the photos of
the plant uh up close if you're having
challenges plus uh you know entire the
entire plan so we can look at for hidden
and mobile nutrient issues uh
um you know we check on what their
environment is all of these different
things that can affect again just trying
to figure out what that limiting factor
of growth is and if it is indeed
fertility but barring the ability to do
a full-on like
comprehensive console which is something
that you offer too if people want to go
down that route I think this is the best
available online tool out there and if I
were if I were a grower and just looking
to get you know I had a soil test and I
needed to get a result
um and I wanted to do it affordably I
would absolutely use
your soil doctor tool I think it's I
think it's awesome so yeah thanks a lot
I appreciate it and it's one of those
things where it's like
I sort of leave it up to
head Growers or you and Brandon our IPM
experts to like really identify in the
Top Lane thyroid or you know like a
watering issue there's so many things I
just can't address oh I can't address
all of it so the tool is really intended
to be it is intended to be like just
focused on one specific area where you
guys could use the tool in your more
holistic analysis so it's not yeah I
wouldn't call this a holistic agronomic
tool it is a nutrient organic nutrient
management tool so
yeah no that's that's great
um
well we've already been talking for over
an hour here uh I I could I could talk
to you all day honestly I love all of
our conversations I always learn
something new uh was there anything else
you wanted to share though before we uh
before we sign off
you know I don't think so
um
yeah we could we could go on and on I
feel like we do sometimes
um even in preparation you called me
asked me to come on and we ended up
talking for an hour so it's easy to to
burn an hour talking about these topics
um but no there's nothing else that's
popping out in my head I think
um
something I've been really excited about
and thinking just more about in general
is just particle size of amendments
and there's always the topic of water
and pH adjustment but I think we
actually addressed that in our in the
last podcast and I'm happy to to chat
about that at a later point on a on a
live video or another podcast because
those are big topics
yeah I'd love to get you back on I mean
lately what's been on my mind is uh
watering as well I think that's always
something that I'm always thinking about
uh you know I mentioned I just got a
bunch of house plants and so I'm
learning how to water differently for
different plants in different media
which has been really interesting and
then also heavy metals just um
there's so much there that we have to
learn and there's so many variables that
affect heavy metal uptake that um
I I it's one of those topics that I just
I I keep learning more and more about
and and I'm I'm interested anymore
because I also think about my health
like
I mentioned this the other day on a
podcast I was in I was in Costco the
other day and I was
um looking at some organically grown
um
what was it uh
trying to remember the vegetable it
might have been um
let's just let's just say uh tomatoes uh
so I was looking at organic tomatoes
grown in Mexico versus uh Greenhouse
grown tomatoes conventionally grown in
California which is actually going to be
healthier for my family
there was once in Mexico I don't really
know what the heavy metals levels are
they probably weren't a ton of
pesticides applied necessarily or other
inputs that I might have issue with on
that Greenhouse or hot house grown
tomato I don't know
um
it definitely I'm definitely thinking
Less in terms of Organics versus like
conventional and More in terms of like
healthy and sustainable if that makes
sense
yeah absolutely yeah I mean I I think a
lot about
nutrient density I always have again
Steve Solomon was I find a major like
pioneer in that space for me I got
started with his book probably 10 years
ago or something
and yeah it is just such a it is such an
important thing and I'm curious if ever
in our lifetime we're going to be able
to quantify that be really nice to know
the other thing I think a lot about is
because I know how crops are grown
um a lot of them not all of them but
sometimes I know what's more likely to
be sprayed and what's not so like you
know strawberries for example always
freaked me out I tend to oh yeah yeah
tend to uh but but like and sometimes
sometimes I think that stuff got pretty
Pest and disease-free crop so yeah
there's so many it's a very complicated
World
um when we start importing food
yeah well I again I appreciate your time
maybe that's another conversation that
people are interested too
um because it's something I've been
thinking about a lot as well let me let
me leave one more thought for the
Cannabis Community as pre you know in
like this this era of sort of low prices
and a contraction in the market and
things
you mentioned Costco
and I think three years ago I did a big
fun project with a massive organic
blueberry farm in Pacific Northwest and
I did this big analysis and spent many
days on the farm walking around their
blocks huge Farm like I got lost I'd
couldn't find the exits of the farm
um
and
they were their fertility budget was a
thousand dollars per acre so they were
spending a thousand dollars on organic
inputs liquid fish hydraulicate gypsum
microbes like a lot of the stuff that
we use and I was blown away because a
thousand dollars for Acres a lot and
when I asked him about that the the farm
manager he just made it really clear
that when you're growing a high value
crop
you can't skimp on your fertility budget
and that's not to say have an unlimited
fertility budget for cannabis production
I'm not saying that because I am a fan
of precision and not throwing the
kitchen sink at it but I also think
people should forever be thinking about
fertility and inputs and really focusing
on nutrient management when you're
trying to achieve a high value crop of
any kind and so I just want to leave it
on that note because I think that other
agricultural crops have really figured
that out and they don't ever skimp on
their fertility budget
in a premium Market even when prices are
low
yeah that's a good point I mean for me
when I think about that I think about my
inputs being high quality in the sense
of like I'm not going to buy a shoddy
biochar or cheap earthworm castings if I
can find a higher quality Source I'm
willing to pay a little extra for it to
know that what I'm getting is going to
offer me all the benefits of what that
product is because we do see a wide
variety and again it comes back to
compost like compost is one of those
things I will not skimp on soil is one
of those things I will not skimp on if
I'm looking at two different
Alfalfa meals uh you know or fish meal
or something like that I might go with
the lower price one or gypsum if I can
find a cheaper version of gypsum and you
know they're relatively similar then I
have no problem saving money there but
yeah I mean you
good soil makes growing fine
and then use Precision to just to just
apply only what you need and save the
money and not applying excessive things
but apply high quality things because in
a living soil system or when you're just
reusing your slow round after round
um or if you have a topsoil where it's
not going anywhere and your kids are
going to inherit it the quality does
matter and the microbial communities
over time really do respond well to that
so I agree with you
awesome awesome yeah don't fall for the
marketing hype that you see all over
social media these days uh it drives me
nuts
all right man well hey have a wonderful
rest of your day thank you for your time
and uh let's do this again sometime soon
thanks so much for having me on Tad
um
[Music]
thank you
that was Bryant Mason of soil doctor
Consulting and you are listening to the
Cannabis cultivation and science podcast
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at
www.kisorganics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and please take a
time to leave us a review if you listen
on Apple podcasts or other platforms I
do read them all and appreciate the
feedback and more reviews help us rank
higher so others can help find the show
thanks for listening
[Music]