[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe on iTunes or
stitcher or whatever platform you're
listening on and leave me a rating and
review this is really helpful and allows
me to keep producing good content for
free by drawing on more of the top names
in the industry to the show I'm excited
to be back after the holidays for a
fresh start in 2018 I've already lined
up some amazing guests also we've added
a new commercial growers mix to our soil
mix line and a bunch of other products
to improve the health and growth of your
plants be sure to go on our website and
sign up for our newsletters as a way to
stay up to date with everything that is
going on along with our new product
launches upcoming podcasts and much more
our guest this week is Jesse Blum jesse
is a Northwest native and comes from a
strong background of horticultural and
environmental sciences she's passionate
about animals permaculture and making
functional gardens beautiful she travels
nationwide as a speaker and is the
best-selling author of free-range
chicken gardens and practical
permaculture design Jessie's work has
gotten press and been featured in many
national and local media outlets from
the New York Times Better Homes and
Gardens Sunset magazine Disney Martha
Stewart Living Mother Earth News Utne
reader fine gardening magazine and PBS
is growing a greener world TV I met
Jesse quite a few years ago now and we
became good friends she was instrumental
in designing and planning our farm and
is a big part of the community her book
practical permaculture design is a must
read in my opinion if for no other
reason than to get you thinking about
how to best utilize and structure your
farm or garden and get a better
understanding of how permaculture might
apply in your life
Jesse can you go in a little bit into
how you got into
gardening and garden design and thanks
for coming on the show well thanks for
having me um yeah I have a long history
with working with the earth and with the
plants and I I'd like to think it
started when I was like really young and
just loved being outdoors and making
friends with all the organisms outside
like from insects to plants to all the
mammals and animals and I really loved
the experience of just being outside and
having relationships with everything I
didn't really trust humans at that much
as a youngster so when I was starting to
look at careers as I was a teenager I
wanted to work with animals and realize
that animals suffer a lot of abuse and I
couldn't quite stomach it so that well I
can learn about plants and make my
career around plants because I don't
need to watch them suffer which I came
to realize that's that was um not
correct and once you start feeling into
two plants you can start to see when
they do suffer as I'm sure a lot of
growers can see firsthand but I never
really intended to become what I've
ended up doing for my career I now run a
company that's 20 years in design build
firm that does ecological work
for both residential commercial and some
government work as well but it started
with just a love for nature and wanting
to learn more and my design background
just grew out of people asking me for
help and it started with me working in a
kind of a residential
land care setting and people asking well
what can I do for this space that you
know plant may have died or something
and it just grew and grew to the point
where I couldn't quite handle it after
about ten years and I had to adjust my
life to
to make it what I needed and so the
business is still thriving and it's been
almost 20 years and I'm doing a lot of
other things now too
I've written three books at this point
and
have been a teacher that travels around
the country and teaching for different
media organizations like Mother Earth
News and I'm doing a lot of writing for
different magazines now and really
enjoying that aspect of my career but
nothing beats being outside and working
with the plants and getting my hands in
the soil yeah I remember going to some
of your first talks at Mother News when
you were doing your free-range chicken
chicken Gardens tour and
you've kind of evolved from there onto
the the permaculture and now your latest
book I guess I'm wondering could you
talk a little bit about how
permaculture came into your life and how
that sort of became incorporated into
your design and what you do with your
business
yeah so II when I was in college in the
90s the late 90s I was
entering an industry that I didn't
really know much about and in the world
of horticulture I expected to learn a
lot about how nature functioned and I
learned like botany and soil science and
and we really focused on a lot of the
the foundational
academics of horticulture but we were
also learning about like pesticide use
and the things that didn't align with me
or resonate at all and I I was you know
kind of an angsty young adult at that
time and was kind of pissed off at what
I saw in the industry as a norm and I
just understood nature to work
beautifully on its own and so I couldn't
really understand like why are we
forcing all these things to grow in a
way that aren't natural we're using all
these chemicals that are harmful
and then we're polluting our environment
and I at that time was not
really looking for permaculture but it
landed in my lap through a book and that
was written by Bill Mollison I'm called
introduction of permaculture and he's an
Australian one of the founders of the
concept
and when I looked at the book at first I
was like oh this is totally common sense
it's like ecological design we don't
need to force nature we just need to
learn how to work with it in harmony to
to meet our own needs and at that time
in the 90s nobody I knew was talking
about permaculture and if I hadn't met
someone at that time there was kind of
this air about them that I didn't again
didn't resonate with and I I just kind
of took my path with permaculture in my
own way and
really followed the ethics and the
principles of
taking care of the earth taking care of
ourselves and giving back which that in
itself is the foundation of permaculture
is the ethics that it's it's rooted in
and in the like ten years later I want
to say so I ran my business with
permaculture and my life to a degree and
in 2010 I was asked to design a garden
for Seattle tilth which is a nonprofit
organization that teaches people how to
garden and they wanted me to design a
permaculture garden for the Northwest
Flower and Garden Show and I at first
was just like yes of course this is
super easy and this is like how I live
my life and I couldn't wait to share it
with the world and the show organizers
actually said well we're not going to
use that word in describing your garden
because no one understands what it means
and so I was like whatever you know it's
a it's a lost opportunity but in that
show which the garden was really really
well-received it was called the little
farm in the city and had all kinds of
great systems set up but a man named
Dave Bain Lyon walked up to me and
anyone who knows Dave long dreadlocks
really jolly attitude walked up and like
hey this is a great permaculture design
and I was like whoa somebody actually
knows it appreciates what that means and
Dave and I developed a friendship he's
an educator over at the Bullock
homestead and has been for many years
and we started working together on
projects he works more internationally
and I'm my business is more local so we
started doing work and ultimately
decided to write a book together after
the chicken book came out and the
permaculture book is now I'm really
proud of it I think of my books kind of
like my kids the it's written now in
five languages and is used as an
academic text in a lot of colleges that
teach permaculture and so I'm really
proud of that book and kind of what it's
done out in the world so far but when I
met Dave and I started going to the Bois
Locke homestead and they've been doing
permaculture for about thirty plus years
now I was amazed at how it was used in
real life from not only the business
standpoint but how people were living
off of the land and I left the first
time going to the bullocks going how can
I make my life more like that not just
my business but really you know not
producing waste and growing as much food
as I could on my own and medicine so
that was kind of a big turning point for
me to see it more applied in multiple
uses and now I look at permaculture as a
way of life that you can apply towards
anything you can apply it towards your
finances you can apply it towards
relationships
gardening of course is what most people
begin to know it from or with but really
you can use it for anything yeah what I
love about your book is that it really
is that introduction it sort of bridges
the gap between you know people like the
bullocks or people like Dave who are
amazing permaculturist but for the
average person who lives in the house
and maybe doesn't you know pee on their
plants or live in a year it's a little
bit of a challenge to understand how to
get from one space to the other so that
that's the best thing I think I can say
about about your book is that it helps
people as an introduction into what
permaculture can be before we go any
further though how would you really
define permaculture for people who
aren't as familiar with it so the kind
of high level definition I would say is
it's a design system or toolkit
for human habitat so if you think about
how we design like insect habitat or
butterfly habitat or any kind of habitat
we're looking at how ecological systems
work together and you know we're just
another organism on this planet one
species out of millions and we have a
huge impact in all the environment
around us so permaculture is a system or
of tools resources to help us make
decisions so that we can live more in
harmony or ecological balance and I
think of it like how we're supposed to
live you know as stewards of the land
and the land and the earth offer
everything that we need but we've got
some gotten so far removed from that
that the systems that we depend on now
like food systems or water systems and
they're on automated and they're out of
our control for the most part and so
when I think of permaculture kind of at
a high level it's a design system and to
relate it to something maybe people are
more familiar with like engineering or
architecture those are also design
systems where you could build all kinds
of things you know from an airplane to a
skyrise permaculture designs our
habitats and all the systems that we
rely on and but unlike some other design
systems permaculture is rooted in ethics
and I always say like if you take
nothing else away from
permaculture as an introductory
understand that the ethics are probably
the most important thing and there's
several of them but the three most
important or foundation are taking care
of the earth and so when we make
decisions how are we making a decision
that impacts the earth and every single
thing we do in life impacts our
environment so whether it's what are we
eating what are we fertilizing our
plants with how are we spending our
money how does that impact the earth and
then the second ethic of caring for
people and if people aren't taken care
of or their needs aren't met they're not
going to be able to take care of the
earth and it starts with ourselves first
and making sure that our own need
they're met and then taking care of
others around us and that's one that
doesn't get a lot of like a lot of
people don't talk about it with
introductory to permaculture because
people are usually focused on garden
related things but I like to put a lot
of emphasis on that because it's really
important to take care of people as they
are the ones impacting the earth and
then
there's fair share that's another ethic
that is kind of the altruistic
element or layer where we when we have
an abundance of something we should
share and give back and then it comes
full circle to whether it's taking care
of people are taking care of the earth
if you have an abundance of crop or time
or knowledge and like this podcast that
you do could be considered giving back
you're sharing your knowledge and other
people's knowledge with your listeners
so there's a lot of ways we can do it or
look at that but that's where I always
start with permaculture because some
people could think of it as like just an
organic gardening method but that's
really just one small well not small
necessarily but it's one piece of it
that we look at whereas everything we do
in life is impacted by our decisions and
if we start with the ethics first then
we can start living in more harmony with
the environment we're in I think that's
really important that we look at it
beyond just a gardening system design
how would you say that people could use
it outside of gardening as an example
like I know you had mentioned
engineering and architecture but how
would a company or someone in their life
incorporate permaculture even if they
weren't a gardener at all well there's a
lot of ways it's kind of endless as far
as like the the ways that we can apply
it but it's it's a design system so
usually when we're designing something
we usually have a problem or a goal that
we're trying to achieve so with a
business for example we could look at
first analyze what we're what we're
doing and what we want to change so say
we have a goal of zero weight which is
one of the permaculture principles
because nature doesn't produce waste
right so how can we live or run our
businesses in a way that we're not
producing a lot of garbage and and we
would analyze first well how much
garbage are we producing and what ways
can we start to eliminate garbage and
this was a lesson like going to the
bullocks I learned like in the first
three-day visit I had with them I
produce a zero waste and even from my
body the waste that I produce went back
to the ecosystem and businesses it's a
little bit more difficult because we use
like shipping plastics and we use things
that maybe aren't biodegradable that we
can compost and so one of the first
steps we can do is look at okay well
what kind of packaging or what are we
using that we could change to be
something that is biodegradable or can
be put back into the earth and there's
because of word like talking about a
fictional business it's hard to give
examples or specifics but that's just
one way to start the process so if we're
talking about growing for example and I
know we'll get more into this but we're
going to want to look at like what kind
of inputs or resources we're bringing
into the systems so say we need a lot of
fertilisers to grow our crop where are
those fertilizers coming from how can we
start to look at producing our own
fertilizers potentially or having
something that produces nutrients and
minerals naturally so that we don't have
to buy them and really it's about
creating sustainability or closed loops
so a truly sustainable system isn't
going to require inputs from outside
that system when I think of landscaping
or gardening and I think the the
ultimate goal is that the landscape
could take care of itself it wouldn't
really require a lot from us whether
it's an irrigation long-term or constant
fertilization we should have the
ecosystem working the way that nature
works naturally because you walk out
into the forest and there's nobody
irrigating the forest
it happens naturally the plants are
adapted to the climate right there's not
people out there weeding and forcing the
plants to do what they want but that's a
human element that we have to start
considering when we are creating our own
habitat or we're creating a product or a
system that is unnatural by ecological
standards ok so let's dive in a little
bit to the gardening aspect of it so
when you step on to a new site or a new
property what are the first things that
you look at in terms of evaluating it
and starting that process
um so there's there's layers the
ecological layers I start with so um the
first thing is the solar budget so how
much Sun is the land getting naturally
how much shade is where so that changes
throughout the year so that's number one
and you can do that pretty easily even
through like image images from satellite
like Google image or Google Earth so
that's actually something I do before I
even get to the property as I look at
the land through satellites I do
research with topo maps with soil Maps
depending on how large the property is
and sometimes you just have to be on the
ground to figure that stuff out but when
I am on the land and I can start looking
at other layers that you can't see
necessarily through the computer like
soil and specifics with soil water
waters huge depending on what climate
we're in we either have way too much or
not enough
oftentimes we have to find that balance
of how do we capture the water on-site
and use it in a way that
it were really taking care of that water
supply and the other layers may be
insects or other organisms that were
needing for habitat we could be looking
at fungal presence we could be looking
at the existing plants and kind of what
shape they're in and all of that is
really reading the landscape but one of
the bigger aspects of my job is making
sure that the human or whoever wanting
to use the land their goals are
realistic with what the land can offer
and
that's that's where my job becomes a
little bit more difficult because I can
look at any landscape and go okay well
this is what the land came landscape can
support but if someone has an idea of
you know they're going to have a high
production you know vegetable farm for
example but yet they bought a piece of
land that has a pretty intact forest
it's like well there's a conflict there
so we have to kind of step back and talk
about the human expectations the needs
of the human and how the land landscape
can support that in a way that remains
ecological rather than you know
clear-cutting and then growing
everything we're removing a big part of
the ecosystem when we're doing that so
my job is every job is different when I
go out to a site every every client is
different and usually a lot of people
when they are looking at permaculture
they want kind of a plug in play
prescriptive responsive like alright
well what can I plant here and what's
the what's the five plants that are
going to do the best and it's like well
I could list off 50 plants but which
ones are you going to use and take care
of and really know how to nurture so
that they can feed you so there's a lot
to look at and it's a pretty I guess
complex way of designing but ultimately
we want to make sure that the ecosystem
is sound and sustainable
once it's established and that the human
is happy because how often do you see a
landscape that's not taken care of and
and people then consider it a burden or
they start to use chemicals or something
that then isn't taking care of the
ecosystem I know that most of
permaculture is focused around growing
food and vegetables how would you
incorporate permaculture concepts into
cannabis cultivation well it depends on
the intention of the people growing the
cannabis so if it's I would look at it
differently if it was commercial like if
people are trying to make money off of
it that's one one way of designing and
then if people are just growing it for
their own personal use and I would treat
those two clients completely different
because if we're looking at making money
we have to have our systems dialed in a
lot more and we have to really maximize
space in a way that the room for error
is less but we always got to start
somewhere and depending on that person's
experience they may come to the table
with a lot of knowledge with how to do
it synthetically but with permaculture
we really want to shift everything to
organic I mean that would be the the
best way and from my personal
perspective or opinion is you know not
to use chemicals to grow medicine so
soil fertility is a big aspect of that
you know a plant that in takes a lot of
nutrients and minerals we have to really
figure out where those replacement
minerals and nutrients are going to come
from and to do that sustainably and
using products that aren't imported from
you know halfway across the world
another thing to look at with cannabis
or any crop really is water use that's a
huge aspect of making sure that our
water needs are taken care of and we're
not wasteful with water but if we can
capture it from the sky that's truly
sustainable and there's a lot to
consider with design though and that in
that system alone and energy use so
again with cannabis there's this
spectrum of growers right we've got
people who are doing it inside people
who are doing it outside and if we're
doing it inside then we're using a lot
of electricity some of the growers that
I've visited that's one of their biggest
expenses so how can we start to look at
different ways of producing energy or
getting off-grid like is solar an option
can we do things to raise temperatures
or to have light be something that we
can adjust a little bit easier there's
there's all kinds of things to look at
but if we're going outside of course
we're going to have less control of the
environment but that also has more
opportunity to bring in insects to
create more ecosystem and habitat so
that the plants can then be supported by
other plants
the one of the concepts we can use
outdoors is companion planting we can
actually invite insects that are
predators to the pests and use those as
allies to the crop so that's kind of
another fun thing to play with and it
works really well in vegetable gardens I
think of cannabis kind of like tomatoes
like they're not super easy to grow
they're little finicky if they're not in
the perfect conditions and
you know there's pests there's there's
issues that plants can have and so how
can we look at nature as a resource to
take care of those potential issues or
prevent them from happening potentially
in the first place so just to give some
concrete examples of some of the things
you talked about now for example if you
were a if you're growing five plants for
your own medical garden or your own your
own use you may be able to add a rain
barrel off of your garden shed for
example as a way to collect enough water
for that garden or for our property we
have an 85 foot by 30 foot greenhouse
that we added gutters to so we're able
to collect a massive amount of water
that comes off of those into giant IBC
totes that we can then use to water the
garden so water catchment is definitely
something you can look at there you
talked about
insects as another as another thing
through pollinator plants so you're
looking at planting not just a mono crop
of cannabis or whatever cash crop you're
growing but incorporating in other
plants that may either offer the ability
to accumulate minerals and nutrients out
of the soil like my comfrey or borage
but also things that are going to
attract good beneficial insects do you
have any particular plants that you like
as just general pollinator plants
well there's entire families of
plants that are are known to attract
specific predator insects anything like
in the carrot family so fennel is a good
one or or carrots if you want to let
them go to seed but of course there's a
lot of like little details to think
about if you're trying to grow these
things to produce more than that yarrow
is one of my favorite insect plants
there's really a bunch of them and a lot
of it may depend on climate or exposure
like if say you have rows of crops
around the outside or the perimeter
maybe like along the fence for example
you can have a pollinator mix and
there's seed companies that are now
starting to make these a lot of them are
really they grow in abundance like
calendula for example you can just plant
a few of them and every year you're
going to have more and more because they
germinate so easily from their own seeds
but there's there's a lot of them maybe
it's you know to target a very specific
pests that someone struggling with but I
look at the more diversity the better
because the more insects you have the
less predator or pest populations you're
going to have because when there's a you
know just one type of pest and not a
predator there's going to be population
growth and so the more insects you can
bring in to kind of stabilize that or
you know eat those insects take care of
it the better and sometimes you don't
know like one year you might have a
problem with one thing and the next year
you might have a problem with another
thing so it's important to have as many
plants as possible in my own opinion
that's where I've seen the most success
versus just one type but there's lots of
seed mixes and some do better in some
climates than others so it's hard to
give specifics not knowing the land also
so I try to stay away from that but I
can say calendula yarrow there those are
two of my favorites fennel attracts a
lot but there's there's a ton basically
anything that attracts insects is
probably good and a lot of them are our
flowers that are beautiful so not only
are you getting I'm help with with pests
but you're getting beauty at the same
time yeah and I do just want to caution
listeners that when you do add a
pollinator mix which we've done in our
greenhouse multiple years you you are
creating a little bit more work for
yourself in that these plants also need
to be maintained so as they they die you
may increase a presence of fungal spores
or powdery mildew though not all mildews
are I guess prevalent across all species
of plants so just because there's mildew
say on your comfrey doesn't mean that it
can transfer to your cannabis plant but
the potential is there and so what I
find is depending on the pollinator mix
that I've used in the past will really
determine how much extra labor I have in
terms of maintaining not just that but
my actual crop that I'm growing so it's
just something to be aware of and then
some of these like you mentioned self so
and so you have to be ready for that and
be aware that certain ones you may want
to get before they seed something like
borage for example you'll have hundreds
of borage plants popping up but they're
super easy to pick out of the ground so
it's not a huge big deal but something
to be aware of when your companion
planting I like to run our stuff
sometimes a little further away from our
actual crop but in the same area so one
of the things you worked with us on was
putting comfrey around our vegetable of
our vegetable beds that we do are you
pick out of and that allows us to
create a weed barrier it's for those
weed seeds because those leaves are so
large I know a Bullock's farm they've
used different squashes as a way of
doing that and then we can cut down a
couple times a year that comfrey and
apply it throughout our garden as a
natural mulch that's going to provide
more nutrients it's going to keep down
extra weeds it has a ton of benefits
mm-hmm it's one of the super plants it
has a it basically hits every ecological
mark that you would want from a plant
pollinator medicinal it's a great
medicinal it's a great root barrier
green manure it's got a lot of calcium
and it's leaves so it's got a lot of
really great benefits yeah yeah though
we're still fighting it where people
transplanted into the middle of the
garden and that's been a real challenge
yes to remove but we already talked
about that on previous podcasts so great
so in terms of
permaculture and some of the science
aspect one of the listeners was asking
about that can you talk a little bit
about what sort of science may may or
may not support these permaculture
principles well it's funny because I
come from a scientific or academic
background and I
got into permaculture because I I felt
that it was common sense and saw results
with it but didn't need science to
validate it for me science is expensive
and not a lot of people in permaculture
are necessarily doing a lot of science
there is some out there but it's it's
one of those things that just like
herbal medicine people have been doing
these things for a lot of years in fact
a lot of permaculture principles come
from indigenous cultures like that took
care of the land long before the
Industrial Revolution and when living
locally was really the only way to do it
and there wasn't science back there back
that at that time telling people what to
do they just did what they had learned
and observed over time and I one of the
examples I like to use and actually it
relates to you and how I met you when
when I was maybe like what 12 years ago
now when compost tea was something that
in the industry was kind of looked down
upon because there wasn't enough
peer-reviewed science and I went to a
conference actually where your dad spoke
and
learned about compost tea and I was a
little bit skeptical because of course
I'm reading the trade magazines where
it's like oh there's not science behind
this and it's snake oil whatever and my
partner at the time wanted to experiment
with it and so got a brewer and we got
started and the results spoke for
themselves I didn't need science at that
point I was like wow why isn't everybody
doing this and it makes so much sense to
me and of course there's a lot more out
there now about that specific topic but
science hasn't always been around but
we've been around for a really long time
and the way that we've interacted with
the landscape and with plants has been
like a something that's been passed down
orally so the book that I just finished
writing one of my tasks was to look at
plants and how they were used you know
five six thousand years ago and how that
that knowledge was carried down over the
years but it's just now like literally
in the past hundred years becoming
validated by science it's like do you do
we really need it or can we learn for
ourselves and I it's a hard it's a hard
balance especially in this world because
with something like nature you can't
reproduce
an ecosystem indoors or in a laboratory
so it's hard but one of the questions
that comes up a lot that I can speak
about like dynamic accumulation and I
know this is something that people asked
well where's the science behind and it's
it's pretty soft science there's not a
lot out there because not a lot of
people are looking into it a lot of the
science is going towards synthetics and
it's going towards GMOs and it's going
towards really altering plants not
necessarily investigating the ones that
we could use easily so dynamic
accumulation for anyone who doesn't know
the concept is pretty simple
in that plants use their roots they
mined into the soil they absorb
nutrients and minerals and then store
them in their tissues right so we know
this happens with plants because you
know we eat plants and therefore we eat
the minerals and nutrients like bananas
you know have potassium for example one
of the things that we just talked about
comfrey is known for its ability to
accumulate calcium which is kind of an
unusual thing and we're taught you know
we're supposed to get calcium from milk
but we it's there in that plant in a way
that it's it's so concentrated that it's
been used for 5000 years as a healer of
bones so the science is is there it's
just not necessarily wrapped in a
permaculture package of like here here's
what permaculture can offer you it's and
it's again it's not prescriptive so
every single site and every single human
and their needs are going to be
different and so there's not really a
way to replicate that in a lab and look
at it and try to figure out success
because you know we could set up or
design an amazing
sustainable system for someone to be
completely self-sufficient and all it
takes is a human error or maybe you know
a fencing error for an entire crop to be
wiped out so you know we're not we're
kind of at the hands of nature to some
degree but also our own our own
experience and if we if we look at
permaculture as only something you know
that will accept if area of science is
behind it we've got a ways to wait
because um you know I don't know anybody
who's putting their money towards that
right now they're experimenting with
their land and they're trying to
practice these things in real time and
when I was traveling to research for the
permaculture book that was one of my
tasks which was super fun and I got to
go all over the country and meet people
who were practicing permaculture and one
of my questions is you know like what
failures have you seen and
everyone has experienced failures in
gardening like that's one of the things
that we learn from and it's different
for every single person and that may be
just their expectations of what a
success successful crop may be but
there's not a lot of hard science out
there to support these concepts unless
you look at it purely from an ecological
standpoint but human expectations are
kind of what gets in the way of you know
what is successful what's working what's
not and again there's a lot of error
that can happen because of our choices
so yeah you touched on a lot things
there that I want to kind of review so
in terms of going all the way back to
dynamic accumulators one thing I want to
point out for people that I think is a
challenge as well is if that company for
example is planted in soil that is low
in calcium that leaf tissue is not going
to magically accumulate high levels of
calcium if it's not available in the
soil so you see these I see these lists
online all the time of various plants
and then the amount of nutrients that
they're supposedly going to be imparting
same with or when they're used as
fertilizers and I think those lists can
be really misleading for growers because
you don't know that there's going to be
10% calcium and that leave tissue just
because just because you don't know the
quality in which or the way in which
that crop was grown and you can see a
huge variance in any farmer will tell
you that their crops can vary quite a
bit just based on the soil conditions
that they're growing on and then yeah in
terms of permaculture and the science
aspect you mentioned how we met I know
when I first met you I was very
skeptical of the term permaculture
because basically everyone I had met up
to that point before meeting you and
Dave really came across really a little
bit arrogant to me in terms of oh you're
not doing permaculture you don't know
about permaculture
and when you came out to our property
and looked at our farm you kind of
shocked me I don't remember this but you
we started walking around and you're
like tad this is a permaculture concept
right here you're already doing some of
these things and
for me like the stuff that you were
pointing out like you said was very it's
some of what permaculture is is very
common sense and to me that's one thing
that separates it from people that are
into you know bio dynamics for example
or
the energies associated around water
these things that have not been proven
and there's not a lot of science behind
the thing about permaculture is a lot of
these concepts are design concepts
they're common-sense concepts and
ultimately the the main purpose of them
is really to take care of the earth and
to take care of the the property that
we're growing on and
for that to happen I think it doesn't
have to be as science focused but that
doesn't mean we can't apply science to
it like you mentioned compost tea well I
know a lot of these protocols of people
are using compost teas well that doesn't
mean they couldn't use the available
body of knowledge that's already out
there around that science and apply it
towards the way that they're making the
compost tea so we can take aspects of
science and apply it to aspects of
permaculture it's not that permaculture
is necessarily anti science it's just
that not everything that is happening is
happening because of science it's
happening because of like you mentioned
the ethics around these principles are
number one yeah and I think it's really
important also to say that in order to
practice permaculture it's really
helpful to have science as a foundation
in understanding the ecological systems
like understanding soil science that's
critical in being able to manage soil
fertility and to grow crops and you know
the the hydrology of a site that's
really important to look at as well and
there's there's a lot of science that is
important to know in just beginning but
I I like people to just experiment and
to try of course it's different when
you're trying to make money from systems
but in a home environment there's
definitely steps that you can take to
just get started and
one thing that I experience a lot or see
people have is analysis paralysis where
they won't move forward until they have
all the answers they're seeking and you
can waste a lot of time and your own
learning in trying to you know find
someone else's answers but it it all
starts with soil it starts with the
science it starts with understanding
those basic ecological systems yeah you
know I hope people will look into
permaculture hopefully this talk will
encourage people to consider it and I
think your book is a great resource for
people looking for an introduction let's
take a commercial facility that's
already growing and it could be an
indoor one or a greenhouse one and my
hope is that well rather than like you
mentioned getting paralyzed by trying to
get to zero waste for example which is a
really really tough goal how about
instead let's do let's source one
amendment or one fertilizer source
closer to home or let's try to reduce
the amount of packaging that we're using
or let's do something to make it easier
for our employees to have a better work
environment so these are very basic
things that any any facility could do
that would help improve and incorporate
you know the most basic and permaculture
principles into their into their
cultivation yeah and one of the
principles of permaculture is to start
small we can't go from living in
mainstream culture to completely
sustainable overnight it takes time and
it really takes looking at the systems
that you can change easily for the
biggest impact and starting there
instead of you know investing a lot in a
big huge change that you you don't have
experience with it's definitely good to
just take baby steps on that on the
other side of that if you haven't
designed your property yet and you're
starting from scratch this is a great
tool for beginning that process to get
you thinking about
all your resources on that property and
how you want to design the property to
best maximize workflow and what is
available based on where you're located
so I I really encourage people one thing
I find you know having a farm in a
garden center is that people will walk
in and buy one apple tree and then
they'll plant it then they'll come back
two weeks later and buy a walnut tree
for example and then over the period of
five years you go to their property and
they have all these things haphazardly
scattered around the landscape and
they're like this doesn't look like a
landscape anymore whereas if they had
invested you know a little more thought
at the very beginning of the process
they could have really designed
something that made a lot more sense
that they were happier with
aesthetically putting in that time I
think early on in your
in your business or in your property is
is huge yeah and that's really what
permaculture is it's it's it's the
process of design the steps you take to
make those decisions the things that you
look at and I essentially that's my job
is to help people do that so of course
I'm a biased but all in favor of people
taking the time and the money even if
it's you know a 300 dollar consultation
that could save you
$100,000 in mistakes so it's it's well
worth the time in gaining especially
someone else's perspective who's been
doing it a long time and that another
thing about that like it whether it's
cannabis or another crop or home
gardening one of the best ways to learn
is through someone who's already doing
it in your bio region because the
climate is going to be similar the goals
are going to be similar and just having
conversations with people who are
already doing it is a great way to learn
and avoid certain mistakes before
beforehand yeah I do a little bit of
consulting here and there and one of the
things that people ask me is what cover
crops should they be growing for example
on their field through the winter and I
always say go go talk to your
neighboring farmers find out what
they've already learned that works
really well you know in your in your
environment or in your region so there's
a lot of resources out there getting to
know your neighbors is is a big one for
sure definitely what was anything else
you wanted to cover regarding
permaculture or do you want to talk a
little bit more about what you're up to
these days or it's up to you Ted I'm
I'm happy to talk about whatever I think
just just because you mentioned cover
crops that's one more thing that can be
added to
outdoor cannabis growing is you know
plants that add nitrogen back into the
soil and I'm not sure if you've talked
about that on other podcasts or not but
I'm looking at legumes and nitrogen
fixers as ground covers even is
something that I would I would consider
trying out yeah well let's uh we have
talked a little bit about that but let's
give the listeners a little a little
background into what you have going on
and what your next book is about before
we sign off for the episode okay um well
my next book so I've written
the chicken free-range chicken gardens
which was really about creating habitat
for them in an ecological or
permaculture way as they can be great
allies to us and then the practical
permaculture book was was really
intended to be an introductory design
manual and my latest book is called
creating sanctuary and that book was it
took it to more of a personal level of
well how can we create spaces for us to
be rejuvenated to have our needs met and
it kind of goes into the that second
ethic I talked about of caring for
people and starting with ourselves but
looking at plants as allies and their
sacred powers is what I think we ended
up calling it in the book both from a
historical perspective but also a
medicinal and energetic standpoint so
looking across the globe at how people
have used plants throughout the ages as
healers and it was a really fun but
challenging book to write and I was
really looking for those matches of you
know the the plants that had ancient
uses and the science behind those being
validated now so that was really fun and
it incorporates a lot of
energetics and there's a chapter on
creating sacred space for yourselves so
it gets it gets into the spiritual realm
of really taking care of yourself at a
soul level and how plants can help you
with that so yeah I'm really excited
about it'll come out this fall and
and it's it's all wrapped up but got a
weight for design and printing so I'm
excited yeah I'm looking forward to that
one I happen to haven't read it yet but
really excited for you and thanks again
for taking the time to do this show
today thanks for having me
that was Jesse Blum owner of NW bloom
and co-author a practical permaculture
design her books are available through
our website if you want to support small
business or major booksellers like
amazon.com you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host Todd Hussey don't forget
that there's more information and
articles available on our website and
blog at
a is organics calm as well as links to
the data and information we discussed in
this episode on the podcast page and if
you enjoy these podcasts please take a
moment to leave me a rating a review on
iTunes and send me your feedback and
suggestions through our website contact
page for tad at kis organics comm that's
t ad @ k is organics calm thanks for
listening
[Music]