[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're catching this episode near the
time of release I wanted to mention two
upcoming events that I'm excited about
first I will be speaking in the cannabis
breakout sessions at bio controls USA
conference in Portland Oregon March 4th
through 6th along with Suzanne
Wainwright Evans and Justin McGill two
of my former guests on the podcast and
good friends of mine you can sign up on
the website at www.clemson.edu/peach
Ecch it out at cultivation classic dot
CC my guest this week is Paul Coxon Paul
has been working with plants since 2008
his love for plants was a lifelong
passion that developed and grew through
the Nebraska Master Gardener program and
through his involvement with human nurse
nursery Paul received his Bachelors of
Science from NC State during which time
he published five journal articles
received the International Society for
horticultural society for horticultural
science young minds award say that ten
times fast published over 20 extension
and outreach publications and published
three ebooks Paul has a passion for
scientific investigation with the end
goal of providing growers and producers
with applicable and impactful production
knowledge and practices Paul is
currently pursuing his master's of
science and horticulture at NC State
under the direction of dr. Brian he whip
ker hey Paul thanks for coming on the
show today hey thanks for having me I
really appreciate this
yeah let's go ahead and start off giving
listeners a little bit of your
background and how you came into this
role that you have at the university
yeah for sure so I have always been
interested in plants ever since I was a
kid they were a passion of mine and that
passion just kind of grew and evolved
over my life I was involved in the
Master Gardener program went to numerous
extension events and just through kind
of a roundabout way ended up at North
Carolina State University and I actually
got my bachelor's here and it started
working with plants under dr. Brian whip
Kerr doing floriculture work with him
and continued working with him through
my bachelors
and the opportunity came for me to sign
on with the Masters for him and I'm
currently you're into that and it's been
one wild ride and never expected to be
doing work with cannabis but here we are
yeah you told me a little bit about that
off air how you guys applied for a
license and we're able to get one and
have started doing some research with
cannabis or more specifically hemp do
you want to talk a little about some of
the papers that you there's some of the
research that's happened at your
university yeah sure so yeah it's the
way that we got involved in cannabis
it's kind of a roundabout story dr.
Witter and I were just kind of talking
one day in the greenhouse just you know
shooting the breeze and I joked with him
and said you know hey let's you know
work in him because hemp had just become
legalized in our state you know he kind
of laughed at it and then two months
later he contacted me is like hey I've
just applied for a license we're gonna
be doing work with him and you know ever
since then it's been just one crazy
research project after another and it's
opened a lot of amazing doors for us so
we're really glad that we got into it
but as far as some of the work that
we've done we got into cannabis and you
know normally when you are looking at
researching a new area you know you jump
on
and you'll do a literature review and
look at you know published literature
and you know I got on and jumped on
Google Scholar and typed in either
cannabis sativa and I think I used the
all in title function and I got 12
results and it was then that I knew that
we were in for one wild ride so we
basically had to start at the foundation
as far as research goes because you know
we wanted to establish some baselines
for nutrients for lighting for growing
pH work etc so that's that's kind of how
we got started I can go more into the
specific projects that we've done if
you'd like yeah let's do it why don't
you tell us about your first foray into
indie cannabis research and just for
listeners to let them know I do have one
of your papers in front of me the
characterization of nutrient disorders
of cannabis sativa so we'll probably
spend a little more time on that I'm
gonna be kind of flying blind on
questions is I don't have the access to
the other papers at this time but yeah
if you want to kind of describe some of
the research that you've done and what
some of your findings we're I'd love to
kind of go through that in a little more
detail
yeah for sure um so one of the first
things that we did was look starting
from the ground up basically or the soil
up the two first projects that we
started doing we were looking at optimal
rooting through clonal cuttings because
we realized quickly that sourcing
through seed was just not the way to go
so we started cloning propagating
everything but we were experiencing a
huge variety of rooting habits and
successes when trying to clone root
cannabis clonally and in the flora
culture industry we've had a long time
to kind of standardize things so that
variability that we're seeing really
intrigued us so one of the first two
studies we did we did a reading study
and that has been published
we looked at these a bottom heat and
also the diameter of the cutting the
caliper looking at how those two factors
would impact routing vigor and routing
success and then the next piece of work
that we did was looking at optimal
substrate PHS and that was in tandem
with another lab here at NC State doing
work there the substrates lab so those
were the kind of the foundation that we
did and then from there we kind of went
into the nutrient deficiency work that
you have in front of you trying to
characterize nutrients and nutrient
deficiencies and then we've also had
another study published where we went
into lighting and photo period a bit
we're looking at daylight extension
lighting regimes versus nine
interruption of lighting regimes and I
guess I should back up the very first
study that we did was a baseline hemp
nutrients leaf tissue survey because we
had no idea what optimal nutrients were
so we traveled around the state to
different growers operations and we took
samples off of their plants and sent
them into the lab here in CDA and got
some values back and established the
baseline and that work has also been
published well I kind of want to talk
about the findings from each of these
because I think they're all really
interesting but let's start with what
you were just describing they're
incurred of just surveying and
establishing sort of ranges for cannabis
using tissue tissue analysis what can
you talk about the sort of the
methodology of that and that process and
how you determined what a healthy plant
look like in terms of those ranges yes
so this was kind of the dirty mucky
science that very few scientists will
actually want to reveal it's very
foundational work most of the time when
you're dealing with a new crop or a new
discovered crop it's kind of
shotgun approach so one of the reasons
that we went through multiple different
locations to try and find healthy plants
is because you know fertilizer types
were different and growing conditions
were different and you know the kind of
you know management strategies were
different the irrigation was different
and that that introduced a lot of
variability so we were trying to
homogenize the landscape by taking a
general survey and that is not to be
used as kind of like the golden rule of
you know this is what adequate leaf
tissue parts per million
looks like the survey was just meant to
be more of an informational guideline to
growers saying that you know these
plants which appeared healthy and were
growing vigorously had adequate nutrient
ranges and from what we can infer from
other crops they appear to be within the
healthy range and that work that kind of
springboarded into the nutrient
disorders work which is getting closer
to establishing fertility guidelines for
cannabis got it so what you're
essentially what you're saying is you
don't want people to draw too many
conclusions from your preliminary work
there or that paper other than to see
that there may be a possible range here
of a tissue of elements in the tissue
that maybe allow you to grow what
appears to be a healthy plant correct
yeah so science is a very additive
process and the more and more
experiments you do in a specific
research direction or research question
they begin to add together to form the
whole picture and from that then you can
start inferring and making guidelines so
we're getting close with some of the
work that we've done but it's like like
I said cannabis is still very new for
research and so we're still just you
know beginning to green gained traction
with the research I think that's a
really good point that you're making
there so that people will consider how
you know
this may point them in in sort of a
direction of a trend but there's still
so much research than needs to be done I
mean if you were talking about a you
know an established crop like corn you'd
find thousands of papers just on
nitrogen that could discuss this and a
lot of tissue work that's been done
across a variety of different scenarios
and environments to where you you can
start really drawing strong correlations
but we just don't have any of that work
so it's it's still very preliminary like
you'd like you mentioned exactly yes I
did want to you mention propagation I
did have Dr Kaplan Darren Kaplan on from
the Guelph he did work with dr. Zhang on
propagation already now I don't know did
your work come before or after their
paper which was released in I think May
of 2018 and is there any correlation
there or any anything that you found
that sort of fit or didn't fit with the
work that they did yes
so Kathleen's work came before ours ours
was just published at the end of I
believe it was 2018 is when ours came
out so his work came before ours and as
far as the the correlations between the
two works there were some similarities
but for the most part we were also
exploring slightly different things you
know for example he used rooting
hormones and he his work and we did not
look at rooting hormones we were looking
more at the caliper and bottom heat so
when you say caliper just for people who
may not be familiar with the term you're
talking about the measurement of the
diameter of the stem and when you say
sorry so you were measuring you're
measuring the caliper in terms of the
routing success of that particular
cutting is that correct yeah so
basically when floriculture
when you're trying to establish a more
vigorous cutting
a vegetative cutting you'll apply heat
to the bottom of the tray or bottom of
the bench or close to the bottom and
that increases the temperature of the
substrate and what that does is it helps
speed up the routing across us in some
species in others that will have little
to no effect so we were trying to
explore that and then the other area
that we were exploring is the caliper
which when you take a tip cutting from
another stock plant and you kind of take
the tip portion and you point it away
from yourself and you look at the end
that you cut it and then you were to
measure the diameter of that that would
be the caliper and the theory was that a
thicker caliper could potentially have
more surface area for the callus to
increase route proliferation and a
thicker caliper could also potentially
have more reserves so more photosynthate
etc that the plant could draw on to help
with the healing and reading process was
kind of the line of thinking that we
went down and did your research support
your hypothesis yes so what we found
that was that we divided calipers into 3
differents sizes small medium and large
as far as the caliper was concerned and
we did find that there was a
statistically significant difference in
routing between the the small caliper
and the large caliper but not between
the small in the medium or the meteor in
the large caliper and so what that means
is that when we actually looked at the
date of routing the bigger routing and
we actually then screened the routing
through a visual scale that the larger
caliper produced more vigorous roots
rather than when compared to the small
caliper and when you say large I assume
you're still talking about fairly
immature vegetative plants I do know
that cannabis can develop a woody or
stem over time which can it appears to
inhibit cloning or
propagation I can you talk a little bit
about your how you established your
experiment and what what you really were
comparing there yeah so to answer your
question how we kind of went along the
lines of exploring how to quantify the
size of the cutting or the caliper we
actually went in to mother stock plants
we took some other stock plants and we
took vegetative kind of things off of
those and the paper goes into a little
more detail on how we quantified that I
won't bore you with the details here but
we divided all of the cuttings kind of
did a survey and looked at the different
calipers and the different caliper pools
and from that we came up with the sizes
that we used for our study and the small
size was 1.7 to 2 millimeters medium
size was two point three to two point
six millimeters and the large caliper
was two point nine to three point two
millimeters and so that's that's kind of
the general process of how we approached
categorizing
what a typical caliper would be on an
arm other stock plants that we were
managing and then how we divided them up
through the study
now did you look at where on the plant
itself that the cutting was taken from
in terms of from near the top of the
plants near the base of the plant
was that something that was factored in
it all in this particular study yeah so
we only took from secondary tertiary and
quaternary branches and basically what
that means is you have the central stalk
from which all the other branches come
off so that's considered the primary and
so any branch that comes off of that
would be secondary any consecutive
branch that comes off of that would be
tertiary so on and so forth and like I
said the paper which is freely available
through Murray State University the
Journal of agriculture agricultural hemp
research
has a wonderful diagram in there on how
we actually took the cuttings and
quantified the branches but as far as
looking at say an interior canopy
cutting versus an exterior canopy
cutting we were only taking shoot tips
from the exterior portion of the canopy
and what I mean by a shoot tip is only
the terminal growing portion of a
cutting so it terminated in a growing
tip that makes sense yeah so you weren't
you weren't taking more than one cutting
off of that that branch so in theory you
could go down another few inches and
take another cutting but you didn't do
that for this experiment okay I get were
saying were there any other findings
from this particular study that you
wanted to share besides what you just
shared regarding caliper larger caliper
reading better than smaller caliper yes
so like I said that there was a
statistically significant difference
between the small caliper and the large
caliper and as far as the percentage of
cuttings that had rooted at 14 days
versus 28 days there was a statistical
difference in this study between adding
root zone heating or bottom heating
versus not utilizing about a bottom
heating so that was another interesting
question interesting finding from the
study rather what was your control
temperature and then what did you raise
it to with the the root zone - with the
bottom heating and how statistically
significant are we talking across adding
that heat matter heat source yeah so the
what we did is we measured the substrate
temperature so the substrate temperature
was twenty seven point eight degrees
centigrade without root zone heating and
then it was sorry that was with root
zone heating and the average temperature
was 25
six degrees centigrade without so we
increased the root zone temperature by
roughly two degrees centigrade okay just
to save all of us Americans who are
terrible at Celsius I'm gonna do this
calculation for people so twenty eight
point seven Celsius is eighty three
point six six degrees Fahrenheit that
was your heated temperature what was
your sorry what was the control again
yes
sorry that's twenty seven point eight
degrees centigrade for the treatment
oh okay so the treatment was twenty
seven points so 82 degrees Fahrenheit
correct and then for the control it was
twenty five point six degrees centigrade
or 78 degrees Fahrenheit okay so not a
dramatic rise in temperature but you
still found statistically significant
statistically significant better routing
correct that's actually surprising to me
that I would just that few of a degrees
could raise your rooting success that
that much that's really interesting yeah
so when when doing a study like this you
don't want to raise the temperature the
root zone temperature too much because
you don't want to potentially desiccate
or damage any roots that are forming or
even the catalyst as it forms so that's
why the temperature differential wasn't
overly large yeah I would have thought
that maybe the control temperature might
have been lower rather than the heated
temperature be higher but no that's
great yeah we this experiment was
conducted during the summer so we were
in a poly house and the cooling
coefficient on a poly house is much less
so that's why the temperatures were a
little higher for the control that makes
sense that makes sense okay great so
let's move on to another one of the
papers that you mentioned prior to you
know prior to talking about this
nutrient disordered paper okay are used
the substrate pH work the other one that
we did kind of on that ground-up
approach we're still in the process of
publishing on paper so that one has
happened at least yet those results will
be forthcoming okay I understand so
maybe we do dive right into the nutrient
nutrient disorder paper that you wrote
or co-authored okay now one of the
things you talked about with this paper
was that you guys really are a team
there at the university is there any
anything you want to mention prior to
starting talking about or did you want
to kind of as we go through the paper
mention the people that were involved in
different aspects of this work yeah
that'd be great
yeah so in our lab we have been really
blessed to have a group of fantastic
researchers and collaborators that we've
worked with on all of these projects
both the projects that we have completed
have published and are doing so yeah
Gaby Barajas Patrick needs the David
Logan Matthew Davis
Kimberly McAllister our collaborator dr.
Michelle Schroeder Moreno our other
collaborator dr. Brian Jackson and my
major professor dr. Brian Becker we all
form a fantastic team of collaborators
some of these people have been involved
on all the projects others are
collaborators on some projects but
research definitely does not take place
in a vacuum and as far as the research
process goes we've been really blessed I
have some amazing collaborators and
people in our lab that's great I mean it
really does take a team and I think it's
important to recognize that when you see
a name on a paper that's not the full
story of the work that went into it so
thanks for highlighting that now this
paper itself
it's called characterization of nutrient
disorders of cannabis sativa it was
brought to my attention recently I mean
it's only was published in October 18th
of 2009
tene do you want to give a quick
highlight or sort of a rough idea of
what the abstract was with this paper
and what your goals were when you first
started doing this research yeah so like
I said the first paper that we published
was that general survey paper and that
one is published and that's meant to be
kind of a shotgun approach to guidelines
you know these were the ranges we saw in
multiple different cultivars across
different growing conditions this one is
trying to be a little more targeted and
kind of narrow in on optimal fertility
recommendations for him and trying to
figure out what kind of fertility
cannabis plants need in order to balance
the nutrient cost input to growers and
maximize the you know CBD content and
flower content depending on what you're
growing for so for this specific work we
were looking at nutrient deficiencies so
what that means is we were trying to
stress the plants down to a level where
we could visually see symptoms of
nutrient stress and then we could take
foliar leaf tissue and send that off to
lab and compare that to plants that we
grew with a complete fertility machine
and that complete fertility regime is
based off of what's called a modified
Hoagland solution it's a standard
hydroponic water-soluble nutrient
fertilizer regime that basically
balances all of the cations and anions
and is supposed to provide a plant with
everything that it needs as far as its
macro and micronutrients are concerned
so we were trying to withhold an element
from a plant from that recipe to induce
our deficiency and they compared those
visual symptoms and the leaf tissue
analyses back to that plant and that
plant that received everything was our
control now are there is there research
out there
showing and success and growing with
this Hoagland solution or a formula with
cannabis or were you kind of going into
a little bit of new territory with that
in terms of is making pulling from other
crops yeah so dr. wicker myself
numerous other scientists have used the
solution to provide fertility for a wide
array of plants so as far as specific to
cannabis no we were the first to kind of
pioneer a Hoagland solution with
cannabis but as far as the general
literature is concerned it has been
tested on numerous different plants
numerous different crops and proved to
be adequate okay so and just out of
curiosity
so as you started growing with this
toquyen solution is this baseline for
fertility just anecdotally you found
that it seemed to be providing
appropriate nutrient levels across the
board for macro and micro nutrients for
for cannabis correct yes and so kind of
how the research logic goes is we took a
broad survey approach that was our first
paper and then we kind of wanted to see
what would happen if we took away a
singular nutrient from the plant and
what that would do to the leaf tissue
value is compared to the survey that we
had and what that would do to the you
know control plant that was receiving
adequate fertility that has been proven
to the adequate for multiple different
crop species and then currently what
we're doing and I know we're getting off
track a bit but currently we are then
modifying the Hoagland solution the
solution for all macro and
micronutrients at different rates to try
and get a fully relief tissue curve if
that makes sense so from you know say
like zero parts per million into 2.5 so
on and so forth to try and establish a
curve for fertility as far
as fullier analyses are concerned okay
yeah that makes sense yeah I was just I
was just kind of curious where you came
up with this for you know a baseline for
your control because I think that's
important for people to understand when
you start talking about what you're
removing it's good to know where you
were starting that's all okay I want to
get into a little bit of the methodology
here but just I had a couple things in
the introduction that you guys mentioned
in terms of relating back to prior work
that had been done that I thought was
kind of interesting and I didn't know
maybe it's something you can touch on
maybe it's just something that pretty
much the sentences that you put in there
say at all but I kind of wanted to bring
him bring him out in hemp fiber in hemp
fiber varieties Bosca itaú reported
higher levels of nitrogen increased
plant leaf weight and decreased leaf THC
content presumably due to THC dilution
can you touch on that at all yeah so
that work in particular like I said once
when I actually went into this and was
doing a literature review and trying to
get a good feel for the kind of research
that had been done there was not much
out there so this introduction is quite
bare-bones when it comes to a normal
introduction and literature review but
essentially what we're trying to say
there I think what the article was
trying to get out is first I would like
to draw your attention to the fact that
this is a fiber variety so we were
growing a high CBD clone so the growth
habit and growth parameters are
different for fiber varieties you want
them to be very tall you're trying to
get you know plant them very densely
they're in a field condition typically
in the CBD variety is that we were
growing you know you want those big
beautiful flowers they're more compact
they were grown in a greenhouse but
essentially what we're what we're trying
to get at here is to draw on previous
work showing that nitrogen increased the
total production of leaf biomass and
that's important when looking at least
analyses you know because you're
comparing how much nitrogen is in that
leaf it's a larger leaf you know you can
potentially have a dilution effect and
also that increased plant size could
have resulted in a THC dilution effect
so if you have a larger bud but the same
amount of THC in it because most things
are calculated off of a percentage dry
weight you can have an artificially low
dilution effect however I am unsure I
can't recall off the top of my head
which methodology I actually used to
test THC in this study whether it was a
percentage dry weight or a percentage
concentration so on and so forth that
could be really interesting for people
in growing hemp that are looking to stay
below a given THC percentage in order to
have a legal crop I'd be curious to see
more research coming out on that around
nitrogen levels yeah I would - any
research at this point is just gonna
help that additive scientific effect so
that we can get a clearer picture for
what's going on ok so one thing one
other thing I want to ask you about was
at the end your introduction you
mentioned that no visual guides of
nutrient deficiency in cannabis
supported with leaf tissue analysis and
documenting a progression of symptoms
have been published so essentially what
you're saying there is when I go online
on Google Images and type in you know
nitrogen deficiency cannabis or whatever
a particular element I'm looking for
there's no research that's been
published that actually correlates that
with a tissue test the leaf tissue
analysis to show that that truly is the
deficiency is that correct along with
symptom ology so different stages
correct as far as I know and have seen
and was able to tease out in the work
that I did there have been some leaf
tissue analyses reported I believe the
plant analysis handbook has some tissue
values for cannabis sativa but as far as
correlating those visual symptoms with
an actual
leaf tissue test and what I mean by
actually correlating I don't mean just
providing low fertility when we withheld
nitrogen from the plant the plant
received no nitrogen of any form so we
can say with relative certainty that the
symptom ology that we saw based on the
leaf tissue analysis is truly nitrogen
deficiency because the plant received
absolutely no nitrogen fertility let's
dive right into nitrogen I'm not going
to get into too much into your
methodology it's all there in the paper
people want to read it it's it seems
fairly straightforward to me let's just
talk about what your findings were
related in nitrogen so traditionally
when you think of nitrogen deficiencies
you think of a yellowing on the lower
leaves the plants putting more energy
into its upper leaves lighter greening
overall of the plants what I mean you
have some actual photos here so people
can see initial intermediate and
advanced stages of nitrogen deficiencies
but can you talk all about about those
findings relating in nitrogen yeah so
exploring nutrient deficiencies is kind
of a fun I guess you could call it a bit
of a puzzle certain elements within
plants are mobile and what that means is
the plant has the ability to remove
those from certain tissues and portions
and translocate them to other portions
of the plant so for example nitrogen is
Noble
so what that means is when the plant is
nitrogen stressed it will draw nitrogen
from those lower leaves which is why we
kind of you know drew upon the fact that
the symptomology developed first on the
lower portion of the plant and it will
translate locate that to the you know
other portions of the plant that you
know need that nitrogen you know for
example the meristematic region as it's
developing new leaves and putting on new
shoots
and like you said typical symptom ology
of nitrogen deficiency is going to be
like yellowing or paling specifically at
the lower foliage other elements that we
looked at you know are immobile which
means you're going to see symptom ology
on the newer leaves shoots near portions
of the plant yeah that's a really good
point regarding mobile and immobile
nutrients how related is that to the
hydrology in terms of your watering
habits nutrient mobility or nutrients
that are mobile yeah so the the whole
flow and dynamics and flux of nutrients
within the plant as is much more
complicated than we went into in this
paper like I said we're trying to get
some more foundational knowledge out
there but yes so for example some plants
are tran taken up by the plant through a
process called mass flow and that's very
much related to how much water
essentially the roots can absorb into
the plant and get those nutrients in and
then there's other ways that the plant
can obtain nutrients scavenge nutrients
etc so as far as through this study and
all of the plants were on an automatic
irrigation system and received the same
amount of liquid at the same intervals
throughout the day the only thing that
changed was which nutrients we were
supplying to those plants in that
solution okay and one of your one of the
things I want to point out before we
dive too far into any one element or
nutrient here is in a traditional
cannabis growing environment you're
gonna see multiple symptoms typically
it's not ever just a nitrogen deficiency
or a phosphorus deficiency it's usually
related to your watering or your
environment community your temperature
your lighting intensity insect pressure
there's so many variables so
I hope listeners will keep that in mind
when they're utilizing a guide like this
that it's not as simple as just picking
out one of the photos and saying that
looks the closest to like my plant and
so that's what's going on you have to
have a little more history into how that
plants being grown and what's going on
in the room but just wanted to throw in
that little caveat so sorry getting back
to it when you talk about nitrogen one
of your findings was the plants growing
in nitrate deficient conditions produce
50% less biomass when compared to the
control I thought this was an
interesting finding I mean it seems
expected the plant doesn't have nitrate
it's not gonna be able to grow as as
efficiently but you didn't find that
across all of the different elements
that you were testing was so is there
anything in relation to nitrogen that
you want to touch on regarding that yeah
so we have done numerous nutrient
efficiency studies with multiple
different crops and this trend of dry
weights being variable in their
statistical significance kind of holds
true across most of those studies a lot
of it is just dependent upon the plants
and how they have take nutrients how
they utilize those nutrients their
growth habits you know you can imagine
something that stays in a rosette form
is going to have very different nutrient
needs and utilizations than something
that has a very upright and leggy growth
habits but as far as nitrogen is
concerned we expected to see a
statistical significance between no
nitrogen and nitrogen supplied
treatments specifically because nitrogen
is a macro nutrient and what that means
is the plant uses more nitrogen and
other macronutrients in greater
quantities than say the micronutrients
both macro and micro are still needed by
the plants but as far as the amounts
that they need it means much much much
more nitrogen than safety even
phosphorus or potassium or calcium and
that's one of the reasons why there was
such a
strong statistically significant
decrease in plant dry weight when
compared to the control now in this test
you're you were just dealing with
vegetative plants correct so you never
really looked at cannabinoid content THC
percentage any of those things is that
correct that is correct the current work
that we're doing we are looking at like
I said the nutrient rates for all macro
and micro nutrients across the plants
different life stages so the experiment
that we are doing now we're looking at
leaf tissue nutrient concentrations in
the vegetative state we then again
sample once we have turned off our
lighting and initiated those shorter
days to start flowering and we harvest
at pre flower which is typically a week
to two weeks after we shut our lights
off and then we're waiting until they go
into full flower maturity which we're
targeting about eight weeks for full
flower maturity and then were again
sampling leaf tissue so we're getting
this nice not only nutrient rate curve
but also total plant life cycle and how
the nutrients are changing accumulating
moving within the plant this isn't an
uptake study or a translocation study
it's a nutrient rate study over time but
like I said there's this additive effect
so that's kind of the next step that
we're going on to so on and so forth
yeah I think that'll be really
interesting because it's it's fairly
easy I think to grow a healthy
vegetative cannabis plant but as you get
further into flower as the plant starts
senesce income much much more apparent
so even though as we move through some
of these elements in your in your study
here and you said you note that there
isn't statistical significance in
biomass I think as we move into flower
that'll become a lot more apparent in
terms of the
those deficiencies reflecting either a
loss of THC or cannabinoid percentages
or terpene values or even overall yield
of flower biomass so I'm really excited
to see that work as you guys come out
with it yeah and kind of going back to
what you were saying with the
statistically not the statistical non
significance in the plant dry weights so
for example for phosphorus while we did
not see a statistical significance in
dry weight between the plants that did
not receive phosphorus versus the plants
that did you can look at the leaf tissue
values and see that they were
statistically significant and very
statistically significant actually so
even though that phosphorus treatment
may not have produced a smaller plant
per per se it definitely had less
phosphorus which means that it will be
stressed and won't be as healthy and
consequently could potentially produce
you know a bud that would be suboptimal
sure that makes sense
and you know I'm of the opinion that
most most growers over apply phosphorus
in flower I'd be curious are you going
to look at what sort of what sufficient
sea levels are needed for phosphorus in
flower versus the overabundance that I
think is applied throughout the cannabis
industry in general when it comes to
phosphorus yeah so one of the things
that we'll be looking at is when we take
that final leaf tissue harvest so we're
going to be looking at okay at the end
of the plant's life how much phosphorus
did it accumulate over these different
rates but then we will also be looking
at cannabinoids cannabinoids however you
want to say it and how that can
potentially relate back to the different
rates that were applying so
for example in our phosphorus provided
at let's say hypothetically ten parts
per million what would that bud total
dry mass be but then what would also be
the you know level of THC or CBD CBG in
that flower very cool I can't wait to
see that research that's I think really
exciting I would love to have you back
on once you have you know gotten a
little further along and published that
yeah we'd love to
we'd love to do that cool so let's let's
move on to calcium it looks like that's
the next nutrient that you talked about
here I did notice that you put in
dolomite lime into your substrate to get
some calcium and magnesium in there
Keith can you touch on that and then
also what your findings were with
calcium yeah absolutely so for the
rooting substrate that we use because
these were vegetative cuttings yes some
of that did have delimited climb amended
in it but those levels would be
negligible on the scale that we're
looking at especially as the plants
continue to grow and there's you know
more biomass and consequently less
calcium and you can see that in the
statistically significant results from
the leaf tissue concentration that we
saw but as far as symptomology for
calcium goes calcium is an immobile
element so when you're looking to see
calcium stress or deficiency on your
plants you're going to be looking at the
growing tips the newly expanded leaves
the portions of the plants that are
actively growing and expanding so
calcium the plant isn't able to
requisition any calcium reserves from
old cells or old plant parts and
translocated so that's why you're
looking at these new portions and
another thing with calcium is that it's
involved in cell wall stability and
basically what happens when a plant
through a calcium deficiency is it
cannot adequately develop so you'll see
this severe distortion and stunting that
we saw and you can see in the photos as
they progress and that's one of the
reasons that we were able to see such
beautiful
I say beautiful but if you're seeing the
symptom ology it's not beautiful when it
grew up but beautiful symptomology that
we induced it's quite dramatic it's it's
very apparent which i think is is what
you're referring to there and it is
great to see and you can't see it it
just it almost looks like it had a lot
of light stress I think in a lot of ways
it's it's I was quite shocked with just
how dramatic it is because it's funny
because in the in the cannabis industry
there's sort of this old mantra that if
your plant looks at all sick or
deficient you just apply Cal meg and
it's kind of become a running joke in
the cannabis industry I've just you know
put more Cal mag on that product but in
reality I think it's rare we see these
sorts of calcium deficiencies that they
do occur at least I don't see them as
much with the growers that I work with I
tend to see more nitrogen or potassium
deficiencies but yeah I really like
seeing those photos so that was really
great to see was there anything else
about calcium that you want to add I
love that you're kind of describing a
little bit of how these nutrients work
in a plant because I think that's really
important so I appreciate that too what
if you're okay with it let's move on to
sulfur and you can talk a little about
that too yeah I'd like to touch on one
more thing on calcium real quick okay so
calcium and boron will have very silver
similar symptom ology and they're both
in mobile elements but one of the
reasons and we have completed the
micronutrients experiment run for that
nutrient rates by lifecycle portion so I
can talk a little bit about some of the
symptomology and results not true
results yet we haven't run statistics on
the full study but because cannabis
wants it and
it's its reproductive phase that growing
tip will become the flowering portion
calcium and boron are extremely
important in that development because
you know when they finally are initiate
the reproductive cycle and start
producing that flower bud it's going to
be at that growing tip that you see
across the plant so if you do have
calcium or boron deficiencies you will
not have a properly developing flower
bud because you won't have a properly
developing an expanding growing region
and so you know we saw that with our
boron plants you know we had almost no
flowers produced on our boron 0r8 once
we initiated flowering just because
there the plant was physiologically
incapable of expanding and growing
because it did not have the structural
components needed to build those cells
and expand those cells that's really
interesting and people can go and view
these photos to see what what Paul is
describing here on on the paper itself
there's some great photos associated
with every one of these elements yeah so
you wanted to move on to sulphur next is
that correct yeah we'll just keep
working our way through I think this is
great thank you
wonderful yeah so for sulphur again it
was one of those elements where we did
not see a statistically significant
difference in the dry weight between the
plants that did not receive any sulphur
versus the control however when you
actually look at the leaf tissue
concentration it was statistically
significant so the plants that received
no sulphur had much much lower leaf
tissue concentrations than plants that
received an adequate level of sulfur
fertility and again I want to kind of go
back to what you said a bit earlier on
you know making sure that you take
holistic approach to diagnostics in your
plants you know I that was great that he
said that leaf tissue analysis is just
one way of trying to tease out problems
that you may experience you know it's
like you said it's this holistic
approach that you have to take it could
be another abiotic stress you know it
could be ozone damage it could be water
stress you know so taking those leaf
tissue concentrations from your plant
actually going in taking the leaf tissue
samples sending it off to a lab ensuring
that you can do that and that the lab is
licensed and that the laws and
legalities in your state allow you to do
that to gain this information will be
extremely valuable if you think you have
a nutrient deficiency you always want to
go that extra step if possible and check
to ensure that what you're seeing
visually is also reflected in the plant
yeah that's an interesting topic because
because cannabis is federally illegal we
cannot ship any leaf samples even if
there have a vegetative plant with zero
THC content in the mail so most cannabis
facilities are very limited in their
ability to do tissue testing so a lot of
what we do is sow testing because we're
primarily working with organic soil
growers where we where we have certain
levels of mineral content in every soil
mix that we're working with in native
soil and then it's just a matter of
trying to balance those based off of
like a male ik3 test which is not ideal
I'm fully aware of that but it's one of
the limit limitations within the
cannabis research at least from a
facility perspective because we are
limited not only just in the ability to
mail leaf samples to reach a lab to even
find a lab that's willing to look at a
cannabis sample and then also just the
cost associated with testing for
businesses is is really tough so it's
great that the university is doing work
like this to at least allow
growers to have access to some of this
information yeah that's that's a great
insight and again you know we're we're
learning as much as we possibly can so
honestly the exchanges that we get with
growers and the kind of challenges that
they're experiencing it only helps us do
better research so who knows maybe down
the road we're going to look at possibly
correlating some of you know the
nutrient work that we're doing to you
know some of those soil tests I know
that there's researchers out there who
do a lot of work with that and I think
they jump at the opportunity to do some
work like that if it's needed yeah
that'd be great I mean I'd love to see
more correlation there between like the
may like three and saturated pace tests
with these tissue tests so we have a
better idea of how we're of nutrient
availability in these soils because the
other challenge there too is how much of
those those nutrients are really
available to a plant and and how well is
the biology it's cycling those nutrients
so if we're talking about organic
systems there's so many variables
involved and it gets quite complex and I
think it's gonna be a long time before
we have all those answers but by using
you know chemical nutrients or mineral
salts like you guys are you're really
able to isolate out these various
minerals or nutrients which really makes
a difference in seeing these these
symptoms so that we can we can still
apply some of this knowledge towards you
know are more complex organic soil
systems yeah the one thing I will say
with sulfur that I see is I tend to see
it in very high levels in organic soils
primarily because people either applying
sulfates or gypsum as a way of
mitigating the alkalinity of a lot of
the cations in in soils so I tend to see
like excessively high sulfur levels
however from all the research I found
it's very hard to reach sulfur
toxicities in soils or more specifically
in cannabis plants to where I haven't
really seen it be a big issue it's been
one of the best tools for lowering pH
that I've found in soils is anything you
want to add you mean you in touch on
regarding that comment yeah it's very
difficult to produce a sulphur toxicity
and without going too much into the
details of physiology of that
essentially the plant is very good at
requisitioning utilizing or excluding
sulphur within the soil one thing that
you can see and some things that have
come out of literature is that elevated
sulphur level is just like any other
element being elevated above others in
the soil profile can potentially impact
and I will call it qualify that by
saying can potentially impact the
microbial community and especially in
say an organic system like what you're
working with you know looking at how
those microbes can take those nutrients
and turn them into you know a
mineralized four form that is plants
available you know that relationship
between the organic matter the microbes
and then the production of those mineral
plant available forms is a very
important Network and web to be
maintaining and monitoring so down the
road maybe there could be more work done
specifically with regard to microbes and
say elevated sulfur levels and nutrient
cycling and organic systems yeah it was
really what I would like to see
regarding sulfur is information on how
sulfur impacts of biology cuz when we
talk about sulfur it comes in a lot of
different forms so when we talk about a
sulfate form or it's you know we talked
about potassium sulfate calcium sulfate
in the case of gypsum it appears to have
in this is anecdotal very little minor
impact on overall soil biology and
nutrient cycling but I've heard when
using agricultural so for which is
associated with lowering pH
it can have a more dramatic input impact
on soil biology but I haven't I haven't
seen enough research and I haven't seen
enough data to really show how much
sulfur would need to be added to lower a
pH level this much in a given volume of
soil and how that impacts so about those
are things that I would love answers to
down the road or if that research exists
someone send it to me because I haven't
seen it yeah some research like that one
would be fantastic especially with
regards to organic forms of sulfur
there's like you said there's definitely
very much need for more information to
help perpetuate that adequate of
scientific process okay but let's go
back and and why don't you tell us a
little bit more about magnesium I know I
got off topic there for a second yes so
magnesium deficiency magnesium is
involved with chlorophyll and
essentially what a plant will when a
plant experiences magnesium deficiency
chlorophyll essentially doesn't function
in the way that it's supposed to and
what that means for the plant is if you
have a magnesium deficiency the
photosynthetic activity of the plant
could be much lower and that will impact
the resources and photosynthate that the
plant has and is able to then throw at
the developing bud and other developing
portions of the plant so if you think
about it and a typical life cycle you
know every organism wants to reproduce
and especially in plants as you touched
on a lot of times with the reproductive
stage of the plant you'll experience
much more pronounced stressors and that
will be when you start seeing those
symptom ologies for nutrient
deficiencies or you know other stresses
that the plant may be experiencing
because it's dumping so many of those
resources into that developing flower
bud with the end goal of trying to
reproduce and so especially my
magnesium you can potentially have huge
impacts to your yield and again like I
said we have not explored the full rates
and lifecycle analysis yet of this
element throughout the plant but it's
one of those that you want to keep a
specific eye on given its importance to
plant health overall
and then also touching on the the
symptomology by location on the leaf and
how it develops and progresses like you
said they're very similar magnesium and
potassium deficiency symptoms are very
similar and so understanding that leaf
anatomy and how it progresses you know
is important in the visual diagnostic
checklist that you kind of go through
and obviously in an ideal world we would
identify my initiating deficiency early
before it gets to these advanced stages
so that you know we don't have to wait
until it we see advanced entomology to
determine you know magnesium versus
potassium deficiency yeah now I'm
excited to talk about potassium because
I think potassium is one of the most
important elements when we're talking
about cannabis and I don't have the data
to support this yet at least I mean I
have you know hundreds of soil tests
I've looked at relat relat into overall
plant growth but they're not I haven't
had any plant tissue analysis but the
trend that I think I'm seeing is that
potassium deficiencies occur at a much
higher rate in cannabis as in they need
more potassium than most agricultural
crops and I think potassium has a high
correlation with bud density and overall
weight so essentially talking yield
based on the soil tests that I see
correlating with
plants the plants that appear to be our
soils that appear to be K deficient or
even just case sufficient like barely
sufficient tend to produce lower yield
and lower wait yeah lower weight and
overall lower yield and lower bud
density than these then plants that have
what most we consider an excess of
potassium but I'd be curious to have you
talk on it and also talk about what your
findings were with potassium in this
particular paper yeah so the interesting
thing about potassium especially with
regards to on say a soil profile as
opposed to some of the you know soluble
fertilizers that we were using here is
it's a mono valent ion which means it's
charge is it essentially has a charged
positive charge a singular positive
charge so typically what happens say you
have a heavy rain event those mono
valent ions will be leached through the
soil profile they're readily then say
you're diving lint and so that means
that potassium can move into a plant
relatively easily but it also moves
through the soil profile relatively
easily as well but that's kind of a side
note and as far as the research findings
that we found we also found that you
know limiting potassium had a huge
impact on the the obviously it had an
impact on how much potassium was update
was taken into the plant because there
was none supplied but once it was
supplied the potassium levels were quite
high in the plant and we referenced our
survey values in the paper as well and
those were within the reference values
that we had in our initial study but I
would agree with you that more work
definitely needs to be done in pitaya
Sam as far as its role in the
developments and etc as you touched upon
I am uncomfortable addressing that given
you know we have not yet explored the
potassium rates and the lifecycle once
we do that's definitely something that I
will be specifically looking for and
comparing in our study so that's
extremely helpful I can't wait to see
that because what I so I'll get from a
grower a male like three tests for
example at the beginning of the grow
cycle and then one at the end and what I
find is in terms of how far the
nutrients have dropped in the soil
you know nitrogen and potassium are the
two that see that typically appear to
drop the most and as you mentioned they
are very mobile they could be being
leached out of the soil from a flooding
event but a lot of the guys that were
working with - are using blue mats which
are essentially an automated watering
system that only waters as that soil
dries out so it's it's controlled
through osmotic pressure by the soil
itself and so we tend to not have a lot
of leaching going on through that bed so
in theory if nothing's leaching out the
bottom of the bed then that that
potassium is being taken up into the
plant and as we see potassium levels
drop to let's say around five percent or
lower of the total cation exchange CC of
the death of total the total plant or
sorry total of what's available in the
soil I start to see smaller buds lower
yield that sort of thing so I'd love to
see research on that and see what really
is going on there in the leaf tissue
itself that's actually really
interesting I have to keep that in mind
when looking at the study when we run
the micronutrients like I said we ran
the micronutrients we have yet to run
the macro nutrients so I'd love to talk
more with you just off air about that
that's actually very fascinating
especially if they're using a blue mat
system that could potentially mean well
we can talk later we can we can
speculate about that later I appreciate
you hearing me out let's move on to your
micronutrient disorders coz you had some
interesting stuff going on there too
yeah so like I said one of the nutrients
that I'd like to specifically highlight
would be boron and again that is
involved in the essentially cell wall
development and stabilization and so
especially if you experience a boron
deficiency and then you're close to your
initiation of reproduction and you don't
remedy that like I said one thing that
we saw is we have little to no flower
bud formation due to the fact that
meristematic region was not able to
properly develop and expand into the
developing flower bud and as far as I
guess we can cut talk about how copper
was their specific one that you want I
do address no I think what your your the
overview you're giving is great I will
just caution listeners that when we're
talking about these micronutrients we're
talking about very very small amounts
typically parts per million you don't
need a lot of boron for a plant to be
sufficient so you know don't go out
there and buy borax and apply a bunch to
your soil and think you're fixing a
deficiency because you'll probably kill
your plant I just want to highlight that
for people when we talk about
micronutrients we're talking about
typically pretty small levels of
nutrient that's actually needed yeah
that's a fantastic point and to add to
that
in this experiment we added a boron
toxicity treatment so essentially what
we did is we took that modified Poland
solution we took the boron levels and we
increase them tenfold of what the
Hoagland solution requires and we did
that with manganese as well and the
reason we do that is because we often
see like you said it's very easy to over
apply a micronutrient so we also wanted
to try and capture some of those
toxicity some phonologies because not
every nutrient in
shew that you run into will be a
deficiency sometimes you're over
applying something or something is too
available or the plant is taking up too
much of something or you know another
element may be in such high quantities
that it's causing another element to be
plant unavailable yeah and it's what's
interesting I'm looking through these
photos right now a boron initial boron
toxicity looks almost exactly like your
initial potassium deficiency they're
very close correct and I think that's
interesting for people because I've seen
people walk into a grow room look at a
plant and immediately say oh that's
nitrogen though that's potassium oh
whatever and that always makes me
nervous because there are there's so
many variables associated with this I
mean a lot of especially in soils a lot
of your nutrient deficiencies in
excesses can be related to hydrology or
the way that you're watering by just
under watering your plant you can cause
a lot of nutrient deficiencies because
the microbes aren't able to cycle
nutrients effectively due to a lack of
water so or due to lack of osmotic
pressure move those nutrients throughout
the plant so I think that's really
important to highlight I just want to
point that out while we're while we're
on the topic yeah I think that's a great
point I find one of the most helpful
things you can ask any grower of any
crop is first and foremost for a crop
history because most of the times you're
seeing something that is an issue that
was created sometime in the past it is
now manifesting and so that's a
fantastic point and I'm glad to see that
there's other people out there who are
you know stopping and thinking and
taking a more holistic approach to you
know diagnosing issues yeah was there
anything else you want to touch on
regarding the manganese or boron
toxicities that you saw or either of
those elements in general in relation to
plant growth or plant health yeah one
thing I will say is when looking at
toxicities and you can see this in the
photos and I hope that this photo also
gets posted so the listeners can
reference it you will often see that
toxicity sent rhinology regardless of
element follows a very specific
progression where you see that you know
marginal chlorosis so that yellowing of
the margin first and then it will
progress to the marginal necrosis which
is that burning or that the browning of
the leaf margin and you'll see that and
you can see that in you know the
comparison image that we have between
manganese toxicity and boron toxicity
you know that the marginal symptomology
is very pronounced in almost any
toxicity so just kind of as a side note
you know being careful and cautious when
you know dealing with the leaf margin
especially if it's going chlorotic or
necrotic yeah that's that's excellent
advice I that wasn't something I was
aware of or had really ever thought of
honestly when I think of toxicities so
I'm glad you pointed that out yeah did
you want to touch on did you want to
move on to your what looks like iron and
zinc were the next two on in your paper
yeah so again as I stated magnesium
toxicity or magnesium deficiency
manganese deficiency iron deficiency
they all kind of have this intervene all
chlorosis symptom symptoms that develop
on the foliage and so you know doing
work like this we're trying as best we
can to develop these criterias and
checklist suppose visually and with leaf
tissue to help people diagnose things
but a lot of times the symptom ologies
are very similar so being careful that
when you're looking at these that you're
taking again a holistic approach and
trying to utilize the tools that are
available to you to help diagnose these
the iron deficiency again you'll get the
severe inner vein of chlorosis and those
more advanced symptoms and hopefully you
know we can
identifying remedy iron before it gets
this level but letting the plants go out
this far that's one of the reasons that
we allowed you know the plants to grow
in these deficient conditions for so
long so that we'd have that gradient the
beginning I mean in advanced entomology
and as far as iron is concerned it is
another immobile element so for this
particular opponent if you're seeing
symptomology on the new expanding leaves
the growing portions the plants that the
portions of the plant that are actively
growing this is where you're going to be
seeing that you know intervene or
chlorosis and so looking at where on the
plant these symptoms are occurring will
help you identify and you know kind of
utilize that as a checklist you know is
this iron or is this you know a mobile
element and there's some wonderful
charts online that you all can utilize
if you just look at nutrient mobility in
plants it will tell you which there's
some charts out there that have you know
don't categorize mobile elements versus
in mobile elements and will help you
identify more it's it's a tool a
diagnostic tool that you can utilize to
figure out which element you may be
experiencing which nutrient may be
limiting in your fertility reading
that's great yeah I think you covered it
anything you want to touch on regarding
zinc or I see you mentioned even
molybdenum I have done zero work on the
lib to them I really don't know much
about it overall there's everything you
want to share in particular relating to
either of those yeah we utilized
molybdenum because it is a plant
essential micronutrients but as far as
plants that often display symptom ology
and molybdenum
see it's kind of hit or miss most of the
time I lived in them is more important
for Naja lating plants so plants that
will form associations with bacteria to
form root nodules to fix atmospheric
nitrogen such as your lagoons but for
example poinsettias poinsettias will
often display a molybdenum deficiency so
it was kind of hit or miss we kind of
threw it in just for fun to kind of see
what would happen but like I said and
you can look at the the composite
picture
not much symptom ology occurred and we
did not have statistically significant
differences in dry weights even though
we did receive a statistically
significant difference and leave tissue
concentration of molybdenum so basically
there was more molybdenum in the leaf
tissue in your treatment versus the
control however that didn't display
visually or in terms of your overall
biomass when you measure the two plants
it sounds like from what I'm from what
I'm getting one thing I will say is
because we use you know kelp things like
kelp meal and rock dust I have never
really worried about molybdenum I figure
we're picking some up through those
because they contain some of those
elements but I'll be curious to see as
you move through flower looking at
molybdenum if you start to see
sophistical e significant differences in
overall yield or cannabinoid content
that that might be interesting because
I'd like to maybe start playing around
with the addition of molybdenum to see
if it makes it has a real any real and
growth impact or plant health impact
yeah that's definitely something that
we'll be looking at with regard to our
statistical analysis on the
micronutrients study that we just
completed the raid over life cycle
experiment that all all of these
micronutrients it's going to be very
interesting just
see what happens with the different
rates over the life cycle of the plant
cool well I think you covered all my
questions I know there's some of the
discussion explains some of your
findings which really fits with a lot I
think we already covered most of that
just in our discussion of the elements
but was there anything else you wanted
to add regarding this research before we
sign off yeah just again to reiterate
that one of the most valuable things you
can do whenever you're looking at a
problem is utilizing the tools that you
have available to you you know looking
at what you did in the past to try and
figure out you know is for example you
used water am i providing enough water
and is that causing a nutrient issue de
facto or you know did I apply something
that may now be in interacting and a
negative effect in the soil profile and
causing another element to be plant
unavailable and again this this work
where we're still in a process we're
learning we're producing science it's an
additive process so this is you know
visual symptom ology is correlated to
leaf tissue and you know these these
pictures are very helpful and useful but
again some of the symptomatology is
similar so looking at you know the
progression of the symptom ology
comparing that to the pictures and then
also looking at where on the plant those
symptoms are occurring will be extremely
useful oh I look forward to seeing
further research out of your University
and and you personally and I'm really
grateful for your time today and I look
forward to staying in touch and
hopefully we'll get to have you or
someone when your colleagues back on
soon to talk about some of the latest
research and use some of your findings
absolutely
yeah we're definitely very excited for a
lot of the research we're doing and
definitely even more excited to continue
talking with growers and producers to
you know understand the needs that they
have
as far as research is concerned it's
very much a to ace
treat what the industry needs and does
and the issues that they're experiencing
help us do better research that's more
applicable and helps the industry as a
whole so this bilateral exchange is
extremely important and definitely is
something that needs to continue in
greater quantity for all researchers
that are going to be doing work in hemp
or cannabis that was Paul Coxon and you
were listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our website at www.kttape.com
[Music]