[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and draw
the top experts from around the industry
to share their wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is dr kevin mayer dr
mayer has spent the last five years
driving the development of large-scale
micro-propagation programs from cannabis
in north america
kevin received his phd in genome science
and technology from the university of
british columbia
and translate this experience with
genetics and plant science to every
facet of operations
product innovation and establishing new
sales channels
kevin has established key partnerships
with some of the largest licensed
cannabis producers in canada
and the u.s and continues to ensure
company execution while driving the
industry forward
hey kevin thanks for coming on the
podcast today
thanks for having me yeah let's start
off by telling listeners a little bit
about yourself
sure so i uh my background is academic i
got a phd in genome science and
technology which
with the focus on microbial genetics way
back in the day
and uh you know at the time i wasn't
focused on plants but
i was fortunate enough when the early
canadian cannabis companies and
licensing was coming online
to join an upstart there and really just
grew to love plants more than i ever
thought i would
and dive into this world and and you
know i couldn't be more happy that i'm
here now so i've been working
in uh in the cannabis space for the last
five years and
typically you know just focusing on the
nursery space and
tissue culture wonderful
wonderful i appreciate you coming on the
show i found out about you guys from
suzanne who's a good friend of mine and
uh she recommended that we have a chat
so um yeah this isn't a topic that i
happen
to know all that much about um
so i kind of wanted to let you just lead
the discussion here
do you want to talk a little bit about
what you know tissue culture is
and how it works and sort of what you've
what you found
sure yeah i mean i'll take i'll take
even a bigger step back and just
you know touch on we're going to go a
little bit historical here for a second
you know just so that everybody knows
where this comes from
you know there was a there was this guy
named godly paverland way back in the
early 1900s
who uh we assume was a pretty cool guy
because he was working on this he was
really the
the father of tissue culture and he you
know was studying
what plants you know what nutrients
particularly micronutrients from soil
you know the plants really need to grow
and thrive and this really just got
picked up heavily
in the 1960s when you know the
the concept of growing plants in kind of
a clean
uh environment with very specific
nutrients and minerals and sugars
uh could be utilized you know to produce
plants and actually keep them alive
not only just to keep them from dying
out you know if something was really
challenged or almost going extinct
but actually grow lots and lots of
plants very handily so in the 1960s this
really took off for orchids in
ornamental flower production and really
just through the 60s and 90s it's
kind of exploded as a you know
a way to produce clean plants so you
know plant tissue culture is this very
large
field that encompasses you know really
any study of plants
um growing in a in a specialized media
or nutrient-rich media
and within that larger academic world
there's the subsection that really just
focuses on
clean plant production or you might say
clean cloning and that's called
micropropagation so
you'll hear a sort of throw around the
term tissue culture and micropropagation
a lot but
micropropagation is really the
commercial nursery side
you know for large-scale plant
production within the larger academic
world of tissue cultures so
really i mean any strawberry blueberry
you've had in the last you know 20 years
has actually been produced
or for the most part it's been produced
through tissue culture
and uh you know it's it's critical in a
lot of different industries like
potatoes and berries bananas i mean
ornamental flowers
and uh and even now complex medicinal
plants companies like dole and
driscoll's you know they they
really have taken this technology and
run with it particularly in crops where
we're monocropping and viruses start to
creep up and cause a problem so
that's i'd say sort of the larger
history of tissue culture and where it
came about
and what we do is really focus on on
micropropagation within cannabis and
hemp so hemp type cannabis and thc
cannabis
we've got a couple different entities
sort of focusing on different different
areas of those two markets
and our goal really is to produce clean
plants
virus-free plants or at least uh you
know as pathogen-free or virus-free as
we can get them particularly with some
of the more well-known viruses that
we're starting to identify here
so that growers have a very clean and
healthy plant happy plant going into
production
and you know also can scale that
as they go from maybe their startup
phase to a larger you know build out an
expansion
you know hopefully uh because they're
doing really well
that's interesting so in the case of
cannabis um i've i've noticed that a lot
of
people over the last decade have been
talking a lot about tissue culture
i've visited labs that were going to be
set up but then i kind of died off i
didn't really
hear a lot of people that were
successfully doing it so it seems like
there's some challenges i know people
are now i know it exists
but it seems like it was a lot harder
than people thought it was going to be
what are some of the challenges
associated with uh
tissue culture that may be you know say
more unique to a crop like cannabis
sure so yeah it's it's definitely a
challenging plant
it you know unlike some other crops that
are you know that have been
selectively bred for being robust and
really you know hearty and different
conditions and disease resistant
you know cannabis is really only just
starting to get that kind of
breeding treatment so you know to take
the crop as it exists now and
mass-produce it in tissue culture is
very challenging because
because every you know every cultivar uh
is is a little bit different
some are you know chock full of diseases
there's also
a challenge just knowing what's in the
plant so we you know we deal with
removing
really any bacterial fungal or viral
contaminant
and when you don't even know what what
some of those are
it just makes for a much more
challenging process i mean i think
some of the you know i touched on it
before where you have this very larger
kind of academic
side of tissue culture so there's a lot
of people that have really you know been
studying plants and tissue culture and
tried to apply that knowledge to
cannabis
you know to a degree of success maybe
just producing some clean plants or
clean mother stock but under in a very
uh
lengthy time time frame and you know now
we have some of the large nursery teams
that are
you know doing large-scale
micropropagation tens of millions of
plants
plants per year shifting into the
cannabis space
and bringing that sort of large-scale
commercial knowledge into it
and marrying that with sort of the
academic expertise and i think that's
one of the big differences for why you
know a lot of people got really excited
about this
it's very expensive and time-consuming
to set up and develop a tc lab
you know most companies if something
hasn't really worked out over about 8 to
12 months that's usually the point where
they kind of go okay
i don't know if this is really worth it
um but you know if you're kind of coming
from the commercial production side you
understand that
you know it could be a couple years of r
d just to develop you know the the
precise
you know nutrient formula that it takes
to grow these you know each particular
cultivar happily
in culture and multiply the plants that
that really i think is what's what's
driving the
the development at least for you know a
few of the larger operators in this
space now
so it went went quiet for a while i
think there was a lot of hype
and uh unfortunately you know not a lot
of execution because i think a lot of
the really
experienced commercial teams they
weren't really dipping their toes in yet
so you touched on some of the benefits
of tissue culture
already in the fact that you can remove
you know bacterial
viral fungal diseases things that may be
you know systemic in the plant like some
dealing with something that's like
powdery mildew for example
might be something that you could you
could get a clean plant back to
uh to a grower but in addition it's also
a faster way of getting uh
more plants than than cloning as well
once you have the system set up is that
correct
yeah you nailed it i mean there's i
could go into the whole you know
there's a whole benefit side of tissue
culture when it comes to plant
performance
and and disease resistance or just you
know i guess general health and vigor
um you know plants in in gen i guess
plants that have come from tissue
culture like sugar cane and other crops
that
you know are really commonly produced in
tissue culture almost across the board
you see
sort of an inherent health and
resistance to disease so things like you
might just see an inherent
slightly improved resistance to powdery
mildew just because the plant is
starting healthy it's starting
without essentially being coated
in in you know fungal pathogens and uh
it's really just going to carry that
health through the entire process i mean
if you look at um
just really every single way that we can
produce clean plants i mean
space-wise you know the efficiency of
tissue culture
when you look at it compared to
conventional cloning takes up
maybe 10 of the space and that's you
know that's a pretty rough estimation
but
you know in a in a maybe a few thousand
square feet of a lab in tissue culture
you know we can produce over a million
plants a year
and uh if you were looking at a cloning
room a mother space sort of a single
tier
cloning space you know you you're
definitely not going to achieve those
kind of plant numbers in that space
so take me uh take me through this
process and
and one question i had then is you're
not necessarily you're not doing
anything
to uh modify the genetic
makeup of the plant you're just
reproducing it when we talk about
tissue culture is that correct that's
right yeah so we're not
so you know within the larger world of
plant tissue culture there's definitely
an academic side to it and you know they
might focus on
on uh you know genetically modifying
organisms but that's that's not really
what micropropagation is
you know we're just we're just basically
clean cloning
in a very uh specific environment that's
a little bit more like a computer chip
manufacturing facility where you've got
no dust particles in the air
you know you're working in a very
sterile environment and just
uh taking advantage of the plant's
ability to multiply even when it's very
small
and produce lots and lots of plants so
no we're not we're not impacting the
genetics of the plant at all
okay so as an organic grower myself
how should i feel about tissue culture
in general yeah that's an interesting
question you know i think
you would you would instinctively think
that you know organic production
would would despise or or should not you
know feel comfortable with
tissue culture but what's really
interesting is
that you know there's already a lot of
tissue culture that's used within
organic production which people might
not know
you know we the strawberry industry in
california the organic strawberry
production
you know is heavily reliant on plant
tissue culture there's a
there's a i should say you know
basically there's there's a way that
um organic producers can you know source
plant material from tissue culture
labs and it doesn't impact or you know
as long as they're still running it
through an entirely organic
process it doesn't doesn't impact their
certification i think where
the challenge for some organic producers
you know when using tissue culture lies
is in how
or what type of hormones you're using to
manipulate the plants so
i'll take a step back when you're
producing plants in tissue culture
they're really going through a few
different stages so the first stage
we call initiation is when you're
bringing in the plant
you're sort of sterilizing it you know
cleaning it up sanitizing it just to get
rid of any surface pathogens
and get it then into a you know a test
tube or a glass jar
to grow in tissue culture once you've
sort of verified that it's clean it
doesn't have any of those problems
anymore
which can take a while many months you
move the plants into the next stage
which is multiplication so you're really
just
sort of guiding the plant to
be more bushy sort of like a mini mother
plant really so that you can you know
every few weeks it can it can be
split into multiple plants and you can
build a big stock that way the next
stage is really bringing it out of
tissue culture
and to you know really tell the plant to
start rooting so either you're going
into a plug set up or you're
you're using a media that tells the
plants to using a rooting hormone
and and then you're basically just
hardening the plant outside of the
tissue culture for the last and fourth
stage
which we just call acclimation so that
would be you know hardening it off in
the greenhouse for example
now in organic production if you're
using
synthetic hormones for example in your
tissue culture media
that might not jive well with an organic
production regime because they're not
naturally derived but there's actually a
lot of tissue culture that can be done
even just with naturally derived plant
hormones so
for example you know you can even
utilize something like a willow bark
extract
in a in a tissue culture rooting
procedure that is just naturally derived
there's nothing synthetic about it
so i think you know organic producers
don't need to be afraid of tissue
culture it's not really this
this sterile chemical lab process you
know it really can be done
really just in a very clean and organic
uh i don't know a compatible way if that
makes sense
well it does and it doesn't because one
of the things i struggle with is
is the fact that it does seem to be
quite challenging for a lot of people
um to you know to set up a lab and
actually get successful plants out of it
so what i'm wondering here is i've been
assuming that the
media uh culture the cultural
culture medium and then the nutrients
that you're feeding
to the plants whatever that concoction
is
that would be you know chemically based
or synthetic and then at that point when
you give the plant back to the grower
they could treat it organically and that
doesn't affect the organic certification
but
i mean is there anyone doing this on
scale that's actually using a fully
organic process or do you really believe
that's even possible on scale i mean
i understand i could go and harvest
willow bark and
you know access some of the hormones out
of there
and potentially clone a plant but then
i'm not
i'm not truly getting a clean plant am i
i mean
can i can i still go through that whole
process and get a clean plant
yeah sorry so there actually are there
are definitely our groups that are using
very you know organic regimes where
everything from everything that they're
utilizing in the plant growth media
you know is is sort of uh organically
derived materials that are just
really just going into media that's
producing the plant in a clean lab so
that other external
you know problems paths you know
pathogens and pests can't
get a hold on that plant early well it's
in production so
you know one of the other things that i
think really gets me interested
where you know i think organic
production
can get really exciting here using you
know starting from tissue culture is
you know just because you're removing
some of the
the natural you know microorganisms in
the plant to get it healthy at the start
there's an opportunity there really
right after that
plant is coming out of tissue culture to
really introduce
every type of beneficial you know
organism that you can think of i mean
i i you know one thing that we're really
looking at is
you know what are the beneficials what
are all the natural you know
beneficial mycorrhizal and things that
we can inoculate the plant with
early as it's coming out of the really
coming out of the greenhouse or out of
the lab
and so that you know it's it's we're
just taking advantage of nature there
and you're just setting the plant up to
you know
really thrive instead of just uh being
completely barren of all
i guess microbial life and going out
into the you know into the field or the
the pod or the indoor setup
oh that's really interesting i never i
never thought of that but you're since
you're starting so clean you can really
do whatever you want at that point in
terms of what you want to introduce
to the plant yeah i mean one of the
things we've seen is you know there's a
lot of
um i think there's a bit of a
misconception when when somebody is
growing a strain that
you know they've been cloning it for
years and years and years and it's
declining
you know a lot of people will attribute
it to something like genetic drift and
you know often that's not the case when
a plant is being cloned serially
over and over and over again you know it
also builds up a lot of um
microorganisms within it you know we
that we call endophytes so this is
these are microorganisms you know
bacterial or fungal that their
relationship
with the plant sort of varies from
symbiotic to bordering on pathogenic
and you know the more those build up the
more they can impact the plants vigor
and health and you know what we're
seeing is that the plant is declining in
terms of either just vigor and yield or
potency and you know very often it's
just that
it's been cloned for so long it's just
accumulated so many passengers within it
some of them not very good for it that
you know we really need to get rid of
them before the plant can come back to
it sort of we call it you know
generation zero
seed generation vigor and uh you know
tissue culture allows you to do that but
i think you know with it with an
emphasis on you know beneficial
organisms right after that you can you
can really not only reset the plant
but then set it up to be as
advantageously colonized with you know
stuff that's really going to help it
really going to help it go
yeah i'm really glad you brought that up
that was one of the things i wanted to
cover because you hear people talk about
you know genetic drift or her genetic
exhaustion or
this idea that that clones will degrade
over time
um i think i think is probably more like
you said the case where
it's this this buildup of you know
endophytes or
you know having a plant that's gone
through a lot of environmental stress
and if people are cloning it you know
off of a
stressed mother plant they could be
getting
less vigorous clones it's not
necessarily a reflection
of the the genetic material um
of the plant itself um so definitely not
yeah you know there's there's always
there's obviously the the classic
diseases as well i mean the plant could
be
you know getting fusarium and and
phytophthoric you know could be
impacting the the nursery stock so
there's all these other
you know root borne and you know fungal
pathogens that can be there impacting
the plant
that are really hard to get rid of you
know fusarium obviously in sort of the
california clone nursery
uh it's really just devastated a lot of
more the
traditional clone nurseries and
tissue culture you know allows you to
get away from those which you know often
are the problem
the other side of it that is a little
less understood and we're just kind of
really getting into it now is
the virus side of it so there's a lot of
known viruses right now that impact
cannabis
and we you know we have a pretty good i
guess
idea of what some of them are we test
for we test for viruses
uh separately and i think one of my
colleagues jack dr jack buns hopefully
we'll be able
to jump on the podcast and talk a little
bit more about plant viruses but
you know we we test for plant viruses
because we need to be able to show that
the stock we're producing is clean on
the other side of it we also just need
to help people identify what the problem
is so
you know they're looking at it
attributing it to maybe genetic
drift like you said but it very well
could just be a virus that
you know isn't showing up in a typical
virus screen or just something that
they're not testing for
so i find it kind of tends to fall into
three camps
one being that you just have a buildup
of bacterial and fungal endophytes that
are maybe impacting the plant removing
them
you know you really see a boost in vigor
the other camp being
viruses and you know it's certainly a
big issue we're seeing it a lot
on the west coast a lot of obsolete and
viroid
and the third camp being actual you know
environmental issues or genetic drift
but that's really rare
i mean you know if i were to do tissue
culture with 100 different plant
cultivars
you know it might only be one or two
that are truly aging out
and having a having sort of a either
having a mutation
true mutation that's causing a problem
or uh they're
they're really aging so um that
typically they'll you know fall in the
in the pathogen camp so
if i was trying to consider genetics to
use in tissue culture what sort of
aspects do you look for
in a plant i mean i would assume if a
plant is susceptible to
a particular pathogen like powdery
mildew or you know fusarium something
like that
it may not be a good candidate for
tissue culture just in the sense that
yes you can remove it and get them back
a clean plant but it's probably going to
be susceptible down the road and have
the same issues
later in life i mean what are your
thoughts on that
yeah i mean it's it's a it's a tough
question to answer because i think you
know everyone everyone might select
differently for their own reasons
whether it's commercial or just
disease resistance you know you all it's
easy to say you should always select for
a plant that's disease resistant but
disease resistant but you know i we
understand the the
complexity of the commercial cannabis
market you know on the retail side
and what people are sort of trying to do
and you know there's a
there's a demand i guess every year for
the new new and what's exciting and
you know that's going to really i guess
clash with traditional
breeding right where we're trying to to
have very healthy clean plants that
we're selecting
over multiple generations so it's a it's
a difficult one you know i i think
tissue culture at least is a tool you
know that i think provides some of these
growers
who are dealing with more challenged or
pathogen-susceptible plants with a way
to reset their population so you know
even if you weren't producing every
plant through tissue culture
you might be able to reset your mother
stock every four to six months from
tissue culture
so that there wasn't enough time for
something that you
knew would probably impact the plant
that plant to take hold and cause you
real problems
yeah this got me thinking from my
conversation with
jeremy plum over a proof about this idea
of getting consistent
chemovar expression for like a medical
patient
you know if you are dealing with a
particular
disease or something and you go into a
dispensary and get
this particular strain or cultivar and
you have a good response to it
you could very well get a very different
uh chemovar expression
going back you know even buying it from
the same grower so
that's one of the things he's been
working on and i think tissue culture
could be an important part of that
process
and keeping your genetics consistent
over time too
for a medical patient like that yeah i
mean i remember jeremy i
actually listened to that that
discussion you had to jeremy and you
know he was talking a little bit
if i remember he was actually mentioning
how they had the same cultivar grown at
three different environments
and it was a starkly different chemical
profile
in all the different environments so how
challenging it is even having
you know the same genetics um you know
how much they're impacted by the
environment and i think
you know where tissue culture can play
play a role here obviously is
it really i mean it depends how much the
environment is impacting
variable production or variable
chemotypes you know of a cultivar even
in the same facility
if you have if you're seeing a lot of
variation
and it's caused by you know
environmental things like that tissue
culture might not impact that very much
but if it's you know different
environments
there in terms of pathogens so this room
is a little more pathogen challenge for
powdery mildew or this
room you know potentially is developing
some viral issues
you know having the consistent stock
every time is certainly going to give
you a lot more consistency
you know so you can get that elusive um
you know consistency for the medical
patient which everyone is striving for
and i think people are you know
passionately striving for which is great
and you know this this would just be
another tool to ensure that consistency
i mean when you
look at some of the clinical trials that
you know really have occurred in lots of
different medicinal plants
most of the time you know the project
won't even be greenlit unless the plants
are coming from tissue culture just
because
the typical consistency with that
methodology is just so much stronger
than normal cloning or from seed
that's interesting i wasn't aware of
that so i guess
take me through this process like um if
i was a grower
and decided that uh you know i had a
really special plant that i wanted
to sort of preserve or reset or
cultivate uh in large numbers and i know
this is something i'm going to want down
the road
how what does that look like i i assume
i would contact a company
like yourselves i would have to give you
a certain amount of plant material
you know how does this all work sure so
it depends a little bit on what the aim
is so for if you're just wanting to
if you're just wanting to store
something or bank it so get it into
tissue culture for storage
or you're just wanting to get into
tissue culture to clean it up and get a
few clean plants back
you know that whole process is probably
going to take about anywhere from
five to eight months assuming that
there's not any major viral challenges
with that plan
so you know we would we would talk to a
company like ours
you know we would we would basically
coordinate either visiting and
sampling material directly uh having our
team do it or providing a you know
detailed guideline on how to basically
provide us with uh just large branches
or cuttings that we can sample from
that can be shipped to us in a sort of a
good way either same day or next day
and we would basically harvest as many
you know viable samples off that tissue
as we could
so that we would have you know at least
a couple hundred sort of surviving
what we call explants you know so
samples in tissue culture now growing
without contamination that have survived
kind of the initial cleanup
process and you know that all happens
pretty quickly you know from the time
that somebody says let's go
we can we can show up the next day or
within a week and get that going
and we won't really know how successful
that plant is initially in tissue
culture for a few weeks but
you know after that we're really just
taking it through a series of steps
you know within kind of the regime of
how we grow that planting culture
so that it's really just getting used to
growing in culture because you know
you're sort of taking plant material
you're telling it to grow in something
without roots right so it has to just
morphologically adapt to that
environment just like any plant would in
a different environment so it takes some
time for the plant to get used to
growing in tissue culture
and then you know then you're driving
the plant to start multiplying so that
we can build some stock
and then really at that point once it's
happy there we could pull clean plants
out
you know anytime so if you just wanted a
couple clean plants back we might be
able to do that in three four months
if it's just a few plants but usually
people want to you know
get a couple hundred or at least 100 or
at least 50 or a tray back
so that they can run some type of trial
either put that right into mother stock
or get a few in production and do a
side-by-side comparison
you know with those plants versus the
plants from traditional cuttings
and we just work with you know with
everybody to to find a plan that fits
their needs if they're
wanting to just store the plants at that
point you know we would just maintain
maybe a very small quantity in tissue
culture
but if they're wanting to go and do
production so you know they have
a room that they want to dedicate or get
supplemental clones from us for
then it really just becomes kind of a
math
and calculations around you know if we
have a thousand plants but they want
three thousand a month and the plants
are doubling every month you know it's
going to take us a couple extra months
just to get the stock up
and then be able to provide them that
you know 3 000 every month sort of
quantity so
really just there's a lot of weird
calculations that go into it in terms of
figuring out the timelines but
for the most part i think you should
expect um to be able to get back some
clean material if you're putting
something into culture you know within
six to eight months
if it has viral challenges particularly
like obsolete and viroid
we usually tell people to anticipate
about eight to eight to 11 months
because there will definitely be
additional steps and what we call sort
of deep meristematic culturing where we
might have to culture just from
meristematic tissue so for anyone who's
not aware the
apical meristematic tissue is sort of
the the most
newly forming uh piece of tissue on that
plant
so it hasn't really been vascularized so
it hasn't connected to the circulatory
system of the plant yet
so it hasn't really been infected by you
know other viruses or pathogens that are
in that plant tissue
so if you can sample from that you can
essentially get away from the viral
problem just because that tissue hasn't
been infected yet so
you know if you hear about people
talking about tissue culture you know
often you'll hear things
uh talk you know you often hear
meristematic tissue culture mentioned
that's certainly a method to sort of get
clean tissue from a from a mother plant
that has a problem
and get away from viruses but it's not
the only way to get or get away from
those problems there's quite a few and
we usually take a parallel approach and
maybe have about three methods running
the same time so that we're covered
because meristematic tissue culture
takes a really long time it could take
10 10 to 12 or more months developed to
develop samples from from aristomatic
culture so
yeah i think there's roughly a timeline
there that you know i think people
might their eyes might bug out a bit and
go wow that's that's a sticker shock for
sure that you know that it's going to
take that long
but you know if something is
commercially important for you
you know you're producing it
consistently on a recurring basis
you know there's probably an easy case
to be made for for getting it cleaned up
and having a backup of it and being able
to scale up production clean production
if you need it
yeah now this got me thinking about one
of the challenges associated with giving
genetics to
a company like yourself or really any
company that has the ability to
reproduce those genetics or
do research on those genetics if i have
a special plant that i have you know
ownership over in the sense that i've
either bred it or
you know i want to use it in commercial
production in the state
you know i don't want more competition i
don't want other people using this plan
uh what sort of rights and privacy do i
have
around you know working with a company
like yourselves or
yourself regarding uh protection you
know essentially ip
of uh whatever plant tissue i give you
yeah i know ted i'm glad you brought
that up we it's a question that i get
every day
you know how to how do how are our
genetics protected and
and what do you do so we we first of all
we
make it very clear and we have contracts
that support this that you know
your genetics are your genetics we have
no claim or ownership on them we can't
do anything
with them we can't do any genomic
sequencing we can't do any breeding we
can't do any cloning without your
approval
um on all of those so there you know i
think it's
critical especially within the nursery
space you know where you are dealing
with
customers only customers genetics they
might have bred those themselves or you
know
done an extensive amount of phenol
hunting to get them and
uh you know we understand the value
there is is huge
especially on the retail side like you
said if you have something and you don't
want it to be flooding the market so
you know we we take that very seriously
um kind of intellectual property and
protection of our of our customers
and uh you know we make no claims the
other side of it for us is you know we
just we don't do any breeding
so if you look at a lot of nurseries
whether they're doing tissue culture or
not i think you know it's very hard to
say that you'll protect a customer's
genetics if you have a breeding program
over here where you're you know you're
trying to develop
and acquire and get interesting
cultivars so
you know i think that's a really big
piece of it for us is to to make sure
that we
you know not only can show that we have
you know no interest and no business
developing genetics ourselves we just
want to help people scale and produce
their own
i think that's that's a big piece you
know you might want to look at look at
the nurseries you're working with you
know if that
if they're developing a breeding program
you know that might be a bit of a red
flag that
they're you know there's probably an
incentive somewhere for somebody to
you know even even if it's not uh
something that they want to do where the
ceo
will drive you know there's going to be
somebody in the lab somewhere who's
going to be interested in it
and i think not having a breeding
program just takes a lot of that
incentive away
but also the the contractual protection
of course
i i think yeah i think you hit on two
things that are from a grower
perspective really concerning
um one is you know the the idea that
they're gonna someone's going to do
something with that actual
tissue or those specific genetics but
also this idea of genome sequencing to
where you can identify
in a genome these specific occurrences
across
multiple genetics you know you're gonna
see
thousands thousands of plants um and you
can say hey this is what
seems to be special across all these
plants and then take that
data and start a separate breeding
program so i love the i love that you
guys are not doing
any genetic sequencing without
permission from a grower
themselves yeah that was one of the
issues you know here in the northwest
that happened
a couple years ago that you may maybe
you're familiar with too
yeah yeah no we're very aware of that
and
i think it was a it was a bit of a
wake-up call for everybody i mean you
know one thing i didn't mention we do
we do have the ability to do a genetic
fingerprint of things and i think that's
critical for a nursery for quality
control you know if i if i go and
produce 10
000 plants i probably should be checking
you know
that batch as it's going out to just
verify that it was the right plant
before it goes out and gets grown by
somebody
this is really typical in like the
blueberry industry and other other crops
that are produced in large scale
but the big difference between doing a a
genotype a very simple genotype and
doing you know genomic sequencing is
exactly what you mentioned the ability
to kind of do a deeper dive for
for underlying information potentially
on what makes that plant interesting
you know the way we genotype is
completely anonymous
it's it's what's called a sort of
variable nucleotide 10 and repeat
sequencing which is the same way that
humans do forensic
genotyping so when you're you know
looking for
somebody who matches a sample of hair or
blood you know you can use
a very kind of basic genotyping method
to
to figure out that the identity matches
but it's very much like a fingerprint it
doesn't tell you if that person has blue
eyes or brown hair
or is really great at producing thc it
just tells you that this plant
equals this plant they are the same and
that's it
so i think you know that kind of
methodology and maybe understanding the
underlying technology and
when groups are talking about genomic
sequencing or genotyping
is really critical so you know the event
that you talk about in the pacific
northwest
uh that got really people frustrated you
know does tie a little bit to the method
they were using
so you know there's some companies that
do a genetic fingerprint
using what's called a snip profile so
they have a panel of you know
30 000 individual regions within
a plant genome that create a fingerprint
but
some of those single you know nucleotide
regions
can be tied to a gene that actually
matters and impacts the plant or is
important
and you know so they can sort of
potentially derive some information i
say potentially because i don't want to
infer that they're trying to do that
they might not
i have no idea but certainly the
possibility is there to
get functional information from a snip
panel you know whereas
a vntr type fingerprint
doesn't give you any information you
know really about the
you know any any functional genes within
that genome
that can really provide any useful
information for for things like breeding
or developing a breeding program so
i realized i went on a bit of a tangent
there but i think it's sort of
interesting for
for people to understand the differences
you know in genetic fingerprinting and
genome sequencing and
and you know what uh what the downsides
or risks are with some methods over the
others
yeah i'll be the first to admit that i'm
fairly ignorant on a lot of that stuff
and so
i think one of the challenges that
happened with that you know particular
company
wasn't necessarily they were uh bad
people or bad intentions they just
poorly communicated and then people
didn't fully understand
exactly what the implications were that
were associated with a lot of what
they were looking to do too so i guess i
see both sides of that story but
um you know having i think whatever
company someone decides to work with i
think having a very frank
discussion and understanding what rights
you have as a grower
is really really important and then
having that contractually
written up so that both sides understand
what your
you know what services that are going to
be provided and uh
and all of that so thank you for
explaining that
yeah no problem i mean i think you'd
nailed it just having a really clear
not overly complicated you know
agreement you know we often just call
them material transfer agreements but
you know ours just is meant to be very
readable and
really it's all just built to protect
the ip of of
the growers you know we want to just
plant our flag and say
it's yours you know we don't we don't
want it we just want to help you know
our our specialty and a lot of
micropropagation tissue culture
nurseries you know our their specialty
is large-scale production
so getting really really large number
numbers of plants
produced in a clean way efficiently
economically maybe even cheaper than
traditional cloning
and uh you know we think that's going to
drive the market i mean
stratification across you know any
developing crop where
you know right now nursery is internal
for most companies but
you know as markets develop just like in
washington and california and a lot of
a lot of states that have been going for
a while now you start to see
a nursery side start to develop and and
i think that's going to just continue
you know you're going to
you've already seen obviously processing
extraction separate kind of from
traditional cultivation
but the nursery side i think is pretty
ripe for that that
uh differentiation where you know we can
the economy of scale for for us to
produce a lot of clean clones for a lot
of different groups
is just a lot more economical you know
than than a group doing it themselves
so i think we think that's really the
way it's going to go because it's gone
that way in almost every other crop
that's produced
produced clonally so let's talk a little
bit about
your company you mentioned the economic
side
so where are you guys what states are
you guys in currently
and um what are the costs associated
with this process
sure so we're in washington right now
and we've been in washington
for just just under a year we uh we have
a hemp
nursery hemp tissue culture nursery as
well as a thc cannabis nursery now
um that's been going since since the
summer and uh i can tell you since the
summer it's been
we've been kind of bombarded with demand
and interest in this it's uh
it's really really quite surprising
pleasantly surprising just to see
you know how many groups were interested
in this and that we might be able to
help them
there's a couple different things on the
services side so just you know putting a
cultivar into tissue culture getting it
cleaned up and getting some plants back
typically that might range because it's
sort of time dependent it might be a
monthly cost for example
somewhere in the range of 3000 to maybe
4 500
per cultivar roughly to get it into
tissue culture cleaned up and hand it
back to you
and then if you want to continue storing
it or scale it for production
there's probably just a continuing
subscription fee a couple hundred bucks
a month or a few hundred bucks a month
to for us to maintain that for example
in uh
scaled production we really just at that
point shift to a traditional nursery
model so you know you say i want this
many plants
there's a purchase order you're putting
a deposit down and
getting uh you know getting a clean
clone order so many months down the road
so that's a bit more typical
um you know everybody asked me what what
what's the clone pricing and
it really does vary by market so you
know
more developed markets whether they're
external genetics right so you know if
we
if we as a nursery have genetics from a
breeder because breeders do license
genetics to us as a nursery so we
support the
you know breeders too if they're trying
to get you know something that they've
developed
to market at scale we can do that so
growers can acquire those genetics they
might cost more than than us
mass producing their own genetics
because they you know there's no royalty
associated with their own
and whether it's sort of a one-off clone
purchase versus a recurring clone
purchase so
i'm dancing around the price question a
little bit but you know just to give you
a range
it might be you know a one-off might be
anywhere from like eight to twenty
dollars clone depending on
if it's their own genetics or you know
a very very exciting new interesting
cultivar from a breeder that has a
massive royalty tied to it
um and and they're really just providing
plants one time
so that the grower can mother off those
if it's recurring clone production
definitely tends to get down you know
more in like the 48 dollars per plant
range
potentially even getting sub four
dollars you know if it's very very large
scale
commercial micro propagation on a
recurring basis
okay good i was gonna i was going to try
and pin you down for at least some sort
of number range at least so i appreciate
everybody
everybody does i realize there's a lot
of variables that go into it so
um you guys are only in washington but
it sounds like you had plans to
potentially be in other states are you
in canada at all
no no sorry so we're in washington right
now we're active and we'll also be
active in about six weeks in california
so we actually have that lab
just finishing up it's set up here over
the next few weeks and we will actively
be able to
take in samples and work with people
probably about six weeks from today
so yeah really looking forward to that
so that would be you know roughly the
last week or the first
last week of july or the first week of
august we'll be able to
start working with growers in california
so really excited about that
and you know we we're also really just
looking to expand into a few other
states
you know we can't be everywhere but we
certainly
have a model where we integrate with
existing companies in states they're
already licensed and functional
you know we can come in develop a
nursery division
under their license and sort of share in
that
and they also get access to a lot of
those benefits so you know if you're a
company that
is in a different state that's coming
online particularly you know maybe on
the east coast for example
you know we'd love to to chat you can
reach out to me and
we you know we'd love to have that
conversation about how we might be able
to work with you
very cool very cool so uh here in
washington state
you have a medical market that or you
have laws that allow for a grower to
grow up to 15 plants at home if they
have a uh
prescription um and a license uh
card from the state directly uh so is
that something you guys support like
you know paying eight to twenty dollars
for a clone as a home grower for six
plants or
even 15 plants i'm going to yield a lot
more than i would have
going you know going down to the rec
store and buying it
plus it allows me a little more control
over the growing process do you guys
support that sort of thing um
on a smaller scale yeah i mean i'd
absolutely we're
you know i'm glad you brought it up
we're you know we're in discussion about
how we can do that we want to be able to
support home
you know medical patients and people who
are growing at home i think the
challenge for us is we just don't have
the bandwidth to have you know deal with
a lot of microtransactions so what we're
really trying to do is partner with
retailers
who can sort of set up all of the
transactions with uh
you know with with the home growers and
then facilitate a larger order from us
um just so that we can we can do that
and then people can you know we can just
coordinate uh local pickup for those
for those people that that need that and
i would absolutely love to be able to do
that we're you know we're still fairly
new and
a lot of the groups we're working with
are our large
wreck growers right now so you know
they're taking a lot of our bandwidth
certainly as they expand
but you know i we we never forget about
you know wanting to help out medical
patients when we can and i think that's
sort of the way we'll be able to do it
yeah it's such a challenge for uh
medical patients to get clean clones
because of
the fact you know you you have plant
limits you really can't do a ton of
cloning yourself because
of the number of plants you're allowed
to have and then when you go out and get
you want to acquire new genetics or get
new plants if you don't grow from seed
the chances of bringing in hemp russet
and some of these other you know the
cannabis aphid
are really really high so i love the
idea of starting from
uh you know tissue culture plants
you know even at twenty dollars a clone
that's not that's kind of the market
rate
for clones in a lot of ways so you're
not really that uh that high
uh surprisingly yeah i mean the the you
know the prices i'm i'm talking about
are you know typically like
large-scale wholesale kind of production
for for commercial growers
i mean i think i think the you know the
retailer is probably going to tack on
what they tack on and
i think the number i've heard is you
know whatever whatever the typical
cult you know prices directly for a
cultivator it's usually going to end up
being about three times that by the time
it gets
to retail but yeah i think you know
ideally we can we can target
um some cultivars that you know maybe we
already produce that we can provide at
as little cost as possible for those
for those home growers all right fair
enough fair enough
um well uh that was sort of it for the
questions
i had regarding tissue culture i really
appreciate you uh
you know taking their time today to
answer some of them why is there
anything else that you wanted to add
before we uh sign off
yeah i think the only thing i'd want to
leave people with is to to maybe just
shift their thinking a little bit around
you know how a facility is laid out in
in cultivation where you know right now
the internal nursery side of the
business you know maybe takes up
anywhere from 10 to 25 percent of the
facility space
certainly takes a lot of bandwidth and
and
personnel and there's a lot of costs and
challenges around clone production
and you know what would that look like
if you know you didn't have to produce
any clones yourself all of that space
could be dedicated to
flowering you know well you know
additional veg space but also just more
flowering
space you know how would that impact
your business right if you
if you could take the space you have and
you know generate 10 20 30
more revenue generating product from
that and i think it's a
it's a weird shift for people just to
think about losing
what you know what feels like a piece of
a piece of the whole entity you know
that
the facility is but you know
take a look at other industries and
maybe don't be so scared of the idea
that you know maybe working with a
dedicated external nursery
slowly not all you know not not 100 to
start but
you know supplementing your existing
clone stock taking over some of your
clone production even if they can do it
cheaper or on par with what you're doing
and expand your production capacity
you know maybe that's a different way to
think about things and maybe that
might be something that's worth taking a
look at that's a
that's a really interesting point
thinking about how you know the amount
of
labor stress uh workflow
crop risk uh you know
chances of not having a clean plant all
of those things that come in
with a traditional cloning method that
we're also used to using in
in facilities it is a little bit of a
of a mental shift to consider some of
these other options so i'm glad you
brought that up
yo glad we could chat about this thanks
for having me on yeah well
like i said thanks for your time today
and i will be talking
with your colleague regarding viruses
too which i'm looking forward to another
another topic that i don't know a ton
about so um i thank you for your time
and what you're doing and i wish you the
best
you too ted take care all right talk to
you later bye
bye
[Music]
that was dr kevin mayer and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
i'm your host tadd hussey of kiss
organics don't forget to check out the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab then podcast
and if you want to support the podcast
you can do so by checking out the wide
variety of gardening products and soils
we have on our website
ranging from grassroot pots to custom
blue matte designs and premium organic
living soils that i formulated and have
been refining over the past decade also
if you haven't already please do take a
moment and leave us a comment or review
on whatever platform you listen on
i do take the time to read them all and
appreciate the feedback you can also
follow us on instagram at kis
organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening