foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics
the podcast where we discuss The Cutting
Edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
first off I want to say thank you to
everyone who has tuned into the podcast
I know some of you have been listening
since the very beginning and others are
still just finding the podcast I really
appreciate when folks Reach Out directly
or leave a rating in review I do read
them all or mention this to friends or
on social media it all really helps and
a big thank you to those of you who have
been able to support us on patreon as we
fired that back up and got new and
exclusive content for subscribers on
here
today's podcast is a little different
I've been listening to the Andrew
huberman podcast lately he's a
neuroscientist and professor at Stanford
University and he does a variety of
podcasts related to human health that
are worth checking out
anyway in addition to his regular
podcast interviews he does this extra
Series where he answers listener
questions and talks more in depth about
a variety of topics
the first 15 to 20 minutes of these
podcasts which he calls ask me anything
are available for free on the podcast
Channel and then you can subscribe to
his premium channel if you want to hear
the rest
well I have found in the course of all
my interviews I sometimes find topics
that I want to talk about more in depth
or share a deeper opinion on than I get
to in the podcast itself
sometimes the flow of the podcast
changes direction or it just doesn't fit
in the context of the interview but
regardless of the reason I thought a
format like this would allow me to both
share more information on the podcast as
well as further support and provide
value to the listeners Who currently
support our patreon Channel
also I found that in some of my earlier
interviews the information has changed
or I may not agree with everything that
was shared by a guest this will allow me
to go share an alternative Viewpoint or
perspective on a topic it takes me a
long time now to vet guests for the show
and while I'd like to release podcasts
more frequently I'd rather focus on
quality content rather than quantity
so in the spirit of this new idea I'll
be releasing some shorter podcasts on
here that will be just me talking about
a particular topic or answering
listeners submitted questions that I
think are really interesting or deserve
to be shared some of the topics I know
I'd like to cover already are
mycorrhizal fungi the use of teas and
cultivation like nutrient teas or
compost teas how water impacts
cultivation no-till in soilless media
science-based metrics for growing
cannabis and much more
this is all going to be additional
content and won't take away from we are
already doing with the podcast I promise
that all the guest interviews I do
outside of Kiss Organics will continue
to be free to access on the podcast
that's really important to us and a part
of our mission to share and provide
science-based education
and I'd also like to give you an update
with what's going on with kiss Organics
and my life
I'm finally ready to start growing at my
house I'm putting the finishing touches
on the HVAC which Dr Nadia Saba AKA Dr
Greenhouse gave me feedback on I
recorded that conversation and we did a
video walkthrough and I'll be sharing
that here soon too on our YouTube
channel
I have the electrical done finally
that's a whole other story on why it
took so long and we'll be hand watering
most of this first cycle but the goal is
to show the entire process of cannabis
cultivation from a science-based
perspective and really share and talk
about what we're doing and why there's
too many companies out there right now
that will show you how to grow using
only their products and frankly I think
many of the products are not necessary
and a total waste of money I want to
show you how to grow amazing plants with
minimal inputs and look forward to
starting that really soon
anyway today's topic for our first
podcast is the soil food web
this is a bit of a controversial topic
why I don't really know I think some
quote unquote experts have taken this
concept of microbial nutrient cycling or
the microbial Loop just way too far I
see this with a lot of methods or
beliefs in the organic gardening World
whether it's biodynamics Korean natural
farming soul food web mineral balancing
permaculture or some popular living soil
companies methods or ways folks get so
dogmatic about it it becomes part of
their identity and it starts to feel
more like a religion than a cultivation
method
but today on what I want to focus on is
the soul food web how does it work how
do we use our knowledge of the soil food
web to improve our gardening or
cultivation practices what can microbes
really do or not do in our soil for
instance can they prevent or eliminate
disease or help plants resist pest
pressure does the fungal to bacteria
ratio really matter or play a role in
soil health
you've probably heard the statistics
before and they're pretty unbelievable
that a mere teaspoon of soil contains
over a billion bacteria several yards of
fungal hyphae thousands of protozoa and
40 to 50 nematodes or more
so what is the soil food web
the soul food web represents the
community of organisms many of which are
microscopic that live in the soil and
are a part of the ecosystem
now why is it not the soil food chain
the idea being that one organism gets
eaten by another organism and this
continues in One Direction going from
one trophic level to another and on off
the chain well the reason it's called a
web is because of the complexity of
these processes
in addition because much of the soil
food web is microscopic it's been very
difficult to research and fully
understand in fact we are constantly
learning new things about how plants and
microorganisms interact in the soil
for example Jeff lowenfell's new book
teeming with bacteria I had him on here
as a guest if you want to learn more on
this topic discusses new research from
Dr James White on rhizophagy particular
bacteria called endophytes that are able
to move into the plant roots shed their
cellular walls release nutrients to the
plant and then move back out of the root
hair tips into the soil reform their
cellular walls where they can obtain
nutrients from the soil and then
potentially repeat the process
this is something we had no knowledge of
until 2008 when some researchers at the
University of Queensland discovered a
relationship between a particular
bacteria a non-pathogenic E coli and a
fungi saccharomyces cerevisiae also
known by most people is brewer's yeast
the soul food web is a dynamic
constantly changing ecosystem but the
concept is relatively simple
plants take in sunlight in the form of
photosynthesis and convert this to a
variety of different substances which
are then excreted as root exudates
these exudates are comprised of sugars
amino acids organic acids vitamins
enzymes and more these x8s not only feed
symbiotic bacteria and archaea but they
work to suppress pathogens by attracting
microorganisms that are antagonistic to
these pathogens
the exudates can adjust the pH of the
rhizosphere a fancy word for the area
around the roots so the pH could be
buffered into a range that is more
suitable for nutrient uptake that's one
of the reasons why organic Growers can
get away with growing in Greater pH
ranges than say a hydroponic grower
so the plant is releasing nutrients to
feed the microbes in the rhizosphere
these exudates are being consumed by the
bacteria and archae in the soil
our care are singer-celled in organisms
that initially were classified as
bacteria and originally discovered in
deep sea vents they were able to survive
in places where no life was thought to
exist
now we know they exist everywhere not
just in the soil and the ocean but even
in our stomachs and on our skin and have
a variety of roles very similar to
bacteria so from here on out when I
mention bacteria you can safely assume
that I'm talking about archaea too
getting back to the soil food web though
these bacteria are essentially consuming
the root exudates and then some of what
they excrete back into the soil is plant
available nutrients meaning it's an
ionic form like phosphate or nitrate
identical to what we are adding when we
use chemical fertilizers
now some of these bacteria are being
eaten by larger microorganisms like
bacteria feeding nematodes or
flagellates or ciliates a bacteria
feeding nematode can feed on up to 5 000
bacterial cells per day which is six and
a half times their own body weight what
they then poop out or excrete is plant
available nutrients as well this process
is called the microbial Loop or referred
to as nutrient cycling
now in addition to all of this bacteria
and fungi play major roles as primary
decomposers they release enzymes to
break down organic matter into inorganic
forms so that these elements and
molecules can be released and recycled
this is how composting works and why
organic matter is so important to soils
taking it a step further when organic
matter becomes humus it is a more stable
form of organic matter and it is no
longer identifiable as to what the
original source of organic matter was
whether it was Leaf litter a dead animal
or an old shoe microscopically it's been
broken down to be indistinguishable but
organic matter in humus is probably its
own podcast
so the big takeaways are that one the
soul food web is complex and dynamic and
constantly changing
two it's the primary way a plant
receives nutrients in an organic system
called nutrient cycling and three these
microbes have roles in protecting the
plant from pathogens and disease
creating soil structure and much much
more
so the soil food web and microbes in
general are very important in our soils
and soilless media when we are
cultivating using a method like living
soils which technically is not a soil
and I don't want to understand how
important the soil food web is to
healthy plants I think it's crucial in
all my gardening practices take into
account how they would impact the
microbes in my soil
and again this was not meant to be
exhaustive or comprehensive explanation
of the soil food web but I wanted to
give you a foundation that would help
explain why don't subscribe to
everything that's being put out there by
folks calling themselves soil food web
consultants and what I think the limits
are to what microbes can consistently
and reliably offer us in our garden
so let's talk about some of the basic
concepts or practices we can do to
encourage and support the soul food web
in our soils
this is pretty straightforward
maintaining optimal moisture levels is
the absolute most important thing you
can do for microbial life and activity
in your soil
water is so critical to not just plants
and animals but to microbes as well sure
microbes have strategies for dealing
with drought such as insisting or going
dormant but if we want to keep nutrients
cycling then we want to keep the
microbes alive and happy and if you're
Watering your plants correctly this is
really not an issue if soil is just
sitting without a plant in it and I tell
folks it's still treated like it has a
plant and keep watering it accordingly
if it does dry out say in a bed or a pot
then I suggest adding a handful or two
of organic alfalfa meal or watering with
a tablespoon per gallon of water with
unsulfured blackstrap molasses something
to get the microbes more active prior to
planting but as long as you remember
that your soil or soil mix is alive and
treated as such you should be fine
the next thing is using high quality
compost or earthworm castings
without going too deep as it's deserving
of its own podcast just know that you
want to use compost or castings that are
high in biological diversity and overall
microbial biomass but also with a
balanced mineral content and there's
ways of testing for some of that but
don't think that all compost is created
equal and you can get in a lot of
trouble for using bad compost either
that's not fully composted or may
contain things that you don't want like
herbicides or pesticides that have not
fully broken down in the composting
process or even things like weed seeds
which can be really annoying compost can
also contain harmful pathogens so
understanding what the inputs are and
how it's made is really important you
really have to trust your source
and then one last thing I'd like to
highlight is soil disturbance tilling
soils can be very destructive to soil
structure and soil biology there are
times when I think it's necessary to
till but let's not confuse tilling with
a mechanical tiller to what we may have
to do in a bed with digging in nutrients
they are not the same thing I have a
whole blog on this topic on our website
if you want to read more
and some Souls of disturbance may be
beneficial to the Ecology of your soil
not all disturbance is a bad thing it
adds benefits too like the potential to
encourage microbial diversity just know
that microbes play a big role in soil
structure and we want to support that
process
oh and if you can always keep a plant in
your soil this will encourage healthy
microbial communities due to the
relationship between the plant and its
ability to continue tributing to
nutrient cycling as I mentioned in the
beginning of this podcast
so why is any of this controversial it
seems pretty straightforward right and
it is everything that I shared above has
been established and is generally
accepted by soil scientists universally
now here's where it gets a bit more
complicated
alright so that was the first part of my
podcast on the soil food web I hope you
found it interesting and apologies for
the vocal quality I'm recovering from
covet as I record this and I'm still a
bit stuffed up and out of breath if you
want to hear the full podcast the rest
of it is available on our patreon
Channel where you can sign up for as
little as five dollars a month and we
have a ton of benefits including monthly
Hangouts with the kiss crew extra
podcast content immediate podcast
release and many other perks you can
find it by searching for the podcast
name or under our company name kiss
Organics
this is the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast and I'm your host Tad
Hussey stay tuned for exciting future
podcasts on an organic cloning solution
and our trials with it and a new
granular Bavaria product that I'm super
excited about let me know your thoughts
on this additional podcast content as
well thanks for listening
foreign