foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics
the podcast where we discuss The Cutting
Edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is Dr Wendy Zellner
Dr Zellner received her doctorate from
the University of Toledo in 2012 where
she trained in molecular and cellular
biology focusing on the role of silicon
and plant defense responses
upon graduation she pursued a four-year
postdoctoral position with the USDA ARS
where she continued studying the role of
silicon and alleviating both abiotic and
biotic stress in tomato and tobacco her
current studies are to design standard
methods for quantifying the uptake of
silicon from fertilizer material in
addition to identifying uptake
mechanisms for silicon in model species
and testing for similar Pathways and
other crops
I learned a ton from Wendy in this
podcast and it got me excited to do more
plant trials utilizing silicon so in
conjunction with the release of this
podcast we are offering discounts on the
two main silica products that we carry
at kiss Organics egg cell 16h and will
last a night for a limited time now on
to the show hi Wendy thanks for coming
on the show today
good afternoon how are you doing
well thank you for having me yeah
wonderful I'm so excited this is a topic
that I've been wanting to cover for a
very long time but it is shockingly
difficult to find a true resource and
expert on Silicon so tell me a little
bit about yourself and uh we'll start
there
okay
um I
um am from Northwest Ohio born and
raised in the midwest I didn't come from
an agriculture background but always had
a love for nutrition and disease and
really started to get into Plant
Nutrition in high school and then in
college really got into the cellular
molecular aspects of things and so I was
fortunate enough after
graduation to get a position with USDA
ARS where I was able to study the role
of silicon and disease in a much broader
sense where I was exposed to the
Horticulture and floor culture industry
and it was really as we've been
exploring this seeing how important
silicon is as a plant nutrient
especially with how it pertains to plant
Health really pushed me to pursue it
even further and so I've been really
active with different regulatory bodies
and different groups to really get the
correct education of silicon out there
and what it is and how to use it
correctly
that's that's wonderful I I know you've
done a number of podcasts now there's a
lot of resources if people Google your
name
um
for this podcast I want to lay a little
bit of a foundation before we dive into
the real uh you know meet of the topic
here so can you start off telling us
just a little bit about what what is
silicon
definitely so silicon as an element
um we've refer to it as silicon it is uh
the second most available or the second
most abundant element that's in our
soils the problem is the amounts that we
need for plant uptake is very very low
fraction of that so
with that
um as we've been growing plants in soil
or as we have them in soilless media and
hydroponic system the amount of the
plant available silicon that's there is
actually really really low and just like
any other nutrient it has specific uses
by different plants so with that we've
really been trying to understand why
plants take up the amount of silicon
that they have and what they're actually
using the element for and so there's a a
couple different terms for silicon that
are kind of thrown out there so when we
talk about silicon we're talking about
the element then we have the silicates
which is usually when it's associated
with something like calcium or potassium
salicylic acid is the plant available
form and then you have other forms of
silicon like silicone which is used in
other Industries and so what's really
interesting about this element is we use
it in our everyday life we use it for
things like electronics for abrasives
and toothpaste for
Cosmetics additives even for our own
health people take silicon supplements
for their hair the nails cartilage
reduce wrinkles so this nutrient we have
been taking advantage of both in our
physical life and our health life and
the plants do with the same thing and
we've all evolved to use this highly
abundant element in different ways and
so really everything that we're trying
to educate on Silicon all of this
knowledge has been present in the
literature and we've known about a lot
of this for centuries and we're just
trying to put it together in an easier
way to explain it and when we start
talking about silicon in the terms of
nutrients it really takes
um kind of that weird
anomaly that people use to try and
describe what silicon is and puts it
into a much easier understandable
um Realm
of topics
so you mentioned uh silicate is the form
when we have talked about something like
potassium silicate or silicate um
that breaks down to salicylic acid and
then that's what's actually available to
the plant
is that correct correct so yes with the
silicates the so it's a cation the
calcium potassium or sodium keep the
silicon and oxygen from interacting with
one another because silicon loves to
interact with itself and if they didn't
have these other
elements present then it would form an
amorphous
um almost like a gel and not always a
gel but an amorphous group of silicone
compounds that the plant can't absorb so
it only absorbs those single units of
salicylic acid and so by having
uh potassium calcium or sodium in that
formulation it helps keep more of them
in smaller units that the plant can then
take up just like any of our other
nutrients nitrate phosphate they all
have different forms that the plants are
able to absorb through different
mechanisms silicon is very similar and
we know salicylic acid is that form
that's the one that we're looking for to
be transported by the plants
so you mentioned that amorphous forms
are unavailable
um
can can we jump ahead actually here and
I want to come back to the benefits but
can we talk about some of these forms so
when I think of potassium silicate uh
starting there that's probably the most
common I'm familiar with it's you know
in dynago protect uh egg cell 16h
um
can can you talk a little about that and
then maybe we can go to like calcium
silicate silica sand diatomaceous earth
you know these these sources that like
pop into my head as a grower of silica
yep and so really the word amorphous
versus crystalline
um when silicon's in an amorphous form
it it's going to be more easily broken
down in salicylic acid than a
crystalline form so we can think of
Crystal like um like a diamond is highly
crystallized carbon and you know it's
very strong and so when we think of the
crystallized form of silicon that is
what quartz is in the sand so it's a
very strong crystalline it's going to
take a long time for us to get those
salicic acid units to break apart from
that structure with the amorphous
structure it's a much more relaxed
structure usually with a larger surface
area so we have more of that silicon
that can come off of salicylic acid
so but at the same time not all
amorphous forms of silicon have the same
release rate so it gets a little bit
tricky there when we think of
crystalline versus amorphous
now when we get to the potassium
silicates even though
um when I think of amorphous silicon I
think of a group like what's present in
the grasses or the phytolus or the Opals
or the biogenic silicon that's deposited
within a plant where it's a larger
amount of
silicone deposited and that is not what
is present in these potassium silicates
um whether they're in solution or in a
dry powdered form
with that the Silicon is in much smaller
subunits and a lot of it is
kept within that single salicic acid
unit so the release rate from a
potassium silicate is going to be a lot
higher than say a release rate from Rice
Halls which have a biogenic amorphous
form of the Silicon that's present there
and so we can think of these potassium
and calcium and sodium silicates as
having
a salicic acid fraction which is a
certain percent of that and then small
amounts are either one or two silicon
group together in like a dimer or small
polymers that can be released into that
salicylic acid for plant uptake
so I actually stated that incorrectly
the amorphous is the more available form
for those listening um and
one thing I was worried about when we
were when I first started using
potassium silicate was
um
I believe the term is silicosis
um how dangerous
is it to breathe
these sorts of things as you're
utilizing them from a grower perspective
how careful do we need to be with PPE
and things like that
so with silicosis that usually is due to
the particle size the particle size is
the biggest thing that you need to look
into with that for the most part for
something
to be small enough to be inhaled deep
enough into our lungs we're looking at a
particle size less than five
uh I think it's five
yeah I want to say nanometers or microns
it might be five microns
um but it and it is is so when you have
a very very small particle size
um and the other thing is it's
crystalline silica that does this and
it's because
um within the lungs the macrophages try
to engulf it
um and get rid of it and it's not able
to and then it causes
um
scarring and release of hydrogen and
there's a whole disease process that's
associated with it however when we look
at the Silicon materials that are on the
market as a fertilizer and specifically
looking at the dry material that have a
higher incidence of dust and inhalation
these particle sizes are much much
higher than the crystalline size that is
associated with asbestos and other small
silicone compounds that would cause
silicosis
um or mesothelioma so a lot of the
products that are out there as a
fertilizer they pass
safety tests because they are a larger
particle size and they won't be inhaled
deep into the lung to cause that type of
reaction
that's good to know that makes me feel a
little bit better I still want to be
careful when mixing these yes well and
that's with anything that's going to
form a dust it and it doesn't matter
whether it's Clay whether you know all
products that form a dusk a dust they do
suggest wearing a mask and reducing that
inhalation
but in the form of the scoliosis it's
really dependent on the particle size
and the crystalline form of the Silicon
that's in there
now in terms of the the silicates is one
better than the other if we're comparing
potassium calcium or sodium
in terms of uh honestly salicylic acid
salicylic acid
so in terms of
um a silicone fertilizer if you apply
any of those at the same salicylic acid
concentration you're going to get the
same silicon response I have not seen
any tests yet that would
so that one formulation is going to
outperform another based on whether it's
a calcium sodium or potassium
what you need to think about though is
for instance with the calcium silicates
they can release calcium oxide and it
might have an effect on ph which you
might need or you might not want
with the Sodium silicates every if
you're worried about
raising sodium levels that's always a
concern but with the concentration of
the salicylic acid that we're putting
into these systems the amount of sodium
that's coming along with it is very very
small and so even though there's that
potential there you can kind of you need
to be aware at what concentration the
sodium is really going in so you're not
really adding that sodium stress that
some people shy away from the sodium
silicates from
that makes sense yeah that reminds me of
the idea of with
table salt versus uh Himalayan salt the
amount of trace minerals in there is so
minimal that we really probably aren't
getting
uh as much of a health benefit as people
claim
um versus using you know straight
calcium chloride so it's all about right
concentrations I guess is the point
correct um
yeah so moving on uh you know I went to
a trade show quite a few years ago and
there was a company selling uh silica
sand and they claimed this was a great
source of uh silica for your plant and
and my first question to them and I'm
fairly ignorant on on Silicon was
um you know when does this become
available to my plant and they didn't
really have an answer they said there's
a lot of variables associated with that
um
what would what would you think about a
product like that in uh cultivation
scenario when we would want
the you know the salicylic acid Within
you know period of a cultivation period
of let's say weeks to months
right so and that's that's really what
it comes down to is is it a soil
additive or soil amendment or is it a
silicon fertilizer so when we think of a
silicone fertilizer that means it's
going to release enough salicylic acid
through that single growing season
um and you know if it provides more the
next or the third growing season awesome
you have an added benefit versus the
soil amendment which is something that
you're putting in to help rebuild the
Silicon pools within the soil which
really is not something that you would
do if you're in the soilless media or
more of a Horticulture floor culture
type of production system
so when we look at things like these
sand additives
the test that I've run on the products
that we have that are more of the
crystalline sand have not shown any
release rate of salicylic acid that
would provide enough silicon for any of
the plants that we use during a growing
season
however if we were to work that into say
a soil system where you have microbes
that can actually weather crystalline
forms of silica that would be present in
sand material or more
um highly structured amorphous material
that may work as an additive and you
might see benefits from that over years
but from what I've done we haven't
really seen much of a benefit using
those types of products so one thing I
would ask those companies is to show
information where they grew plants with
and without and they saw an increase in
foliar silicon with that treatment that
would be an indication that the material
would provide silicon to the plants
I mean that seems like a reasonable
standard for for a company
um you know a lot of times you'll just
see side-by-side photos but there can be
so many other variables associated with
that so correct yep and that's the thing
it could improve water drainage it could
improve so many other physical barriers
that the response they're showing you in
those photos is not a silicon response
but showing that they see a difference
in Silicon concentration in the foliar
tissue that suggests that it does
release silicon and you may have some of
the benefits that are mentioned in the
literature
wonderful well in a kind of a similar
product would be diatomaceous earth can
you talk a little bit about uh that as
well
yes so
um I haven't again I've just done
extraction studies with diatomaceous
earth it does come in lower
um so when I say extraction studies
similar to how they determine what uh
the water soluble nutrients are we have
right now A extraction that we use to
determine if there's plant available
silicon in that and so we call it just
shorthand of the five-day method so
that's what I'll be referring to as so
with this five-day method in the
diatomaceous earth we do see that it
provides
um at least 0.2 percent silicon which is
2 000 parts per million
um and what our application that we
suggest is anywhere from 60 uh 30 to 60
parts per million in a soilless system
and so with it coming in at 2000 it does
have a potential to be a silicon source
for uh both the Horticulture and
soilless type Medias or for soil as a
soil amendment however it probably has a
better advantage or if you have the
crust microbes in your soilless mix that
could help release even more of the
Silicon that's present so not all the
Silicon that's present within the
diatomaceous earth is going to be
released in some situations but you
could encourage that release depending
on what's present within your growing
environment
so d e does have some potential then you
think in in soilless media
um
what I do think it does it warrants it
definitely warrants more studies
wonderful I mean it's a very affordable
Source
um what so do you know what percentage
of salicylic acid
um we we could expect or how would it
compare to like a silicate application
um so it's going to be much lower
um with some of the calcium silicate
products that we use it releases about a
one percent silicon when you get into
things like will last the night that's
up to
with the five day extraction anywhere
from four to six percent silicon so it's
at a much lower range and you would have
to add more of the product into the mix
to get to those silicon levels
um but then again depending on what it
is you're growing that's going to
dictate how much silicon you actually
need additionally in that growing media
so for some
um fruits or vegetables the diatomaceous
earth might be great whereas for your
plants that accumulate silicon to the
levels of calcium potassium or nitrogen
you might need to bump it up with other
sources or use a combination of sources
for those
higher feeders
now in this case the podcast is focused
more for cannabis or hemp production How
would
I mean I know cannabis hyper accumulates
it seems like everything
um how have you seen any research in
relation to silica
um there have been some and this
actually came out I did get some
information from uh Dave who's part of
the dynago group and they did tissue
analysis for cannabis and so it comes in
about two percent SI so it's up there
above the calcium
at potassium and nitrogen that's how
much silicon those plants need and so
when we get into stuff like cannabis but
then even there's floor culture plants
verbena which takes up two percent in
Lantana these plants take up such a high
amount that you need to make sure it's
present within the media at a high
release rate because they continually
take it up well while they're growing
and while they're maturing so unlike
other plants that take up certain
amounts only during certain times of
their maturation these plants that hyper
accumulate silicon tend to take it up
continuously throughout their life cycle
and so they need a continuous supply of
it in order for them
to benefit and have the best health and
the best production that's available
yeah I realize we haven't talked about
the benefits yet I still want to hold on
that one because I had a couple more
questions now that we dove into this um
so in in regards to
um
you mentioned with application rates how
important it is that it's a consistent
application do we need to worry about
toxicities or excesses with silicon in
relation to plants if it is a
essentially a nutrient
so with it it is a nutrient um and
hopefully we'll get it to that status
here soon in the U.S but all that aside
one of the most amazing things about
silicon compared to all the other
elements is I believe it is one of the
most regulated and the most
well-regulated nutrients that are
present
plants only take up and absorb the
amount of silicon that they can deal
with at that time so what that means is
unlike nitrogen and phosphate copper and
all of our other nutrients we do not see
phytotoxicity symptoms from over
fertilizing with silicon
um so even if you're growing a plant's a
wide variety of plants some that are
hyper accumulators some that accumulate
at the micronutrient level you can apply
the same concentration to all those
plants and you're not going to see
negative effects the only instance in
the literature where they do so
um
abnormal floral development is when they
were applying a really high
concentration of a liquid silicon is a
drench
um and they what I think was happening
is it was tying up low levels of either
nick nickel or zinc in the growth media
and so they were having a metal induced
efficiency but at those levels they are
well above the recommended level of any
fertilizer that's here so as long as
you're following the label rights and
um the fertilizer recommendations that
are on the packages that type of
um
a metal deficiency should not occur with
application
wonderful well finishing up
um these the sources conversation we you
mentioned biogenic sources one of those
being uh rice holes I know you've you've
mentioned off air to me that there are
other potential sources uh that are that
you can derive silicon from can you talk
a little bit about these as a category
and then more specifically rifles
yeah
um sir so obvious there are lots of
plants um especially within the grass
and Grains that take up high amounts of
silicon and they do so because they're
actually depositing it into uh epidermal
cells or cells that are on the outside
of the leaf tissue and so with these
deposits as the leaves go back into the
soil this helps regenerate that silicon
cycle and helps break down and provide
silicon and so a lot of different plants
have different mechanisms to get silicon
up into foliar tissue whether it's the
epidermal cells trichomes
um and then as those fall back down to
the ground it can be released so we can
take advantage of the plants that take
high concentrations of that like rice so
when it goes into the rice halls and I
sorry I don't have the number in front
of me but it's a I think between 40 and
50 percent of the nutrients that are
present is silicon and so it's a great
source but only if those rice plants are
grown and fertilized with silicon and so
when we think of other things
um wheat straw another great source but
the problem with wheat is you can also
get some pathogen carryover
um miscanthus has been tested bamboo
um
I'm kind of uh people are looking into
horsetail
and some other of these really high
accumulating species to see how they can
incorporate either that vegetation as a
compost
um with the rice halls I know we were
doing some work with the USDA where we
were making the rice Halls into a
biochar and seen really get great
responses
um and using it that way and with the
rice Halls too they are starting to look
at extracting the silicon and making
almost a nano silicon material from the
rice halls and so getting rid of
everything else and strictly using it
for a silicon source
there are other
um
biogenic forms though such as in pine
needles surprisingly enough Piney
needles have a really really high
concentration of silicon but due to the
chemical composition it doesn't break
down and release over time so even
though there's a lot there the phenolics
and everything do not make it a viable
source to incorporate or get any of the
Silicon benefits out of those pine
needles
um so there are options out there that
can help
as a more natural source but the main
thing to be aware of is how was that
Source material grown with silicon used
in the production because if it wasn't
and it's on land that had been
cultivated for a long time the Silicon
values are not going to be as high as
they should be from the trials that were
published in the literature
so you're actually seeing pretty big
variants there so we can't just assume
that because they're rice holes they're
going to be
high in Silicon for example
correct correct and as with rice holes
being a waste or a byproduct well a
byproduct waste in essence
they are not currently to my knowledge I
don't think anyone goes through and
there's no guaranteed analysis on what
the Silicon composition are of the rice
Falls and so it's really
um unless you're there you're doing that
on your own to ensure that you are
getting that silicon out of the rice
Halls it's it's kind of one of those
things that it could be hit or miss and
that could be why some people who have
tried using rice Halls to incorporate
and have not been seen the responses
are not seeing the responses because
that silicon isn't there like it is
um in some of the earlier trials where
we were making sure that the starting
material were fed silicon
I think that's a really important point
because I see these charts uh floating
around the internet of a variety of
different um
nutrient values for everything from
you know various manures fish uh fish
meal Alfalfa whatever
but people don't take into account like
what that animal ate
um you know what what it actually
accumulated and so it's important I
think for folks to consider testing
their sources or this is where
guaranteed analysis uh comes into play
and labeling um which we will talk about
as well
um wonderful now
the I think we should probably get into
why the heck people would want to use
Silica in their Garden
um in the first place I I kind of jumped
ahead of you there
um let's talk about all the benefits
okay well there there are quite a few
benefits especially if you are growing
under silicon deficient type situations
so really what silicon is best known for
is to mitigate stress or to reduce
stress in a plant's life and plants are
constantly
under changing environmental condition
um microbial attack test attack insect
herbivore lots of things are going on
that they're trying to compensate with
changes in water from you know over
watering to underwatering
so with all of this when we start
putting silicon back into the system
what happens is the plant is now able to
better manage the stress it has a more
balanced environment and it's doing this
number one what we're starting to see is
when we start feeding silicon it can set
up the barriers that are present within
the roots that can help hold the water
in and it can help reduce the
transpiration or the water loss through
the leaves
and so by maintaining that water
constantly within the plant what that
does is it helps maintain a more
balanced concentration of all the other
nutrients that are there it helps dilute
out waste products so it's just having
that water response helps the plants
just better deal with everything this
also helps them cool faster less
susceptibility
to heat stress less susceptibility to
Drought stress but then on top of that
we also know that silicon is involved in
a lot of the enzymatic reactions so when
we get a pathogen attack or a heavy
metal toxicity silicon can help offset
what's going on within the cell and help
the immune system respond more rapidly
when it comes to say a pathogen disease
or it can also not just help with
reducing the enzymatic stress from
having too many or heavy metals in there
it can also keep the metals from
actually making it into the cytoplasm
where it's having its effect
so I apologize I got a little bit deep
there but really the responses of
silicon
is the plants can deal with changes to
the environment so whether it's hot or
cold wet or dry
too much salt too much sun it can also
help when we have
toxicities which you might not see too
much in your garden but you know if
you're using some of the copper
pesticides you might see responses it
can help mitigate against that
the main thing that a lot of people see
though is disease reduction especially
when we talk about our mildews or our
bacterial diseases and that is the one
coolest thing that you can see that we
don't talk a lot about when we talk
about fertilizers because then they want
to label silicon as a pesticide but it's
not it's a nutrient because it's not
acting directly on the pathogen but it's
reducing that
um infection process and so if you're
dealing with a lot of mildews or
bacteria botrytis root rot silicon can
help the plant have a better response a
better immune system and so those are
where you're going to see more of a
visual response when it comes to Silicon
so essentially you're saying there's
research related to fungal pathogens
bacterial as well as insects
yes yep and viruses so every so and
that's you know people think that it's
too good to be true
um one thing I really want to point out
silicon is involved in all of these but
all of these responses are not directly
due to Silicon it's due to how silicon
is bringing the internal
um environment within the plant into a
balance and so it's allowing the
genetics that are already there to
perform to the best ability that they
can and so that's where silicon looks
like it's affecting all of these but
really what silicon is doing is it's
balancing the plant out so the plants
own responses can perform to the best
potential that's there
so using silicon your garden doesn't
necessarily mean you're not going to see
botrytus and
spider mites and a variety of other
issues but you may see less pronounced
damage or
it it greatly reduces these responses
and so that's where we we start talking
about
um you can if you go in and you're using
any type of
um if you're using a pesticide or a
chemical to help control what we see is
you can use less of that chemical you
can use less of these synthetic
responses because now you have a more
robust
biological response by the plant the
same um like if you're using beneficial
insects or another means to deal with
this if you don't have silicon you're
you're missing out on a huge part of
disease resistance or health for those
plants and so by bringing silicon in
it's going to help your itm strategies
um be a lot stronger and you can start
reducing costs on some of those
components depending on what it is that
you're
using to combat some of these issues
so
kind of
you know going off of that how do we
best apply
these silicon products
you know some are going to be applied
directly to our soil some are used as a
foliar application
um
does it make a difference in terms of
how we apply it like let's say I know
I'm starting to see but try this should
I be doing foliar applications of a
silicate product versus
counting on there being sufficiency in
my soil mix
so the great thing is um what I tell
Growers and Farmers apply it the best
way that you can work it into your
system
whether you're applying it so obviously
if you have a solid product you're going
to want to incorporate into the media or
the soil with the liquid products you
can apply either as a drench or foliar
application
and we're still seeing benefits from
both how the mechanisms are likely going
to be different between a foliar
application and a root application but
however you can get that silicon into
your system is going to help the plants
respond to that what's nice about
applying it as a drench when we're
talking about liquids is it can be taken
up through the root system and
transported all throughout the plant so
we know with silicon similar to calcium
and copper and some of our other
nutrients it doesn't load into the
phloem so it moves through the xylem
tissue which means once you apply it to
a leaf it's not going to move out of
that leaf into other areas of the plant
and so that's why with the foliar
applications you have to do a continual
foliar application so that the new
growing
um tissue has a silicon present for its
Developmental and um
Health needs
and so
even with that though we do there are
benefits that are shown in the
literature with foliar application and
definitely with using these materials as
a drench so
depending on the product itself they may
suggest one application versus the other
but it really comes down to what's going
to be best to get it into your system
um to help combat that so even if it is
a foliar pathogen moving up through the
root system it's going to get into the
internal portion of the leaf and help
have that response because it's coming
from an internal response it's not
coming from a physical barrier that's
just being formed on that leaf surface
it's happening inside that leaf
foreign
that was exactly what I wanted to hear
thank you so much for sharing that
um so we can do soil drenches
essentially and still effectively treat
disease in a reasonable time frame
um for plant response
all of my studies that I have done as a
graduate student and with USDA we're
using silicon as it drives I'm just now
this year starting to get into looking
at what effects full your application
has on some of these responses
well that that leads me to a conundrum
here I want to talk about
um
you know you mentioned foliar versus
soil drench and that makes me think of
potassium silicate and the labeling laws
around it
um but then I also want to talk about
heavy metals which would you like to
cover
first
um let's talk about heavy metals and
then we'll get into the legalities of
everything okay perfect all right well
yeah talk to me about heavy metals and
um you know some of these sources
I and and how that might be uh something
that Growers should be thinking about
yep so
um going back to the Rice hall
um talk and how we want to make sure
that these materials silicons present in
that the same with our plants if we have
these hyper accumulators and we aren't
providing silicon
they're craving the silicon and it's
kind of like you going into your kitchen
late at night craving chocolate and
there's no chocolate in the house so
what happened well and I shouldn't say
you I'm gonna it's me it's really me
that does this I.E everything that's
present whether it's sweet whether it's
salty trying to get that chocolate fix
so when we think about plants that are
hyper accumulators they are trying to
get that silicon so they're turning on
different transport mechanisms trying to
scavenge any part of silicon out of that
system and with that what we do is we
get an imbalance of nutrients in the
plants phosphate's one of them but the
sad part about it is arsenic cadmium
some of these other heavy metals can
also be taken up
and with arsenic Arsenic and silicon
have very similar
um
chemical features they're very close on
they're right next door to each other on
the periodic table and so one of the
downsides that we know with rice is
silicon's not present it will pull
arsenic out of the soil profile and
people might not be aware of it but we
have quite a bit of there's arsenic
there's heavy metals there's all sorts
sorts of what we call contaminants that
are naturally occurring in the soil and
for the most part the plants don't take
them up because they have plenty of the
nutrients that they need but when we get
into these hyper accumulators the
Arsenic will move up to where the
silicon's opposed to so when we have
something like rice halls and we're
starting to use that as our silicon
fertilizer we can start in
unintentionally be putting arsenic again
likely at low levels into our profile
but if we're growing plants in a silicon
limited environment they are going to
pull that arsenic out and bioaccumulate
and specifically for the Cannabis
industry this is a big concern because
of the high amount of silicon that they
take up they are desperately trying to
get that silicon in any way that they
can and I think this is where a lot of
the issues with the higher arsenic
levels that were seen or the higher
um heavy metals that are being taken up
into the plant because they don't have
those mechanisms in place that the
Silicon would have used to reduce the
movement of those Metals into uh the
cell and into other parts of the plant
and that's the same that we see not just
for cannabis but for a lot of the other
plants as well
is as soon as we start putting silicon
into the system we see a reduction in
um the phytotoxicity of these Metals if
we are on a contaminated soil and so
they can kind of outgrow those negative
responses and still provide a quality
plant or a quality fruit
well that's a real Gem of information
that we may be able to increase silicon
in our plant tissue as a way of reducing
heavy metal uptake
um
right that's fascinating it's something
that I'm going to have to do some more
testing and research on myself because
it's it's a real challenge in cannabis
like you mentioned um
and you know I do see a lot of Growers
and soil suppliers using rifles in their
mix and
um you know many of them are testing
their soil mixes which is great I mean
if you use I assume if you use like a
acid extraction for heavy metals you
would be able to a strong acid you'd be
able to see what is potentially in there
but um one thing I want to go back to is
you mentioned that because rice holes
are a waste product there's no
guaranteed analysis so we could get
quite a bit of variability batch to
batch so unless you're testing every
every batch I don't see how you could
really determine your levels of arsenic
that you're bringing in every time you
mix it into your soil
well and the other thing so I don't want
to scare people away from Rice Halls
saying that it has arsenic I'm but the
potential is there and even what you
have to it could even be a trace level
that's not even detectable
but when you have a hyper accumulator
it's going to bioaccumulate very very
small amounts that might be there just
as a very you know background no
chemical is a hundred percent so even if
it's at that point zero zero one percent
it's going to be able to find it and
Pull It in trying to
satisfy that silicon need within the
plant
and so that's that's where the issue
comes from it's not that there's High
contamination of arsenic coming in it's
that that background amount that's there
that's no different than what's out in
our natural soil system that we
naturally have you know around us every
single day it just gets accumulated in
these species because it's trying to
find the Silicon
and that's where why it's you know we
consider these hyper accumulators
um that can be used for bioremediation
silicon is one of those elements that
it's going to hyper accumulate but if
that's not there it's going to find
something else to take its place
yeah I think it's more we're always just
looking for a potential vectors are
because I I find water to be one of the
biggest factors soil dust that's kicked
into facilities can oftentimes bring it
in
um water and contact with Metals
especially RO water yep we see so so
there's a variety of other things not to
single out rifles but it is something
that I think right people should be
thinking about when with all of their
inputs but especially these ones like
you said that could hyper accumulate
right
yeah and you know that's brings you back
to the adage that you know as you're
trying to do something that's a more
natural source you still have to be
careful because natural doesn't always
mean the safest Source or the best
source
um and so it's just understanding where
that natural source is coming from and
what's present in there and what's
lacking in there
yeah now
that made me think of something else
does the pH of your media affect your
silica uptake
like with other nutrients that is
an awesome question
uh I would say that's kind of a loaded
question
um and in that I main thing I and I
don't know
um I'm not sure of studies that have
looked specifically at pH and uptake
um because and I'm thinking in more of a
soilless media where you don't have that
buffer capacity really within that the
plant is the major driver of what that
pH of the media is and I know you know
um and growing systems really work hard
to maintain it within a certain th range
um So within those heavily regulated pH
ranges
um you're going to get the same probably
I don't think it'll have as large of an
effect because the solubility of silicon
between I think it's like four and nine
is going to be the same throughout so
you're not going to get into a situation
where it's below four at least in
soilless you know you might in acidic
soils or above nine and So within that
range there's really
very little difference if any in the
availability of maintaining silicon in
that 60 PPM or 2 millimolar
concentration
I mean if you're outside that PH range
you have other problems at that point
trying to grow plants right yeah there
yeah you're going to be yeah this really
doesn't
it really does sound like a miracle uh
element
um
in a lot of ways the way you're
describing it
um
so I I think this is a good transition
into sort of the labels and products on
the market because
um
there's there's challenges around
labeling and I think it's really hard as
a grower to know how to compare uh can
we start off just talking a little bit
about potassium silicate because it's
the one I'm most familiar with now it's
approved in organic production uh as
certain applications can you kind of
explain the the regulation around it
sure
um so all silicon uh products here in
the U.S including the potassium
silicates
um are regulated through
um
the fertilizer biostimulants soil
amendments
um
portion of the state regulation so it's
regulated at the state level the
American Association of plant food
control officials or APCO is the
governing body that gives
recommendations to the States but then
it's up to each individual state to
determine
um how if they accept those
recommendations or if they have their
own slight changes to that and so that's
where some of these labels that we see
in some states such as the California
Washington and Oregon might look a
little different than some of the other
midwest states
and that can add to some of the
confusion especially when it comes to
Silicon as it has just recently within
the past 15 20 years been a regulated
fertilizer within this group
So currently the avco recommendations
are that when a silicon fertilizer is
labeled it's labeled with the percent
silicon so just percent s i and that's
based off of that five-day extraction
method I mentioned earlier so what that
tells us is the amount of salicylic acid
that we can expect to be released from
that material
the problem with this is it was
developed for our solid materials and
not our liquid materials so from a solid
material basis what we tend to see is
that the percent silicon that they put
on the label for the solid tends to
overestimate the amount that we see in
plant grow out trials so
um it tells us there's a higher number
than what's actually released within
that growing cycle for grass whereas
with the liquid products the percent
that we see is lower than what we
actually see from the uptake within the
plants so it tends to underestimate
liquids and overestimate solids can you
explain what an example of a liquid in a
solid is
um okay yep in this case so for instance
the and correct me if I'm wrong here
um
the is it the egg okay
is that a solid or a liquid
okay so with the potassium okay the egg
cell with the solid egg cell sorry yes
okay uh so egg cells of powder that's
yep 100 soluble that
um like for example we mix with water uh
as a way of okay creating a a liquid
solution so that's where I was kind of
confused in terms of how you're defining
these things
yep so with that since it's applied as a
liquid that would be it would fall
likely under the liquid so most of the
potassium silicates we work with are
already in the liquid form that we
purchase from a distributor when we talk
about solids these are things like the
diatomaceous earth will last the night
um there's ignumberite the sand material
all of these that are more solid
components that would be a soil or a
media incorporation are what we refer to
as solid and then we have a number of
different silicon liquid silicon
products we have potassium silicates we
have some that we really don't even know
the source of
um that refer back to the monosulicic
acid there's calcium silicates that are
in a liquid form and so with that again
all of these are are recommended to
provide the percent s i
so that when we go in to purchase we are
looking at how much salicylic acid is
released the problem is since there
every state has the ability to allow the
labeling there are still products out
there that will give the percent sio2 or
even the percent salicylicic acid which
is sioh4 and so that what that means is
they can put a higher number in that
percent label
and it it's still the same so if we have
a one percent s i which is a silicon
they can say that it's two percent sio2
and as a consumer you're just looking at
one versus two percent
um and then even with the sio4 a one
percent Si would be a three point four
percent sio H4
and so
making sure that as we're reading on
these labels and we're understanding
what that percent s i is
um that's where we need to make sure
that we're looking at these accurately
the other thing though a lot all of
these liquid fertilizers
um are usually in concentrations
above at or above three percent s i
which is really kind which is
concentrated compared to what I would
suggest as an application rate of 30 to
60 parts per million which is
0.003 I might have missed the zero in
there
um so whether it's one percent or three
percent s i
all that means is you're going to either
dilute it out more or less to get that
same response from the Silicon
so if I'm understanding it correctly
you're suggesting that we should convert
all of these products to
SI percentage just silicon so we can
compare them
Apples to Apples is that right correct
okay that is correct and that is what
APCO suggests for their labeling
recommendations when it comes to Silicon
products so there's no magic bullet
proprietary silicon
chelated
I don't even know what other buzzwords
to hit here that justifies a
significantly higher price point than
really just looking at SI percent
when we talk about these liquid products
so there are some products when we talk
about
um performance
there are some instances where the
formulation some of the formulations
allow the products to have a much longer
shelf life
um so some products only state in
solution for maybe six months to two
years and then form a really thick
silicon gel that isn't going to provide
anything to your plants I have other
products that I've had for over 15 years
and are still in solution
so there are differences in formulation
that might
give an advantage of one product over
another but again those aren't affecting
the Silicon response that you're seeing
if you apply that product at the same
salicylic acid concentration
um the other thing a lot of these
products are not a stand-alone silicon
product like the potassium silicates and
so they incorporate other biostimulants
or other nutrients and so it's more of a
blended fertilizer and so you're not
just getting that silicon but you're
getting other nutrients or biostimulants
that are coming along with that silicon
component and so these are the products
that tend to show differences
in plant size and plant yield because
usually those plant size and plant
yields those are not coming from the
Silicon response unless you're under
extreme stress and so those positive
responses in plant growth are coming
from something else in that formulation
aside from the Silicon component
okay but if I'm just comparing
silica portion of a product because what
you said makes makes perfect sense for
example I'm looking at a potassium
silicate product right now or a
SI product that contains urea phosphoric
acid calcium nitrate you know these
other ingredients
along with potassium silicate but if we
want to talk about just the silica
portion that potassium silicate is going
to be essentially the same potassium
silicate that I'm getting from egg cell
it's it as far as I understand it's all
coming from the PQ Corporation
um
this idea though that we're getting a
different silica response may or may not
actually be accurate
the SI is is s i is s-i is s-i I guess
is what I'm getting at is that you are
100 correct that's safe to say it is
silicone is silicon that is very safe to
say it's salicylic acid is salicylic
acid no matter where it's coming from
what it's weathered from when it's in
that form that's what's taken up by the
plant and so when you put everything on
that same plane as looking at comparing
salicylic acid to salicylic acid that's
why that percent s i from the five day
method even though it's not the best
method that could be out there it's a
it's an extraction method that at least
gives us a starting point to start
looking at where they fall within that
release rate of the salicylic acid but
yes you are correct whether it's coming
from a potassium silicate Source a
calcium silicate Source whether it's at
six percent or three percent
silicon silicon it's going to take up as
much as it wants of the salicylic acid
and you're going to get similar
responses
independent of what that starting
material is
I I only say this because in the
Cannabis industry we have
so many products and so many companies
promoting products and it's it's very
confusing and there's a lot of marketing
hype and
you know
some of these products are just
exorbitantly expensive because with
cannabis you have a crop that's high
value people can spend the money but we
don't necessarily want or need to so I
just it's good to hear
um that you know maybe we can look for a
source that's more affordable knowing
that
at least the Silicon that we're getting
is going to be essentially taken up the
Same by the plant the plant doesn't care
if it had a fancy label or not I guess
correct correct yep wonderful okay
um
on that topic you brought up
monocylistic I can't even say it
monosilicic acid uh is that a different
form of salicylic acid
um as well no and I apologize nope so no
it's good I I yep nope so orthos
salicylicic acid monosilicic acid and
salicic acid they all refer to the
compound
s-i-oh4 which means there's four
hydroxyl groups surrounding the silicon
and that is the natural form that is a
single subunit silicon is never
um by itself in nature it's always
interacting with the oxygen and so when
we say orthosolic acid that means it
forms and I'm not a chemist so please
don't quote me on all this but it's
um it's just the form the chemical form
of the formula and how the hydroxyls
come off monosilic acid refers that
there's just one silicon subunit of the
salicic acid
um and then I just salicylic acid is the
easiest way to say it without adding the
mono or the ortho to try and not scare
so many people away but it's still kind
of a mouthful you're talking about the
single silicon compound that is absorbed
by plants I personally I'm really glad
you brought it up because I'll have
someone say hey you're you know
you don't want to use will last night or
calcium silicate because I have a highly
concentrated monosilicic acid product
you know and making it sound like it's
something
you know inherently very different so I
I'm glad that you you touched on that uh
did you want to add anything before I
move on to the last topic
um no no just with that um really it all
comes down to that percent SI so whether
it's
on its own as a there are some products
that do have a really high concentration
of salicylic acid that don't have a
calcium or a potassium or sodium that's
in combination but they have other
components in that mix that's allowing
it to stay in that high concentration so
again looking at percent s i that's
where you're going to start putting
everything on an equal playing field and
that's where that five-day extraction
comes in it really doesn't care if it's
a straight salicylic acid if it's
combined with calcium potassium or any
of the polymers that are out there it's
strictly looking for how much of that is
going to be in the salicylic acid form
for the plant uptake
you know there is one thing I forgot to
touch on with you was uh one form of
silicon which is silicon dioxide
and availability can you touch on that
before we move on
um so again
that's uh silica
uh the availability is really going to
depend on how it was formed so when
we're talking about uh the silica from a
volcanic eruption you know in a more of
a glassy type thing it's still amorphous
but it doesn't have the same surface
features of a biogenic silica which is
the opal that we were talking about in
like the rice halls and the grass grains
so
um really how that silica was formed is
going to play a role in the release rate
because there's some recycled glass that
they heat up really really high and it
becomes really porous and we've found
that even that recycled glass which is a
silica releases a significant amount of
silicon where we can actually see
increases in Silicon and plant treatment
when we put a certain amount into the
growing media so it does release
we know it can relieve salicic acid but
the amount of release is really going to
depend on how it was formed
and then you're seeing good results you
mentioned uh briefly biochar so if a
high silicon material is pyrolyzed
you're getting a good silicon product
yes and with that we were comparing we
had rice hauls that we knew were coming
from a source that had high silicon we
were using the rice halls and then they
were also paralyzed at the 700 degrees
Celsius in the muscle furnace so the
oxygen was deprived and we were seeing
similar amounts of solicit or silicon
accumulation in a graph study between
those two types of treatments
that's wonderful big fan of biochar in
general so that's so good to hear but
biochar just like everything else you
need to know the source because not all
biochar is going to release
uh or have a high concentration of
silicon it really depends on what the
starting source is yeah I
biochar has a lot of the labeling
challenges and issues yes many other
things in this industry so
um okay last question uh thank you so
much for this what are the differences
across various media sources in regards
to Silicon uptake and plants
is that too big of a question to end the
podcast are you asked like media
components like when we're in like
Hydroponics versus soilless versus uh
actual soil
um okay are there are you seeing it's a
huge it's a huge question yep so with
soils especially when we're in our
heavier with our clay obviously we're
going to have a high
um
a high potential for salicic acid
release when we get into things like our
sandier soils that reduces so but
they're still seeing great responses
when we are fertilizing with silicon
fertilizers on the heavy Clays and on
the sand so this there's still a lot
more to the story that we're learning
when we get into these hydroponic
systems though in soilless media we're
really really lacking that parent
material and minerals that are going to
give us that Baseline amount of silicon
that's needed especially with these
hyper accumulators or macro accumulators
of silicon things like perlite and
vermiculite can add a small amount of
silicon to that and then if we're using
certain water sources we found well
water
is going to give us a little bit more
boost at least here in Ohio where it's
percolating through clay parent material
then our surface water is giving us
um but you're still getting a small
amount if that water is coming
um
from a non-distilled source which I
don't know many people that use
distilled water or purified water in
those studies but still it it's greatly
lacking for the responses that we need
and then when you get into these
hydroponic systems
um if you're doing a beta bucket system
with a hundred percent perlite we're
actually finding that there is quite a
bit of silicon that's being taken up by
the plants and when we ran analysis of
the Silicon concentration in the
reservoir of our perlite buckets they
were very similar to that that was
present in our two millimolar silicon
treatment so there is a potential that
in those type of systems you might not
to eat need as much of the Silicon
fertilizer as you would in others but
then when we get into nft systems
um your fertilizer source for those
systems and your water source are going
to dictate how much silicon might be
there as a background but it's still
likely going to be well below that 60
PPM concentration
that you would need to add continually
or weekly to that solution to maintain
enough silicon for the plant needs
am I missing any of the media no the
only other thing that you and I had
talked about
that I thought was sort of
counter-intuitive for me is I I
mentioned this uh these you know what
people call living soils these highly
enriched soilless media
um it's what our you know my company
produces uh for the industry
um we and we had Rock dusts and we have
a compost fraction so there are some you
know silicon sources in our media
already
um but you had mentioned that you saw
better results related to
um soil applications with some of these
you know Sands and things because of the
the biology I believe
right yep
so the micro the microbiome we don't
we're not even scratching the surface
with our understanding of silicon
weathering and movement between all the
different aspects within the rhizosphere
within the bacteria and within the plant
so we may see some sort of
um
SI solubilizing bacteria or archaea
commercially produced down the road
correct
um what's interesting
they're they're likely already there so
the bacillus species that everybody has
come to know and love
um a lot of these rhizosphere
um species that we're already using as
inoculum are the ones that have been
identified as being important in the
Silicon mineralization within soils
so it is likely that we're already
putting the potential in there as
um silicate mineralizers now we just
have to give them the food to help them
break that down even further so you can
actually you can have that continual
release and that beneficial response
um from the nutrient
see we use a very fine rock dust and a
couple different sources of rock dust
that are pretty high in uh
silicon as well
um
as well as a couple other things with
the idea being because folks are reusing
their media which is not as common in
you know Horticulture and floor culture
industry these things will become
available the SI will become available
down the road even if it's not there
that first cycle
um but that's correct and the other oh
go ahead oh no go ahead
well just thinking about it the rock
does being their present
um and with reusing the media what
you're doing is you are supporting a
microbial community that I don't think a
lot of people think about that are
colonizing these nutrient-rich areas so
you're actually selecting for the
bacteria that are able to live and
survive and weather that material and so
yes as you're using it year after year
um the efficiency of that mineralization
will likely increase
um as that Source you know as they're
continuing to benefit from the plants
that are growing in there and the
nutrients that are available and haven't
been used up
yeah we also use a larger volume of soil
relative to what our soilless media
relative to what most Growers
traditionally would use so we're in beds
or you know 15 20 30 gallon pots in a
lot of cases and I think that plays a
role in in the microbiome and we we tend
to see our better yields in plant health
on the second or third cycle which puts
us you know six months four to six
months down the road versus that first
uh you know 60 days 55 days that that
initial crop is in so you know that
would I think it's an interesting
hypothesis the other thing I wonder
about in terms of the research you've
seen is these types this type of media I
found you know
qualitatively looking under the
microscope tends to be more biologically
active than traditional soils that are
agricultural soils now I'm not
you know doing DNA analysis on what the
you know particular
microbes are to a to a species but I I
wonder if um research would show
different results versus
um you know more a more common soilless
media like pro-mix or something for
example
well like it from what it sounds so
pro-mix
in the soilless media that we use
obviously it isn't microbial inert but
it's nowhere near what soils are but
when you're talking about a highly
Intense or you know um
a well-blended
uh living soil where you are providing
the nutrients you're providing the
environment and you know one that is a
well adapted for enhancing the growth of
these microbes the growth of the plant
that's a lot different than a soil
system where we're just applying
fertilizer to and we're putting plants
in the ground even though we're working
you know
we can be putting in compost that to me
it sounds like these types of living
soils are a little bit more calculated
and more balanced than what you would
see out in atypical
agriculture soil so the fact that you're
seeing
more microbial
um growth or more microbial action that
excuse me that makes sense
um obviously you know having some type
of data to look at those two would be
really really interesting but in essence
that's you know you're just you're
really working on creating the perfect
environment to culture both the microbes
and the plants and so you would expect
to see I think a more dense population
are a more efficient response within
those types of situations
yeah I mean I hope we see more research
down the road but it's such a complex
topic and it would be so challenging to
research anyway just because there's
going to be so much variability uh at
the microbial level right
um I don't know if we'll ever get there
but yeah no no I'm sure people will try
and come up with really great inferences
from that but you're absolutely correct
when you try to control the variables or
you know to be able to even start to
compare studies to one another it's
going to be a huge challenge
yeah well I'm I'm super excited you've
really inspired me to uh revisit uh
silicon and how I might be able to
better utilize it in my garden and uh I
really just thank you for your time
today
you are absolutely welcome and if
there's anything that I can help
yourself or your viewers please just
reach out
um I'm always open to sharing any and
all information that I've got through
these past 17 years with whoever is
interested in learning about it
great well I'll put some uh you know
some links and information
um I think what would be really useful
is a a conversion chart if those are
available so folks could easily compare
products
um and yeah hopefully as more research
comes out uh you and I can chat again uh
down the road
that would be fantastic
[Music]
that was Dr Wendy Zellner and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Tad
Hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on Instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information don't
forget that we're running a limited time
sale on our silicon products in honor of
this podcast thanks for listening
foreign