[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is a repeat guest I
wanted to follow up again with Travis
Higginbotham Travis is the new director
of cultivation support for fluence prior
to working at fluence he worked at a
state-of-the-art environmentally
controlled greenhouse covering 50 acres
where he was the head of research and
development
they grew annual and perennial crops for
big-box retailers supplying the
northeastern United States his focus was
on rearing beneficial insects IPM
protocols disease testing and trialing
new genetics from around the world he
recently received his master's in
horticulture from Virginia Tech this
resulted in equipping irrigation booms
with lights for photo periodic flowering
applications to a controlled environment
which propagated over 1.2 million
perennials from stage 3 tissue culture
per year he also has a Bachelors of
Science from Clemson University hey
Travis I really appreciate you coming
back on the show there was a lot of
stuff that we didn't get to touch on
during our last talk about lighting and
you have this vast background in in
controlled environments and agriculture
that I'd really love to chat with you
about today yeah Chad no I'm happy to be
back
eager to see what we talked about today
so this podcast is probably going to
jump around quite a bit but the first
thing I wanted to talk about was VP D
which stands for vapor pressure deficit
as you know it's a relationship between
temperature and humidity and I know
fluence has a VP D chart can you explain
what VP D is and how humidity and dew
point are important variables in
greenhouse and indoor environments sure
sure so it's a loaded question but I'm
gonna be my best here so the VPD chart
that we have on our high ppfd guide is
is that it's a guide and it's for people
to kind of understand what DTD is but in
some way it could be pretty complex but
hopefully we don't want to do it real
quick and it can be a little bit more
simpler you know it's this is the
deficit VPD vapor pressure deficit it's
the difference between the amount of
moisture in the air and how much the air
can hold that moisture in the form of
vapor before it is condensed into do
right before it's condensed into water
droplets on leaves and things so
whenever I think about VPD I think to
myself how much space in the air is
available for moisture and vice versa
and usually in a greenhouse setting you
know by based on what we feel we equate
this to humidity and in a way they're
tied but in a way they're not so if we
think about how plants use moisture and
how temperature can regulate this and
ultimately light can regulate it it's
through photorespiration photosynthesis
and ultimately transpiration in the
plant
okay so and co2 is linked to it as well
it's hard to talk about one thing
without having to talk about six others
when it comes to this kind of stuff but
when a plant takes a co2 molecule in
donate you have three orders of
magnitude worth of moisture come out of
that still mate so in order for that
process to be efficient you have to have
space in the air that's open for
moisture and this allows the plant to
transpire and translocate minerals
through the plant efficiently and let's
say if it's if the air is completely
saturated with moisture and you're
getting to the plant possibly where
you're going from vapor and clouding in
the air of moisture to puddling on the
plant it's going to be very hard for
that plant to breathe so to say because
there's no room in the air to keep
pushing out moisture and so that's why
it's very important to understand the
relationship between humidity and VPT
and why why it matters does that make
sense
so
we want to avoid too high of humidity in
the sense because at that point like you
said the plant can't breathe but we're
also creating a better environment for
mold and mildew at that point to on the
extreme end of high humidity or high vbd
is that correct yes so so how a lot of
these pathogens work and you know we can
get to melody but first we can talk
about botrytis because it's very
ubiquitous it's its ever-present it's
everywhere and you have to have three
main positions for a pathogen to be
effective and one of those is for one
you obviously need the pathogen to you
need the adequate temperature for this
pathogen to be effective and three you
need the conducive environment and so
when we talk about botrytis in this
situation for one we need to package and
we have it we have to try to spores that
are floating around everywhere and then
usually you have moderate temperatures
which botrytis usually live you produce
the moderate to low temperatures
especially during the night and then you
have moisture present which is huge so
when they score lands on moisture which
could be puddled on a leaf due to high
humidity that abides the spore and the
spore produces a germ tube and that germ
tube can sit over cells and produce
enzymes that break down the cell walls
and they are infected with botrytis if
there was not water puddling on these
tissues
you wouldn't be imbibing botrytis spores
as fast so the what you're trying to do
is have a good environment for the plant
but then you're also now with too much
vapor and too high of a humidity you
have a conducive environment for
pathogens to infect your plant
mildew is similar in that it works a
little different than botrytis but it
needs a similar environment and it can
spread extremely fast and start
colonizing a cell after cell and in some
ways the way the cell reacts to mildew
some plants have a what you would call a
hypersensitive response
once they get infected and that's the
plant defense response against the
pathogen so let's say if a powdery
mildew infects a cell the plant responds
the plant notices this is happening and
it tells the other cells around the
infected one to die and the plant's
thinking there is that it will inhibit
the growth of that pathogen but however
it's its opposite when it comes to
botrytis and powdery mildew once that
hypersensitive response happened and
those other cells are dead okay now it's
easier for the pathogen to infect
themselves so some plant defense
responses are actually beneficial and
with some hypersensitive responses in
regard to powdery mildew or not so
that's why powdery mildew can can
colonize and move so fast when the
conducive environment is there so do we
have those same issues at the low
humidity end of things this is where
temperature you know an irrigation
strategies also come into play too and
sanitation so there's a point where you
know the conducive environment will
allow pathogens to spread and multiply
and infect you know at a rate that we
can't control when we have the
environmental conditions and a certain
level to where we can prevent infection
that helps we also have to know that
many of these pathogens are ubiquitous
they're everywhere and so our sanitation
practices have to be in line not only
with how we're treating our environment
but also how we understand the pathogen
that answer your question
yeah a little bit so moving back a
little bit here and I want to talk about
treatment options too so we're not just
explaining a problem but actually give
some options for listeners to solve the
problem but sure one thing I've noticed
with my outdoor squash I think I've
mentioned this on previous podcast is it
seems to me that it's when there's high
fluctuations in temperature and humidity
outdoors is where I see powdery mildew
move in so if we have a nice sunny day
followed by rainy
you know rainy day or vice versa those
big swings in temperature seem to stress
the plant and seem to allow these spores
to really take hold so I've always I've
always gone under the assumption that we
want to avoid major changes or
fluctuations in humidity and temperature
for an indoor environment because that
seems to cause a lot of plant stress do
you have any thoughts on that no I agree
I agree usually in nature you'd like to
think on a let's say not on a rainy day
just doing it in a normal day when the
Sun comes up and the Sun comes down
things are the environment is slowly
transitioned right there seems to be at
least somewhat of an acclamation period
during each stage of the day so to say
and in in controlled environment you
know many many times we have we have
environmental conditions turn on and
then they're on for the photo period and
those environmental conditions include
co2 and irrigation everything helps turn
off during a dark period these blunt on
and off are not what plants receive in
nature right and plants are obviously
inclined to favor what they want they
genetically in the past received through
through the environment so I agree that
we're still fine-tuning growers are
still working how to fine-tune their
systems supposed to adequately fit the
genetic reads that have been brought up
in these plants and their native native
habitats so what I'm hearing a lot of
growers doing is having their lights
shut off gradually so maybe half the
lights will shut off at one point in the
next set I'll shut off a few minutes
later or ways of reducing that extreme
on-and-off that you're describing have
you seen any research or results to
support that sort of approach to reduce
dewpoint
and can you talk a little bit about
dewpoint that's something that we I
wanted to bring up as well
sure so let me thank howda we've done
some studies when studies on you know
slowly at the beginning of the day let's
say during veg you have you know long
days 18 hours let's say that the first
two hours in the first
you slowly increase light intensity to
somewhat mimic a sunrise right and then
you have your photo period and then
towards the last two hours or last hour
you slowly decrease that intensity again
to try to mimic a sunset when you have
these it seems like a good idea but when
our goal is to increase yield and to
increase quality during those two hours
that we slowly increase and slowly
decrease light intensity we're losing
overall light accumulation for that day
so it's been hard to justify doing that
you know I don't think anyone has yet to
iron out the perfect photo period for
this plant
don't get me started on the options of
photo period manipulation with cannabis
but I feel like in that regard you have
to you have to determine what your goal
is right is our goal to treat this plant
as perfectly as we can or is it to crank
out as much yield and as much compounds
and it is possible and if that's the
case then these gradual on-off stages
are told you know decreasing our overall
energy production in the plant because
of the total light accumulation during
that 24 hour period well what about
going then to if you knew what your DL I
was amount of light that the plant can
take in over a given photo period if you
took that and had a rate that you wanted
to hit over say 20 hours then or 19
hours could you then incorporate it in
some of these principles I would say I
would say yes no and you hit the nail on
the head though that you know I say that
growers do need to talk about the Li and
once they under the Li that they can
approach these things a little
differently right so if you have a deal
I of I don't know let's just say 40 and
that that number came from a duration of
18 hours but you know that you want to
apply a long day and so if you were to
bump your D Li to 41 I'm not doing the
math right here right now good
wanting to bump into 41 and that gave
you an alibi for and an hour after and
now you have a total but you are able to
slowly increase intensity then you had
your 18 hours and then you're able to
decrease intensity I think there are
ways that you could go about it as long
as you didn't wake up your 18 hours and
you didn't take up that desired DLI is
there any advantage to it from the
perspective of reducing dew point on the
leaf surface there I think so if your
temperature mimics the increase right so
temperature dictates yeah you know
dictates humidity in big tasty point a
lot so it's a good question and you know
I working on a few things right now I
will go to too much detail but all of
these environmental conditions are links
and I've said that in the past so if
we're slowly increasing light you know
transpiration of photosynthetic Laden so
this is both photorespiration right
those are all linked to this as well so
house how should CEO to be treated
during that hour how should temperature
gradually increase from the night
temperature so we can alleviate any
possible negative you know effects of
dew point things and that that in my
opinion is still yet to be determined
and it's the reason for that is because
every one system is so different you
know you may you may talk to a grower
who has a system like this but at the at
the during their photo period they may
actually bring temperatures up into 85
degrees right so their temperature
regime is so different from someone who
keeps their max depth at 75 so it's a
it's a challenging that's a challenging
point right now and I can appreciate the
question so really the big takeaway then
would be that we just need to be aware
of what VPD is and how it relates to
humidity and that we need to make
adjustments based on our own environment
as we learn things and say okay well in
my environment I seem to do really well
within this range and try and try and
maintain and stay at those levels
yes I agree and we need that we need to
try to make sure that temperatures don't
drop too quickly right because the water
vapor will condense you know into into
the liquid liquid water on lead you
think when temperature drops quickly so
when we turn off light and you know the
plant process is somewhat decrease in
for overall percent of function then we
also need to make sure their temperature
is adequate admit to it
the next step with cannabis I believe in
controlled environments in general is
we're going to have to monitor all of
these things you know we're gonna have
to monitor at what pace right - all of
these fall in line together and how can
we maximize it well it's exciting to be
part of an industry where we're still
learning so much I really I really enjoy
that aspect of of cannabis and its such
a fun plant and to grow in that regard
one thing I want to bring up just the
different listeners to keep in the back
of their head is that ultimately the
cultivar that you choose is so important
when it comes to milk mold and mildew
resistance especially I you can grow to
it exact same or two of the same plants
that are different cultivars and get
very different pressures in relation to
mold and mildew so I just want to touch
on that so people don't get too caught
up with this and forget about how
important the cultivar astray and
they're growing really is yes completely
good you and glad you don't if we if we
can take another second on mildew I'd
like to say one other thing yeah
definitely I want to actually go back to
that so that this is a perfect time okay
cool so yeah every no matter what we do
you're 100% right that everything is
strain dependent right or strain
specific depending on your system
depending under what you define as
quality and even pathogen resistance
everything else it's all based on your
strain but something I wanted to share
with your listeners was in the in the
ornamental market you know in the flower
market those growers in one greenhouse
at one acre of greenhouse probably
managed over ten
different genera and that can probably
equate to at least 50 to 60 different
varieties and ultimately maybe 40
different species it it's quite amazing
and each plant like we just said
responds this heart differently to
different pathogens something that we've
learned in the past two to three years
that's actually been implemented on a
commercial scale is how to make the
plant more resistant to powdery mildew
and fungi and general diseases how do
how can we make the plant be tougher
more tough to combat these pathogens and
there's two strategies one of them is
what's called silicon and it's a mineral
nutrient it's one of the most plentiful
minimal nutrients out there it actually
covers the Earth's crust but silicon is
not considered a essential plant
nutrient but a plant can use it and it
comes in the form when you apply outputs
once it comes in the form of potassium
silicate and one of the strategies
that's being used in other crops outside
of cannabis for mildew prevention for
example on vineyards on roses even on
basil in some cases is adding potassium
silicon to your fertilizer and you would
apply this at a certain parts per
million every feed and you would slowly
slowly build up an accumulation of
silicon in the plant and what silicon
does is it it's similar to calcium in
that it focuses on the cell walls and it
makes cell walls more stiff and to some
degree it can be so stiff that it
inhibits the enzymes that pathogens
produce to try to break down cell walls
so you know it's it's it's amazing to me
with how our agricultural industries are
moving away from pesticides and
embracing bio controls the extent at
which we're going to prevent disease and
to prevent pest damage we now can
implement something as silicon to make
the plants
strong in some cases that we reduce
powdery mildew severity by up to eighty
percent and the rest of the powdery
mildew is actually killed by our
preventative sprays so you know it's
just the growers in my opinion should
take some time and dive into the
literature in some cases on some of
these pathogens you can find very cheap
and easy to implement solutions to some
of these pathogens just by what's been
done on other crops in the past now the
challenge with with powdery mildew and
you mentioned potassium silicon which is
I think a great product we carry a
powdered version in our online store
called AG sill 16h there's a lot of
people now selling it for the reasons
that you mentioned and there's a great
article which I'll post on the podcast
page about silica it has a ton of
benefits one of the ones I found most
interesting is it actually mitigates
micro toxicities in the in the leaf
surface or on the in the leaf tissue
itself so if you have a little bit too
much boron or copper or manganese for
example it'll help spread that out so
you get less of a toxic effect in in the
leaf tissue on top of all the other
things that you mentioned so yeah I yeah
and that that's I don't mean to
interrupt you but that that's called
soluble silicon the plant converts it
into that and so when you apply let's
say egg cell you have the plant
converted into soluble silicon and then
polymerize silicon polymerize is what
helps you on your cell walls and a
soluble is what helps you transport a
lot of the mineral nutrients like you're
saying yep okay yeah I didn't know that
and the other thing I found is that
cannabis in particular seems to just
thrive on potassium even more than other
you know vegetable crops and ornamentals
that I'm familiar with growing so
getting that extra potassium is in
general a good thing so it's a good mix
but the one thing I do want to mention
is that it's not organic and that's
important for a lot of a lot of our
listeners and at least something to be
aware of when you are applying something
in your garden yes true
there's some forms out there that can be
but yeah yeah there's I've seen other
silica products but in terms of what you
mentioned there with the amount of
available silicon is there there tend to
be a lot lower so that they're not
necessarily plants available like a lot
of people put rice holes in their media
because they're high in silica but it's
not in a form that the plant can take up
so you're waiting you know for months
potentially for some of this to become
available to the plant as it gets broken
down yep I agree and that you know the
crop times that we deal with those no
point in adding rice holes and you know
you can effort strategies of how you can
break down rice holes and then and then
apply a powder and that you know you can
have a plant response in less than two
weeks when you integrate a powder but
most of the you know most of the growers
I meet are not using a loose substrate
right they're using these compressed
blocks of whether it be core peat or
rock wall so you couldn't even mix in
something like that
so I agree yeah that's a challenge to
get a product like that and I wanted to
touch on your potassium I've learned
similar things like you have with
potassium being important with cannabis
but we have to be careful because
potassium also regulates the EC so the
more potassium we the more potassium you
include in your fertilizer you increase
your EC also and then it's a little
harder for you know the fertilizer to be
up to be taken from into the plant
because the water is a little saltier
and when you look at your nutrition you
you want to apply potassium in a
one-to-one ratio with nitrogen so just
something to keep in mind I yeah I
definitely want to talk about nutrition
because I think you have a lot to share
there but before we do can we talk a
little bit more about strategies for
dealing with these these particular like
botrytis and powdery mildew so some of
the other ones that I'm aware of out
there are let's see there's sulfur
burners it is one option that I hear
that a lot of people have used
lactobacillus you know through Rob
and some of the enzymes in there there's
been some research on there's potassium
bicarbonate and then there's another
form of bicarbonate that you can get I
think it's green cure I can't remember
what it is right now I'm blanking but
are you familiar with other you know
more organic options out there and their
efficacy around cannabis great question
um so powdery mildew is tough and in for
example like in the ornamental market
it's so tough to control in some cases
they're just breeding away from it you
know they're they're making plants that
are just resistant to it period so like
now there's instead of in patients that
were covered and they'll do in the past
now we have resistant genetics that
won't even get infected with mildew
that's how that's how other markets are
dealing with it because it's such a
struggle that's why I think things like
silicon in your constant feed just
automatically gives you a strong buffer
but as far as other measures you know
like I've seen some growers who they
have they get plugs you know from other
suppliers and you automatically have to
treat these plugs as infected plants I
mean even if even if the supplier is
completely clean it's just a safe bet to
have a quarantine program right and
there's products out there and I could I
could list an array of products problem
is I've learned that one product will
work in one state and that same products
will not work in another state that
really is frustrating but you're right
there's potassium bicarbonate I believe
that's called nil stop and then you have
the sulfur burners and bacillus and I
believe sulfur burners work well you
have to be careful because that can add
too high of concentrations it's not too
healthy also for humans and you can have
some burn on plants but elemental sulfur
is sprays helps but my advice is I would
have something in your feed whether it
be silicon or high levels of calcium
chloride to help the plant strengthen
its cell walls to reduce over
all infection and then have preventative
sprays in place with potassium
bicarbonate or even have vaporized
diffused sulfur in your growing
environment to try and help mitigate
whatever micro environments that you
have that could Harbor powdery mildew
and third if we had a cultural change I
would say if growers can and this can be
a struggle but if you can get your
airflow to 2 meters per second then you
are automatically kind of diffusing all
of the micro climates into one in your
room and that way the more airflow you
have the less chance you're going to
have mildew actually having a stabilized
population well let's talk about air
flow really quickly in relation to
mildew so I've seen some people where
they're just you know blasting the plant
it affects their transpiration rates in
the hopes of preventing it and then I've
seen other people where they want the
air coming out underneath the canopy and
being pulled up through the canopy and
then I mostly what I see is fans up
above the canopy to help cool the lights
to keep that heat from coming down to
the plants now obviously with LEDs that
changes a bit but what what are we
looking for in an indoor environment for
airflow in terms of where we should be
positioning our fans relative to our
canopy yep and I would say that that is
definitely defined by what regulations
you grow like so are we dealing with
large plants very few plants but large
plants are we dealing with a ton of
small plants in a grow and they're
shorter and they're not so big with so
much canopy and that that to me is
really where we first have to ask okay
what what kind of plant in the stage of
plant the size of plan are we dealing
with and then or equal to position
stands underneath the plants and are you
also able to do either horizontal or
vertical airflow for example like in
lettuce you know and we can learn from
other industries if we look at lettuce
lettuce has a problem and it's called
leaf tip burn and this is due
to calcium deficiency and it's because
but it was with LEDs as sole source
lighting or supplemental lighting when
you try to push the plant at a certain
pace with a certain amount of light at a
certain temperature the plant can't
translocate nutrients fast enough so you
end up in the new growth having cells
that don't mature in it then it over
time it looks like burn not because
those cells die and they stretch and
they split it's not a way to fix issues
with vertical airflow and it does
exactly what you said when you have
airflow that comes directly down onto
the plant you're automatically
increasing transpiration rates and so if
you work to increase air flow you would
obviously need to also change the way
that you perceive the plants
transpiration rate and does that mean
changing you see a little bit bringing
it down just a little bit so things can
move to the plant easier and so it's
it's interesting I get some of the same
questions all of the pins on the system
ideally you would want some airflow that
yes touches the plant from the side and
also from above but it's the main thing
with mildew is can you get inside to
canopy right so you usually have a
bordering edge which is called the
buffer zone all these plants that are
found in the middle there is in the
middle can Harbor many many populations
throughout and if you're not careful
during the night period they can spray
to your outer buffer and then it's very
hard to get control so we want to manage
our canopy to making sure that people
you can that airflow can go through
there to reduce the Spore pressure in
the areas that are getting less airflow
essentially exactly yep and in other
industries they just space their plants
you know if they have the available
space they just space them so there's a
fair flow but in this crop in this
industry right now that's that's the
last thing I'm going to recommend
somebody is spacing so yeah it is a
challenge right now trying to get air
flow in between two canopies of multiple
plants but so when I first started
growing I was told that you want to be
able to see through the plants that was
how they you know just that the
two-second lesson on pruning but then as
I got into it more and
our people started looking at how far
light is penetrating the canopy and then
removing leaves that were below you know
a certain ppfd for example in the in
that canopy as because they just weren't
photosynthesizing light as effectively
and they were potentially places where
mold and mildew could could take off do
you have any thoughts on that so you
talking about pruning pruning leagues
we're talking about pruning viable solar
real estate to the plant I understand
that people are worried about different
wavelengths penetrating you know a
certain amount of leaves to where let's
say by the fourth leaf down you're not
getting any benefit from the light
that's where fluence I think really
separates I'm not trying to have a sales
pitch here but that's where full
spectrum truly comes into play right so
a multitude of spectra when it's being
applied properly you can have let's say
red and blue that's not going to
penetrate one leaf that's going to be
absorbed as as soon as it touches the
leaf surface but these other spectrum
actually actually channel through the
leaves and do have photosynthetic
ability as they travel through now what
is the extent of that right that's all
based on your density and light
intensity but I have seen systems where
they they prune the heck out of their
plants and I understand why and it's
further reasons you say but at the same
time I'm thinking those leaves are
generating your energy so it I think if
anything pruning at certain stages could
be effective for the the objective of
your plant so during flowering when
you're focused on buds and let's say by
the end of week five in flowering and
you know at the end of week six your
flowers and your buds should be formed
that may be a good time to actually take
some leaves away and focus on the buds
but at the same time any energy that
could be harnessed during that time goes
into the bud but that's a hard one and I
wish that you know in the future of
getting more and more hands-on
experience with cannabis we can kind of
see what the threshold is with pruning
so essentially what you're you're
hitting on is that you can use pruning
as a trigger to with the plant in terms
of stressing it and removing extra xxs
families for example to focus its energy
on bud production the plants naturally
trying to senesce its ending its life
cycle it's trying to produce seeds
obviously these are you know not viable
in that sense because they haven't been
pollinated but the plants still going
through that process and by removing all
these this excess all these excess
leaves the plant really has to focus its
energy into its its bud production that
sound about right well the the plant
process is going to be dictated by photo
period cutting of leaves
yes I would say a fission causes a
certain level of stress but overall if
you're under a short-day the plant is
going to be focused on flowering I do
think that some leaves can be a
nutritional sink so some older leaves
that let's say most likely look pretty
rough you know to the naked eye
co-curricular fleshly those could be a
sink for macro nutrients so in that case
if they're darker green if they have
some chlorosis things like that
definitely prune them because they're
taking away from what is the newer
growth and in flowering during a short
day I wouldn't say that this stress
helps the plant in regard to pruning but
more if you were to prune than the plant
reach annals the focus from going into
those leads and goes into the bud
I don't know if they came off clear but
yeah I get what you're saying the reason
I'm asking is because I've seen there's
there's a book out there and it's like
thousands of dollars or something crazy
where the guy I think he's out of
Colorado recommends removing all fan
leaves in flower so literally all you
have is these these bud sites and they
claim it it maximizes their their yield
and I know a few people have tried it
and gotten decent results and I always
attributed it to excessive sort of plant
stress that's opening you up to more
diseases and other problems but
potential
allowing the plant to focus more of its
energy on its bud sites though I haven't
really ever wrap my brain around how
removing all of those you know
photosynthetic or potentially all that
leaf surface is actually going to
benefit the overall plant health and
yield ya know I'm with you there and we
have to be careful because I've seen
strategies of let's say reducing
nitrogen towards the end of flowering
right and either that's to apply a
stress or that's to try to not have so
much nitrate concentrated in the bud or
applying a stress through water
stressing the plants towards the end of
flower or cutting off leaves like you're
saying abscission stress stress can be a
good thing when we understand what it
does and how it does it if we apply
stress too much stress the plant is
going to put all of its energy into
combating that stress response and it's
not going to be focused on what we want
it to be focused on so I think I think
they are and to your point we still have
so much to learn on how to manipulate
stress to increase quality and to
increase yield and the next question is
happenes compounds and it depends on who
you're talking to when are they produced
and why are they produced you know
there's theories all around on why the
plant produces them but then okay what
what causes an excess production of
those can we harness that energy so we
need leaves but if we're applying stress
to its vision maybe we don't need to
lease because it's a stress response
you know there's it's interesting this
plan is just fascinating it is and the
other factor is on a commercial scale
you just don't have the labor to prune
that much in most cases it's it's just
too much work so most other growers I
know that are producing on scale are
typically you know staffed but running
around crazy and don't have time to go
through and remove all of these leaves
in most cases and it may not be
beneficial based on the the difference
in in yield and what we know about plant
stress and and all the reasons that you
just mentioned yeah I completely agree
with you labor that
and that certainly needs to be a
priority to take into consideration so I
would say if anything if you if you go
in there and pruning as part of your IPM
integrated pest management schedule
right so if you end up seeing
environments that are forming within the
canopies I would prune so you wouldn't
have powdery mildew you go in there and
eat that look like they're nutrient
sinks I would prune that out so the rest
of the planet can use the nutrition
properly I personally would not prune
for an absent stress yep
let's let's simply let's simplify this a
little bit so take me through your
you're gonna go through a room and scout
for powdery mildew and botrytis and for
pests and insects in theory on a daily
basis if you're staffed for it just to
know what's going on in your room so you
come across a plant that has powdery
mildew say and at some point how are you
going to treat that in a in a flower
room for example where you don't want to
be using any doing any foliar
applications for numerous reasons what
options do you have besides removing the
infected material that's a great
question in regard to mildew you don't
have many right now that's why I why I
really push having things in your
constant fertigation system because that
helps you when you get to a case like
this because hopefully it prevents a
case like this so when you're when
you're in there scouting and you end up
finding but and when you end up finding
mildew pruning would be the first option
but then you're touching it right you
could possibly be spreading it doing it
that way the first thing I would do is
if you have any ability to space the
plants I would space them so either
those leaves can be exposed to light or
air you dry them out and you fry them
with light intensity the spores or if
you possibly can't apply any spray under
the under the buds I guess it depends on
your regulations there then you would
obviously try to hit it with some type
of spray and an interesting approach so
that I want to mention that's come out
to a company call
by Oh safe is is a product I believe
it's called prevent and what this is
it's a it's a microorganism and I can't
think of the strain right off top of my
head right now but it's for applications
to prevent powdery mildew and botrytis
and what you do is you would apply it as
a foliar spray and it actually colonizes
the tissue so botrytis and powdery
mildew cannot it has no it's completely
an environmentally friendly item to use
but it takes up the real estate before
botrytis and powdery mildew try to move
in
and so in my mind if you're gonna have
any success with powdery mildew is all
going to be due to your prevention
strategy yeah so we want to grow
cultivars that are less susceptible to
PM we want to manage our our relative
humidity and VPD we want to treat all
plants that come into the facility by
either you know dipping or spraying and
quarantine we want to keep our our
clothing and everything our access to
the room really controlled so that we're
not creating any new vectors but at the
end of the day spores are going to make
it into your room there's no such no
one's growing in a clean room per se so
at that point it's just a matter of
managing you know like you said using
IPM strategies to really keep everything
as as controlled as possible yeah and
that's a great way that that's a great
way to bring it all together yeah so the
other one that we touched on at first
that haven't gotten back to you it is
botrytis it's really it's the worst and
it spread so rapidly the first time I
saw it in a crop I started doing a whole
bunch of research and read just how
quickly it can spread you know it
multiplied so so rapidly in when it gets
in ideal environments how do we really
treat that because it's always happening
at the end of flower and it's it's just
a big problem for growers yeah Petridis
is finicky because it's everywhere it's
sitting all over our face right now as
we talk but it I actually worked on
botrytis from
Aster's and we tried to use strategies
using UV light to kill it on contact
with as short of a dose as 30 seconds of
pulse and it was highly effective and
with LEDs and UV it's very very
difficult it's not impossible right now
to have such a high radiation wavelength
in the form of an LED right it's not
it's not efficient at all there's
technology out there from other
companies that use UV UVB and UVC for
sterilization of certain pathogens but
anyway my point in saying that is I even
went so far as UV because botrytis is so
hard to control the thing with botrytis
is first it's key to because the
different stages of Petridis there's a
stage called
sclerotia and the fungus can produce it
is referred to as an overwintering
structure and this structure is formed
when the environment is not conducive
and so let's say you have botrytis likes
cooler temperatures anything below 70
degrees it usually performs much better
it can perform at higher but it performs
much better and much more effectively
below 70 degrees Fahrenheit and so when
temperatures are consistently higher up
into the 80s and 85 it can transform
into the sclerotia form as that form it
can tolerate pretty much most
environmental conditions that will come
in contact with and even some chemical
products they can still withstand and so
we're these sclerotia
take place is they are on dead plant
material on your tables they're on the
floors they're in the cracks they're in
places that you you wouldn't think twice
to even clean but they're staying in
there and they're staying dormant until
the environmental conditions come to
where botrytis is is known to grow and
then it triggers it back into the
reproductive stage and that that's where
I think people don't take sanitation
seriously enough in between harvesters
all plant material every day that falls
or any cut mature
needs to be cleaned up because botrytis
will go dormant and it will colonize and
grow on there and if you're not careful
you could have a spore spawn out of
colony grow on there and air hit it
right you have thousands of spores in
the air so cleaning is huge when it
comes to cat right and you're right
there's not many things you can spray on
botrytis that's why I think in the
future UV light may have some potential
on killing pathogens on contact when you
when you're not allowed to spray but
cleaning and sanitation daily and in
between crops I mean scrubbing the
corners of the room
scrubbing under the tables and hosing
things down that's critical when it
comes to the Treader Wow you know it's
terrible as you know a lot east past and
diseases are at the same time it's
pretty amazing the survival and
reproduction strategies that Nature has
come up with in these cases I have to
kind of tip my hat to a certain extent -
to these - these diseases but yeah it's
been a ting yep one thing that I hear a
lot of growers doing in in organics is
just taking their leaves off of their
plants when they trim and using them as
a mulch right there on the soil and I've
always sort of been against that and I
think the reasons that you just listed
are the biggest reasons why we want to
make sure we're removing all leaf
material that doesn't mean just throwing
in a bucket and leaving it in the corner
of the room for the rest of the day you
got to get it out of there you got to
clean your hands if you're if you're
doing that you know you want to go back
in with the same clothes so yeah these
are all things that people need to think
about and with their workflow to really
reduce the amount of pressure that
they're getting so that's that's a great
point
yeah that's using leaves on top of the
soil as a mulch I completely agree with
you that's gonna be a haven for trips or
spider mites eventually and yes it's
dark under there usually cooler under
there and it's usually more moist under
there you will have botrytis thrive in
those environments you know that's a
no-no all right well we haven't even
gotten to the topic that you wanted to
talk about when we first chatted before
the podcast which was nutrition so I
don't know if now's a good time to
touch on that or if you want to take it
up and maybe another podcast but it's
definitely something I wanted to hear
your thoughts on sure yeah I can I can
talk about it briefly at least the
things that can be manipulating it
should be thought about so I think the
first thing that needs to be said is you
need to think about nutrition in regard
to your substrate and you have to
understand how your struggle your
substrate buffers or how quickly it uses
that the nutrition delivery system for
your plant so in regard to rock wall
that's considered hydroponic right a lot
of times the fertigation strategies that
are applied to rock wall are also
applied to just flowing water for herb
production in hydroponic systems and
tunnels and and things like this and in
regard to core compressed coir or
compressed peat and you know it's we're
getting close to the age where many
growers of multiple industries are going
to start to use wood fiber because it's
truly a renewable resource and a
renewable substrate compared to the
alternatives especially peat so wood
fiber is a is a very complex molecule
and I'm not going to go into that
because that's a more than IPM thing but
these different substrates have
different buffering capabilities Rock
oil does not the rock wall will have a
continuous feed to it right there's no
buffering you're not gonna have build up
you're not going to have difference as
much in PH like you would in different
substrates so that's the first thing I'd
say that you need to understand first is
what subsidies that choose why is you
gonna choose it and how is you gonna
deliver nutrients through that substrate
to the plant how are you going to manage
it so with that I think everyone
understands easy pretty well or you're
getting to the point where they do an EC
and this is just simple it's the amount
of saltiness your fertilizer it's right
so how many how much salt is present how
fast can the plant take it up in in
liquid form is based on its saltiness
that the increase of decrease of EC and
usually due to high concentrations high
ppm sand concentrate and depending on if
you have a delivery system of one to
fifty or one to 100 because then you're
easy at the end of the hose is going to
be different based on your injection
rate so without going too much into the
substrate and looking more on just a
nutrition in general some key rules of
thumb to keep in mind are first off no
matter what fertilizer you using I
wouldn't mix it how's your vendor
recommends that you mix it if you allow
it to go through your injectors and you
take a sample at the end of that hose
and you send it in to a lab and you get
a nutrient analysis no one can help you
and you can't help yourself until you've
seen what's on that nutrient analysis
and what I mean by that is all the
microbes and all the macros listed out
and parts per million that's exactly
what your plants receiving or that's
exactly what your substrate buffering
that to me is a huge priority for any
core it's hard to know anything from a
label to be quite frank you need to just
allow these things to go through your
systems and then see after your system
because injection rates we can do the
math but they're not perfect there's
still at least a 5 to 10% error within
some of these systems so don't be don't
be too firm on the numbers on your piece
of paper get them sent into a lab when
you see these parts per million of
macros and micros but first start with
the macros you have NPK nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium a rule of thumb
for nitrogen and potassium is you need a
one to one ratio if you have a hundred
parts nitrogen you need 100 parts
potassium potassium is known to regulate
EC so let's say you under a strict
growth or encourage growth you can add
more or less potassium increase or
decrease your EC and you can control
growth that way phosphorus on the other
hand if you're not careful you can have
deficiencies quite easily and see here
when we talk about phosphorus a baseline
number for phosphorous if 12 parts per
million is the lowest you should ever go
that's when you're trying to pinch
pennies and you want to apply as less
the least amount of fertilizer
you can ask how parts-per-million you're
at saturation point with phosphorus at
24 parts per million and when you go up
past 24 there's there's not been
anywhere shown that there's a benefit
for that there's there's growth benefits
when you understand how to manipulate
phosphorus so in some some crops
especially in leather stock crops you
can you can manipulate inner node
between nodes you just need to
manipulate the links with phosphorus you
can also inhibit flowering so if let's
say you're a grower and you're
struggling to get the amount of yield
that you want and you've never done a
nutrient analysis well you know you
could lack in phosphorus and that's
reducing your overall yield because it's
inhibiting flowering so phosphorus is
critical to be I would say at least at
20 20 parts per million in your safe 24
is in saturation your even better
anything above 24 it's not worth it and
anything below 12 you're going to see
deficiencies and start really hard
coding the plant let's see what else
here calcium calcium and magnesium are
two that need to be understood because
if they're out of balance you then all
have deficiencies of one or the other or
both when thinking about calcium you
need a ratio at least a three to one
three being calcium and one being
magnesium and it's because they don't
interact well together so you need to
trump it with calcium so you can still
get the plant to absorb both of them if
you can and if you understand how to
make salt you want a five to one ratio
of calcium to magnesium so there's
there's multiple ways and it's
fascinating I don't think anibus has
even touched on this yet but there's
multiple ways in regard to light
intensity and photosynthetic rate on how
you can manipulate insurance in relation
to light and control the plant so much
more precisely than we do right now
yeah and basically what you shared I
think is really important if you're
growing we're using ionic nutrients or
mineral salts now how do we apply that
to organic growing where we're actually
in living soils
in media that contains a lot of high
levels of microorganisms that are
actually cycling these nutrients for us
well it's it's a lot of the same
principles and at the end of the day
right now all I can tell you is that
kind of thing is the Wild West and the
reason I say that is is because I hear
these living living soils right and I'm
sure plenty of them I've heard plenty of
them works fabulously and it's because
those companies have done the science in
the background to understand how these
microorganisms have mutualistic
relationships and symbiotic
relationships with each other and also
the substrate and the plant and certain
bacteria you know work together to
produce nitrogen and ammonia and I think
right now you know it it's hard to
regulate organic nutrition like you can
you know mineral salt nutrition because
there's so many microorganisms that can
have multiple reactions that's hard to
have precision with I think it's it's
there I think some some companies have
it down and even you know including
castings of certain larvae and another
microorganisms and you can even rear
nematodes inside wax moth larvae in
living soils if you wanted to to prevent
entrance of peas areum carried by fungus
mats like it it there's there's all
these different strategies out there
that I don't think are ironed out just
yet and in some cases if you if you have
the ability to make sure out salts I
think that that first needs to be
figured out with this crop before we try
to figure it out with organic mineral
nutrition well I totally agree with you
that we don't have it figured out from
an organic perspective and these living
soils I don't think we ever truly will
just because of the fact that there are
so many different complex interactions
going on like you mentioned between in
the rhizosphere between the plants and
its exudates
the nutrients that it's able to uptake
through these different microbial
communities that are
so incredibly complex that we're still
learning about and you know how
antagonistic or symbiotic various
microbes are and many of which we
haven't even identified or can't culture
in a lab to really study so I totally
agree with you there
that being said what I'm seeing is
because this is basically our side of
the industry and what I'm really
passionate about and I untold yet why
why it's something that you're not as
into coming from an ornamental industry
perspective because this just doesn't
exist over there for numerous reasons
that make a lot of sense but what we're
doing is looking at soil testing you
know an acid extraction using like a
male like three tests for example or
something similar as a way of seeing all
of what nutrients are potentially in the
soil not necessarily plants available
and then comparing throughout the cycle
and at the end of the cycle and seeing
what's being used up by the plant over
that period of time and then reom ending
that same soil as a way of maintaining
those levels of fertility over time does
that make any sense yeah exactly
it does it does and like you can think
of it in the same principle as a grower
constantly using the same nutrition in a
concentrated concentrate what's the word
tank so let's say that you you irrigate
with a certain fertilizer concentrate
with rockwool you use that same tank and
the same recycled water over and over
and over and over again
what does mineral nutrients are going to
be taken up at different percentages at
different ratios by day three you're
gonna have a different ratio of those
nutrients in the tank versus day one so
I agree with you the plants will take up
these and use these minerals so
differently that we constantly have to
keep amending them can I just I'm just
gonna go on a short rant here really
quickly so one thing I've noticed about
this the cannabis industry and you may
not have seen this coming from the
nursery side of things but people will
come up used to come up to me and be
like hey have you tried Product X I'd be
like no never heard of it whatever so
I'll research it and either a it's
something that is got
ingredients you know that you know you
could find you could find a much cheaper
version of or what I find more commonly
is that grower will be like hey my buddy
tried it and you got the most amazing
results ever and I'll look at the
product and let's just say it's a it's a
phosphorus product now but maybe the
reason that his buddy got such a great
result is because his soil was low in
phosphorus or his nutrient program was
low in phosphorus and that boost and
phosphorous caused his plant to be
healthier and he he did great or but
that doesn't mean that that product is
magical and it's not necessarily the
right product for your program if your
soil is already high in phosphorus or
your fertigation program already has
appropriate levels of phosphorous it may
it may be have negative effects on your
on your soil or on your overall plant
health and I just think that's something
that a lot of growers don't take into
consideration when they're looking at
all these different products they just
they just look at it either as
beneficial or detrimental and they don't
know they're not taking into account all
the other variables that have to
interact with within an you know a
proper nutrition program yeah no I
completely agree and that's for the
reason I said that first before you dive
into your nutrition understand what the
capabilities holding a buffering
abilities starter charges of your
substance and in figure out how are you
gonna measure your nutrition in those
substrates and then start thinking about
your nutrition and how you're going to
deliver it I completely agree with you
yeah yes bit you have to understand the
soil first and you can't just take take
something by you know by word of mouth
you have to trial it yourself you have
to see a performer stuff it you have to
send it and get an analysis run do you
know exactly what's being delivered to
your plan yeah and you can't use EC in
the same way with organic soil as you
would with rock wool or some of these
hydroponic programs that you're talking
about I have seen people use EC if they
didn't want to do or didn't have time to
do testing and say that their EC was at
a certain level and then they try and
hit that same level with their remember
program but it's not very accurate but
the numbers are going to be off the
charts for organic soil versus rock wall
and in some of these other more inert
media yep and they're going to be
different forms of minerals hence the
difference in DC
it's going to be different the EC's
gonna be different coming out of your
hose as reviews if you were to get a
leach test out of your substrate I agree
yeah well was there more you wanted to
talk about in regards to nutrition I
thought that was really helpful what you
shared I I I learned some stuff because
I've never looked at it strictly from a
nutrient in a ppm perspective because
I've always used organics so it's never
something I've looked at in quite that
way well I knew I don't really have too
much more I think in the future you know
we could maybe have a discussion over
more organic nutrition or as I learn
more about this crop to but I think in
the future we can talk about organic
nutrition down to the ppm you know and
we can make mixed substrates with
certain per you know certain percentages
of this type of carbon versus this type
of carbon and trying to figure out you
know degradable cycles and things like
that and you know at the end of the day
that's a sense the right direction to go
and we still have a lot to learn like
you said but now I appreciate the
complication you know you bring that up
but I wonder how do we do that if every
soil is going to have a have different
microbial concentrations and diversity
so our nutrient cycling rates are gonna
vary so we may have the same inputs but
at the end of the day I just don't see
how we really you know completely dial
in that that level of complexity that
we're getting out of nature right now
yeah well and I think that's going to
take you know certain companies are
going to have to invest in labs and you
know other industries do this now and
they they're going to get to the point
where they they understand the
interactions because they've tested the
interaction of themselves you know you
can do this you can you can take let's
say you want a certain
trichoderma mycorrhizae bacillus strain
you can make a selective media you can
make a petri dish the only grows that
and then you want to compare that
relationship with another one and then
you can put those on the same plate
together and see how they interact and
then extract that putting your liquid
concentration and tested and see what
enzymes or what mineral nutrients
produced from the interaction you think
can be done the problem is half of the
products they give you a cocktail of
over a hundred microorganisms and in my
mind part of the reason they give you a
cocktail is because they're hoping some
of those or at least 50% of them are
going to have a relationship with the
plant so in nature wherever let's say if
petunia was native to there's one strain
of one microorganism but had a true
relationship with that petunia that's
why the products that we apply on
petunias have a cocktail of
microorganisms because growers are
hoping that they'll see a response from
one of these strains because we don't
know yet which strain does the response
we're looking for yeah and I'd add to
that I heard Colin bell with mammoth
microbes talk and he was talking about
how they created their product and
essentially it's a it's a combination of
four different strains of bacteria and
individually the plant responds they got
from the four of them was not nearly
what it was as those four combined and
it was just through trial and error that
they came up with what they came up with
but there is this sort of synergistic
effect to that we don't totally
understand either so there's a lot to
learn there and you know I would love to
chat again I I really enjoyed this
conversation I learned a lot too once
you've sort of been on the job for a
little while I know this is still a new
industry to you and you're starting to
visit more more cannabis facilities and
learn more about this plant so that
would be great
yeah no no I'd love to how is enjoy it
yeah we're learning every day and it's I
can appreciate your your listeners
because all of them you know they care
so much they're trying new things and
they're all seeing different things and
eventually we're gonna have to find a
way to kind of come together as an
industry and be like okay what have we
learned you know what what can we put in
as some industry standards to actually
leave this crop along together so yeah
learning every day man this is great
yeah well I again I really appreciate
your time today
and I look forward to chatting again
here in the future yep sounds good Ted I
will talk to you later
[Music]
that was Travis Higginbotham with
fluence bioengineering manufacturers of
LED lighting for the horticultural
industry their website is fluence dot
science or you can type fluence lighting
into google and it will be the first
link you're listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'm your
host Todd Hussey don't forget that
there's more information and articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
is organics calm as well as links to the
data and information we discussed in
this episode on the podcast page thanks
for listening