[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is dr ethan russo
dr russo is a board-certified
neurologist psychopharmacology
researcher and author he is the founder
and ceo of
he credoscience.com from the university
of pennsylvania and the university of
massachusetts medical school before
residencies and pediatrics in phoenix
arizona and in child and adult neurology
at the university of washington in
seattle in a practice with a strong
chronic pain component
in 1995 he pursued a three-month
sabbatical doing ethno-botanical
research with the mataguena people in
parque nacional de manuel peru he has
held faculty appointments in
pharmaceutical sciences at the
university of montana in medicine at the
university of washington and as a
visiting professor at the chinese
academy of sciences harvard university
and john hopkins university he has also
published numerous book chapters and
over 50 articles in neurology pain
management cannabis and ethnobotany his
research interests have included
correlations of historical uses of
cannabis to modern pharmacological
mechanisms
phytopharmaceutical treatment of
migraine and chronic pain herbal synergy
and phytocannabinoid terpenoid
serotonergic and vanilloid interactions
he has consulted or lectured on these
topics in 39 u.s states and canadian
provinces and 39 countries now on to the
show hi dr russo thank you for coming on
the show today
pleasure
really appreciate it i uh i wanted to
ask you some questions uh regarding some
of your more recent research
i know you've done some work with jeremy
plum who was recently on the podcast i
thought maybe we could start off talking
a little bit about that
sure that'd be great
do you want to explain some of the uh
methodology
and what you were looking to accomplish
with jeremy
yeah so what we were doing was uh
testing out a novel solventless
extraction technique uh the idea being
to try and preserve can cannabinoid
particularly terpenoid content
of fresh flour
and i should point out that
the source article is open source
it's available
online
at
ethanrusso.org if people just hit the
library tab it'll be about the second
article down so it's called novel
solventless extraction technique
to preserve cannabinoid and terpenoid
profiles of fresh cannabis inflorescence
and um
so basically that was the idea um
what i was doing was operating under the
feeling that
um the standard way of presenting
cannabis is to try and cure it and this
is based on the idea that everyone is
going to smoke it
but that isn't always the case
um it's been known for many years that
you lose up to 50 percent of the
monoterpenoid content so this would be
the lower molecular weight turbinoids
the so-called headspace volatiles that
are going to be what you smell when
you're in the vicinity
of a cannabis plant
so
in drying and curing
you're losing
50 of those now if you're a person like
me that believes that they're part of
the entourage
of uh cannabis chemicals that contribute
to therapeutic effects that doesn't make
a lot of sense
so what we're doing is for the sake of
so-called smoke ability we're
squandering these important components
on not just smell and taste but effect
so i wanted to develop a technique that
would preserve
the profile of the fresh flower
as you see it growing
and this involves
exposure of the fresh cut flower
to
co2 vapor from dry ice
and
we were hoping it would be sort of a
lyophilization freeze drying effect as
well get rid of some of the water
apparently some of it remains however we
did succeed quite well
in demonstrating a marked concentration
of the components we could kick
the
cannabinoid content upwards of 60
percent
in some cases
and
basically double or triple
the terpenoid fraction um
as compared to the fresh flower
so what you end up with is
what the moroccans term keef
basically separating the trichomes
from the rest of the plant material
now when it comes to cannabis
therapeutics aside from roots and some
things that occur in the
leaves
to greater extent than in the flower
when
usually
we're most interested in the
cannabinoids and
terpenoids
that occur in the trichomes and the rest
of what's in the flower is really
extraneous so you do have a bunch of
cell wall ballast that's sort of fatty
you've got chlorophyll which you don't
need for therapeutic effects and then
there's all the
woody material um so basically you're
getting down to the nitty-gritty of
what's needed medicinally if you're just
looking at trichomes and that's
basically the reason that there's been
hashish
for thousands of years our ancestors in
the middle east figured out a long time
ago that the real action
was in the trichomes even if they
couldn't see them at the time they knew
how to
separate them from the rest of the
biomass and create this concentrated
product
so this is a sort of modern type of
hashish or keef um
but um it was really important to me
that we do this with material that was
organically grown and under control
conditions so that's where jeremy plum
came in because he has what to my
knowledge is the most sophisticated
indoor
controllable organic regenerative
approach to cannabis culture that i've
ever seen and believe me i've seen a lot
between working at gw and having visited
numerous of the licensed producers in
canada
um in the netherlands etc
so there are plenty of people growing
cannabis they're very few that i think
are growing it the way i'd like to see
it done
so with this process
um
how
practical do you see this scaling
commercially if it's a more efficient
way of preserving
uh you know terpenes and
and everything in the process well it's
a great question and one that we're
still trying to answer as it is um this
takes some time
um it may be
we did
different sessions one was just with an
hour of dry ice exposure
and we did two that way and two uh with
48 hours of exposure now that's probably
overkill
it may be that a happy medium is
somewhere a few hours of exposure
um this does take some time
um there could be a marked cost savings
however because with this process you're
not having to have a drying facility or
take that time to dry uh ostensibly it'd
be possible that you'd be from fresh
flower to the
finished kryokev as we call it
um in just a few hours
now the yields are not fantastic but
depending on the of our involved
we did see yields that were quite
comparable to what people get with water
hash
now water hash
can be a very nice product
however there are issues with it because
you end up with a bunch of wastewater
and to my knowledge it would not be very
easy
to um
to fix that up and use it for another
purpose
and you also end up with um
with that process with a bunch of sludgy
uh biomass material that again may not
be good for much except composting
with cryokeep it's quite different
however what you end up with
is flour that has partially been denuded
of its trichomes
however as we tested all the material
each step of the way we know that that
remaining
byproduct
could also be extracted
by co2 or cold ethanol and so it's not
wasted at all which might be the case
with water hash
so ultimately what we'd end up with is
this byproduct that's extractable
plus a
high quality
extract the cryoke which
we believe would be useful in a number
of fashions
on the one hand it may be very
attractive to the high end
uh keef connoisseur market
and so it could be a va
you know be sold at a premium
additionally for
like pharmaceutical applications this
may be a much better way to go because
again
what you're ending up with is a much
purer product
as you're starting material um
you basically have got
again upwards of 60 percent
uh cannabinoids and hopefully
uh depending on the source material
somewhere
six or seven percent
terpenoids and there probably is some
water left there
but you're not ending up with hundreds
of extraneous chemicals that really
aren't
uh contributing to the therapeutic
effect
um so we we think this will be viable
but you know it will be a specialty
product
um
we haven't quite worked at all the
economics but we think it's uh could be
a very good thing
depending on the application
can you touch a little bit on the
entourage effect
and uh its therapeutic benefits in
regards to
terpenes um
and how they may be like medically
beneficial
sure
okay so the entourage effect uh this
term was coined in 1998 by professors
muslim and ben shabbat in israel now
originally they applied this to
endocannabinoids it was the idea that we
have two main endogenous cannabinoids
anandamide and two arachidona glycerol
and what they noted experimentally was
that related molecules the entourage
that seemingly were inactive or very had
very poor activity on their own when
combined
with the main players on ananda mind and
through ag
there was a remarkably markedly
synergistic effect
say on treating inflammation
the next year they published another
article where they said well you know
this could apply to the plant as well
um and you know this keys into a concept
that's been present in botanical
medicine forever that
um you know there usually isn't one
active component
or
a key ingredient but rather a collection
of chemicals that work in concert
to produce the desired effect
and
you know that's sort of analogous as
well to traditional chinese medicine tcm
where it's usually not a simple meaning
one earth but rather a combination of
verbs and so you might have two or three
that are aiming at the pain
but you've got additional ones that
improve the taste or reduce the side
effect from the first three
well cannabis is like tcm or an
entourage unto itself
we know that
there are upwards of 150 different
phytocannabinoids that the plant makes
now beyond the familiar thc and cbd
um there are probably
10 others where we know a fair amount
about the pharmacology and each of these
has unique therapeutic properties that
are distinct from thc and
cbd beyond that you have the aromatic
components of cannabis the turbinoids
and there have been 200 different ones
that have been described in cannabis
none so far unique to cannabis but
they're common to other plants
just to give a few examples
limonene is going to be familiar to
anyone who smelled citrus
so limonene is at the base of the
essential oils from all the citrus
whether it be orange lemon lime kumquats
even
and
limonene is a well-tested
molecule and it has been shown in humans
to have marked antidepressant effects
um and we've recently done experiments
at johns hopkins with ryan vondre
showing that limonene in conjunction
with thc
makes a significant decrease in the um
anxiety levels that thc can produce
so that's one example it's also limonene
is also an immune stimulating compound
uh mercene mercinese the most common
uh
terpene that we find in cannabis in
conjunction with thc is very uh soap
horrific
uh produces fatigue and it's what i like
to call the couch lock compound
um
so it really can be helpful for sleep in
particular but has anti-inflammatory
properties
as well
linalool
is common to cannabis and to lavender
again even in humans
linoleul
or lavender essential oil has been shown
to be a very effective anti-anxiety
agent this has been demonstrated
clinically in demented patients patients
with alzheimer's disease that can get
quite agitated particularly at night
so improvements in sleep decreases in
nursing care have been demonstrated
and these things all are boosted
um by
their association with thc
cbd or others
another example and this is an
interesting one
caryophyllene um occurs in cannabis
um it has the distinction of being not
just a terpene but a cannabinoid as well
because it works on something called the
cb2 receptor
cb2 is a non-intoxicating receptor
that has pain relieving and
anti-inflammatory effects
so having caryophyllene along with thc
and other components can make it a
better drug for pain or inflammation
uh it also has an anti-addictive
property
and all this is work that's been amply
demonstrated in basic science
experiments
so
those are just a few of the examples now
you will hear from people that the
entourage effect isn't proven well
there are plenty of examples uh whether
they be now in humans or in animal work
or in laboratory work uh that
demonstrate that uh
there is this entourage effect there is
synergy of these ingredients so it's a
bold statement um you know they're
trying to prove the negative by saying
that the entourage effect isn't proven i
just wonder
how much evidence is going to be
sufficient for the doubters to come on
board
i mean also anybody has to do is try
marinol
synthetic thc and compare that to what
herbal cannabis is like
and it will be
very self-evident
that these are two different
types of effects different animals if
you you will
thc on its own is not a pleasant
experience
it's more apt to produce dysphoria
unhappiness than euphoria and it's quite
disorienting even to people who are
accustomed to use of cannabis
whereas
with these other components they tend to
tame thc
and increase its therapeutic index
meaning
increasing the the allowable dose
um that can
exert the therapeutic effects without
producing side effects
[Music]
yeah there's there's a lot there um
one one thing i thought of is the work
of dr eddie ray and the cannabis cup in
oregon that jeremy's also a part of
where they found that the sensory
experience
by the judges
was
not necessarily
like the highest thc cultivars were not
the consistent winners so
consumers even though were driven by uh
thc
from a marketing perspective
from a consumer experience sensory
experience
the the high thc cultivars are not the
ones that are winning so
it fits with what you're saying about
this
therapeutic experience having
all these other components to the plant
um
along those lines
as from a cultivation perspective one of
the questions that was given to me by
from a cultivator was
are there issues with unsafe levels in
the case of making extracts in relation
to
these terpenes
any potential long-term issues for
workers that are being exposed
on a daily basis is that something to be
concerned about um yeah it's a good
question in general
what we usually see with concentrates is
a loss of the turbinoids
so i've already as i've already
mentioned
in the drying and curing process
you're losing up to half of the lower
molecular weight monoterpenoids to begin
with
then that's compounded oftentimes by
the tendency to do supercritical co2
extraction
um in one pass
now that's really efficient at getting
the cannabinoids out but also waste the
turbinoids
um
you know it would be better to do two
passes one aimed at the turbinoid
extraction and a separate one
for the cannabinoids um but going back
to the question can you have too much
terpenoid yeah the the answer is yes
let's use the example of pinene now
pinene is a very important agent
it actually
can reverse or eliminate the short-term
memory impairment from thc
but it is a little bit irritating if the
concentration were too high it's going
to be irritating to the lungs and cause
cough um if it were inhaled
so that's a possibility
but
you know a rule of thumb i like to use
is follow what nature does
so let's just say for the sake of
discussion
we've got a cannabis flower that tests
out at 25
on uh thc or total cannabinoid content
what would be a reasonable
corresponding content of turbinoids
well um
you know there
um
we usually see something
five percent a big great one
um so maybe 20
of the
uh cannabinoid content
uh would be a good figure for the
turbinoid content usually it's much
lower than that as i'm sure you're aware
um
but um the key thing would be
does it produce irritation if it's
inhaled
um
there
are toxicities
um to the the uh terpenoids found in
cannabis but usually at very high
concentrations or high doses
for the most part
these are agents that are in our diets
uh they're often used as food
supplements and are
erected their grass
that doesn't mean the stuff in the lawn
it means generally recognized as safe as
food additives or flavoring agents
um
so yeah i mean they're rare rare uh
terpenoids um
uh pulagone for example
um
i haven't seen it in cannabis in many
years
uh but there have been
reports that it could produce
miscarriages on at least in animal
testing
it's also found in penny royal which
isn't recommended for pregnant women for
example
but in general these are very safe
compounds of
used in a reasonable concentration
that's good to hear um and i'm sure
folks can take proper
uh where ppe is appropriate if needed
getting on to another question though i
want to jump back you had mentioned one
of the reasons that you did this most
recent
extraction study or sorry a drawing
study with
jeremy was because of his facility and
the fact that he uses organic production
can you
explain a little more on why you feel
organic production is important from a
medical perspective or a therapeutic
perspective well first is a safety
factor
um inorganic culture
it's a given that you're not going to
use pesticides
and
these are things that
just shouldn't be
in cannabis that consumers are utilizing
particularly if it's in healed because
in the same way
that
inhaling
cannabis smoke or vapor
gets into the system very quickly the
same is going to be true for pesticides
and in general if something kills a bug
there's a fair chance that it's got
toxicity for humans as well
now there are exceptions
there are certain pesticides that target
receptors and insects that humans don't
have but
in general
most pesticides are bad for you um so
there's that whole element
um i think that part's pretty obvious or
logical
but beyond that um i can just say i've
been an organic farmer myself for
geez
at least 40 years
it's important to me
to know
what i'm putting into my body
and i hope the same would be
particularly true for people that are
taking medicine
so there's again um beyond the safety
factor
i am quite
convinced
that
growing plants organically is going to
provide a healthier plant
and a healthier product
by healthier product i mean that
a happy plant is going to likely produce
better medicine and that could be in the
form of higher yields of cannabinoids
and terpenoids or better balance
um
you know
we have to go back
a step and ask why does the plant make
these things well it wasn't put on god's
green earth
to get us high
how we know that is the human species is
under a million years old and the
cannabis plant is 30 million years old
well then you should ask the question
why are cannabinoids in the plant
the endocannabinoid system is actually
much older than that
it's um
300 million years old um
so
the plant happens to make these things
and it does so for ecological reasons
so making these chemicals whether they
be cannabinoids or turbinoids serves the
purpose of the plant
in this instance it is to
have antibiotic effects anti-fungal
effects
and to discourage predation
now it's a happy accident for us
that these chemicals that the plants
making for its own purposes happen to be
very salutary
good for our health
or enjoyment as the case may be
um but
we also have to recognize that
things are not the same today as they've
always been
what is always been with respect to
human medicine was that
medicine came from plants
and it's only been in about the last 75
to 100 years
that we've had the capability of
synthetic chemistry to make drugs from
scratch that
in some instances
don't exist in nature
now that can be a good thing or a bad
thing um i really
am well aware of the bad things in terms
of the toxicities whereas
um
medicine from a plant
often not always
but often it's going to be safer and
easier for the system to incorporate or
detoxify as the case may be
um
so there's that
i'll stop there for a second
yeah the one the one thing i wanted to
get back to was the the pesticide
comment we do
in organic production there are some
pesticides that i still wouldn't want
folks to use even though they would
qualify as organic like urethrins for
example yeah you know i i happen to know
how you know sam over at proof and
jeremy are running their facility and i
feel quite confident in the quality of
their flower but it's a definite concern
one other aspect from the cultivation
perspective that you and i touched on
before the podcast was this um
sort of the
the microbial uh relationship in the
rhizosphere between plant root exudates
and you know the microbiology that
exists
and how those work together in a
symbiotic way
to really allow the plant to control its
growth
you had an interesting analogy there if
you want to share it
in relation to humans
um
if you want to
mention that yeah sure i mean um
we are humans but we're complex
organisms as well
we have a whole gut microbiome that
consists of trillions of bacteria
without these we would be in serious
trouble because they are responsible for
eating digestion
reducing inflammation and
often producing chemicals that we
couldn't get from our food
without them plants are the same
plants have roots
they're
going through the substrate hopefully
soil
and seeking nutrients
now they can manage this
in a sterile soil
however
they incorporate these nutrients a lot
better
if there is also the presence of
appropriate
other
microbiota usually fungi in this
instance but also bacteria
there's a symbiosis there that
they nourish the
fungi or bacteria and in return
get help in incorporating the nutrients
that they need
in a proper ecology of a cannabis plant
or tree or anything else is going to
include the plant itself plus these
other agents
and
when those agents are present
plant finds it a lot easier to draw
what it needs
um and so you're going to have a
healthier plant you know when a plant is
really healthy
maybe you don't have the need for any of
these pesticides
or even organic controls
um but
we make it tough
for cannabis in a lot of instances
because
um
they're in crowded conditions
um they
usually isn't a lot of thought given to
providing
uh
these mycorrhizal agents that are going
to help the plant be healthy and so
you've got to use all these artificial
agents to try and control diseases after
the fact
so
i mean it's
having proper nutrition of your plant um
more naturally it's sort of like
preventive medicine
makes sense i mean one could survive on
mcdonald's and steroids
but you certainly wouldn't be as healthy
as someone who's eating a balanced diet
and you'd be more likely to get illness
be more susceptible to
a variety problems um
so that makes sense
one one other thing that i thought of
when we were talking about uh proof is
and jeremy was this uh
goal he has of getting replicable
chemovar expression
so that uh from from a patient
perspective
he can get a consistent response
every time you consume um a particular
you know cultivar a particular product
how
because the big argument i've heard for
moving towards
you know more chemicals um
more synthetic more synthesized um
versions of thc is that we can get
consistent you know pharmaceutical
uh responses or quality
how do we do this
from a cultivation perspective or as an
organic grower
yeah and how does that benefit the
patient
first and foremost i need to say that it
not only should be done it has been done
and one reason i wanted to do this that
the experiment of proof was
so that we could highlight jeremy's work
in showing that indoor organic
regenerative culture of cannabis
was practical
and beyond that
this is using the ultimate controlled
environment now
it would be great
if we could
plant on outdoors under the sun
and get reproducible crops however
um
in the pacific northwest these days we
have wildfires
late in the summer there's smoke
exposure there's dust in the air there's
straight pollen
there is pesticide contamination from
your neighbor drifting over
it's not controlled
um and
this is unfortunate but it's the truth
and it's a hard thing to avoid or one
hail storm can wipe out your crop
um
let's concentrate for a second on the
pharmaceutical market to make a
pharmaceutical from a plant
this has been done it can be done again
it's got to be controlled every step of
the way to get the kind of consistency
that the food and drug administration
requires of a drug
that there's very little variance
in the components from one batch to
another this is a scenic unknown if you
don't have that you don't get approved
and you have to maintain that throughout
the life of the drug
but this can be done it requires that
you have
consistent genetics but also consistent
environment
so this
is best done in a greenhouse or totally
indoors
um and in the case of indoors um
using led lighting it's possible to
affect the spectrum that in turn affects
the expression of these chemical
components
so
you know it is the ultimate and
scientific culture
for medical applications
um
so
with that though there's all these
variables that the plant is exposed to
from how healthy is your mother plant um
you know and in theory you're starting
from clones so let's say we take the
same the same clone all the way through
round after round
you know we'll see variances in
irrigation
pest pressure
all these things nutrients
will all have impact on chemovar
expression as you know so i guess what
i'm wondering is is it
you say it's possible how do we get that
level of consistency to a point where
maybe the fda would accept um would
accept something as
you know
as medically consistent
well it's already happened it happened
with epi dialects which is a purified
cbd derived from plant it also happened
with sativex sativex is
uh extracts of a high thc plant in a
high cbd plant with other com
components other cannabinoids and
terpenoids
although it was not approved clinically
by the fda it did make it through the
chemistry manufacturing control
uh process at fda what that means is
the consistency was demonstrated despite
the fact that there were hundreds of
components
so i mean i could show you a slide of
different batches of sativex over nine
years
and
the traces superimposed look like single
peaks you can't see much variance at all
um
now
for example in europe
when you're making a medicine from a
plant they usually have allowed a
variation plus or minus on a particular
component of 10
medically
it's got to be better than that um
accepted figure now is about 5
but um with the fda i'm sure that the
variance was much much less than five
percent
um and again this can be done
if you have um consistent genetics
uh you have an uh
stipulated process every step of the way
um you know i can tell you at gw it was
77 days from when the rooted cuttings
went out until they were harvested not
76 not 78.
they
didn't use pesticides at all
when there were bugs
thrips and what have you they were dealt
with through integrated pest management
good bugs eat bad bugs
and this is all acceptable so this has
already happened it can happen again
that's not to say that it's easy or that
it's cheap
but
again in the pharmaceutical market
you're always paying a high price
for what we hope will be an effective
safe and consistent agent
okay i mean that makes
that makes sense
um
do you see this always being an
extracted product then or do you think
flower could get to a level to where
we could get that kind of consistency
sure well ted you know
whether people like it or not they're
always going to be three echelons of
activity with cannabis based
products
uh herbal cannabis isn't going away
um
the second echelon is supplements that
hopefully
have some degree of standardization and
quality control and then the top tier if
you will
is pharmaceutical production which again
has to
surpass a higher bar in terms of all
these um stipulations
um but these are always going to be
around
um
you know but i i can tell you the u.s
federal government made a mistake in
when they um
the fda
approved synthetic thc as marinol and
thought that was going to take care of
the
whole issue of cannabis on herbal
cannabis as medicine that didn't happen
and it won't happen
um
right
so we need this we need this plant um
essentially what you're saying i know
it's glory and all its different uh
manifestations
i i want to touch on that with you
because
uh
you know genetic diversity in cannabis
is is massive
we're learning more and more it seems
like every day
as to not just its effects but what
what its potential is
how important is
the genetic diversity we currently have
in terms of preservation and what are
you most excited about um
seeing coming out of the cannabis plant
well uh
and that we know a lot about cannabis
however we've only scratched the surface
of what it can do therapeutically as i
previously mentioned
if there are 150 known phytocannabinoids
people mostly these days only have
access to about three in any
concentration thc and cbd
uh last year our team did the first
human study
of cannabidirl and it's turning out to
be a fabulous agent
and the same can happen for thcv and
cannabidivarin and a bunch of others we
could reel off the names of over the
next half an hour
but um
you know there's there's plenty more to
come
yeah we really want to show the validity
of the entourage effect um and i'll make
a bold statement
there are plenty of uh clinical studies
that have been done with cannabis in one
form or another however most of them
have been with very substandard material
particularly nida cannabis
that really creates a false impression
of what the plant can do
i would make this statement that i don't
think any studies so far have been
undertaken with what i would call an
optimized preparation
um meaning being all it could be
getting the right balance of therapeutic
components cannabinoids and terpenoids
to do the job
uh the best way it can be done
so a big part of what we're doing now at
cretoscience is
trying to formulate
for what we think are going to be better
preparations
can you talk a little bit about your
company credo science
sure
well
ken i've been at this for 26 years now
and
uh working for other people and that has
its pros and cons but
um
you know basically at the ripe age of 68
i decided that like it or not i had to
do this myself
so nisha whiteley and i
started credo science right at the start
of the pandemic
that set us back a while but the idea
was to develop
some concepts that i've been
rattling around in my head
um different uh approaches to cannabis
and the endocannabinoid system
uh so you know we've discussed one of
these applications already and that is
the kryokev technique
um but we also have
plans for a
cannabis based disinfectant a cannabis
treatment for head lice
we have our formulation service
so we're doing lots of different things
we also
developed
a screening test for the genetic
mutations that we observed in
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
um so it turns out that this isn't from
pesticides or neem or
other explanations but people that have
this seem to have a genetic
susceptibility on it causes them to get
sick
when they're
using too much thc on a chronic basis
that's interesting because i have heard
the the neem comments in many forums
along with a variety of other
hypothesis so it's good to hear from an
actual doctor that that's not not only
that i'm somebody that uses name on my
fruit and berries
and
whether it's a good idea or not i've
eaten stuff i sprayed the same day
um
it didn't do any harm to me
neem like anything can have toxicity
however the toxicity
we know to be attached to neem doesn't
match uh that
uh of
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome at all
um so people would like a different
explanation and the unfortunate truth is
some people are susceptible to this and
until we find out otherwise they
shouldn't be using cannabis
which can be really unfortunate for the
people involved
because they find it extremely difficult
to stop
you you did a whole podcast with shango
on the shaping fire podcast on this
topic and right i just want to mention
the folks if you're interested in more
of the medical
therapy side um
i i think you've done six podcasts now
with shango over there over the years um
they're wonderful so i highly suggest
people go check those out um
i just want to i want to mention that as
a resource for folks
yeah
well um
that's really exciting i never would
have thought of using a cannabis product
for
head lice for example
well it's only a 4 000 your
prescription
this was described
by the uh ancient sumerians so in what's
now iraq 4 000 years ago
um you know and it's a simple
prescription cannabis on lice but the
exact same thing is done
contemporaneously
in pakistan um they use fresh
cannabis and rub it on the head and i
think we can do this much more
effectively
what we want to do is hone in on
you know which components are
our most efficacious but we know already
that certain phytocannabinoids and
terpenoids are insecticidal
um
so
you know it's a relatively
straightforward set of experiments to
prove the concept
well you mentioned neem which made me
think about all the applications we have
for neem
historically i mean i've used neem
shampoo and neem toothpaste
it's used as a fertilizer it's used as a
pesticide and a fungicide
as uh disinfected in many cases
do you think that one of the main
benefits you're seeing with the head
lice
is relation to the oils in the in the
cannabis is more of just a suffocant or
does it have something like as a direct
and where it has a chemical component
that you feel is really
both
um
in my uh slide presentations they show
an example of what happens when aphids
are on a cannabis flower
and there are two things one is
their little legs break the trichomes
and which then
burst
uh and polymerize and trap the bug so it
can get killed that way but the uh
components
of the trichome cannabinoids and
terpenoids are also insecticidal so it's
mechanical
uh and chemical
are the mechanisms there
so if that's the case why do we have
such a proliferation of insect problems
and with flowering cannabis i mean once
those trichome come in how come you know
hemp russet or even the cannabis aphid
are so successful sure well part of its
monoculture
you know uh
you know often uh in nature uh plant is
growing with other plants and um it may
seek out things that help protect a
companion planting if if you will
but the other thing and i think this is
important
we have a lot of culture of plants that
aren't in the right environment so
you've got people that are trying to
grow um
afghani genetics in a humid
climate
where
afghanistan's pretty dry
so
some of its male adaption of the
particular
chemovar genetically to where it's
trying to be grown
and again nutrition really enters in
i think a lot of these plants that are
subject to insect attack are not getting
what they need from their substrate um
and uh
and again if it were
a rich soil
uh with all the necessary bacteria and
fungi i think it's going to be much less
likely that be subject to the same level
of predation and damage
yeah i would i would agree with that to
an extent i do think that we see
in
controlled environment agriculture when
we're indoors too you don't have natural
enemies so we don't have the the natural
bio controls for a lot of these pests so
once one enters a facility
it's much harder to remove whereas out
in nature you wouldn't have those same
issues
exactly
right now i have a fruit tree outside
for example with aphids but yet my
entire
garden is not infested with them they're
primarily on this one plant and they're
not even covering the entire tree
they're just covering a portion of the
tree so um
there's there's just natural ways
outdoors that these things are more
controlled for so they don't necessarily
kill the plant because it's not
necessarily in the pests interest
from a survival perspective to to kill a
plant uh it needs something to continue
to eat that that food source so very
true
i could i could see that being the case
um
wonderful well was there anything else
that you wanted to touch on in regards
to
some of the the research you've been
working on that you'd like to share with
listeners
ah no i think we probably covered it i
would just like again to make a pitch to
people for the idea that yes you can do
uh organic regenerative culture of
cannabis
and even indoors
and i hope that people will
use your products i mean i i
spend a lot of time looking at
ingredients and things i use and i'm
not sure i've ever seen products
better balanced having the things i'd
like to see
and i've seen the results in terms of
what cannabis looks like when
it has this kind of substrate available
so
uh boy there's no more compelling
evidence than that
we'll have to get you some soil for your
garden
um
yeah i didn't
i
didn't quite do it this season but next
season i'm i'm looking at uh getting
some
uh
raised beds put in and uh yeah it's
important to me what goes in
i might try a little google quilter but
uh we need to uh wonderful
otherwise too
yeah we've been working now with uh
jeremy and sam over at proof for um
a year or two
with uh providing them with media with
with soil
and that's been a really wonderful
experience because of all the data
collection they do we're really able to
refine and improve our processes because
of the feedback
that we're getting from them um
one thing that some of the other
facilities that we work with are doing
and i know uh proof is starting to
experiment with is this idea of reusing
the media too in the facility um which
can lead to some challenges around
consistency
as as you know every time you harvest a
plant you're pulling out organic matter
you're pulling out nutrients those have
to be replaced so um replacing them to
the exact levels that they were at
before and keeping the biology
you know consistent to what it was to
get that same ex scheme of our
expression is is really challenging but
we do have some facilities that have
been reusing soil now for
oh five to eight years in some cases at
five cycles a year indoors um
quite successfully with good yields so
it's uh i really i hope and think that's
really the future from a sustainability
perspective of how we're going to
cultivate um
not just from a cost and labor
perspective but also just from an
environmental
perspective as well so
excited for that
yes that sounds very promising
[Laughter]
well i thank you so much for your time
today i really appreciate it and uh i
look forward to hopefully seeing you at
another event uh
locally as well you picked you picked
the best year not to garden because
we are having historically cold weather
this year um it's
nightmare
certainly noticed
yeah
okay well thank you again and have a
wonderful uh rest of your day
that was dr ethan russo and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information thanks
for listening