[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe on iTunes or
stitcher or whatever platform you're
listening on and leave me a rating and
review this is really helpful and allows
me to keep producing good content for
free by drawing on more top names in the
industry for the show this week's
podcast is all about soil testing in
this episode we dive into the importance
of soil testing some of the different
types of soil tests and how to
understand and interpret the results our
guest this week is Chris Boardman Chris
earned a Bachelors of Science and crop
and soil science from Washington State
University and has over 19 years of
experience in agronomy field management
sustainable program surrounding
agricultural turf and natural
environments he is currently the
president of agronomy for yoona best
international who were the makers of the
soil savvy test kits the ion exchange
technology in these kits has been
utilized by large agribusiness companies
like Wilbur Alice McGregor crop
production services Simplot and much
more chris also manages a large family
dry lands and irrigated wheat farming
operation in eastern Washington
welcome to the show Chris yeah thanks
Todd I appreciate the opportunity yeah
so today we're talking all about soil
testing and I want to start off with a
little bit of your background not going
too deeply but just a really brief idea
of where how you got into this realm and
what your background is was so testing
yeah yeah really my background started
out I acquired or earned my Bachelors of
Science degree in crop and soil science
from Washington State University that
degree had a turf grass emphasis and so
I really focused on turf grass systems
from there I graduated and
I'm a golf course superintendent and
worked at a couple golf courses built
two golf courses and grew them in the
last golf course I was at we built and
grew it in and I was there for about
three years and in that time I met the
owner of Univest international who has
the soil savvy product that we'll be
talking about today he was curious if I
was interested in the technology that he
had and if it was applicable to turf
grass and I was really blown away by
this technology that he had and the
accuracy of this technology and soil
sampling he mentioned that he was
looking for an agronomist and I actually
made a career change to come work for
Univest who developed the soil savvy
product and I've been here for seven
years almost eight years now okay so
let's talk a little bit about why
someone would want to soil test what's
what sort of actionable information does
it give you with soil testing yeah so
soil testing is really going to give you
you know the best opportunity or ability
to manage the system that that you're
looking to manage this can be you know
large-scale agricultural systems or you
know small scale plots size gardens at
home potting plants I mean you name it
but really we want a soil test to give
ourselves the the highest probability of
achieving high-quality or yield and so
soil testing is a very critical
component of achieving both quality and
yield and these systems that that were
managing you know I like to look at as a
way of helping avoid making mistakes so
the soil testing will tell us
essentially what sort of excesses and
deficiencies we have or things that
might be building up over time if we're
reusing the soil
I think it's personally I think soil
testing is really important so if we
could talk a little bit more about the
different types of soil tests can you
talk a little bit about you know
I know there's a bunch out there can you
just touch briefly on the major ones
that people may be familiar with yeah
sure so the major soil tests that are
that are currently offered to to most of
us are often through extension agencies
but you might have direct access to soil
testing labs these labs are going to
offer chemical extraction type soil
tests and maybe paste extractions our
chemical extraction soil tests are most
common especially in commercial
agriculture this is where they use
different types of weak or strong acids
to essentially they apply these acids to
your soil and extract off the nutrients
that are in your soil that may be
available to a crop that is growing
there's also paste extractions these and
simple would take your soil make it into
a slurry and the paste extractions
really look at the the solution or
soluble forms of nutrients within within
your soil type those are really the two
main the chemical extraction and the
paste extraction of the two main soil
tests that are most familiar to to most
growers or agronomist so I'm most
familiar with the Mallik three test
that's the one that we typically use and
as I understand it and correct me if I'm
wrong what we're getting when we use
that Mallik test is we're getting an
idea of everything that's in that soil
but not necessarily what's currently
available to the plant
whereas with that saturated paste test
that's telling us a little bit more
about what is currently soluble and
plant you know more plants available is
that is that an accurate way of
describing the - yes so the the Mallik
extraction is going to be you know an
acid type extraction and it's really
dependent on the soil type that you have
and what extraction is going to give you
the the best idea of nutrient
availability in your soil so there's a
lot of different types that may lick the
Bray the Olson there's a lot of
different types of extractions
accuracy of those extraction really
depend on the soil type that you have
and often labs use certain extractions
for areas where most of their soil
samples come from and then the paste
extraction obviously is going to give
you a better look at the soluble forms
of that total amount of nutrient what's
actually soluble and in the solution
phase that would be available to your
plants and I think it's important for
growers to know what type of test that
lab is using that they go with so that
they know if they're getting a braid
rubbery extraction or a male ik3
extraction so that they can base have
some sort of basis for those results
would you agree with that yeah yeah and
I think it's important to know that and
you know once you've once you've gotten
results from a lab it's best to really
stick to that lab and look at those
results compared to the responses in
your crops and start to really you know
mesh those those tests with your crop
responses and kind of stick with that
lab that that you're using it's not good
to change labs or send soils to
different labs because it really gets
confusing to us as growers or agronomist
and trying to interpret these tests
across labs we should be able to do that
but currently in industry they recommend
that you stick with one lab versus
trying to send your soils you know to
all different labs and see what
responses or what readings you get from
multiple labs yeah we've actually done
that where we've sent same samples to
two different labs and gotten you know
fairly similar but different results you
know the pH can vary by as much as 0.4
between these two we've seen different
calcium and magnesium levels
I totally agree with you that it is
important to stay with a lab once you
like a lab now personally we've been
using the standard soil test at Logan
labs because we work with we've worked
with Steve Solomon and Erica Ryan himer
and it makes it really easy if
everyone's using the same
lab results so that's the one that I'm
most comfortable with but I've seen
tests from all these other labs too and
they make these recommendations but I
think for listeners it's important to
realize that these recommendations are
sometimes based on certain crops or
crops that are different than cannabis
so it's good to know are they making a
recommendation for turf grass or for
potatoes or for tomatoes that can factor
into how you interpret these results as
well yeah correct so you typically when
you submit a soil sample to a lab if you
want recommendations they're usually
gonna ask you what the crop is that
you're growing maybe what the previous
crops were and then usually you know
they want they're going to ask for a
yield goal that you're trying to achieve
and that really drives recommendations
in commercial agriculture now obviously
if we're not dealing with commercial
agricultural applications you could
probably still provide the crops a
tomatoes for example the it's a
commercial crop as well you could
provide that but the recommendations may
not be specific to the systems that
you're trying to manage and I think that
will lead into a little bit about the
soil savvy technology that we're
offering and how we can help growers
with the specific systems and
recommendations that they're that
they're managing so just to highlight a
couple of things you've already covered
so it's important to stay with a lab
once you go with a lab know the type of
test that they're doing and realize that
these test results are guidelines
they're not written in stone here so
your actual soil may be you know within
a certain percentage or close to the
results that you're getting but not
necessarily exactly those numbers would
you agree with that yeah yeah and like I
mentioned previously you really want to
you know look at your you know look at
your plants you know if you're doing
tissue testing stay on top of that if
you're seeing consistent you know
deficiencies and certain nutrients and
you know maybe you're picking those up
on the standard soil analysis and maybe
or not but you want to keep comparing
those tests to one another and you know
just your visual observations of of your
plants and your tissue samples in
conjunction with that soil test is going
to start to kind of lead you in the
proper direction and nutrient management
if you're seeing the same deficiencies
over and over again obviously we need to
you know maybe amend these soils with
these specific nutrients and that way
you know we're not trying to make up
with foliar applications during the
growing time we want to make sure that
those nutrients are in the soil they're
available to the plant once that plant
starts to grow a lot of times plants
will begin to adjust in quality and
yield in deficient systems and may not
display all the deficiencies but they're
going to start adjusting to it based on
the deficiencies in the soil so we
always want to start with building a
good soil so as an agronomist you're not
just looking at this soil test but
you're also looking at where your last
crop finished in terms of yield you're
looking at what you're visually seeing
so for example if the if the soil test
showed sufficient magnesium but you're
seeing magnesium deficiencies that may
lead you to believe that that magnesium
may not be plant available or that you
may still need to do applications to get
those levels up or adjust the pH so
you're not just looking at the soil test
but there another tool and your sort of
your agronomist toolbox would you say
yeah exactly you want to use all the
tools you know and we've talked about
you know chemical extractions paste
extractions we talked about tissue
sampling so far and then we're going to
get into resin testing and what that's
going to offer we have all of these
tools and it's not saying though you
know ones may be better than the other
they all have their place and fit and
what we're trying to do is just bridge
the gap between all of these different
tools to help us manage these these
systems great and I think another
important factor is the biological
aspect of all of this so in organic
soils we're counting on the micro
organisms releasing these nutrients so
the the soil tests that we talked about
so far all of these tests sort of give
us an idea of all of what's in the soil
not
Sara Lee what's available and that's
where the having good biological
activity and the soil helps release
these nutrients to the plant
now the biological is even in commercial
agriculture logical agriculture becoming
one of the biggest sectors or increasing
sales or in biologicals and we're really
starting to realize even in commercial
agricultural systems that biologics play
a huge role in soils and keeping those
soils essentially alive and you know the
more micro new molecular organisms the
more activity we have going on in those
soils are continually breaking down
nutrients holding nutrients and it's
just a much better system than having
you know more of a chemical fallow type
system where you essentially are not
promoting that biological aspect of
those systems great so let's dive in a
little bit more about the soil savvy
test now I grilled you guys when I first
found out about your product I was
really excited for the potential of it
and I want to just kind of go through
some of that conversation that we had
you know months ago in terms of some of
the questions I had about the soil savvy
test so can you talk give a little
background into what what the test is
and how it works
sure yeah so the soil savvy test really
started with and with the foundation of
what we call our ion exchange resin
technology this technology was acquired
by our company out of Montana State
University and really we've spent most
of our time in commercial agriculture
building the foundation the baselines
for for resin soil testing and
agriculture but what we've done is asked
after we've built that foundation and
got traction and agriculture we really
moved into more specialty type systems
all the way to where we're offering what
we're calling soil savvy which is more
for our independent gardeners our
homeowners that that need access to a
soil test
they can read they can understand they
can interpret and then it also provides
them with an actionable item a
recommendation for both an organic or
synthetic fertilizer to help them you
know with their with their cropping
system so the base of soil savvy the
soil savvy test kit really came out of
commercial agriculture and even when we
look at the turfgrass applications that
are available with soil savvy those came
from
you know golf courses sports turf fields
all that data that backs that up came
from these applications and we've just
moved that to make it available to the
homeowner or the home or the local
landscaper there's a lot of applications
for this soil savvy product so
essentially the way it works is like a
an artificial or synthetic route in
terms of you're putting the soil into a
tiny container with a little gel like
resin yeah so the resins themselves are
in what we call a resin capsule and as
tad mentioned this is essentially
mimicking a plant root and the way that
that our system works is that these ion
exchange resins can only absorb
nutrients from the soil if it's in a
form available for plant uptake so if
you have nutrients in your soil and
they're not actually in a form available
for plant uptake say they're tied up
your phosphorus is tied up with your
calcium or your pH is reducing the
availability of your phosphorus the
resins are really going to account for
that so we talked about our standard
soil analysis or chemical extractions
they're really telling us okay this is
what's in our soil but it doesn't
necessarily mean that those nutrients
are in a form available for plant uptake
so now we have the resin test that's
going to tell us the actual available
portion of our nutrients in our soil
that are going to be available to the
plant it's almost like taking
a tissue test in the soil we have a lot
of data that correlates what we see in
the soil with the resin test back to
tissue concentrations in the plant so
it's almost like taking a tissue test
but in the soil and we're also on the
predictive side we're predicting an
excess of a nutrient or deficiency of
the nutrient in the soil
prior to even planting a plant or
starting a cropping system so we have
the ability to go in and amend that soil
or build it to what we need based on
nutrient availability of that particular
soil I'm glad you mentioned tissue
testing because that's something that
with cannabis is not available - I'd say
you know 95% of the growers out there
because of the fact it is it is cannabis
so having the ability to get something
that will offer you know similar results
as tissue testing in a form that is
affordable but also easy to access I
think is really a handy tool for growers
so like you mentioned the Mallik test or
the Logan labs test that we've been
using is the standard soil test will
tell us everything in the soil more or
less in an idea of what it is and then
the soil savvy test will tell us what's
currently available out of all those
nutrients into the soil because it
really doesn't matter how much total
calcium I have if not enough of it's in
the form that the plant can actually
uptake it I think that's really
important so on that note let's talk
about ways you could utilize this test
to actually make some good changes in
your garden so for example for me I love
the idea that knowing if I get a bumper
crop with a particular cultivar that I'm
growing I could test that soil and set
that as my benchmark standard for future
crops so if my next crop isn't quite as
good I could do another test and know
relatively quickly oh my my manganese
levels are dropped off and maybe that's
the difference or my calcium levels are
lower whatever a particular micro macro
nutrient has changed I can make
relatively quick adjustments to that
soil would you agree with that yeah yeah
I think that's a great way to position
and the test within within those systems
you're always comparing back and forth
we mentioned this you know many times
just in this podcast you know that we're
always we're always watching the plants
and we're always comparing that back to
our analysis of our soil that we that we
currently have available in making you
know those changes even though the
analysis might not come back and tell
you the exact thing you need to be doing
you know as managers we're continuing to
compare you know what we're seen and
make adjustments as we go
speaking of adjustments the other way I
thought this tests would be really handy
would be I could take a test a slow Savi
test apply a particular fertilizer or
nutrient and then do another test say a
few days later a week later two weeks
later at whatever point in time frame I
want to know how available that actual
application had been to the plant would
you hear that yeah that that's a great
way we're doing that in agriculture as
well and really you know when we have a
limited amount an unlimited amount of
fertility products out there on the
market biologicals
they all claim have claims you know that
they do certain things or provide the
best nutrient availability but we really
don't know once we apply those nutrients
to the soil or those biologicals you
know the effects we haven't been able to
really quantify those those effects of
these applications but with the with the
resin technology we can we can we can
take a test we can look at our baseline
soil before an application then we can
apply either a biological or certain
nutrient package that is available to
you guys that you're using we can apply
it to the soil wait a little bit of time
maybe a week or so come back soil test
again send that in and look at the you
know the efficacy or the value of the
nutrient that we applied maybe that that
nutrient in your specific soil type
isn't the right one and you can make
adjustments to determine you know which
products are really the best for the
soil types that you're growing
more plants in and one other thing I
want to touch on for me was what was the
big difference between saturated pace
tests and this soil savvy test then
because they're both essentially telling
you what's soluble or more available to
the plant and one of the features of the
soil savvy test I liked was that this
artificial resin or root sits in the
solution for five days so it's giving us
a little more accuracy of what's
breaking down and available over that
time period rather than just a snapshot
of what's available right when the right
when the lab technician is doing that
saturated pace test is there any other
differences there that you'd like to
highlight yeah no I you know just a high
level of thinking of the two different
testing methods you know our saturated
paste essentially is going to tell us
you know what's in the solution phase so
they're adding water they're spending
that sample and they're taking the
solution and looking at what's in that
solution phase the resin technology of
the soil savvy is going to look at what
nutrients are in that in the solution
phase but it goes beyond that because
once the nutrients are adsorbed out of
the solution phase by the by the resin
it then starts to exchange for available
nutrients on exchange sites so it goes
beyond just that snapshot of what's in
the solution phase it's going to tell us
okay once we've absorbed nutrients from
the solution phase what's that soils
ability to continue to provide available
nutrients once we have beds orbed it
from the solution phase and that's where
the resins are very dynamic and seeing
what the plants actually going to see in
that soil type because we absorb from
the solution phase and then we go and
adsorb from the cation exchange sites on
on the soils and we know what those that
soils ability is to continue to provide
available nutrient that's great one
other thing that I forgot to mention
earlier that I get asked a lot are about
these home soil test kits that you see
it like you know home depot your local
garden center do you have any comments
on those I know I have some thoughts but
I'd let you go first
ah you know I haven't spent I know
Brandon our VP of Martin new market
development
here at Univest has spent a little more
time looking into those systems but
they're so general in what they provide
even pH testing you know at laboratories
still today as a as Todd mentioned
earlier it can vary you know almost a
half a pH unit depending on the lab and
how they do pH is and I can only think
that the variability in a home test kit
for pH and other you know even NPK can
be highly variable and I think the level
of you know soil testing and management
of where where we're at today I just
don't think you know that's that's gonna
be enough to provide us with actionable
recommendations yeah you know I found
these home kits to be very inaccurate
personally and I we won't tell them an
hour that our feet farm and feed store
or garden center because I just don't
think they give us good information as
you mentioned these these tests you know
they're they're doing alright there
you're going to see a color change
sometimes so you're being asked to
interpret a color and that's really
challenging a lot of ways and you guys
have a lot of expensive you know
equipment that you're using and so for
me to spend twenty five to thirty
dollars on a soil test and send it into
a laboratory that's going to have a
technician that's trained on
interpreting the results and also using
much more expensive lab equipment than I
can afford at my you know in my garden
to interpret those results I think is
really important so moving on here now
that we've kind of covered your tests
and also these other types of soil tests
and the way they can be used can we talk
a little bit more about what someone
might see on a soil test in terms of
what these you know what these different
categories or numbers are and what what
they really mean can we talk a little
bit more about what what pH is yeah so
on the soil test I guess we'll kind of
transition more to speaking about the
soil savvy test but any test when we
talk about nutrients a lot of times
you're going to see the pH or the
percent hydrogen and you're also going
to see parts per million values apart
per million of nutrient you may see
percentages so there's a lot of
different things you're going to see on
on a soil test I guess first to talk
specifically to pH what we're looking at
is the percent hydrogen in that in that
soil and so it's a reverse logarithm of
the amount of hydrogen in the soil so if
you think about it the more hydrogen
that you have free hydrogen in the soil
or on exchange sites that's going to
decrease your pH and the less hydrogen
you have you you're going to have a
higher pH and pH is really you know the
first thing that we want to tackle when
we look at a soil test if your pH is you
know either high or low that's one of
the first things that we want to adjust
before we start to tackle you know some
of the other nutrients so if we have a
low pH for example you know maybe we're
down at five or five point five pH you
know that's pretty low for for most of
our plants with the exception of you
know blueberries as a elyes
rhododendrons you know you can be at
those lower PHS they thrive at those
lower PHS but most of our most of our
crops do the best you know between a six
and a seven pH so if our pH is low you
know we're really going to want to look
at you know some liming applications and
limes essentially calcium carbonate that
we're adding to the soil and that's
going to help you know kick off some of
these free hydrogens get rid of those
hydrogen's and increase our our pH in
the soil if we have soil test that comes
back with low magnesium you know and our
pH as low we might want to use a
dolomitic lime and this is going to have
your magnesium component in there so if
you have low low pH and low magnesium
you'll want to use a dolomitic line
because that will help you increase your
magnesium as well as increase your pH so
when you look at a soil test that's one
of the first things I look at is what is
the pH of my soil and justed by just
adjusting pH alone you can also make
more nutrient available that wasn't
available at that lower pH so as we
increase that pH we can increase
nutrient availability and that might
solve a lot of our deficiency problems
alone just by adjusting pH we've talked
about against low pH now what do we do
for high pH you know we're going to want
to use more ammonium type products
ammonium sulfate or similar products
because now we want to add these
hydrogen's and these acidifying
components back into the soil to
decrease the pH and in the same way as
we did with the low pH we might increase
nutrient availability of certain
nutrients that weren't available under
the original pH regime so pH is a very
good place to start with your soil test
and really get that balance before you
start to tackle your macro and
micronutrients
yeah I'll post the pH availability chart
which is sort of what you were kind of
discussing there as you were talking
about pH so people can see at what
levels things are available and one
thing that's interesting too is as you
mentioned certain things are available
more available at certain PHS and some
things are at lower pH are more
available that you don't actually want
like aluminum for example or some of the
heavy metals so keeping the pH above you
know certain levels is really important
as well and this is a really complicated
topic
you know people obviously go to school
for a long time for this and there's lot
of stuff we're still learning so we're
just going really basic into it but
there's a lot of put up other resources
for people who want to read more the
other aspect of pH and I just wanted to
mention is I've seen some good research
showing that the plant can actually
buffer the pH in the rhizosphere based
on the exudates it puts out to select
for certain microorganisms so I've heard
that the pH can vary a fair bit so
that's how you can get plants that can
survive in you know less than optimal pH
ranges in terms of the soil test but
they can still thrive have you seen any
research on this yourself yeah yeah yeah
plants
definitely do that they can adjust for
certain environmental conditions I guess
one caveat to that mean saying they
might not be thriving they might they
may just be managing you know to get by
so I wouldn't you know just think that
the plants can adjust to these things
because everything that plants having to
you know give out or those plant
exudates you know those are all being
created you know through through light
through sunlight you know that's all
have to be transferred those are all
processes that take energy to do that to
buffer out you know the offset these
soil factors so we really want to still
focus on the soil but tadd is correct
that plants can adjust for some of these
things but you know obviously in the
cannabis industry we have a very great
opportunity to really get these soils
exactly where we want them you know
especially with the resin technology and
I really wanted to also talk about you
know the value of the resin technology
we've talked about all these chemical
extractions we talked about pH and how
complicated all of these components are
which extraction is the best one you
know what do I do the great thing about
the resin technology that we've
developed is its accounting for all
those things for you it's kind of doing
that work for you in a sense you know
the pH of your soil is going to tell you
what nutrients are available the resins
are going to adsorb those so it takes
some of that that work or that thought
out of thinking you know which
extraction is the best or what nutrients
are actually available and so I like to
think of the resin as doing a lot of
that work for us that we've tried to
figure out in the past ya know that's a
good point as we as we move on to some
of these other topics some of these
things that I'd like to cover not
necessarily on the soil savvy test most
of them are but I'm actually looking at
a may like three tests right now in my
screen to so I just kind of want to
cover both one of the the ones that they
offer you too is your organic matter
percentage can we talk a little about
what that number tells us yeah so our
organic mint
matter percentages is a important factor
in in our soils and you know really it's
tied to ability of soils to hold water
or certain percent moisture is really
tied to the amount of organic matter it
really controls say the amount of
irrigation that we can apply at one time
the holding capacity of that soil but
it's also tied to nutrient holding
capacity and more cation exchange sites
the amount of organic matter as you
increase it's going to have the ability
to to hold on to more nutrient the
ability to release more nutrient if our
microbial populations are good it's
going to continually break down this
organic matter and release more nutrient
into our soil so having organic matter
in the soil is very important obviously
when we get into our sandy or soil
systems typically they have less organic
matter they have less ability to hold
water nutrient and those systems are a
little bit tougher to manage but the
downside of too much organic matter also
is that organic matter can tie up
nutrient very readily and make it not
available so as you apply these
nutrients that we talked about these
products there's a chance that in some
soils that organic matter could tie that
up immediately and it may become
available over time as it gets broken
down by these microbial population these
organisms that may be become available
over time but if you're managing the
lifecycle of a plant in a very short
period of time we need to be working
with nutrient you know that's more
available more readily available into
that solution phase in that short amount
of time that we're managing that we
don't want to try and manage nutrient
that's going to be available in a year
or two we want a mad managed nutrient
that's out of mediate availability yeah
and the other thing about organic matter
percentage to that I've found is because
we're dealing with a lot of people using
potting soils is that high level can
break down over the time so you may have
you know 20% less soil at the end of
your crop cycle then when you started
because the microorganisms are breaking
that material down toward you know the
cue makasian of that soil and so it's
important to account for that if you
plan on reusing your soil to realize
that you're going to have a lot less
soil come recycling time if your organic
matter percentage is higher and any of
these potting soils are going to be a
lot higher than say a field or
agricultural soil we're typically trying
to get organic matter percentage above 5
percent and if you get up into 10
percent you know you're you're rocking
from an agricultural perspective but
from a potting soil perspective that's
very low one so you kind of already
jumped into the next one that I want to
talk about which is a cation exchange
capacity or total exchange capacity
you'll see it as CEC or tea CEC on soil
tests can you talk a little bit about
that you kind of already touched on it I
know ya know this is a very important
component and one of those components
that we talked about what the resins are
kind of telling us as far as nutrient
availability so our CEC or our cation
exchange capacity is a measurement of
the amount of nutrient or exchange
exchangeable sites on a particular soil
so these are negatively charged sites on
a soil particle and this is kind of a
scale or an idea of like high CEC soils
versus low CEC soils they a clay type
soil because of the the type of soil the
amount of surface area on a clay is
going to have the most negative exchange
sites and so it's going to have ability
to hold on to a lot more of our
positively charged nutrients or calcium
or potassium or magnesium it's got the
ability to hold on to a lot more of that
at one time essentially versus our
sandier soils are going to have a low
cation exchange capacity or a low amount
of negative exchange sites to hold
nutrients so it's very important and how
we load soils with nutrient and their
ability is to actually hold that that
nutrient
so as we mentioned in a sandier soil you
know I might not be able to put as much
nutrient down at one time because I
don't have the exchange capacity to tie
up or hold those nutrients on those
exchange sites versus a high organic
matter or CC soil like with clay you're
going to have a lot more exchange sites
to hold on to a larger amount of
nutrient at one time so it's a very
important measure you know of your soil
and its nutrient holding capacity so as
Todd mentioned you know in in commercial
agriculture we're trying to shoot for
you know four or five percent organic
matter you know on those soil types but
in the systems that you guys are
managing with potting soil those
percentages are going to be much higher
so that and CC is going to allow you to
load those soils much more upfront and
have the ability to carry it out through
the lifecycle of the of the plant versus
lower CEC soils and lower organic matter
soil so always look at your CEC levels
of your soil one thing that is really
tied to CEC - and I think everybody
should ask for this test as a base
saturation test and this is a very
critical test because this is going to
essentially tell us the the balance of
bases in our soil so this is the balance
of our calcium to our magnesium and to
our potassium and the availability of
those nutrients is very much tied to
that that base saturation you know
typically on a good soil when we look at
a base saturation measurement about
seventy five percent you know of our our
base saturation should be calcium so 75%
of those exchange sites roughly should
be taken up or occupied by calcium about
four to seven percent of those exchange
sites should be occupied by potassium
and then the remaining exchange sites
should be applied by our magnesium which
i think is usually around you know
twelve to fifteen
or so of those exchange sites so when
you guys get a test the base saturation
is very critical because depending on
the balance of those nutrients on that
exchange site it's really going to turn
determine the availability of those
nutrients if if we have a too much
calcium and magnesium on those exchange
sites we're going to have very low base
saturation number four potassium which
is a very key nutrient and most of our
plants and so look at that base
saturation number to get familiar with
those numbers if they're offered to you
we don't do that on the soil savvy test
but this is one reason why we want to
use all the tools that are available you
know at Universal Savi we're not saying
to not do a standard soil analysis
because we've talked about the the
critical components of these tests the
base saturation the CEC these components
that we don't offer with just the
availability test at soil savvy so use
these tools in conjunction with one
another as we mentioned to give yourself
the best opportunity to to manage these
soils yeah you know I like to think of
CC sort of as a giant sponge and it's a
little bit of a double-edged sword in
the sense that with a soil with a low
CEC it's not going to take very much
nutrients to fill that sponge but then
it's not going to hold as much nutrients
either so we're going to apply nutrients
more frequently whereas something with a
high CEC it's going to hold a lot more
nutrients but it's going to take a lot
more to fill that sponge as well so you
have to keep that in mind too when
you're looking at your your cation
exchange capacity so really really high
it's not necessarily a lot better it
just means you have to manage that soil
differently now in terms of baits bass
saturation percentage you know I've read
a few different books on the subject and
everyone sort of has a slightly
different idea of what they call an
optimal level or optimal range I know
currently I'm I'm reading a book by Neil
Kinsey and he likes to have calcium
around 68% and magnesium at 12%
depending on your crop your potassium
labels levels may vary
I like to run potassium a little bit
higher with cannabis but that person
based saturation is essentially what
percentage of that sponge is what
nutrient and like you mentioned you know
high calcium can cause less magnesium or
potassium availability these things all
interact together and there's
relationships between these different
nutrients and it gets really really
complicated and I still is a lot of it's
still over my head and I'm still
learning a lot myself because they'll be
relationships between you know zinc and
another another nutrient or iron or
phosphorus and and there's all these
levels and in relationships that get
very complicated I guess is there
anything uh do you want to talk about in
that regard or don't move on to the next
the next thing on the soil report yeah
sure I mean like like you said everybody
there's kind of different ranges for
these nutrients and you know one of the
things that had just mentioned is you
know potassium in the cannabis system
just like in you know Tomatoes is huge
and a lot of ranges for potassium are
often too low for these crops and so
when we look at nutrient levels for
potassium it might say that you're in
the range for potassium in the range for
that specific lab or even our soil savvy
test it might say that you're in the
range but I would say that you know for
a cannabis you're going to want to be at
the high end or even above that range
because we know that cannabis is a hot
as a high demand for potassium and so we
want to actually be at the higher end of
that range so don't let the range is
totally dictate you know where you're at
it might come back that you're
sufficient but you could still see
deficiencies in your tissue samples that
you take or just visual deficiency
symptoms and that's because it's but
saying that you're in range but maybe a
lot of that potassium is not available
or you just need to continue to increase
the amount of potassium to displace some
of that calcium magnesium because you
need more potassium for that specific
crop that you're managing where those
levels might be
for another crop we needed to manage the
high demand nutrient now it's kind of my
second thing after pH we want to look at
our macronutrients and see you know what
our macro nutrient levels are you know
and that really leads into you know
potassium looking at our n P and K
levels and you know where those levels
are at and if I have a plant that
requires a high amount of a certain
nutrient we want to address that
nutrient yeah that's a really good point
that you bring up there that these
recommendations are like you said just
their guidelines and we need to adjust
them for our specific crops and in
addition traditionally these
recommendations to by you know by
naghralla just by a lab to a farmer
would be just enough to get that crop to
grow for an optimal yield they're not
trying to necessarily build the soil so
as an organic farmer as we're trying to
reuse the soil and have this high-value
cash crop our recommendations may we may
want to vary our guidelines based on
that and actually put a little bit more
into the soil or try and do a little bit
more to build the quality of the soil
for successive you know successive
generations of crops
all right so Chris one of the other
questions I had was that you don't see
nitrogen on like for example the Logan
lab standard soil test the may like
three tests can you talk a little about
why that might be yeah I think a lot of
times we don't get a nitrogen
measurement maybe unless it's specially
requested um on a test because a lot of
times if they're doing a grower is doing
like a pre plant soil sample usually
they're looking at nitrates only and
most of these tests and they typically
may assume that those nitrates are going
to be readily lost or leached out of the
system by the time you get to growing
the crops so they might soil test you
know two or three months before the
actual crop goes in the ground so they
would assume that most any nitrates and
most systems may be lost prior to the
crop going in and so a lot of times they
may not offer the the nitrate test
unless it's maybe specific
we requested one good thing about the
soil savvy test is we're going to give
you a measurement of nitrate in your
soil but we're also going to give you a
measurement of the amount of ammonium in
your soil that's going to be available
to the plant typically ammonium has been
a lot tougher nutrient to analyze for
with the standard analysis methods but
it's very easily absorbed by our resins
and our resin blends so we're going to
give you the nitrate and ammonium
portions of nutrient in the soil and
that's really important to kind of
managing the ratios of those nutrients
to one another you know we don't want to
be leaching or pushing a lot of nitrates
through our system so we can also build
up nitrogen levels with ammonium which
can be held on exchange sites are not
near as leachable as our as our nitrates
so we want to balance out the amount of
nitrate to ammonium in these systems a
lot more a lot of the organic soils tend
to have more ammonium higher ammonium
levels than nitrate so just look for
that on the soil savage test and see
what your balance is of these nitrogen
components and try and balance those out
because we don't really want to even
though we're a lot of times indoor and
potting systems we're not pushing
nitrates through and into the
environment we could be recycling them
even we just don't want to waste them
and push them through if we don't need
them so look at the balance of your
nitrate to your ammonium in your soil
savvy results as well yeah excess
nitrates is a big problem with the
cannabis industry in terms of
contributing to algal blooms and other
problems with our with our groundwater
so if we can optimize or even limit the
amount of nitrogen that we're using not
only does it save us money but it's a
lot better for the environment that kind
of leads me to my next question so if
you were a cannabis grower and you were
looking to utilize soil testing and
we're reusing your soil say in in the
ground or in raised beds how would you
go about what would your protocol be for
that sort of a thing yeah you know what
I would do is you know at the
at the end of the growing time I would
obviously put all these soils in one
place composite these soils all together
really well and I would pull a soil
sample or two and look at you know where
our nutrient levels are at you know even
run a standard soil analysis and see
where our organics at now where our base
saturations are where our available
nutrient levels are run the run these
tests get an idea where they're at and
then now we're going to have a baseline
of that soil after it's after it's been
used and now that we could actually
rebuild that soil by knowing what our
target nutrient levels are and soil
savvy is going to give you a general
recommendation or guideline of how we
could do this we could come back and
once again introduce our biologicals and
kind of rebuild this soil after we've
already grown a crop in the soil so
don't think about it just pre you know
pre plant and in season but also after
season and recycling these soils so you
can give me your comments on this but
for me I like to know everything that's
in the soil so I use that that may like
three tests at the end of the cycle to
find out all of what's still left in
that soil and then that soil savvy test
can be taken at the same time as a way
to see what's currently available for
that plant if I were to plant right back
into it and then I could amend that soil
and retest prior to planting and I think
what people need to keep in mind is they
think of soil testing as an expense but
we're talking about a really valuable
crop here where it's all it could save
you tons of money down the road with
such a high value crop you can't afford
to have crop loss in in most cases with
cannabis it's just it's too much money
throwing down the drain so spending you
know 50 bucks a hundred dollars couple
hundred dollars depending on your scale
on on the soil test to get you that
information I think is really really
important and one thing that you touched
on was you know mixing all that so all
together in one place well a lot of our
growers may be growing different
cultivars in
in raised beds for example where you're
not necessarily you're not necessarily
going to be able to move that soil or
Rehim ionize it what do you think about
taking you know samples from different
beds and then just using that as a
general guideline for where your soils
at or do you think people should be
sampling every bed if they're going to
be slightly different where do you land
on that topic
I mean if you're managing each bed
differently I think you'd want to sample
each bed alone if you're doing the same
thing across multiple beds you can go
ahead and just take soil cores or
portions of soil from each of those beds
and then composite them together in a
bucket with your hand get a good
composite of that soil and that's going
to give you a good representation of all
of those beds but yeah if you're
managing the beds differently for
different characteristics you're going
to want to test them individually and
there's some good examples on how to
take a soil sample online but a couple
points I want to hint at is that you
want to go down on at least six inches
and it's important to use either you
know I guess you could use your hand I
always used to you'd like to use a
plastic shovel or a core sampler because
if you use say for example a really a
rusty old hand trowel you're potentially
adding a lot of iron to that soil sample
so there's little things you want to
think about too when you're sampling and
making sure that you're getting an
accurate mix or sample of your your
given soil so that you can get a more
accurate result yeah that's a that's a
great point you know you don't want to
introduce other factors into your soil
test that might throw it off such as a
rusty you know soil probe or shovel you
want to make sure that's clean because I
could definitely throw off throw off
your your analysis I think it's critical
you know for for professionals that are
doing this all the time to invest in a
soil probe they're not that expensive
you can find them online very easily you
know invest in a soil probe it's it's
it's a critical tool I think to have in
any curve anybody who's managing a
cropping system and then you know as we
get into potted plants say we're in
season during the growing time
and we want to you know test like Midway
you know through the season see where
levels are you know you might want a
smaller diameter probe that's not going
to pull as big of a core you know out of
the pots but maybe take multiple take a
core from multiple pots but we want a
smaller diameter core when we do that so
we're not you know disrupting a ton of
routing mass as we pull that soil sample
out of each of the pots yeah that's a
really good point you know we have a at
work I have a course sampler and then I
also have a compaction tool it's like it
looks like kind of like a super
scaled-down like I don't know maybe a
jackhammer shape that you push down into
soil and it tells you how much you know
psi are pressure you have as you go down
so you can see how much slow compaction
there's a lot of really fun you know
little tools and gadgets out there that
can help you in analyzing your soil
better and making you know actionable
decisions about how to manage your cell
fertility and manager so better I might
throw one other kind of idea or concept
in there to think about when your soil
sampling we I mean in with the cannabis
stuff we really like to build that soil
you know prior to the plant going in and
get our guitar levels for most of our
nutrients where they are and then as we
go into planting and afterwards in
season we want to understand say maybe
we put some slow-release or some coded
fertilizers or prills or some type of
prills and in that pot we need to
understand you know one if we have those
prills in there when we're taking the
soil sample because one of those prills
can really throw off a soil sample so it
could come back very skewed so the more
we can build our soil up front and then
if we need to test in season we don't
have those big pearls and stuff in that
in that pot we just want to avoid any of
those type of things that are going to
skew your data and it's usually pretty
obvious when you hit those type of
things
you're gonna get you know just huge
numbers that are you know off the chart
or any any scale because one pril of
anything can really throw off
test so you know be aware of your
management system where you've placed
nutrient and try to avoid you know those
large those prills if you can but I
think building the soil out front is
really going to give you know the best
results for most of our macronutrients
you might manage nitrogen in season a
little bit a little bit differently but
I think building that soil upfront is
really key when you say prills I see we
talk about something like Osmocote yeah
that's sort of its product yeah then you
know we're big proponents on this
podcast of getting people to go organic
to really build their soil and consider
their biggest resource on their farm so
a lot of what you're saying just really
speaks to sort of our philosophy around
farming and gardening and cannabis
cultivation in general again I just want
to say thank you for taking the time
today to chat about soil testing and
I'll be sure to put up some more
information including that pH
availability chart some sample test
results and links to the soil savvy test
and website information as well as some
good resources that people want to dive
further down into all of this soil
testing and in books they can check out
so yeah thanks for your time Chris I
really appreciate it and look forward to
talking again soon thank you ted
that was chris boardman with yuna best
international makers of the soil savvy
test kit which we currently have
available on our website for only $30
with free shipping the kits come with a
self-addressed envelope with prepaid
postage so it's super easy to take a
sample and send it into the lab for
results I encourage everyone to look
into soil testing as a way of improving
both the fertility of your soil but also
as a way of increasing yield and
reducing plant stress some places like
King County here in Washington State
offer three free soil tests to every
homeowner and while these tests are
basic and information they give you it
is a good starting point and your local
Extension Service may have something
available to you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host Todd Hussey don't forget
that there's more information articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
is organics calm as well as links to the
data and information we discussed in
this episode on the podcast page and if
you enjoy these podcasts please take a
moment to leave me a review on itunes or
send me your feedback and suggestions
through our website contact page or ta d
@ kiss organics calm thanks for
listening
[Music]