[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe to our
newsletter on our home page at WWE is
organics calm to stay up to date on the
latest podcast product announcements and
videos our guest this week is Kurt
Becker Kurt is the executive vice
president of commercial products for the
DRAM Corporation for anyone looking to
improve the efficacy of their spray
applications I highly suggest checking
out this podcast and reaching out to
dram directly I got to hear Kurt speak
at a bio controlls conference last year
and he is a genius when it comes to
spray applications for the past 23 years
current has worked with growers to
improve their spray and irrigation
practices through improved technology
and technique DRAM now in its 76th year
is a leader in horticultural technology
focusing on watering chemical
application air movement and water
quality hey Kurt welcome to the podcast
thanks for coming on today thanks dad
appreciate you having me yeah can we
start out giving listeners a little bit
of a background into your history and
how you came into this role and all this
knowledge regarding spray applications
well most of that is on the job I
studied you know political science in
college I worked in banking before I got
into the horticultural industry I've
been doing this for 24 and 1/2 years as
after a sales role took me into the
company and as in those 24 years you
know I've been very active in developing
a lot of our product line on the Spray
side as well as what we as a lot about
as well as on our philosophies and in
working on a lot of the science behind
what we do from a spray standpoint Oh
that timeframe jerem has really focused
on you know different particle sizes do
different things and making sure that we
think either we know how to make a
different sized droplet the trick is
knowing how to make that applicable to
plant protection and so we've developed
a number of different tools over that
time frame
during my tenure at the company that
basically focus on you know okay we want
to try and achieve this so we make a
droplet that does that or we want you
know we need this much force to get him
in the canopy all sorts of things that
basically all of our different equipment
is designed to do slightly different
things so it's why we have you know I
think we make over 37 different machines
for indoor plant protection we don't
really make equipment for outdoors and
some of our stuff could be used that way
but the majority of what we've done and
where we focus is for indoor plant
growth now when you say indoor you're
talking about greenhouse environments as
well correct any indoor yeah well that's
where we start I mean we are the trim is
a 77 year old company and we've been
involved in the in the greenhouse
industry indoor meaning you got walls
and you got a ceiling and so there's
there's really different characteristics
of a spray that you require and there's
different concerns that you might have
you know when you're spraying outside
versus spraying inside you know a lot of
outdoor spray equipment tends to use
bigger droplets tends to be wet or
applications unless we really bring an
aerial and you need to do that because
there's a lot of concerns one is drift
management we don't want to spray the
neighbors farm we don't want to you know
have stuff drifting into different crops
that we don't that we don't want to
apply a pesticide to indoor it's very
different I'm not really worried about
I'm not really worried about intrusion
into other crops so that allows us to
use a much wider range of droplet sizes
to achieve better coverage if you look
outside a really aerial applications
work very well in very wide open spaces
where you've got the same crop over and
over again and some
use an aerial application which is using
generally smaller droplets although
still much larger than some of the stuff
that we can create for indoor use and
the intent there is that they can cover
a lot greater area a quicker but they
also do it with a lot less liquid
because can't carry you know a tanker
load full of liquid on the plane that
you'd be using to apply the pesticide in
our instance I'm not really worried
about the amount of water that we're
going to apply from transferring it and
carrying it standpoint it's more about
using smaller droplets and then we just
need less water to do the job because we
can create cover much more surface area
the smaller droplets we get so you're
talking about droplet size and how it
affects an application and what I'm
hearing is that the smaller the droplet
size the better surface area or better
coverage you get over that leaf surface
are there other considerations pretty
much that that's the that's the
important effect to pull out of that the
basically it's not only showing a linear
relationship it's actually exponential
when we drop when we cut particle size
we got droplets down into smaller sizes
we cover a lot more surface area because
they themselves have more surface area a
pretty common graphic that we that we
like to use in in communicating that is
just explaining that okay if we took one
100 micron droplet the liquid contained
in 100 micron drop 100 microns is
already pretty small that's about the
size of your hair the diameter of your
hair is about 100 microns if we took one
droplet that was 100 microns and we cut
it in two in that same amount of liquid
we took that same amount of liquid and
made droplets that were 50 microns okay
with the same fluid volume we would get
eight droplets that would be the same
volume of liquid but we would be able to
cover more surface area cuz you know
eight droplets just by cutting the
particle size in half if we take that
and we cut it to a tenth of the original
size or about ten microns we get about a
thousand droplets with the same liquid
contained in the 100 micron droplet so
again we can come
much more surface area if you think
about majority of what we're using to
spray plants is water-based there are
oil based products very few generally
those are never used without without
something else not without being
dissolved in something which is
typically water so if you think about
water water has a very very strong
surface tension it tends to bead up we
can chemically alter that using
surfactants and things like that to help
it spread more evenly but oil in it has
a very low surface tension so it's
spreads it early evenly it's why it's a
good lubricant it spreads out over
surfaces if you think about what we're
doing we're basically doing the same
thing mechanically that a surfactant
might do we're taking that large droplet
and we're making it into a ship we're
spreading it out we happen to be doing
it by chopping it up into tiny little
droplets and spreading it more evenly
instead of a liquid that that spreads on
its own but the effect is the same we're
covering much more surface area if we
take that same example the 100 micron
drop when we cut it to to a twentieth of
the size or about five micron droplets
which is something we can do we get
about 19,000 droplets with the same
liquid contained in the one 100 micron
droplet so if you think to be at the you
know 100 microns is at the very low end
of hydraulics brain there's not a lot of
hydraulic sprayers that put out a
droplet with an average particle size
that's small when we talking about some
of the fog type systems that we have
we're in you know we've got directed fog
that is a 50 micron droplet we've got
ultra low volume fogs that are in the 5
to 10 micron droplets so we can cover a
lot more surface area which is really
where that term actually gets its name
low volume and ultra low volume is
really referring to the amount of liquid
that's used to make the application and
those are in our terms those are those
are industry terms the nice thing about
that even when we talk about hydraulic
sprays because there's a lot of times
right when hydraulic sprays are very
applicable and fog is not always the
best choice but understanding that
relationship of if I take a
and I cut it in it cut the average
particle size in half I'm going to get
about eight times more droplets with the
same liquid in the tank give you give it
basically illustrates the idea that it's
one we can create smaller droplets even
if we don't you know go all the way down
the spectrum we just cut them in half we
can cover certain we can cover more
surface area much more effectively than
we can with bigger droplets and so in a
greenhouse or an indoor space where
we're not really worried about wind
drift contaminating other crops we might
be spring the whole room you know using
the smallest droplet applicable for that
is generally going to be a good thing so
just so I understand when you're not
taking that hundred micron droplet and
cutting it in half in your example
you're saying that if you sprayed a
gallon of 100 micron droplets versus a
gallon of say a hundred or a gallon of
50 micro droplets you're going to get
eight times the coverage would that
exactly okay I want to make sure I
understood the math on there that that
makes a lot of sense actually so that
brings me up to my next question which
was can you use a hundred micron droplet
or a sprayer like that with a surfactant
and achieve the same results as you
would with a smaller droplet size not
necessarily the same results but
surfactants are always a good idea as
long as you know they're they're safe on
the plant you're going to be flying them
too and they're labeled for that plant
or the use
surfactants are generally a very good
idea because you're going to cover more
surface area but you got to get them
there too and so that's where that's
where smaller droplets tend to sometimes
have an advantage you also won't ever
get to the to the reduction in volume
that you will so before talking about
wet spraying or hydraulic spraying even
if we're talking about targeted low
volume so kind of break the world down
into hydraulic sprays or the wet
sprayers that's you know you're you're
spraying a gallon two gallon and a half
a minute the plants are going to be
visibly wet when you've after you've
done your job
you know that's the typical hydraulic
spray that people think of we talk about
targeted low volume we're basically
taking down that spectrum we're creating
droplets in the 50 40 to 60 micron range
typically where we're able to then use a
lot less water a higher concentration of
product to water so we reduce similar
amounts of pesticide we just put it in
less liquid and then we would aim that
as well so there's different types of
machines that we can use to aim that
into the crop so that we can be
selective about where it wants to go so
in that instance where I mentioned
drifted is generally not a concern
indoors in a greenhouse sometimes it is
sometimes I don't want to hit the bench
next to the one I'm trying to treat and
so an ultra low volume treatment when we
get into that five and 10 micron range
that is a space treatment that's flea
bomb so your cat comes home with fleas
you need to bomb the whole house to kill
them all that's what ultra low volume is
we are filling the space with pesticides
and you can't do a bench you are doing
the entire room at that point when we
want to just treat a bench or a portion
of a bench targeted low volume where we
can use smaller droplets but not as
small as we could go we can aim that and
and had it not float away and drift
around the whole house those droplets
tend to follow them much quicker than
say a 5 to 10 micron droplet which can
stay airborne for as much as 3 to 4
hours how do these smaller droplets
affect humidity then over time they must
raise it quite a bit I would think
actually not yes well if we look at a
typical application generally not those
types of nozzles can be used or or
nozzles creating similar droplets can be
used to affect humidity for instance a
frog system so we fell in in other types
of systems we do besides spray
application we do moisture management we
do irrigation systems we do you know
missing systems for propagation with
your drip irrigation and stuff like that
we have nozzles that will create 80
micron droplets and there's other
companies that have drops that have
systems that will create their with high
pressure that can create 10 to 10 10 10
to 20 microns those are typically
distributed systems where you have a
pipe running on your nozzles all over
the place and each one of those nozzles
is going to maybe put out you know 5 3
to 5 liters per hour of liquid when we
look at what we do we're going to do a
similar output but we're gonna do that
for with one novel and we're gonna do
that from one location to try and spread
the pesticide around so you if we if we
use more volume in or if we continued
that operation through a long period we
can increase the humidity but generally
if I say I take a 10,000 square-foot
space
we're generally not adding more than 2
litres of liquid to that or half a
gallon when we're doing a pesticide
application so it's it's generally not
effective admitted grammatically and
then when you think about it if you
compare that to something like a wet
spray if I'm going to put 2 litres into
that space but the wet spray you might
you know put 50 gallons into that or 30
gallons into that same space you know
that amount of moisture is actually
generally more detrimental it can you
know cause more humidity issues then
then say the the low volume application
that makes sense so you're actually
having less of an effect on humidity
than a spray we haven't put out more
liquid that I get what you're saying
there
so overall generally that's the case
yeah before I forget you mentioned
surfactants for organic growers or
gardeners do you have any
recommendations for favorites that
you've seen just over the years that
people are using I don't typically
there's a lot fewer than most of the
ones that are organically approved are
going to be yucca based extracts almost
all of them are SAP and in Vince
versions so happening is a chemistry
chemical in in certain plants that
basically is it's almost it's a it's a
loose
and based surfactant Sappington is is an
active ingredient and a number of
different organically registered
products so that you could use you know
that are applicable for organic
production as far as specific brands
there's there's not any of them that I
would definitely recommend necessarily
recommend over another because they're
all fairly similar in the way that they
work they're normally yucca based but
there aren't some other basis of Sapa
and that you can you can get generally
those tend to work pretty well we
actually there's a couple that we've
done some tests with with regard
specifically to one piece of equipment
we make you know I mentioned the the
ultra low volume range we really create
droplets in very different ways so we
have you know we have different methods
to make smaller droplets we can use high
pressure hydrogen hydrostatic pumps we
can use aerosol generation systems so
basically we're using air in a very
precise manner to chop the droplets up
here the droplets and spread and then
apply them we also have volume based air
systems where we use high velocity
volumes of air to shatter the droplets
those ladder systems tend to be a little
bit more sloppy in the way that they
create a droplet they're not as accurate
as far as how evenly they'll they'll
break up the droplets in those cases we
typically require some type of
surfactant to help with that process so
that we want to make so in non non
organic agriculture we are using a
product of our own design but it's not
Omri to prove it's not it's not
organically approvable it's basically
it's a salt based product in those
instances we can use some of this happen
in based products to help that machine
do its job basically reduce the surface
tension of the water so that as we
shatter it with that velocity and volume
of air we're able to shatter the
droplets more evenly and get a much
better result as far as distribution
through the through the facility so
as someone who is a grower gardener that
has a greenhouse or an indoor garden
where they're cultivating what sort of
like practical considerations in terms
of actual sprayers would you recommend
for them to have on hand in a given
situation like this like you mentioned
having a way of applying to the entire
space which seems really important what
they also need to have one for targeted
spraying and what what if you could
recommend specific sprayers I think that
would be useful too okay well as I said
before you know the low volume stuff is
a great time-saver great labor saver
generally does a really good job of
applying pesticides but it's not always
applicable so what when when we look at
someone say you're just starting out
looking for a new piece of equipment and
you need your you know you've got a
greenhouse area but you want to spray we
generally start with a good hydraulic
sprayer we like to see machines run up
to at least 500 psi we make a number of
machines our Hydra and our MSO line both
run up to 500 psi and then we like to
make sure that one of the things we see
in greenhouses
quite often and someone might have a
machine capable of 500 psi but they turn
it up to 250 or 300 the machines are
meant to work at higher pressures and
there's a reason why you may want to
reduce pressure for business for some
specific applications but for the most
part if you're trying to apply a
pesticide a fungicide to the plant and
you're not worried about things like
drifting on to the next crop or you know
you're generally not going to damage the
plant by increasing the pressure because
the nozzles generally taking care of
that by helping you manufacture a
smaller droplet of course if you've got
a nozzle that's putting out two plus
gallons a minute
higher pressure can be a problem but
nozzles that are meant for fine
application which anything that we would
sell would would come standard ly with
that the higher the pressure generally
means the the finer the droplets we're
going to create plus we also get
the added benefit of more force so you
know when we're trying to apply
pesticides to a plant a lot of the
things we're trying to target aren't
sitting on the outside of the leaves and
they're sitting at the top of the papal
growth or inhales they're not I mean
easy spot to get there generally hiding
inside the plant and they do that
because it's the safest place for them
so if we want to get whitefly or spider
mite or somebody that's up underneath we
want to target mildew or botrytis at the
stem or things that we have to you know
really get into the canopy droplets
gonna help but also some force you need
something to actually propel that
product into the crop and so when you
have a higher pressure it's actually
giving you a little bit more force to to
push that spray in the plant now we
don't want force like a pressure washer
force we don't want something that's
very hard straight stream we want force
with very fine droplets so you end up
with a very swirling spray you end up
with very diffuse droplets that the
force is there but it rapidly dissipates
when it encounters other forces like a
plant it'll hit that plan and spread as
opposed to you know battering the plant
so a combination there you're looking at
particle size and pressure you want to
always make sure you have the right
nozzle in married to that so we'd start
with something that's a good up to 500
psi sprayer but as I said there's times
when you may want to reduce that
pressure so variable pressure is
important when you're looking at a
sprayer you want to make sure you can
turn down the pressure because sometimes
you may want to spray just a little
section and you don't want it drifting
on something else there's plenty of
different products that we use
commercially plant growth regulators
where I want that on a specific set of
plants and I don't want it drifting all
over the place there's some times when I
might need to springe the soil or just
get the soil slightly moist and fine
droplets don't help me with that you
know I need a little bit coarser of a
droplet so it'll actually impact the
soil and and and soak in a little bit so
pressure can you know altering your
pressure can help
with that so variability is important we
look at Venn things like you know that
the next thing that I would suggest
that's probably the next most important
besides a good solid pressurized system
is usability and ease of use you're
gonna go and spray a greenhouse and take
time doing it it's not a real fun job I
don't think there's a lot of people
would say that's something that they
really enjoy doing it's a job that's a
necessary thing but it's not anybody's
favorite job and so our beliefs as a
company is we want to make it as easy as
possible for the applicator the harder
it gets for the applicator the worst job
they do in our opinion they're
uncomfortable they've got to run back to
the machine because a hose keeps getting
caught and pinched against the side wall
the thing is a real bear to move around
you know 50 gallons we've got a lot of
machines that are fifty hundred even 200
allen sprayers someone has to move that
it better be very very easy to maneuver
because 50 gallons is 200 pounds so
moving that you know it's important to
make sure that that it's designed well
to be able to maneuver you've selected
the right wheels for the type of surface
you're going to be covering with it
you've got the right kind of reel that
doesn't create a pinch point so you're
20 feet out and the hose gets pinched up
against a side wall and you got to run
back to the machine to undo it
you want to look for guns that have that
are comfortable to hold when you're
pulling the trigger there's some guns
that are out there where you basically
you know they're like an exercise what
like one of those spring Z that they
used to have in the eighties for you
know building up your forearms and your
grip that there it's got a very tight
spring and so when you pull the trigger
they they're there's a lot of force
involved you want to find things that
are more comfortable to use because if
you're not comfortable doing the job and
you're constantly having to deal with
issues around the equipment generally
the job suffers it's our opinion so we
spend a lot of our time designing for
designing for
of use and comfort so when we look at
hydraulic sprayers any of our equipment
is going to fit into those types of
things we want to make sure that they're
easy to use we want to make sure they've
got they've got a good a good range of
pressure but also that they can get up
to about 500 psi to create a fine
droplet and then beyond that you know as
long as those types of things are
covered I think you're gonna you're
going to start out just great from there
that's when we start to talk to people
about maybe you want to think about a
little volume machine to cut some of the
time that you're putting into this but
if you're starting out a good hydraulic
sprayer is the best place to start okay
and that kind of robbing my next
question because the moment you said
smaller droplets I immediately thought
of compost tea applications or microbial
based applications where in my
experience a smaller droplet can
sometimes an higher force can lead to
actually being quite damaging to
microbial life can you touch a little
bit on options in that regard and your
experiences and what you're finding to
an extent that can be indication it
depends on the manufacturers
recommendations there are certainly some
products whether they're compost teas or
microbial products where you are
applying say an antenna Pathak fungi
that's going to parasitize a white fly
or do you want to be aware of the
limitations of those those microbes I
know that certain pressures can cause
damage and so you have to be very well
aware that other things that are going
to impact those applications is
filtration you know every one of the
sprayers we make has filters in them and
it's and that's done to protect the
system protect the nozzle protect the
investment the person you know has put
into that machine but the most of the
time we look at that as that's one
application and we need to how do we
modify things to to make that
application it's not going to be every
application so we work very closely with
a lot of manufacturers of those products
and we're very familiar with so if we're
going to apply you know a Bavaria basi
on a product we're very familiar with
the limitations of that you know it for
the most part pressure is not a big
issue for some
like that but he is and so that you know
that that one of those ultra low volume
machines that we make is actually a
small jet engine and there is heat that
results so we've we've actually
developed a specific version of that
machine which cools the exhaust so that
we don't have issues and we can't apply
those types of products we work very
hard at making sure that we understand
our equipment and relationship
biological applications and for the most
part we can use any of them without any
real concerns sometimes like I said you
might need make a modification you're
gonna buy something that we don't want
to filter out all the good stuff you
know so we need to make sure that we
sometimes remove the filter but then
there's the person you know that's
that's with the caveat that you you take
that filter out you better make sure you
really rinse the machine and flush it
well before you put it away if you're
going to use a heat sensitive product
making sure you've got the correct
machine to do that job and our team is
very well-versed in those types of of
issues we're good at working there's a
lot of violence occasion even
non-organic horticulture
there's a lot of those are just very
very good products to use they're you
know they're safer environmentally they
are they have a totally different mode
of action than a lot of the other
pesticides that are available and it's
great to shake that stuff up even if
you're a conventional growers so the
majority of our customers are using
those types of products already very
regular regularly that's good to hear I
my experience with it is that I using a
microscope we would check the product
for activity like a compost tea for
example and then we would send it
through the sprayer and look at it on
the other end and I know this is just a
one-off thing I looked at an atomizer
someone had a hydro shop once and even
the bacteria the motile bacteria was
killed off by going through this
atomizer now you mentioned heat that
might have been a factor I don't know I
assumed it was the the particle side the
droplet size or something inside there
it can be both yeah sure it can be maybe
not even a droplet size but sometime
it can be just the actual application or
the the process of making the droplet so
the droplet might be fairly large but
but the forces involved in doing that
might cause some damage to something as
you said the best way to do to test that
stuff is to actually run a test and see
what what comes out the other end and so
with most of the commercially available
product in the horticultural industry
we've actually done that work we work
with the manufacturers of those products
to get approval with any of those
products we we had one of the chemical
manufacturers actually is a biological
manufacturer a number of years ago you
know always basically said we always
need to keep keep together we always
need to work together because they make
the bullets we make the guns you want to
make sure they fit we want to make sure
that our stuff works with their stuff
and vice versa so we have a very close
relationship with the various
manufacturers in the industry and and
anytime something new comes out we're
really good about making sure that it
gets tested and and that we understand
how to use those products in our
equipment okay so a grower could contact
DRAM and find out from them exactly what
sprayer would work best for the types of
products that they're applying in their
green house or in their indoor
environment essentially definitely yeah
right that's great to hear and along
those lines I yesterday was out in a
facility they have a 500 gallon compost
tea Brewer that they're then sending
through a dosatron out into okay these
brooms and I haven't I told them how I
would test it you know similar to what
we just discussed using a microscope
look at the tea before look at it after
have you do you how do you have any
results relating to dosatrons and how
they affect microbial life though well
when it comes to specifically a compost
tea it's it's hard to know because
there's there can be such a wide range
of constituent microflora in in what
you're trying to apply there when it
comes to commercially available products
I don't think there's any issues at all
from what we've seen the design of a
piston in that you you know basically
the way that those work you have water
runs through the drives of piston up and
down the majority of
but you might get some issues against
the sidewall of the of the chamber but I
would think that you wouldn't get very
much damage at all especially given the
type of pop you know the size of the
population you'd be trying to apply so I
would think that an injector generally
would be a very fairly safe method or a
piston based injector like a dosatron
okay just because there you know you're
basically siphoning liquid out of a tank
and you know with one pull on the piston
and you're pushing it out
with the with the with this river stroke
so you've got a large chamber that's
being filled each time so I wouldn't
think there'd be a bunch of an issue the
only thing that I could see being an
issue is that dosatron has a filter on
the intake of the solution line and so
you may need to depending on you know
how big the the microbial product is you
know the different little bugs you're
trying to pull through that machine are
they're filter might be trapping and
filtering some of them out so you might
need to look at what the filter does but
I would say the actual mechanics
wouldn't probably be an issue okay well
that's good to know I appreciate that
along those lines and then we started
talking about microbes here I recently
was sent a test result from a buddy of
mine he's a golf course superintendent
and he had started looking at water
quality specifically chlorine and how it
affects microbial based products and it
was pretty sure a pretty big die-off
associated with adding chlorine to a
finished
you know microbial product or compost
tea do you have anything that any
anything you would add along those lines
or any experiences yourself with that so
one of our businesses we have a segment
of our business called REM water and
what we do in that that segment of our
business is water treatment we manage
you know basically we do water
management we move water we pump water
we store water we use it for irrigation
we develop irrigation system but we also
do disinfection of water we do
filtration of water we don't use
chlorine as a disinfectant and main
reason we don't like
well one we feel that there's there's
more effective disinfectants for some of
the things we're trying to do but at the
same time chlorine is really not a plant
friendly product but it's certainly not
a microbial friendly product in the
entire the entire point of putting
chlorine into your pool is to prevent
the spread of pathogens in that pool I
don't want somebody to get in there all
journey and have those little germs to
learn and get somebody else the whole
point of that is to kill those so that
what you're stating as far as you know
the tests that they did that that
completely makes sense so no I would
generally not use chlorine as or if
you're gonna use chlorinated water to
let it dance off for a bit a little bit
agitation and you'll gas off a lot of
the chlorine in a period of time
otherwise you could use things like
carbon filters and stuff to remove the
you know the remove the chlorine if
you're going to be using like city water
and you're concerned about I certainly
wouldn't add it we use as a disinfectant
we use ozone which is from the air we
breathe we basically stripped the
nitrogen out we concentrate the oxygen
and we run it through a generation
system that basically is like lightning
in a bottle it splits up some of those o
2 molecules and repairs them with other
o2 molecules making o3 it's a very
reactive product which is why we like it
it's very good at the you know
eliminating biofilm and things like that
it'll nuke anything you know if you if
we took straight very high level
ozonated water and we mixed it
immediately with a bunch of microbes it
would get rid of a lot of them the nice
thing about ozone is is so reactive that
typically it tends to you know in an
on-demand environment if I've got
nothing I need to oxidize it's still
only you know I have a half-life of 20
minutes so what ends up happening though
what's really nice about the ozone
system especially when we're talking
about you know using it with microbial
products most of the products most of
microbes we like
to the aerobic most of the microbes we
don't like for plant growth tend to be
anaerobic the one of the real big
advantages of an ozone system for plant
growth is that when when the ozone goes
away it reverts back to o2 basically one
of those Oh
oxygen molecules on a no.3 molecule
split off oxidizing something leaving o
to that o2 is still dissolved in the
water so the advantage is we can
actually have very high levels of
dissolved oxygen and now we've actually
done some tests using highly ozonated
water that had been run through a system
so the ozone is basically being used up
ending up with very high levels of
dissolved oxygen generally you know when
we in our tests in the 20 to 25 ppm
levels of dissolved oxygen which is at
that point with the temperature water we
were using was actually above the
saturation level saturation was about 11
we can put that in because ozone is much
more soluble in water than o2 is so we
get it into solution stays in solution
much like carbonization you know carbon
dioxide does in a canno soda you know
you have a pressurized canister that's
full of supersaturated gas in a liquid
you open it up the pressure pressure is
relieved it starts that for vests and
says that's what's happening in this
case but it takes it doesn't happen in
two minutes it happens in about 20
minutes it takes a while for you can a
can of coke to go flat same thing here
we've supersaturated the liquid for the
water with oxygen and then we are able
to keep that in solution so we've done
some trials with specifically Burberry
of Asiana where we saw as well as some
Trichoderma products where we saw better
colonization as a result of using highly
oxygen and water from the ozone process
mainly because we're providing them with
an environment that allows them to
thrive a lot of oxygen in the water yeah
that makes a lot of sense but that does
it there's a roundabout way to answering
your question about chlorine in in
Spray solutions meeting microbes but
yeah I would I would say that that
chlorines probably not a good tool to be
using in in that type of that
application not a bad way to clean up
afterwards but you know say you want to
or you get something in the tank that
maybe shouldn't been in there I've seen
it happen where we're a compost tea
system something that we didn't really
want the compost wasn't very good or
there's a bad source and it was too
cerium or something in in there that
could be bred as well so you know
chlorine would be a good tool to help
clean about afterwards yeah now you
touched on biofilm briefly is that
something you can talk about a little
bit more in terms of maintenance and
care and sprayers and irrigation lines
and such things like that that's
actually a very big part of what we do
for me from water treatment standpoint
biofilm is a big part of any irrigation
system you're gonna find biofilm I mean
you find in any water system at all what
we hose own because it's so reactive is
actually a very good tool to eliminate
biofilm it generally isn't going to
slough it off one of the times one of
the things we see with other biofilm or
you know radicans is that they'll loosen
chunks and send it downstream where as
ozone tends to react very quickly and
then it stops because it's that you've
used you've used the ozone so what it
ends up doing instead of weakening the
bond to the pipe it ends up kind of
burning up the ozone or the biofilm and
then more ozone comes along and burns up
a little bit more so it basically eats
its way down the pipe without really
removing it in big you know snake skins
worth of algae and biofilm and gunk that
and a clogging stuff so one of the more
effective tools that we've found for for
controlling biofilm is ozone just
because it's so reactive it density
tends to do a better job so is there a
particular device or something like an
ozonator that you can put
your irrigation or something that you
can use to run a tap to fill your
sprayer with that water and then run
that through your sprayer as a way of
because it sounds like it sounds like a
great option to have right on your
irrigation to where you just run it
through it takes out the biofilm and you
end up with high dissolved oxygen water
hitting your plants is that am i
understanding this correctly or that's
exactly that's exactly the what we feel
the benefit is it's cleaning it's
basically doing a lot of cleaning at the
same time it's giving you water that's
healthier than it was before much
healthier for for plant growth as well
as for beneficial microbes as far as the
system no it's unfortunately it's not
really a plug-and-play thing because
there's so much that goes into this
typically a system like that is gonna be
something we would design for a customer
we do have some basic sizes of systems
but one of the things we like to look at
right away you know first we have how
much water you know how much water do we
need to clean secondly we would look at
what's in the water what do we need to
remove and we do that with filtration or
disinfection in the water and that's
something that we find that a lot of
people don't they don't always look at
what's in the water to be removed and
it's important because if I if I base my
disinfection system on flow alone but
I've got really really high loads I'm
gonna overload the system very quickly
because it's going to be working really
hard to get rid of the very high load
even if it's not a lot of water so we
need to look at both of those things
anytime that we do a system like that
you know we can come in with some basic
recommendations just by looking at the
water but most of the time we want to do
a water sample and test the water and
see what's actually there that needs to
be around sometimes it's not you know
things that sometimes are things that
need other other tools to help remove
you know so if we're high in salts or
bicarbonate or something like that
ozone is not effective on those types of
things so we would look at other types
of you know whether we're going to
adjust the pH air we're going to use
something like nano filtration or even
ro you know we would look at different
things when applicable
you know we don't necessarily advocate
those types of things all the time
because a lot of times water it's you
know the water in a lot of facilities is
great to start out or it might need just
a little bit of tweaking
sometimes we see growers that think ro
is some special magical water and it's
it's actually what it is h2o it's - its
hydrogen and oxygen only and it has no
buffering capacity it has nothing else
whereas most of the water on the planet
has something else in it water is the
universal solvent so much stuff is
dissolved in the water around us and
most of that is benign sometimes it's
not so we need to look at you know what
we're trying to do with it for trying to
grow plants there's some things we want
to you want to adjust yeah was it I
think it was you I was talking to at the
bio controls conference that said that
RO water is not the best option for soil
growers that are growing in soil can you
expand on that at all
well yeah basically for some of the
reasons that I just mentioned the most
what the the main issue that we find
with RO is that there's really very
little buffering capacity to it so if
I'm growing in you know very commonly a
soilless media all right so I'm using
something that's fairly inert a Coco
whatever you know what so in rock wall
if I keep putting in water there you
know we're we're I've adjusted it for
the pH but it's it but it's been
borrowed or I'm using a fertilizer that
is already is it's that's acidic it's
gonna start to drop the media pH and
I've got nothing in that water to help
buffer bicarbonate is actually you know
yes we can have too many but a lot of
times those by governments are helping
us keep that water fairly stable if we
don't if we're applying things like like
an acidic fertilizer without those
bicarbonate Stu help buffer that water
we're going to start crashing the media
pH and we find that we've seen that in
in grow facilities where people have
used RO water just in discriminately and
say no yes I think I need this
but they don't adjust their they don't
have anything buffering it back when we
look at our systems even when we when we
sell an RO system we rarely tell the
grower to use the RO water by itself we
generally are going to blend that back
at some ratio to their original source
water number one is it's it's going to
be easier to grow with Caesar's sphere
you know it's kind of let you know when
you when you've got no buffering
capacity it's kind of like you can only
make right turns in your car if you come
up with kind of 30-degree angle you're
not gonna be able to make it you're
going to make lunch or right turns back
and forth back and forth to oversteer or
it's like sailing in of your sailor it's
like sailing a sailboat directly into
the wind you've got to make a bunch of
tacks along the wind you can't go
straight into the wind if we have more
buffering capacity we can head more
towards the lint and if I get a motor on
there because you don't you don't have
to over steer all the time you get
yourself there but then that said ARRA
is expensive
especially when we're talking about you
know water are becoming more expensive
water is going down part of the issue is
where you put the effluent from that you
know if you're getting 50 to 60 percent
conservatively out of there that you can
use where does the forty to fifty
percent go that you can't use that's now
concentrated with the salts and things
that you took out of your water you got
to find a place to put that some places
won't let you do anything with that very
easily so it's it's a that's a concern
we look at it from a standpoint of total
water management if you've got you know
if I blend back at a 50 percent ratio
that means that you know I have a whole
lot less effluent as a percentage of my
total water going now I'm not I'm not
stripping everything out and sending it
down the drain and then finally one of
the things as a sprayer manufacturer
that concerns us about ro in fact we we
put labels on our equipment now that say
do not use RO in this machine by itself
straight ro we always recommend blending
back and the reason for that is ro as I
mentioned before is a universal solvent
it is hydrogen and oxygen mo if you go
to your tap right now you will not have
only hydrogen oxygen and you will have
30 45
the other things in that water and
that's because water is when it's just
hydrogen oxygen is very hungry it wants
to bond with other things with other
materials but other minerals metals
whatever if I put that water into
systems with certain metals and actually
in in some instances all metals even
stainless we can cause damage to those
components and we can also strip some of
the components of those metals out so ro
going through brass fittings will start
to affect those brass fittings ro going
through brass fittings if we use certain
disinfectants with that like hyper
oxygen based peroxy acetic acid based
products will accelerate that
dramatically stripping bits of the metal
out causing oxidation of those
components causing some of those
components end up in the water causing
damage to the machine or where
potentially stripping some of those
components out and putting them on to
your crop so depending on what your crop
is you know and the Constituent metals
in your spray equipment plumbing you may
be applying those to the plant now in a
lot of instances that's not a big deal
in some instances you know there's
there's some crops where people are
being tested for the metals that are on
the crop and so they have to be are
careful of that from an RO standpoint
the RO is probably exacerbating the
problem that's fascinating I had no idea
you know I hear about people that
complain about their water and they just
go straight to RO systems and just use
RO water but I here in the Seattle area
we're really fortunate we have we have
really good water for the most part so I
haven't had to deal with that right but
that's a great explanation our arrow is
kind of a nuclear option it's it's just
it's a way over steer you you can go 20
percent of the way there and do a much
better job you know it's it's not you
don't need to remove everything you know
there's you talk with somebody that is
adapted water treatment and well we can
help you very easily say no this is
let's just let's target this and get it
to a normal level not strip the whole
thing out and start from scratch that's
great yeah that's really great I had I
did have a couple other quick questions
for you here one of them was to talk a
little bit about this nematode bucket
that Suzanne Wainwright evidence raves
about okay can you discuss a little
about why this came about and the
importance of it when applying nematodes
sure so one of the companies
manufacturing nematodes a number of
years ago you know as I mentioned we
work a lot we work really closely with
the manufacturers of the different plant
protection products that are in the
market they kind of came to us and said
hey you know we have a real issue with
nematodes in our industry the biggest
issue is that they they're aerobic
they breathe air we put them in water
but they still breathe air and so what
they'll do is they'll breathe up milk
they'll suck up the oxygen in the tank
and start to go in oxic and so they'll
though they'll basically start to to
suffocate if they're not you know so
what we really need they said to us is
we need something that'll help agitate
but it would be great if we could add
oxygen at the same time so that it would
basically you know it would mix them up
in the tank which is good it's better
for distribution of the product as well
as but it also helps keep the oxygen
mixed through the tank and if we can add
some air that would be oxygen that would
be great we started looking into
different ways to do it based on you
know some recommendations they said you
know hey we've done it with you know
bubblers and things like that where we
just pump air into the tank and we
started going down that road and are the
first attempts we made we weren't ever
real happy because you know and then
that company basically said well can you
just you know help us get us the pump
and we'll tell customers hey buy this
air pump from DRAM and we'll you know
we'll put a little instructional video
on our website showing them how they can
make this and the problem with that is
when you compress air
it heats up and so one of the secondary
concerns that they had that they told us
about when we first discussed this was
we don't want the water to get hot when
I compress air and pump it into a bucket
it tends to get hot now depends on how
much compression I do for a while we you
know with the product kind of languor
for a little bit and I languished and we
didn't get didn't get it finished until
a number of years ago when we realized
that we could inject oxygen into a
passing stream which wouldn't compress
the air instead of pumping the air and
that's what we started doing in fact
we've got a kit that we can now add to
the agitation systems on some of our
hydraulic sprayers you just add an air
kit to our hydraulic sprayer to
oxygenate the tank so we have a bucket
so we started out by making a bucket
where it's it's really two buckets one
bucket houses all the components inside
of it and the other is just for the
liquid and what we do is we recirculate
that so it's got a switch where we can
either turn on or off the air so it
allows us to use it as a agitation
system say for fertilizers and things as
well what we might not want the air
because it might kind of cause bubbling
and foaming but then we can flip a
switch turn on the air injection and
that will add oxygen and what we've been
able to do is maintain saturation levels
of oxygen in the tank as we mix it now
from a nematode standpoint you know
anybody using them at ODEs has probably
been very well cautioned that you want
to make sure that they're you know for
them to do the best job you want them to
be active and raring to go and you know
if you look at just even some of the
instructional videos or theirs they'll
show pictures showing what they should
look like under a microscope you don't
want to see you want to see them
wiggling you don't want to see them all
bent over and kind of stiff that you
know they might still be alive but
they're not real active so the idea of
adding the oxygen is to help keep them
in an optimal state to go and do their
job mixing and agitating and oxygenating
is going to do that and so we developed
that that specifically for that product
but the nice thing about the edge
stations
them is it'll it'll mix up fertilizer as
well so it's kind of a dual purpose
since you can flip off the switch and
then we also make it in the we like I
said we make a kit for our spray
equipment but we also make a 50 gallon
stock system for really large areas
we've got some large growers where it's
a 50 gallon tank with a dosatron on it
like we had mentioned before this is one
of those places where we know it doen't
Strunz no damaging a microbial product
or in this case a little worm but the we
have an agitation and aeration system on
that so that we can use it for a 50
gallon stock tank full of of nematodes
that and that's being used in in large
greenhouses where they're you know
basically where they are you know
applying them through booms or or you
know hand watering or whatever but
they've got multiple areas they're doing
it once so it also allows you to get an
even application as in a certain number
of nematodes per se per container or per
bed or per space that you're essentially
trying to cover over a given application
it's not right well yeah because what
you're gonna do is you're gonna mix it
the you know it's important to be able
to make sure the concentration is even
through the container through the stock
tank yeah so you know they said that you
know without agitation they tend to sink
to the bottom breeze up all the oxygen
and then they start to suffocate
so agitation is helping one by mixing
them through the liquid and to the
aeration is helping by adding oxygen to
that liquid to keep them happy so
changing direction the last question I
have is I know Suzanne harps on this
everyone like a lot of growers are using
paint sprayers which are not designed
for you know horticultural applications
I know I was guilty of this when I first
started growing you know everyone has
access to a paint sprayer can you talk a
little bit about the disadvantages and
what we're missing out when we're using
something like that for a horticulture
application well I think that the
summary of that is exactly what you said
they're not really dissolved or designed
for spray applications of agricultural
products
they generally aren't always the most
durable pieces of equipment they're not
made for some of the products we're
putting in so they can cause damage to
seals most commonly that's what we see
as seals and things fail and stuff like
that
pressures things like that aren't always
really well thought out there's there's
you know they're not designed for the
type of duty that's being put onto them
you know when someone's going to go use
a paint sprayer most the time they're
buying something they're gonna go paint
a wall and it's going to take them 15
minutes and they're gonna be done you
know we've seen guys take that into
three four acres of greenhouse where
it's going to take them several hours
and it's not the same kind of duty so
from a standpoint of you know the size
of the motors and all that stuff it's
generally not meant for agricultural
applications now that said some of the
things that some of them try to achieve
you know we use an agricultural pump to
produce a 3,000 psi droplet to create a
spray that's a targeted spray paint
sprayers doing something trying to do
something similar although it's
generally using a diaphragm pump not a
piston style pump which depending on the
the products that you're applying may be
better maybe worse
but those seats but the diaphragm itself
you know generally what we've seen with
paint sprayers is those diaphragms
themselves aren't aren't meant to
tolerate some of the products that go
through our machines and so certainly
not powders they're just generally not
good for that they're meant you know for
the most part these things are meant to
apply an oil-based priority or even a
latex based product but they're not
they're not like water I mean it's a
different type of liquid and they
certainly aren't gonna have powders so
most of the time they don't tolerate
powders very well the nozzles aren't
really meant for that type of
application as well they're generally
sometimes you know I think the best you
can get is a carbon steel tip which can
work in some cases but with other
products that doesn't work for a well I
guess the biggest thing I can say is you
know looking at how something designed I
mentioned earlier when I was talking
about hydraulic sprayers
our philosophy about spray equipment is
you know you I wanted the right
pressures and I want to do the right
thing I want to create the right droplet
but beyond that the second most
important thing that we think is
important in a piece of equipment is
that it is designed to make that job
easier
meaning the hose reel the wheels the you
know the pump everything's not going to
fail in the middle of the job it's gonna
make it so that you don't have to worry
about flipping the switch turn the
pressure up and going and nothing's
gonna get in the way of that and what we
find with paint spray equipment is
they're not they don't that's not they
haven't been designed for someone to
take out into a greenhouse and pull
around and spray you know everything
from I think you get maybe a 25 foot
hose on some of those things and you
know you got to pull it down an aisle or
you know they're meant to use a bucket
they don't agitate they don't you know
all those things all add up to making
the job in our opinion more difficult
and then when you have a pump that's
gonna start failing on you because it
wasn't meant to handle the products
you're putting through it it just makes
that job more and more difficult for the
grower and it might be cheaper to go buy
one of those but we look at from the
standpoint of you know you're going out
we look at there's there's there's
several different places of value in
pesticide application
one is the labor that's involved you
know the people that are doing the job
you're paying them okay
there's there's there's the other value
is there their happiness in your
workplace those types of things
typically tend to suffer when you have
products that that you have equipment
that doesn't hold up and do what they
need to customer you know the guy or the
guy spraying get frustrated and it
becomes a problem more importantly you
know so you have the consideration of
the other value when you're doing this
and that's your crop you know the plants
that you are spraying you know they're
out but there's the potential in some of
those diaphragm based paint sprayers for
that diaphragm the cracked especially
with some of the products we're using
that they're not meant to tolerate and a
diaphragm cracking behind that that
diaphragm is a big chamber
of pressurized motor oil do you want
that to be sprayed on your crop I looked
at like a piston style pump it's
actually designed so that if there is a
seal failure the water flows into the
oil not the oil flowing in the water
because the pressurized side is where is
where the water is the liquidus we're
pressurizing liquid side with a system
like that the oil only serves to
lubricate the Pistons in a diaphragm
based pump we're pressurizing a chamber
which makes the diaphragm fluctuate up
and down which then transfers that
pressure to the liquid if that diaphragm
fails that oil goes right out the
sprayer and when the kind of droplets
and things that were applying you know
with that type of equipment the
potential for damage to the crop you
know I don't think anybody really wants
to spray motor oil onto their plants I
don't think anybody would think that'd
be a good idea
and so we look at prop value is one of
the reasons why yeah okay I might have
gone to Home Depot on demo by a cheap
paint sprayer but what's the potential
liability in doing that what's the
potential cost to that depending on the
value of your crop could be very high so
that's that's one of those things that
it always makes me scratch my head when
I see somebody buying something cheap
like that and then I walk into a room
and they've got a million dollars for
the plants in there and you say okay is
this it's just really a good saving of
money by you know you saved a thousand
bucks you know is that is that is that
smart so that's that's kind of my
opinion on on those types of equipment I
don't think that they are meant to do
the job they generally don't hold up to
the job they cause potential liability
and you know then again like I said our
philosophy is building for ease of use
so that the guy doing the job is
comfortable doing it well and I would
think the biggest factor that you
mentioned earlier in our conversation
what I've learned from you is that the
droplet size may not be optimal and so
we may not getting the actual coverage
on the leaf surface that we want so the
the spray application itself may not be
as effective
which well that's certainly true it
hasn't been designed for spraying plants
yeah we don't know what it's producing
you know some of those are produced are
capable producing some pretty pretty
fine droplets but they're meant to be
doing that with like a varnish or
something you know so so yeah that's
that's a good point
so we need the right tool for the right
job which brings up one other thing that
I was thinking of because I was out in
my garden and I have one of your I think
I think that's called a professional
wand I know you have a bunch of
different lines so probably a rain wand
or you know it's some sort of rain one
but I have I have one of your ones and
it has a really small head that's
probably the size of like a half-dollar
or smaller okay and it's it's a nice
high-quality one and I used that in my
raised beds out front now I was I need
one for the hose in the back and I went
and bought a $10 one at Fred Meyer I
can't remember the brand name and it has
all these nozzle adjustments I can make
from wat from shower to mist - whatever
and when I go to water with the nice
DRAM wand that I have in the front yard
I get a really nice spray that's high
volume but low pressure so I can water
my tomatoes my peppers without damaging
them while they're small you know still
starting out whereas the the other one
in the back even when I switch to
different nozzles like shower that's
supposedly going to be higher volume
less pressure I'm still like shooting it
at this poor plant and stressing that
plant out so having the right tool and
maybe spending a little more on like
your water wands are phenomenal that's
sort of where I associate DRAM you know
you started with this whole this whole
side of things
I suggest users give them a shot because
they're great well thank you yeah that's
we started 77 years ago with the
invention of the 400 al aluminum water
breaker and that's what's really what we
started as as company is a hand watering
company now we make dozens of different
nozzles and we don't make them you know
we do have a consumer side of our
business where we sell those in
different colors but we on the
professional end we make them all with
different patterns different hole sizes
all meant to do different things
different widths of patterns we actually
have you know on the professional and we
a video with series of videos to talk
about you know how to water and and
using the right tool for the job
you know there's some times when you
need a lot of water sometimes don't need
a lot of water use the right tool when
when doing that because as you said I
mean one of one of my biggest pet peeves
is those multi-pattern heads because
they're you know the old friend is jack
of all trades and master of none they
don't do anything well you get you get
might get nine different things you can
do with it but none of them is real is
as good as what it would be if you
bought the two or three nozzles that you
selected it for you know and that's so I
appreciate you saying that because
that's yeah those are that's a very
important part of our business you know
hand watering is and we never you know
we've always known it's important but
especially when we talk to professional
growers it's people that that water all
day you know and take it seriously you
they are very protective very religious
about the watering tools they use in
fact I mean it's it's very nice to be in
that position to be trusted that well
because we don't have you know we may
have plenty of competition on the
consumer end where we're selling to you
know every home gardener you know
anybody with a with a potted plant but
on the professional and we don't have a
lot of competition because nobody did
all the other stuff that's out there is
just isn't it's not it's not meant for
professional use it's meant for a
homeowner years and we've you know we've
been trusted by the commercial
horticultural industry for so long that
you know it's it's a its position we
don't take lightly in fact we just you
know just announced we're modifying one
of our oldest trolls and offering a
protective ring on the outside of it
that they could because other customers
have been asking for it we come up with
different nozzles and and valves and
things all the time because we don't
want to take for granted that market
which in our opinion is you know the
professional markets very picky and we
liked and and so are we so it's good fit
so I like that I'd appreciate you
bringing that up yeah when I'm watering
my front garden with a nozzle and it's
not as it's not as good of one you know
it's it's annoying but when I go to the
Torre nursery and I have to water
for two hours you know I can cut off you
know a half an hour to an hour of time
just by using a better nozzle and right
with that cost of labor and like you
said the happiness of the of the the
labor using that product it makes a big
difference because it drives me crazy
when I'm when the water pressure is so
high that I'm actually shooting soil
back up onto the leaf tissue of my plant
it it's not good so oh definitely no I
really do appreciate your your higher
quality nozzles and I for anyone that's
hand watering their plants I highly
suggest you check them out and I think
the big takeaway from today's podcast is
really get the right tool for the right
job is so important and I think that's
really where you guys you guys shine so
but thank you I think that's a big part
of our philosophy as businesses you have
the right tool and and and that's our
customer base is people that appreciate
that thank well I appreciate a lot yeah
I appreciate the time today I learned a
lot I hope the listeners will really
enjoy this and I will put up the contact
information for your company so some of
the stuff that we talked about today
people if they want more information
they can reach out and get a hold of it
great thanks Deb appreciate it that was
Kurt Becker executive vice president of
commercial products for the DRAM
corporation you can go to WWE on comm to
check them out
that's dr a mmm comm you are listening
to the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast i'm your host tad hussy don't
forget that there's more information
articles available on our website and
blog at WWE organics calm as well as
links to the data and information we
discussed in this episode on the podcast
page thanks for listening
you