[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tad hussey
of kiss organics this is the podcast
where we discuss the cutting edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
my guest this week is dr jordan zagger
jordan is an expert in natural product
biosynthesis and chemical analysis of
cannabis resin compounds dr zeiger
earned his phd from washington state
university where his research set the
stage for studying the regulatory events
governing gene expression and cannabis
and their effect on the biosynthesis of
trichome cannabinoids and terpenoids
early in his career jordan set his
sights on aggressively applying modern
scientific methods to the medicinal and
recreational cannabis industry and to
bring cultivators the tools to become
exceptional
dr zager is now the ceo and co-founder
of dewey scientific in pullman
washington now on to the show
hi jordan thanks for coming on the show
today
hey kat happy to be here thanks for
having me
yeah let's start off talking a little
bit about your background can you share
a little bit about how you got into uh
this type of research
yeah so my you know formal educational
background i'm a biochemist who chose to
study plant biochemistry
um i have a bachelor's of
biochemistry and molecular biology from
the university of nevada
while i was there i worked in a plant
biofuels lab where we were looking at
a
potential crop for biodiesel production
specifically looking at the the oil
quality of the the seeds produced by
this this crop
um
and it was during that time you know as
my college years i found this love for
biotechnology um i was a college student
smoking weed
and sort of have this idea of let's
let's merge these two things let's do
some biotech in cannabis um so that led
me up to washington state university
um in 2014
recreational cannabis had just become
legalized and they had a market at that
time and i found a lab that studied
terpene biosynthesis in glandular
trichomes
so at the time i knew enough about
cannabis to know that that was very
relevant and just to sort of back up
right glandular trichomes are these
little tiny
um cellular
chemical factories that stand on the
leaf of plants they're they're found on
about 30 of all plant species
um
so the last the lab i entered for my
doctorate um studied the metabolism in
those and and typically
uh these these structures these
trichomes they make essential oil
compounds which for the most part are
mono and fescue terpenes
and now those are famous in cannabis
because they they provide each variety
or strain with their own unique aroma
and you know it's
gaining traction that it's also the
these terpene compounds sort of
influence the user experience for from
strain to strength
so yeah that's how i got into all of
this
i eventually was able to work with
cannabis genomics as part of my phd
dissertation
and upon graduating
with my doctorate in plant biochemistry
when often started dewey scientific a
cannabis focused biotechnology company
where we are trying to make cannabis
better through can
through credible science
and so that's what uh you're doing now
with dewey scientific
that's right so yeah dewey scientific we
are you know implementing modern methods
in
plant breeding right leveraging the
genome as much as we can to identify
markers that associate with certain
traits and then make sure these traits
get into
the the varieties that we develop and
ultimately put onto the market both for
other farmers to use and we also have a
commercial brand dewey cannabis company
we're located in washington state
where we get a sort of market test the
varieties that come out of our breeding
program
and get you know consumer feedback uh
directly
that's what we're doing at dewey
great well
can you just touch briefly on so what
you're doing is is breeding not you're
not necessarily doing any uh
gmo stuff at this point is that correct
yeah that's correct we are not
directly putting genes from other
organisms into cannabis we are not
you know
using
various viral or bacterial
constructs to sort of manipulate
cannabis genetics all we are doing is
you know sequencing the varieties we
like
sequencing the genome of the varieties
we like to sort of
better understand what we have
and then once once we know what we have
we can start to make targeted
and intelligent breeding decisions right
if you think of the way that cannabis
has been bred and treated
um over the last 40 50 years through
prohibition
right breeders have been very limited in
their access to technology their access
to facilities
and so it's sort of fallen behind other
horticultural crops right if you look at
blueberry there's
there's a thousand papers on blueberry
resistance to various pathogens
fungus
insects
and
because of the the pro
the prohibitory nature of cannabis we
just hadn't
no one's really quite gotten there so i
think that's that's
that's really what we're focused on is
just catching it up to these other
horticultural uh species from an
understanding and then you know putting
that understanding into practice through
smart breeding
yeah i think that's a really good uh
analogy that you're using they're
comparing it with vegetable crops that
we're more familiar with because i know
when i go out to buy
say an apple tree i'm going to look for
what diseases are most prevalent in my
area
and then look for a particular variety
that i know is going to provide some
resistance to that um you know we have a
lot of issues with rust around here for
example with pears so i know that
there's varieties i can choose that are
going to be more resistant i'm going to
have a better crop
and and you know what you're getting in
terms of a flavor profile too and and
yield profiles so
uh i think it's wonderful so you're just
identifying
what uh particular markers may be most
useful for someone
and then by identifying you can then
breed plants that have these traits is
that sort of what you're what you're
getting out there
absolutely yeah so you know without the
the genetic marker component of this the
breeder is sort of left to
uncovering things visually as the plant
matures now you know cannabis is a
relatively quickly maturing plant you
know compared to say an apple tree
so you know the time burden there an
eight week flower cycle
is you know relatively quick but
there's so much ground that we have to
make up in cannabis
that we need to be making decisions a
lot quicker and that's what genetic
markers enable right so we now have a
genetic marker for
say
powdery mildew resistance
um and we want to make sure that this
gets into all of our commercial
varieties
so at the seedling stage we can just
take a a small little leaf sample run a
quick pcr
um
assay and and then we know which in this
population is powdery mildew resistant
and then we can we can get rid of
everything that doesn't have powdery
mildew resistance and then we're
you know
at ease that all these varieties that
we're growing and developing are are
will be protected against powdery mildew
this is just another tool essentially
utilizing technology to speed up the
process because normally as
traditionally as a breeder you'd have to
grow out all these plants you then have
to evaluate them you know qualitatively
in terms of
terpenes and
the effects
of you know whatever whatever effects
that may synergistically occur with that
particular plant um
how resistant it is to different
diseases that it may have been exposed
to
and then you may choose to clone or
reproduce it that way but
this just gives you a lot more
information earlier on if you can
identify these markers and and what
you're saying is that we haven't
we don't we haven't identified all these
markers so we don't know where on the
genome
you know powdery mildew resistance which
is what we're going to talk about today
is is particular was
located is that
sort of what you're what you're saying
there
yeah yeah exactly we're developing the
the tools rooted in molecular biology to
accelerate plant breeding
um
exactly
okay well let's let's dive into the
paper and i have to admit um you know
breeding is not
it's not my strength it's not an area
that i have a lot of knowledge in so um
i'm probably going to be asking the
types of questions to help
other listeners like myself that just
haven't
don't have anywhere near your academic
background on this
but the paper itself i will have a link
to directly in the podcast
it's called discovery and genetic
mapping of pm1 a powdery mildew
resistance gene in cannabis sativa and
this was a paper produced by dewey
scientific in conjunction with oregon
cbd
and we'll have links directly to the
paper
and
[Music]
is there anything else you want to say
on that before we dive into the paper
yeah you know i just want to sort of
make clear you know i'm not an author on
this paper um this was work performed by
my company doing scientific in
collaboration with oregon cbd like you
had mentioned but i really just want to
give a shout out to paul mahalos and
andre garfinkel the the two authors um
you know this was something that
was a side project in in terms of you
know publishing a public access
research paper um you know i think most
companies if they'd come across a marker
like this they'd steal their lips and
it's only theirs
but you know
for for us to advance the cannabis
industry we we really want to be
developing tools that anybody can use um
and and paul and andrea just really took
the uh
the initiative on getting this work out
there putting it in the public domain uh
because you know the cannabis industry
is only going to advance if everybody
can advance and as if you know we're
holding this you know close to our chest
we're the only ones benefiting
and um you know we're just not at that
stage in cannabis where there should be
a dominant market player um so just
yeah wanted to
to praise paul and andrea because this
is really their their their brainchild
but they they did a tremendous work here
i i appreciate you uh saying that and i
100 agree i wasn't confident pronouncing
their last name so thank you for uh
giving them a shout out for
for this work um and and the fact that
you are sharing this i think that is
important um and something that i hope
more companies will will do as we can so
we can further our overall knowledge
um
i think that's definitely important
so uh
yeah let's let's dive into this paper
and again this is open access so you can
read the paper yourself
we'll have a link on the podcast page
but let's just start off talking a
little bit about powdery mildew in
general so what what is powdery mildew
yeah so powdery mildew is a common term
for a lot of
or i should say a lot but of many
um pathogenic fungi these are
you know fungus that
attack the plant as a pathogen meaning
it will
you know maybe act as a parasite maybe
just wants to take advantage of the
plant to spread its spores so that the
fungus can live another generation
but peppery mildew is is one of these
pathogenic fungi
and it's been found on all sorts of
different crops you know of course
cannabis of course it's cousin hops
it's a problem in the wine industry it's
a problem
uh anywhere where you have fluctuating
humidity during the growth cycle
of any crop
and specifically you know at least in in
terms of our research on this we are
referring to the specific uh
fungus
golovinomyces ambrosie
which
is
what we found on our plants um and and
we did some genetic sequencing and found
that it matches the the you know general
term of powdery mildew found in kentucky
and ohio and oregon
so it is a just a general
uh fungus that attacks crops as they
grow
and uh i just want to clarify too that
when you when you see pm on
you know different plants that's not
necessarily
able to cross all plant species so we're
not going to necessarily see
the powdery mildew that we may find
on our squash as is the same species
that's going to be infecting our
cannabis
just something i wanted to point out for
listeners
yeah that's absolutely correct
and uh since it is a catch-all we know
that there's multiple species that
infect cannabis is it necessary really
from a grower perspective to actually
identify the species or can we treat
these all fairly
you know synonymously in terms of our
our approach to treatment
you know
we uh that's a great question and i
don't have a particularly solid answer
for that no i think some more research
needs to go into this
however we we do know that the species
we identified here in washington is
problematic in oregon
kentucky and
ohio that that doesn't mean that
that
there are others in those locales that
that you know other species of powdery
mildew that might be um inhibiting crop
growth and you know we we haven't
um
done these sort of artificial
inoculations of these other powdery
mildew species
mostly because
of sort of the biohazard that that poses
bring that into a cannabis facility
sure and you you touched a little bit on
humidity fluctuation what conditions
lead to you know higher spore pressure
and actual infection of the leaf tissue
yeah so things that that you know where
the fungus likes to produce more spores
and
sort of rapidly take over a population
are where you have you know larger
fluctuations uh in humidity doesn't
matter if it's you know through the day
period or through the night period or in
between the two but it's generally when
there's this swing you know say you're
getting up above
60 to 70 percent uh relative humidity
and then dropping down to you know say
below 40. um so what that allows is for
the
spores to be spread when the
humidity is low
and when that humidity comes back up the
the fungus can then
begin to grow on wherever those spores
landed
i think some some simple ways for people
to get around this is just to have a
stable um
humidity
in their their grow environment um you
know what we've seen and you know this
is a
sample size of one but at our facility
when we when we kept things you know in
the between 50 and 60 we we saw a rather
large reduction in powdery mildew
um
so it's really that swing that allows
the spores to spread and then the
increase that then allows the
the fungus to flourish
yeah i i will comment just anecdotally
uh whenever growing giant pumpkins for
years i noticed whenever i had a uh
you know a really
heavy rainy day
followed by a super sunny day
um that was sort of
that triggered those those big swings
was when i would see powdery mildew
start to appear in our in my garden
outdoors and it obviously it's something
we can't control outdoors but um
indoors that's a big that's a big uh a
big thing to control in terms of the
environment and uh
i guess that leads into
genetics then so
what was your experimental design and
how
how how did you discover what genetics
to really start your project with
yeah this was sort of a a
circumstance of of luck um we
we at dewey we have a
very nice plant research facility
and we have these really old growth
chambers that they sort of look like
commercial refrigerators from like the
60s just these big monster units
um they they do a good job of regulating
light and temperature but they they sort
of suck with humidity they don't
exchange a lot of air with
the external environment
um and so we were just housing some of
the genetics that we were working on um
you know we
we had some um
i don't know a couple dozen different
varieties
and
it was in our early days we were leaving
these chamber doors closed humidity was
getting well up into the 80s when the
lights were off and the lights turned on
it dried out quite a bit
and we noticed one of our varieties this
pmw 39 which commercially we call rain
dance
was powdery mildew was not growing on it
um so our breeder paul
said hey i think i think we might have a
resistant variety um so so what he did
was he took this pnw 39
very resistant
he crossed it with this jumping jack
variety that was
very susceptible or you know on the
higher end of susceptibility
and and made a breeding cross
you know some other background on
pnw39 and jumping jack pnw39 while it
was susceptible is a very low yielder
commercially
it's phd content is generally sub 20
so it's not really a commercially
appealing variety for farmers
on the flip side jumping jack is a very
high yielder it regularly produces flour
that tests above 28 thc um and that's
that's you know sort of the the farmer's
dream however it succumbed to powdery
mildew
whenever it came into contact with it
um so so what paul did was he crossed
these two
um
he he raised
he was just shy of a hundred of those
progeny those children
and we took those children and put them
into that that swampy humid growth
chamber that we have
and we started scoring for powdering
mildew resistance
um and what we saw and this is sort of
jumping back into you know high school
biology with gregor mendel um was a
segregation pattern of one to two to one
which is
just classic mendelian segregation as
it's called right i think back to
punnett squares
um
where can you elaborate on it for those
of us that
[Music]
may not have taken these courses or
really remember all of the stuff i mean
i took a little bit on mendel but i've
promptly forgotten most of it so yeah
yeah so greg gregor mendel was a i
believe a belgian monk in the late 1800s
who was
breeding peas and what what he saw was
you know now i crossed the green with
the yellow and
some of those kids are green some of
those kids are yellow
and he did it with with color and with
wrinkle wrinkled peas
but it pretty much breaks down to for
every gene in a genome there are two
copies of it
and in some cases
the genes are dominant in some cases
they're recessive and it's it's possible
for
any
any two copies to one be dominant one be
recessive
um and so
when you you make a cross let's say you
have a parent that is dominant dominant
with something that is recessive
recessive
everything all of those progeny are
going to be what we call heterozygous
meaning it has a dominant allele and
also has the recessive allele
however when you're dealing with things
that are heterozygous
when you go to make additional crosses
say with something that's completely
recessive or or something that's
completely dominant you start to get
different ratios of those those children
so what we witnessed was just sort of a
a classic example of a gene segregating
in a dominant recessive fashion
um that sort of clarifies things yeah
that brings back some
some memories there yeah that does make
sense so basically things played out the
way you would expect them to um
from the from your your crosses
and then uh so you took those crosses
and what did that uh
what did that research show you
um so what that showed us was that
um
well just because the pattern of the
progeny just gave us okay there is a
single
dominant r gene uh so that that sort of
confirms what we call
vertical resistance um to to the the
pathogen that we're working with
um and this is this is something that's
been found in you know it's pretty
common in domesticated crops that you
find a single dominant resistance gene
um and so so that that's sort of you
know
paul looked at the data and said okay we
should do some sequencing here
um because we can find a marker that
will associate with this this dominant
um
powdery mildew
resistant gene
so so basically what you're saying is
this gave you the confidence that you
could
actually find a particular marker
based on
the cross that you did
is that essentially yeah
that's correct okay
uh so you you discovered this marker
um which is essentially what what the
the paper is about um
what uh
what does the research show you um
when you guys use the word resistance
for example example in the paper
um
what does that actually mean like let's
just say visually
and then how do you
i know you talked about this in the
paper but how do you show that this
plant is indeed resistant
yeah so um
you know sort of to identify powdery
mildew on on a crop you know it's
has these white little
pears that grow all over the uh the
leaves it sort of looks like you took a
powder uh powdered sugar shaker and just
put them all over the leaves that's how
you can identify it once it's already
started to to uh colonize the toast
um so yeah visually we just had this
this set of children from from our
breeding cross and you know
almost every other one
had powdery mildew growing on it or had
no powdery mildew there was it was
you know
um
it was just leaves there was there was
none of that powdery powdered sugar on
it so what we did was you know we took
some of that that
powdery mildew off we examined it under
a microscope
um and
that's sort of the classic way of
identifying a a pathogen is to look at
it under the microscope you know you go
back and reference various textbooks or
resources
and so you identify the spores and you
identify um
the
[Music]
pondium is sort of the scientific word
but sort of um
the the legs growing off
the off of the spores
which is sort of how the the fungus
grows
um
and you know we then took it next a step
further we took this isolated powdery
mildew at this point and we did a quick
pcr test and
[Music]
and was able to confirm that it was the
this specific
species of powdery mildew
and then basically
all of the plants that had
uh that weren't showing any powdery
mildew all had contained that marker and
the ones that did have uh pm did not
contain that marker
yeah so this is where we we went and did
some um it's called a sniff probe um
it's
smith fnp short
um
sorry single nucleotide polymorphism if
you've ever taken a 23andme or ancestry
uh
dna test your your dna was run on a snip
chip
um and so what this does is it
identifies single mutations throughout
the entire genome so there are cannabis
specific snip chips and and we worked
with lighthouse genomics out of canada
for for this specific project and so we
ran dna samples from all of these
children in addition to the parents
um
and just looked for mutations throughout
the population
and so what we saw with you know i think
there was 40 000
markers that were run but on one of the
markers we saw
okay in the parent
in in pnw 39 the resistant parent there
was this uh mutation at this specific
marker in
jumping jack the resistance i'm sorry
the susceptible parent
there was a different mutation at that
that marker and then we saw that the
children split into three groups
um where they had
the profile that matched the resistant
parent the profile that matched the
the susceptible parent and then things
in between that had and this goes back
to those alleles each copy where they
had one
of each of the mutation at that that
genetic marker
um and so then we we took that data we
looked back at sort of our phenotyping
data what we saw with our eyes
and we were able to determine that okay
this is a
dominant trait meaning that it you know
it's either dominant or recessive if
it's dominant it's going to show
um in the presence of of the recessive
um
and so we saw this pattern where some of
the progeny went uh
clustered with with the resistant parent
and of the same same mutation profile at
that snip
we saw things that had in the middle and
then things that went with the
susceptible
so was this a spectrum of resistance
that you saw based on
how much of that original
pnw marker was there
with this particular population we did
not see a range of
resistance um just sort of
indicating that
this particular marker
um is it infers strong resistance that
that i'm not going to say that's going
to be the case for every powdery powdery
mildew resistance marker that might be
out there um right this is just pm1
there's you know our geneticists believe
there's probably five or six in cannabis
and those remain to be found
um however with with pm1
if if you have the correct mutation in
that spot what we saw is that you have
full resistance to this strain of
powdery mildew
so what you're saying is there could be
down the road other species or strains
of pm that could still and potentially
infect a plant with this
with this marker but
what you saw
in your experiment was essentially full
immunity
um in your growth chambers
yes that that's correct um i think i
think it's very likely that there are
other powdery mildew
uh strains out there or species that
could infect a a plant that is resistant
to this
the powdery mildew species that we were
working with
okay that makes sense um
and uh so
what kind of conclusions
can we draw so what like what's the next
logical step in regards to this research
and advanced advancement so
obviously for you guys um i would assume
now you're doing breeding projects where
you're going to check for that marker as
you breed more of
you know progeny from these uh
this these
this plant line
um
creating you know varietals then that i
assume you would you would then take to
market or potentially
sell down the road what's the
what's the game plan there and then how
can other growers outside of your
company use this research or companies
to further advance
our overall knowledge in cannabis
yeah so some of the steps that we've
taken uh the next steps we've taken with
with this project is of course we want
this in all of our varieties that we put
into our commercial brand that we we
then sell to other farmers as well um so
at this time i believe we have just
about a dozen varieties that we have
introduced uh this powdery mildew
resistance into
um and those are available uh for for
washington growers
and the other stuff that we're taking is
we want to find these other pm genes
right it's sort of a dream that we would
uh start pm resistance genes pm two
three four five if there's that many
um
and and start to stack these resistance
genes into a variety so like you
mentioned earlier right is it possible
for a farmer to have one of
these these varieties and grow them and
still have powdery mildew resistance
um if we can get multiple resistance
genes stacked into a single variety it
just lowers the chance that
powdery mildew can infect the plant no
matter where it's grown no matter what
species of pattern they'll do it's
subject to
and uh
that just gets me thinking do you have
in line to do any research regarding
botrytis i know that's a
another major one that uh
a lot of cannabis growers battle
even more so than pm is there a
potential there i guess
um that's that's definitely not a focus
of ours you know i think unfortunately i
mean it is it is definitely uh we are
fortunate to be in this situation in
general but you know for the sake of
botrytis where we are we're in eastern
washington uh botrytis isn't as big of a
threat
to cannabis out here it's a bit drier
um than say the willamette valley of
oregon
or you know
anywhere in western washington or even
you know
humble you know the emerald triangle in
california right as they get fall reigns
that increases the pressure of botrytis
so for us in eastern washington it's not
as big of a problem and
on the other side of that we don't want
to intentionally bring botrytis into our
facility
so we are
working with a few folks that that may
or may not have
detritus resistance they think they do
um so we we work with folks on on sort
of trying to find this marker and then
sort of you know jumping back to your
question on you know how can other
farmers uh make use of this today um
you know what we did was develop a a
pcr assay
um and we we provide the primers for
that so you know of course you might
need a molecular biologist on your team
to sort of
run this assay but you know we did
provide the framework for anybody to be
testing for this at their facility if
they have the right tools and
staff
so i realize there's some limitations
with state
uh you know boundaries and such but if
you were a washington farmer for example
um
could they send a sample to you to test
for that marker
is that something a service that you
guys offer
you know that's not a service that we
offer although if there's any interested
listeners out there you know we are very
happy to work with folks on ensuring
that consumers are getting a
safer product
in the end
and
but are you also and again this is
something i haven't looked up yet um do
you guys offer actual plants then um for
sale
that contain that market yeah we
we we do we
we can only work within the confines of
washington state at the moment
um
but we we are very happy to work with
with folks on licensing our varieties
you know this past
growth season we worked with a large
group in central washington
uh getting them some of our varieties
um and this is what this is what we do
you know we we license plant varieties
to to interested farmers
great and that kind of just brings me to
a couple more pm questions if that's
okay
one
that comes to mind is have you seen any
research that actually shows uh
any health risks associated
with
uh consuming or combusting
cannabis leaf that has
some you know
level of powdery mildew on it i wasn't
able to find anything online i was just
curious if you uh
if you had any anything on that
yeah i'm unaware of any research that
that shows that powdering mildew
consumption or inhalation is
dangerous to one's health um you know it
i'm not a medical doctor
but i think it's it's
it's reasonable to think that it could
elicit an immune response you know
sometimes that could that could be in
the form of asthma or it could be a you
know
uh
allergic reaction
um to the respiratory tract
but i think what's what's more important
here is that when powdery mildew is on
plants it reduces the vigor of the plant
ultimately impacting yield and in the
case of cannabis impacting potency and
that's not something that farmers want
to have to deal with so oftentimes they
will treat their plants with damaging
fungicides
and spray that on the plants and that is
that's my primary concern and that's a
huge poses a huge risk to
the
health and safety of cannabis consumers
is are they inhaling
combusted fungicides and pesticides
and that that's really our goal with
this is to just reduce depend reduce
dependence on
fungicides that are damaging to human
health
absolutely um and i just want to make
clear i'm not condoning the use of like
or the sale or or uh
smoking or consumption of plants that
have pm on them i would assume that any
mold spores in general are probably
things we want to keep out of our body
but i was just curious if you'd actually
found any research and then in regards
to the fungicides
it's an unfortunate reality that some
people are still using things like eagle
20 you know
systemic fungicides and pesticides so
i think that's a wonderful point that
you bring up there in that regard
as i understand it you know any oil
based or even water itself will kill pm
it just won't keep it from coming back
and reinfecting the plant um
and and you've already elicited the
stress response at that point from the
plant so i assume it's more susceptible
even than it was before you killed it so
it's something you're going to be
continually
fighting
um
would that be accurate
yeah i think i think that's that's
accurate there are there are other
strategies out there other than you know
innate plant immunity to to powdery
mildew um but you know it just sort of
goes back to you know it maybe it is an
organic oil that you're spraying on your
plants that um
you know it is
keeping the uh the powdery mildew at bay
however i mean you're still when you're
doing that you are you know adulterating
the the end product you know maybe
you know let's say you're using neem oil
it's
pretty widely used in the cannabis
industry
as a safe
pesticide
but not everybody reacts well to neem
oil i mean it is a mixture of uh
essential oils and sometimes essential
oils can elicit a negative immune
response in people
um so while it is much much better than
using you know something as dangerous as
eagle 20 um you know it's
it
it's it's not going to remove your
problem um and it does adulterate your
end product
yeah and i would just add that you know
realistically um
we're not we don't want to spray
anything once the plant starts producing
trichomes so once we get a couple weeks
into flower
you're pretty limited in what you are
able to
spray on a plant
my preference i'll just throw this out
here would probably be something like
self-oil x or mineral oil based
even though it's petroleum
based
there's a lot more research to support
that these products are
safer and they don't leave a residue on
the leaf tissue
more so even the neem
but
yeah i i hear what you're saying the
less we have to spray not only is that a
labor savings uh it's it's keeping us
from having to adulterate the plant at
all or potentially risk anything being
on the leaf surface come harvest time
you know a lot of people ask me
is powdery mildew systemic
and i don't know if that's something you
want to address i can kind of share my
thoughts but i was kind of curious
you know how you would how you would
describe the life cycle of this of these
set this set of fun fungus
so sorry your question is is it systemic
and
what is the the general life cycle yeah
yeah that's sort of what uh what a lot
of people
are asking regarding this this fungus
yeah i would say um
it doesn't
it's only systemic if if the the
environment which you're maintaining
clones or whatever is is sort of
inundated with powdery mildew spores
um
and what what what is the life cycle you
know it's
this is a fungus um
generally
fungi have
two phases of their life they have their
their sport producing phase and they
have their sort of fruiting body
production phase
um so you know
what what
how this works is is you know spores are
introduced to an environment where they
can grow and they'll they'll
start producing it sort of looks like
plant roots um
you know these hyphae
as they're called through whatever that
that medium is sometimes it's
soil sometimes it's something that's
particularly carbohydrate rich like say
a rotting apple
um
or an apple it's rotting because the
fungus is eating all the sugar
and and once it gets to a point where
the the hyphae or this
you know the the fungus equivalent to
roots is strong enough it will start to
produce its fruiting bodies so in the
case of mushrooms right it's the
mushroom it comes out of the hyphae uh
has this this fruiting head um and then
that fruity head is actually what then
produces the spores for the next cycle
um
and and so you know you'll see that
sort of as as you know mushrooms that
have gills um
underneath right sort of your typical
cremini or
um
you know various mushrooms um they'll
drop those spores out of those gills and
then they get spread by the wind or by
animals or insects
and the life cycle continues so in the
in the case of cannabis and powdery
mildew
yeah those spores can can be dormant for
quite some time and when the conditions
are ripe
they can take over a population so i
wouldn't say it's systemic right if you
take a clone
and bring it to a clean environment um
you know
there's a moderate risk
that that plant could then become
inundated with powdery mildew but only
in the right conditions i think you know
having a clean facility especially where
you do your cloning is very important
in not passing pattern milduan
from generation to generation
yeah i was just gonna i mean you
essentially
uh
better explain
my thoughts on it i guess uh it's not
systemic but
it can act in ways that are similar to
something that would be systemic in the
sense that uh the spores are dormant
they may not be visually present um to
the naked eye so when you are cloning
you can
while it's not living inside the leaf
tissue the the
the fungus itself does penetrate the
leaf tissue and so um
you just want to be uh very careful when
you are cloning if you are cloning a
plant that's had pm uh to really do a
good job of
spraying or treating it prior to cloning
and then even after cloning just to make
sure that you're not
you know creating a situation where
you're going to have spore pressure down
the road
exactly
um
well awesome hey i really appreciate you
taking the time today to explain this
research um
was there anything else that you want to
share regarding uh this paper dewey
scientific uh things that you guys have
going on down the road um
or or future research
yeah you know future research and i did
mention that we're on the press or we're
looking for other powdery mildew genes
and we we do think we have a couple
other in hand right now um we're
awaiting sequencing confirmation to just
to see that
um
but you know i think
my big takeaway here is is and i didn't
even really touch on this but you know
none of this would have been possible if
it weren't for uh sort of the
collaborative
um
framework that we had with oregon cbd
you know i think uh because of cannabis
and history people are a little hesitant
to work with others
um but look none of this would have been
possible without them you know we we had
the germplasm we had some of the
key competencies to getting here and
then oregon cbd was able to complement
us in ways that you know we couldn't do
in-house and i think this is just a
testament to you know what's possible
when when folks in the cannabis
community
uh work together you know we we can
achieve great things um and you know
we're
you know i'm a huge proponent of
collaboration and sort of you know
helping other people um
improve their practice and and you know
hopefully that leads to
some more really cool discoveries like
like what we found with uh working cbd
awesome yeah i really appreciate
you know both your companies
doing this work and furthering you know
advancing our knowledge on the subject
and then sharing that publicly and and
you taking the time today to come on the
podcast um i really appreciate it and
again just for folks interested we'll
have this available on the level link
right on the podcast page
i highly suggest people check it out
i just want to say thank you again for
coming on the show today
yeah thank you chad happy to be here um
big fan of the show
even before you asked me to come on
well thanks so much
[Music]
that was dr jordan zagger and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey i'll post pertinent links on the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast if you're looking for consulting
soils or soil amendments or fabric beds
or blue mats for your facility or garden
please give us a call or hit us up
through our website contact page or
t-a-d-k-i-s-organics.com
thanks for listening
you