[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge I've
got some exciting news to share
I've finally been able to release two
white papers that are now available to
read and download on our website the
first one looks at a comparison of
living soil methodologies in relation to
plant health and yield in a controlled
environment for cannabis in this trial
three different living soil recipes were
tested and then put under fluence
lighting in a controlled room and yield
was documented the other white paper
looks at a cost analysis of living soil
cultivation at different yields in
comparison to the cost of more
conventional methods like followed
nutrients or hydroponics we'd love to
get some feedback from growers on these
white papers and hope people will go on
the website and check it out just go to
our front page click on blog and it's
the first two articles on there I'm
hoping this will spark more discussion
and research into this methodology as a
viable way of cultivating cannabis and
controlled environments and also get
some growers to attempt similar
experiments to replicate the results now
on to the podcast my guest this week is
Sarah Pell Cofer Sarah grew up in a
small town in Northern California in the
olive growing capital of the US she got
her BA in environmental studies from UC
Santa Barbara and worked for years for a
private environmental consulting firm
writing environmental impact reports and
statements and creating remediation
plans for Superfund sites she then moved
over to Switzerland to get a master's
degree from the Department of
evolutionary biology and environmental
studies at the University of Zurich
studying and publishing work on the
importance of urban gardens as habitat
for solitary nesting bees and wasps
while starting a microbrewery to pay for
her tuition after she completed her PhD
in plant science and policy at the
University of Missouri
studying plant soil interactions and
publishing her own work on solve a
diversity and the stability of ecosystem
functioning during her PhD she was lucky
enough to be able to travel around the
world to share the results of her years
of research with other researchers and
scientists Sarah wanted to bring this
knowledge about the crucial state of
soil biodiversity to the public so she
left academia and started the company
micro culture in Seattle in 2015 under
which she designed the microbial
inoculant plant probiotics with the
motivation to empower all levels of
gardeners to easily start to bring their
own soil back to life now on to the
podcast yeah I wanted to talk a little
bit about your background you have a
really interesting academic background
relating to everything from evolutionary
biology to environmental studies can you
just tell me a little bit about about
yourself here to start off the podcast
well it took me a while to find in my
direction
after I I grew up in Northern California
in a small farming town and when I
finally went to school I had no idea
what direction I wanted to go but
eventually I was kind of you just went
towards environmental science because I
found that there was just a viewer you
we were just seeing so many problems in
the world and it seemed like a good way
to try and you know make an impact so I
went to environmental science as an
undergrad and I started I was doing like
a geography minor with an environmental
science major and from after I graduated
with my undergraduate degree I went into
environmental consulting and started
working on Superfund sites and doing
environmental impact reports for new
construction sites and it was it was all
pretty it felt like a big Dioner because
it was just just a lot of degradation in
the environment and I decided but I
didn't feel like I was making a big
enough impact so I wanted to go back to
school again and I found a great an
evolutionary biology program at the
University of Zurich in Switzerland and
who doesn't want to live in facility so
I decided to go there and started
studying wild bees and lost in urban
environments and so we were looking
how how these they have these these kind
of urban gardens there
they're like little plots of land that
you can rent and have your own little
garden in the middle of the city and I
was studying how how important these
these gardens were for acting as a
habitat for for bees and lost and it was
pretty cool because we found that these
little tiny gardens that didn't seem to
have they weren't actually like a ton of
space they were very very small like
completely surrounded with you know
high-rise buildings and they were
actually acting as a really important
habitat for for bees and wasps and they
had even more diversity in them of
different species than then were out in
in agricultural areas so it was a pretty
like impactful study in terms of talking
to the city and telling them to kind of
preserve these spaces but after that I
mean I was spending a lot of time in in
the garden and in these gardens and I
was looking at also how the diversity of
bees and wasps was also related to the
diversity of what was in the garden so I
was looking at a lot of plant stuff and
and as my master's degree finished I got
the opportunity to stay to do a PhD and
decided to say for that and ended up
studying the biodiversity underground
and how that was related to biodiversity
above ground and with my work I was
looking at how slow biodiversity affects
how plants grow and how they function
and so we were looking at you know when
I say functioning of an ecosystem we're
talking about the carbon sequestration
nutrient cycling how like how well the
the plants are able to grow like biomass
production and decomposition and like
several different functions like
basically trying to look at the
functionality of the system of the whole
and we called it multi functionality and
we are finding that the more diversity
that you had living in the soil the more
diverse excuse me the more the better
functioning the above-ground system had
and we also the more novel part of my
studies was that we looked at this
stability of that ecosystem functioning
and so we were able to find that systems
that had more soil biodiversity actually
had the greatest ability in the
ecosystem functioning and so it was kind
of like a really like it was really like
it backed up previous work showing that
that there is this relationship between
biodiversity and the functioning of a
system but it also found that that
biodiversity is great for stability and
it really kind of gave like a good a
good background for who are saying that
we need to preserve soil biodiversity
and it's and it's it is really important
for not just you know the underground
but the above-ground systems so after
like finding all of that stuff out and
you know my PhD was coming to a close I
had to figure out do I want to stay in
academia and you know keep spreading the
word in academia and keep building on
this research about soil biodiversity or
do I want to go some other direction and
I decided but I felt like with my
results it seems you know obvious within
the academic community that this was the
way things work but it didn't wasn't
really translated into the public eye
and I figured that you know soil
biodiversity it needs to be preserved
but there it wasn't really like there
was it just needed to be told to the
people somehow in a better way because
scientists and and the public just kind
of have this lack of communication
sometimes so I decided to start a
business called micro cultured and I
make a microbial inoculant that kind of
gives people an easy way to bring their
soil back to life and improve their soil
biodiversity in their backyards and so
it was a major change of hats going from
academia into the public sector but
that's kind of a general story of how I
got there and I know that's great I it's
wonderful that you're local - I've had
the opportunity to meet with you in
person which was a lot of fun and I know
we've talked off air about quite a bit
of stuff and you really impressed me
with your knowledge there's so many of
these microbial based products on the
market now as the industry is
realizing the importance of microbes and
this this concept of plant probiotics
that you're hearing more and more so I
really enjoy I really enjoy that I can
you tell me a little bit more before we
get into this concept of biodiversity
cuz I have some thoughts on that can you
tell me a little bit more about what is
in your plant pro bat probiotics product
well we have when I say we it's me but I
always talk in there the reasons but I
have a mixture of just of three
different kinds of bacteria and four
different kinds of listed fungi that
they're the bacteria all they're
bacillus species and the Thunderer gloma
species and I I came up with this
formula because I wanted to make the
product kind of universally applicable
to different Gardens and different
growing environments and these are
species that my studied in in my
graduate work and they always seem to be
present in healthy really healthy
systems and they're they're naturally
occurring species if you have a healthy
natural soil like if you go out you know
into any grassland or forest you're
gonna find these species there but there
are the species which tend to be lacking
in you know the soils that we process a
lot bagged soils yeah if you basically
if you're adding a lot of fertilizer and
chemicals to your soil you're going to
be pretty efficiently killing these guys
off but they are the ones that that
really help the plants you know they
really form a symbiotic relationship
with the roots of the plants so I have
these different species in the mixture
along with a few starter nutrients of
kelp amino and humic acid and those guys
are there to kind of help the kickstart
to get the bacteria and fungi once
they're activated because the the
product is in a powder form at the dry
powder form and so they're in this
suspended state and then when you add
water to the system they're activated
and then this kelp and amino acid amino
and humic acids come in and kind of give
them some food to start out with before
they are able to seek out the plant
roots in a pair of
them yeah now I found out about you from
Stephanie down at fire cannabis in
Oregon she's been using your product and
she's a good friend I love what she's
doing down there she's an amazing person
I have to give her a shout-out and some
credit and so that's sort of how I found
out and then I realized you were local
and you and I had some conversations
offline and you gave me a sample which I
threw under the microscope and tested
the problem with these a lot of these
like you said suspended microbial
products is there not motile bacteria so
they're not very exciting under the
microscope but I did see an increase in
bacterial biomass over time when I added
distilled water and a food source so I
don't knew there was something alive in
there it just wasn't a lot of fun to
look at under the microscope like some
of the more exciting things like the
fungal hyphae and flageolets and in
motile bacteria but yeah that was that
was great so basically what you did was
you took your background in academia and
looked at the specific species that you
had researched or found to be most
effective and then and then put them
into this product essentially is what is
what I'm getting yeah and I was also I
think I was kind of funneled as well by
by the market and availability of
different laboratories reliable
laboratories in the United States
because I wanted to have a solid source
I mean there's there are tons of
suppliers out there that can they say
they can give you whatever species you
want essentially but a lot of them are
overseas and it's just is is yeah I
didn't have a lot of faith in in the the
viability of the species that we were
beginning so yeah and I didn't want to
like come over on the system as well
with too many species so this is just
kind of a good start for for the mixture
that I have right now yeah I know you're
looking to branch out and you and I
talked about some other microbes that
you were excited about hopefully getting
into a commercial
production with your products down the
road which I love that you're open to
that and it's constantly evolving one
other thing though you had mentioned off
air that you do some testing back with
your old University on the viability of
your product on a fairly regular basis
to make sure that you are providing the
microbial levels that you're claiming on
the product yeah so I sent some samples
back to Switzerland and I luckily I have
my old colleagues a lot of them are on
my scientific advisory board with
microculture so I get to answer back
with and forth with them about ideas and
just kind of Mayberry have better access
to the current state of the science and
so as things are evolving and we're
discovering new things which we are all
the time because you know sciences or
excuse me soil is really like the great
frontier we know so little about it so
it's it's great to have them there like
with their hand and academia and being
able to have access to the journals and
all of the current science and so I sent
samples back to them and they've
incorporated them into some greenhouse
experiments and then they also have you
know the DNA extraction laboratory and
equipment to do that but I also have
contract or I have samples going out to
some local labs here in the Pacific
Northwest and they're doing the fungal
spore analysis for me and I think it's
really important to kind of just
constantly keep testing your product
because it's just it's a really
challenging medium because we can't see
we can't see the species either it's
really hard to have quality control
visibly and so you have to you know send
stuff out and you have to pay for it but
I think it's important to have have
these to be able to know that you have
the viability that is listed on your
product and at least at the minimum
concentrations that are that are on the
package so it's it's it's yeah it's
money out of your pocket but I think in
the end you're gonna have a better
product that's more reliable that's
going to give more reliable results to
your clients
and so I think it's totally worth it
yeah one thing that a lot of growers
don't realize is that with microbial
based products you I believe you have to
submit an initial test that shows the
concentrations to support what you're
putting on your label
but beyond that there's there's very
limited testing done by the state to
actually ensure that the levels that
you're claiming on the package are
really in the bag and then you don't
know how long it's been sitting on a
shelf how it's been stored by whatever
company is distributing or selling that
product and it gets really really
convoluted I would say the only state
that I know that's actually done any of
this testing is the Oregon Department of
Agriculture so I suggest if you haven't
signed up for their fertilizer and
pesticide alerts it's something that
everyone should go do it's just a free
email service that they provide you just
give them your email and there they do
this a study are some testing back in I
want to say two thousand fifteen or
sixteen and they found that the levels
were quite different based on what the
claims were on the bag so just something
for people to be aware of when they're
looking at comparing microbial based
products yeah I think it's important
that there is there should be you know
kind of a shelf-life listed on the
product because it's I mean that's just
let's say for the the producer and for
the consumer because yeah Ben because
even microbes they want to grow I mean
fungi and bacteria they want to grow if
they get any access to sugars or if it's
a suspended form like what I have in a
dry powder farm if it gets access to any
kind of moisture there they're gonna
grow and things are gonna change and I
mean that's the beauty of fungi and
bacteria is it's they're constantly
changing evolving but I think if you're
going to be selling the products with
you know X number species listed X
concentrations you have to be able to
kind of stand behind that so yeah I want
it I want to kind of change directions
here now you'd mentioned biodiversity
early on in our conversation and how
that was one of the findings that you've
had in your in your university study and
I haven't actually talked to you about
this yet but I
recently went to Chicago for photo X
which is a conference put on by fluence
bioengineering it's it's a lot of fun
and a lot of really good studies are
presented there and I hope to share some
of that later on but interestingly
enough I'm sitting in on the plane and
this guy next to me is reading a journal
article on how how earthworms can be
used to in soil remediation this
particular earthworm species and so I
leaned over to him and asked him if he
was a soil scientist and sure enough I
got I got seated probably next to the
only soil scientist on the plane which
was which was wonderful so he's he was a
German professor who looked at they were
measuring in a given amount of soil they
would find they may have 20 different
species of earthworms and a certain
amount you know a certain concentration
of those earthworms and they were able
to use that data for a given area to see
as an early indicator of the quality of
that soil or so to be able to address
soil problems before they got too bad so
essentially using the earthworm as an
early indicator species which was I
thought really interesting and then he
was taking that and he said that they
were that they found some farmers were
taking earthworm castings or course or
that have actual you know viable
earthworm species in it and then
planting him into fields that were
degraded that didn't have good
biodiversity and these cores they were
able to move I believe it was 3 meters
per year and so you'd end up with this
like circular patch around that core and
there's a company doing this now in
Germany and coring these fields and
you'd see much healthier plants
biodiversity all of these benefits from
this application so that was just
something I wanted to share that
happened happened to me this weekend but
then when I got to this conference it
was very different because
one of the things I found with
university professors is they want
everything to be controlled you know if
they want to run a study they want to
control every variable and the challenge
there is when you look at organics and
and what we've talked about with
biodiversity you really you really can't
so that a lot of the studies a lot of
the studies with organics may add too
much too much variability I don't know
what your thoughts are are on that but
it seemed it was difficult to get the
academic people there to talk about
organics sorted or to look at organics
just because of the complexity of the
ecosystem yeah I mean I think that's
that's one of like the hardest things of
working in ecology is you're you're
working with these living systems that
have I mean ecology is like the it's the
inner linking of all of these these
different things and there's just
effects from the the light the the air
and the like all the different gases the
water is just all these different
effects and I think it's it's yeah it's
incredibly difficult to isolate you know
the variables of you know what what has
actually happened in effect and I mean
it's funny because it's my PhD work I
had access to these incredible systems
we called them eco tubes and it really
looked like you did not look like a
natural system at all but it was the
best shot we had at trying to figure out
the true effect of soil biodiversity and
so these eco tubes were designed by my
my in German it's called dr. father
it's my PhD advisor Marcel Vanderheiden
and they are these systems that they're
these it's used kind of cylinders with
these clear plexiglass
tops and all of the air in the water
going into the system was filtered and
so we would we would only add it was it
was of the entire soil medium only five
percent was our treatment so most of the
soil is actually sterilized but we would
add in a five percent inoculant of the
soil biodiversity that we were testing
and so with with all the air and the
water being filtered going in and trying
to be basically eliminated the outside
contamination of different microbes
we're living in the greenhouse already
we that was a I would say probably one
of the best systems that I've seen for
for trying to isolate solo biodiversity
and of course it's artificial and
there's you know some negatives from
from having such an artificial system
but yeah I think that kind of really
what you're saying is nails nails the
difficulty of testing organic systems
because to have an are you know to
really test an organic system you have
to kind of make a a non natural system
to do it so it's it's incredibly
difficult to isolate the effects and and
seeing like what's really causing the
differences in your system is it you
know it's yes it's incredibly
challenging yeah I would also say it it
may limit the amount of academic
interest in studying some of these
organic concepts to because it's so much
harder to draw any sort of trends or
conclusions from the research and it's
so there's a lot more challenges like we
discussed so I I guess my big takeaway
was that it still felt like at this at
this conference that more and more
people are pushing for more conventional
agricultural I guess processes or
applications but hopefully we can take
some of that data and then apply it back
into organics so so take some of the
things that we're learning regarding
lighting and nutrition and then find
organic ways to replicate or or use that
information that they're from that
they're doing so along that note you had
sent me this recent article in Wired
there's a lot of stuff that you're
finding in the news this came out on
October 2nd and I'll post these articles
on the podcast page this particular one
is called farmers can now buy designer
microbes to replace fertilizer would you
want to talk a little bit about what the
findings in that article were yeah so it
was this Berkeley biotech start-up and
it was called pivot they called pivot
bio and they they launched the first and
only nitrogen
reducing microbial treatment for four US
corn farmers so they're essentially
trying to in the nitrogen fixing
bacteria that you normally find in like
legumes or the fungi and bacteria but
pair up with legumes they're trying to
do it pair it up with corn which is this
it's unheard of I mean it's it's
incredible to think that we have the
science to be able to do this but they
use like a bunch of gene editing tools
to rewire the gene expression of these
bacteria that they found that they found
them in nature paired up to the roots of
some some corn but normally what happens
in these agricultural systems is when
you when you throw fertilizer onto the
system you basically shut off the
responses of these these nitrogen fixing
bacteria like they they basically get
this thing like the plant sends out the
signal that it has enough nutrients
coming in and so the the bacteria
doesn't get the signal to pair up with
the root but they've kind of switched
the genes to make these bacteria keep on
pairing with with the plant even when
there is fertilizer inputs and so the
kind of idea of is that the farmer can
keep adding fertilizer but also have the
benefits of the bacteria that are there
increasing the efficiency of the uptake
of of the nitrogen so it's yeah it's
crazy to think that we use we're already
at a point where this is being put onto
the market pretty advanced yeah now
knowing with your background I guess how
much concern do you think there is for
the for the addition of you know
essentially these gene edited microbes
or even non-native microbes to various
soils in terms of their effect on
biodiversity it it appears from what I
see that you just don't see a lot of
microbial persistence which is why a lot
of these are being applied over and over
again
but what what sort of findings have you
seen along that along those lines well I
think and nature is going to sort out
the populations itself you know if these
guys don't if they're not fitting into
the niche space of a particular
environment they're they're just not
going to be a little
there and other bacteria are going to be
able to out-compete them but it yeah so
it's it's I don't know like what kind of
guarantee this company is going to give
for the viability of this kind of
application and if they if they're
expecting people to probably have to
reapply every year I'm not sure but I
think it's I don't think they can give
any kind of guarantee of the
effectiveness of this kind of product
because everyone's system is different
and they're going to have a completely
different soil microbial community
underground but is going they're good
the species that are living they're
going to determine you know whether or
not this one survives so yeah it's it's
gonna be really interesting to see like
how how this all works out and and I
mean it's terrible to think that you
when you put these you know gene edited
species into the ground you're kind of I
don't know it's a little too hand like
human hand heavy in in my opinion I
think there's probably should be more
tests done but yeah you you you think is
like the worst case if you're kind of
growing a monster and if it somehow
if this species really like takes off it
could take over and kill off native
species and I think we just don't
understand soil biodiversity enough to
really be messing with it so much but I
yeah we'll see where it goes I guess see
what happens so we may be playing God in
a sense and releasing essentially a lion
in a petting zoo potentially I you know
I had an interesting conversation with
this German professor on the plane about
this and I was asking him about you know
essentially the exact same question I
asked you and he gave me a response and
I was like well you know you study
earthworms earthworms are not native to
North America but they have a ton of
benefits and we're all glad they're here
and he said well his colleagues in
Canada actually there's certain species
of plants that require a mulch a heavy
mulch layer and the earthworms are
breaking it down too quickly causing
these particular plants to really suffer
and potentially go extinct so Wow
you know
something that I think I've always
thought of as a positive addition to our
soils when we talk about worms does have
non-target organism effects that may or
may not be beneficial so it's something
to think about yeah and actually some
some work of my colleagues in
Switzerland and they found that that
some of the the biggest differences in
in the effects on the above-ground
community of soil biodiversity when they
looked at the the soil community they
found that the those systems that did
the best actually had populations of
more rare species in them so they're
thinking that may be the reason that
they systems did better with the higher
biodiversity was actually more of an
effect of the rare species in the system
so I think you know maybe these rare
species is there's something that we
need to focus on preserving more rather
than just finding one species that does
X really well and so we had a bunch of
that it's like you need to kind of focus
on the entire community and not not just
individuals yes and one difference I do
want to point out between you know your
product and you know this particular
study is that your product contains
bacteria and fungi that are already
found essentially worldwide they're
native to I think all soils as far as I
know yeah that's exactly okay I just
wanted to point that out for people
because I want to make sure that we're
we're distinguishing the two yeah so
what I wanted to move on to there was
one other study I want to talk about
with you that Stephanie actually sent
over and this one I thought was really
fascinating it came out on July 26 this
article out of the University of
California Berkeley entitled fertilizer
destroys plants micro biomes ability to
protect against disease I know she sent
it to you as well did did you want to
talk about that a little bit yeah this
is a really interesting study yeah they
found that that when you when you add
fertilizer to the system before before
they they threw an
it was a Pseudomonas species that causes
some kind of blight in the tomatoes
before applying that Pseudomonas they
they applied fertilizer and they found
that this application of fertilizer
negated the protection of that the mic
that the biodiversity normally had for
protecting the plant against the disease
and so so when when when there was
fertilizer applied and they put the
Pseudomonas on there it completely took
out the the plant and if they had
biodiversity there then the plan was or
they didn't have the fertilizer
application before send the microbiome
was it was able to protect the system
from the incoming Pseudomonas so yeah it
was it was it's a really interesting
finding
so in yeah I think it's just the
changing of the nutrients when you when
you throw in as fertilizers into the
system it really just throws off the
balance of the microbiome and and then I
think also that when you throw on
fertilizer
the plant if it gets the signal that it
has enough nutrients and so it doesn't
send out the amino acids and signals to
pair up with with more of the species on
your ground and so then you're you don't
get the symbiotic pairing with with the
good guys and so when the bad guys come
in the systems open and free and they're
able to come in and just you know munch
at the at their will on the plant yeah
one other really interesting result from
this study was they found the best the
most protective community of of microbes
was the lowest application dose as well
so the higher they applied the microbial
community the less plant resistance they
got to the diseases that they were they
were adding yeah and you initially look
at that and you're like cadets that's
weird but and if you think about it
there they looked at the details of this
because that this just looks strange to
me and and I found that they they only
applied
culturable species to the that's what
their microbiome was they're there
manipulated microbiome so it's only
twelve species but they only they did
the testing it was one week after the
application and so in my mind if you if
you have more species that you're
throwing in its gonna take a lot longer
than a week for everyone to kind of get
situated and find their place so yeah I
think that you have species trying to
they're kind of all battling for
nutrients and getting settled in their
new space and so I don't know I would
like to see how those results would
change if they tested later than one
week after application but yeah I would
I don't know about the details of what
exact species they were and yeah I'd
have to have to read more on it so they
yeah they took healthy tomatoes and then
cultured twelve bacterial species that
they found naturalized and and thriving
on these healthy tomatoes and then
sprayed them on to new Tomatoes so just
to kind of explain that to people and
all I'll post this article on the
podcast page as well so people can read
it did you notice if the twelve species
came from the same location I didn't I
didn't see that in there I just saw that
they took them from healthy Tomatoes
yeah and so I was wondering if maybe
they were coming from different
locations which would then indicate they
would probably even be battling more for
the new space and it would just be like
a rougher transition for that first week
of the species together but I don't yeah
it's just another thought yeah it's
interesting because one of the claims
that you hear out of the compost tea
world which is something I want to talk
to you about next year is that foliar
applications of compost tea provide
aerobic or beneficial microorganisms
directly on the leaf surface of the
plant that will out-compete pathogens
for that leaf space now whether or not
that is true it's hard to say I haven't
seen enough actual research on it and
compost tea very so much that it'd be
really hard to draw any conclusions
anyway but it sort of goes in well in
some ways opposition to the
but also in support of the idea of
having a healthy microbiome on your leaf
surface yeah I mean it's called like
pre-emptive colonization is like if the
yeah it's just there's no space in the
end you know if it's someone's living
there and they're eating up all the
resources there's just not going to be
any available for the new guy coming in
so it's just it's harder for them to
colonize so I think it's it's definitely
a valid valid argument and also I think
we should be careful with foliar
applications knowing that we may be
increasing the opportunity opportunistic
bacteria for disease I guess on our on
our Leafs themselves so that would be
the other conclusion I'd want to draw
from that but let's talk a little bit
about you know plant probiotics versus
compost tea and some of these other
products on the market you know they are
they are quite different can you can you
give a server an overview on your
thoughts about about these differences
yeah and I mean compost tea is great
like it's it's I think if you can
compost tea you should compost tea and
I'm not we're not trying to replace
compost tea but I just think that
everyone not everyone has the time the
resources and the knowledge to make a
really good compost tea as you know it's
it takes a lot of trial and error to get
like your compost heap
right and you have to have the right
temperature the right nutrients with
feeder they have to figure out the right
time for your environment it's always
you know your stuff your starter species
is its dependent on what what you have
in there to start with so it's just a
lot of yeah it takes a lot of trial and
error to get it like a really good
compost tea going so I made plant
probiotics there's an easier way to get
a lot of the benefits that you get with
a compost tea without having to you know
have a have all that trial and error
time and and also without the mess so
it's especially good I guess if you're
you're in an apartment or something
neither can't really do a compost tea
you know in your kitchen and you could
but yeah it's just not as convenient so
plant probiotics is kind of a convenient
way to
a lot of the species that you're trying
to grow and a good compost tea but just
have it in a more guaranteed and
convenient form and so yeah I think that
if you can compost tea you should do it
but it's it's it is like the next best
thing is a plant probiotics or or of
course having your own compost would be
even better yeah I think when we're
talking about this we really have to
compare oh look at all the pros and cons
so with compost tea or aerated compost
tea just to be specific here if there's
there's a lot of there's a lot of cost
associated with with having a good
Brewer it's not as simple as just
throwing an aquarium pump in a bubbler
in a bucket and then throwing in some
compost and a food source there actually
is a fair bit of science that goes into
designing and and using a good brewing
system and the other child's with
compost tea is is variability so we
don't we are never going to get the
exact same brew even if you use the
exact same water source compost source
brewing time it's still gonna vary quite
a bit and that's one of the challenges
is that variability there's also the
risk of potentially having pathogens in
the compost tea now I think that's a
fairly low risk due to if you're using
high quality compost there's going to be
a majority of beneficial microorganisms
and then the last thing along that lines
is one advantage of compost tea is that
we're getting functional nutrient
cycling which is something that you you
don't necessarily get with these other
microbial based products that being said
you know microbial based product like
like yours may help increase nutrient
cycling once in the soil so I know a lot
of people have moved away from compost
tea just because of that variability but
at the same time there's so much that we
just don't know about soil plant
interactions in the rhizosphere that
people are you know even when people
make a less than
great compost either a lot of times
they're still seeing benefit and you
know you've you've shown me results with
your product where even if you have a
pretty good soil by adding you know
plant probiotics you're still seeing an
increase in overall plant health yeah
exactly
yeah I think it would but I think you're
the major point there is is we don't
really understand what's going on and so
it's yeah it's kind of better to give
the system more options you know without
doing too much obviously but but letting
it kind of sort out what it needs and
just giving it giving it a kind of a
buffet option of you know what to eat
yeah and while we've talked about how we
can't really control for every variable
with organics and with these trials what
what you could do is you know take a
product like yours and apply it to a few
of your plants in your garden and see
how they respond versus the other plants
you know trying to eliminate as many
variables as possible and that would
really be an easy way to determine a
cost-benefit analysis of you know adding
a microbial product like this totally
yeah so you can't look at your garden
and say like oh I'm missing some Glomus
and you're a disease and they're you
really it's if you gotta just to guess
and check um and if you side by side pot
experiments that's definitely the best
way to try and figure it out figure out
where you're missing your biodiversity
where's your dad so what other things
are you seeing here as you've started
working with gardeners and growers that
are using you know your product or
microbes as as an additive into their
gardens what am I saying yeah what kind
of what kind of results are you seeing
is there anything you've learned from
now that you've had this company for a
few years
in terms of how what sort of like
responses people are getting do they
vary quite a bit
are you hearing back the same things
from from growers or gardeners I I've
gotten a lot of reviews from people that
were just like you saved a plant that
was just totally on his way out and
they'd be tried you
adding different fertilizers and they
thought they had certain pest problems
and they found that just adding the
plant probiotics really just it just
made the plant stronger and people are
finding I mean I have a guy who sends me
pictures of his roses every year cause
he's just like these are the most
beautiful roses I've ever had and he's
he's like just the guy's really into his
roses and so it's cool I mean I didn't
design the product for making roses more
beautiful but it's it's a great
byproduct of plant probiotics so but
yeah people are finding they just have
more robust plant communities they're
able to resist disease better they
they're able to survive through our
crazy rowdy summers now better and
that's because you know when you have a
fungal community that pairs up with the
roots of the plants and it really is a
crece now and extending the root of the
plant
that plant is going to be able to get to
more of the water that is existing in
the soil so when you do water it's it's
going to be more effective and more
efficient and the plant is going to be
able to better survive that the you know
the hotter drier days but yeah people
people have done a lot of positive
reviews and some people have said you
know didn't really do anything from for
my plants and maybe that's because they
had a really great diversity in their
soil already or it think it's really
hard to say you know why why exactly it
you know it might not have shown
positive effects on someone's system
like maybe they I don't know maybe they
they applied it in a wrong way or
something but yeah it's really hard to
say but it's a good first Abbot at
trying to restore your biodiversity in
your soil but I think we just started
making a new shaker jar this year and
that's seem to go over really well with
a lot of people because that's one thing
I found is that people really like
convenience and the we have a shaker jar
it it looks kind of like just a little
spice jar and so you can take it and use
it in house plants really easily and
keep it under the sink and pull it out
whenever your plants looking a little
sad and and just sprinkle it on the soil
surface and water it in and bam you're
done and you
have to go out to your shed and change
out your soil and it's just a really
easy and convenient way to try and help
your plants kind of in a more natural
way than a lot of other things that you
can do so it's I found people really
like convenience and they seem to be
pretty pretty happy with their results
in general so that gets me thinking
based on this research that we've
already discussed what do you think of
for I guess best practice around
applications of microbial based products
whether it's compost tea or your product
in regards to fertilizer and other
applications well I think if you can get
your soil community strong and robust
and diverse you're not going to need to
add excess fertilizer I mean unless it's
like a really closed system and you'll
probably have to if you're not restoring
it if you're not restoring the nutrients
in your system in any way and you're
taking stuff out of it constantly you're
probably gonna have to restore it
somehow but in general if you have a
natural soil community that's strong and
robust the soil microbes are going to do
the work for you and you don't have to
add all the synthetics and the terrible
things that have become like the norm
and mainstream that we're all starting
to realize or just they're bad for the
environment they're bad for us for our
bodies they're bad for the planet
essentially they're bad for the soil
community so we can kind of steer clear
of those if we have our soil or soil
diverse and strong and healthy but I
think yeah just just try out different
species on different mixes and see what
works in your system see what you're
missing so yeah it from that respect I
would say yeah look for to look for like
a diverse species list you're trying
something else and then just yeah see
how your system responds so what about
adding additional micro mycorrhizal
fungus at you know at say for example
taking your product and another micro
product and adding them in at you know
initial transplant for example or
when when cloning have you seen anyone
doing anything like that yeah I think
that's probably the most effective time
to add the product because you're really
like you're you're putting it in right
at the root zone when you're planting
and and it's more of like a yeah a basic
system so the the fungi and that the
plant root are more likely to pair up
but you're asking like what's the
difference between like between two
differents two different products or
what like are you saying well I know you
have some gloma species in your product
uh-huh and then there's other ones that
are more to have higher spore counts
that but may not have that same
diversity like for for example the ones
that we currently sell or specifically
rise of agus inter a disease or Columbus
inter a disease because that is the most
researched form of our species of micro
so in regards to most of the plants that
people are growing is I know you already
know this so I'm just throwing it out
there for listeners so adding a higher
spore count say of the of that
particular Glomus species at the time of
inoculation we could add in your product
at the same time I guess is what I'm
getting at is a way of increasing the
overall microbial community or a
microbiome yeah totally and I think
again it's finding that yeah that
missing missing piece and your in your
garden puzzle and because the system is
going to self-regulate like if it
already has too much inter a disease it
can only support so many so it's going
to balance it out and I think yeah you
can you can add a bunch of different
stuff and I don't know if the spore
counts it definitely matters up to a
certain point but after that I think
it's just kind of maybe overkill because
long as you can guarantee the successful
growth of spores you know a certain base
base base line of spores they're going
to propagate and so they're gonna
they're going to fill up fill up your
community you know even if you start
with a low number if they have the
resources there and the the environment
is right for them they're going to bloom
so you just need to have like a
I would say like a minimum there's like
a minimum viable number that you should
have but yeah I I don't think
necessarily having a lot more is really
going to make a huge difference in your
system because if they can't support
them they'll just die off yeah that's a
good point I mean ultimately all we
really care about is that we're getting
this micro Raizel infection as quickly
as possible when transplanting because a
lot of people you know we're talking
about a pretty high value crop here with
cannabis and a pretty short growth cycle
so getting that done as quickly as
possible but the research that we talked
about today is showing that maybe higher
amounts of microbes are not always
necessarily better so I think there's a
lot more research to be done on this I
think that's really interesting so while
I have you on the phone is there
anything else that you'd like to share
in regards to the future of your company
or the future of sort of microbiology
and you know agriculture and
horticulture in general that you're
seeing well yeah I mean I think for
plant probiotics you gotta just keep an
eye on things cuz I I have some some
ideas in the works of you know expanding
and adding different products you know
targeting different plants specifically
because we know that there are there
specific species that pair up better
with certain plants and and so yeah I'm
trying to constantly evolve evolve the
product maybe just go for a different
you know having a line of products that
that go for different different plants
and different targets so keep an eye on
that but yeah in terms of I think I
think it was it Dave Montgomery talks
about like the first agricultural
revolution that we're in right now and I
think yes it's I think it's an exciting
time like we we are learning how to kind
of give the power back to nature and in
our growing systems and we're realizing
that you know us interfering and adding
you know all these synthetic you know
fertilizers and pesticides is not really
the way to go and so it's exciting to
see like where we're going with this
kind of encouraging our soil
biodiversity
and letting nature do what it does best
which is grow plants and you know it's
yeah it's it's it's an exciting time so
um it's good we'll keep an eye out on
things and I'm really interested to see
like where these these new biotech
companies go with trying to isolate
different genes and and put them into
the agricultural systems yeah I've been
seeing more and more stuff pop up on
endo Finnick fungi and bacteria so
microorganisms that actually live within
the plant the plant itself or within in
within the seed and I think it's I think
that might be the next big thing here in
terms of biologicals and plant growth
but I'm it's sort of really really new
at this point I don't know if you've
seen much research on that but it's
something that I'm I think is really
interesting yeah I haven't read much on
that I'll send you an article and when
we get off the phone okay but yeah I
really appreciate you coming on today I
I think that answers all my questions
and I look forward to I guess catching
up with you
here in the near future yeah yeah thanks
for giving the opportunity to be on yeah
no actually I think we have a delivery
coming here through shop today some
plant probiotics so that was Sarah Pell
Cooper with plant probiotics I posted
the links and information we discussed
in this podcast right on the podcast
page at WWII s organics comm just click
on the podcast menu at the top of the
home screen and don't forget to sign up
for our newsletter on our website right
on the home page and subscribe on your
favorite listening platform so you can
stay up to date with all the latest
information and podcasts right when they
come out you can also view and download
the new white papers and their results
on our website blog page and thank you
for all the wonderful comments and
reviews regarding the podcast
sometimes I get frustrated or stressed
trying to keep up with my regular work
schedule and also produce this podcast
so I appreciate the positive reviews and
comments thanks for listening
you
[Music]