[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from a around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge just a friendly reminder for
folks who enjoy the podcast content and
want to support our small company we
have a patreon for the podcast where we
do a book club Hangouts and share
private content that we don't share on
social media we also offer a wide range
of products on our kiss Organics website
ranging from living soils LED lighting
beneficial insects organic fertilizers
and professional Consulting for this
week's podcast though we we're talking
all about water drram is an industry
leader when it comes to equipment
related to irrigation and horiculture my
guest this week is Les Evans Les has a
degree in biological engineering with a
concentration in water soil and
environmental engineering from NC State
University and 29 years of Industry
experience helping Growers of all types
of crops with their environmental and
water quality challenges L's day-to-day
involves supporting the dram sales team
and their customers with water treatment
designs that maximize investment while
minimizing environmental impact when
he's not at his desk he can be found
planting perennials with his family or
running the NC mountains to Sea Trail
system a Stones thrown away from his
home in Raleigh now on to the
show hey Les thanks for coming on the
podcast appreciate it I I am really
happy to be here thanks for having me
Ted yeah I you are actually the third
dram person person to come on the
podcast uh we were talking before the
show and you mentioned uh reminded me
that Casey schenberg had been on the
podcast talking about fish hydraulis
State and how it's made if folks want to
go back and check that out and then the
wonderful Kurt Becker also came on and
talked about all things water so we're
going to do a similar sort of style
podcast today I I recently caught your
webinar on dissolved oxygen and I will
link to that for folks who want to go on
a deeper dive specifically into dissolve
oxygen we will talk about it today uh
but I really have just a a random list
of questions related to water that I
think will be useful for Growers to
think about as they think about their
water source but uh can you tell me a
little bit about yourself before we dive
into the
podcast sure yeah um entered the
greenhouse and Nursery space now we call
it ca in 1995 out of NC State University
biological engineer water soil and
environmental engine engering
concentration got really lucky hired by
a Swedish firm uh that is really
involved in controlling the environment
in green houses right out of school and
just they sent me around the world and I
started seeing a lot of neat um ways to
grow plants and have been in the
industry just ever since been with drram
for I'd have to do the math 12 13 14
years um you mentioned Kurt Becker and
Casey it's a neat team it's from we
really FR does a great job we're from
all over the place um in terms of
backgrounds and dram water sort of
officially became a thing I'm making it
up 10 years ago and we started really
putting uh water projects together so my
job at dram is sort of the lead designer
uh we have a lot of vendors of course
that we work with and we take a
customers's new project or problem uh
specifically again in dram water with
their with their water um and growing
plants and we put packages together for
them uh that could look like a very
complex system or hopefully a very
simple system dissolved oxygen has
become more of a topic every year uh
we've been learning a lot more about how
important dissolved oxygen is in terms
of growing a healthy plant um and so
it's just something that we always are
talking about um from again the most
simple to most complex growing
situations um dissolved oxygen is
something that just is not going away
and the more we learn about it the the
more we we realize how vital it can be
to growing a efficient healthy plant so
that's that's where we're at and yeah
thanks for I'm glad you were able to see
that webinar that the magazine hosted
for
us yeah so and just a reminder for folks
if you are looking for a more complete
engineering solution for your water in a
commercial ftil facility or Greenhouse
dram is a wonderful resource for that um
it is actually quite complex the amount
of variables and things that go into
that sort of a system um so I can't
recommend them enough they also since
we're talking about a little bit about
their products as a quick plug uh they
make these wonderful Water breaker wands
uh that was I think where you started in
the industry as well as uh probably one
of the best sprayers um commercial
sprayers that I've ever seen and a very
cool nematode bucket that Suzanne
absolutely loves so they have a wide
range of products uh that are definitely
worth checking out uh but even if you're
not a commercial scale grower a lot of
what we're going to talk about today I
think will just apply to water in
general I I even think about it in terms
of um a homeg grower so uh let's just
start with dissolved
oxygen starting there uh the the big
takeaways from your your webinar on that
was that raising dissolve oxygen led to
much healthier plant outcomes can you
kind of expand on that though in Greater
detail yeah absolutely so generally we
are unable to apply as much dissolved
oxygen as we're learning the plant would
like to have that's the bottom line
rather if it's if it's the reservoir in
my basement grow uh or you know a
100,000 gallon tank or straight well
water or what have you it just we aren't
providing that uh root zone system and
that plant enough dissolved oxygen to be
in its happy place is kind of how I
think about it um and the more we learn
about its happy place the more complex
it gets but it boils down to a lot of
symbiotic things working well together
to efficiently do what we also want to
happen which is to have a healthy plant
grow as much flower or fruit or color or
whatever we want that plant to do um as
possible and so dissolved oxygen is
something that is part of every
conversation we have um sometimes we
aren't doing anything to manipulate it
because we might have uh enough uh but
again it's it's generally we're talking
about ways of uh even keeping what we
did start with in the water longer and
getting it to the actual crop but and a
lot of times it's mechanically adding it
to a system to be able to get it to the
crop but like you said it can be um it's
just a lot of conversations
conversations and under
understanding uh what what we're growing
um what the media is what fertilizer
regime you are are you organic are you
salts are you combination so all of this
again it's it's a conversation to
understand U but we know that dissolved
oxygen as an input should not be ignored
right so we're looking at all these
other things that we're apply you know
that we're doing to grow our plant let's
not ignore dissolved
oxygen now if I have a reservoir it's
very simple to add a bubbler and that
will get me what to sort of a ambient
level of dissolved oxygen potentially
and then there are ways to Super
saturate the water can you touch on what
that technology looks like perfect I I
can geek out on um the res
increasing dissolved oxygen and not
shooting ourselves in the foot in doing
so I've learned from a lot of the best
and a lot of uh colleagues and a lot of
uh friends in terms of uh and the
smaller the
reservoir the harder it can be to not
shoot yourself in the
foot um and I bottom line is we don't
want to overheat the Water by putting a
a a nice even if it's a really high-end
Aras Stone in the bottom of a 20 gallon
res um we might be increasing the
temperature dramatically and that causes
other issues and it becomes a lot harder
to keep any dissolved oxygen in that
water if we've increased the temperature
of that water and so be careful what we
like to do is pick an appropriate
technology and now there's just like you
said some wonderfully simple things to
do um and then if we can stir the water
it might be our classic dropping a fish
little two gallon a minute fish pump in
my small Reservoir um or I might use
fancy Mass transfer nozzles in a 10,000
gallon tank but we're stirring the water
to keep that dissolved oxygen in
solution longer we're not mixing or
bubbling the water that's just going to
raise it to the surface inappropriately
if we have made True dissolved oxygen um
and we can keep it in the water longer
so again depending on the vessel if we
do have storage again from a 25-gallon
reservoir to a 5,000 gallon or 50,000
gallon tank there's different
methodologies in adding and keeping the
dissolved oxygen in solution uh so
that's a really fun conversation again
whether it be just a hom grower um with
or a commercial grower we're going to
look at different ways of enhancing or
just keeping what we can in in in
solution so temperature plays a a big
role in terms of the water's capacity to
retain oxygen as the water gets warmer
it can it can't hold as much um I'm also
thinking that we have to water with
water that's temperature appropriate for
the crop that we're growing you know we
don't want to water with 50 degree
temperature water so what does that
balance look like yep so you're right
we're generally aiming for industry
standards 68 70 degrees Fahrenheit right
that's our that's our general happy
place to not Shock young root systems
anything under you know plants can
handle quite a lot obviously uh but we
don't want to apply cold water to the
younger the plant the more detrimental
it can become we've we've lots of
studies out there cold water to a
younger root system can really slow
things down dramatically a few hours of
really cold water we've seen affect even
a cannabis a vigorous cannabis species
uh it can slow it down by many days if
not weeks so that those are interesting
studies to go and look so really wow
really pay more attention I don't I mean
I'm the dissolved oxygen guy sort of or
one of many but pay very much attention
to not applying too cold of water um if
you're nice buffered big living soil
environment it's kind of got its own
warmth so to speak it's going to ma not
matter so much but if you're hydroponic
grower if you're growing in Stones you
know if you just have a more media less
media free en environment that water
temperature is really affecting and the
younger we're trying to grow those root
hairs we're trying to do all these
processes and if it's too cold things
are just thinking oh I got to go into
dormant I'm I'm getting ready for
something but it's not fruiting right
it's the opposite so just think about
the the seasonal changes so again I I
digress but the colder the water we can
hold more dissolved oxygen well let's
make it really cold so I can get more
dissolved oxygen no there is that fine
line that you just mentioned we're
aiming for Mid 60s mid 70s is the happy
place and we can put in five six seven
eight parts per million of dissolved
oxygen within that temperature can we
get it to the crop you know and again
again what else is in the water what
what's going to steal from the oxygen
that we're trying to create um the
biofilms the just goo you know uh some
of our soils we're adding dissolved
oxygen let's let's get it to the
beneficial microbes let's get it to the
appropriate things in the rizosphere um
before it gets stolen in the piping
system or just again high temperature is
bad it's going to come out of solution
really quickly we can't hold as much too
cold has its own problems so there's
that happy medium when applying it to
plants yeah one question I asked you off
air that I was curious about is what Doo
levels are we getting using a dram Water
breaker watering head because in my in
my brain I figured there's got to be
some Doo getting added just from the
mechanism of the way the water is being
split into such small particles but
maybe I'm totally wrong what are your
thoughts around something like
that and my answer was I think if we
start at zero if we have just wellwater
or a municipal water coming right out of
the spet right out of our faucet and
it's near zero probably uh we might be
lucky and have a couple parts per
million that's still not a good level of
oxygen right so we're going to get
things happening in Reverse if we apply
anoxic or hypoxic water to a root system
things are going to go in reverse right
we're stealing oxygen out of the plant
because of Osmosis properties right so
we've got to make sure we get that
minimum when we say five parts per
million does a Water breaker
help it has to do with so many things
there's so many different flavors of
Water breaker
um if you haven't been to a a garden
center um you know and seen the drram
water Breakers typically on the retail
side and what we see at home grows is
the 400 hole Water breaker the original
aluminum one you can still buy it's a
nice beefy one you can drag around on
the concrete it's not going to get hurt
there's the plastic ones but they have
400 holes you can purchase a thousand
holes generally the idea for the Water
breaker was to break up the water to
soften the water to not compact the top
layer of the
soil in which you know which helps us
have a more poorer soil which allows
more oxygen to do what it needs to do in
the root zone so the original idea was
not to probably add dissolved oxygen via
the water breaking um mechanism of a of
a dram Water breaker or anybody's Water
breaker but I think that you're right
it's got to increase it if we started at
zero I think it's going to help if I
happen to supply 10 parts per million of
do I might lose dissolved oxygen because
it's smashing against the screen and now
it's introducing it to a lower
environment so it's going to try to
reach equilibrium so if I came at it
with a real high like if I'm got a dram
water system and I've got 30 parts per
million in my reservoir and then I'm
spraying it out of my hose it's going to
decrease it versus uh if you can imagine
spaghetti tube you know drip
irrigation right to the soil we have 30
parts per million in the tank and a lot
of that if not most of that depending on
distances and and elbows and stuff a
drip emitter is going to get right to
the crop you know right down into it if
it's a steak or a weight or what however
we're doing versus hand watering we're
actually going to get rid of all of that
that 30 PPM of dissolved oxygen out of a
dram Water breaker it softens the water
it feels great we're not Splat you know
we're not smashing our soil everywhere
but we're actually going to be taking 30
and knocking it down hard because of the
pressure change so another thing that
takes gases dissolved oxygen out of
water is a pressure change right so that
we're battling pressure changes also
high temperature pressure changes you
know two things that are going to take
dissolved oxygen out of the water so
it's a neat conversation and I mentioned
the screen air I think is the name of
it is actually meant to it's a it's a
very expensive Water breaker for larger
pots that are going to have you have
longer grow times and it just really
softens the water it's got uh inputs on
the top of the nozzle to allow air in as
that stream comes through so we're kind
of infusing more air than we ever would
in a normal Water breaker but the green
Air dram green air is a neat funny thing
for for generally much larger pots in
your outdoor grows uh that that's
definitely helping taking well water
generally in in a Big Field of hemp or
cannabis especially you know that's
going to be out they all season so can
talk about water breakers for for hours
now when we water with any type of water
regardless the do level we're we're also
pushing oxygen as a physical mechanism
of that water pushing oxygen down into
the soil as well
correct right so depending on what that
soil looks like if you are if you have
do in your water and you're and again
depending on if we can get dissolved
oxygen
to the surface or even subsurface lots
of sub irrigation out there obviously um
you know so again depending on how we're
applying the water um and uh So Many
Factors you know what is it clear water
that we're applying to a living soil is
it fertilized water uh with just salts
or if we added things to it um so again
we depending on how we've made the
dissolved oxygen and what form it's in
is it truly dissolved is it soluble in
the water and then how we're applying it
to the crop but if we're just handw
watering it onto the surface that's
probably an inefficient way honestly if
we've made a lot of dissolved oxygen i'
do what ever I could to sort of get it
smoothly we say laminarly laminer flow
through a
hose and then gently onto it it's going
to keep the oxygen in solution longer
than a Water breaker would
so be cognizant of what you're using a
Water breaker to do obviously it's a
wonderful watering tool and it's there
for a big reason U but we don't want to
shoot ourselves in the foot yeah so what
options do I have in a scenario like
like here at my house I've used using a
essentially a drip irrigation system uh
directly from my hose which is hooked up
to Municipal Water
Supply how can I address dissolve oxy
oxygen in a situation like this uh where
I don't have a reservoir or is are there
any affordable options for Growers like
myself in this
scenario great question
um it very difficult so Venturi
injectors and we don't I don't think we
make it anymore but it was a really neat
tool the thy inject there are others out
there uh it is a ventury injector that
is just pulling air if you're leaving
the tube out of usually it was used to
put a nutrient uh knock the PH down you
would put it in your bucket and it just
had a tube and it's just using the water
flow across it but we could use it to
introduce atmospheric air has 21% oxygen
right let's not forget um and so that's
it is urine the most common and
trickiest way if you don't have a
reservoir if you aren't uh if you aren't
refilling a
reservoir um and then utilizing that for
watering um I'm in a Prohibition state
so I'm going to state that in my
Perpetual tomato garden um I have a
reservoir and it refills and I add
oxygen to it and I use uh a sub
irrigation platform that I just it's
super easy and when I was travel a lot I
could rely on things to keep happening
when I needed to leave um but that's I I
had zero parts per million do and it
worried me just because I was going to
be pulling from my and especially in sub
irrigation where it's just sort of using
that water as it needs to the little
valve opens and I'm you know it's it's
cool it's an easy way with a living soil
to to grow you know uh my tomatoes
really efficiently um but I had it
hooked up like you did and I just felt
like I was adding probably some
inappropriate things even if I was using
a little one of those RV carbon filters
which I really enjoyed it was doing a
pretty good job uh good for a few
thousand gallons um so to answer your
question is maybe ventu injection but
that's could be tricky and I'm going to
think on that one because it's something
that we get asked a lot um it's just
really the media the porosity of your
media make sure that if you're using
soils over and over again that you are
making sure it's been well you know
Blended and do all those things that you
guys teach us about in terms of uh soil
Health but it's really making sure that
we have air spaces in there to allow
natural things to happen and that we do
not overwater
underwatering bad overwatering of cour
just as bad um and so we try to teach
especially new production cannabis
Growers um to be uh drier Growers right
don't don't just irrigate for the sake
of irrigation let's look at the moisture
level depending on your media let's make
sure that we are not it's generally an
over irrigation problem um and that bad
for a number of reasons in a hom grow
you're not worried about wasting a few
few dollars or nutrients or Organics but
the larger facility that becomes a big
issue but it's just you start chasing
your tail if you're over irrigating um
in terms of the media saturation and
paracity and available oxygen
I I find with folks switching
from a more traditional hydroponic or
chemical growing mineral salt
environment to Growing with living soils
they actually tend to underwater because
they're used to these pretty big dryb
backs um so I'm coming at from a
different perspective interestingly
enough um yes overwatering leads to root
hair death which will cause a lot of the
same issues as underwatering um and and
is potentially just as awful I will say
you're opening yourself up to more root
diseases like fusarium pythium uh things
like that and that's a big reason not to
overwater um and that's so we I was
actually just having a conversation I'm
not a huge fan of sub irrigating sub
irrigation but if you're a new grower I
think it's a excellent option or like in
your case where you're having to leave
for a while um it's a it's a wonderful
tool to keep from avoiding these you
know massive fluctuations in hydrology
that cause these problems so it it
allowed us nonprofessional Green Thumb
folks it allows you to get by really
well but it is not steerable in any sort
of way now we have massive production
and I've been involved with flood floors
since 19 forever ago flood benches flood
floors have been a large component of
you know large scale commercial
horiculture from ornamentals to
vegetables Etc of course so we do know
that it can be very very effective yeah
depending on the crop and all these
things but you've got to know what
you're doing and again it's just tougher
to steer crop like you said so there's
great yeah goods and bads depending on
what you're trying to accomplish 100%
agree all right well let's uh let's move
on from dissolved oxygen you you've
definitely got me thinking though and I
want I'm going to want look into now uh
adding a carbon filter we'll talk a
little bit more about filtration but
also a uh Venturi injector sort of into
my system before it gets to irrigation
and just see I'll have to see what I can
what I can do I used to have a deer I'll
have to track that down there's little
little levels and I worked for biotherm
if you if you know the biotherm guys I
was there for nine years working for
them they have the O2 tube and not to
plug at company but we use their their
their dos X Series which is diffus which
is Mass transfer gas infusion in this
case oxygen so they have small systems
you know for real small hobby sized
grows to really do a impressive job I
don't know how small they go though so
that's a product that came on board a
lot later after I left working for them
but again there's companies out there
that you can go and research and I think
it'd be fun to incorporate I would
carbon filter we'll talk about that
before you spend the money to infuse any
Oxygen into it but great so like I said
we're going to jump around I want to
cover a lot of questions that people
just have that are just really general
questions about water so let's start off
talking about the differences between
chlorine and chloramine for people that
are on Municipal
Water great question I am not the PHD on
this subject but have had to be the uh
what's that commercial I stated a
holiday in express last night if
familiar like all of a sudden you sort
of oh well but on that I'm an
expert um anyway the chlorine has been
traditionally used as an oxidizer an
effective oxidizer chlorine as we all
know has been used in pools um and in
municipal water treatment plants for for
eons um it does what it does and
generally becomes harmless if we are
doing it correctly which of course we
have learned to do in our City municipal
systems what we've learned not we the
the water treatment folks have needed to
get more residual they've needed this
disinfection power to last longer
chlorine again U has you know its
Half-Life is decent enough to do what it
needs to do and we probably aren't
getting I hope a lot of free chlorine
parts per million out of you know your
faucet if you're smelling chlorine i'
probably call you know the the city if
I'm on a municip system and you can
smell chlorine like a swimming pool or
something that's probably not the levels
you want coming into your home um or
certainly you'd need to consider trying
to get rid of it in your home before and
so it's really trying to keep pipes
clean um chloramines were added again
they become trickier from what I've
learned and uh we had a quick chat about
it before we started recording
chloramines have been added and they've
been really added uh we've seen since Co
and so when they started testing the um
effluence going back into water
treatment they can study how you know
the covid trends I guess they started
getting nervous and they started turning
up the dial on a higher residual
chloramine yep and we saw certain uh
Municipal plants and these are generally
from dram water working with cannabis
facilities new facilities some of them
uh smaller operations other msos that
had been burned in one state and really
with us taking a hard look at Municipal
we started asking the municipal folks
questions if they are seasonally
Municipal Water has changed way more
drastically than I've seen a well water
on average because they've had to you
know what uh during the summer the uh
grows in the corridor of Michigan are
pulling from the lake and the water
temperature increases and the M the bad
bacteria
because of the water temperature
increasing from the lake increases so
they have turned up the dial literally
variably turned up the dial and added
chloramines to try to get rid of a
higher bod biological or oxidative
demand the bad stuff they're trying to
kill for longer and that
chloramine that's what I feel is turning
into things we really don't want again
chlorine if done right we aren't too
worried about it we haven't been we've
been drinking that water for decades and
decades but chloramines to me is still
uh proof is not in the pudding um and I
want to make sure I'm getting rid of
them and asking more questions to my
Municipal treatment folks about their
use of chloramines so if that's the
takeaway it's learn if there's
chloramines being added to your
Municipal Water Supply and I'm not a
conspiracy theorist or anything I I
think we're doing everything we can very
appropriately it's just what if that
water's actually super clean and now the
chloramines don't have anything to to
get it to get rid of it right it isn't
it isn't doing its thing it's still in
the water supply and we've seen
chloramines come out into our irrigation
water um it's just something I want to
be sure to remove and again well you
might ask me about it but filtering it
out right off the get-go is generally a
very
inexpensive great insurance policy um
and everybody's pretty familiar with the
carbon filtration and so carbon media
has changed a little bit over the years
and we can get into that and it's become
much more efficient there's a question
like on the questionnaire are there
chloramines yes well then I'm I'm going
to make you spend a little more money on
a different kind of uh carbon medium
that's basically it it's more efficient
at absorbing those those
chloramines so I'm going to give you
my very limited knowledge on chlorine
and chloramine to try and simplify this
for folks and
please correct me where you can uh in
anything that I say we're learning from
each other learning from each other as
as it's been explained to me over the
years because I've been hearing about
chloramine for over a decade now because
they have it in I think Portland Oregon
which is not too far away from us I have
chlorine here and chlorine like you said
pretty
unstable uh chemical it reacts with
oxygen um and organic matter and the
constituent remains is is fairly safe
like you said um chloramine I thought
change to chlorine and I think ammonia
was what I was reading recently about it
um are sort of the constituent remains
of what happens when it comes it
complexes or comes in contact with
Organic Matter
biological uh microbial life something
like that um chlorine very stable
component you can't you can leave water
out with chlorine in it it will off gas
over time or you can bubble it to remove
chlorine chloramine that's not the case
you actually has to come in contact with
something biological or some sort of
organic matter whether that be an old
boots a handful of soil uh carbon
filtration is the simplest and easiest
one that's that's why you've got me
thinking about a carbon filter um in
general I don't tend to worry about
chlorine or chloramine relative to a lot
of other things it's pretty low on my
list uh primarily because I've always
been under the assumption that soil is
so biologically active it has such high
levels of organic matter I mean much
higher than even agricultural soils to
where what's what may potentially be
dying is being replaced so rapidly and
uh you know the level of chlorine is so
low that I I tend to be not too
concerned about I haven't noticed any
detrimental effects from watering with
chlorinated water but again what you're
bringing up I think is really
interesting I haven't thought about it
postco um I haven't had to deal with
chloramine
um I have heard you could use theoric
acid also as a good solution vitamin C
potentially and there's actually some
commercial sorbic acid products
specifically for removing chlorine I
can't remember I think it was called
vied Decor was a product we used back in
the day but
um yeah that's sort of that's sort of my
take on it um I I don't know how you
feel I assume too if I'm watering with
something like a Water breaker where
that water is in such small particulates
of finer droplet size as that water is
traveling through the air towards the
soil it's coming in contact with a ton
of oxygen um I I wonder how much
chlorine is really even making it in the
soil at that point
so yeah those are my
thought I I love it again we agree I'm
not overly worried about an
appropriately chlorinated municiple
water supply and
I'm asking more a lot more questions on
Chlor if they are adding
chloramine and it feels like there's
more flavors of chloramine then again
you and I will learn together and find
somebody that that knows what's what
because I've heard the same thing when
in com combination chloramines and
organic matter have created some really
nasty things it turns out so I keep sort
of we'll have to go down that rabbit
hole off offline yeah no I appreciate
that if you do find some answers please
reach out um okay talking about uh not
so great things in water a question I
another question I had for you was past
or pfas those forever chemicals that you
keep hearing
about I hear they're everywhere now um
what's your experience or knowledge
around dealing with
this more personal than than business in
terms of I haven't run up against
anybody that was concerned about pasas
in their Horticultural their irrigation
water or Supply but it has absolutely
been a topic where I am I'm sitting in
Raleigh North Carolina and we have these
forever chemical producing manufacturing
plants um within a couple hours drive of
me it has absolutely gotten into the
water supply it has been a problem for a
long time we keep learning more and more
about uh these nasty things that are
manufacturing you know um I forget
anti-flammable materials it's a lot of
chemistry right and they do not go
anywhere ever and they come into our
bodies and they stay there and they are
very carcinogenic um so it's been a real
mess I would be working with some
experts if somebody brought it as a
potential um contaminant in their water
supply I would really go somewhere quick
that isn't just us making our best
guesses in Googling I'd want to reach
out to people that really knew what they
were talking about my guess is it's
probably not terribly difficult to get
out of a water stream the problem with
these is that they have contaminated
aquifers and the soils Etc and when you
know it's just they're part of the
ecosystem that's that's tough like if
your well is
contaminated dig a deeper well get a
clean aquifer I I think is kind of what
the sad reality is um of me standing if
they're there It's just tough to
remediate them or get rid of them out of
the environment that you know once
they're in there they're just being
recycled again and again in part of our
water so so it would be something that I
would not mess around with in terms of
just assuming we could get rid of them
with our typical methods which we can
get rid of some really nasty things well
some pretty basic methods you mentioned
ation to get rid of a lot of chlorine um
you know uh there's all kinds of things
that we can do simply but the are a
different beast and that's why you are
appropriately uh hyper sensitive to them
yeah let's jump into filtration really
quick then so can you touch on sort of
what removes what
like obviously R is you know reverse
osmosis is sort of like the best the the
top-of-the-line option for removal no
you're saying no I'm learning okay it's
it's in my head it's don't call it the
best well has it has downsides for sure
right right right it's going to get rid
of a lot most
everything whether you want it to or not
yeah so it's we don't just throw r o at
a cannabis we will have man okay first
give me R why do you think you need Ro
right well just that's what you do in
cannabis we grow with rro could we have
a discussion about that so we've become
very aware that it's just it's not
something that should just automatically
be part of hey I'm going to spend some
real money on my facility or on my grow
R that's that's been the case and we've
seen it not just cannabis production but
in other sort of especially in indoor
growing let's just take whatever water
it is no matter how good or bad it is
and we're gonna R it well let's just
talk about that R is absolutely um a
really good tool at removing everything
and starting from zero why would we do
that in our industry if then we're going
to add ppms back into it well what if
all those ppms were most of them were
fine and you're stripping them all out
and now you're paying to add them back
in in the form of EC right and getting
our parts per million back up well why
would we do that right so that's we just
question we use Ro for salts high
chlorides high bicarbonates like these
things you can't filter out so to speak
you do have to use an RO membrane and Ro
to remove or reduce salts so that's our
stance is it is absolutely necessary
when it is necessary right and can we
blend back can we blend back this crop
and I'm growing um in soil beds in a
living soil I'm an organic grower I just
want to start with high quality water uh
great then you can talk us into using
more and more pure permeate right so Ro
makes permeate and then it makes the
reject water we can add we can blend
back in all of our systems have the
ability whether you think you're going
to need it or not to blend back in the
untreated maybe it's been carbon
filtered and then not
softened but so I'm blending my carbon
filtered water that hasn't gone through
the r back in with my RO permeate at 0
to 50% more that Ro machine starts
paying for itself a lot more if we don't
have to use Ro permeate so it's rare
that we're going to recommend Ro
permeate be used it could be very
aggressive water it can pull nutrients
out it's trying to make itself whole so
there's lots of bad things about a pure
AR permeate especially in young young
crops that are trying you know with
super small root systems and fine hairs
it can be really take it could slow
things down just like that cold water
scenario I mentioned so so so irrigation
with pure R permeate you really got to
know what you're doing
um again it's just trying to make your
whole so that's that's R is the extreme
right so yeah talk about
normal yeah so the original question I
was I wanted to ask you though was like
what so what does like for example a
simple carbon filter not
remove yep simple carbon filter cannot
remove salts okay right I don't care how
fancy I there's catalytic activated
carbon and now catalytic carbon two
Medias that are our go-to Medias um
catalytic is just a little more
efficient it's a little more expensive a
little more efficient removing
chloramines um it's just stickier
they're stickier sponges um essentially
but they cannot remove salts that's its
biggest thing it can remove a lot of
things it can absorb some levels of
heavy metals but if you have heavy
metals it's typically not the the only
filter we're going to look at if you
know man I've got high levels of boron
barium um nickel these things some of it
could be absorbed by accident on purpose
but then we really need to make sure we
look at levels um and there again
certain heavy metals we can't so Les can
you clarify when you say salts that
you're not just talking about sodium for
folks that are listening in case they're
not familiar with the sort of the
broader chemical salt term yeah salt can
mean uh a lot of things and when when in
the nursery and horiculture we ask are
you a synthetic grower you're growing
with salts right I mean salts are
chlorides potassiums um manganese these
are all types of salts and we can't take
those out with carbon filters if you
have way high levels of salts um or your
water is hard sodium bicarbonate right
um these are things we need to be aware
of and that's when we start looking at a
salt removal machine reverse osmosis
ultra fine filtration but really to
remove soluble salts which again right
not just sodium um but all a whole strip
of the of the Periodic Chart are
essentially we call them salts and
they're easily they become soluble in
water um and we can
physically get rid of them we have to do
special things uh to remove salts so
what what would something like an ozone
machine be used for if we're talking
about filtration not a filter yeah ozone
ozone is like uh it's an oxidizer
disinfectant right so chlorine dioxide
hydrogen
peroxide um oxidizers we are using to
disinfect the water um and so ozone not
necessarily a filter it does almost
always require some thought about
prefiltration and postfiltration if
we're using ozone as a disinfectant uh
ozone super efficient uh again if you go
to the webinar I get into it a little
bit but it's a really efficient way if
we needed it its use for
disinfecting and for precipitating out
Metals so it's really powerful and can
we can we can get rid of ir IRS we can
get rid of these other if we have high
levels of metals again at the Periodic
Chart we've got Metals metal halides can
we precipitate those out is we'd hate to
have to inject a ton of chlorine which
is a way we would do so with small
levels of
iron ozone is so powerful and is so
reactive we can we can harness its
powerful oxid oxidizing power to
precipitate out MET
so that's so you get like iron is that
what you're saying we're removing the
iron precipitating it out and then we
have to filter it out otherwise we're
going to have you know its its
precipitate clog up anyway but at least
the iron we get it out of solution so
you either use there's there's multiple
ways of removing high iron which is a
problem all around the country with
Wells um and we we've always seen that
some of us have the orange stain uh in
our wellwater that's iron typically
soluble iron and we're trying to Des
solubilize it and capture it we have to
filter that out though but ozone not
necessarily A filter but it can be part
of a filtration system if that makes
sense great are there any other major
ways of filtering water or I guess I I
guess we touched on disinfecting with
ozone but um besides carbon and
Ro I like to break it into my simple
brain into to there's sort of there's
mechanical
filtration if I have particulate if I
have things floating in the water that
is a very different kind of filter than
if I'm trying to remove some chemistry
right out of the water and by chemistry
we've talked about chlorine chloramines
salts right that's part of the water
chemistry and I'm trying to alter or
remove things that are too high of a
level so there's those kinds of fil that
can do that carbon filtration happens to
have those properties of being able to
change the sort of chemistry of the
water well if I just trying to remove
silt out of a well that's just got silty
water that clogs up my my micro
irrigation or just it just really
becomes a hindrance and it's um you know
I'm trying to remove physical
particulates that's a whole different
set of filters and boy are there a lot
of those screen filters media filters
you know sand filters are an old school
media filter so there's just all kinds
of things I just sort of sometimes
there's they're one and the same a well
can have high high it smells like rotten
eggs it's got high hydrogen sulfide I
need to remove that and it's got silt
great well I need a physical filter and
then I need a sort of a chemical filter
type system to change the water on two
different levels if that makes sense so
physical filtration in my mind and sort
of more of a chemical altering or remov
filtration
systems yeah so so jumping back to
straight R water um and you brought up a
great Point like people should
absolutely test their water uh don't
assume that you need R Ro is not ideal
uh I've always heard R referred to as
hungry water because it wants to bond
with various uh minerals and things and
so when you add it to your soil or when
it goes through a pump
system like you said it could pick up
things that we may not want to be adding
to our water and I think that's a good
story on heavy metals that we'll share
that you shared with me that let's get
to here in a minute but uh the the quick
question I had uh because you already
answered the question of why not do use
straight Ro but what's a good Target PPM
just broadly possibly that a folks
listening could aim for if they did need
to use r o that's a terrible question
Ted because where did you start because
if you started at an EC of 2.0 right and
and I'm an EC guy and you're you know
tell me where your PPM is you're trying
to hit what ppms are you trying to hit
give me in a vegetative state walk me
through the ppms your averages that you
like to see that your your crop enjoys
give me those ranges so they're fresh in
my mind and then I I have to go and I
would use a calculator right because you
guys start come to us ppms and we talk
about the makeup of an EC and then we
then we start parsing that out so if you
know I know that an EC of one to two is
a heavy feed and you go more than that
you know what I mean in terms of that
and that 500 PPM is that well so you're
okay so you're approaching this from the
perspective of I'm fertig gating and I'm
maintaining my mineral my My overall
plant fertility
through through chemical fertilizers and
and continually adding that level of
small levels of fertility throughout the
plant's life I'm coming at it and keep
in mind we get all types listening this
podcast but I'm thinking of it like the
majority of my fertility is already in
my soil because I'm an organic living
soil guy and so for me I'm I'm I'm I'm
looking at the water purely for
irrigation purposes yes and so my
my my question back at you
is is are any ppms needed I'd hate to
say that RO water isn't going to hurt
your crop that has all the PPM it needs
in the soil in your amendments in that
crop so I guess I'm throwing the
question back at you to teach
me what is the PPM makeup what is it
made of because if it's harmful or
adding salts and or you know something
that if we're trying to cut the water if
I'm coming in with too high PPM you're
asking the question where where is that
level I honestly don't I can't answer
that as an average because you could
have a
hotter mix because you like to do it
this way I think again you're teaching
me on the Organics and living soil side
of things and I'm saying it might be
very different for somebody who's just
really trying to um
I mean generally we're most all trying
to create the same kind of product right
um and do it within that same time frame
of this plant that is an annual in terms
of cannabis but I don't want to answer
it if somebody's growing um uh you know
not cannabis or not Tomatoes or not
something that's fruiting or if it's a
longer term crop or we have customers
that are growing Cactus and propagating
Cactus and I'd be like man we there air
plants that are tons of folks that are
you know production small medium and
large of airplants where we get closer
and closer to zero PPM required needed
it does it cannot handle high levels at
all if it's a if it's an air style verm
milads orchids right so it's hard for me
I'm trying to wear your hat but then the
Hat of 99 different other crops but yes
in your world I
think to to to start with the water and
look at the PPM of your Municipal let's
just say a municipal Source coming into
house and then you're gardening with
that Municipal Water I want to take a
look at it and go are those ppms okay
for you it looks like you guys have
pretty
even uh the PPM makeup because what
makes up PPM is a it's like a soup I
could have added the soup is got the PPM
but my soup's got I've got a chicken
stock base my wife's got the vegan thing
going on over here and our ppms are
exactly the same but they're completely
made up differently so I'd be afraid to
add mine onto a certain kind of soil mix
does that make sense I'm not smart
enough to know no it does start you're
I'm trying to simplify the question and
you're telling me it's too complicated
so you're saying like if if we get the
soil or the water sorry if we get the
water down to 50 PPM but that 50 PPM is
all sodium it may still be a problem if
that PPM is like calcium right then we
just need to account for that and it's
perfectly fine in our over our fertility
plan so absolutely thank you that is
what I'm trying to get to because we see
people take out good things and add it
back in we see people very appropriately
on purpose by accident take out the bad
things and then add their good things
back in we just need to start so that
PPM is a soup in my brain of could be
anything it's like man well it's free
calcium put a 100 like what's going to
not harm your crop obviously we don't
want to have anything become toxic level
and build up over our our life cycle our
crop um you know again or if we're
growing trees or nurseries wow we've got
to be really cognizant of a 50-year crop
if you can imagine we have customers
that they're growing Nursery stock
that's years um so so maybe a better
question or approach then would be to
say okay let's let's set targets for all
of these Bad actors whether that's
chlorides bicarbonates sodium and say
when we hit that threshold let's say we
don't want to see more than I'm going to
make up a number here 5 PPM of sodium
overall in that RO water or in our
remineralized water before before at
that point we don't have to take action
and we can feel comfortable using it as
as our irrigation water but if that 50
PPM of total
uh is as a total in my water is is
entirely comprised of sodium then that
may put us above our Target threshold
and we'd have problems still but why is
it so important that we remineralize
water in this scenario because I do know
of Growers that water was straight rro
in living soil systems like you said it
is more buffering we do we don't see as
many issues but I feel like it's
suboptimal for all the re it is too I I
do too and I don't want to be completely
anecdotal or feel that way but it does
it is a hungry water the chemistry is
the chemistry it is trying to make
itself whole um and it is very
aggressive meaning it's going to pull
and make it it it it grab and break
apart certain things that you might not
want broken apart in terms of bonds um I
don't think it's um you know pure
permeate would be an interesting
experiment to really take a look at it
in terms of uh beneficial I don't I I
don't think its properties would behoove
the the life cycle of an nematode right
I I can't imagine it it increasing their
life cycle I don't I feel like it would
be harmful I'm now just sort of coming
up with things that we use and we make
sure that we have an appropriate media
um you know and based on on the media
type or right if we keep depending on if
we're talking um from Hydroponics all
the way to where you what you do and the
organic side of things I think R
obviously becomes it becomes nearly
impossible to work within Hydroponics if
if we do a lot of lettuce Bath Systems
like acres and Acres of floating lettuce
Bath Systems 41 to 50 days crop Cycles
from seedlings to harvest at the other
end of a big long greenhouse on these
you know really neat production
facilities and that is a we have to
really be careful there's enough water
there we do have some buffer in the
water but it's purely hydroponic so
any change right we're on the razor's
Edge in pure pure Hydroponics and I
think you get away with a lot more very
positively in living soil and organic
because you have such a proliferation of
all the beneficials increasing the the
uh the health of the crop and really
just becoming very powerful and watching
out for the root system when you when
you have the living soil so it's a lot
to talk about so much going on that
that's actually a really good transition
because you mentioned how we have much
better buffering capacity in living
soils than with these other forms of of
growing
um
yet I I still believe that the pH of my
water can matter it doesn't always
matter you know but it can matter
specifically around this idea of
alkalinity and hardness so
if which which relates to and again
correct me I relates to the ability of
the of of the water to change that pH so
the the buffering capacity of that water
um or ability your ability to change the
pH of that water and so if your water
has a very high EC if it has
um a lot of alkalinity it could impact
the pH of your media and yes these
microbes and the rizosphere interactions
there absolutely play a role in in
buffering that and and
transitioning it into a form into a PH
range that's going to be more optimal
for the plant but my perspective has
always been if we water with water
that's been properly phed um and you
know assuming that the alkalinity is
high and we need to adjust the pH if
it's low you know rainwater something
like that even if it's eight8 you know
82 I'm not that worried about it because
that pH can swing same with ro low PPM
RO water I don't worry about pH
but if we can make water that is high in
alkalinity into a better PH range I I
would assume that that would allow the
plant to put its energy and those
microbes in its energy into a more
efficient plant processes that would
increase its health and growth what are
your thoughts around that yes yes it is
it is it is easier to talk about in a
soilless environment because water
chemistry is everything right the water
that's it and and like you just said if
we are if we have zero buffer zero
alkalinity things change immediately
right and titration is how we test it
and I can barely remember but you you
keep dropping drops into this water and
nothing's changing nothing's changing
nothing's changing and then one the next
droplet everything shifted right you got
to the top and then it just plummeted
right so it's just an interesting uh
experiment in how
quickly a
non buffered water environment can
change and that's we call it the razor's
Edge right if you're trying to steer a
crop uh if you're trying to
utilize zero alkalinity water pure arop
perate right it's got you've removed
you've stripped everything and now you
it's it's it changes really quickly uh
depending it's can be very frustrating
the buffer your envir you you provided
in the media in the soil in the organic
soil is absolutely going to be less
dependent a lot less dependent uh on
hitting that pH just right right the if
we're completely salt-based grower
synthetics nonorganic you know
production facility that pH 5.8 to 6.0
and I mean we want 5.85 we want five
what do you want what does this crop
like the hydrangea in that PE media
versus I mean it's just you know exactly
we've dialed that in we are hitting that
in your I it's just a way happier easier
window of pH to be applied to I can't
imagine it's really rare a water source
well and certainly Municipal that come
that would come out with a pH that you'd
have to be concerned about if you knew
what you were doing on the organic soils
growing um right I I think you're 100%
correct now we have to watch what again
what are the ppms made out of what is
that alkalinity is it high is are we
accumulating too many salts because of
that Municipal Water or that well water
did have a high iron we have seen iron
levels really detrimental and we have to
do something about it the rest of the
water absolutely perfect but 15 parts
per million iron I mean
this is crazy it really affects
different things that you know I again
you're having to there's a lot of things
that if you're getting your your media
made for you based on your water
chemistry that's a thing right for
larger production facilities their media
is being made for them based on my
wellwater source which is that's a neat
we're matching oh my well water's got
this so make me a blend that complement
that yeah but an organ right but in an
organic I
mean a wonderfully living soil organic
water only
media I I think we get away with a lot
more meaning it's a lot easier to do
with various water chemistries so I
think that's super appropriate and a
really really wonderful way to to grow
basically yeah and all that being said
though I would I would still uh I would
still state that I I believe pH of the
water does matter and it's something
that we should be paying attention to on
the water test but what you brought up
was a good point is what's creating that
pH is really the key to a lot of that a
lot of what we're looking at exactly
yeah you you have to know what's in your
pH if you're injecting anything even
Organics um if you're putting an
additive uh for that last couple of
weeks uh a flour you know if you're
putting something extra in it that pH if
it's if it's acidic or if it's um non-
acidic if it's neutral how does it
affect whatever you're adding because pH
will make things more or less available
and could alter their form and you asked
about acids and types of acid right
citric acid for organic growing that's
my next question for you yeah I I
thought it was a simple question asking
you what are the your favorite or best
uh pH adjusters and you looked at me and
like that was a huge question so let's
talk about if I if I gave you an answer
then thousand colleagues would be like
what you I mean everybody has their own
preference organic Growers are sort of
stuck with the citric acid I think is
one of the only is there anything else
out there you know it's a super weak
acid that sort of dissipates quickly
it's tough um to utilize on large
production facilities we found this out
firsthand from our large cannabis
Growers that we're using citric acid I
mean so it's a wonderful discussion um
if we are in pure big scale commercial
uh horiculture
it's bu it as most cost efficient to get
to your doorstep as you possibly can and
that is typically unfortunately as high
a percentage of phosphoric or sulfuric
acid as you is legal to purchase you
know 400 Gall 270 gallon totes or is a
400 gallon totes of as high percentage
costic danger you know like it's it's
it's a shame right but so depending on
what you're trying to do it can be a
very expensive input for facilities if
they were trying to use a weak acid to
take 8.0 to 5.8 at 1,000 gallons a
minute is you've got to start with the
most concentrated acid so those are the
two complete extremes are are the citric
acid uh and and its strength and
compared to a you know High sulfuric or
phosphoric
Etc and one other factor for folks to
consider is that all of these can
potentially bring in heavy metals as
well so you need to make sure you have a
clean Source um and citric is just gets
very expensive on scale um and it's not
going to hold your pH for very long in
in a
reservoir correct it is it is pH just
waiting to happen you've got to use that
water quickly you can't make up too much
of a batch you've got to make it use it
uh make it use it make it use it and and
and and still test it when it's coming
out of your dripper or your hose uh just
to make sure because we're going if if
you've crept in the in that wrong
direction and we're applying 8.0 pH
water to like you were saying it does
matter and it's certainly going to
affect things over the life cycle of a
crop and the younger the crop I like to
think the more susceptible to root
systems before it's matched right before
we've matched the root Zone Mass with
the production we're trying to do it's
critical it's more critical the younger
the crop is when we first got our small
little transplants or um we've really
got to pay attention to it because it
just that plant hasn't reached its its
full efficiency yet down
there well let's talk about heavy metals
um we we talked a little bit off aab
about this I am going to share with you
my experience and story and then I was
hoping you could kind of expand on that
so I have a I have a good friend who's
growing Medical in a in a state where
they also have wreck he decided to test
his product to see if it would would
pass his flower and he found it came
back uh high in Arsenic so it would have
actually potentially failed for arsenic
and he's growing in living soils he's
reusing his media he's in beds
um a and so he was sharing this data
with me and he was looking at it and he
was using things like soft rock phosphat
kelp meal um but being very conscious of
that and being that he's an engineer he
was looking at how much you know what
ppms of arsenic specifically was that
adding to his overall load his soil and
what he basically the long story short
was he found that relative to his water
source which I think um first of all he
had get it tested to a lower detection
limit because his original test wasn't
low enough um and this is municipal
water that is perfectly safe to drink by
EPA standards you know you're drinking
whatever that is a gallon or two a day
totally safe levels of arsenic but he
was putting 40,000 gallons of that water
through his grow room in a given cycle
and uh that2 PPM of arsenic let's say
you know very safe levels was building
up in the soil over time and actually
contributing potentially way
more
um sorry someone was logging into my
zoom account I'll cut this part out
uh that that level of uh the level of
heavy metals in that water that level of
arsenic was actually contributing way
more to the overall uh amount of arsenic
being added to his soil then the soft
rock phosphate or the kelp meal uh
became rather insignificant from an
arsenic load and he tested this by
testing his flower every cycle and he
set up an AR filter and he found that
the next cycle his arsenic levels had
dropped in his final flower so he was
assuming this was working and then his
next test the levels went up and he was
totally stumped
he came back to me he's like oh my whole
theory is not working I I cannot figure
this out well two months later he
reaches out and tells me that he found
out his plumber had put the filter in
backwards and then when he fixed the
filter he just flushed everything that
was on the filters through into the beds
um so essentially all that arsenic went
right into the beds anyway it sounds
like and he was right back where he was
um fast forward another year so if few
more cycles and he's seeing levels
significantly lowering every cycle in
terms of the amount of arsenic in his
flowers so it does seem to be working
it's this idea of of can we reduce the
amount of overall heavy metals coming in
to a to a rate that's lower than what's
going out in the plant this you know
hyper accumulator in the case of
cannabis um and I guess my big takeaway
is that water is actually probably our
one of our biggest contributors of heavy
metals and we have to look at it at a
very low detection limit
potentially much lower than what would
be much lower for agricultural use than
what would be safe for uh drinking use
as humans what are your thoughts on all
of
that all of that is a perfect story and
all of that represents what we have run
across multiple times over the last few
years and and cannabis Growers have
really taught us because of its hyper
accumulation um and testing the flower
is the end all Beall it's been
fascinating for us to watch how the
smallest parts per million comp like you
said I mean it's just it's exactly this
story over and again over and over again
it's all a question of where did it come
from and how do I control it so your
your friend's story is perfect and it
was coming in on the water source and he
just accumulated too many ounces or
pounds
over the crop cycle especially in that
soil bed that you reuse incredibly
important to make sure we are watching
what our soup is made out of right even
if it's completely safe to eat the soup
if I keep pouring soup you know it's
going to just those and and then the
water just imagine the water evapor
transpiration right it we're going to
accumulate what all of those things that
were in the soup but the soup was fine
to drink but gallon after gallon of soup
and we're going to just left with this
pile of who knows what what is it made
out of so that's that water test is
you've got to make sure I mentioned in a
followup to your story of some of the
highest level best Growers um that were
and again I'm not don't mean to poo poo
R permeate and to grow with pure
permeate again just really got to know
what you're doing but it is this hungry
aggressive water failed his first flower
test in a State and it was I believe
barium what barium heavy metal right H
how on Earth zero barium in the original
water source it had been stripping off
the arop permeate had been stripping off
a I think it was a chromal coating of
old pump impellers so the the pumping
mechanisms uh and this R permeate had
pulled this stuff heavy metals out of
the pump and it had accumulated so well
in this super efficient hyper
accumulating cannabis plant that he
failed we figured that out the Hardway
but it all worked out bought new pumps
with appropriate you know everything uh
and no problem and so it's just where
did it come from so I love that story
and the others that are just yes your
water source water is super important
but is the system to you know after that
let's take a look at the whole system
too and see what other potential um
contaminants could be introduced and why
it's pretty
fascinating yeah love it very cool well
I really appreciate your time today uh I
learned a ton of things and I hope we
can stay in touch as you continue to
learn more about chloramine and P and
heavy metals I know this is a constantly
evolving uh industry we're still
learning so much about water that's
really amazing to me we haven't figured
it all out yet so isn't amazing like
said it's just one thing to be
comfortable in drinking water but when
we start growing plants all of the
different things we've discovered about
water and how much we still don't know
about its effects you know on on what we
do as as Horticultural you know as as
growers in our our spaces so just been a
lot of fun thanks for reaching out
[Music]
that was Les Evans and you are listening
to the Cannabis cultivation and science
podcast if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on Instagram and YouTube and
don't forget at kiss Organics we have a
wider range of products we offer on our
website ranging from soils amendments
beneficial insects soil test analysis
and Consulting thanks for listening