[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
IND to share their wisdom and knowledge
now before starting the podcast I want
to remind folks that we do have a
patreon for Growers who want to access
to the unedited podcast weeks earlier as
well as extra content on our own grows
virtual Hangouts a private Discord
Channel and more that we don't share
publicly you can check it out for a free
trial if interested to see if it can
help you with your cultivation goals now
my guest this week is Dr James altland
Dr altland is a research
horticulturalist and the research leader
for the US
ARS application technology Research Unit
also known as the atru although the role
of the atru has historically been to
develop new pesticide application
Technologies it has shifted its focus in
The Last 5 Years to developing CA
Technologies while leading a team of 10
scientists in various aspects of CA from
entomology Plant Pathology engineering
and horiculture Dr alin's expertise
encompasses the development of substrate
Technologies for containerized plant
production with collaborations at Ohio
State University this has recently
evolved into the microbial Community
analysis of container substrates now on
to the show hi James thank you so much
for coming on the show today I really
appreciate it yeah thank you for
inviting me Tad I'm I'm glad to be here
so I caught uh most of your presentation
that you did for the American Society of
Horticultural science talking about the
long-term sustainability of Pete in
Horticulture and this is I think such an
important topic but can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and why you
were selected to be the speaker on this
uh particular topic yeah sure so I'm a
horiculture scientist for the US
Department of Agriculture what we call
the agricultural research service so
I've been working with soilless
substrates for about 20 years and a lot
of my research has been with uh Douglas
furar when I worked out at Oregon State
University pine bark here on the East
Coast um and I've heard all the
Rumblings about the use of Pete and the
sustainability of Pete and its impacts
on climate change Etc and um you know
Pete's an excellent substrate but you
know I I I didn't really pay much
attention to that it wasn't really what
I was focused on and then I attended a
conference up in Quebec um last summer
um on Pete land restoration and what I
saw and what I experienced at that
conference and now going out and
visiting some of the peeps did not mesh
well with what I'm hearing in the media
so what I wanted to do was to and and a
lot of what I hear in the media is is a
lot of um you know a lot of diet tribe a
lot of uh you know uh just um what's the
word I'm looking
for see this is why editing is good
um I hear a lot of comments that aren't
substantiated by facts so what I want to
do was add some context some factual
basis for this conversation and let
Growers and others make their own
informed decision about you know the
sustainability of Pete versus all the
other Alternatives that we might have um
in L of
Pete yeah and I absolutely want to talk
about some of the the Alternatives that
you mentioned like the wood fibers the
Pine Bar Coco core obviously is a big
one um but when we talk about substrates
you also have to include things like
perlite and rock wool which we know are
are not very sustainable um but yeah so
for me as someone who grew up in the
nursery industry and has been in the
horiculture industry uh pretty much my
entire life um I've I've heard very
mixed things about Pete you talk to one
person and you hear that Pete is
destroying the world huge carbon
Footprints and it's quite damaging uh
and then you talk to other people you
know you know you talk to you read
what's on the premier promix website for
example and it'll say that Pete is quite
sustainable and it seems like there's
science on both sides and it's very
confusing for an average grower to
figure out what
if that if they want to be sustainable
and be um you know environmentally
conscious what our options are and in
your presentation right out at the
beginning you you share some headlines
from The New York Times saying why
gardeners should stop using Pete and
what they should use instead uh you have
one from Better Homes and Gardens
talking about how Pizza sore point in
the industry due to its lack of
sustainability and then National
Geographic uh one that we talked about
before the show uh the headline to their
article is potting soil has a dirty
secret so there definitely is a media
push uh towards moving away from Peter
that Pete is is really harming our
environment um what what would you say
to all that well I don't have a dog in
this fight I don't get any money from
the Pete industry they don't pay me
anything I can't as a as a as an
employee for the federal government I
can't accept money from um outside
interests like that so what I would like
to I what I am trying to do with some of
these presentations that I've done is
just share the facts and um I think when
you look objectively at the facts that
you come to the conclusion um that um
yes there is a price tag environmentally
for using peep but oftentimes the price
tag for using these Alternatives that
are touted are much higher and another
thing I like to do is to put into
context what how much what is the carbon
footprint of growing Media or Pete
specifically
relative to some other human activities
um and when you look at it from that
perspective you know and one thing I
tell people we're not using Pete or
other substrates to power private jets
and luxury yachs we're using this to
grow food we're using it to grow uh
Forest seedlings for reforestation and
we're using it to grow um plants for the
urban landscape which have um well
documented benefits on human wellness
and mental health and all sorts of
things so you can say well we don't need
patunas but you know the truth is even
ornamental plants have value to our
society and to human health so we're
using uh these soiless media for very
good reasons how can we do it in the
most sustainable way possible well we
can't do that we can't make those
decisions without facts so that's what
I'm trying to share with people is just
what does the data tell us in terms of
the sustainability of these various
growing media
well I want to get into the the data um
but I really think there's two things
that we need to look at when we're
talking about substrates and the first
is uh first and foremost is
performance and so before we get into
like the sustainability of these
substrates in terms of performance where
does Pete rank on this on the scale of
Horticultural substrates Pete's the gold
standard and you know you can read I
could I could fill this room with
scientific studies com you know looking
for alternatives to Pete and there's a
reason why we don't have a good one yet
is because Pete generally outperforms
other substrates um the way that it is
processed um it is it's very uniform
it's very predictable um we've been
growing with this for over 60 years now
we' just gotten very good at engineering
the substrate um developing fertilizer
programs and irrigation programs so that
we can optimize the grow grow and
development of our crops now when you
change that to a different material um
often times it requires more fertilizer
more water more time um and and those
all cost uh carbon energy time dollars
everything labor so um in terms of just
ranking the substrates Pete really is
the gold
standard yeah I just want to get that
out there for folks because I I think
that's really important I know um as
myself and my company search for other
alternative for Pete we keep we keep
falling short because ultimately we want
to create the best product you know for
growing plants and at the end of the day
Pete really is that standard and one
other thing and this is probably a
little bit outside of your um your world
but in our in my industry by starting
with Pete Moss which is so acidic it
allows me to add more cats more
fertilizer essentially into that media
so that I can create a more fertile mix
than I could with cocoa core for example
because cocoe course starting with a
neutral pH um starts pushing us into
outside of range optimal pH ranges for
nutrient uptake so um with with Pete
Moss I can add biochar that's alkaline I
can add compost that's alkaline I can
add um a variety of different
fertilizers to reach a pH rain that's
still quite acceptable for nutrient
uptake um so I just wanted to mention
that for the folks that are listening
because I know that a lot of people that
grow grow similarly to the way we do in
terms of creating a very fertile soil
mix um in this industry so I just want
to throw that out there yeah you know
you're absolutely right we're very good
at raising the pH of substrates you know
a small degree like Pete and pine bark
Falls in that same category generally
has a low PH we're very good at
elevating the pH to the right level when
you have to lower the ph because your
substrate starts out already too neutral
or basic that becomes very difficult we
can do it but then we run into a lot of
other problems so it's not nearly as
neat and clean as when you talk start
with a low PH substrate like PE you're
exactly right great well let's let's
dive into the data then so um just from
looking over your your presentation here
um where where would you want to start
do you want to talk about the the Peete
boogs themselves or did you want to get
into some of the data around
um carbon sequestration and and that
sort of thing well I think I think it's
good to start with Peete bogs and what
is a Pete bog or a Pete land and why are
they so important and how does that
factor in to you know the uh global
climate change because that's really
what's driving this it's not that oh I I
want to substrate that works better than
Pete um you know there's a lot of
information out there a lot of
disinformation about you know how using
Pete affects climate change so that
might be a good place to start that if
if if you want to do
that yeah that that would be great I
didn't really know what a Peete Boog was
um and I think we should differentiate
between the United States and or I guess
North America would probably be better
and and Europe and Asia um what what
what is a peat Boog and what is the
condition of the Pete bogs across uh I
guess globally would be the question
yeah so Pete lands or Pete bogs are are
really it's a type of wetland um so if
you think about Wetlands but Pete lands
are special in that as plants die and
start to Decay that the the organic
matter accumulates faster than it breaks
down so you get a buildup of this
organic layer beneath um the the Wetland
or the Pete land and that it's it's a
it's a layer of Pete then um so that's
what characterizes a Pete land um now
one of the important characteristics of
a Pete land is that water will saturate
it up to about near the surface at the
surface or near the surface um as you
can imagine that type of land would not
be conducive to building roads or houses
or Farms or anything else so the first
thing you have to do when you use that
land is you have to drain it so you
drain the water off of it and then that
Pete land becomes degraded now in the
history of you know Humanity um you can
look at the history of Europe they've
been using the Pete lands for farmland
and other reasons for a lot longer than
we have been in North America and what
that has resulted in is um over half of
the Pete lands in Europe are now
degraded um and a degraded Pete land
will tend to give off CO2 instead of
sequestering CO2 from the atmosphere the
The Situation's a lot different in North
America where we've just had fewer
people and most of these Pete lands in
North America are in Canada at you know
very high um latitude
so where there's not a lot of people
living to begin with so the Pete lands
in North America are in just in much
better health um and so that's one of
the things that we discuss um but yeah
so a healthy functioning Pete land will
have water ader neared surface and it's
constantly sequestering CO2 from the
atmosphere that's what makes them so
valuable globally they're removing CO2
from the atmosphere instead of giving
CO2 off
so when I try to visually picture uh
Pete land um because Pete is primarily
just a bunch of organic matter that's
broken down and become this sort of
stable substrate that we know as Pete
Moss uh I would assume these lands are
quite rich with plant matter in order
for there to be plant matter to be
broken down to create the Pete is that
accurate like are there grasses and
shrubs and things like that on the land
or are they fairly barren
looking well the when you talk about
Pete lands there are two major types and
one is called a f you've probably heard
that word probably before just casually
but aen is kind of an early development
Pete land and they're dominated by
sedges and grasses um over time and as
as the characteristics of that Pete land
change and basically they start to swell
up above the water table they become a
bog and a bog is typically dominated by
stagnum mosses so you'll see shrubs and
some other plants and even maybe some
trees growing in a Pete land or a Pete
bog but they're dominated by the sagna
Mosses which is where you know as those
mosses grow and then Decay beneath um
that's where we get this coveted sagum
Pete Moss from Canada so yeah that's
true um if I guess if you think uh and I
have some pictures on here that you can
show Maybe um you know in in the in the
podcast but uh I I always Envision them
as being kind of like those images you
see of the tundra but there is a little
more variety of plant life when you
visit them in person especially the ones
that I visited in Ontario again more
shrubs more trees than you might expect
but they are dominating stagnum
mosses okay that makes that makes a lot
of sense to me um and that's great you
got to visit them so uh what were your
initial thoughts when you actually
visited and saw them in person
what what were the differences between
what you had pictured in your head and
what you were actually
seeing well um I I guess one one of the
things that struck me we we visited a
what they would call Pristine bog never
been touch or never been altered in any
way and we visited a rehabilitated or
restored Pete bong post extraction so
they they extracted Pete from this for
10 20 30 years I'm not sure how long and
then they restored it you couldn't tell
the difference my eyes couldn't tell the
difference and maybe a biologist would
come in and they you know see they're
looking for certain plant species or
something but you know to me visually
they looked very similar so I I was
really struck by that um the uh you know
it's really strange when you walk on
these peep bogs you know just
how I guess not a scientific term but
how squishy they are I mean you really
sink down in them so so uh they're
beautiful um they they're
uh it it's you can you know put your
hand down in there and pull up a big
clump of Pete it it's really um it's
fascinating to see everyone should do
that if they get the
opportunity uh but you know hearing
about the restoration efforts and the
success that they had in that that that
just didn't it's more of a conservation
practice is what I observe than what you
know some of the media would have you
think they're strip mining Canada and
it's just not the case the area that
they're harvesting P from is is
incredibly small and then they're
restoring it afterwards anyhow so it's
just a different narrative than what you
see in the
media yeah let's throw some numbers at
people here and I'm I'm looking at your
your slides here and so on the when you
talk about pristine Pete bogs you
mentioned that spag mosses grow slowly
about 20 to 120 millimeters per year and
Pete accumulates at about half to one
millimeter per year just to give people
some numbers there
um what what amount of Pete is actually
being uh harvested in North America
right now Rel relative to the the vast
size of these geographically of these of
Pete
lands so um and let me let me pull up
those numbers so I don't say something
inaccurate here um and and while you're
looking that up I'll add one more fact
here uh from from your slide is that pet
lands cover about 3% of the earth's land
area which I thought was really
interesting I wasn't aware of that and
it's a massive source of carbon
sequestration which is why this is such
an important topic uh for people that
are concerned about the environment so
well let me talk let me get back to that
point because that's really interesting
too because that gets to the heart of
the problem but to put this into
perspective every year during a good
year uh they will harvest of around 12
million Cub meters of Pete to sell for
horiculture out of Canada now you can
estimate this several different ways but
what I've estimated that the Pete LS in
Canada are accumulating about 600
million cubic meters of Pete every year
so they're harvesting 12
and another 600 million cubic meters are
being generated that's because almost
all of the Pete land well over 80% of
the Pete lands in Canada are still in a
pristine condition they're untouched
unfazed by human activities so although
they grow at a very small rate there's
such a massive land area that is growing
Pete um that it's it's it's accumulating
50 to 100 times faster than it's being
harvested uh for Horticultural purposes
in Canada so it it's it's growing at a
very rapid rate well I say let me take
that back it's not growing at a rapid
rate it's growing much more more than it
is being harvested the scale of it is so
massive that we're accumulating it
faster so that's that's really
fascinating to me because that is
something that you hear uh the opposite
a lot is that we're we're harvesting
Pete way faster then uh it's
accumulating and so we're
demolishing you know these beautiful
Canadian bogs
um so that I think that's an important
point that I just want to highlight that
you that you say there yeah and you know
like I said the the image they paint is
that we're strip mining Canada and
that's just not the case the area that's
being harvested is really small um and
now over the let's say they remove a a a
layer of about one meter okay over the
life of that bog it may take 10 or 15
years to do that but let's say they
remove a layer of one meter deep now
because it only brows about a half a
millimeter to a millimeter a year if you
wanted to replace that meter it would
take like a thousand years so that's the
argument often thrown out we're
harvesting Peete from these bogs and
it's going to take centuries for it to
be replaced but the truth is once
they're done harvesting they will what
amounts to receding it with stagnum it's
a it's a fairly involved process and to
to to restore those pee bogs but once
they're done those pee buls become
carbon accumulating carbon sequestering
fully functioning bogs again so they
start accumulating carbon in Pete almost
immediately within several years um it
can take three to maybe 10 or 15 years
depending on the you know rainfall and
things like that um
but well short of that 10,000-year
window that people like to convince you
that it it's going to take to rest they
become functioning pee bogs again
relatively
quickly okay that makes so essentially
what you're saying is this idea that um
once a bog has been harvested yes it
will take hundreds if not thousands of
years for that bog to get back to the
level of of Pete Moss that it had
however it that during that time it's
still going to be sequestering carbon
and because it's such a small overall
percentage of Pete lands that we own
that we have um we're still growing more
Pete than we're harvesting yeah
considerably more
massively more Pete in Canada is is
accumulating way faster than horiculture
is using it by by by again one to two
orders of magnitude faster okay and
let's let's touch on that so the the P
Moss spagna Pete Moss coming out of
Canada is primarily used uh 90% of it
according to your slide goes to the
United States and it's all used for
horiculture um however this is not the
case in Europe so Europe is a very
different situation uh than uh North
America when it comes to the uses for
Pete can you touch on that a little bit
yeah now one thing Europe does have in
common all of the Pete harvested in
Europe 96% of it stays in Europe so
that's one of the first things that Drew
me to this discussion um Europe has a
much longer history than we have here in
North America um and I can touch on that
a little bit too in terms of population
but uh you know the Pete lands in Europe
are in very bad condition the Pete lands
in North America are in relatively very
good condition so what we do in North
America for Growers I mean we're using
you know the Pete from Canada it should
be based on the conditions here in North
America let Europe handle their problems
the the Pete we use in North America
comes from North America the Pete used
in uh Europe comes from Europe but now
getting back to Europe um right now 62%
of the Peete that they harvest there is
used for energy that's something that
has never been done in North America
they have never used Canadian Pete to
generate fuel or to you know heat homes
but most of it is used for that purpose
in Europe um 38% of the pee they call it
and this paper you know it's been cited
there um 38% is what they call
non-energy uses but that's all
horiculture when you read between the
lines all of that P so it's either
energy or horiculture in Europe um but
that's not the case in North America
we're we're we're harvesting it just for
uh horiculture in in this
continent and I would assume combustion
of Pete has further carbon consequences
um would be my assumption when we look
at the carbon footprint of Pete used
from horiculture we assume that all of
it is mineralized or decomposed at some
point so and and and that's that's one
important point when I give you the
numbers for the carbon footprint of Pete
that's assuming all of it's converted
into all that is harvested is converted
into CO2 so you would get the same
result by burning it
um you know so but even that said when
you look at the numbers for the carbon
footprint and Pete is relatively small
compared to other human activities and
even other
substrates that's interesting because
when I think of Pete use in horiculture
I assume that there's an ological cost
to the harvesting which there is but
then once I as a consumer receive that
plant or soil uh that plant that's
planted in in the Pete Moss that I'm
planting into my yard I see I look at it
more as a redistribution
of of Pete Moss into you know my local
native soil or some other I mean I
realize there are people that are using
this media and then it's ending up in in
landfills and things which is
unfortunate but
um that to me has I guess a different
ecological or environmental impact than
combustion I agree no you're you're
right that's 100% correct however when
they calculate the carbon footprint you
you may not see this but that Pete
within a 100 years is going to decompose
probably completely in your yard if you
plant you know Alia in your garden the
Pete Moss is going to be gone within 100
years so they're assuming all that has
been converted to CO2 so when you look
at the carbon foot for peep that's a
worst case scenario and okay it's
probably as you said much better because
you're using it to grow plants maybe
using to grow four seedlings that turn
into 80 foot tall you know spruce trees
in on on the side of Mount Hood um who
knows but uh the the the the carbon
footprint the way they calculate it is a
worst case scenario and most of it comes
from the actual carbon stored in the
peak okay so what what were your finding
in regards to the the studies and
research on Pete and other substrates
and their carbon uh impacts well one
thing I'd like to bring up first before
we get into that is just the the the
global climate situation um now what
really why this is such a concern to so
many people is that if you look on
planet Earth and this in and and in that
slide that I showed you this is on slide
12 um right now there there are about
885 gigatons of CO2 stored in the
atmosphere and a gigaton is just simply
a billion metric tons so
885 billion metric tons of CO2 or CO2
equivalence in the atmosphere
um soils around the globe contain about
1,700 gigatons of that 550 to 600 gatons
are stored in Pete now the problem is
and the concern is what if we continue
to degrade pet Lance if we continue to
lose that carbon into the atmosphere
what if even half or or a quarter of
that 550 to 600 gigatons is released
into the atmosphere to join the 885
gigatons already there well that would
be an ecological disaster so that is why
there's such a push to maintain the CO2
sequestering functions of heat lands
around the globe and that's the concern
now if you go to the next slide this
shows um
how the change in CO2 levels caused by
human activities um around the globe and
basically our biome Forest grasslands
Etc can absorb about 6.6 gigatons every
year the oceans absorb about 2.8
gigatons so planet Earth under natural
processes is absorbing around 9 or 10
gigatons of CO2 from the atmosphere
every year the problem is humans are
giving off about 60 gigatons now 20
gigatons comes from energy production
burning coal burning fossil fuels
whatever um 14 gigatons comes from
industry there's this term called afolu
or AOL I don't know how you would you
know sound that out but it stands for
agriculture forestry and other land uses
that's given off 13 gigatons so that's
basically farming right um now in that
number there's the Canadian Pete
industry that is responsible for
generating
0.009 gigatons so when you look at the
global
scorecard it's a very small fraction
coming from peep but the concern is you
know maintaining the quality of heat
lands around the globe but can we use
heat from Canada for Horticultural
purposes and you know based on this data
the carbon footprint on an annual basis
of using Horticultural Pete is so small
it it it's not zero but it is very small
relative to other human
activities yeah I'm looking at your
slide you're saying like 8.7 gigatons of
carbon or CO2 is released through
Transportation yeah and then yeah but
yet Canadian ped is
0.009 gigaton so it's substantially l i
mean this is a pretty terrifying slide
when you think about it in terms of the
amount of sequestration we're having
relative to the amount of
release
um but in in terms of Canadian Pete it's
you're you're saying it's it's it's
rather negligible or small negligible
relative the other activities and you
know we should always strive for zero um
but again you know we're growing plants
we're using this Pete we're not burning
it for fuel we're not you know powering
luxury Yachts we're growing food we're
growing uh you know for seedlings and
we're growing plants so it's
[Music]
um so it has further sequestration
properties as it adds to our overall
quote unquote biome as it's used in this
in this image um that's absolutely right
and one of the things I talk about at
the end of my talk is that the only tool
we have right now the only reasonable
tool we have for
reversing CO2 levels in the atmosphere
is reforestation of land that is
currently not forested in the United
States and around the globe and the only
reasonable way to do that is to
drastically ramp up our reforestation
nurseries our for seedling nurseries and
now Studies by the four seedling
industry has said the best way to do
that is use container gr for
seedlings that use Pete so an irony of
ironies Pete is the one material that
may help us get out of this
mess that is
interesting so uh before we move on can
you just touch on Europe again because
you mentioned that um you know a lot of
it's used for energy that it has they
have all these issues is there I mean in
your opinion is there a solution for
folks in Europe in terms of uh other
options or is the conversation around
Pete quite different like if you lived
in London would you use Pete Moss versus
if you lived in North
America well I believe in Europe there
is much greater scrutiny now they've
banned all Harvest of Pete from Ireland
so I you know they had to shut down Pete
harvesting completely and and now what
has happened though is they're just
getting their Pete from somewhere else
like laia or Estonia so they haden't
stopped the use of Pete they just
shifted where it comes from so Ireland's
taking care of Ireland but they're still
using Pete I guess is that now they have
been um very proactive in using wood
fibers and other alternative growing
media but again comes with its own set
of problems so um you know and when I
talked to some of my European colleagues
what is actually legislated what is
proposed what is actually being done in
Europe it's it's a real mixed bag and
it's really hard to be you know give a
concise overview but um there is more
pressure for environmental legislation
there there is more pressure against
using it just socially so I think they
want to phase it out completely from
England by the year 2030
um so but keeping track of what is
proposed versus what is actually done
has been somewhat challenging you know
from this side of the
pond well this might be a good time to
transition into other substrates and how
they compare so um one of the things
that you did in your presentation was
you look you know we've been talking
about sort of the environmental impacts
of Pete Moss as a substrate but if we
want to make a determination a true Det
mination about a substrate uh we need to
also look at its uh social and human
health impacts as well um that's correct
yeah which I think is a really important
aspect especially when we start talking
about things that are being transported
over large distances to get to us so um
yeah let's dive into it so can we kind
of cover Pete Moss first from sort of
this uh I think you call it a life cycle
analysis in terms of um human health
effects social effects environmental and
then we can do the same with some of
these other substrates yeah so um now
some of your listeners probably have
heard about this before but there are
there's there's a there's a process
called a life cycle analysis or life
cycle assessment where they try to
quantitatively measure the impacts of um
any service any process or any product
on um you know the environment human
health society and and you know they're
they're constantly expanding what they
can measure the impact on um but the the
goal of these is to do a fair and
objective quantitative analysis to
determine how these um uh how these
products you know impact you know again
society and and and the environment so
when we look at Pete um we can measure
the the the the the big one is the
carbon footprint how many kilograms of
CO2 per cubic meter of pee is released
in the atmosphere um when you harvest
that Pete and use it for horiculture so
they've done that and those values range
from 20 to 150 kilograms of CO2
equivalent per cubic meter um now what
what is you know you can look at
different studies each study makes a
different set of assumptions where was
that Peete harvested how far was it
transported and then how was it used So
based on those assumptions they will
come up with slightly different values
but generally speaking most of the
values range from about 20 to 50
kilograms of CO2 per cubic meter one of
them was as high as 150 um so there's
some variability there but um now as we
discussed before we we got on here a lot
of this data comes from Europe so we
only have one study to my knowledge that
was done in North America and I think
they ter determined that the the carbon
footprint was about 50 um kilg per cubic
meter so um now you compare that to core
just in terms of its CO2 equivalence or
or its carbon footprint in most studies
but not all in most studies core has a
slightly lower carbon footprint than
does Pete but now the carbon Footprints
only one part of the story you can look
at the environmental impact that also
considers things like um terrestrial
acidification fresh and Marine water you
rication uh ecotoxicity land use fossil
resource scarcity and water consumption
when you factor all those in core
becomes it has a higher relative impact
than Pete usually much worse and a lot
of that has to do with how core is
processed it uses a tremendous amount of
water um and it also releases a high
salt load into the environment wherever
it's done in order to you know flush the
salts from the core piip so um yeah when
you look at the the total environmental
impact generally Pete has a much lower
impact than does core or other products
like rock wool and
perlite yeah when I first started
looking into this I was trying to put
together an article comparing uh Heat
versus Coco because it was something
that I was interested in and one of the
things that I found was with cocoa core
like you mentioned there's a there's a
huge water consumption and water is
premium um these days clean water is
something that we struggle with globally
uh so we're using a lot of water to
flush all the salinity like you
mentioned that salt has to go somewhere
um and then that clean Core has to be uh
dried and compressed and shipped all the
way over here to North America because
it's being harvested um in in tropical
areas and then uh the other thing that
surprised me too that we haven't talked
about and that falls under sort of the
social human health aspect is is the
respiratory effects that this was having
it may have been generating um economic
wealth for a particular Community but it
was causing huge respiratory problems
for the workers that were collecting the
core and I don't know if that has
changed since I first looked into this
15 or so years ago but um that was
something that I I thought was a
considerable point to consider when
making a substrate decision too yeah
that you're absolutely right now all the
core today most of it comes from Sri
Lanka or India although they are trying
to develop some um products from South
America as well now you know harvesting
from South America so we'll see how that
goes but you're right you know they can
also measure human health impact that
incur it includes things like toxic
effects carcinogens respiratory effects
that you mentioned ionizing radiation
fine particulate matter in Ozone
depletion and when you factor those
things in again in every study that we
have data for both Pete and core core
has a higher human health impact than
does Pete um and and rock wool in one
case rockwool was actually lower than
core but rockwool was also pretty high
um so yeah you're right now one thing I
will say is that I I believe there's
been a lot of investment in the core in
the last 10 years so some large
companies from North America are
investing in that and I think they are
um so so you know you're right when we
first started using core there was lots
of concerns about worker safety worker
conditions and in some of these
developing countries but I think a lot
of that has changed and I think you know
um corporate investment and those sorts
of things has improve that situation
although I don't have firsthand
knowledge of it that's just what I
suspect um but still I mean these
studies were done in the last two or
three years the human health impact of
core is still greater than what Pete is
and along with this I just would like to
add that I'm making personally the
assumption that rock wall and perlite
are worse substrates than um Peter Coco
so I'm kind of ranking them in terms of
environmental impact as uh from lowest
to highest going sort of Pete
Coco and then I would assume perlite
then rock wall um as the major
substrates you know rock wool is
something that's used of course by
hydroponic Growers and that's kind of
almost a whole different category you
either use it completely or not at all
but per light's something that we've
always traditionally mixed in with our
substrates especially Peete um and I
think everyone in the industry from
grower up to substrate providers
manufacturers
everyone you know that that's that's the
first thing that people are looking to
replace that's kind of you know people
are looking to get away from perlite and
now I get a nasty email from the perlite
manufacturers every time I say that but
that that's just you know the reality
um yeah that's a tough one because
um I mean perlite works so well now we
use pmus and our soil mixes because um
it it's it's heavier which is great from
uh a substrate perspective but in terms
of shipping and and those sorts of
things and fossil fuel cost it's it's
definitely higher to move pmus around um
one of the things that's so awful about
the Cannabis industry which I'm a a part
of um is that uh a lot of people are
throwing out this media so whether you
know at least with Rockwell people are
now starting to reuse it and things but
um the amount of of perlite the amount
of cocoa core and Pete Moss that gets uh
put into landfalls or dumped out every
round is is really quite quite a
contributor I think to environmental
damage um
one of the things and you you don't know
me you know we haven't talked about this
one of the things that my company does
is we work with folks um in creating uh
like for example taking the Cannabis
putting it into a soil bed like let's
just say a 4x4 bed of soil and then at
the end of the cycle uh we will soil
test and reuse that media so we're just
adding you know nutrients back into it
treating it sort of more like
agricultural land so while we do have
the environmental impact of of starting
with Pete Moss we're not adding more
media every cycle we're reusing that
substrate over and over again and we
have people that have been doing this
for you know 5 to 10 years now with the
same uh the same media and so that to me
feels better at least in when I'm using
Pete at least I feel like I'm I'm
creating a highest use case for it from
a Horticultural perspective to where I'm
having less environmental impact once
that soil is sort of created it in place
yeah that's right yeah um and there are
lots of creative ways that you can reuse
Pete and you know I think think it's
it's an especially post production it's
an excellent soil amendment if you have
that Outlet nearby where you can apply
it to agricultural land um you know it
whereas I know using some of the mineral
products like uh rock wool or perlite um
disposal is a problem it's a challenge
um uh now you know you mentioned pmus I
I was a a professor at Oregon State
University for a while so yeah we we
work with pus a lot that that's an
interesting material to work with and
it's a very good substrate and um can
you share a little bit about pmus since
it sounds like you have some experience
with it in comparison to perlite and
other options you know I I guess in the
Oregon Nursery industry it was used now
this is outdoor Nursery crops Woody
plants you know container nurseries it
was used almost exclusively relative to
perlight we didn't use pearlite and
Nursery crops we use Douglas furb bark
and pmus and so I went and visited there
were at the time there were two sources
of pmus in Oregon um one from the bend
area and one down south southern Oregon
I forget the exact region um but just
visiting those you know those pmus area
the pmus mines and seeing how they they
mine it from the ground um and then
looking at some of the chemical and
physical characteristics of the pmus and
how it's used in in in Nursery crops
that and I've wrote some articles years
and years and years ago I don't remember
the details anymore but um and we' use
it like 10 to 20% of the growing of the
container mix so it was relatively minor
uh component in the substrate but um
yeah it was interesting looking at it
especially visiting the mines and seeing
how it's extracted and and you know
processed and that sort of
thing and what are the differences
between uh prite and pmus for people
that are
unfamiliar well I would say the primary
difference you mentioned is the weight
the the the the pomus is just heavier
and and almost if you're not to the
untrained eye it might even look the
same feel the same it's um you know it's
a porous uh volcanic material and um the
the the pomus out of Bend was very white
and so you might almost be tricked into
thinking it was perlite the pomus out of
Southern Oregon had a it was stained it
was the the ribbon of pomus they were
mining was closer to the soil surface so
it was stained a little more yellow and
it didn't look as bright gleaming white
as the the bend pmus did um but other
than that as far as growing media other
than it increased the bulk density of
your media a little more relative to
what per you you really didn't measure
anything there was no measurable
difference in chemical properties or or
otherwise at least from what we've done
it was just you know about the same
particle size now the the products that
we using Nur Nursery industry were a
little dustier um they had a lot of
fines in them you know the pus product
unless you had a double screen but
otherwise it was very similar to
perlite yeah we had to move to using uh
2/3 medium oneir large pmus for that
reason when we use just medium pmus the
amount of finds in there actually
created less Iration end up being this
sort of goopy mess so that is that is a
good point um one thing as I think about
other things that we can add to Media
for IRAs and I want to transition into
uh pine bark next but um
as I look for other options for ariation
in in my industry people will use rice
holes as a form of ariation but that has
sustainability issues and it also is uh
potentially a a source of arsenic which
um because Canabis is being tested now
for heavy metal content at very very
strict levels in some regulated States
um that can be a huge contributor and a
big problem um that also makes it hard
to use things like lava volcanic lava
rock because as that breaks down if
you're reusing your media that also
could be adding heavy metals whereas the
pmus um that we've seen is is pretty
clean relative minerally it doesn't it
doesn't really have a lot of uh heavy
metals so uh I just wanted to mention
that as a sort of an aside
around you know airation options there
really I haven't found a better one but
maybe um maybe exploration of of pine
bark or or some of these other wood
substrates um is a possibility I mean
what are your thoughts on
them yeah so one one thing is that um I
did research with biochars about 10 or
15 years ago and problem was at the time
it was an interesting product to work
with but there was no there was no
Source no large volume source of it and
as much as people talked about it and
how exciting biochar was you know you
really couldn't find it for a reasonable
price well that's changed now I don't
know what has changed in the energy
sector but now there are more sources
abundant sources of biochar commercially
so that's something that um I know one
of the major substrate manufacturers now
are using biochar instead of perlite as
the kind of the coar quote unquote
aggregate that you put in the media to
provide drainage and so um presumably
biochar would be very stable for very
long periods of time and um you know not
have some of the you know the the heavy
metal toxicities that you might find
with other you know mineral sources from
the ground um wood fibers are something
you know I think we discussed this a
little bit before we got on the air um
that's something that started in Europe
and now you can find an abundant supply
of that in North America as well there's
there's at least one major manufacturer
and there may be two or three coming
online soon but um literally taking the
wood portion of pine trees and um and
I'm not sure the mechanical process they
put it through it's some sort of dis
extrus Extrusion I think but it creates
a fiber it's almost like you know a
wooden Brill pad is what it feels like
very difficult to mix and very difficult
to work with from a mixing standpoint um
you need specialized equipment to do
that but if you have that equipment and
you can mix it uh it it does create a a
fairly good substrate you can replace up
to 30 to 40% of the
or maybe use that as the Iration
component of your
media yeah I want to back up for a
second I'm really glad you brought a
biochar it's something that I sort of
take for granted uh because it's
something we've been using for a long
time and I I I've done podcasts just on
biochar because it I think it's so
fascinating but yes that is another
great option I haven't experimented with
using it as more than eight% of my uh
total media primarily because of cost
and again when we talk about biochar uh
it's like compost I just for listeners
keep in mind they're not all created
equal um particle size is going to have
a big impact in terms of the gas
exchange moisture retention irration
effects of biochar so uh don't just go
out and buy a bag biochar and think that
you're going to get these results you
need to do a little little bit more
research into it but um yeah I think I
think biochar would be a great solution
it's still I think the the I they still
find it prohibitively expensive to get
quality biochar in a media at a high
percentage but um you know for a home
grower that might be quite reasonable to
consider experimenting with at higher
ratios than the eight% that we go
with yeah and what we have been working
with is more of like a
15% um on a volumetric basis so we're
probably closer to you in that regard um
uh yeah and and and again as a scientist
I one of the last things I think about
sometimes times is the price which maybe
I should think about that more often
because that's what the grower
ultimately is going to be looking at um
so I'm not sure what the cost on the
material we've been working with has
been but it's a wood-based biochar uh
you know as when I work with these
companies that do the pyrolysis that
they're they're primarily after the fuel
and the the biodiesel and the biog gases
and then they have this black stuff this
solid material at the end like hey what
do I do with this and and you know using
it in a growing media is a is a real
obvious choice but I yeah they they need
to get the price down a little more or
at least not rely on Growers to
subsidize that fraction of it for them
if they're going to be making money off
the gas and the fuel from uh you know
the pyresis and but um that that's
usually you know how the conversation
starts there's a supply of it and then
how do we get how do we use this you
know sustainably and maybe make a little
money from
it yeah and I've seen um
that I've SE actually in Oregon my
father was actually working with some
folks down there in terms of using uh
kilms to uh uh when they go out and and
do logging for the forest slash to
sequester the carbon from the forest
slash and then create a byproduct then
could either be put back onto the land
or potentially sold to offset some of
the costs associated with setting up
biotar kills um so yeah biochar is
something I think is great uh and it is
carbon positive in terms of sequestering
carbon versus the carbon loss that we
would normally see with um the timber
industry so I think that's I think
that's a really good one that you
brought up and and we've seen um we
we've done some some trials ourselves
and but there's actually a lot of
research around biochar um but we've
seen better growth uh plant growth by
using baar even as low as 5% of our
media um which sort of surprised me in
some ways um but um yeah I definitely
think it's something that people should
consider it in their substrate if we're
having a substrate conversation like
this I'm I didn't think to bring it up
and I'm so glad you did um yeah well and
you know you brought up an interesting
point and it's funny because I used to
say the exact same thing biochar is a
lot like compost you got to consider
what was the feed stock originally
because that will determine a lot the
chemical properties when when you create
the biochar how was it processed you
know just like how was it composted you
know what was the pro how was it
pyrolyzed and then we're post treatment
you know uh post pyrolysis treatments
that were applied but yeah not all
biochars are not created equally they
they vary incredibly depending on what
you started from and and how it was pyro
you know pyrolyzed so um there a very
good point it considering it as as you
would compost not all are created
equal yeah and people ask you know can I
just go down to Home Depot and buy some
charcoal throw that in my soil and a lot
of times that's not um pyol ized uh to
the extent that we want for um biochar
and also it may contain heavy metals and
other toxins because they're not looking
to create the same quality product that
we may want for Horticulture at least is
is my knowledge around it um I wanted to
before before you go I did want to talk
about these wood substrate Alternatives
because I think um it's something that
I've looked into and I personally have
not had a lot of success with them in
terms of creating the same level plant
health and plant growth uh but I'm not
going to attribute that to the media or
the substrate I'll just say that that's
on me um I'd love to hear your thoughts
around it and one thing that I do want
to bring up uh before I let you talk
about it is the fact that on on soil
bags the way the labeling Works around
these products is you may see them
listed as Forest
byproducts uh pine bark pine bark fines
um and a variety of other names and like
biochar or like compost that could speak
to anything from you know high quality
pine bark finds that are going to have
good results potentially in your mix to
something like sawdust that's just may
be added as a filler so it's very
challenging as a grower to determine
what you're getting in a bag without
doing a little bit more digging I guess
the labeling doesn't give it all
way yeah that's right and you know I I
my guess is that the larger commercial
uh substrate providers are going to do a
better job at guaranteeing what comes in
that bag than what you might find from
like say like a Home Depot or just going
down to the garden center and products
that are and I know this from personal
experience products that are geared
toward homeowners they'll fill that bag
with anything um where the manufacturers
when they're selling it to a commercial
grower that needs crop uniformity from
not only within a crop but from year to
year and you know crop to crop they're
they're much more conscious about what
they're putting in and making sure it
falls within certain um quality
standards so uh but the that that's my
experience when you when you're when
you're using a homeowner geared product
it's it's you never know what's in there
it's just the wild west it you have no
idea so when you say p pine bark finds
you kind of described that a little bit
or bark finds um can you talk a little
bit about sort of the physical
properties um as well as what what sort
of percentages people are using them in
and what sort of results we're seeing in
horiculture right now so with pine bark
and pine bark fines um and that can mean
a lot of different things so you know we
would generally look at a particle size
distribution of those but um you're
never going to get the water holding
capacity that you would find with Pete
and no matter how fine you go with these
pine bark fines Pete Moss is just going
to be a little better holding water and
buffering water
um water buffering capacity uh I also
believe that the
um you know the C exchange capacity and
the the the the pH buffering in Pete is
a little better than it would be in pine
bark fines um generally speaking um you
could use 100% pine bark to grow an
outdoor Nursery crop um it what what
kind of our ideal substrate in Ohio
would be something like 80% Pine 20%
sagum Peete that will grow a really good
crop now of course then you have to add
you know a little bit of lime and
fertilizers and everything else in that
but in terms of the physical components
of the media that's a great crop for for
an outdoor Woody plant um now when you
go into more herbaceous things smaller
plants the smaller the plant the more
sensitive it's going to be to the
chemical and physical properties of the
growing media so that's where Pete Moss
generally does a lot better than pine
bark wood but large robust Woody plants
we have a saying you can put 20% of
anything in those pots and it's going to
grow just the same um now they're all
that but they're just more robust to
less ideal you know uh substrates than
than than a a small Flor culture crop or
perhaps you know cannabis plants and
maybe a one or two gallon pot um so that
that's my experience with pine bark and
pine bark finds makes for an excellent
growing media the primary component used
for nursery crops um but it when you
start growing you know again more
araceous or smaller plants you have to
be a little more selective and careful
with what you're you know
using one other thing that we haven't
really talked about I just want to bring
up too is sort of the uh because when I
think about a substrate and I've
mentioned this on the podcast a lot of
times that I'm looking at a substrate
from about essentially like three
different pillars like I want to look at
the the physical properties of that
substrate the chemical properties So
like um where's the pH what sort of
minerals is contained and then lastly
the biological properties of that
substrate and we haven't talked about
biology at all and and one thing with
Pete Moss um and I can say this just
from looking down a microscope is it's
biologically active it contains good
biology whereas some of these other
substrates like cocoe or um pine bark
findes that would have to be introduced
it's not going to come in with any sort
of nutrient cycling on organic side in
terms of the the the biology in that uh
substrate do you want to touch on that
at all yeah that's actually something
we've been working on a lot for the last
five to 10 years now going back since we
started using growing media in the
1960s studying the biology has been
incredibly difficult because you're
limited to studying maybe one or two
pathogens or say beneficial organisms
like Michael risey one or two things at
a time and only things that you can
plate in a Petri dish other organisms
are just too difficult to quantify or or
anything else now with the Advent of DNA
Technologies say 15 or 20 years ago and
around 10 or 15 years ago they became
very affordable in an agricultural
research sense so now using uh DNA
sequencing technology we're just
starting to look at the microbiome in
growing media you can find several
papers out there now um what I would say
is the the the microbiome
depends on what you start with and on
Day Zero they're going to be very
different in containers filled with
different Media or even compost but
after two or three months in that
growing media under those conditions
with the irrigation the fertility the
temperature all the environmental
conditions that you have that's going to
select for a certain consortia of you
know a microbial community and no matter
what you started with a lot of that's
going to die out because it just can't
survive in that environment what we find
is if we start with different media of
different composts or different you know
components they tend to look the same
after about three months in the same
environment so it's kind of like I tell
people if you want to increase the
biodiversity of the North Pole you took
a bunch of tigers lions and zebras up
there after about a week you have a
bunch of dead lions tigers and zebras so
it's not so much what you put into that
media it's what what will the
environmental factors sustain in terms
of you know microbial organisms growing
um one of my colleagues here at Ohio
State University she did something
really clever she was looking for
beneficial bacteria and she collected
her sources from a commercial Greenhouse
so those bacteria if she found you know
plant growth promoting properties within
those bacteria they are more likely to
survive if you then apply them to other
containers and that that program is
actually working quite well um but it's
a it's it's something there's a lot of
snake oil out there a lot of Growers
will like to buy things because they
think it's biologically active and what
what does that even mean in in in a
realistic sense it's whatever that
company wants it to mean that they're
that they're trying to sell the product
to so um we're just starting to learn
now about what actually lives in these
container media and um and you know what
you what will survive in a growing media
versus what you apply to that media so
it it's it is very a very young science
we know a lot less about that than we
know about the physical and the chemical
properties just because it's so hard to
measure and even now it's still really
expensive you just can't go out and and
it's it's it's really difficult to do
it's it's you know measuring pH and EC
or paracity those things are relatively
straightforward and simple me you know
getting a good microbial Community
analysis of a growing media takes a
dedicated person who knows what they're
doing and it's it's somewhat difficult
so well I think that's really
interesting about what you said
regarding um various substrates uh
containing similar
biological uh communities after a given
period of time just being in the same
environment that's that's really
interesting um one thing so to summarize
sort of your opinion on on microbes or
biology it's that um it's it's a side of
the industry that we're still learning a
lot about um it's it's expensive and uh
maybe not the best tool for making
diagnostic or uh you know datadriven
decisions about our cultivation habits
that's yeah you're exactly right and
what what I what I know about
it is only the tip of the iceberg I mean
we know so little about those biological
communities even if you looked at all
the papers that been published to this
day it it it's just a small amount of
information and we just we we know less
than what we know I mean there we have a
lot to learn about that before we can
make any really
conclusive um decisions or you know give
it conclusive advice on what you should
or should not do all I'm talking about
is based on the scantest amount of
information what I've observed um on
some of the studies that we have done on
how these communities start out and how
they change over time but again we have
not done nearly enough research on this
to um speak
authoritatively and we just don't know
enough to to really say one way or the
other yeah I went to a talk by a soul
scientist uh at a college oh 10 15 years
ago now and one of the things he said
that really stuck with me was he said we
know more about the surface of the Moon
and the depths of our Ocean than we do
with what's going on directly underneath
our feet um we just don't understand
that biology and it's so complex and I
also got to attend at the international
Soul science Society of America
conference one year oh it's a mouthful
um was uh a speaker that did research
doing DNA analysis on agricultural lands
in relation to hydrology and so
basically they measured um they they
they looked at all of what was in a soil
a soil uh when when the soil was dry and
then they came back after a rain and
measured it and then maybe after a
watering event and then again let it dry
out and you saw a massive change in
fungal to bacteria uh ratios you saw a
huge change in the Consortium microbes
that were present it's such a complex
community and yet I see people making
decisions about their cultivation habits
based off of what they see under a
microscope and I'm literally looking at
my microscope over here because I it's
something that I like to do but I don't
make I I use a chemical analysis a soil
test because like you said we have very
reliable metrics around EC pH um you
know the levels of calcium and magnesium
and and potassium that we know a
particular crop needs and so to me those
are more data driven uh variables than
the microbiome even though it is quite
important yeah you're absolutely right
that you just nailed it that's exactly
that's exactly my assessment of it now
and again we just spent five years doing
studies on the microbiome and we just
know so little that it's really hard to
make you know yet like you said data
driven um decisions based on you know
what we what we do
know yeah I mean we do know that compost
is this magical tool that we have in our
Arsenal that we can add into soils and
see these because it is such a
concentration of microbes that we see
such great results from it um when used
properly but in terms of identifying the
microbes and I think that is a challenge
but I look forward to what you know what
research is coming out of uh your
University and others on this topic yeah
it's going to be slow I fear um just
because of the expense of it but it is
so it's it's really to me it's the Last
Frontier you know we we have we're
really good at the chemical and physical
properties but we need to be better at
measuring and understanding how to well
first of all how to measure then how to
manage the biological properties because
I think that's what Growers are really
looking to do um they understand the
importance of the biological component
but we just don't know enough to know
how to manipulate it or how to use it to
our
advantage
great so there were two substrates that
I wanted to ask you about that we didn't
talk about um I'm kind of throwing you a
curveball here too have you heard of pit
Moss by chance it's a newspaper
cardboard based substrate I've I've
talked to the owner um we actually did
some trials with it I personally wasn't
able to create a chemical analysis soil
test that I felt really comfortable in
utilizing but I think it's a really
fascinating recycled product in terms of
uh you know utilizing a waste stream
into a potential
substrate it's a great story but I have
not seen evidence yet that it's going to
make an
effective commercial substrate um I I
would just say you know do your HK
before you commit to doing anything with
that product whether you or one of your
audience members you know do your
homework and make sure it works well in
your production system um because there
could be some
challenges okay and uh Dairy wash is the
other one that I see at trade shows that
is another waste product that when I
hold it in my hands and look at it it
seems like it would be a very viable
substrate it feels like it would grow
plants but I but with the high ph and
some of the other challenges around it I
haven't it's another one that I haven't
really had good success with have you
done any trials or seen any research on
that as another option I have seen some
of these um Dairy digestates and and
things like that and they they look just
like Pete Moss and they feel they they
look and feel right but again you know
and I've seen several of these companies
come and go and their products come and
go and none of them have been successful
none of them none of them I should say
not the companies but I have not able to
use those products successfully in you
know to to grow plants well now maybe
that's because I'm a bad horticulturist
but you know that's how I feel about
myself with those too so it makes me
feel a little bit better uh but I would
tell any of your listeners you know you
know always try new things but you know
do your homework and and really vet them
before you you know consider going you
know all in on it because um I you know
I've seen a lot of
challenging they've not worked too well
for most people that I you
know the
examples okay so just to summarize sort
of our conversation today um Pete Moss
does have an ecological impact an
environmental impact it may not be quite
as Extreme as some of these the the
media stories are telling us and all of
these other substrate options like cocoa
cor Rockwell perlite all have an
eological impact as well um biochar is
something that could absolutely be
considered but check your you know check
your quality do a little research before
incorporating it and then um some of
these other Alternatives like the dairy
wash pine bark and uh pit Moss all have
challenges as well but maybe could be
incorporated in at smaller percentages
than uh say just completely switching
over as a media maybe use it 10 or 20%
um but as of right now there is nothing
from a plant perspective in regards to
substrates that's going to beat Pete
Moss that's correct and one thing that I
tell Growers too is this we've been
using Pete Moss for 60 years and since
that time we have as we discussed
earlier we have engineered the right
particle size you know we buffer the pH
we we amend it with starter charges we
have you know wedding agents all that
and we we're very good at using Pete
Moss what if we put 60 years of that
same rigor and Research into using core
would it be as good because core is the
only product in my opinion that can be
used in the broad Spectra you know and
all the it could replace Pete in in in
many of the situations where you use
Pete now there are challenges again as
you mentioned with the ph and the
salinity sometimes and the quality um
but if we put the same amount of
research in the core could it be as good
as Pete that's you know so what can
replace Pete that that's my only in my
opinion that's the only thing I know of
right now um there's some things that
need to be figured out but that that's
what I would tell Growers is um it has
it has the potential but we just we put
so much effort into refining the use
refining sag and Pete Moss it's going to
be really hard to just start using
something or find something else and say
hey let's try this and it's going to
work as well as Pete does we just we've
engineered that so thoroughly well um
it's a really great substrate