[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discussed the cutting
edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is David Montgomery
David studied geology at Stanford
University before earning his PhD in
geomorphology at UC Berkeley he teaches
at the University of Washington where he
studies the evolution of topography and
how geological processes shaped
landscapes and influenced ecological
systems
he loved maps as a kid and now writes
about the relationship of people to
their environment and other things that
interested in 2008 he was named a
MacArthur Fellow he lives with his wife
and in Seattle Washington he's written
multiple books but the ones most
interesting to gardeners are dirt the
erosion of civilizations the hidden half
of nature and growing a revolution
bringing our soils back to life in dirt
the erosion of civilizations he explores
the compelling idea that we are and have
long been using up Earth's soil once
Bera protected vegetation and exposed to
wind and rain cultivated soils erode bit
by bit slowly enough to be ignored in a
single lifetime but fast enough over
centuries to limit the lifespan of
civilizations a rich mix of history
archaeology and geology dirt traces the
roll of soil use and abuse in the
history of Mesopotamia ancient Greece
the Roman Empire China European
colonialism Central America and the
American push westward we see how soil
has shaped us and how we have shaped
soil as society after society has risen
prospered and plowed through a natural
endowment of fertile dirt David
Montgomery sees in the recent rise of
organic and no-till farming the hope for
a new agricultural revolution that might
help us avoid the fate of previous
civilizations
in the hidden half of nature which I
will discuss in more detail with his
wife and the clay who is a co-author and
also a biologist is a riveting
exploration of how microbes are
transforming the way we see nature and
ourselves and could revolutionize
agriculture in medicine and in his most
recent book growing a revolution david
introduces us to farmers around the
world at the heart of the brewing soil
health revolution that could help bring
humanity's ailing soil back to life
remarkably fast-growing a revolution
draws on visits to farms in the
industrialized world and developing
world to show that a new combination of
farming practices can deliver innovative
cost-effective solutions to problems
farmers face today I was honored to have
him take time out of his busy schedule
for this interview I hope you enjoy it
and you can find his books available
online at their website at
www.growingproduce.com older well sure
you know I came to that interest from a
rather unusual route because
professionally I'm a geologist so I
study the way that Earth's surface
features form the kind of geologist that
studies landscape evolution so you know
how rivers shape lowland terrain and
carve valleys out of mountains what
glaciers do to mountains
what limits the height the mountains
what creates pools for fish habitats and
mountain streams in the northwest and
what happens to rivers and volcanoes
explode all that great geological stuff
that impacts the surface of the earth
that we live on that we walk around on
and it shapes our not only our daily
lives but you know really sort of the
whole lay of the land that we know as
our world so I've been fascinated by
that for four decades professionally and
the first thing you want to know about a
landscape as a geomorphologist that that
flavor of geologist that I am
is is their soil on the on the land
because it influences how things are
Road the shape of terrain it's sort of
the first thing you want to know and the
first issue you run into there is well
how fast the soil form was a format of
how does it form what are its properties
and how fast does it erode because it's
that balance between soil production and
soil erosion that shapes how much soil
we have on Earth's landscapes so I came
to the sort of an interest in the soil
and an interest in farming and thinking
about how agronomic practices affect the
cultivation of crops from a fairly
unusual direction for someone who thinks
about that stuff so I come from sort of
a bigger picture longer time frame and
bottom-up perspectives rather than
looking at it from the top down and so
you've sort of looked at it now from a
macroscopic and a microscopic level with
the books written yeah when you go into
looking at soil and thinking about what
makes it fertile and all this sort of
the complex relationships between plants
you're growing in soil and what's going
on around the root systems below ground
you run right into the microbial world
that world of microscopic organisms that
are you know can be a great benefit to
plants but you know that can also be
sources of pests and pathogens and my
wife who's a biologist and McClay and I
wrote the hidden half of nature about
that part of of the whole deal here and
so yeah I wouldn't have gone from the
broad picture down to worrying about
things so small we can't see them but
they have big effects that that not only
affect how we can grow our our food and
other crops but but the sort of the
shape and character of Earth's surface
so I'm fortunate enough to be able to
talk to an here soon regarding the
hidden half of nature so I'm looking
forward to hearing about that book from
her but can you tell me a little bit
more about dirt and growing a revolution
and what inspired you to write these two
books yeah sure that you know there's
three books together form one and I sort
of partially jokingly call our dirt
trilogy because the the dirt book there
at the erosion of
was the first one in it that I wrote it
came out about 10 years ago 2007 and
it's the book that I think helped pave
the way for MacArthur award that I got
back then basically I think on the
strength of that book and when I'd done
on the environmental history of salmon
that's a whole different story but that
dirt book what it looks at is it's the
kind of book you might expect a
geologist to write about soils it's a
backwards looking book through history
that looks at what happened to ancient
civilizations that degraded their land
enough that it compromised their ability
to grow their their food crops their
fabric crops their ability to support
themselves agronomically by degrading or
losing their soil and it traces that the
course in history of those kind of
interactions literally since the dawn of
Agriculture right on up through the the
post-war era in the 20th century when
what we know today is modern
conventional agriculture the sort of
chemical intensive variety of
agriculture really came to be the norm
across conventional agronomy so it's a
broad sweeping view of the way that
humanity has related to the land
over the millennia and how the way we've
treated the land has in turn influenced
the way that the soil has been able to
support civilizations or not once the
land was degraded enough that it
undercut the ability of societies to
feed and provision themselves so it was
a fun look back through history that um
the bottom line is essentially societies
that didn't take care of their soil
didn't last yeah that's really
interesting so as we move into an era of
modern agriculture here in sort of the
United States and Europe with the end of
I believe that was World War two when we
started to see a lot more of ammonium
nitrate and some of these fertilizers
being used in conventional agriculture
how how do you see that influencing our
society and the impact that it's had
moving forward
well you know there's one of the big
problems that we face in the 21st
century is that the amount of really
productive farmland that we have has
been decreasing for the last 100 years
but actually big theme of the dirt books
has been decreasing for longer than that
but it's it's accelerated in the 20th
century
whereas our human the global human
population is going up at the same time
projected over the next half century to
century and those curves are working
against each other where if we're it's
going to become harder and harder to
feed everybody if we have more people in
less land that's in good fertile shape
to do it so that that's one of the big
concerns and one of the other concerns
is that the ways that we've practiced
agriculture with in the modern world
with intensive tillage intensive
fertilization and and pesticide use
really compromises all that soil life
that you'll talk with Ann about when you
talk about the hidden half of nature and
all those microbes live on the organic
matter in the soil and modern agronomic
practices have reduced that on average
around the world by about 50 percent
roughly half of the organic matter that
was in US topsoil that was you know when
we were originally breaking ground to
farm it about half of it's gone so we've
drawn down the the fertility batteries
if you will of our nation's soils by
about half and that number is roughly
about right for the world - and that's a
great concern if when you think about
the problem of feeding the future and it
also comes into concern and when we
think about the quality of crops because
it's the interaction there's a lot of
interactions between soil life and plant
roots that help influence the way that
mineral micronutrients get into plants
the things that build enzymes and that
build healthy plant bodies that are
versatile on their own defensive systems
and it also affects phytochemical
production in terms of the kinds and
amounts of chemicals the plants
themselves produce which can affect
their nutritional quality for us or
their medicinal properties and in other
in other arenas and in non-food crops
but we've been learning that the
way that we grow our crops or the health
of the soil we grow them in can have a
big effect on the quality of the stuff
that comes out now I did a previous
podcast with Steve Solomon who was the
author of the intelligent gardener and
gardening west of the Cascades which is
a really popular book here in the
northwest and one of his influences was
Weston Price and his oh yeah in his book
on remineralization I guess in soils and
how the soil in a certain area would
affect a cultures dental health
what are your findings in terms of
mineral levels in soil because you're
mentioning phytochemicals and other
influences that the nutrients in
different soils are having on plants
yeah you know Western price and his work
is very interesting as were others of
his peers in that era in the 20s 30s and
40s because it's very difficult today to
get good sort of population level data
to try and connect the health of the
soil to the health of people and they
were there's some examples of dental
records and other things from back in
his era but today one of the problems is
that you know you walk into a grocery
store and there's food from all over the
world and so you know very few people in
the developed world are eating food
that's you know primarily grown in soils
that you can identify where it came from
did it come from a good healthy soil and
in a field off of a farm or did it come
from a very degraded farm or a farm in a
very degraded part of the world so it's
hard to connect it's hard to get studies
that connect those dots today but
there's some very interesting ones back
in prices day where you could make that
assumption that people were eating food
that was grown fairly locally to where
they lived so you could examine you know
broad scale impacts of things like the
the geology the kind of rocks in a
region and it were they calcium Richard
is a calcium poor for example in the
dental studies and attract through to
sort of affect to affect dental health
in ways that were we're fairly clear
might be fairly crude studies by today's
standards of science but they were
they're interesting
and fairly clear in my view and that
opens questions about you know how much
does the way we grow our food and the
places that we grow it and how much of
the character of those processes and
those those places really translate into
things like the mineral density and the
foods that we eat and how does that
translate into health effects for us and
Ann and I are working on a new book
that's going to be looking into that
kind of stuff
in as much detail as we can find out
there in the literature as we pull it
together but we're literally in the
early stages of working on that book oh
that's great I'm really excited to see
how that turns out there just isn't
enough research out there that I've seen
at least on human nutrition and its
relation to soil and you've sort of
touched on it in all of your books to a
certain extent especially in the hidden
half
yeah we've dug into it in way to the
extent that we could find things and to
the extent of those things mapped on to
our sort of plan for the arc and flow of
those books and the topics we hit on and
the hidden half is where we got closest
to it because we talked about the way
that bacteria and microbes will fungi in
the soil helped to provision mineral
elements or to grab them out of mineral
particles in the soil and get them into
crops and yeah there needs to be more
data that looks at the effect of how we
grow food on those on the mineral
micronutrients on the phytochemicals the
kind of things in through in plants that
we know should be affected by agronomic
practices but for which nutritionists
don't tend to identify them as as
nutrients because there might
micronutrients we don't need very much
or in the case of phytochemicals they're
not really sure what the column are
consider them even though they have
demonstrated human health benefits in
other studies so yeah there needs to be
a lot more research and look at that
it's a fascinating topic but yeah we
touched a bit on it in the hidden half
as I'm sure you'll talk with her about
but there's a lot more that can be dug
into and so we're trying to synthesize
as much of that information as we can
get our hand
yeah it makes me wonder what the future
of Agriculture really holds in terms of
consumer perception if at some point in
time we'll go into the grocery store and
we'll have conventionally grown produce
and we'll have organic produce and maybe
we'll have nutrient-dense produce or
similar to the wine industry where
certain areas are renowned for their
terroir or their mineral content in
their soils we you know we may see
something similar in terms of vegetables
that are grown in a particular region or
grown in a particular manner something
like yeah yeah no I know if you look out
20 if you look out like 20 or 30 years I
would forecast that there's going to be
much more in the way of what you might
think of like supply chain information
on where your food came from and how it
was grown at the point of purchase so
you might be able to you know scan a
code that would tell you oh this is from
s.x farm and it has this much zinc and
this much beta-carotene for carrots or
something and you could compare this
batch of carrots over here labeled
whatever it is organic or regenerative
or conventional versus that batch of
carrots over there and try and actually
assess what's the quality of the product
as opposed to all we really know today
walking into a food store is you know
okay was what's it labeled as a label
organic is a label conventional and
there's a huge spectrum of practices in
both those arenas convention of
conventional AG and organic agriculture
and that's a lot of what I wrote about
in the the latest book growing a
revolution where I was looking at
farmers who had adopted practices that
rebuilt the fertility of their soil and
how that affected their their crop
yields their diesel used their
fertilizer use their pesticide use their
profitability but we didn't end up
looking at the quality of the produce
because there wasn't I had a hard time
finding enough data to to weave in along
with all the other stuff I was looking
at which is why Ann and I are taking on
this new project to try and see what
kind of data is come to light in the
last couple years since I did the
research for grower evolution but in you
know in really
a Shinto I think some of your listeners
might be even more interested in it I
was really quite surprised to find that
in the cannabis industry they're way
ahead of the vegetable industry in
testing the phytochemical abundance and
their products and I would love to see
the day when tomatoes would come with
the kind of labels that are Gard now
common in the in states where cannabis
has been legalized yeah that's really
interesting I know there are some
challenges right now around the testing
methodologies and and how much we can
trust these tests from the various labs
that we're getting that yeah I would
imagine yeah but at least the the
testing protocols are there and there's
requirements around testing that I think
are really important so when it seemed
it seems like there's consumer interest
in knowing things like the terpene
profiles of cannabis sort of what are
the what are the active ingredients in
the phytochemicals that affect the
nature of the product whereas for
tomatoes there's no such information
available to consumers at all and yet it
would relates directly the flavor and
helpfulness yeah as someone who has an
edible nursery in sells produce I you
know we carried a variety of plants of a
particular you know a particular type so
we have all these different Tomatoes and
when you read about a description of
tomato you may hear that this particular
one is higher in phytonutrients for
example and you know we'll grow it but
we don't really know we're not actually
testing that tomato to see if these
claims are true or what levels the
differences there may act it may be so
minor that it's not even worth not even
worth mentioning but we don't really
know right yeah we're how or how much
how you grow it affects the expression
of those fight okay those phytochemicals
and phytonutrients and that's that's
something where I think that you were
talking about the future of Agriculture
a minute ago and I think in the one
level there's this sort of there will be
more consumer interest in understanding
what is in things but I also think there
will be opportunities to explore the
degree to which the style of growing
actually affects the expression of
phytonutrients as opposed to just the
hard-baked genetics in different
varieties of crops and you could think
of them as those there are two different
dimensions that could be explored
agronomically once the crop breeding to
manipulate the genetics and the basic
practices of how do you treat the soil
you know are you what are you
fertilizing it with are you disturbing
the ground surface are you returning the
crop residue from the same plant to the
same fields
do you have other plants growing along
in the same soil over time those kind of
things are sort of this whole other
dimension in to explore in terms of the
phytochemical to find a nutrient
expression in in crops so when you wrote
growing a revolution you got to travel
around and visit a lot of these farms if
I remember correctly and yeah can you
touch on a little bit of some of the
different practices that you saw you
know the good the bad what really was
what was really working out there sure I
mean yeah I what what annal talk to you
about in talking about the hidden half
of nature's how she restored the soil
and its fertility in our yard with her
with her gardening practice and and her
mulching and her composting and I was
watching this after writing the dirt
book about how ancient societies had
destroyed and degraded their land and
Anna's turning that whole story around
on his head right and in my backyard and
you know it took me a while to sort of
clue in and watch and it took her a
while to notice the changes but they
happened really remarkably fast as I'm
sure you guys will talk about um but I
came away from that experience wondering
okay what to what degree could similar
kinds of practices bring the fertility
of our cropland or agricultural soils
back how how long could would it take
could it be done at scale could you
doing on big farms because you have
little farms so I took six months off
from teaching at the University of
Washington where I work and visited
farms around the world that had adopted
practices to prioritize rebuilding the
health of their soil and thereby the
fertility of their land and I went to
farms in the Dakotas North and South
Dakota
to Ohio and Saskatchewan I went to Costa
Rica and equatorial West Africa and
looked at farms that ranged from 20
thousand acres in size for really big
industrialized farms in the Dakotas and
then also really small subsistence farms
and in Costa Rica and in an in Ghana and
when I came away with was the
realization that there's a simple set of
principles fairly high-level agronomic
principles that if adopted all together
as a system really our recipe for
cultivating the kinds of beneficial soil
life that antal tell you all about
because after all she's the biologist in
our in our household on the geologist
but there's a set of agronomic practices
that really cultivate that beneficial
life that are pretty simple conceptually
it's minimize the disturbance of the
soil it's always keep the ground covered
with cover crops or some of a living
plant no bare soil don't farm naked
always keep the ground covered and the
third principle being grow a diversity
of things don't just grow one or two
crops in the same soil because over time
that is an invitation for pests and
pathogens to take root but so either
grow a diversity of crops around your
cash crop or in a rotation in between
your cash crops and you know those three
simple principles were the common
elements that every farmer I visited
that had restored
you'll remarkably turn their soil around
within a decade or two they'd all
adopted practices that were faithful to
those principles now
the practices they had in different
parts of the world they were different
so you know the guys in Ghana we're not
doing the same things as the people in
Costa Rica or the people in the Dakotas
or Ohio they each had their own specific
style of practices to minimize
disturbance and to keep the ground
covered and to get a diversity in there
but those those 40,000 foot high-level
principles were honored across the board
in those systems and they had exhibited
remarkable transformations over you know
what a geologist considers to be a
really short period of time so I was
really impressed with how fast
a different style of thinking about the
soil is the foundation for agriculture
but how big a difference that could make
and it scales from you know our yard in
North Seattle to these 20,000 acre farms
and the Dakotas and there's all kinds of
side benefits that come with it in terms
of reduced fertilizer use reduced
pesticide use reduce diesel use and when
you look at sort of modern big scale
commodity crop production farms in the
u.s. at least those are the key
expensive items on the farms if you can
cut those expenses and keep the yields
up it's a recipe for a more profitable
farm and that's where I turned into an
optimist on this stuff yeah and in that
sense as a geologist can you go into a
little bit more why it is important to
not disturb the soil and why it's
important to cover the soil I think
those two especially from a geological
perspective are really interesting yeah
you know if you if you go out into the
woods somewhere and you dig a hole and
you look at the profile of the soil so
you like clean off face off and just
look at the wall of the hole that you
dug and look at the nature of the soil
there's generally a lot of organic
matter on top and the farther down you
go you got more mineral matter more
broken up rocks and if you think of what
makes soil fertile it's that marriage of
geology and biology the mixing of the
dead parts of rocks and when with the
living stuff of live organisms or the
once living organic matter you know
rotting leaves animal carcasses the
whole sort of all the stuff that plants
animals rot into it's that combination
of organic matter and mineral matter
that makes a healthy fertile soil and
the most the lion share of fertility in
the soils in that surface layer that the
topsoil but it's only about you know six
to twelve inches thick in most places
it's a fairly thin and fragile layer on
the surface of the earth before you get
down into the the subsoil which has far
less fertility in it and then get down
to the bedrock which you know it's hard
to grow plants just and on bedrock some
plants can do it but those tend to be
pioneers not the ones we grow for crops
and so if you think about soil is this
fairly thin and fragile layer that coats
the surface of the earth that is the the
recycling engine for turning all the
nutrients that are held in living
organisms plants and animals back into
the raw materials to feed the next
generation of living organisms through
the way plants take the stuff up through
the roots and then herbivores eat the
plants and carnivores eat the herbivores
and the whole circle of life goes around
and around again soil is a pretty
fundamental resource when you think
about it that way and yet the big
degrade the history of humanity for the
last ten thousand years that we've been
mining soil fertility to feed ourselves
in regions around the world and now that
we have in a global civilization where
regional food shortages translate into
global crises whether through refugees
or economic crises and and they're the
roots of some of the the big modern
conflicts around the world can be traced
to land degradation and conflict over
land you know just look at the Middle
East today the soils going to become an
increasingly important touchstone and
resource for humanity through this
century because it's of its very
fundamental nature to maintaining
agronomic productivity and production
and now I've rambled enough that I
forgot where your question was well I
was looking at it no I I found that
really fascinating and I also think it's
very interesting how when you look at
culture I was an anthropology major at
the University of Washington so my own
ok great
yes all right I looked at it from a
cultural perspective but if we look at
how soil influenced culture it helped
and how you know societies grew up based
on you know the fertility of the land I
mean agriculture was sort of what
allowed us to make that next
evolutionary step in a lot of ways from
a cultural yeah so I mean we can note
that for that you know there's there's
whole courses on just that topic so oh
yeah you know the the sort of the food I
like to think of us having gone through
four major agricultural revolutions so
far in the first one we're just thinking
about a trio
doing agriculture in the first place it
was a it was a radical act and in the
dirt book I talk about the early origin
of agriculture in the Middle East and
how it was a process that was in many
ways driven by desperation due to a
client due to climate shift coming out
of the last ice age there was a cold
snap that the the climate in the Middle
East snapped back to full-on glacial for
about a thousand years at a time when
the the hunter-gatherers in that region
had come to rely on the new plants and
animals of the warming then warming
climate and that all of us in there back
to full glacial conditions and their
food sources disappeared except for
grasses and that's when we started
cultivating grains like the proto embers
and wheats and things that there was a
big problem in terms of feeding oneself
with in the shrieking shrinking resource
base but once people started
intentionally collecting and hybrid and
hybridizing and planting seeds pretty
good at growing food and the population
was able to sort grow and increase and
we've gotten better and better and
better at having fewer and fewer people
grow more and more food so that today
instead of you know 99% of us being
farmers in the United States 1% of us
are farmers we've kind of totally
flipped the ratios in terms of who's
feeding how many people over the course
of agricultural history and that of
course lets people like me you know be
things like professors at universities
because I don't have to be out working
in the fields all the time so a bit
major first step on the road to
civilization was was was agriculture and
the audacious act of planting and
tending our food sources as opposed to
just gathering them from you know keen
observational experience in nature and
that I would think the second
agricultural revolution was when we
learned how to do things like plant
legumes and crop rotations and rotate
our crops say manure the field things
that boost helped to boost soil
fertility through acts of soil husbandry
and those were identified by
societies around the world and they
became traditional and you'll notice
that two of those three principles a
minute mentioned earlier you know
keeping the ground covered with cover
crops and having a diverse rotation
these are old ideas there's not new
ideas societies around the world adopted
them
what's brand new is taking those old
ideas of soil husbandry and coupling
them with things like no-till farming
that allows us to farm without the plow
and that's important because if you plow
the surface of the earth and you invert
the soil you turn it over it leaves it
bare and vulnerable to erosion by wind
or rain for until the next crop comes in
or the or the or weeds take over your
field whatever comes in next if you get
a good rainstorm when the ground is
ground is bare you get that phenomenon
I'm sure that we've all seen of like run
off a construction site where they've
stripped off the vegetation you got bare
earth to get raining a muddy muddy water
running off well that's fertility just
going right down the drain and that's
the story of farming in many ancient
societies that relied on the plow for
weed control and preparing their seed
beds is that over the generations they
literally lost their topsoil and then
the third agricultural revolution to go
back to that thread was mechanization
and and the use of chemical fertilizers
in the 19th and 20th centuries in the
20th century we then got on to sort of
the biotechnology revolution was the
fourth revolution looking at the so
called green revolution and the
development of GMO crops and so forth in
the agro tech business and I think we're
poised now for actually a fifth
agricultural revolution that's built on
identifying practices that build the
health of the soil as the foundation for
a sustainable agriculture not to abandon
modern technology but to essentially
integrate the best of modern technology
with the best of ancient wisdom and soil
husbandry in a new system of farming
that honors those three principles so
that's that's where I kind of ended up
in the growing revolution book is that
we've got an opportunity to rethink how
we look at the soil in agriculture and
that that's you know
a huge opportunity for Humanity the
century to try and get it right this
time
so what would you say to people on the
other side of the coin that maybe
looking at the future of agriculture
from the perspective of hydroponics and
nutrient solutions that are specifically
created for crops you know and in many
cases GMO crops moving it further and
further away from organics yeah you know
that's a sort of a big debate and I are
starting to gather data and to look at
some of those issues for the new book
that we're starting to work on on
relating soil health to human health so
everything I say will be provisional
until we dive in and sort out as much as
we can but Kay you based on the work
we've done in previous books you've got
to wonder about the you know if you're
growing plants in a non soil medium
you're just you're growing them either
really hydroponically or in a medium
that's not really soil where you just
have a like a sand or coconut fiber or
some substrate that's there to hold the
roots up and then you're adding
everything to the mix to grow your plant
what are you missing in terms of the
interaction of that plant with the
microbes in the root system of that
plant and and I'm sure tell you a lot
more about the the exudates the plants
push out into the soil and the things
the microbes make from them that the
plants take back up that shapes to fight
a chemical abundance and profile and
plants and them and their mineral
micronutrient concentrations their
nutrient density there's what we know
enough about the relationship of plants
to their microbiome their microbiology
and that surrounds them in the soil to
know that there's connections between
the state of the soil and what's getting
into plants and so if you then remove
soil from the equation or you remove
that life from the equation and you just
say add zinc or copper or whatever
micronutrients you want to add and just
the right proportions for your crop how
much are they taking up how much how
important was the role of soil life in
actually getting the plants to absorb
the
nutrients so there's questions there in
terms of what the basic effects are but
if you look at the problem of say like
growing on a lettuce in US in a city and
you look at it from an energetic
perspective if you're not if you're not
growing that plant in a soil where the
biology is doing a lot of the work of
nutrient acquisition and provisioning
and transport for you then you've got to
acquire those nutrients from somewhere
else and bring them to your hydroponic
system and add them and that may not be
energetically efficient for all
nutrients the beautiful thing about a
soil it is grabbing a lot of those
nutrients the life in the soil just
grabbing a lot of that in the
micronutrients out of the mineral
particles and recycling organic matter
and that's a difference a whole
different game than if you're just
adding you know a little chemical a
little chemical B into the mix that said
the flip side of looking at hydroponics
I think there's all kinds of interesting
opportunities for thinking about
microbial amendments and microbial
inoculants both for plants grown in the
soil and also and probably especially
for plants that are grown hydroponically
because without a soil there's going to
be different in terms of their their own
microbiome so you'd want to have some
kind of a compost tea or microbial
amendments and my suspicion is there's
an awful lot yet to be learned about how
to dial those kind of systems in for
either optimal optimal growing or
optimal you know phytochemical and
micronutrients of various crops we're
sort of in the early days of
understanding how those microbial
communities affect plants and a lot of
what the people in the wine business
referred to as terroir a lot of that is
probably shaped and influenced by the
microbial communities in the soil on the
skin of the grapes that get involved
that get involved in the fermentation
process there's a lot to still be
learned about how it all works yeah to
me it feels you know almost air
to think that we can create a nutrient
solution that can match what nature does
in the soil and we don't even know it's
we don't even know half the species in
the soil so yeah that we there's no way
that we can match it the quest I think
the real question is with the real
arrogance is that we could do better you
know that yeah they think that yeah it's
I'm with you on that I mean we know we
can grow a plant completely
hydroponically and completely control
that plant's life that's been
established and well accepted now can't
prove is that that plant is gonna offer
us the same nutritional benefits that we
would be getting from a plant that was
grown in you know in well made soil so
that's the reactor rigs actly and that
that's the kind of thing and I are
starting to Pokhara noses into and we'll
see how far we can get into that but
it's a fascinating area because we now
know enough about the science to know
that there's some very legitimate
questions like you're asking to ask and
there's probably not as much data as
anybody would like to have to answer
those questions which makes for an
interesting challenge in terms of
triangulation of you know what kind of
perspective and data can we bring in
from different kinds of studies to
develop a mature understanding of those
connections so that people could make
decisions about you know where they want
their food to be grown how they want
their wine to be grown how they want
their weed to be grown I mean there's I
think I think in the next in the coming
decade or two we'll see a lot more
people asking questions about all three
you know your your comment reminded me
of a book I've been reading
it's called proof I believe it's by Adam
price but essentially he talks in the
book about sort of the microbial
interactions that go on around alcohol
and how with some of these distilleries
these famous whiskey distilleries have
tried to recreate their their building
you know their whole infrastructure half
a mile away from the original facility
and they can't make the same whiskey
they can't get the same microbial you
know even that microclimate of microbial
life has that much effect on the crop or
they believe that they're the special
yeasts are living in the roof of their
buildings so they built another roof on
top of their roof when that roof started
to fail there's just it's so fascinating
to me how these microbes influence you
know influence our behavior and
influence our crops and influence oh
yeah sure and I know Ann isn't really
the one to speak to a lot of the
microbial stuff but you just made me
think of that as we were chatting ya
know it's me it's amazing
oh yeah we're and we're just becoming
aware of the magnitude of those impacts
and the influence of of not the kind of
ideas of you know there's like a
particular disease organism that causes
a particular disease though the whole
German Theory thing but how it's the
community of microbes for a lot of these
beneficial effects that matter and when
you think about how little how long it
took us to actually understand the
community ecology of the nature we can
see with our own senses I mean it took
us a hundred years to figure out that
taking the Wolves out of Yellowstone
cause the elk to over graze the riparian
zones which change the river morphology
and so if you wanted to restore the
river you had to bring wolves back you
know it took us a hundred years to
figure that out and we can see all the
animals and the plants and how they
interact and now the water flows so just
imagine how complicated it is to
understand that microbial community
ecology when we can't even see the damn
things so as someone listening in this
podcast who's cultivating cannabis they
may say who cares they're not eating the
crop in Joe I mean some of them are but
in general it's being you know combusted
or heated so the nutritional aspects of
the cannabis is probably less important
to them so why does this data and why do
your books matter I know I'm putting you
on the spot here from the from the
perspective of cultivation with cannabis
hello fair enough I don't mind being put
on the spot see I'm I think that one of
the connections there
you know if you're not relying on
cannabis as a mainstay of your diet
which I do not recommend if you're then
I can see how you know worrying about
say the micronutrient profile is not
going to be your biggest issue but if
you look at things like the various
terpene profiles the balance of CBDs and
THC in cannabis these are things that I
think that most growers probably think
that the biggest influence on those
things lies in the genetics of the plant
and there's been you know people
breeding cannabis back since I was in
high school in Northern California that
have been you know playing with how to
influence the expression of
characteristics in that crop but the
whole microbiome connection in the soil
is another dimension to what could
affect terpene profiles phytochemical
abundance which could translate into
either the the relative medicinal versus
psychoactive effects in case of THC and
CBD s or even more so I think in terms
of the flavor profiles and and sort of
the nature of the psychoactive effects
whether you've got something like mere
seen a lot of mere seen or limonene is
going to affect both flavor and effect
in cannabis and those things the
relative magnitude of phytochemicals are
things that should be influenced by
agronomic practices so you know the
style of hydroponic growing outdoor soil
sun-grown
you should see differences in the
expression of phytochemicals due to
those kinds of practices and so as a for
your listener who may be maybe a grower
I guess I would I would suggest is that
if they're thinking about this sort of
the genetic palette that they have to
work with us all the crosses and strains
and whatever that they have it there in
their their repertoire shall we say the
style of growing is another dimension
it's sort of a different access in terms
of how to influence the expression and
character of the product and think
there's a lot of room to experiment with
that that probably hasn't received as
much attention
in terms of the outcome as the science
that would that anti are familiar with
sort of would suggest that it might
warrant yeah that's a great answer and I
think that's a really important aspect
in fact I have some off to put you in
touch with a friend of mine he just got
some really amazing results down in
phantom farms in terms of their terpene
numbers being so much higher than what
you're normally seeing in the industry
and growing using you know living soils
and these organic practices I think
that's a really important task yep
definitely and that and that's exactly
what I think Ann and I would predict and
we'd love to communicate with that
person and get them and if they're
willing to share their data cuz we're in
the new book we want to have chapters on
you know grains vegetables wine grapes
and cannabis as sort of a wide range of
agronomic applications so assuming that
the listener to this podcast just
doesn't care about the environment
doesn't care about sustainability I mean
I don't think this is the case but even
even barring those thoughts and doesn't
care about organics what did you see
when you were writing growing revolution
in terms of pest and disease suppression
and some of these practices well there's
some really good examples now in nature
of studies that have looked at the
connection between a healthy living soil
in the sense of an organic matter rich
soil with a whole bunch of
microorganisms in it which is sort of
what healthy living soil is shorthand
for the there's a whole bunch of
examples where the defense the
interactions between the that microbiota
and the soil and the plants sort of
mediated through what's going out of and
back into their roots influence that
Center the defense system of the plant
and if you have a crop that is sort of
over fertilized and growing in
relatively sterile soil then you've
essentially dismantled its defensive
system which is in great part manifest
in its relationship with a soil
microbiome that makes chemical compounds
that the plant can take up and use for
its defense there's a lot of complicated
actions and synergies there that I that
an can probably talk with you about when
at length and on the hidden half because
that's at the heart of that book but the
key thing is that if you have plants
growing in a health in a life rich
fertile soil they're going to be more
robust and both pests and disease
resistant and those are experiments that
go back a hundred years in botany back
to Hiltner back in the what 1910 teens I
think it was where you know if you try
and grow plants in a sterile medium
they're very susceptible to pests and
pathogens you grow them in an organic
matter rich soil full of bacteria and
fungi the pests and pathogens can't
really get a seat at the table to attack
the plant they get out competed by all
the bent more less damaging or even more
beneficial organisms that thrive in the
root zone around plants so I think that
in terms of you know sort of net
expenditures on fertilizer net
expenditures on pesticides what I found
in conventional agriculture was that
farmers who had adopted practices rooted
around those three principles I talked
about earlier they were able to reduce
to so reduce their input costs their
need for pesticides their need for
fertilizers then it saved them a you
know a boatload of money interesting you
know this is something I might have
mentioned in previous podcast but it
made me think of it is I don't know if
you're familiar with the giant pumpkin
community but these guys the story of
what community the giant pumpkin
community this is a giant pump Jayant
pumpkins that's correct
that's what I thought you said there's
like what do you think so these guys are
as passionate as cannabis growers about
their crop they grow from seed to fruit
trying to get one the largest pumpkin
they can in a season and they're up I
think over 2,600 pounds now it's it's
insane but initially pumpkin yeah
initially they were they were sort of
stalling out right around a thousand
pounds and so by a combination and and
they were doing it mainly conventionally
they're using all your traditional
conventional things and just pumping
pumpkins full of nutrients and they're
getting split stems they were having
other issues and rot to where the
pumpkins weren't making it to the
weigh-ins or they stopped they stalled
out on they're growing and so they
started using organic practices again
like mycorrhizal fungus and comas and a
combination of you know improving
genetics and these practices this hybrid
approach of feeding small amounts of
chemical nutrients in conjunction with
organic practices and building their
soil has allowed him to reach these new
you know they never thought they'd break
the 2,000 pound barrier you know even
five six years ago so it's really it's
right now time a long way and I think
that that's a lot of the future of
Agriculture's maybe we're not going to
throw all chemical nutrients and
traditional agriculture away but find
ways to incorporate it back into our
organic practices in you know micro
doses
yeah the sort of the happy hybrid kind
of a way to look at it where you know I
was up you know blissfully unaware of
the giant pumpkin community um let me
but that sounds like a really
interesting story I might be interested
in digging more into the but a number of
the farmers I interviewed and growing a
revolution there were conventional
farmers who had so reduced their input
use based on improving the fertility of
their soil that I started teasing them
that they were organic ish farmers and
they had better yields than their
neighbors they had much lower expenses
of their neighbors it was it seemed to
me to be a really positive combination
and you know and they were not fully
organic they had basically done what you
just described of trying to take some of
the best features of organic agriculture
and reserving the ability or the right
as some of them put it to use other
means some of that some of the chemicals
that they've come to rely on when they
thought they really needed them but the
more they improved their soils I found
the less they needed them and they were
happy not to buy it that reliance on
petrochemicals too is obviously a global
issue and global concern
there's yes there's a lot of motivation
there to move away from them so I'm can
you talk a little bit more than about
the this idea of organic so as you went
around are you seeing this as sort of
like you mentioned this next revolution
do you really think this is the future
of Agriculture or do you think as
speculation is society are we going to
hit a point where conventional
agriculture just no longer functions you
know if we go there's a report that came
out in 2015 from the United Nations
called the global state of the soil
report assessment I think it was called
and they basically maintained in that
report that we're losing about 0.3
percent of our agronomic production
capacity globally each and every year
due to ongoing soil degradation and loss
and you know point three percent is kind
of a small number unless you think out
over the next 50 or 100 years and then
it's another 50 to 15 to 30 percent of
global agricultural capacity reduced we
if we maintain farming practices that
continue to degrade the land that we
depend on to grow our food we're gonna
get in trouble down the road that's the
story of ancient societies I laid out in
the dirt book what I'm really happy
about is that a lot of these soil
building practices if they were adopted
more widely could reverse that and turn
it around in shockingly short order in
the way that a geologist thinks about
things we could actually turn it around
this century we could pull it out of the
fire but it would require thinking
differently about how we farm on our
conventional cropland but I think
there's a lot of opportunities to do
that whether we'll do it I don't know
there's a some fairly large and obvious
interests that would prefer we maintain
that what we now call conventional
agriculture because there's some very
profitable industries that are built up
around that that aren't necessarily on
farm but are involved in selling farmers
things and buying things from farmers
it's one of the big I think big
environmental issues of our time that
doesn't get anywhere near the attention
that it deserves
but I don't see the downside of trying
to restore health and and fertility to
the world's farmland soils are our
great-grandchildren are gonna need that
that soil in good shape to make their
living and I think if we can do it
profitably we should pursue that and
take whatever turn over there is in
terms of its impact on certain
industries in stride
yeah and we're losing soil too as our
population expands you know we're
asphalt yeah there are more and more of
it every day yeah yeah and that most
things are working in the wrong
direction against each other and so
we've got to figure out how to you know
sort of strike a balance I think between
what we've considered to be conventional
agriculture and organic agriculture in
terms of trying to make more more of
conventional agriculture this ort style
of organic agriculture that I argue
about and argue for in the book and
we've also got to sort of think about
how we going to grow food in cities near
where people are as more and more of us
or in cities and how do we grow all our
all our other crops as well from from
from wine to cannabis to took the fibers
that we wear yeah that's a it's not
anything we're gonna be able to solve
overnight for sure but it's good to know
there's people out there writing books
about it and encouraging people to you
know all these things like regenerative
agriculture agricultural practices you
know sourcing things locally I know you
have a garden at your at your house I
have a garden at my house oh yeah
it's important that people get in and
learn where their food comes from and I
think that that can't be emphasized
enough yep and there's you know if we
all if we all improve the soil in our
daily lives whether it's in our garden
or on our farm you know if everybody got
into doing that there's a shocking
amount of carbon that could be parked in
the ground in ways that benefit the
expression of phytochemicals and
micronutrients in our crops that just
benefit the fertility of the land it's
it's one of those things where if
everybody could do their own little
piece and their own little core
the world it would add up to a lot if
enough people did it you know you
brought up something that I'd wanted to
ask you about a little bit earlier so
the last topic I would have is when I
was talking about not less disturbance
of the soil I was really looking at it
from a carbon perspective can you
explain for listeners briefly the
importance of carbon and a little about
that cycle and and why it's it's such an
emphasis in regenerative agriculture
yeah sure um if you think about how
carbon works between the sort of the sky
and the earth plants are the middlemen
because plants through photosynthesis
grab carbon dioxide out of the
atmosphere and combine it with water
that they pull up through their roots to
make carbohydrates sugars the building
blocks of their bodies you know and they
give off oxygen in the process which is
good for us as well but in in building
their bodies they're grabbing carbon out
of the sky and so then once it's in a
plant's body it sits there over the life
of the plant unless that plant pushes
some of that carbon out of its roots
into the soil which they do some plants
will push you know 30 40 percent of the
carbon they capture from the sky out to
their roots into the soil and they do it
in the form of sugars and proteins and
things we might think of as food because
they're feeding microbes in the soil
that do things in return for them that
annal talk with you a lot about but that
basically when those microbes in the
soil die their bodies are rich in carbon
and in nitrogen and phosphorus and all
the other micronutrients that form
living things that form the constituents
of the bodies of plants and and and
microbes and so once that that that once
living material that becomes dead it's
then organic matter and organic matter
the carbon rich compounds that were once
living that's food for microorganisms
that break that down and particularly
you know saprophytic fungi things that
eat dead things they break down that
once living organic matter and reduce it
to it's sort of its elemental
constituents and tend to transform it
into forms that can be taken back up by
the next generation of plants
so you can think of it as a full cycle
we're living organisms our decay and
recycled into the the ingredients that
are used to build the next generation of
living things and if those if the
recycling function in the soil wasn't
working it wouldn't take all that long
for you know this world to be buried
under dead things if nothing broke down
so it's it's a good thing that system
works so now again I forgotten where you
started with it on the question so we
need carbon in our soils oh yeah so you
can think of carbon as the fuel that's
feeding the microbes that's helping to
drive the back half of the circle of
life and that is helping to get mineral
micronutrients out of the soil so you
can you can literally think of sort of
the organic matter content or the carbon
content because you know organic matter
is roughly half carbon so the more
organic matter the more carbon the more
carbon the more organic matter you can
literally think of it that carbon
content of the soil is sort of a measure
of the biological batteries that are in
the soil if you have a lot of organic
matter and a lot of life in the soil the
cycling of nutrients and nutrition and
the per in the acquisition from fresh
mineral particles will just be running
faster because that that that's what the
Easter the what the ever-ready Bunny of
the soil is just gonna be working mat
them it's faster and when you run out of
organic matter you're just drawing down
that battery and he's bitten hitting the
drum slower and slower and slower so
that's why biochar or Terra Preta
from back in the Amazon rainforest was
so effective as a way of improving soil
fertility well that's that's part of it
there's um because there's what biochar
is is if you take organic matter and you
combust it in a low oxygen environment
it becomes charcoal and a lot of the
volatiles are driven off of it in the
process but there's still some and
depending on what temperature you make
it at and what you're making out of in
the first place there can be elements in
it that microbes can scavenge for food
in addition to just the raw carbon
matrix but one of the real
things that I think the biochar does in
the soil isn't so much the direct
fertility boost from it but it's that it
increases the water holding capacity of
the soil charcoal is really good at
holding water and I like to think of it
as as habitat for microbes so some of
the farmers that I visited in Central
America for example down in Costa Rica
we're using biochar to restore fertility
to their land but they were taking the
biochar and then inoculating it with a
compost tea that they made from the
mycorrhizal fungi that they would get
from the native forest from out in the
jungle and so you basically think of
biochars habitat for organisms they were
populating that habitat with with fungi
and bacteria out of the native forests
mixing with other biochar then
integrating that into their fields and
they're essentially cultivating the
beneficial life in the soil to help
break down the organic matter that they
would leave on their fields and feed
their next generation crop that's really
interesting so just to keep this I feel
like we can talk on these topics forever
I really enjoyed chatting with you is
there anything else though that you want
to cover before we sign off in regards
to your books or some of the history of
soil and how it might relate to cannabis
cultivation oh boy well you know one one
thing if you think about how to restore
soil I haven't really seen anybody write
or talk much about about this next point
but I'll just bring it up because it
crossed my mind if you think about how
it is that you would sort of boost the
organic matter content of the soil what
you want to get is organic biomass and
fiber into the soil and there's a
parallel with the human gut that and
I'll talk to you about with with the
hidden half of nature but if you know
but hemp is one of the great crops for
fiber that's why we used to make rope
out of it after all and so if we're
thinking about you know cover crops to
boost the organic matter content and
fertility of soils getting hemp into the
crop rotations
and then using you know some of that
biomass as microbe food in soils is not
a bad idea I
my initial dot on that my one concern
would be that your the species may be a
little too closely related and you may
end up with pest problems but I don't
know of any well but do you know what
but what but what if we put it in
cornfields and put in soybean fields oh
the hemp
yeah yeah no grass I was thinking of it
as a rotation with a cannabis crop no
what I would that I said you know my
recommendation I haven't thought that
that deeply about cannabis cultivation
because I don't have any experience with
it and I have a brown thumb I can kill
any plant you give me and it's the guard
and as the gardener in our household she
may give you better advice but in terms
of getting diversity into rotations with
cannabis I'd encourage farmers to think
about if you're growing outside think
about planting other plants in between
your crops don't leave the bound the
ground bare don't let it look manicured
intentionally plant what you might
otherwise call weeds pardon the pun in
between your cash crop in ways that
would you think of as green manure and
for for indoor operations I mean maybe
you grow a low-rise crop in the soil
around the cash crop get diversity into
the soils by having mixes of low-rise
crops I think that the in terms of the
pest resistance and disease resistance
it might be well worth experimenting
with yeah I see a lot of people running
cover crops with their cannabis crops
now that's that's becoming more and more
common i Pro good good so it's already
been thought of oh man cannabis farmers
are very good at experimenting and
trying new things they're definitely a
cutting edge in that regard which is
which is why it makes it so much fun
that being said I personally on indoor
facilities haven't seen a lot of people
pull that off on scale successfully but
I know they're people there are people
out there doing it I worry about it as a
habitat for pests and disease because we
do have such a mono cropping called
and we don't have yeah we don't have
that diversity of insect life that we
have outdoors because it is limited so
the pests they make it in but that
predator and other diversity may not
well what what why don't people actually
like you know release predators inside
their operations oh that's a thing -
yeah we definitely have a lot of people
doing beneficial insects I had a couple
podcast yeah already so that's another I
think that's the nature of agriculture
in a lot of ways as we move away from
pesticides
yeah the examples I've seen on sort of
conventional farms that have gone to
biological pest management have been
very successful there's a guy named
Jonathan Lundgren at blue Dasher farms
in South Dakota if any of your listeners
are want to follow up on this stuff go
to his website and check out what he's
been doing in the research he's been
doing on alternative means of pest
control it's really impressive but yeah
but if people are interested in in our
books and we've got the dirty rows in
the civilization's book that I wrote the
hidden half of nature that Anne and I
wrote and then growing a revolution the
new book about regenerative agriculture
those you know they're available at any
bookstore we have a website that is dig
to grow calm dig the number to grow calm
and we're active on Twitter we're at dig
the number to grow and you know people
can reach us via our website if they're
interested and obviously we recommend
the books growing revolution was a
finalist for the EO Wilson literary
science writing prize this year so
there's some um there's been getting
good reviews
yeah I'm staring at my autographed copy
right now and the hidden half of nature
I got on audible so I can listen to it
as an audiobook when I'm driving around
and doing other things so there's
definitely I definitely recommend the
books and I will put all the resources
up on the podcast page for listeners
after the podcast goes live so Dave I
really appreciate you taking the time
today to chat I know you're busy you're
over there teaching it well my favorite
school so I wish you the best and thanks
again alright thanks Todd I enjoyed
talking to you take care
that was David Montgomery geologist
professor
an author of numerous books notably dirt
the hidden half of nature and growing a
revolution bringing our soil back to
life you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget
that there's more information and
articles available on our website and
blog at WWF as well as links to the data
and information we discussed in this
episode on the podcast page and if you
enjoy these podcasts please take a
moment to leave me a rating and review
on iTunes and send me your feedback and
suggestions to our website contact page
or ta d at kiss organics com thanks for
listening
[Music]