[Music]
Welcome to the Cannabis Cultivation and
Science podcast. I'm your host, Tad
Hussy of Kiss Organics. This is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and draw top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge. Before starting
the podcast, I wanted to share about an
exciting new conference that we are
hosting in conjunction with Collective
Elevation in Bosezeman, Montana. I've
been talking to Suzanne Wayright Evans,
the bug lady, about hosting a conference
for years, and Adam at Collective
graciously offered to open up his doors
and let us host it on his property. The
event is happening September 5th through
the 7th, 2025. And I'm super excited. We
are kicking it off with workshops from
the bug lady Suzanne and Dr. Nadia Saba,
also known as Dr. Greenhouse, followed
by a facility tour and then a bunch of
excellent speakers and networking events
over the next three days. Then on the
7th, the Montana Living Soil Alliance is
hosting a tasting event that will be
included in the price of the conference
ticket. The tasting event will be a
private event with cannabis donated by
the Living Soil Alliance as a way to
have an amazing sensory experience and
see what premium quality Montana Living
soil has to offer. Tickets are limited
to 200 spots, so be sure to grab a
ticket if you're interested. The tickets
are now on sale at
kisorganics.com and the conference is
called the Cannabis Cultivation and
Science Conference. In honor of the
conference, I wanted to do an interview
series with some of the amazing folks at
Collective Elevation to give a grower's
perspective and share some of what
they've been able to accomplish. I've
already had Adam Arnold on the podcast
and you can view also view a tour of
their facility at the Kiss Organics
YouTube
page. My guest this week is Jared
Ferguson, the greenhouse manager at
Collective Elevation. He's been at
Collective for over four years now, but
prior to that, he studied environmental
horiculture at Montana State University
in Bosezeman, during which he worked for
the university's greenhouse facility and
research farm, where he got his first
experiences in mixing soil, amending
plants, managing irrigation, and
conducting IPM processes. Now, on to the
show. Jared, thanks for coming on the
show. Yeah, no problem. Thank you for
having me, Ted.
Yeah. So, you uh you've been with
Collective Elevation for a little while
now and you are the fertility uh
manager. I don't What is your exact
title? Uh greenhouse manager is what
I've been going with and no one's told
me no, so I going with that. Um yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I do the uh fertility
management and kind of the irrigation
management and basically just uh taking
care of the green houses once we got
plants in there through their veg cycle
and uh flower cycle.
Yes. And as you know, irrigation and
fertility are tied very closely
together. Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Can you just
tell me a little bit about your
experiences and what you've learned uh
since starting here at Collective?
Yeah, I've learned a ton. Um, so I came
from uh the academic background. So I
went to school at Montana State
University, got a horiculture degree
there. Um, and kind of the biggest thing
from transitioning from that over to
here was just kind of figuring out how
to take the big picture ideas of soil
fertility and doing your soil math and
everything from kind of a turf grass
management perspective like large scale
agriculture, vegetable farms, kind of
figuring out how to combine all of that
to a system that's going to work good in
a soilless media in a greenhouse. Um, so
yeah, I learned a lot specifically when
I initially trans transitioned over just
um about the plant itself because I
hadn't really worked with cannabis
before. So learning photo periods, all
that stuff. Um, yeah, and then from then
on just kind of dialing in the nutrient
program over time after I I kind of gone
through and figured out how I wanted to
be doing the soil math. Um, slowly kind
of figuring out what works best for us
in our our green houses because
obviously every growing system is a
little bit different. So figuring out
like how to adapt what I learned through
other people for our specific situation.
Um yeah, I was able to do the uh the
soil doctor cons uh his soil fertility
course um a few years ago and that was
super helpful just kind of like giving
me a a path to kind of figure out how to
bridge that gap there. But yeah,
yeah, Bryant Bryant Mason's course is a
good resource for people who are
interested in learning how to do their
own soil fertility. Um, it's well it's
well worth it. We do actually. Yeah. No,
it was
Oh, I was just going to throw out a
shameless plug. If you type in Kiss
Organics, all one word, I think you get
a discount on it, too. So, um, there is
that. But, uh, yeah, getting back to it.
So, when you when you first got here,
how were how were you guys managing
fertility in the green houses?
Um, so when I initially started, um, I
got hired on as an assistant kind of to
start out. Um, and then we had a
fertility manager who was kind of
transitioning out at that point. Um, he
had his own method of kind of doing
things. I think he was using the soil
doctor class as well as kind of a guide
as far as our targets and everything go.
Um, and so we had kind of that like
framework that we were using, but we
were really once he left, we were kind
of basically taking old soil amendment
plans that he had created and still soil
testing and everything and like looking
at those with their the soil test they
were referencing. Um, and then kind of
using our current soil tests and kind of
trying to extrapolate off of that and
figure out like, okay, well, he did this
for this case, so how do we adjust that
for our current situation? Um there was
a period where we were kind of we're
using a fertilizer mix and so we were
just kind of broadly targeting all
nutrients making sure we had fertility
in every area there. Um which was good
for a while but I do feel like it ended
up with us kind of adding too much. We
were getting into situations where we
had high sulfur or high magnesium and we
didn't have a way to with this mix to
apply nitrogen without also adding that
in. So from then we kind of started to
transition. My first summer was about
like that where we were doing the using
the fertilizer mix and kind of
extrapolating old data. And then going
into the winter I was able to go through
that course and with that just kind of
figure out how to start targeting
specific nutrients. Um and from there
figuring out how to bridge the gap with
my soil math to make it match up for
what I want to be doing for like a
soilless media because obviously there's
huge differences between the soilless
media versus an actual soil outdoors.
And so figuring out what I need to take
into account, disregard and stuff for
our uh container grown plants. Um at one
point we
did we sent some soil tests off to both
you and the soil doctor and I kind of
did my own like amendment plan for it
and then compared them with the two and
was like, "Okay, well I'm not 100%
accurate, but I'm not super far off." So
use that to kind of double check some
work and everything and keep like
building up from there. Um, yeah. And
that was about the that's kind of the
initial stage.
Yeah. So, uh, for people who are
unfamiliar, uh, I just want to back up
on a couple things and state that, yeah,
Collective Elevation, if you want to see
the facility that we're talking about,
there is a YouTube tour on our Kiss
Organics YouTube channel that people can
go back and watch. And then uh, this a
lot of the soil that you have is our
commercial growers mix. That's what was
in the beds. But you guys got that in
years ago now. Yes. I think even before
you were at Collective, so it's really
your soil at this point. Yeah. Yeah. It
was about right when I started. We were
um so we had two Nexus green houses that
have had soil in them for about I think
it's about seven years old at this
point. It's very old soil. Um that was
prekiss soil. Um I think they mix that
up themselves. Um, and then as I started
that summer, we were building out our
NextG facilities, and those are the ones
that we filled with the Kiss soil. So,
those were kind of my first fall here
was my first uh cycle through with Kiss
soil. Um, but yeah, and so even within
that, it's really cool to see just
like wide differences between the two
soils. Um, and even between the green
houses with that kiss soil in it because
over time we just get through
microclimates and everything within the
greenhouse, we start to just see
different trends based off which our
north greenhouse versus our south
greenhouse with how they're lined up.
Um, a lot of small microclimates within
the green houses themselves just in the
beds and everything and kind of like
getting to spend the time in there to be
able to observe that and actually notice
it has been super super helpful. And
then we've started to kind of tailor
each amendment plan towards each
greenhouse and then our season and
everything as well.
That's that's really interesting. Um
yeah, so one thing that when you when
you mention soilless media being
different than actual soil, what you're
referencing is actually this kiss soil.
So what we're calling living soil
indoors is not actual soil. It doesn't
have sand, salt, and clay. Yes. In it.
Yes, it's it what aronomists would call
soilless media. I just in case people
are confusing the the terminology
because it is confusing. Um I just
wanted to add that. But uh I want to ask
you so you mentioned that you're soil
testing. What does that actually look
like in reality? Like take me through
when in the cycle you take those tests,
when you get them back, and then how you
use that interpretation in your as a
guidance for what you're doing. Yeah.
Um, so as far as the timing on it, we're
taking it about day 56 of flower is kind
of the latest I can take it and still
get them back reason in reasonable
enough time for us to do our amendment
before our next cycle. So it's hard
because obviously I' I'd rather wait
later, take them right at the end of the
cycle. But um, being commercial
production, we kind of got to keep that
going. So obviously they're a little
less accurate with taking them earlier.
But um, that process itself is we have a
soil core probe thing that we're taking
the test with. Um, I'm taking I usually
go about every 8 ft in a room. I'll take
a sample. Your your soil test is only as
good as your sample is representative of
your room. So, trying to get the most
representative sample as I can, which is
obviously you're never going to get that
unless you tested the entirety of your
soil volume, but making sure that I'm
taking a wide range of tests from all
over in the greenhouse so that I can
have as as representative of a sample as
possible. Um, sending those off to Logan
Labs. Great lab. um usually get our
results back super quickly and
everything from them and I just like the
layout of their how they uh present the
data and everything on it. We are
typically doing I think it's their
complete test but it is a standard mic 3
soil test a saturated pace test where
we're sending our own water in with it
um and then they give us like our
micronutrients and like our silica and
our nitrate numbers and everything on
that as well.
Yeah. And one thing that I've noticed,
and I've talked to Bryant about this,
uh, is we've had guys test every bed
individually and then also test the
entire room, you know, maybe so maybe
like 20 tests as composed of like one
composite test that's that's mixed of
all those and they all tend to be fairly
similar unless we have like one real
outlier bed. Uh, has your experience
sort of agreed with that? And how many
tests do you do per greenhouse? How big
approximately is your greenhouse? So,
we're doing composite tests with them.
In the past, we have done individual
beds and sent those off and we kind of
found the same thing where we were like
within 10 to 20% at the most difference
between beds. And it really is would be
like we're testing a bed that is
absolutely getting less light versus one
that gets a ton of light. And that's
where we're seeing like the slight
differences. Um, so for the most part,
we're sending off a composite sample for
our green houses. Um, so we have four
houses altogether. I don't know the
exact square footage of the house
itself, but we have in our smaller ones,
we have four rows of what is it? 84 feet
by 4 feet wide by about 2 feet deep. Um,
and then in our larger green houses, we
have six rows of 88 feet at about a foot
and a half deep probably. So, a little
bit different volume there. Um, yeah.
Yeah. And so you found that one test
gives you a pretty good idea of what's
going on in the room. And that saves a
ton of money as a grower. So if you are
thinking about going this route, don't
feel like you have to test every bed.
Yeah. You don't. Yeah. No, I think it
gives you a pretty good composite. And I
would say if you if you feel like you
have something going on in the room,
like if there's a bed that's wildly
behaving differently than others, then
you can look into that. And then at that
point, tissue testing as well, just to
know what's going on inside your plants.
Actually, um, we tissue test
periodically. We don't do it every
single round. It's something I'd like to
do every single round, but at a certain
point, you're you got to balance the how
much data are we getting and using um
kind of there. But, uh yeah, the tissue
testing can be really helpful if you're
in a situation like that. Um and in the
past, we've done that. Typically, when
we have a greenhouse where it's like
something seems off, we'll do that and
it's usually been pretty representative
of what our saturated pace test is kind
of reading. Um, as long as you are
getting adequate or getting not just
adequate water, but getting a good
watering program to where your plants
are able to take up those plant
available nutrients that you're seeing
in that saturated paste test, it's
usually pretty representative.
Yeah, that's a that's a great point
touching on the watering. I will just
add one note that taking one test for a
room is sort of predicated on the idea
that you're treating all the beds
exactly the same. So if you start
amending all the beds individually
different, I think then you're kind of
forcing your hand into having to test
them all. Exactly. Yeah.
Um but how does how does water play a
role in
um well I mean I was going to say how
does water play a role in terms of
nutrient availability but I know that's
kind of a obvious one. Um, how do you
have a real life example though of how
uh irrigation changes have impacted
available fertility in your beds where
maybe you had sufficient fertility but
it was too cold or you weren't watering
properly? Um, yeah. So, just with the
the microclimates kind of in the
greenhouse in general. Um, our nexus
green houses we have they are east to
west facing the east end of the wall
gets shaded out in the morning time.
There is a solid like about six foot
section of that bed that gets
considerably less light for the first
few hours of the day in those beds which
again I guess this isn't just directly
water and that's also bringing light
into account but in those beds they are
they always are holding water like those
sections are holding water significantly
longer than the rest of the bed itself
and just that row. Um and with those we
will see a lot more kind of towards the
end of flowering like plants that look
not as far along as the rest of the row.
So plants that don't look as developed,
they maybe are still a little too dark
green. They almost look like they have
too much nitrogen at the time, they
haven't been like processing as much
because they just haven't been taking up
as much water due to not having as much
light and also just um and just having a
more saturated environment around them.
Um and then we've also seen the case too
where with underwatering as well, you
kind of develop those same
like things that look like nutrient
deficiencies, but the soil itself might
not be deficient. the plant is just not
getting it because you don't have the
proper environment around the plant for
it to uptake those nutrients. Um, we
kind of see that just seasonal
differences. We have areas in the
summertime that just get blasted by
sunlight and they are like at least a
touchup water almost every day and then
down to the winter time we have rooms
sometimes where we'll go like four days
without watering it. So, it just really
is there's a lot of huge seasonal
variability here. Um, and that's kind of
the best representation
of how water and water like uh
availability kind of plays a role in
that. So you're not treating the whole
greenhouse uh the exact same way when it
comes to irrigation. You're basing it on
Yeah. the beds. And how are you
measuring that? So we measure both
through we have a uh a blue lab um pulse
which does volutric water content. We
that's not our main source. We use um
the arometer probes uh the tensometers
um and so we use those. I feel like that
gives us a more accurate kind of idea of
what the plant itself is going through
because uh the volutric water content is
great but the number kind of if you're
doing a certain number dryback on that
it's really only applicable to that
specific room that you found that number
is like a good one for. Um once you
start looking at because we do have
different soils in different rooms,
let's say 15% dryback in some of our
zones is a lot different stress than 15%
dryback would be in some other ones just
because we have older soils, smaller
pore space. It's holding on to that
water a lot more. So it might have the
same volutric water content, but that um
the tension that it actually takes the
roots to pull that in is a lot more and
it's a lot more just osmotic stress on
the roots. Um but yeah, this the main
way we're going about it is using um we
have barometers in every greenhouse um
kind of checking those and watering
based off of uh certain kpa numbers. And
now we are transitioning into where
we're going to start testing out some
volutric water content probes that we'll
bury in the beds as well. And then kind
of the process with that is going to be
putting a a probe in the bed and then
also putting an arometer next to it,
watching what finding out what 20 kpa on
our arometer actually is as far as
dryback for our plants and kind of
adjusting our numbers based off that for
each room specifically rather than just
the whole grow. Yeah, that's very cool.
Very cool. And I like the way you
explained that. Um that's a very good
point. I I like the blue lab pulse
meter. I mean, we sell them at Kiss. I I
think they're a really cool tool. They
give you a very fast number and I like
that I can correlate a photo in the app
with the moisture notes and everything
too. Yeah. But I totally agree the
arometers are going to be more accurate.
And I just want to highlight where you
said you can't take the same percentage
on that um volutric reading on the pulse
lab the pulse meter and uh use it across
different media. Um
and expect to get the same results I
guess. Yeah, that that was a really good
point. So, thanks for having Yeah. Yeah,
for sure. One other thing that you
mentioned around your when you time your
soil test that I wanted to add because I
happen to just know this that you guys
keep all the amendments that you use on
site so that when you go to remend, you
don't have to place an order with a
company to like or run somewhere to go
get these amendments. You have them all
on on site and ready to go. So, once you
get results back, you can amend right
away. Yeah. And uh yeah, we basically we
have half a fertilizer store essentially
in our pole barn. Um I maybe have gone a
little crazy in my ordering in the past
and gotten really hyped about some
specific nutrients and ordered a lot of
them and then realized I didn't need
that much. So what are your what are
your go-tos and what do you see yourself
using? I guess the same question. What
do you using the most your in terms of
your favorite amendments and I guess
trends in your soul fertility uh
amendments?
So, um, it's developed, it's changed a
lot since over the last few years, just
as I'm kind of figuring more stuff out.
Um, my main kind of idea is I want to
have for every nutrient we have, I want
to have a two different sources for it
if I can. That way, like say calcium for
example, if I'm only feeding gypsum and
I'm also feeding potassium sulfate and
maybe magnesium sulfate, I'm probably
going to get too high a sulfur at some
point. So, making sure I also have like
something like an axill so that I can
switch off or not an axil, a glassite
for for the calcium so I can switch off
and like add calcium in a different form
and kind of not take anything out of out
of where I want it to be just to get
other nutrients in there. Um, I would
say as far as historically our main
amendments have been we've used a lot of
fish meal, soybean meal, insect frra,
gypsum, sulfate of pot ash um as like
rock dust as well as a more recently um
kind of currently right now we're
shifting some of our nitrogen toward
using uh blood meal feathermeal as kind
of our main nitrogen sources just so we
have that like
standalone 1300 rather than having the
phosphorus or the potassium attached to
it. Um, and the thing I'm playing with
right now that I'm really excited about
is I'm kind of trying
to I'm taking my nitrogen goal and I'm
breaking it up into portions with
different breakdown rates for my
fertilizer. So, I'm doing like a 25%
portion of kind of a blood meal, which
is a quicker breakdown so that they have
it more more available earlier. Then
like the middle section, I'm doing like
a moderate breakdown at about 50% of our
nitrogen goal and then a slow breakdown
as the last like 25%. So we're getting
like kind of a broad spectrum of
different nitrogen sources in there
that'll be available at different times
as the plant needs it too. So kind of
trying to frontload our nitrogen
availability a bit, but then also have
enough for them to taper through their
cycle without like plummeting down to
like 10 ppm or something like that.
Yeah, nitrogen is definitely the
trickiest uh mineral to manage because a
huge pool of what our nitrogen is in in
these soils or in soil in general is
organic nitrogen which you can't really
see on these tests. So, um yeah. Yeah,
nitrogen is all a little bit guessing
game and I totally agree with you. Uh we
always with our recommendations want to
have at least two to three sources of
nitrogen. I really like organic alalfa
meal even though it's not a big nitrogen
source. I just think it has a lot of
good like microbial benefits and other
things that it does that uh I like to
use it. But um yeah, that's that's
that's a really good point that you
brought up around having multiple
sources for different different
amendments.
Yeah, we definitely went through a phase
where we used a lot of alalfa meal. Um
and I I use it in all our tees and
everything as part of that recipe and
when we do do some like supplemental
feedings throughout the cycle, I'll use
it there. Um but yeah, as you were
saying, it's really really really low
nitrogen percentage, but you do get
carbon from it. Um it's a very good
carbon source and everything and just
organic source for the plants. Um yeah,
and we've used a lot of kelp meal as
well. There's we've used basically most
of the organic inputs you can think of.
We have a few bags of them out there. So
um yeah, kind of gone through a lot of
different sources. We walin's one that
we've been using a lot more recently
just because we were getting high sulfur
in some green houses and I was like all
right I need to figure out how to go
around this and not keep adding sulfur
because at at a certain point you're
just creating osmotic stress for your
plants and it's just going to create a
more stressful environment for them and
we want to we have enough other
stressors that I want to try to limit as
much of that as possible on my end. Um
it's hard to kind of use stress to like
try to do crop steering if they're
always stressed. So trying to figure out
how to yeah keep them in a good spot and
make sure that again whatever I'm
amending I've got multiple options so I
can really kind of per soil test kind of
customize what we're doing each time.
Yeah, sulfur is an interesting one
because uh typically I find with our
soil tests is we tend to range more
alkaline because of the our in a lot of
our inputs are cat ions. you know, we're
using a lot of calcium, a lot of
potassium. Um, and so we we tend to push
the pH tends to be high. So, the sulfur
really helps balance that. But what and
we don't really see any issues with
sulfur toxicities per se, but you you
brought up the big issue with sulfur,
which is um essentially when you have
very excessive levels, you know, and
I've seen thousands of ppm of sulfur on
soil tests, what what can happen is uh
your soluble salt, the EC of your soil
becomes higher and then it's harder for
the plant to essentially acquire those
nutrients because of the osmotic
pressure around the roots. So, um, yeah,
just wanted to further explain what you
were talking about because I think
that's a really fascinating concept. So,
as as a soil, uh, you know, fertility
manager, you're always doing this dance
of balance with your nutrients.
Um, that being said, something that that
uh Bryant always said that I really
appreciate and I take the same
philosophy is we always start with I
always start with sufficiency and then
balance. What has sort of been your
approach with with this whole process? I
would say very similar as well like
um taking into account both the
saturated and the standard tests um
trying to make sure that we have
obviously sufficient available nutrients
to the plants but then making sure that
we're in a situation where if I am
wildly out of whack on my cat ions like
if my ratios are not down in there if I
have like nuclear high which this hasn't
happened too much but um if I have out
of whack like calcium or anything like
that where it's kind of sitting high as
in as far as like our ratios of the rest
of the cat ions. It maybe makes me kind
of pause for a second about adding to
try to up my saturated pace test because
if we are at a high situation there then
we do have it in the soil. It's just
about getting it um plant plant plant
available and like uh mineralized over
and everything or demineralized.
Um, yeah. So, it's definitely kind of
sufficiency first is
the main idea and then without
completely like disregarding what's
going on in our standard test and making
sure we're not getting into a situation
where we're going to run into issues
with nutrients being tied up and not
become plant available. Um, yeah.
Nice. Nice. And uh do you have any
examples of where you saw something on a
soil test that was then reflected in the
plant that you were able to address or
correct in a way that increased yields
or fertility or plant health? High
nitrogen at harvest. I have definitely
put too much when I first started kind
of uh running the nutrient program.
There's a period where I was definitely
throwing too much nitrogen in there. Um,
we're seeing still plants that weren't
fully they're full not fully green, but
they were still a lot greener than we
wanted them to be at the end. Um, and
then coming back on our soil test around
like 50 ppm of nitrate at the end of it,
which isn't where I want to be. Um,
trying to shoot more towards ending at
like 20 to 30 has been what I've seen
like do really well for us. Um, and then
just kind of lowering that top end
nitrogen goal down a bit to try to ease
us into that lower finishing at that
lower area. Um, that's been a really big
thing in winter
specifically just because we go from
having such intense sunlight in the
summertime to when we're in January,
February here, if we got curtains closed
up, we're we're sitting maybe a little
bit under what we should be with light
by a few hundred PAR. Um, and so we're
definitely processing less nitrogen. And
so I I have to change my thinking for
sure on our summertime runs versus our
wintertime runs. And now I'm kind of uh
coming up with different sets of
parameters for the two of them. um
treating the summers a lot differently,
pushing more nitrogen, um kind of
pushing just more nutrients in general
because we're going to go through more
of them. And then in the winter time,
just having a really light hand there,
just like getting them up to what I feel
like sufficiency is and trying to just
write it out and watch the plants.
Yeah, I know Bryant has talked about how
nitrogen availability, especially
outdoors, is is tied fairly closely with
temp with soil temperature and in
indoors even, I would assume in your
green houses, it's a little bit colder
in the winter than it is in the summer
naturally. And so, you probably would
have less nitrogen cycling. And um you
know, we routinely see soil tests where
you're at, you know, one, two, three ppm
of nit nitrate at the end of the cycle.
And conversely, those plants, it's like
I I know you left some yield on the
table and definitely some plant health
because the plant completely ran out of
nitrogen. So, hitting that sweet spot,
which I'd agree with you, 20 30 ppm is a
great finishing spot for for nitrates.
Um it makes a huge difference in overall
yield.
Yes. Yeah. I know, like you said, it's
kind of like it's threading that needle
where it's um you have to find that
balance to where you're not ending too
completely
like just zapped out of nitrogen. Like
you have to end with a certain amount
still to where you're not getting you
don't ever or for me personally like I
don't ever want to see I want to see
actual natural scinessence from the
plants where they are fading because of
their age and because of their maturity
level, not yellowing out because they're
depleted of nitrogen towards the end of
their cycle. We've definitely had
periods of that too where it's like
intense sun and everything and they they
process through that nutrient quicker
than we maybe expected them to and we
start to see maybe instead of two weeks
before harvest where we start to see
color changes happen. We start to see
that happen three or four weeks before
like some yellowing start. Um and so
definitely figuring out over time like
my initial first year here we had a lot
of a lot of high nutrients, a lot of low
nutrients and it's just been trying to
slowly just bring that to balance. um
over time. But yeah,
that's very that's very uh honest of you
to admit that. Yeah, it was it's a
learning process for sure. And anyone
that's like, "Oh, I for sure know the
100% correct way to do this." is
probably projecting a bit. But yeah,
these soil tests are not always 100%
accurate, too. So, you kind of have to
take them with a grain of salt. And I
always like to air a little bit low
because you can always add more, but you
can't really take away. So, yeah. What
is your approach if you know you are
midcycle and you realize that you're low
in and we can just stay with nitrogen
just to keep it simple. Um what's your
approach to combating that?
So especially for midcycle it's very
very like I'm being very cautious with
how much I'm trying to add um through
that. We add a bit through te's and
stuff but it's it's a pretty small
amount so it's hard to account for too
much with that. Um but we've been more
recently we worked with uh David Peron
um and he kind of introduced us to this
like whole slurry method of applying
nutrients down. So more recently um over
the summertime we had been
applying just with water through a pump
and through a hose um some nitrogen
early into flower like the first week of
flower or so if we felt like we needed
it to kind of give them that bump. But
it's really hard. there's a really short
window where once you're into flower,
you got a few weeks to where you can
amend and not be too far along into it.
So, it's a really kind of delicate time
frame for the plants. Um, typically it's
been in the past before we started doing
the slurries, it was just kind of like
top dressing some fish meal and stuff.
But again, that's
like for me if if you're seeing if
you're seeing a deficiency and then
applying nutrients, it's almost too late
because for me, I feel like it's you're
waiting until you're seeing like kind of
the uh the negative side effect of not
having something before adjusting it.
And so, yeah, for the most part, I try
to stay like proactive rather than
reactive with that. But again, there's
the needle that you got to thread there.
Um, and then again, if you're top
dressing a nutrient, then it's you still
have to wait for that to break down,
become available to the plants. So,
there's still kind of even once you
amend, there's like a little few more
days at a minimum of time where it's
still not getting that yet. So, I think
the slurry has been really good as far
as just helping us kind of disperse our
nutrients a lot easier with a lot less
like manual labor put into it. Um, as
far as our like flips go, our in between
cycles, um, kind of a remend process
between cycles, we've taken that from
being like a four or five person job
that takes about the same amount of
hours down to a just me job that takes
about three hours. So, it's been really
helpful in that regard. Um, and then
obviously too kind of not exposing as
many people to the dust and everything
that comes off of these. Like even if
you're wearing good PPE and everything,
if you're exposing yourself to last
night and stuff like that on the
regular, it's not great for you. So
trying to kind of limit it's I'm
basically the only one working with
nutrients now. I know the proper PPE I
need to be wearing when I'm working with
them and everything. And so it's kind of
helped to simplify that a lot.
That's that's great. So what does what
does your process look like for
remending? Because you mentioned you you
top dress. Are you mixing the nutrients
into the soil when you remend or are you
top just top dressing them? How does the
slurry method describe that a little
more too and for people familiar? Yeah.
So, um, previous to using that method,
we were just kind of applying the
nutrients to the top of the soil and
then we would usually just kind of
like we just call it like a scratching
them in basically where we're kind of
trying to make sure we're not we're
getting them mixed in with the top three
inches of the soil layer. Um, about once
a year we usually take some soil out and
add some Pete Moss back in or something
and then we'll do like a more of a full
like kind of till at that point. But for
the most part, we were just scratching
into the top surface making sure we
weren't having things kind of cake up.
Um, with the slurry itself, it works
really good at kind of like dispersing
it on its own already. A lot of our
soluble nutrients just kind of get moved
throughout the soil. Um, and then
there's a lot less. We again basically
just come by and scratch it into that
first little top layer after doing the
slurry amendment. Um, but for the
process itself, it's kind of I get the
soil test back. Um, go through, analyze
them, obviously like look at, right, do
I need to leech these beds first off
before anything else? if I don't need a
leech or anything. If we're looking good
there, then it's looking at pH
adjustments or like soil structure
adjustments if we need to do anything
like adding any other media or anything
to it. Um, and then kind of going down
and just looking
at our obviously our macronutrients, our
NPK, looking at calcium, magnesium,
sulfur, and everything. Um, those are
the ones I'm like most focused on.
Obviously, those are the ones that have
the biggest impact. Um, really making
sure we sh up those holes.
Um, and also taking into account our
micronutrients and our trace minerals.
Those are just ones where I'm very wary
to make adjustments because you mess
that up and you mess the soil up. So,
um, Absolutely. Yeah. So, and then,
uh, kind of now what we've been doing
recently too is adding a bit of biochar
in between each round, adding some
compost in between each round to try to
just add a little more back into the
soil from what we're taking out
throughout that cycle.
Couple questions. So, uh, question
number one. If you're just scratching it
in and not, uh, you know, well, I guess
we'll use the word tilling because,
yeah, that's what people are familiar
with. Um,
what about the bulk density of the soil?
So, over time with water, with
everything, that soil is compressing
down. That's why when we, you know, if
you put soil out, fresh soil out in your
garden bed at the beginning of this
garden season, you come back out the end
and it's dropped four inches and you're
like, where did that soil go? it's it's
compressing in bulk density which limits
the amount of air and water that the
pore space essentially in that soil. Do
you find that to be an issue at all with
uh your method or just you get like an
annual reset? We so with that we do kind
of a once a year we pull some soil add
some Pete moss typically back in um add
some irration in if we feel like we need
it and stuff too and then we do a big
massive kind of full bed till that
usually helps up the soil volume just
from incorporating that air and
everything back into it and then we
definitely do see like a settling um for
the most part a lot of our like I'll use
zones one and two for example those are
the ones without the kiss soil those
ones have been processed so much that at
a certain point it almost looks like
we're just growing in worms castings.
So, we have a lot of kind of bigger pore
space in those. Um, we definitely do see
settling still and everything, but I
feel like we reset it on a quick enough
bas or on a regular enough basis to
where we're not getting too many issues
with large amount of compaction. Like,
we're still getting good root
penetration and everything. um still
getting good water penetration and
stuff, but it definitely it's definitely
not ideal obviously to have like that
that soil get super compact, but I feel
like we're kind of on a good schedule to
where
we're while balancing the amount of
labor we're putting into it and also
balancing kind of trying to not disturb
too much of the soil structure since we
do have a lot of fungus and everything
growing within our beds. Um I feel like
we're on a good middle ground of not
fully like no till, but not fully
complete till every time. So, kind of
trying to shoot that gap where it's
like do what's best for our soil
structure and balance out also our labor
costs and everything with it. And also
trying to uh give the soil time to
establish itself as kind of more of a
obviously it's not the same as an
outdoor soil but as more of an ecosystem
within itself. Yeah. No, that makes
sense. You don't want to disturb the
microorganisms. I know that's the big
reason people don't like to tilling or
soil disturbance on any level. So, and
I'm kind of I'm
like I'm in the middle on that because
I'm not sure like how much it it it
would take a lot of monitoring and
testing things to see how much that
actually messes with us. Like we would
have to not till some beds till some
beds and kind of see what happens over
time. I definitely feel like we get
better root penetration after we do our
big turn and everything and after we
lighten that soil up. Um, and I think
it's good too just as far as like the
stratification of our nutrients and
everything in there because you don't
want to get to the point where you have
if you don't till it ever you're going
to end up getting layers of nutrients
that are more and less mobile than the
other ones. And so I think it is good to
kind of just refresh the soil, mix that
all back up and kind of redisperse all
those nutrients as well.
Yeah, I mean I'm a big fan of soil
disturbance as you probably know. Um, so
we've t I've talked about it on this
podcast. Um, I think these microbes are
more resilient than people give them
credit for. I do as well. Yeah. But I I
see really happy plants in soil that is
grown in noil indoor beds as well as
soil that's been highly disturbed. So,
um, I think there's a lot of ways to
grow this plant. And, uh, I think you
kind of bridge a good gap there of of
kind of maybe addressing both ways. And
so now what you're doing, you're saying
is uh maybe less soil disturbance
because you're taking your soil
recommendations that you've you've set
based on your targets. You're taking
that, you know, fish meal gypsum last
night combo of inputs, putting them into
like a giant vat, uh agitating it, and
then essentially just putting it all out
with water in the form of a slurry over
those beds. Is that accurate? Yeah,
pretty accurate. Um, yeah. Yeah, that's
that's essentially the process. And and
through doing it, we've al obviously
like I've found something some nutrients
work better with it, some don't. Like if
I'm using soft rock phosphate, it's hard
to get that to not settle on the bottom.
Um there's definitely a carrying
capacity too for the size of the tanks
that we have and
um how many how much fertilizer we can
put in with a certain amount of water.
So it's like been finding that out. Um,
and again like like alpha alpha for
example, we ended up just a lot of it
would just kind of float to the top and
so then we wouldn't get very much. We
would get a lot of like what looked like
alphalfpha stems coming out initially
and then we would get no alphalfpha kind
of coming out for a while and then as
the tank emptied we'd start to get more
of the kind of lighter material. So kind
of going through that and figuring out
which which nutrients are better for it
and not. And there's some things that we
apply like dry still like I apply rock
dust um still just by like putting it
out dry and everything. And same with
like if I am using soft rock phosphate.
Um yeah. And so just kind of figuring
out it's not it's not a full it's not
like every single fertilizer is going to
work great with it. And obviously we
could probably do some of our heavier
amendments if we had less total
amendments in there with the water. Um
yeah, for the most part that's it's been
really helpful just being able to kind
of get that done a lot quicker. And
again, it's a I feel like it's a more
even process as long as we have the
appropriate agitation in our tanks. Um,
it's been a trial and error process of
just kind of figuring out it's like, all
right, do I need one pump, two pumps
during this? Which way do I need to
orient them and like all the little
things that go into that stuff?
Yeah. So, you kind of addressed a couple
of my questions like how do you some
things just aren't great to use with
this method and you have to plan
separately. So, that that was question
number one. Uh question number two was
sort of like you said you feel like it's
more even and in my head I was thinking
about well if you're only taking one
soil test then how would you know if
it's even or not for the you know
aggregate for the whole room you
wouldn't know if your fertility is even
but I've also seen your rooms and your
plants look very
uh evenly fertilized. I mean the they
look very homogeneous in terms of the
amount of fertility that they're
getting. I don't see like, oh, there's
still a ton of potassium here and none
over here based on plant response. So,
it must be working. Um, how do you
manage like uh how long do you water a
certain bed? Like, do you just go do you
count to five and then go to the next
bed and or next walk 10 steps or Yeah.
How do you get that part of an even flow
rate out onto the bed? So, just watching
we have a it's more just going by gallon
markers on the tanks themselves. Um, and
we're applying a lot. So, per row I'm
applying about 100 gallons of water
overall per row. Um, and those are the
84 foot rows to 88 foot depending on
which greenhouse we're in. Um, and so
typically just checking back in making
seeing where my numbers at on that and
everything. Um, and it definitely is not
uh it's not 100% like I know I got
exactly the same amount spread across
the whole room, but it's just about kind
of minimizing as much difference as we
can there. Um, yeah. And then just
making sure basically I'm going by the
gallon numbers. is I've got a pretty
consistent for the first two and a half
years for when I started here I was
handwatering everything and I got pretty
good pace down on my handwater whereas
like I move at about the same speed with
everything. So it's uh just kind of
keeping that same pace with it. Um
making sure you're trying to distribute
it as evenly as possible. Um yeah.
So you're you're just finishing up with
your tank right as you hit the end of
the row kind of at the the end of the
bed. Yep. at the end. Uh, so I I use
like one 250 galon or one 200-galon
tank. Um, it's 250 gallons, but I
usually fill it up to 200 per like two
beds or two rows essentially. And so I
can kind of do one up, one back on one
row, and then one up, one back on the
next row. And that's usually right about
at the end of the 200. And that saves
you a ton of time and labor. Tons. Yes.
Application. Awesome. Well, cool. Yeah,
that's a very handy tip that people can
experiment with. Yeah. Yeah, definitely
a lot of trial and error with it. Um, we
have to use a giant hose for it, so
that's that's one thing where if you try
to use a regular garden hose, I think
you'd get it get clogged up pretty
easily. So, yeah, just finding the right
equipment and everything. And then a
thing, we currently have like square
totes that we're doing it in. If I had
my my dream setup for it, it' probably
be a round tank just to help minimize
settling in corners and everything.
Yeah. Um, but yeah, it's it's it's
helped reduce a ton of labor.
Um, it's help and mostly for like the
rest of the cultivation crew, all the
guys that have to clean the greenhouse
right after they just got done
harvesting, got to pull root balls and
everything, that's already a very long
labor intensive process. So, if we can
take away days a day of packing
nutrients and tilling beds, that's
that's super helpful for them. Um, yeah,
so being able to take that kind of like
off their plates and then I I I like
having the control and it being able to
apply it myself because at least then if
something goes wrong, I did it. So, we
know we know what happened with it where
in the past we've had like had some hot
spots in beds where it's like some beds
are mixed really really well and then
you find a whole pile of gypsum in one
bed that's just barely under the soil
surface that's turned into a giant cake.
So, yeah, make it just as far as a
uniform application. Um, yeah, I feel
like it's really helpful.
Awesome. Awesome. Well, I really
appreciate your your time today. Was
there any other uh any other things you
wanted to chat about here?
for sure. Nothing that comes to mind too
much.
Um, yeah, I guess that's that's just
essentially kind of how the the process
has developed over time.
Um, see anything else with
that? No, I guess I think that kind of
covers it. We've um we've gone through
different iterations of what we've been
doing. We've gone through I think the
main thing is just
like trial and error is a very important
uh process of figuring out if you're
doing things right. And like we varied
all the way from like teeing, for
example, at one point we were teeing
once a week all the way down to only
four times a cycle. And so just like
figuring out having the freedom to be
able to like test different things and
see what's working best for you and
adjust it and not having kind of a like
don't be stuck to one thing is I think
the biggest thing that's been really
helpful for me. Um I feel like there's a
lot
of there's a lot in the cannabis
industry where it's like you have to do
this this way or you're entirely wrong.
Every single grow is different. There's
a thousand different ways to grow
plants. It all comes down to what is
aligning with you ethically, what aligns
with your business and everything. And
just um in your specific rooms
themselves because again, if you're
growing under in a room with HPS's
versus in a room with LEDs versus in a
greenhouse with natural sun, like those
are those by themselves, just light is
such a big change in environment that
there is going to be a whole domino
effect of everything else. So just
really having an open mind to kind of
tailoring your system to your specific
growth I think is really really
important and not being stuck on
specific ideas.
That did bring up two other questions
that I had I want to get in before you
sign off now. Uh you've brought up tease
a few times in this conversation. Can
you just explain uh what that means?
Yeah, so just a micro tea. So just um
essentially mixing we use a mix of worm
castings and uh compost mixing those
with water a food source we use molasses
so like a sugar source. I typically add
in some hydraulicate just to help with
kind of the bubbling and everything. Um
as well and food for the microbes as
well and then some kelp and alalfa. And
essentially the idea is we're taking the
microbes from our compost and from our
worm castings. We're giving them a food
source. We're airrating them in a liquid
to help them just reproduce kind of up
the concentration of how many microbes
we have in that tea and then we're
watering it into the into the beds to
help apply it into the beds to help
speed up our process of uh kind of
cycling our nutrients and everything and
make them more plant available. And
again, we've gone I'm not still not sure
what the right right ratio is to how
many you're doing throughout a cycle,
but we've gone everything from once a
week when I first started down to like
four times a cycle and just kind
of been messing with that and testing it
and seeing how we've also changed tea
recipes, but just uh messing with it and
seeing like what that affects in the
plants. Um yeah, so just basically
giving the plants a boost of microbes to
help kind of process those nutrients in
the soil a little quicker.
So, you're making uh airrated compost
tees. Yes. Yes. Yeah. Yeah. And uh
long-winded way of saying it. Yeah. No,
I people might not be familiar with the
term or the difference between that and
say a compost extract. I'm literally
staring at my microscope here. And uh
don't let me forget when I come out for
the conference, if I drive out in
September for the conference that we're
putting on at your facility, I will
bring my microscope and we can uh look
at the TE's and uh maybe make some make
some recipe adjustments at that point,
too. Yeah. See what's No, that'd be
great because Yeah, because again, it's
uh we think we're doing the right thing.
We hope we're doing the right thing by
applying the TE's, but unless you scope
it and are able to actually identify
what's in there, it's kind of it's kind
of a mystery. So, yeah, that'd be that'd
be helpful. That'd be fun. All right.
Well, hey, thanks again, Jared. Oh, last
question.
Uh, you disappeared. Oh, you're still
there. Oh, you're back. Okay. Okay. Um,
last question was, uh, your outdoor
runs. Um, yes. Yeah. You guys do those
in you handle your fertility a little
different on those, right? Yes. Yeah.
Yeah, for sure. Omin. It really depends
on which zone we're in outside because
we have we have everything from plants
in pots to plants in beds that have
soilless media on top of the soil in the
ground and then all the way to just
growing in the field um in just straight
up soil. So yeah, we kind of tailor it
to each zone. Um we test all those as
well. Um yeah, definitely kind of
approaching the amendments differently
there. I'm upping my nitrogen quite a
bit since we are in like a full sun,
full season setting.
Um but again that's kind of determined
by our pot size too. With some of our if
we're growing in 25 gallon pots, we end
up having to feed them a little more
often throughout the cycle. But um with
our inbed plants and with our inground
plants, we can usually get through the
season off of one kind of initial
feeding and then just monitoring them
from then on. But yeah, definitely
um definitely upping our fertility
overall with a focus on upping our
nitrogen to kind of the high end of what
I would ever apply. And uh yeah, it's
been it's been we're dialing things in
still, but it's it's been working well.
We've been getting getting better crops
each year. So, now that we're growing uh
we're growing kind of a big a big field
of autoflowers, um definitely have to
treat those a little bit differently
than everything else because they're
kind of queuing into flower immediately.
So, it's not necessar you don't
necessarily need as much of the
nutrients you'd be focusing on for like
a longer veg period. Um and then also,
we're amending soil. So I got to take in
to take into account the cation exchange
capacity. The organic matter is actual
organic matter in this case where it's
been broken down over thousands of years
not just like organic matter in the form
of pete. Um but yeah so a lot more to
take into account with the outdoor soils
but yeah kind of same process still.
Nice. I just I remember coming out and
seeing your outdoor plants and they
looked uh phenomen
they got too big. Yeah, it was uh it was
fun to see though. So, awesome. Well,
thank you so much for your time. I
really appreciate uh on the show. We'll
talk soon. No, I appreciate it. Yeah,
thank you. See you soon. Yes.