[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge I'm so excited to share my
interview this week I had the privilege
of interviewing Don Marshall Don is a
good friend a spirited educator
Landscape designer and Horticultural
professional who established one of the
top Horticulture programs in Washington
state over 40 years ago at Lake
Washington Institute of Technology in
addition to teaching Don is a certified
professional horticulturalist ecopro and
certified Arborist he owns and operates
plant designs a landscape design
installation and maintenance firm
special izing in organic fine gardening
now retired from teaching he is enjoying
growing for himself and his extended
family and friends I actually went back
to school two years ago when I heard he
was retiring just so I could take his
classes on botany as he is one of the
most knowledgeable people and best
Educators I've ever met I'm so grateful
he agreed to come on the show now before
starting the show I did want to share a
cool cannabis resource worth checking
out I had a good conversation with Nick
over at Growers Network on YouTube they
have a few channels which include can of
cribs Deep Roots and the Cana cribs
podcast I watched the episode where they
toured yerba buena in Oregon and it was
cool to see the inside of their growing
operation just wanted to share that so
folks could check it out now on to the
show hi Don thanks for coming on the
show today I really appreciate
it hi Ted thank you yeah so I wanted to
start off talking a little bit about
your background you've shared a little
bit off air with me about uh how you got
into horiculture and teaching can you
share a little of that uh with our
audience sure I'd love to I I have kind
of a an odd background in that I was
interested in plans from age five and I
I always wanted to work with plants I
mowed lawns I worked in green houses I
worked in nurseries even as a kid um
when it came time to go to college of
course I wanted to go to plant science I
wanted to be in horiculture so I went to
the University of New Hampshire and I
was majoring in plant science and I was
just loving it except I felt like I was
getting only science only science I was
I I even asked my botney instructor
could you relate this to a
plant and she was insulted she's like
excuse me and and I just thought wow and
then the problem came up when I when the
plant science instructor intro said that
we must put a 51010 fertilizer in a
compost pile and I raised my hand and I
said is this really necessary in an
organic situation and he basically
pulled me in his office office after
school and said there's no place in the
State University for someone like you
and so I I had a rough two years there
science-based science based science
based so I
quit and moved to Seattle and worked in
the industry worked in a greenhouse
nursery in Seattle and um for a couple
years had a great time but I became
increasingly um unhappy with the
wonderful practitioners that I was
working with because I kept saying well
why is this happening
why is this happening and they'd say
just do what you're told why do you have
to ask why all the time so I was now
frustrated that that I couldn't
understand the science part of it all so
I went back to college went to
WSU and uh uh finished my degree got a
dual major in education as well as uh
horiculture but then I student T and I
hated teaching I hated teaching I hated
the whole scene so I went to work in the
industry after after college and um
worked for a while until I heard Lake
Washington was going to start a Hort
program and I thought I could do that
and so I walked literally walked in
sight unseen there was no job posting
and I said I understand you're thinking
of starting a Hort program and I could
do that for you and they said really sit
down and then I got the job and then 40
years later um I just retired so the
interesting thing is I had the
opportunity to marry the science and the
practice which is what the college
wanted and for me it was a gift from
Heaven because I could always be
challenging people to say why is that
happening why is that happening as
opposed to you prune here because the
plant does this and so it was a very it
was a very great um situation for me
because I could always be looking at
both sides of the
street well so many people I know so
many people who have been through your
program uh locally that are now
wonderful horticulturalists and uh you
know you had such impact on this area
here in terms of the education that you
delivered um I wanted to get you on the
podcast to talk about some of the stuff
that uh I've learned from you from the
you know the classes I've taken from you
uh can we talk about some of these basic
plant Concepts and the why uh that that
you mentioned from a a plant physiology
perspective yeah that'd be great that'd
be great um what what one would you like
to start with I know you we had talked
off air about uh root hairs and plants
right maybe that's something we could
start
on that'd be that'd be a great one I
think to back up just a hair I think as
a grower as someone working with plants
every day you need to be a critical
thinker you need to really have be a
Discerning
practitioner
um trying to teach
yourself what is actually happening so
let's talk of root root hairs root hairs
are a great example because because if I
over fertilize sorry I've got on my
throat if I over fertilize a
plant then the result is I get marginal
Leaf necrosis or more dead tissue on the
margins if I overwater a plant I get
yellow leaves and so if I underwater a
plant then I get a lot of yellow leaves
and I even get marginal Leaf necrosis
and so here's a here's a a view of a
plant here's looking at a situation and
saying what is wrong with this plant why
is this happening when you when you go
down to the soil level when you go down
to the to the root
level you see you see really what's
going on is root hair death and root
hair is let's remember for your audience
root hairs are an extension of the root
epidermis that is one cell thick one
cell thick and that's where all the
moistures coming all the water is coming
in all the nutrients are doing their
anion and cation exchange and all the
stuff is going on I mean it's quite a
bit of activity and it's at the root
hair level not the root lit level not
the small root level it's at the
microscopic root hair which is one cell
thick and so when you over fertilize a
plant you have moisture coming out of
the cells and dehydrating and and um
excuse me and the cells die and those
root hairs dying doesn't allow the plant
to take up moisture the same thing that
happens in dehydration actually the same
thing that happens in overwatering
because you have root hair death and so
here's an example
of what happens when roots are damaged
due to overwatering underwatering over
fertilizing
um high salt content in the soil you
know those kinds of things uh and yet
the top growth look exactly the same and
so if we're a
practitioner we often will say well it's
because you overwatered the plant what
was going on you overwater the plant and
the plant
suffocated the plant doesn't suffocate
it's root hair death and actually
overwatering causes drought
stress just as overwatering causes
nutrient
deficiency because of root hair because
it because they can't take up nutrients
through the root hairs now root hairs of
course are rejuvenated very quickly and
and things can come back back pretty
fast but it in the meantime you're
getting yellow yellowing leaves in the
meantime you're getting marginal Leaf
necrosis you're just getting some weird
stuff that that as the Discerning
practitioner you have to kind of step
back and say okay think critically what
is actually happening here what's going
on what's the history what's what's my
employee doing meaning this person has a
tendency to
overwater and that may be what's
happening because what I find with with
employees or stud students is that first
they overwater everything and that's
three months and then they underwater
everything and that's three months until
they find that happy median and so
that's why it takes time to develop
people uh it takes time to to say Can
you look because if you just say water
Monday Wednesday
Friday that may not be the same all year
or that may not be the same in the
different areas of the growing room or
the greenhouse because you've got fans
in this area and you've got a a dead
spot in that area meaning that there's
no air circulation um you know our
structures our growing structures have
all kinds of
microclimates and that impacts water and
nutrient
absorption kind of rambling here but um
no that was great I want to go back and
touch on two things that you said that I
thought were really interesting one was
that overwatering causes drought stress
because it has the exact same effect on
root hairs and root hair root hair death
because that's just so um contrary to
your thought you think you're you know
like you said you're suffocating the
plant but actually it's a drought stress
issue so I think that's really
interesting and I want to highlight
that uh the second thing that you
touched on in in there that I think is
interesting is this marginal Leaf
necrosis that same
symptomatic uh effect that you get on
the leaves regardless of what the
condition is in you listed you know over
fertilization high salt under and
overwatering uh traditionally in the
industry people will immediately say oh
that's a that's a nutrient deficiency
and they'll look at either applying well
cmeg which is not even a a nutrient you
know it's two nutrients or uh nitrogen
those seem to be the the two main things
I hear a lot of times in those cases but
really it's it what you're saying is it
could be sufficient in the soil and
really an issue of uptake related to uh
root
hairs right that's exactly right it
could be root hair death and root hair
remember everything is going through the
root hairs and so lack of root hairs
damage to root hairs death of root hairs
will manifest itself in the above ground
portion as either a deficiency or a
wilting or a gray green color in the
foliage you look at the foliage and like
doesn't have that vibrant green that it
should there's an off
color and and sometimes we even get this
off color and we blame it on a fungus
when in fact the fungus is an
opportunity opportun opportunistic
organism that is living off of dead
roots and in fact it didn't kill the
plant or it isn't attacking the plant
it's attacking dead
tissue so it's it's really it's really
one of those things where you have to
kind of become a Sherlock Holmes that's
why I encourage people when I when I was
teaching them to walk in your facility
whether it's a greenhouse or a grow room
or whatever every morning morning even
before people come even before you get
your day going when you're walking
around with your coffee and just do a
wellness check how's everybody doing
how's everybody doing here let's kind of
walk around and take a look not with the
task of writing a list I got to get this
done or this done or that done just kind
of a a a a well person check you know as
they do in the hospital are you okay or
not okay do I need to be worried here
and so that that totally can help you
catch things early and then become a
teacher to your employees or to whoever
is working with you on take a look at
this because what you do is you Empower
people and yourself when you configure
this out early and catch it
early so when you see a plant or a
section of plants that has an issue
going on what's sort of your mental
checklist you know you've already talked
a little bit about watering and over
fertilization how do you start narrowing
down the variables to getting to what
the real you know the root of the
problem is no pun
intended I yeah I look at the
environment I start looking around and I
start going yeah this is my this is my
quiet Zone meaning there's no air
circulation in this corner that's why
they're not they're not drying out as
fast as the ones over by the fans I I
just start really looking at my
environment because so many of our
problems are
environmental and in a greenhouse so
many of our problems are um envir Al
because maybe in the winter time we're
not getting the air flow maybe we're not
doing an air circulation maybe we're
worrying about Heating and so therefore
we don't want to do an air
exchange and an air exchange causes a
buildup of of humidity which causes them
not to take up as much moisture and now
we're watering them the same as we were
in July when we were having more air air
movement or more air uh exchanges so
really the way you start that is you
just become very aware you develop the
six fence of walking around looking at
the facility looking at the plan and
saying that's funny these three are all
in the same corner or these are not in
the same Corner they're in three
opposite areas what's the commonality
here what is going on and you have to do
it when you're fres you can't do it at
five o'clock you know you have to do it
when you first walk in when your energy
level's High when you're not stressed
with with people saying what do I do
next or what needs to happen or what
needs to happen you know you kind of
have to take a breath walk around I used
to get there early just so I could walk
around and say how's everybody doing
today um that's where you start you
really start with a with a with a well
plant check and say how's it going and
then then you have more confidence to to
tell people this is what needs to happen
this needs to happen and hey what's
going on in these Corners how often when
do you have that timer set or when are
you watering by hand how often are you
watering these um what I'm seeing is a
gray greenness to the color to the plant
not that vibrant green and he change
your over
watering even though in your head you
know about the root hair stuff you could
explain them if the employee is
interested or if they're you know the
person is interested um sometimes
they're
not Yeah so basically it's it's
important
to gather all the information and and
really dive into what's what's
potentially going on and in my head I'm
thinking about the fact that I every day
I see people posting pictures of their
plants online asking
you know essentially that what's wrong
with my plant and I have a standard
answer of I can't diagnose plants from a
photo just because I don't really feel
you you can fully diagnose a situation
from a photo um and uh I I just see
people getting answers and jumping to
conclusions and making you know pretty
big changes in how they're maintaining
their plants based off of this
information and right essentially what
you're saying here is that there's a lot
more information out there that we need
to gather before we can really determine
what's really going
on right and one thing we we haven't
even discussed is the need to not only
look at the top growth but knock it out
of the pot knock it out of the pot look
at the roots smell the root mass um Feel
The Roots the Roots should be white and
should tug when you tug when you tug on
them they should tug back a little bit
or they should snap or break if they
break off if they slime in your hands
you've got root death H okay what that
root death who cares what's going on up
top what's going on with this root
system because that's where all of this
is going on and so that's where you know
the the above ground portion is kind of
the final here it is this is this is the
result of what happened in our root
system so you really got to start down
there you got to get comfortable
knocking stuff out of their pots without
disturbing The Roots You know you just
kind of pick it up with one hand tap it
with the other hand tap the pot with the
other hand and the the whole thing comes
apart and you look at it and you smell
it you feel it with your fingers you
look at the color um you look at the
side of the pot where the roots are
meaning if you're in a greenhouse very
often The Sunny Side of the plant The
Sunny Side of the pot has no
roots because they've died and they've
all migrated to the cooler side because
that black pot is absorbing so much heat
so I mean you know those are things that
you'll notice wow there's no roots on
this half of the plant they're all on
the North side well maybe I need to
shade that south side of the greenhouse
I get a lot of heat coming in there I
thought that was good but with that heat
and that black pot we're actually
damaging some of the
roots so those are the kind of things
you see when you when you um knock it
out of the pot and and again the root
hairs you know the root hairs are so
important those are harder to see often
because you know again they're one cell
thick they're an extension of the root
epidermis so that's pretty small
but carrying a magnifier is a good thing
you
know so talk to me about root girdling
or why it's important when we transplant
plant plants to uh break up the roots
and how that relates to this this root
hair
concept right and you know and my theory
too on uh we have a tendency to put
human emotions into plants plants don't
like this plants don't like that um
plants are drowning when in fact plants
are responding to their environment and
so what we're doing with with roots when
we're
transplanting is we're knocking a plant
out of the pot we should be scoring the
root ball which means cutting Roots
damaging Roots because remember Roots
have no nodes and inner nodes like a
stem does a stem has nodes and inner
nodes and you know that if you cut a
stem um and and you leave an in node on
it'll die back to the node and then the
node will Sprout and that's typical you
know above ground dealing well below
there's no nodes and interner nodes so
wherever you cut it they're going to
sprout wherever you cut it they're going
to they're going to Branch they're going
to send out roots um a root system once
established in its Position will stay in
that position meaning if you take that
6inch pot and you put it in a five
gallon container and you don't score the
root mass then most of the roots are
going to stay in that 6inch pot and
continue to get thicker some will
venture out as opposed to if we took
that 6-in pot we scored the root ball in
four places um and the bottom or we
ripped off some roots and then put it
into the five gallon it would suddenly
Branch where we broke it and they would
score and they would venture out into
the new
environment another big mistake I see is
that people take a 2-in plant or a
cutting and they put it in a gigantic
pot and very often they say well I did
it and really I'm not getting any top
growth I better be fertilizing more or I
better be watering more or whatever when
in fact the The Cutting is actually
filling up that pot slowly with roots
and you're not seeing a lot of top
growth so what I like to do is I like to
go from a cutting to maybe a four or a
cutting to even a six let it root let it
establish let it grow well let it fill
up that pot with soil then bump it up to
a five or to a large your pot but we
have a tendency keep in mind that when
you've got a cutting and you put it in
this gigantic
tub and you continue to water it or if
you water it heavily that water plants
thrive on that air water relationship
where they they get watered they take up
the water it dries out there's oxygen
they need oxygen and so the the air
around there remember oxygen is a part
of
respiration which means that's how
they're getting their plants and
respiration is not breathing it's
converting that sugar that the plant has
into energy and so um by keeping that
soil Mass super saturated because you've
got this cutting in a 20 gallon
container you start to get less oxygen
you start to get less
exchange and you start to get less
growth and slower growth and root growth
that is being hindered uh and hampered
by the by too much
water so man it all goes down to air
water relationships it all goes down to
root hair life
um and then hence the need to score the
the root ball prior to moving into a
larger container that was kind of a
long-winded answer wasn't it no that was
great uh can you describe what you mean
by scoring for people who may not be
familiar with that
term yep scoring is a term where you can
take a Hy Hy or you can take a pair of
shears or a knife and when you're in
production you don't have time to be
fussing with it and teasing the roots
and all the kind of stuff that a
homeowner might do and so scoring is
simply taking a h Hy um or a knife or a
pair of shears and cutting the root
system in maybe four places and the
bottom and doing it in a in a in a
timely fashion I you know teaching is
always is always uh susceptible to
criticism and people would say well in
Industry we don't have time to do this
you're not in touch with reality it's
like if you don't have time to do it
well then maybe uh you shouldn't be
doing
this because I really feel like you can
you can balance doing it well doing it
fast and doing it properly and so proper
scoring is really if you're if you're
moving right along you know you can do
the bottom you can do four sides you can
put it in a pot you don't have to worry
about teasing taking 10 extra minutes
with that one plant I don't have time
for this because I'm busy I know you're
busy so am I let's move on and so you
score it you move on you score it you
move move on you plant it so I don't
think it has to be I don't think we have
to sacrifice quality I don't think we
have to sacrifice doing it right because
you don't understand I'm trying to do it
fast well I'd say we have the other
problem with cannabis cultivation where
they people see this plant and they want
to be so cautious and careful and gentle
with it that they don't score the roots
enough you know in a lot of cases okay
okay but good good because I'm used to
dealing with industry that is like well
we're not being fast enough for not
being fast enough so so those who are
who are um scoring too too much you
don't need to take all that time you
just need to do it well need to do it
completely maybe four spots is enough
because remember wherever you cut it's
going to
branch and that's what's important you
don't have to worry about the top growth
where it's like well go to a node go to
a node you don't want to leave an in
node I want to do it right you know
that's above ground pruning this is
below ground prun pruning where it's
just like just cut it so I I see these
photos online of roots just wrapped over
and around each other you know it's
completely filling a pot um as the
people use as good examples of root
growth but that's not what we want from
a plant perspective right can you talk a
little bit about
why why root girdling is is bad or or
why that might not be
optimal you bet root girdling is is
basically it goes down to water
nutrients doesn't it root girdling is
basically strangling or cutting off the
vascular system of roots and so as these
remember Roots increase in girth you
know they they have a meristematic they
have a lateral meristem uh they have a
lateral layer of tissue that is growing
in girth and as it grows in girth and
you have two growing in girth they're
causing
pressure um it's like it's like staking
a plant above ground and as it increases
in girth if that twist tie or whatever
you've used to attach it is not loosened
then the stem
basically starts to become girdled or
strangled and it impacts water and
nutrient
flow so that's why girdling is bad
because it's impacting water and
nutrient flow and so that's why the need
every stage of
repotting is is necessary to do that
scoring or that cutting of roots so that
they can expand so they can go into
their new environment the purpose of
roots is seeking out water and nutrients
and so that anything you do to to not
help that happen is going to impact top
growth great answer thank you okay um so
just to highlight you brought up
something that we hadn't talked about
before but I I have struggled to explain
well when on the phone with people in
terms of of the need to transplant now
you mentioned not going from because a
lot of people want to skip that
intermediate transplant
um let's assume you're growing in a in a
bed or a large pot as your final
flowering container whether a tomato or
cannabis you know people want to go
straight from a 4 in into that 30 like
you said or from a clone into that large
Plant because it seems like less labor
can you just I I know you kind of
covered this but could you just
highlight again the reason why those
transplants are so critical from a from
a plant Health
perspective right right that's great and
I see that too and I see that that
really they've got to go back to
remembering it's all about air water
relationships in the soil and so putting
that plant into a six or a gallon uh is
going to let that cutting establish it's
going to let it fill up that pot with um
with roots you're going to be able to
knock it out you're going to say wow
nice roots and then put it into the 30
put it into the bed because you know
you're putting something that's really
well established what we find is we get
loss you have plant loss when you put a
cutting into a 30 and it's usually
because of overwatering and it's not an
overwatering it's just that that soil
Mass especially if you have an organic
matter in there that soil mass is a
sponge and it's just holding on to all
that moisture and not allowing that air
waterer relationship which is encour
encouraging the roots to grow so I think
it's really wise to to do that next
stage which is to take that cutting put
it into a gallon let them establish
then move them into the 30 I think you'd
be ahead um by doing that you would also
be able to Rogue out plants that are not
establishing and some plants that what
is wrong with it and sometimes cuting
just don't root well for whatever reason
and you thought it looked pretty good
but then you put it in the one gallon
and it
died well that's a lot less labor than
moving it to the 30 and then having it
die and it's like oh great now would
I've got these holes
here um so I think it's a I think it's
wiser to take that interim
step yeah and I would add that I to me
it seems like too when you go from uh
you know the two small of a plant in a
large pot uh the like you said that pot
may still be heavy and feel like it has
a lot of water but that area right
around in the root Zone which is a
pretty small area may be completely
dried out and it's really hard to water
especially when you're watering on scale
like let's say you had 50 or 100 of
these plants that you had to water I
think it's really hard to water them
effectively when they're really small
relative to the mass of soil that
they're
in
and oh go
ahead well I was just going to say and
sometimes the rooting media is a
different texture and structure than
you're planting and growing
media and so that that difference of
media often the the rooting media maybe
is hydrophobic it doesn't want to take
in moisture and yet the and yet the
growing mass is super saturated
and yet they're not Crossing they're not
Crossing those barriers because of the
repelling of the water going on from the
rooting media to the growing
media interesting phenomena well that
brings up another important point when
transplanting into the ground or into
different you know into a different
media uh one thing my dad's always
emphasized with me is that you it's
really important to uh mix to remove
that barrier between the two media by
mixing in uh some of the Native oil or
this the New Media in with the you know
the old that the plant is in so that uh
The Roots will want to reach out of
their
current media into the other one so you
kind of remove that barrier do you have
any thoughts on that oh yeah absolutely
and you know even when I was in college
we were taught you know you
a plant you get rid of the soil and you
put in good growing media into the pot
into this into the ground so that the
plant will root and establish and what
what science shows later is that
basically that's a pot inside the ground
and so absolutely your dad's right you
want to take and and and co-mingle the
two the new and the old um even in a
landscape you know they're they're
saying organic matter you know add
compost add compost well if you dig a
hole and you add a plant and then you f
back fill it with compost the root
system will stay in that nice soil
structure of the compost and won't
Venture into the native soil so yes you
want to mix the the new soil with the
old soil or the new soil with the
existing soil um so that the root
systems say oh this is the same texture
oh this is no problem and they go from
one one uh one texture into another one
structure into
another again we're putting human
characteristics into a plant but that's
just for the sake of
discussion sure so we've been talking
about everything sort of below ground uh
can we talk a little bit about what's
going on above ground with a plant as it
grows sure um
yep boy I don't know where to start here
I mean we could talk about plant growth
from a hormonal perspective or we could
talk about them from say a a pruning or
training what's going on when you
um when you when you cut a at a node or
you know in an inner node uh what what
would you want to tackle here well those
two are those two kind of go hand in
hand meaning why are we pruning and why
what's actually happening um so keep in
mind that the apical meristem the
growing point the terminal Bud of the
plant has hormones growing in it um and
or the hormones growing in it sorry
hormones are produced in that apical
meristem which is the growing Point
that's the top of the Christmas tree
right that's right it's the very tip
it's it's the is inside the butt of the
top of the Christmas tree you know I
mean you you take away the let's go to a
top of a Christmas tree it ends in these
Buds and in those buds those buds are
covered by Bud scales deep inside those
Bud scales is an apical
meristem okay it's it's a group of cells
that are kind of your Wonder cells and
they produce everything everything
starts there one of the things that
starts there is
hormones many hormones not all of them
but one group called oxin which is a
group of hormones and so um those oxin
control lateral growth and terminal
growth and those oins basically tell
that apical meristem we're growing up
we're not growing out uh let's keep
going and so the tip of a Christmas tree
keeps growing straight up the farther
you get away from those oxin that
terminal
Bud uh that apical meristem farther you
get away the less impact those hormones
have and that's why you start to get
branching below eventually you get
branching below that um where those oxin
are not impacting so by pruning by
removing the apical mirror stem you
basically remove that control that's
what's called apical dominance you
remove that control and you get
branching so when we're pruning we'll go
to a node and the node is where the bud
comes out of the stem and the inter node
is the distance between buds um you go
to a node you prune it you cut it above
that and what happens it branches
meaning um the bud just below where
you've above where you've below where
you've pruned starts to grow and the one
below that starts to grow and the one
below that starts to grow and those
start to to grow and get larger and they
in turn have an apical marem and they
control their own lateral
growth and so there so therefore if you
want those side branches to Branch then
you tip out that apical meristem as well
we do that with fuches for instance
where we let them grow a couple nodes
and then we tip them and then they
branch and then we let those branches
grow a couple nodes and then we tip them
and then we let those branches grow a
couple nodes and then we tip them why
because we're trying to encourage
bushiness and all this pruning is
successful because of hormones that are
that are encouraging and that are um
inhibiting branching
so from a cannabis perspective
by removing or limiting by pinching for
example the amount of uh oxin coming out
of that the apical marem we allowing
other branches to grow and and getting a
fuller canopy uh is essentially what
what what you're getting at more of like
a I guess a
candelabra design versus a a Christmas
tree if we're going to use visuals good
choice good choice of words yep is a
great choice that's right right calabra
is right you know by pinching you
develop the Candelabra you develop the
bush by not pinching you you have a
Christmas tree telephone pole and it
will eventually Branch lower once those
hormones have less impact um but you get
a strong what's called apical dominance
it's the dominance of that apical Mir
stem to control the lateral growth
that's what apical bomin ances and as we
get this bushier plant we're getting a
lot of you know interior branching and
lower branching which may not be have
access the same access to light and air
flow uh so why what what is the
importance of pruning a plant and
removing those branches or leaves uh
from a plant Health
perspective good so so you're right
there's 's less light down there there's
less air flow down there the thing you
want to keep in mind is then when you
take that Branch out to the point of
origin on the stem you're not
encouraging any more lateral growth if
you just took that side choot and cut it
back you're encouraging more lateral
growth so that's an important concept
yeah can you explain that again so or
say that one more time I'm not sure that
I fully caught
that so you've got a plant whether it's
cannabis or whatever and you've got side
branches coming off at the bottom and
you're saying I want to improve the
quality of this plant and so I'm going
to reduce it by
20% because I want more light and more
air circulation going on so you take
that side branch and if you prune it
back to the point of origin what I mean
by that is back to the point where it
came out of the
stem okay if you prune it back to that
point then nothing's going to sprout
from that point say you have a leaf out
Leaf there that leaf is going to stay
there you're not going to get a new
shoot coming if you were to just tip
that lateral Branch it would in fact
Sprout lateral branches and you would
have more
bushiness okay so that's why I'm saying
on that side choot if you want to
improve um light those lower branches
then you're going to take it out
completely and I call it the point of
origin what we see a lot of if we're
talking about an indoor facility ility
would be uh static light coming from
above from a a light artificial light um
and so what'll happen is we'll create a
a canopy using trellis netting that's
essentially even and then everything
below a certain point is De leafed and
removed from the plant uh but for the
most part the branches the lateral
branches are left and and people are
just removing the the leaves cuz
essentially they're not
getting I mean the idea being they're
not getting enough light and air to
where they would be more of a a nutrient
sink than a you know photosynthetic
benefit right okay okay any thoughts on
that um not a lot except that when
you're growing with lights your quality
is often better meaning than the sun
because you often have less Shadows I
believe
um less shading so that's a really you
know growing strictly in lights like
Grow rooms and things like that I have
friends that that that are growing
cannabis and Grow rooms and and Bo the
light quality is so bright compared to a
greenhouse sometimes you
know yeah the actual uh the actual light
intensity in a greenhouse I mean
depending on where you are is usually
can be quite a lot higher but the the
spectrums um of of sunlight allow for
that in a lot of ways then we were able
to mitigate that um yeah whereas
indoors uh light spectrum's gotten so
much better especially since you you
initially started and I I don't know
that you had lights in your in your
Greenhouse out there in uh at Lake
Washington did you did you guys use
stuff on we did we did but you know
first of all on the prop bench we just
Ed cool white fluorescent because that's
what we had and and and we were in the
process of doing a lot of changes and
and my co-teacher that took off took
over after me has done a lot of of
adjusting and making you know updating
and things like that with with good
quality grow lights oh okay cool yeah
exciting one thing I want to touch on
because this was something I learned
from your class that shocked me was uh
looking at
oxin um you you gave us this uh this
handout I remember on oxin and light
and can you maybe you know where I'm
going with this uh my my understanding
was the exact opposite of what was
actually going on with oxin
right without without saying it myself
do you want to kind of explain y what's
going on there yeah so so we've all been
in situations where we've put lights by
windows or something and the plant bends
towards light is that what you're
thinking yeah yeah so what's actually
going on inside the plant I think that's
fascinating that's so funny that's right
it's it's so fascinating because we
always say well my plant love loves my
window it bends towards the light or or
even even even under grow lights you see
the ones on the edges growing towards
pointing towards the light source and so
we have tendency to think the plant is
really enjoying that and bending towards
the
Light When in fact the reality is that
oxin which is a hormone is responsible
for cell reproduction cell
enlargement um cell development and it
also is damaged in the Pres of light and
so what happens is oxin migrate to the
Shady Side of the plant therefore and
causing cell cell reproduction cell
enlargement causing that one side of the
stem the Shady Side of the plant of the
stem to actually
enlarge at a faster rate than the ones
on the Sunny Side therefore causing it
to be nodding towards the sun because
the back of its neck if I can use that
analogy the back of its neck is actually
growing faster than the front than the
throat and so what do we do we turn the
plant and so that the sun is so that the
pointed part is now in a different
direction and it evens out now in in re
in nature outside plants don't have this
because the sun is moving across the sky
and if you've ever looked at slow motion
pictures of plants they're always in a
constant of Mo constant state of motion
they're moving in a very small way and
following that sun and hormones are
actually moving around the stem in the
same way so yeah it's it's it's kind of
a misunderstanding that people are
saying yeah my plant's bending towards
the light which it is bending towards
the light but for different reasons of
what most most people think because the
cells are elongating and growing because
of ox oxin essentially on the Shady Side
that's Shady Side yeah see that's a
really surprised me I remember learning
that and being pretty yeah pretty
impressed by yeah it's kind of it's kind
of cool yeah fun to think about that so
uh I had a couple more questions I
wanted to change subjects again and just
talk a little bit more about how plants
eat to use a human term for for plants
again um I know you had talked a little
bit about um root hairs already but can
we just talk a little bit about how that
the nutrients and water uh and a
littleit about photosynthesis too sort
of the the important aspects of how
plants grow
wow this is huge I know it's a big
question yeah I don't even know where to
start um let's skip the photosynthesis
respiration part at this point let's
just talk about nutrients and and water
and what's going on at the root hair
level it's a it's basically
chemistry um goes down to I'm trying to
summarize all this goes down to anions
and cations which are positively charged
ions and negatively charged ions and
that these roots have a
um homeostasis if I can use that word
where where there's an electrical
balance in the root hairs and so it's an
active process we have a tendency to
think we water the plants and they
passively suck everything in and all the
nutrients with it kind of like opening
your mouth and having someone pour in a
hose and you just kind of swallow
whereas actually what they found is that
it's actually much more involved and
much more detailed and more scientific
than that in that plants are actually
having carrying on their own cation and
anion
exchange with the organic matter with
the soil solution with the minerals that
are in the soil and so they are giving
off a cat I they are taking in a cation
so they're giving off a positively
charged ion of hydrogen and they're
taking up a positively charged ion um of
ammonium or something like that and so
all these neut nutrients I mean this is
like a whole quarter chemistry class
these nutrients are in an ionic form
cations and anions and the root hairs
are going through their exchange process
and so it's an active process and oh
let's do it anyway it's an active
process and this active process requires
respiration requires energy and energy
is achieved through respiration
respiration is the is the
uh transfer of the sugars that are
created in
photosynthesis into energy therefore
using that energy in the root hair level
to carry on this process of cation and
anion
exchange this this is a
lot it is uh one of the things did any
of that make sense yes yes um in in
terms of that cation anion exchange you
know you you mentioned like there's
certain basic cations ions that we talk
about with you know calcium magnesium
potassium sodium and annion like uh you
know I think of nitrogen and and
phosphorus being the main two uh sulfur
yes sulfur is a big one because it
allows us to lower the ph and a lot of
what that comes back to is pH and I
don't want to spend a lot of time on ph
but I I would like to mention that I
think in Organics people underestimate
the importance of pH in a lot of cases
and when we talk about the plant's
ability to uptake nutrients by
having by having a pH in a Range that's
optimal for a plant it just makes it
easier for the plant to make these
exchanges so it's using less energy to
receive the nutrients that it
needs okay okay and it also yeah yeah
that's true and pH also impacts the form
that the nutrients are
in in the the ground for for instance
plants want to take up nutrients in a
certain form they want to take up
nitrate they don't want to they won't
take up
nitrite well nitrate is NO3 nitrite is
NO2 and they're both an
anion and given too low of a pH too high
of a pH these nutrients although they're
present are not available to the plant
because they're in a form that the plant
can't take up and that's why pH which is
one major reason why pH is so important
because it keeps nutrients in an
available form to the plant you know if
you want a box of C you want to eat some
cereal you have to take it out of the
bag and put it into a bowl so it's in a
form you can eat as opposed to just
eating the box and the plastic and then
and the um
cereal I don't have a lot to add to
that so it's kind of a weird weird
analogy but just came to me yeah no so
uh when we're talking about optimal
Plant
Nutrition um all of these things you
know we're talking about root hair death
and you know water and and over and
underwatering and all of these things
all affecting nutrient uptake and then
we talk about nutrient availability from
a a pH
perspective um there's all of these
things playing together so it's not a a
simple concept when you like you
mentioned when you say how plants grow
or uptake new nutrients um is and we
have a tendency to think that presence
is the same
as um availability so we do a soil test
and unless we really tune into that
pH
um Well here here's a great example so
people will test their soil their lawns
because I deal with a lot of homeowners
and they'll test it in the wintertime in
the Northwest and in the winter time
what do we have we have a lot of rain
and in the winter time we have a lot of
leeching and so they test their oil and
it comes back that nitrates are zero and
they go no wonder no wonder my lawn is
so bad I've got to fertilize I have no
nitrogen when in fact nitrates are an
anion or are moving with the groundwater
and therefore in the winter time you're
not going to have any
nitrates and you don't want to you don't
want to apply nitrates in the winter no
because it's just going to move with the
groundwater whereas you have plenty of
nitrates in the summer if you have
organic matter and ammonium because the
microorganisms are converting that
ammonium into a nitrate and so it's so
that's why that's why the pH needs to be
really looked into and dealt with um
because it's not only a nutrient present
issue it's a nutrient availability
issue you this is a little off topic for
this podcast but I I thought this was
really interesting in your class when
you talked about fruit trees and when to
fertilize and when to prune uh because I
know a lot of people that listen to this
podcast also grow food could you give
that quick synopsis because this is
something I I always forget and I I I
want to keep it fresh in my head too as
as something that I think is important
because because of you when I look at a
plant now I don't look at a Rasberry
plant and just say oh I prune it you
know right I can prune it right now I
start thinking you know when does it
when and how does it grow what is the
optimal time for me to prune it and I
think see the biggest the biggest
mistakes happening with fruit
trees yeah well that's great because you
know I was doing a lot of consultation
in my Heyday and I'd get a ton of
questions from homeowners or from people
who were saying well when do I prune
when do I fertilize when do I this when
do I that and I and I used to think man
I'm getting a lot of these same
questions so I started teaching in class
think like a
plant how does a plant grow what is
going on at certain times of the of the
year and
so and we're often sold to bill of goods
by fertilizer companies by chemical
companies that are basically saying it's
February time to fertilize your lawn and
so let's let's talk fruit trees for
instance so what's going through the the
life cycle of or of a plant in the
winter time it's dormant and so it
doesn't need nutrients in the wintertime
um in the spring March it's going
through a grow surge so does it need
nutrients no how's it getting this grow
surge the grow surge is coming from
stored food in the root system that it's
stored last fall and so we don't need to
be fertilizing in February and in March
and in fact it's just going to be
leeching away in the Northwest even
though the weather is getting better um
we need to resist that Temptation and so
as a plant grows it puts out it starts
to grow um say we've pruned it in
February March it starts to grow in
April it bloom rooms it puts on this
massive amount of Chute growth it puts
on flowers those flowers are fertilized
by the bees and other pollinators and
then it starts to develop fruit at that
point in the Pacific Northwest at that
point when that when that fruit starts
to come on those leaves are fully
expanded its food reserves are at its
lowest E I mean that's the time to
fertilize I usually tell people around
here Memorial Day because Memorial Day
the end of May that that's when plants
are are really needing some
nutrients but usually we've done it in
March so Memorial Day they need those
nutrients and they need to to be storing
food they need to be they've already
exhausted a ton of energy by producing
lots of leaves they're now producing
fruit the fruit is is taking taking um
products to photosynthesis to sugars and
starches and those kind of things it's
just taking a lot of energy so like I
grow a lot of blueberries you know so i
f flize them in May for I fertilize them
miday and mid
June because I'm going to be harvesting
in
July and then as we move into fall
what's going on what's going on in late
summer in late summer in August
daylength is shorter um nutrients are
migrating from the leaves back to the
stems so that's not the time to prune
because you've got to again I always try
to get people thinking like a plant
think like a PL
you don't want to be pruned when you're
when you're trying to um take those
sugars and starches and nutrients and
store them into your root system then
someone comes along and cuts off 30% of
your foliage it's like whoa whoa whoa so
and in fact we've had bad fruit years
when we've had a early
Frost when we've had an early hard
freeze first of November when the leaves
have not finished migrating sugars back
that impacts our fruit production for
the next year
so so always getting people to think
like a plant and what is actually going
on will help you answer questions on
when to do things when to fertilize when
to prune um if you prune a plant in
October and I was taught this growing up
in New England you don't plant a you
don't prune a plant in the fall because
it will send out a lot of new growth
that'll get frozen off well that's a
Croc that's been shown that's not true
at all the plant pruned in the fall
doesn't suddenly over overcome daylength
cool night
temperatures um the migration of sugars
back and suddenly put out a ton of New
Growth it can't do that what happens
actually it start it may just die or it
may just die back if I want growth
Resurgence when do I prune I prune right
before growth Resurgence which would be
February for us in the Northwest because
right before growth Resurgence is when I
prune and then I get this massive amount
of stored food coming from the root
system encouraging new branching and I
get this explosion of growth so always
encouraging people to think about how
plants grow and what's actually going on
in their natural cycles with daylength
with night temperatures um and what
impact will this have if I want to
rejuvenate a plant well I'm going to put
them in
February if I want if I want a hedge to
stay the height that I want it to stay
at when am I going to prune it I'm going
to approved it in July because in July
it's already gone through its grow
Surge and its food food reserves are at
their lowest de therefore pruning that
hedge in July it'll stay nice until next
spring I had a client that said I want
you to prune my hedge I said I can PR it
now and you can pay me to PR it again in
eight
weeks why would I do that I said because
if I pr it now it's going to have a grow
surge well it looks Shaggy I said let's
let it look Shaggy till July then I'll
prune it and it will stay nice for
almost a year oh well that would be a
lot better so understanding how plants
grow helps you to be a better
practitioner and I I know that uh one of
the things that you talked about too is
different plants fruit differently for
example um in terms of like raspberries
fruiting on second-year wood can you
touch on that quickly
too sure uh different plants bear fruit
and that's a question you ask yourself
if you're trying to say I don't know how
to prune this thing ask yourself on what
wood does it produce
fruit is it seconde wood is it first
year wood with raspberries if it's a
single crop raspberry as opposed to an
Ever bearing a single crop raspberry
will produce fruit on seconde wood and
then the cane
dies so you cut it down to the ground
you cut that cane down to the ground
because all during the summer while one
one cane was bearing fruit another Cane
was growing up and living its life and
it will produce fruit next
year and people always say well how do I
know if I have ever bearing or single
crop raspberries I say well you look at
the plant and you say well here's where
this here's where the fruit was from
last year Well if you scratch the bark
on that cane and it comes up green that
means that cane is still alive and that
means it's an everbearing
because everbearing raspberries bear
fruit on the tip in the fall of the
first year and on the midsection of that
same cane the next year and then the
cane dies with raspberries canes are
banial meaning they die after two years
but the roots are perennial they
continue to live we could have a whole
topic on raspberries
here I know well I so we recorded when
you came out to the farm and did a
pruning video we recorded that I still
watch that periodically cuz have to
refresh for myself with the plants that
I have you know like think like a plant
you know why when and why do I want to
be pruning and I realize for this
podcast you know a lot of people are
focused on cannabis production but
they're growing other plants and even
with you know cannabis it's good to have
an understanding of why we're pruning
the plant the way we are and what what's
causing the effects that we're seeing
when we do
so yep and and and I think even in this
time you know of pandemic food security
is on everybody's mind and I think the
more we can do to produce our own food
and part of that is understanding on
what would am I going to get fruit we
all want food security and we all want
to be producing we all want to go out in
our Landscapes and our Gardens no matter
how big or how small they are and pick
an apple and say oh this is pesticide
free I know
that and you know we can't control a lot
but we can control what we're
growing yeah and you mentioned blue
blueberries and I know I had uh I had an
issue growing blueberries I put a
blueberry plant in the ground and it I I
put some of the our biochar soil in with
it and the thing just didn't grow for
two years and I had to stop and think
about that and then I realized well our
soil tends to run a little more alkaline
biochars alkaline I've got this
blueberry bush growing in soil that's
you know close to S 71 in some cases uh
it's not it's not happen
you know because it wants it's working
really hard just to stay alive because
the nutrient availability even though
there was a ton of nutrients in that
biochar soil it wasn't available to the
plant wow wow what a great learning it
likes four five to four to five five pH
yeah we weren't even close I mean
especially because you know it's a
logarithmic scale just like uh the RoR
scale with earthquakes like it's uh we
were so far off from what that plant
wanted um and I frankly haven't I
haven't grown a lot of great blueberries
um unfortunately um but I've had good
success with raspberries and other crops
um but I look forward to learning you
know and think thinking about how how a
plant grows and what it wants and then
trying to structure a soil because I
know if I go back to grow blueberries
now I'm going to approach it entirely
differently and really think about how
do I create that acidic soil that uh you
know and very like
heavy moisture soil that that
blueberries are going to want like what
environment do they normally grow in you
know that they grow in bogs which is
heavily moisture but is also heavily
oxygenated and so therefore people say
around here they say my blueberries
won't grow and and we've got an acid pH
in the whole bit well it's because
they're putting them in heavy clay
blueberries don't grow grow in heavy
clay they want they want a bog they want
air they they want air at their roots
that airwater relationship so it's pH
it's airwater relationship they're a bog
plant so what does this boil down to it
it goes back to where we started which
is critical thinking isn't
it yeah I mean when you say that I think
of moss in uh in Turf in in grass and
Lawn around here you see that so much
and people say how do I get rid of my
Moss you know and they'll they'll take
it out and put in you know new sod MOS
kill yeah or MOS kill and yet it doesn't
really solve their problem because their
problem is compaction it's shade it's
you know excessive water in that area
that doesn't allow the grass to out
compete the Moss you know right right
and and they don't understand that Moss
is not I mean you see tons of moss in
full sun
areas and that's because they don't
understand that Moss is a function of
poor nutrition low ph and
environment well if you've got poor
nutrition low ph ag even though it's in
full sun you're going to have a lot of
MTH yeah I mean we see moss on roof
around here all the time obviously it's
getting light yeah right right so it's a
it's a yeah it's that critical thinking
what what's really going on
here and plants because we've grown up
with plants because plants are
comfortable there's a ton of room
for home
Elixir hearsay and you know plants like
this and plants don't like this instead
of really looking at the plant and
saying okay what do you need you know
what's going on here becoming you know
becoming
Discerning that's a really good point
because in the Cannabis industry
especially there's millions of products
and uh you know people you'll talk to
someone and they'll say you need you
know product X in order to grow a good
canvas plant I put this product on and
my plants took off you know and they
grew so much better so people think they
need that product uh but with a little
bit critical thinking you can think well
that product contains high nitrogen and
my my that person that was growing with
it had a nitrogen deficiency so by
adding this product and getting that
nitrogen in there that was the
underlying issue uh they were able to
grow a better plant but if you have a
soil that has high nitrogen and you
apply this special product you're not
actually helping your plant you could be
making things worse worse and so right
that's a great example some people put
in high nitrogen because they have a lot
of bark in their
soil all the bark is break is the
nitrogen is is helping the microbial
activity break down the bark and that's
why that's working and maybe that whole
scenario is working but then you're
right you take somebody else with a
different soil mix and it doesn't work
at all great great great comment so I
know I could I could probably keep you
on the phone here chatting all day but
in the interest of uh your time uh we
can sign off here can uh since since you
established Lake Washington College uh
can we give a little plug out for that
program because uh it's such a great
sure a great program can you just you
know a quick two minutes on on what it
is and and if people are interested if
they want to take courses there great L
Lake Washington Institute of Technology
which is in Kirkland Washington um has a
great horiculture program it is a i i I
had a co- teer who who was with me for
gosh almost 15 years is now is now
running it it's doing very well it's a
program that is very strong in the
basics it's strong in science it's it's
meant to give people a strong foundation
so they can go into cannabis or they can
go into nurseries or retail or wholesale
or or growing or whatever they want to
go into in this industry the field of
horiculture is so Broad and so vast but
people need a strong Foundation the
basics because once you understand the
basics then you can branch and become a
professional uh in a certain specific
area but it's it's really strong in
providing a wide range of of topics that
that would help you understand soils and
botney and propagation and you know all
those things that that you can find your
Niche and and sometimes people think I
don't even like this part of it I don't
like that part of it that's great but
then the next class you take you're like
this is it these are my people and so
we've had a lot of a lot of cannabis
people we've had a lot of of landscape
designers landscape um practitioners in
the field in many ways and it's a place
to really develop skills and develop the
eye of looking from some I think that
you need to be there a year and it's a
one-year program certificate or degree
um and basically you need to be there a
year before you even know what's going
on in the greenhouse before even know
it's they've got 12,000 square feet of
growing space and so it's a very
practical Hands-On um approach to
horiculture and you know you need to be
doing it for a year before you see some
re repetition of oh this is what happens
in October in November so anyway I could
talk forever it's a it's a great program
it's a great College it's full of really
caring people um and it's Lake
Washington Institute of Technology in
kirkburn Washington thanks Dad for
letting me say that well I would add too
that you recently added a Growers
program um not specifically listed for
cannabis Growers but targeted towards
people that are headed towards that
industry and that you've taken out a few
courses that may not be as useful for
someone that that already has their
heart set on the canvas
industry boy and that was a challenge
you know that was something I did right
before I left and it was a challenge
because the college was worried about
Federal funding and so our president
said very concerned about this and so I
had to convince her that someone taking
the grower program would also be able to
transfer that knowledge into growing of
any type and so we you're right we took
out the landscape design part we took
out the things that that people may not
want that are becoming cannabis Growers
um but it's still strong in botney and
in soils and in Pest Management um
integrated Pest Management um using
beneficial and all those things that
that are helpful for a cannabis grower
but we've taken out the the design part
and some of the other things that are
not as not as beneficial and the the
college is behind it and the president
was behind it once I first she nixed it
and I said could we talk about this and
let's she said well this is my concern
and I said well let me expand your view
of this program a little bit and by the
time we were done she said wow I'm so
glad you came and talked to me because
she was very open to it and said this is
a good idea um so yeah it's a it's a
pretty exciting
program well Don I know you're sitting
out in your Greenhouse right now in Port
lllo freezing uh so we could get good
reception for this interview so I
reception's good here though that's why
I'm here I I really appreciate it and I
really enjoyed talking to you today and
uh I enjoyed talking to you too this has
been really fun thanks yeah I look
forward to uh hopefully catching up in
person here in the not too distant
future me too thanks a lot all right
right we'll see you thanks Don bye okay
bye
[Music]
okay that was Don Marshall and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at www kis
organics.com just click on the learn tab
then podcast and please take the time to
leave us a review if you listen on Apple
podcast or other platforms I do read
them all and appre appreciate the
feedback and more reviews help us rank
higher so others can find the show
thanks for listening