[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge it's
been a little while since the last
podcast I wanted to let you know that
I've been busy with some other projects
but also tracking down some new and
exciting guests I have some really great
podcasts lined up in the coming month
including one with Alison Justus of Elko
to help dispel some of the myths they've
been floating around the cannabis
cultivation industry for decades and I
know we've already done some podcast
discussing mycorrhizal fungi including
one with jeff Lowen fellows that I
suggest you check out I wanted to do
this interview though to get a different
perspective on mycorrhizal fungi from
someone who has been involved in the
industry and selling and using it for
over a decade I've had my opinions based
on the research I've seen regarding
topics like using a single species
versus diverse species of Enda
mycorrhizal fungi as well as the
addition of Trichoderma to these mixes
our guest this week is Jim Egan jim has
been working for plant revolution for
more than a decade having been the first
company to bring mycorrhizal inoculants
to commercial applications he and the
company have been spreading the good
news of the benefits of healthy soil to
gardeners landscapers and farmers all
over the world his degree in
environmental studies his work in the
permaculture community and his
experience running a small farm form a
background that has given him a deep
understanding of the importance of soil
organisms for plant and ecosystem health
he continues to learn and explore the
fascinating worlds of food production
native ecosystems and sustainability
all right thanks Jim I really appreciate
you coming on the show yeah I think that
really excited to be here so let's just
start off and dive right in talking
about mycorrhizae and mycorrhizal fungus
would you go ahead and I know we've
talked about it with previous guests but
can you
give us a brief introduction into what
mycorrhizae is for people that may be
new to the new the subject before we
dive into the little little tougher
questions yeah no problem
essentially mycorrhizae means fungus
root and it's a very important grouping
of fungus that exists in the natural
environment and it literally is a fungus
that lives on the roots of plants so it
has a really hard time producing its own
food namely carbohydrates and sugars but
actually has partnered with plants and
it did this as far back as we can tell
in the fossil record so plants when they
first came on land from oceans had very
primitive root systems and it was this
coming together of fungus and ocean
plant you can think of it as like a
holdfast for a seaweed right so the
mycorrhizae fungi allowed much more
surface area so it's much finer than
root hairs and it basically would cover
the arid land and absorb water and
nutrients it would break down minerals
all the things we're going to be talking
about but it covered these root systems
and eventually formed with about 95
percent of the world's plants and this
includes you know the early nonvascular
plants from hornworts and liverworts and
mosses to you know the giant redwoods
and conifers and flowers and vegetables
so almost all of the world's plants
formed with this soil fungus and it's a
little bit different from saprophytic
fungi which sort of exists independently
and break things down in the forest this
stuff relies on a host plant so that's a
very brief overview many any of those
topics we could have spent many minutes
on but that's just a very brief overview
no that was great I do want to highlight
a couple other things too for people so
for those of you that are you know I
know this is a cannabis podcast but we
get a lot of people that are growing
other plants too now there's many
different types of mycorrhizae fungi
which we
we can talk about in depth the main ones
being you know endo mycorrhizal fungus
ecto my gradual fungus and then there's
another one called era coid as well
which I always associate with azaleas
and rhododendrons but it's important to
realize that there are different types
of micro Raizel fungus can you talk a
little bit about what those types are
and which plants they associate with as
well as the you know things like
brassicas that don't have that
relationship yeah absolutely so like I
said there's there's a couple of a
couple broad groups there's the endo
mycorrhizae and the echo micro z are
probably the two biggest they also have
things like iroquois mycorrhizae and
even orchids have their own sort of
partnering microSD interestingly enough
and really the two main types that
commercially and practically we concern
ourselves with are these endo and ecto
and so endo mycorrhizae is what we're
all familiar with it's also called our
bus cooler mycorrhizae or VAM vesicular
our bus cooler mycorrhizae those are two
structures that it forms testicles and
our bus fuels and platforms with roughly
about 85% of plants so that's the types
of forms of cannabis it forms with
vegetables it forms with fruit trees and
really that the main type that we deal
with in commercial uses the other type
is called techno micros with fungi and
this forms mainly with your conifers
your you know your Oaks other hardwoods
and things like that and that forms with
roughly about you know 10 to 12 percent
of the world's plants it's much more
ubiquitous in the environment so I was
on a conference call earlier this
morning to just kind of walking around
the garden outside here and I literally
found a giant fruiting body of one of
these ecto mycorrhizal fungi so they're
really they're everywhere you're
probably breathing in the spores right
now but those yeah so that forms another
big portion of the microbes will French
I out there
and then like you said the iroquois form
with you know kind of your your acid
soils your acid loving plants so you
know cranberries huckleberries
rhododendrons things like that and then
we also have which so those they're not
as stable and easy to produce and also
that's a much smaller grouping of plants
that they form with so it's as far as I
know those inoculum aren't very
available on the market
same thing when it's orchid micro so now
I'm sure orchid growers probably have
access to that or they culture their own
you know but generally those two types
really aren't available on on the market
either retail or commercial and then you
know yeah the plants that don't form
which actually there are a lot of weeds
so there are a lot of the sort of plants
that thrive in disturbed soils right so
they're the the pioneer plants as we
call them in permaculture and and they
come in and they don't need a lot right
they can survive they can break through
concrete and and you've seen like a
dandelion things like that so these are
plants that have that have evolved and
just really never had a need for this
mycorrhizal symbiosis which is a really
interesting thing but yeah there are
small grouping of plants and luckily for
gardeners a lot of them are weeds that
don't really need a Mike Reiser
relationship and in fact mycorrhizae
actually helps deter these a little bit
in one's garden so yeah that's kind of a
broad overview of all the different
types now if we were growing something
though like cauliflower or broccoli
which does not have a microbial
relationship aren't there studies that
show it actually will potentially be
detrimental to the plant if if it does
form that relationship so we want to be
careful and how we're applying it into
which plants to my knowledge they don't
form that relationship so it's not
really like a fungal forcing onto the
plants it's the plant really chooses
which my crazy to let in and in fact
plants can act
turn off and changed the mycorrhizae
that they're forming with throughout a
season the same plant to get its needs
met so you know if it needs you know
more micronutrients there's their
species that are more depth in getting
you know maybe zinc or something like
that out of the soil and so the plant
will actually ship the mycorrhizae that
it's forming with so the only thing that
I can think of is that you know in a
heavily Mike ride will dominated soil if
you have other plants growing with
mycorrhizal fungi maybe it's out
competing the brassicas but I've never
heard of it being detrimental to brass
because that would be a new one to me
but yeah I'd love to learn more about
that ya know I thought I'd read a study
where it showed that it is possible to
form that relationship but it's actually
detrimental to the plant but it's not a
natural Association I know it was a long
time ago and I could be wrong I haven't
brushed up on it in quite a while
honestly so right know if you do find
out anything let me know
one thing you did bring up though that I
want to go back to is you mentioned you
saw a fruiting body or a mushroom of an
ecto mycorrhizal fungus and that's
something that I see with a lot of
growers is a couple things out there
where you see photos of roots and people
are you know let's say you choose
cannabis in this case and they may see a
bunch of mycelium and say oh that's you
know that's our my mycorrhizae or though
they'll see mushrooms popping up in
there
you know indoor cannabis garden and
they'll say that that's because they
have a micro Raizel relationship now as
I understand it feel free to correct me
here
the endo mycorrhizal fungus you can't
see without special microscope tools to
dye their roots to see if they're
actually infected and then those
particular Glomus species don't
necessarily form fruiting bodies or
mushrooms is that is that accurate
hundred-percent yeah yeah so what
they're what they're seeing is probably
some saprophytic fungi that has found
its way and it's breaking down organic
matter so the most common one is the the
the flower pot it's a little yellow
mushroom and
what's it called flowerpot forget the
exact species a cydia more something
like that and that is it's just pot
culture conditions so growing plants and
soil and pots is just the ultimate
environment for this stuff so it
hitchhikes in on a lot of you know maybe
it was probably in the soil to begin
with or just finds its way in there and
that comes up that's coming up in my
houseplants right now but we get guys
that will send us pictures of that and
no that has nothing to do with the end
oh my cries will fungi you're correct
and that they don't form fruiting bodies
which is why and we'll get into this
there's so little study they really are
if you look at the studies it's like two
or three species that's tops and you
know the estimated numbers at this point
is is over 300 and that's including
that's all the ones we don't know about
so we've only studied a small portion of
them because they don't form fruiting
bodies so essentially yeah they have to
you know they have to isolate these
spores they have to pull them out of
soils they have to they can pull some of
the mycelium which like you said is
smaller then it's visible to the naked
eye you can see ecto mycorrhizae is it
forms these things called rhizome Morse
which is like a lot of strains of
mycelium kind of coagulated together so
you can actually see that which is that
famous picture if you've ever googled
mycorrhizae it's different species of
pines but on their root systems it's
this big sort of hair net of mycelium
radiating out in all directions so you
can see that because that's an ecto
mycorrhizae but you're correct in that
these mushrooms are not connected to the
mycelium and growers you won't really be
able to see the mycelium with the naked
eye now you will probably see a strong
healthy root system you know we can talk
about that later but just the so there's
some things that I can't
talk about we can't make any claims
whatsoever about our products because
we're not registered as a pesticide so
but if you google some of these species
you'll see that you know there there are
benefits from the fungus that when you
pull a root system out and there's it's
white you know it's there's not I should
be very careful in how I say this but
there's not certain things the color is
the color that you want
the roots are vibrant that indicates you
know often times that it has the strong
my mycorrhizal relationship and
everything's functioning as it should
all the micronutrients are making it up
and all the you know the different
chemicals that the plant forms with that
to protect itself for all functioning
properly
but yeah so you can't actually see the
mycelium if you were to pull out a root
system so you know I think I think it's
safe to say that plants that are
healthier are less susceptible to
diseases and other pathogens so a plant
that may that has a micro Raizel
association may in theory be a little
bit healthier than a plant that doesn't
because most plants like you mentioned
95% them what to have this relationship
and can you talk about some of the
benefits and how they may differ between
endo and ecto micro Issac is with the
ecto you're on the outside of the roots
like you mentioned it's reaching out
into the soil the the endo is infecting
into the root itself what what are the
differences in the benefits of these
these two types of micro Raizel fungus
yeah so generally with both types you
see increased surface area so like I
said the the the first coming together
of these organisms was because plants
root systems weren't the purpose wasn't
mineral nutrient absorption it wasn't to
break down minerals and nutrients you
know it wasn't to absorb water they came
from environments that those things were
in and sort of a kind of an aqueous
solution in the ocean
so one thing you get is you get much
more surface area so the mycelium
essentially radiates out but you have
right around the roof it's called the
phosphorus depletion zone so plants when
they're you know first given nutrients
bill they'll eat up all the phosphorus
and nutrients right around the root zone
and so what these mycelium do is they
sort of poke out through that so they
radiate through that and they get much
more surface area able to take up those
minerals and nutrients you also see they
release exudates in the soil they
release enzymes into the soil which
makes nutrients that get locked up but
once again bioavailable so they they
make that bet available to the plant the
phosphorus and the nitrogen and the
micronutrients so yeah there's uh you
know a couple other benefits so they can
actually fix nitrogen atmospheric
nitrogen just like the the bacteria
there's some bacteria out there we even
in our blends we have bacteria that do
this as well it's not the risin
Rhizobium bacteria like in a like in a
legume it's actually free living
bacteria but also the the mycorrhizae
fungi can fix atmospheric nitrogen which
people don't know not many people are
aware of that's one piece of it so
stress on the plant transplant shock
when the plants transplanted its sending
out chemicals into the soil to actually
germinate any my gradual spores around
it when I seed germinates in nature it's
immediately sending out these signals
because it's it's grown and evolved if
say to have this symbiosis so it's it's
it's used to having these ambient spores
around in its soil environment so once
this germinate
you know through all these mechanisms
that I've been talking about and ones
that we haven't mentioned yet
it allows the stress tolerance of the
plant to go up so too little water too
much water variances and pH variances in
temperature the plants actually going to
be able to withstand that and actually
thrive through that a lot better than if
you didn't have the my gradual
association and that's really one of the
benefits of mycorrhizal fungi and
actually one of the reasons that we'll
get into diversity later but you know
once one thing that these that these
inoculants do is they allow you to bring
your your baseline up so your
worst-performing plants does a lot
better now your best performing plant if
everything lines up for that plant and
and you know your ph is right on all
your nutrients are right on everything's
perfect and that plant does great you
know you're not going to get a 10%
increase in yield no matter what anyone
tells you but not everything's perfect
and really what these inoculants do and
what mycorrhizae specialty is is it
brings that that sort of I don't think
the law of minimums where it brings your
poorest performing plants up to a higher
level so overall you're getting a more
stable yield you're getting a more
consistent yield and that's actually one
of the reasons just briefly why we
included diversity in our blends because
specific microbes will species perform
different functions so like give you an
example you Guam is Claira one of the
Glomus species it helps with dealing
with excess salts it improves mediation
of heavy metals heavy metal toxicity
Glomus desert Accola comes from arid
regions it's better at drought stress so
let's say Glomus ma say it reduces
uptake of arsenic one interesting
example but
they all have these different sort of
specialties and so when the plant
encounters something that it's
detrimental to its growth it literally
will change directions and start to
utilize whatever species that can
perform those functions that it needs
now in terms of your question about endo
versus ecto to be honest I need to
research that I have never actually been
asked that and yeah I'd be really
curious to hear the differences in the
different benefits of the different sort
of morphologies how they work in the
root zone how that translates into the
ecosystem and one thing you touched on
if yeah EXO grow kind of between the
root cells and endo grow into the root
cell and they form these little
structures which just kind of tell
people this is why it's called Arbus Q
or busk Euler mycorrhizae is that they
go into the root cell form these little
structures that look like root systems
and that's actually where the water and
their own nutrients are traded to the
plant through a there's a small little
membrane around Arbus fuel and in
exchange for that it gets sugars and
carbohydrates that like I said earlier
it can't produce itself through that
structure inside the root cells why or I
think of it as endo in but yeah in terms
of the difference between the endo and
the ecto on the in the benefits realm
I'd actually be curious myself I think
the important thing for people to keep
in mind is that you want to make sure
you have the right species for what
you're what you're planting and you know
there's if you're not planting conifers
do those ecto species have benefit I
know you and I have talked previously to
this and I've been a big proponent of
single species inoculation because all
of the research that we see out there is
primarily with Glomus ensure a disease
or rise of Vegas and sure a disease now
as they're calling it and the Glomus
Moss a or however however you pronounce
it I think that was the researcher that
discovered it but those are the two most
widely
and most widely available and I'm I'm
just curious what research you've seen
that would support using more diverse
diverse species of micro so in a micro
eyes'll product yeah so the big one is
endo versus EXO right yeah clearly if
you're not growing EKKO plants you don't
there's not a need for the ecto so yeah
we have a number of products you have a
single species and though we have four
species and though we have a diverse
multiple species endo and ecto so we
support all kind of directions that the
market is going but yeah
clearly you don't need ecto if you're
not growing in ecto plant the reason
that we've included it in some of our
blends over the years is it's like I
said it's ubiquitous it's literally you
know almost pennies per pound for us to
include it for example you know in a
gram of our popular product there's
played out maybe like 250 speed spores
of endo all I mean Ellis is right this
is one gram of material you got about
two to three hundred spores of viendo
you have a couple million spores of the
ecto so they're much smaller than the
endo and they're super super cheap to
produce they're literally you know
coming up we harvest those wild so we
harvest those fruiting bodies wild and
what that did for us was allow people
you know allow our blends to be used in
a diverse array of environments the
specific ones where we decided to
include both we made them really easy
for the end consumer and so you know
that was probably ten years ago we came
out with those products and sort of as
people the market developed and people
were saying saying you know we just want
the endo and we just want the bacteria
you know we don't want everything
included we started to broaden our
product offerings so yeah we have
products that are just endo and bacteria
and then like I said we have to just end
up
so there's no absolutely no detrimental
effect having the ecto in there but yeah
like you said you know if you're not
forming with the conifer it's not
absolutely necessary but you know it's
one of my favorite products that we
still do is the great white in terms of
bacteria and endo mycorrhizae even if
you weren't even you know considering
the ecto for the value the value that
you get the concentration of endo and
the bacteria in there is really
unrivaled in the market you'd really
have to buy two separate products that
you know almost double the price to get
those concentrations but yeah I mean I
get it I totally get it you know if
you're not growing a connoisseur there's
no need for it but yeah they still they
still prove to be super effective
products if they do have bit of blend in
there but yeah we support you know one
species for species like the great white
that's eight species of endo now
specifically talking about endo
diversity what the what what our
research is showing and what the
research is is kind of beginning to
reveal because it's in the past it's
basically this stuff is very little
studied like you said we have the the
Glomus irregularity Alma Center a
disease you have Glomus mas a Glomus
aggregate um so you have a few species
that have been studied and and really
they've only been studied for a very
limited kind of set of parameters or
they're not testing for it's tough to
test for all the whole the the
conditions that are out there all the
reasons people might be using these
inoculum xand in the actual field and so
sort of the thinking this has been
passed on I'm not the researcher you
know this has been passed on from sort
of our research department and our
scientists and and they're continuing
actually to to isolate different species
and begin to test those for their
viability in the market and you know
what what was passed on to me is that
that having diversity for first of all
my ethos is diversity right so
permaculture and ecology sort of dictate
that as a principle diversity it's more
resilient so how that works out into the
mycorrhizal sphere is it's just like I
said all of these mycorrhizal species
have different specialties so Glomus
inter a disease is known as a broad
former it forms early and it's grated up
taking phosphorus but that's not the
only sort of problem that growers are
facing you know there's all sorts of
conditions you know you have pH problems
you have temperature problems you have
disease problems you have sort of
micronutrient deficiencies you have
nutrient sort of lockout you have all of
these things that the plant needs to
well either the plant figures out a way
to overcome these problems or it shows
up you know as a reduction in yield or
some sort of resolve seeing deficiencies
and our leaves and then those sorts of
things and it kind of talks about
further you know the plants natural
defenses they actually rely on the
ability to get micronutrients and to get
these you know just water and all of
these other things to actually form
these compounds and form these different
chemicals and exudates and things like
that
which can actually keep the plant
growing - you know maximizing its
genetic potential so with the my gradual
fungi like I said what we've seen is the
plant is actually able to cut off flow
of nutrients to specific species and
throughout the season switch that over
to other species that are actually
taking care of and have the ability to
solve the problem that the plant is
facing
and that can happen throughout the
course of a season or that can just
happen straight out of the gate
especially with this kind of moving more
into broadacre applications you know
there's so many different conditions and
environments that growers are facing
right so different pH is different soil
makeups right different soil chemistry's
different climates all those sorts of
things you know one my gradual species
is somewhat limited in its ability to
overcome those various problems with the
plant is facing whereas a diversity of
species does have the tool belt sort of
in the tool chest if you will to solve
those problems and and create those
compounds and be able to adapt to the
situation so that's really like I said
we offer single species but we promote
diverse species within those groupings
right endo versus ecto so that's what
we're seeing and that's kind of what
we've how we built our NOC ulam
any inoculation is great if you're using
single species you know multiple species
your plants really going to see a
benefit so you mentioned that the plant
can switch its mycorrhizal association
or infection mid mid lifecycle how does
that work then let's let's take a
cannabis cycle for example where you
have a plant that may only have 55 60
days flowering time are you saying that
the plant could start off with a say a
relationship with Glomus enter a disease
or Rago phase Rezo vegas inter a disease
and then switch halfway through to
something else say if conditions change
like to the Glomus desert Accola for
example or can it have multiple
infections within the same plant of
different species at the same time on
say different different root hairs or
root tips
that's what I've yeah that's the
information that I've been passed on is
that both of those scenarios can can
happen was mycorrhizal fungi so yeah
yeah to my knowledge that that is
possible with both of them and like I
said all this stuff needs to be studied
further and especially as cannabis is
you know we can actually study it now in
with labs and you know universities but
just the mycorrhizal discipline and in
general has a long way to go
so like I said inoculum single species
inoculum is fantastic for plants you
know as a principal I think diversity is
is a good good way to go but we have a
lot to learn in terms of how that how
that functions in a root system sure I
would totally agree with that and
there's a lot of challenges around
organics and research we were talking
about this I think last podcast but I
know definitely off air I was talking
with a friend about this how a lot of
the research being done it's very hard
to do it with our ganks because there's
so many variables and there's so much we
don't know about the microbial
interactions in the rhizosphere that
it's very hard to isolate and make any
definitive claims or evidence of claims
moving forward based on what we're what
we're seeing because there are so many
things going on there's a relationships
between you know different microbes as
relations between the plant and the
microbes and it's it's really hard to
isolate down to the effect of one one
particular variable but that kind of
brought me to another question here so
one of the challenges as a consumer is
there's so many different micro Raizel
products on the market how do we
evaluate them and we talked just now you
explained your your opinion on diversity
versus single species which which made a
lot of sense but how do we you know how
do we evaluate these because there's
there's a few different things I want to
look at here so we already talked about
endo versus ecto so if we're if we're
applying it to fruit trees if we're
applying it to our garden we want to
make sure we have endo mycorrhizal
fungus
mix and that echo is probably it's not
gonna hurt anything but it's not
necessarily what we're looking for for
that inoculation so we want to make sure
we're comparing endo species and then we
need to look at do we have a single
species versus a diversity of species
and then finally the the concentrations
which and this is something we should
probably go over to talking about how
labeling works with propagules versus
spores and what's most viable for for
consumers when they're applying these
things because you see guys and they'll
look at a label and they say oh my gosh
this has 2 million proper gills per gram
but when you break it out it's actually
maybe 250 proper gills per gram of the
actual species that could potentially
infect or you know benefit the plant
that they're growing so can you just
kind of maybe go over some of those
things in a little more detail and
explain your thoughts on that yeah
fantastic question so hmm how I think of
it is this is gonna sound funny but
we're exiting the age of the wild west
microbial inoculant and what I mean by
that is you know we've had companies and
products just claiming the most
outrageous stuff I won't name names but
those products are somewhat gone from
the market you know the super outrageous
ones are gone but the reputation of the
company the the age of the company is is
a big deal because this stuff is
microscopic so you're you're essentially
buying a car that's you know under a you
know under a blanket or something like
that you're not allowed to look at the
car you're not allowed to inspect the
car to see the you know the integrity of
the engine of the wheels or anything
like that so this stuff is microscopic
so you know the company's reputation in
the industry makes a big difference and
the first thing so you know when you go
and take a look at these inoculum yeah
the first thing you want to do is flip
it over and start with what they're
claiming you know we'll get into that
whether or not that's reliable in a
minute but
start with what they're claiming so if
you're looking at you know apples for
apples so you know you're looking for
endo look at the diversity and then look
at this the propagules it'll either say
propagules or grams or proper gills or
spores per gram and that's a good that's
a good indicator of how many I guess
units of material are in that that will
actually germinate and create this
mycorrhizal Network and so what proper
gills and spores is is that the spores
are the it's like this seed of the apple
right so you can grow this fungus with a
spore because it has the genetic
material just like a seed and the term
prop akyuu laz we're talking about
earlier it would be easier with fruiting
bodies and mushrooms who produce much
more even spore material they're
actually spores but with the endo mica
rise because they're underground so
think of that how that functions in an
ecosystem right you have plants that die
that their root system is where these
spores were formed and where these
spores are going to pass on that genetic
material so oftentimes the spores don't
have the advantage of you know hanging
from a cap as a gill would in a mushroom
and it can be blown around by the wind
or it could be knocked by an animal or
oftentimes squirrels are really
important especially for truffles with
distribution of these organisms you
don't have these these mechanical means
of moving these spores around the forest
so oftentimes the spores end up in the
roots themselves and the plants just die
and that slowly decomposes but that root
is actually still viable because it's
it's either filled with spores or it's
just a fragment that will actually
germinate into when the next plant root
finds its way down there sends out those
chemical messengers we're talking about
earlier then that can germinate so we're
talking about production of endo mike
rizzo fungi you're going to end up with
both root fragments and spores and
they're both viable and you know it's
you
there is a process that you can just
kind of extrapolate the spores but it's
very expensive at this point so when
people claim oh we've got this and that
no billion spores program it's it's not
accurate if they're gonna have any price
that's somewhat competitive in the
marketplace at this point it's that's
they probably don't understand their
product because they show their but yeah
so usually it's going to say proper
yields that's a more accurate
description of the material that's on
the market right now and yeah like I
said you want to look at the
concentration so you know two or three
hundred prompt joules per gram is it's
very very hot it's very very high at
this point that's a real concentrate you
know around a hundred is is a good is
not bad that's kind of what our lawn and
garden mixes are just because you know
the average person buying a rose or a
tomato plant is not going to go for the
higher prices you know because when you
add those concentrations the price goes
up so you know we could sell you a four
ounces of material for seven thousand
dollars or something like that because
you can get these things really
concentrate but so you know what you're
looking for is good two to three hundred
coffee you'll program material are
liquid
however with milliliters it's a little
different it's a little different volume
so we're close to I think like sixty to
eighty property goals per milliliter and
how that works out is is like you know
it's the same rate or the same cost per
plant to use even though the the numbers
are different the way that the volume
works out it's the same you know if you
were going to treat a four-inch plan it
would cost the same with our liquid as
it would with the great white or you
know our powder products and then you
can go with the straight mycorrhizal
inoculum we have products like that a
little bit of our products like I said
we pride ourselves on diversity also
carry
specific bacteria that have been
well-documented documented and studied
to provide things for plants so for
example nitrogen fixation or phosphorus
solubilization enzyme production so all
these things that that work hand-in-hand
with the mycorrhizae fungi and all the
other soil organisms for that matter but
these secondary metabolites azar codes
from the bacteria are super functional
and helpful for plants and my garage
will fungi so if the inoculants have
beneficial soil bacteria in there we've
found that the synergistic effect of my
grass with fungi combined with these
bacterial concentrates is this shows
better yield or better results versus
just using one of those individually
okay so essentially as a consumer what
you want to look at is the
concentrations which will most likely be
expressed in property goals per gram of
the particular species which we're
looking for or type of micro zone which
would be endo and then beyond that
diversity like you said and then lastly
one of the things that you touched on
there that I want to I want to examine a
little closer is that there's no one
really doing researcher or testing of
people's claims as I understand it I
know with soil like I had to have when I
registered my product I had to make a
guaranteed analysis claim if I'm if it's
gonna be registered as a fertilizer and
then whatever that claim is I have to
show a lab test supporting that but then
at that point it's the state would have
to would be randomly testing the product
maybe pulling it off the shelf
to see if it actually met those
standards down the road in terms of in
the actual bags themselves so I assume
it's the same on the microbial side like
you if you had one test for example that
said you had a thousand proper girls per
gram you could put that on the label and
then in theory until the state or
whoever registered
he tested it no one would ever know what
was actually in that product am I am I
saying this correctly I feel like I know
there's been some tests done by the
Oregon Department of Agriculture that
have shown mycorrhizal levels and other
microbial levels from 2016 has being
very different than the claims that were
on the label can you touch on that at
all or is that too tricky of a subject
no absolutely and that's you know that's
we're actually really happy that that's
happening because like I said you know
that gives companies like us who have
been you know honest and you know
actually putting in what we claim a huge
advantage
so yeah Oregon is beginning to test
microbial products and you know they're
not perfect
I think they we actually my family's
company sort of help them develop some
of the tests for the microwaves will
fungi in terms I mean this is you know
10 15 years ago so you know microwaves
with fungi are much different than
bacteria and they were sort of treating
them like bacteria and so yeah the
testing is beginning to happen and
that's kind of why I said we're coming
out of the age of the wild wild west
because there were some products out
there that just made outrageous claims
and that's going to this testing is
going to consolidate and kind of weed
out some of those companies and products
who are playing you know who aren't
being truthful
so yeah that's absolutely accurate like
you said no people can put whatever they
want on we're responsible for a
guaranteed analysis and analysis in
terms of NPK and you know derived from
statements but with the microbials it's
kind of been this gray area and organs
kind of leading the pack but a lot of
other states will probably add a doc
some of the testing methodologies and
and the regulatory piece of that so it's
actually it's a good thing for consumers
and
what we do this is kind of how it works
on the on the microbe side is so we'll
actually you know we'll formulate things
to concentrations that we think are
adequate for you know the type of grower
that we're making the product for and
then we'll actually get it tested by an
independent lab and they will verify
what we've been doing and aiming for and
then we'll reduce it by about twenty to
twenty five percent when we when we
claim it on the back of the bag to give
a window so that when they do because
they'll the the regulator's will go
through and as you know just pull you
know product off the shelf at any you
know any licensed retailer and test it
and so you know we we actually allow we
we met we claimed less than we know is
in the bag for the odd batch that
doesn't have you know didn't get mixed
perfectly or whatever so we actually
claimed a lot less than what's in the
what's in there that we we aim for
and there's fertilizers the same people
do the same thing with fertilizer but
that that's kind of the the state of the
testing and it's it's a really good
thing for consumers because these you
know microbials like I said are
invisible so you know people could claim
anything and it would never be tested so
the best thing for people to do is to
take a look at a label trying to
understand it to the best of their
ability do their own research and then
really just see look at plant response
so I think you know use great white use
some of these other brands and and you
know see what kind of results you get
and that's ultimately what we're looking
for anyway I think is plant response so
absolutely yeah
be in touch with your garden and that's
that's really why we've been successful
as a company because people do these
side by sides you know I can't tell you
how many times I go to a new nursery or
you know or we hand out a sample at a
trade show and we'll get pictures back
like wow look at the difference in the
root system you know because this is
this is an ancient relationship this is
plants depend on this it's like it's
like going through and bleaching the you
know the inside of
human-being you'd only last about a week
or two so it's almost how we've been
treating plants as we just destroy the
biosphere and expect these plants to
perform you know at a high level but
then we end up okay well now we need
like 90 percent extra fertilizers
because most of us getting locked up in
the plant roots can't release the
exudates to get it unlocked or we hit
them with fungicides or pesticides
because now their immune systems are
compromised like it's a no-brainer these
microbes work like my gradual fungi
works it's it's a relationship that's
like I said there's oldest land plants
so yeah use the stuff and see you know
see it for yourself and until you
actually try something and see it it's
all hearsay anyway so don't they doesn't
think what I'm saying is is you know the
truth try it out for yourself great now
I want to talk about some of the other
bacteria and other ingredients in great
white but before we do can we talk a
little bit about best practice so how
what is best practice around application
of these microbial products because one
thing I want to touch on kids we were
just talking about labeling now that I'm
thinking of it is I see you'll get a
soil bag or a bag of fertilizer and
they'll say with mycorrhizae on there
and then you go and look on the back and
it's like point zero zero eight
propagules per gram or something like
just a really really small number and I
typically tell people that that's
probably not enough for them to get
mycorrhizal infection they're better off
applying it directly to the roots of
their plant rather than applying it you
know homogeneously throughout the soil
or trying to get it with fertilizer and
as I understand it because it is a spore
a proper goo it also doesn't move
through the soil very effectively it
needs a physical mechanism of watering
or something like that so we want to
apply it directly to the roots but can
you give what your pointers would be for
people who want to use you know a
mycorrhizal product whether with their
plants absolutely so yeah direct contact
is essential the plant root releases a
chemical I'm forgetting the name that
triggers the spore to send out a Hisle
tip which then plugs into the plant
itself so that physical contact is
crucial when you have microbes that are
dispersed you know a foot away three
feet away from the plants if you're
doing it short you know short seems an
annual crop most likely it's not going
to germinate until you know late in the
season and by that time that really is
not benefiting the plant so you got to
think of all those spores as investments
you know you spent money to get those
into your soil the best way to use them
is to get it right on the plant root so
we have powders that you can sprinkle
right on the roots themselves you can
also dissolve those powders in water and
water it in you can send it through your
fertigation system put it in your
reservoir you know have it drip down in
there so any way for it to actually make
contact with the root system is
beneficial we also have granular
products that were designed not to be
dissolved in water just to be sprinkled
and sprinkled into the hole at
transplant time so that's really the
most cost effective way to inoculate
your plants and to talk about bagged
soils and fertilizers yeah I think it's
a good thing that people are paying
attention to and and soil companies
fertilizer companies are beginning to
honor the soil microbes and include them
the problem with soil is that you know
like you said the concentrations are
really really low so to see a good plant
response for example our bare minimum
for a four-inch plan is about ten spores
if you're talking about endo mycorrhizae
ten spores per plant so often times with
these you know bagged soils you'd have
to use a whole others there's just not
enough material in there to actually
make a real difference with the plant
besides that these bags are often stored
in direct Sun so if this bag sits on a
Sun for a day
most likely everything in there is dead
if something does happen to get in there
that you don't want what's you know so
once again I haven't even talked about
this with the concept of having
a sterile soil the problem with that is
that that is a ripe environment for an
explosion of some sort of disease or
something that you don't want in there
so you don't one of the real ways that
these inoculum work is that they create
this balance they create sort of this
net that when something unwanted comes
in to the system it's immediately
out-compete it that's a huge one with my
guys will fungi is that there's not a
lot of ambient nutrients or spaces for
disease to exist so that's that's a big
one with the soils is that they often
get sterilized in the Sun besides having
low concentrations and with the
fertilizer it's generally the same thing
really really low concentrations it's
too expensive for them to really hit it
with a lot of sort of microbes so what
we recommend is buying straight
fertilizer buying us you know you're
straight soil and then adding the
biology when it makes it to your your
grow your site and you know another
reason is that we as a company pay a lot
of attention to and spend a lot of time
and effort and maintaining an
environment and shipping our products
and educating the stores and the
retailers on how to store these products
it's printed right on our bags the bags
are all designed as well as the jars for
sort of maximum stability of these
organisms so also in the like you know
the supply chain the delivery these
organisms are taken care of so that once
they make it to you they're in a prime
condition to come out of dormancy and
colonize your soil in your root system
so yeah those are those are key points
so for a fast crop like cannabis for
example that may you know maybe 90 days
for example or even less in a lot of
cases we want we want to get the
mycorrhizal infection to occur as
quickly as possible which means directly
onto the seeds or rooted clones when we
transplant how important it is it to
reenact you late
when we transplant at later stages
because I've always been a big proponent
of doing a really heavy inoculation
right at right at the time of planting
saying you're rooted clone or your
seedling and then not reapplying when I
transplant it later stages just because
it gets so expensive relative to
potential benefit have you seen have you
seen benefit with later applications of
micro eyes'll fungus yet you know state
other stages of transplant with a pure
mycorrhizal inoculum i would say that
what you're doing is fantastic maybe one
more application with our products they
also contain huge diversity and really
high concentrations of the beneficial
bacteria not talking about our products
but talking about BT Bacillus
thuringiensis which our products happens
to contain you know that's a bio
pesticide in the organic world so it's
almost so I think of these inoculants
that contain the bacteria as well as the
mycorrhizae fungi is basically
interesting compost teas so I'm always
revolving sometimes I'll just use our
straight powders in water or sometimes
I'll brew compost tea with worm castings
or compost you know I'm constantly
adding teas and biology to my soil but
in terms of a straight mycorrhizal
inoculum I think that one heavy
inoculation will give you a really good
colonization of your root system doing
it more you know it depends on the the
specific growing conditions but you know
people will have to try it for
themselves there's a general rule with a
straight micro inoculum I don't think
you're really going to see a huge return
on investment for a second in a a third
application but like I said our products
are a little more complex we have seen
people using it every feeding every
watering as a preventative so you know
whether that's broad acre or you're
growing in a very you know controlled
environment and growing indoor
you know every conditions different
you'll kind of have to
that's it for yourself and see if that
prevention is is necessary and worth it
for you or you know if you're getting
along just fine you don't need it but
it's essentially like taking a probiotic
you know so people take those ongoing
and with the mycorrhizae really what
you're looking for is just to get around
you know 75 to 85 percent colonization
of the root system that's what you're
aiming for so ends on the success of the
first inoculation which you know it's
different every time but if you're doing
it like you said a really heavy
inoculation right on the roots probably
getting a really heavy colonization now
how long does that time to infection
occur or colonization as you're calling
it my understanding is it takes at least
10 to 14 days under good conditions or
even longer
is that accurate or what are you finding
for infection rates yep that's accurate
we see the bacteria and our products go
to work a little quicker so like the
Great White has glycine which is a
simple sugar b1 vitamin C and we see
people like oh my gosh my roots are
going nuts like they're super white you
know or it helps remediates something
that's gone awry generally that's the
bacteria and like the Trichoderma which
I think we'll probably talk about next
but those are heavy enzyme producers so
they're breaking down organic matter you
know you've got dead roots on there you
that are turning brown you've got slough
da fruits you've got excess you know
organic matter in the root system those
bacteria are just really really heavy
like I said enzyme producers
micronutrient soluble Iser so they're
really going to work and just cleaning
up that whole root system so yeah
generally my kraslow colonization takes
just under two weeks and the bacteria
sort of peaked and then the root system
returns to a tortoise kind of a steady
state based on the exudates and the
sugars released by the root system
itself so bacterial peak and then my
gradual colonization takes about ten to
fourteen days like you said okay I do
want to
and talk about the bacteria but I had a
couple more questions before we do so
yeah one of the questions is the
persistence of these mycorrhizal
property goals are spores in the soil
like for example if someone was running
a living soil indoors or even this let's
say soil in their greenhouse or outdoors
they you know they pull the plant or
even just cut the plant at the stock and
let those roots break down right there
in the soil
what is the persistence of that
mycorrhizal those mycorrhizal spores and
do we need to reenact you late every
cycle in say a living soil bed or in
soil that we're reusing yeah so you know
what I generally tell people I haven't
seen a ton of studies on carryover of
roots and to you know season after
season you know I guess it's fair to
assume if it's the same species you will
have some carryover I don't know so like
a lot of these spores for a lot of these
end oh my car is old root systems don't
well you know some of them take it
depends on the species I mean it depends
on the growing condition so some of them
can take 3 years to produce spores some
of them can take you know six months
seven months like one growing season but
I'm not an expert in that you know it's
plausible that the the roots of you know
will stay along long stay alive long
enough from where the mycelium will stay
a long life a lot alive long enough to
colonize the next crop but I don't think
there's a whole lot of research done on
that so I wouldn't really be confident
or comfortable making a recommendation
you know with the cost of inoculation
and the business that we're in it's a
no-brainer for me you know it's like if
you're gonna buy some fish and and some
kelp which and rock dust which I
advocate you do you know why not buy
twenty dollars of material or to treat
your whole
crop with my kreizel fungi I mean you
you don't have to use this stuff like a
you know like a flower you you know like
a like a pizza dough or something like
that you don't have to throw a ton of
this stuff at it you can actually you
know dilute it and use it at the
recommended rates as well which will
make it go a lot further I'd actually
recommend that over using a ton and then
hoping it carries over from season to
season because of the benefits of using
it on a new seedling for for stress and
transplant and all the things that we've
talked about but yeah in terms of
carryover I'd like to see some studies
but I haven't seen any well I guess I'm
wondering is if that if for example we
had let's just take a 4x8 raised bed
just to simplify things and we had a
plant a cannabis plant growing in there
and that plant we go to harvest that
plant and let's say we take out the
roots you know or the the main roots but
don't worry about so there's gonna be
root there's gonna be a bunch of root
hairs and leftover root material in that
soil if we were to plant say a cover
crop or our next cycle of cannabis
plants would the microcell fungus that
had infected the crop before potentially
infect the new crop yeah it's definitely
uh potentially but you know it all
depends on what species colonized the
cannabis and what species of cover crop
you're planting and whether or not the
two are compatible it depends on the
length of time between the two you know
if it's a day or two yeah it's
definitely reasonable and plausible one
I totally support that I just I just
don't know okay no that's fine I was
just curious if you knew the answer yeah
no I mean I love it I come from the
world of you know permaculture and
sustainability and environmental science
so I'm all about the least amount of
inputs and you know extraction and all
the you know phosphorus mining and fish
emulsion that we have to like you know
drive a thousand miles and put on our
land like I'm all about growing
bioaccumulate errs and extracting what
we can from the land in a sustainable
way and reusing it
oh yeah let's do this studies so you had
mentioned in our email you have
something about explaining techniques
for extending effects can you touch on
that a little bit or what you meant by
that yes like I was talking about with
the bacterias they kind of peak and then
plummet and same thing with the
mycorrhizal fungi is they the reason
that we include sugars in our blends is
that those are the preferred those are
best the food source of the bacteria in
the fungi that fuels the whole soil food
web so what we've come out with is this
product called my coach um which has
fish hydrolysate which as opposed to
emulsion you had the gentleman from DRAM
on and I just loved his explanation of
how that works but essentially the
hydrolysate is much better for bacteria
and fungi because it contains all of the
proteins and fatty acids and a much more
diverse palette of foods for these soil
organisms as well we have kelp which has
a huge array of micronutrients we have
molasses once again high in
carbohydrates and micronutrients and
then your humic acids which have your
humic substances so it's feeding the
microbes is one thing that I think is
really a beneficial thing to do it's
it's adding your compost teas regularly
it's you know topping off your compost
teas after you're done brewing them with
a little bit of kind of those things
that I just talked about to extend their
life in the soil so we've over the years
you know the things that we cultures and
grow these mike rizzo fungi with and
we've run the gamut of soups to feed
these things and to see their responses
is this is what this my coach um product
is is these are all of the the foods
that the soil food web thrives on so
yeah what I meant by that was just
feeding these organisms encouraging
these organisms and it's all the same
things that well generally that plants
like right so you have good aeration
you have a stable pH
you have you know good water content
you're not over watering you're not
under watering and you're providing a
food for these organisms you know things
like biochar that provide a habitat if
you will for these organisms is super
beneficial but really culturing and
nurturing these soil organisms is is
what I was talking about so you you know
you have a healthy population of
bacteria that doesn't plummet and then
rely solely on the plant exudates is you
can kind of keep it running at a peak of
soluble izing any nutrients in the soil
making available available to the plant
so there's like excess of these enzymes
and micronutrients available to the
plant instead of sort of letting them
die back and then there's a bare minimum
so you know it's the same logic as like
I said the adding compost teas to your
soils you're just kind of maxing out
that soil biology so that when the plant
needs it the soil food web delivers okay
that makes sense I you know I got a cop
copy I mean I got a sample of the
miCoach um I keep wanting to call it
Chum food I think I don't know why I do
that
but the micro jump so the micro Chum
does not have my kreizel fungus in it
but rather it's this combination of fish
kelp humic at a very good price point
I'm excited to try it out my next round
of microscope testing it's at the top of
my list of things to experiment with to
see how it works with compost teas and
what its effect are is on soil microbes
so yeah and I have a I have an order
coming in if there's any listeners that
want to try it out they can reach out to
me via email but it's not available on
our website yet but we can definitely
help get some into your hands I know I'm
sending some to my buddy Nelson down in
California to do some experiments so
yeah I'm excited to hear I'm decided to
hear what's going on with that product
but let's go ahead and jump in and talk
about the bacteria now and some of these
other microbes in your soil because you
and I talked off air about this I had
some questions that you that you
addressed when we had earlier
discussions be
as one of the things that I've seen is
there's a lot of mixed opinions around
Trichoderma and mycorrhizal fungus you
know if you if you look at some of the
research and there's a variety of
research out there one of them was a
study at the University of Florida
showing that Trichoderma inhibited
mycorrhizal infection in plants along
with high phosphorus that one's fairly
well-established cuz you know one of the
main benefits of mycorrhizae is that
phosphorus or relationship so if the
plants already getting plenty of
phosphorus and thinks oh I don't need
this micro as a relationship even though
the mycorrhizae has a bunch of other
benefits that you already mentioned for
the plants so we want to avoid high P
early on after but you know before the
plant has time to get that infection but
would trichoderma
you know there's there's a lot of
different species of trichoderma so
which is I think important to
differentiate but then in addition to
that you know it's been shown to inhibit
spore germination and colonization of
you know mycorrhizal fungi particularly
the endo species what are your what are
some of your thoughts on that yeah so I
think that you know it definitely has
been documented that
Trichoderma can inhibit or can consume
my gradual spores or it can also sort of
inhibit them mycelium grows to a degree
I think there's a lot more testing that
needs to be done so there's also other
studies that show there's absolutely no
effect there's a there's a study out of
Spain that
can't see the University but I'm
actually looking at it right now
so they used trichoderma I don't I can't
see the species it's somewhere in here
but Columbus Moss a Glomus desert Accola
and they showed yeah I can't find the
Trichoderma species but they showed zero
effect on colonization so this study was
done in 2000 but yeah I think that I
think there's more research yet to be
done and what would we
seen in the studies that we did and in
our research that we accumulated before
we made the products is that there's
actually a symbiotic there's a there's a
beneficial effect using both of them so
you know there's certain benefits of the
Trichoderma provided and then there's
certain benefits that the mycorrhizal
fungi provides and you know i think when
they're used in combination you actually
get a little bit of both
and i don't think it's a black-and-white
thing i think like you said there's
there's so many different soil
conditions there's so many different
species and you know what we based our
for we have our products don't have
trichoderma
so once again we have the gamut of
products if you're interested in having
one with or without like our famous or
famous our one of our products the Orca
the liquid version of great white
doesn't have trichoderma so we have
products without it but that being said
great whites still my favorite products
which has the trichoderma in it once
again you know the benefits of the
trichoderma well one of them is just a
really really high enzyme release so
this one's breaking down organic matter
at a really fast rate compared to other
bacteria but also like I said there's
benefits that I can't make any claims
about but if you google Trichoderma you
know there's some bio pesticide research
about it so you know some people stagger
their inoculations right so they'll
inoculate with the mycorrhizae and then
they'll inoculate with trichoderma a
little bit later but one of the things
that i like to point out is that lab
conditions are so drastically different
from TRICARE from field conditions so
some of these studies you know
documented oh hey this is possible right
like so the trichoderma can become
antagonistic towards the mycorrhizae
fungi in a petri dish you know not
necessarily in a growing environment and
one thing about trichoderma is it's
absolutely everywhere so if you ever try
and culture like mushrooms indoors for
example oysters or shiitakes or anything
like that
one of the main you know things that
affects your your media is actually
Trichoderma so it's we're breathing it
in right now it's absolutely everywhere
and it's ubiquitous and soils so it's
already there and the question is how do
these things interact in the soil
environment and from you know as far as
we can tell there's a really big there's
there's a big benefit to actually having
it in your medium and whether or not you
stagger the inoculations you know that's
up to you but you know we've been doing
this for 15 years with the great white
and that's the product that has it in
there and growers just have tremendous
results I think if they're if they're
we've seen a benefit and we you know in
using both in combination I think in if
there is a situation where it's becoming
antagonistic to the micro fungi it's I
don't know I feel like people are
sometimes splitting hairs over this like
clearly using a product like great white
with trichoderma
outperforms non inoculation every time
and even when compared with saying that
for example a single species mycorrhizal
versus of you know a multiple species
mycorrhizae with multiple species
bacteria and Trichoderma it just
performs fantastic so I think there's a
lot more research yet to be done and I
don't think it's black and white
I think Elaine Ingham is a really
amazing researcher and a lot of her
actual field knowledge of how this stuff
performs in actual soil conditions is
very valuable and from the testing that
we've done and the feedback that we've
gotten from our friends and growers is
that it works really well so you know I
don't I don't think the the jury's in on
that but like I said I have access to
all of our all of the products here at
the company and I consistently you know
great white for me is the pinnacle oh
yeah you brought up a few different
points I want to touch on here so it's
it's pretty well established that
Trichoderma attacks mycorrhizae and
plate assays like you mentioned but
in in soils like like I've seen some
studies that show it does cause damage
to the mycorrhizal infection rates but
there's also other ones that show that
maybe the spatial distribution in soils
allowed both to function normally or to
have a synergistic positive interactions
so I think you really need to experiment
with it and then ultimately you might be
right that yes if it is the Trichoderma
that is providing the benefit like
that's something that Tim Wilson the
microbe organics is speculated for years
at the end of the day doesn't really
matter if you're getting a plant growth
response or plant Health's response that
you want anyway does it matter if it was
the Trichoderma or the you know my
kreizel infection that's providing these
benefits one thing I've always wondered
about though is really so like you
mentioned trichoderma is ubiquitous it's
it's an aggressive microbe when you're
putting in say a hundred and eighty
seven thousand CF use per gram how does
how does a endo micro rise that you know
a mere two hundred spores per gram our
property Gil's program really compete
compete in that space that's that's one
question I've always had about is sort
of the the difference in concentrations
I know Trichoderma is a lot more
affordable to add into these products
but why though why the different
discrepancy in the rates I guess yeah so
you know one thing is that you know the
great white in testing has shown you
know break my gradual colonization of
the root system so it's an effective
product and the mycorrhizae is still
infecting the plants or the successful
rate in terms of yeah the question you
know I'd have to ask the researchers on
that or the you know our tech ties
because I don't I don't know the answer
of that and and like you said I that
research of the spatial distribution is
important to allow each to sort of
function and not cannibalize you know
the Mike herb you know eat the micro Z
so yeah that's a good question
about
the concentrations but yeah like I said
at this point the product is successful
and works and has a high colonization
right but I don't know how that actually
plays out with the ratio there so that's
a good question
another one I'll have to do more
research on okay and you know to touch
on some of these other bacteria that you
have in in the product that I recognize
like bacillus subtilis that's in
serenade and a bunch of other products
as you know again particular species of
bacillus subtilis but that's another one
that's been shown to have a lot of
different plant benefits the bacillus
thuringiensis i can never pronounce it
the bt the israelis species is one
that's super useful when trying to
control fungus gnats and other issues
like that or caterpillars it's it's a
spray-on so that has a lot of benefits
and then I notice you have Saccharomyces
service a which is brewers yeast
essentially in there is that I I know
people are taking barley seeds and
grinding those up as a way of and as
something also from the brewing industry
and I've read some really wonderful
books on that particular fungus but do
you happen to know much more about why
what benefits that has in the soil so
that species specifically I am not well
I'm not a bacterial expert I will say
that to get though yeah I don't have
actually a ton of research on the sacrum
I deserve a CA besides the beer that I
threw you probably actually are more of
an expert on that than I am so yeah but
bacteria in general you kind of already
cover it but you know the sort of a lot
of them do a lot of the same things I'm
just kind of from a different different
species different angle but in general
you're getting you know nitrogen
fixation phosphorus solubilization
micronutrients ah legalization and
enzyme production
they also
to create organic glues like high carbon
glues that help with soil structure over
the long term and so yeah those are the
big benefits and and and that really
works in synthesis or in combination
with the mycorrhizae fungi in and help
with their needs and their sort of
ability to extract these micro nutrients
from the soil so you know we include
them we're more specialized we we cut
our teeth and and we started in the
mycorrhizal base and you know slowly
included bacteria in our product so like
I said I'm not an expert on the bacteria
but those are just sort of an overview
of what they do and what they add to our
microbe products okay I know there's a
lot we don't know as a you know as a
species about all of these things like
humans are still learning so much about
all of these different microbes and how
they interact and discovering new
microbes and so I I don't expect you to
have all the answers by any means right
but I we are seeing you know with all
this research that diversity really is
one of the most important things when it
comes to soil health so I mean I can see
why you would want to be applying a
diversity of microbes when you're yeah
yeah yeah one thing that blows my mind
is like the microscope has only been
around for like you know a hundred years
and and popular use for for less than
that so you know this whole world of
microbes is is just coming into focus
for us as a species and you know there's
hundreds of thousands of species out
there that aren't tested you know your
average compost bin is like talk about
diverse these are just the species that
we've isolated and actually ran through
the gamut of expensive testing to see
their benefits on agriculture and plant
growth but this is just the tip of the
iceberg there's there's so much extra
there's so many of them someone
diversity out there that we don't know
about and you know in general like you
said it's it's about diversity and it's
about sort of doing those things like
you know composting and compost teas and
you know all those practices that in my
mind they mimic natural systems right
this is this is how these the forest is
one of the most productive ecosystems on
the planet and it's all passive right
it's all everything leads into into
something else nothing's wasted so a lot
of what we're doing in my mind you know
we're learning more about how these
systems function but a lot of of what I
do and what we do as a company is really
just trying to mimic the best of these
these natural systems and their
efficiency so yeah there's a lot left to
learn I totally agree and I love the
idea of trying to just balance and
recreate these ecological systems like
you said that we know are highly
functional and sustainable so yeah
thanks for coming on the show today was
there anything else that I I'm out of
questions anything else you wanted to
touch on though before we go no I think
that that pretty much covers it all
right well I really appreciate your time
today thanks again and I look forward to
meeting you in person and talking again
soon thanks dad yeah I really enjoyed it
you can follow us on all the traditional
social media channels at great white
might go or plant success organics so if
people are interested in getting more
information you know reach out send us a
message and we'd be happy to help you
out answer any questions and read the
good word that was Jim Egan with plant
revolution I posted the links and
information we discussed in this podcast
right on the podcast page at WWE is
organics calm just click on the podcast
menu on the top of the home screen and
don't forget to sign up for our
newsletter on our website right on the
home page and subscribe on your favorite
listening platforms so you can stay up
to date with all the latest information
and podcasts right when they come out
you can also view and download the new
white papers and their results on our
website blog page I've gotten some great
feedback on them since posting and hope
to get Jaya Palmer back on the podcast
soon to discuss his methodology and how
he set up the trial thanks for listening
[Music]