[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts so far
please take a moment to subscribe on
iTunes or stitcher or whatever platform
you're listening on and leave me a
rating and review this is really helpful
and allows me to keep producing good
content by drawing more of the top names
in the industry to the show also sign up
for our newsletters on our website at
WWE
I send out a newsletter approximately
every two weeks and this is the best way
to ensure you know when the next podcast
has been released they also have the
latest discounts new product information
blog post and what's happening in the
industry our guest this week is Suzanne
Wainwright Evans she is an ornamental
entomologist specializing in integrated
pest management Suzanne has been
involved in the green industry for more
than 25 years with a primary focus on
Biological control and using pesticides
properly she is a graduate of the
University of Florida with degrees in
both entomology and environmental
horticulture she has worked throughout
the United States and internationally
consulting to greenhouses nurseries
landscapers and interior scape companies
additionally Suzanne is frequently
published in trade magazines and teaches
her workshops and lectures
professionally to industry groups her
lecturers use an extensive libraries of
insect photos and macro insect movies
that's actually how I met Suzanne she
really stole the show with her
presentation and I consider it a huge
honor that she was willing to come on
the podcast
she has also spoken at the Smithsonian
Institute as well as appeared on growing
a greener world on PBS she is the owner
of bug lady consulting now in business
for over 16 years
Suzanne lives in Pennsylvania with her
husband one dog and eight cats and a log
home built in the 1820s which is where I
caught up with her for this interview
now if you are a large-scale commercial
cultivator in our series about
consulting or setting up
IPM program utilizing beneficial insects
I can't recommend her enough her website
is WWE
and though if you're just looking to get
a few questions answered or have a small
medical grow and no budget for actual
consulting please try and attend one of
her upcoming talks rather than emailing
her she is a very generous person with
her time and wants to be able to help
everyone but her consulting schedule is
very full and is this is her livelihood
I assured her that she would not be
bombarded by emails after the show as
she is incredibly busy person already
she has a ton of information including
her upcoming events articles she's
written and much more on her website
please do check it out now before we
dive into this week's podcast I wanted
to give listeners a bit of background I
purposely kept the questions as general
as possible because as you will soon
learn with biological controls it's not
as simple as this bug eats that book
there's a lot of other information you
need to know starting with proper
identification and then looking at the
growing environment to determine what
bio controls would be most effective
it's really important to get an expert
with a background in entomology to
properly utilize these beneficial and
predatory insects now let's get on with
the show
alright well thank you so much for
taking some time today to chat with me I
really appreciate it and we are here
with Suzanne Wainwright evans also known
as the bug lady and Suzanne can you give
me a little bit of a background into how
you got into into this industry and why
bugs are so fascinating to you well
first thanks for having me it was really
great to meet you in person the other
week you're very impressive so I agreed
to do this because I really appreciate
you wanting to get good scientific
information out there and getting good
information to growers so they can
manage their pest issues but my
background I decided in middle school I
wanted to be an entomologist and that
was basically the path I set myself on
self on and I went to the University of
Florida where I have degrees in
entomology and environmental
horticulture and while I was in college
I worked in the horticulture /
agriculture industry doing many
different jobs so I've been in the
industry over 25 years and for the last
16 years I've worked for myself as an
independent insect consultant where I
don't sell I do not sell biocontrol
agents I don't sell pesticides my job is
basically to help growers put together
good pest management programs but a
little bit more focused on the
biocontrol options but I do have to
understand pesticides and how they work
and compatibility with biocontrol agents
because sometimes we don't have
biocontrol agents for some of our pest
issues so you do work within the
cannabis industry I know you've given
talks at canna con and then I just most
recently heard you at another conference
and beyond that though you do a lot of
work outside of the canvas industry with
the ornamental with ornamental crops and
things like that can you talk a little
bit more about the sorts of work that
you do yeah I work in I would I
generally what I say is I work in
everything but like soybeans and corn
and big outdoor AG I have customers that
are aquaponics producers where they're
growing fish and they're growing lettuce
I also work with some of the theme parks
dealing with insect pests in their
landscape where they're open for the
majority of the day and they can't
afford or they can't afford the time to
come in and spray or there's the public
perception of seeing people in spray
suits I work with large ornamental
growers I one of my growers they produce
four million points study as a year and
do a million hanging baskets so some
large scale operations all the way down
to some smaller greenhouses that
specialize maybe in edible flowers or
other specialty crops I like to work
with challenging situations and usually
people end up at me when they've tried
everything else and are just kind of
struggling with controlling pests and so
they hire me to come in and basically
figure out what's going on and and come
up with a strategy on how to manage
pests again with a bit more of a focus
on on bio control options great now one
thing I want to emphasize is that we
talked a little bit off off air before
this and you'd mentioned you'd only been
home for I think four weeks so far this
year you're obviously really busy and
your plate is full with consulting as it
stands now if you're listening to this
podcast and you are a large-scale
commercial grower or cultivator and you
need to bring someone in to help you you
would be able to potentially provide
consulting for that but you probably
don't have time for one or two emails
from that guy with three plants or five
plants or a small Grove so what kind of
resources would you recommend for
someone like that starting out who wants
to consider using beneficial insects and
you know wouldn't would necessarily fit
into your consulting schedule it's
challenging because even some of the
small growers you know small CSAs that
are maybe just like an acre or so have
the same kind of challenges of how do
you get current viable information for
their business when most most
publications you know they're they're
targeting large-scale commercial AG and
that's where a lot of the research is
done and it is a real challenge you know
I think sometimes you know having a
network of other growers to reach out to
is really important but unfortunately
what I've seen with in the cannabis
industries is there's some bad
information and it just keeps getting
perpetuated and perpetuated with the the
cut and paste ability of the internet
and even on some of the Facebook pages
where people are posting insects for
identification it you have people and I
see this as nice as you can who are just
not qualified to being able to identify
insects and I see people when they say
they're they're guessing but they say it
like it's fact and growers are
getting bad information a
misidentification with being cannabis
you know you don't have the options of
reaching out to extension with where
other people can but you can you know if
you do have an insect pest you can't put
the insect just in alcohol and as long
as it's not on the plant material you
could get someone to identify it for you
through extension just don't mention
post plant because once they find out
what the host plant is you know they're
not going to be able to help you because
of all the the money and everybody knows
the issue there I don't have to go over
that but there are going to be some more
resources coming I'm seeing more of the
traditional trade journals and magazines
that have focused on ornamental and
vegetable greenhouse production become
more involved in the cannabis industry I
was actually contacted this week by one
of the trade publications that are
interested in doing they want to talk to
me about doing an e publication on pest
management for specifically for cannabis
because cannabis has its own set of
challenges that some of the other
industries don't have but you know they
have different challenges that you know
the cannabis people don't have but I
mean as I've looked around resources are
pretty limited there are some books
available but I tell you I've read
through some of them and it just there's
just some of the information is good but
there's also bad information in there
and it's really hard for me once I look
at a resource that I know has bad
information how am I to trust anything
else that resource says so it's it's
it's a real challenge right now for
small cannabis growers to get good
viable
information I think that some of the
educational conferences might provide
some of that opportunity but again you
have to look at who's speaking what
their background is to qualify them to
be speaking and I've
attended some sessions for people that
are quote unquote cannabis pest
management experts and again I've seen
bad information given out there so you
know I wish I had a better answer but
it's a real challenge so it sounds like
starting with an Extension Service or
university is a good option one thing
you brought up with consultants is is a
good point that anyone can be a
consultant if they want to slap that
title behind their name and there's no
requirements for that one of the
challenges also with that is that these
consultants while they may may have a
good list of customers or clients that
they're working with that doesn't
necessarily mean that what they're doing
is optimal or the most successful option
there so I guess that that leads me to
where where do you like people to start
so if when you walk into a new facility
or a new situation what is the first
thing you're looking at I'm gonna I'm
gonna guess identification is that where
you like to always start when it comes
to these by problems or yeah we have to
know what you're dealing with and again
insect ID is really critical and I see a
lot of guessing and a lot of assumptions
and you know some insects are easier to
identify than others but some can be
extremely challenging
thrips is a good example and trying to
identify immature thrips is is it will
melt your brain it is so hard you really
need to be able to see adults and
ideally you do have to slide mount them
you have to spread their wings so when
somebody posts a picture online of an
immature thrips and everybody is like oh
it's this it's that it's this it's that
you know I went to college for seven
years for this and I've been doing this
for 25 years and I don't know so I don't
know how all these people magically know
so and that's what happens is is you
know people have gotten bad
identifications and pest management
options have not worked so when I do go
in we spend quite a bit of time on
identifying what the problem is I also
want to know what you've been doing
as far as what you've tried and you know
if something should have worked and
didn't work you know we spent a fair
amount of time on troubleshooting so you
had this problem this should have
controlled it but it didn't work why
didn't work just saying it didn't work
it's not good enough for me I want to
get in there and find out what went
wrong
so that we can correct the problem and
either not do that again or correct it
so it does work because sometimes it can
be applicator error you know whether it
be BIOS or spray products it can be the
rates were wrong
you know environmental conditions I mean
there is a whole list of things that can
go wrong when you're trying to treat for
pests pest issues and so figuring out
how we got there is is really critical
ah when I get into a facility that's a
really good point
one other thing because these are live
you know living organisms there's a
chance they could be coming in stressed
as well or dead one of the things he
talked about was identification of the
quality of the bugs that you're
producing you're you're buying or
purchasing and making sure that they're
arriving in a state where they're going
to want to eat whatever pest problem
you're dealing with the correct yes in
fact I've taught some workshops with
some I will call them co-workers but
they're not they don't work for me but
there are industry people that I trust
we've taught a couple times now around
the country how to assess the quality of
your bio control agents again being a
grower you know and what you have
available equipment wise and testing
wise you know it is kind of limited but
there are some you know quick down and
dirty things that growers can do just a
double check that said you know being in
this industry for many many years now
the quality has greatly improved we know
so much more now than we even did know
five years ago it's constantly evolving
getting better at shipping
better ventilation on packaging but one
of the most critical things and anybody
that knows me knows this I think it is
so important for your bio control agents
to be shipped to you directly from the
insector ii-if distributors when a sell
product that's fine but I don't like
when product goes from an insect or e to
a distributor they repackage or they
stick their label on it and they reship
out because that adds extra shipping
time also it's more time for the
temperature to fluctuate within it
within you know the shipping process
where you want to keep those biocontrol
agents at their consistent temperature
basically and until you're going to warm
them up and to be ready to use them so I
have seen situations with product that
have been sold through distributors not
drop shipped but through you know
distributors where the product has not
been so good I've also seen emails
saying hey we've got extra product this
week and offering it a discount but you
know when those insects are stressed or
dead or been cannibalized it's not going
to do a lot of good you know so I think
it's really important to get from a good
quality supplier and it can be
challenging because from you know being
in grows and stuff you know a lot of
people just like to go online order
stuff and pay through it through PayPal
but the key and sector ease that sell to
the US you just can't go order on their
website and pay with PayPal they're more
set up in a traditional purchasing
system it's where you need to contact in
Sector E and set up an account with them
which they do take credit cards but you
know I think that you're just you're
going to get a better quality product
you're going to get better information
now it can be challenging if you are a
hobbyist growers because you typically
need much smaller amounts and some of
the in secretaries do have minimum
orders and that may be a situation where
you may have to use a distributor but
you've just got to stay on top
making sure that product is is a quality
product before you go out because it
gaan there's no point in spending the
money and then the time of putting it
out if if they're not going to do what
they need to do so if you were let's
just say hobby grower Ella that's a good
term for that where would you start not
knowing as much about you know insects
as you do is there a company out there
that they could potentially call up and
place a smaller order if they can't go
directly to an insect or e and then on
the same note if I was a larger facility
or commercial grower and got a
recommendation from you or someone else
that's knowledgeable would I want to set
up an account directly with an insect er
e so one thing about the cannabis
industry is actually you guys are pretty
tight-knit and you guys visit each
other's grows which we can talk about
that later
yes but um and and back in the early
days like you know 20 years ago when
back then I actually did sell biocontrol
agents before we learned I'm a terrible
sale salesperson but what some of my
greenhouse people would do down in
Florida is to help save on shipping is
they pull their order all together and
they would come to one facility and then
people just drive over pick their stuff
up and take it back and so if you guys
do you know you have your friends around
that you know also grow you talk to each
other you know they could you guys could
pull your order together and then you'd
be able to meet some of these minimum
orders from insect erease and be able to
just do it that way is is one option the
other thing is and I don't know the
exact minimum orders for all the in
sector ease but I do think beneficial in
sector II I don't think their minimum
order is too high but remember you are
going to be paying overnight Freight on
this on these biocontrol agents and it's
very frustrating to people when they're
spending forty dollars on on bugs but
then you know fifty dollars on shipping
so you do have to look at the price of
shipping as part of the biocontrol
agents and of course your pricing on
shipping is going to depend on where
your
and you know how much you're actually
getting and things like that but
sometimes whether you buy one bottle or
six bottles your shipping might be the
same because you know there's that
basically the way they're doing more
shipping today it's based on you know
the size of the box and so oftentimes it
I'll tell my growers to do to is talk to
them and if you know you're ordering two
bottles per symbolist you know ask them
how much it is to just go ahead and fill
out the rest of that box because putting
out extra is not necessarily going to
hurt anything and just spending a little
more money to get things SuperDuper
cleaned up might be worth the time
because you're paying the shipping
anyhow on that but the best thing to do
is is look at your needs contact and in
Sector E and see what their minimum
order is for where you are and see if
they can do that but if not there are
smaller distributors that will break
down these larger orders for you but
again you do sometimes can run the risk
of the product being a day or two older
some things can handle it if they've got
a food source you know they tend to do
okay things like sachets can handle it
but when you get into some of the
predatory mites that don't have food it
can it can impact the quality of the
product and especially again if you get
that warming and cooling and any
condensation in the bottle that can
really be an issue now I realize we just
kind of dove right in without ever
talking about exactly why this is so
important I don't want to spend a lot of
time on it because I think a lot of our
listeners are pretty savvy but why are
we really using bio controls why is why
is this industry so important in such a
solution because I know for me when I
first found out about people using
beneficial insects I was I was initially
pretty skeptical of it and to me I
didn't realize how much there was to
know I guess I started out thinking okay
you have this bug I'm dealing with two
spotlights well I get this is the
solution and not realizing that there
were all these other factors like
lighting humidity temperature and and so
much more that went into choosing the
right beneficial insect to deal with the
right past
to make sure it was successful because
I'm sure there's a lot of people out
there buying the wrong insects for the
wrong pests and wasting a lot of money
so yeah do you want to touch on that
just a little bit so I'm going to talk
about let's talk about overall
agriculture as a whole because I mean
cannabis now as part of agriculture the
number one driving force behind the use
of biocontrol agents is because people
cannot manage their pests with spray
products anymore their resistance to
chemical pesticides is a very big factor
it's just like how people have taken
over taken a taken too many antibiotics
and so now a lot of the diseases that
humans get are resistant to antibiotics
the exact same thing has happened with a
lot of these key pests like aphids and
thrips and to spot spider mites they've
had so much exposure to chemicals there
they're not if a lot of people say oh
they mutate it's not that it's it's
they're selecting for insects and mites
that are able basically to metabolize
the pesticide and it doesn't kill them
or people use what is called a sub
lethal dose where they the pests are
exposed to lower doses of a product and
it doesn't kill them but it allows them
to build up resistance to it and that's
why it's very dangerous
when people are like well I don't really
want to spray chemicals so I'm just
going to you know use a real low rate
below what's on the label because that
really contributes to having the pest
resistant to these chemistry's and what
has happened again you know to spotted
spider mites white flies Western flower
thrips a foods I mean you look at -
spotted spider mites they're resistant
to 95 different chemistry's now because
of exposure to chemical pesticides so
this has been overall an agriculture the
driving force is because they can't
management manage them I don't get calls
from growers saying well
oh I care about the drinking water and I
care about no it's oh my gosh I can't
just I can't control these pests we have
to do something and so that really is
what has gotten the ball rolling now
what has happened to is is there are
things called MRLs as our maximum
residue levels and that's what they're
looking at with produce now we're okay
yes this chemical is illegal to spray on
this this vegetable but you can only
have so much of that chemical on it so
you can't just spray that chemical over
and over and over again even though it's
legal to be applied there so people are
looking to break up their spray programs
by using these biocontrol agents so they
don't spray as much now the cannabis
industry can be like well hey you know
we haven't been using these pesticides
and so you know our pest problems
shouldn't be resistant first of all come
on you guys all know the chemicals you
guys have been spraying and it's pretty
poor I hear you laughing cuz you know
what I'm talking about I do
ideally growers would contact me ten
years ago
you know and hey I'm growing tomatoes
I've got spider mites you know it then
there was no concern for human safety
and I don't think it was at a malicious
Witness it was out of just ignorance of
not understanding you know combustion of
pesticides connage concentrations of
pesticides into oils off of plants and
the impacts now there's actually
regulatory rules by the states for which
chemicals you can use and so okay fine
you know we're not using Avid we're not
using flora might the problem is is what
is the rest of the agricultural
community using uh you know if if the
the ornamental guy down the way is doing
a rotation of spider my of avid and
flora might and hexagon and ovation and
he develops resistance if those two
spots spider mites do get into your grow
they already have that resistance so
even though you may have not if you
those chemicals you have a resistant
population and that's how we have had a
major problem controlling this
particular white fly species in the
United States believe it or not it the
problem actually originated in Spain and
they overused chemistry's there to the
where the white flies were resistant and
that population of white flies got into
the United States and has spread so even
though you may not be spraying the
chemicals the pest pop population you
have may have been exposed to it through
multiple generations and so they can be
resistant just to state the obvious here
I assume you're getting good results
when people are following a proper bio
control program you're able to control
or eradicate some of these pest problems
okay first of all destroy the word
eradicate from your vocabulary there is
no such thing even you know back in the
80s and 90s the chemical guys we talk
about eradicating pests now when they
talk about pest management they talk
about suppressing it being below an
economic threshold because you're not
going to be able to eradicate it it's
it's growing a plant that's pretty darn
clean and you know you're not seeing
pest issues and you're not seeing damage
because eradication is just it just does
not happen anymore
so if we had to spot mites or thrips or
brood a fence whatever pest in in a in
an indoor facility let's say so a more
controlled environment we should assume
that those will always be there for the
life of the facility or you know for
multiple crops it's very possible you
know especially if you know have any
kind of hydroponic system setup if
you're using any kind of NFT or where
your urban flood benches especially Rudy
fits you're just going to spread them
and spread them and spread them all it
takes is one being left behind and for
the cannabis industry they don't have
some of the I will air quote stronger
chemistry's that can really knock back a
pest issues they just don't have it as
an option your best thing to do is not
get
the problem but to be honest I think the
cats out of the bag on that
I mean they've just spread all their
problems far and wide between everybody
at this point yeah let's talk about that
a little bit so some of the things that
we're seeing are a lot of problems with
people sharing sharing clones or
spreading you know spreading pests back
and forth
what sorts of things do you recommend
just basic common-sense things that you
think every grower should be doing when
it comes to getting in new genetics or
even just basic bio controls around the
around the facility well every time you
bring new plant material into a facility
you it is a gamble and we're still
trying to wrap our hands around exactly
all the pest problems you potentially
could have it seems like you know new
new pests are popping up that you know
it's not that you can't say well we
didn't think it'd be on cannabis you
just didn't think about it being on
cannabis and it's turning out to be
cannabis is a pretty good host for a lot
of a lot of problems and now that we're
seeing more industrial hemp being grown
outside we're really learning more about
which pests attack it which are a lot of
your common agricultural pests they're
moving right over from you know
vegetable and grain production right
into cannabis stuff but you know if you
cannot bring stuff in which I know is
because you need to get new genetics you
know that that's how people are getting
problems these hem present mites are not
a government conspiracy that the
government is breeding and blowing at
you're laughing again but I know people
believe that it's not part of a weed bio
control program it's a different speed
it's it's it's not even might that's
close to the hemp Russert might you get
him present might because somebody
brought it in on a plant material or
their clothing
and it's kind of been a little self
itself done so if I were to build my
ideal green house today I would
definitely have a quarantine facility
where you would hold all new plant
material just to make sure that it's not
coming in with any pests I also think
that dipping cuttings is going to be the
best way to stop new new things from
coming in the ornamental industry is
really starting to embrace this
technology of dipping cuttings because
then you get a hundred percent coverage
I'm not going to say you're going to
radically single pests on there one
hundred percent but you can get pretty
significant knock back it's a practice
that even people that have their own
stock mother plants in their facility
are when they take those cuttings
they're dipping them before they stick
them even even in house stuff just to
stop that constant cycle of of these
pests so you know having quarantine
facility keeping things isolated dipping
cuttings and just it's all about
sanitation practices and and you know it
just
Cannabis people just need to learn more
about sanitation if you get an
opportunity to ever I recommend for
canvas people go to or some of the
ornamental production facilities that
are doing things like geraniums like you
can't just go in and touch plants with
your bare hands you have sanitation you
got to wash your hands you have to you
know use alcohol things like that to
make sure you're not spreading any
pathogens and granted not all ornamental
facilities have quarantines and do all
the right stuff but they have more
options to clean their products up and
their pests they're dealing with may not
completely destroy their crop and the
cannabis crop value is much higher per
plant than ornamentals you know it's
it's just you can afford to throw away
you know ten pansy plants and it's no
big deal you can't afford to do that
in a cannabis facility also a human
transmission I think is really something
that needs to be look at because most
people that work at a facility grow at
home and it's very easy to transport
those pests back and forth when you go
to a grow facility or you have guests
visiting you know have they been at any
other grows that day because if they
were in an infested grow they swipe
their sleeve up against a plant can pick
up pests there is potential for them
that it possible they brush up against
another plant you know they could spread
it spread insects and mites that way
chance of been happening I don't think
anybody's looked at the you know the
exact risk of that but it could
definitely happen and so protocols of
you know tie-back suits you know lab
coats hand-washing stations all that
stuff I think is so critical and I just
don't see those kinds of things at the
the cannabis facilities being
implemented so in your ideal facility
you'd have no one doing home grows and I
assume no one going from another grow
back to your greenhouse they would have
to go home shower change clothes or a
dress that would you have foot baths in
place do you think those are useful it
depends on how you're growing you know
places that have cement floors I was at
a place this last week you could have
eaten off their floors there was so
meticulous and the chances of a pathogen
being able to survive in those kind of
environments and again it depends on the
pathogen are much slimmer than those
that have little dirt piles and or on
gravel or outdoor production facilities
but I will say you know I'm not
pathologist that's you know the diseased
person Department to look at what the
risk is for disease transmission where
I'm more dealing with insect issues I
also you know the the tobacco mosaic
virus you know a lot of people say oh
well you know I plant you know you can
see some of them
the the symptoms in the plant but I'm
still getting my same amount of harvest
I think is a very risky uh attitude to
have because then if you are taking
cuttings off of those plants and then
Reaper Appa gating you know we don't
want to be spreading a virus you know
through through all the plants out there
and I don't know really if there's been
enough looked at the long-term impact of
this virus on cannabis and what if you
have a secondary problem that those two
problems then could completely stress
the plant out so smoking is something
that you know has to be looked at
because you know do some reading on
tobacco mosaic virus again not exactly
my department because it's mechanically
transmitted by hands and cigarettes and
all that but you know I I think that's
that's a risk you need to look at you
know most vegetable production
facilities do not allow their employees
to smoke because a potential virus
transmission from cigarettes have you
actually seen lab results showing
tobacco mosaic virus in cannabis and
then have you heard of it being
transferred from cigarettes okay so I
have seen pictures of the plants that
they and I did not physically see the
actual report I'm going on them saying
that the report came back positive for
it so in that situation because you know
I can't be all places at all times and
you know I'm in Pennsylvania where
cannabis is just starting over here but
you can get those eliza
test kits like from AG dia that you can
do that quick first initial virus
testing in-house to see if you do get a
positive before paying to send it off
for further virus testing it's just a
quick way to make sure oh because it
could be nutritional it could be
cultural there could be other things so
at least it's a quick way to do that and
I've talked to other people in a
cannabis industry and I will say they've
seen
to know what they're talking about that
this is a concern for them and it will
be interesting to see what happens with
more of the hemp being grown outdoors in
traditional tobacco States to see if you
know it becomes an issue for outdoor
production as well on that so it's just
something to keep an eye out for again
we don't have the answers for everything
because this is such a new new
developing industry and there just
hasn't been a lot of research on it yet
but it does from the report and again
once you get into biology testing and
stuff you know you can get a positive
for one virus when it can be another
virus it gets very complicated but I do
think it's something we need to watch
for and again it's all part of
Sanitation one thing you touched on is
that these these pests seem to be
opportunistic like they prefer you
mentioned plant stress being a factor
how much of a factor is plant stress in
terms of a lot of these pests well when
you say stress um I you know there's
this race to push the plans and again
this is not this is just not cannabis
this is ornamentals they push the plants
want them to grow fast they want them to
be dark green you want nice big blooms
or buds on anything but there is a lot
of support of research now on ornamental
and vegetable crops that when you push
these plans to grow and the plants are
actually growing at a faster rate the
plants can't can't produce a lot of
their natural defensive chemicals and
you know the plants natural defenses
chemicals that includes you know
caffeine nicotine things like that those
are built-in insecticides pyrethrins but
if you're busy growing you can't produce
as many chemicals and you become more
susceptible they've done work looking at
roses and chrysanthemums and they've
actually found by reducing
parts-per-million of nitrogen it can
have significant impact on spider mite
population and Western flower thrips
population so the
something in ornamentals that we're
trying to do you know we're still we
have to grow on a schedule because you
got to get those plans out for Mother's
Day you got to have the poinsettias out
in time for Christmas sales and all that
but we're looking at can we lower
nitrogen levels to where we can help
suppress some of these plants you know
some of the pest pressures but still
grow a healthy quality plant and so with
cannabis you know it's it's you know
more is not better but it seems to be
the motto of this industry of just
dumping every a lot of different stuff
on the plants but I do think this is
something that needs to be looked at is
you know if we can adjust fertilization
to we can still get your same amount of
harvest but reduce your pest pressures
and it takes research and it takes
someone willing to do the research and
unfortunately that's still not going to
be done on a government University
Extension level it takes a growing
facility that's willing to take the time
to do that and to understand research
and how to do it so this is a question
I'm really curious about I hear a lot of
people correlating Brix levels with pest
resistance do you have any information
on that in terms of the the sugar
content in the leaf somehow making a
plant less interesting to a particular
pest well I don't have too much comment
on it because usually you know when
you're talking about brick stuff usually
talking about fruit production because
they're trying to look at the sugars
that way but there was an interesting
study done University of Maryland I
believe it was dr. mike rupp I have to
go back and look but they were looking
at brown marmorated stink bug which you
know we're seeing in cannabis hanging
out and a feeding on the plant they
looked on trees ornamental trees in the
landscape where the brown marmorated
stink bugs were feeding and there's this
in its you know I don't want this job
but somebody does this job where they
actually can when an insect is feeding
you can almost you can basically cut off
their mouthparts and then it works
basically as a needle and
oh then you can collect from the end of
the broken off mouth part where exactly
the insect was feeding they do this leg
with aphids to see what they're feeding
on what part of the plant and the sugar
content and they found that brown
marmorated stink bug knew exactly on
trees where to tap into higher sugar
levels as to them in the plants and
that's with a head for because sugar
content in a plant is not evenly
distributed and so it's something that's
starting to be looked at but I don't
have an exact scientific answer with it
it may be anecdotal there may be
something to it but if you know you're
pushing one plant to do one thing that
it typically can't do another thing you
can you can only do so much at once well
it does appear that when you have a room
of plants the most stressed plant will
be the first one that you'll see pests
on in in mind but unless you have a very
susceptible cultivar yes and that's the
thing - and I think it's really really
beautiful for the cannabis industry to
be tracking okay we're growing these
these 10 cultivars but you know number 9
always seems to be the first with a
spider mite outbreak that needs to be
noted and people need to be sharing that
information so that even though you know
maybe it has some other great qualities
you know selecting for cultivars that
have more resistance issue resistance
resistant issues is the right word but
resistance to them so that maybe you may
give up some other little quality but
selecting for plants that don't have
pest issues saw that in chrysanthemum
production there's a variety called
viren that is a you want Western flower
thrips you grow that variety and most
commercial growers do not grow it
anymore because it is so prone to
Western flower thrips even though it has
a nice flower to it and what ended up
happening is people actually use it as a
trap plant where they would put it in
the middle of their other mums and it
would actually draw the western fly
northrop's right to the viral then they
would bag the fire on and get rid of the
plant and they would actually pull the
pests out that way but there's a
definite correlation between stress and
cultivar deciding on okay who's going to
get fed on and who's not going to get
fed on have you seen I want to come back
to the indicator trap plant in
pollinator plants but before we do I
just want to touch on other things like
I've heard there were some studies I've
read some studies on seaweed helping
with insect resistance have you done any
research or read anything on that I mean
I know that I mean so you know seaweeds
have cytokinins in them and that from
what I've seen in personal experience is
it does definitely help with overall
plant growth I've not seen and this is
also where when you look at research you
have to specifically look at how the
research was done and who did the
research and where was it published and
is it peer reviewed because you know
you've got the whole thing today of you
know pay to publish and you could have
some really bad science but you can pay
a journal to publish it for you and that
doesn't mean it's actually good sound
science and so that's why you got to be
very careful with reading some of the
stuff and and the sources and also look
how the experiments are done what one
example of you know people were looking
at silicon because it was like oh you
use silicon it thickens the cuticle and
then you don't have as many pest issues
well there were some initial work done
where they put silicone on plants and
then they looked at mealy bugs on them
but they saw no difference well the
problem was is the crop they were using
was not a silicon accumulator and you
see this that just because you use
something on one plant doesn't mean
you're going to get the same results on
another plant because plants are picky
about what nutrients they're going to
uptake and in what form and in what
quantities and you know this is where
maybe seaweed may work in some
situations and some even some media's
but may not in another also you've got
to have a
roll when you do the test to make sure
that it's something not environmental or
something else that's causing the
results that you think you're seeing
that's a really good point I'll have to
go back and look it was a book called a
seaweed in plant growth by TL Sen which
was a collection of research articles
that he sort of he sort of went over and
I remember reading about it but I'll
have to go back and look and you do
bring up a really good point that we try
and emphasize and just about every
podcast that people do need to have a
control they need need to look at an
actual study and see how it was how it
was established and how it was set up
and make sure the mythal methodology
fits with what they're looking to draw
from it so those are all really good
points moving on though I would love to
ask you this is one that I know we
talked about a little bit when we met
was about neem and neem oil and how you
mentioned it was not your favorite can
you touch a little bit on that sure I'm
not saying neem oil is bad let me put
that out there cuz I don't want to get
all these you know hate emails you know
but from my personal experience doing
you know what I do virtual oils or not
oils or not oils or not oils you know
there's a reason you cook with Wes and
oil there's a reason we used you know
different kinds of oils for you know
make up and there's different kinds of
oils then that we use for pest
management
there's particle size difference they
some of them you know are mix better
into water than others you know there's
some that do better in certain you know
spray equipment that don't cause
clogging the thing with neem oil is
people like oh you know it's from a
plant so you know we're crunchy granola
is that's great I hate the petroleum
industry so I don't want to use
petroleum-based products well if you
hate petroleum-based products you better
stop driving your car and you know
heating your house and you know drinking
out that plastic cup unfortunately you
know petroleum is part of our lives I
would be great if it wasn't the way it
is but that's the reality just because
something is a plant-based product does
not mean it is always safe for humans
always say for the
you know that's that's a big
misconception that people you know think
that just because it's it's plant based
it's saved
I'm not saying neem is not safe but neem
is a product that is regulated by our
government and it has to be registered
you know and have an EPA registration
number on the products because of its
insecticidal properties where my concern
comes in is we know neem is a good
repellent there's some good research out
of Purdue looking at neem is a repellent
for like Japanese beetles where they
spray a plant with neem they have
another point they haven't sprayed with
neem and sure enough the Japanese
beetles tend to pass up a bit more the
plant with the neem on it because it has
a repelling quality so if you spray that
on a plant and you want to release
biocontrol agents and again you've got
to look at each individual biocontrol
agents you can't say it with a broad
sweeping blanket but there's a chance
you can repel your beneficials off the
plants I've seen biocontrol agents just
go to the stems and walk down in March
off plants because they don't want to
live there there is some research done
where they have sprayed plant material
with neem and then put some of the
predatory mites on there and the
predatory mites choose to leave because
of the repelling quality on there so if
you're not going to use biocontrol
at all sure go for it but if you think
you're going to be using biocontrol
agents you better think about this now
if you're growing outside you know we've
got overhead irrigate you know rain or
irrigation you know UV light stuff's
going to break down a lot faster but
most people are not growing outside
they're growing you know in a protected
environment where they're not overhead
irrigating and and compounds didn't
pretend to persist for longer how long
don't really know because there hasn't
been a ton of work done on this yet but
it is just something if my grower has
the option then they're using bios
between using neem or product
soyal X you know I prefer them to use
the saw file X because once that's dry
we found that the predatory mites do
extremely well on the plants after that
we don't get that repelling quality with
with the product and you know some oil
ax yeah I got a look at your state and
see if it's approved in your state or
not I know it's proved down in like
Colorado but you know it's an armory
listed product so it's a proof used in
organic production it's being used in
vegetable production and it's an oil
that I very rarely see photo toxicity
with the other thing back to knee neem
is not neem is not neem there's
different producers of it there's
different processes so you know you
really got to if you're going to pick a
product you really need to learn that
product and and understand it and know
how to use it in your growing system
yeah I've seen huge differences like
over a thousand ppm difference in as
interacted levels across different neem
oils so I totally agree with you on that
yeah I didn't realize it was such a
repellent so you mentioned some oil X
well I looked into this after the first
time you mentioned it to me and it's a
tough product for most people to get
their hands on unless they are a
large-scale commercial grower so your
alternative you mentioned was the
Monterey garden horticultural oil yes
said it was the same or a similar
product yes and that one people should
be able to source and find even on
amazon.com now for that which brings us
back to dunking your clones so I'm going
to throw myself under the bus and say
when I brought some clones home they
were already in small plants they were
in soil already so I wanted to treat
them because I didn't know if they were
if they had something on them so I
dumped them in a five-gallon bucket that
I had filled with a neem oil and green
cleaner combination at 5050 oh my god
well I want to get your thoughts on this
and the the plants even dunked the soil
the whole thing and the plants took it
fine actually they didn't really freak
out and put them under
a lot of light right after but what do
you recommend
well first off I'll let you cover what I
did wrong and why you think this is a
terrible idea but then secondly what do
you recommend for people that are
bringing in plants that are already in
soil because most people are not passing
clones like they do in the ornamental
industry where it's just the leaf tissue
it's usually in rock wool or it's in
peat or some sort of media already right
well I've just okay so what is hard is
when you have products and you don't
have a good dip rate because when you
look at the research on dips dip rate is
lower typically then spray rate and
until somebody has you know figured out
what that rate by dipping them in there
and growing the plant out and make sure
there's no negative impact you don't
necessarily know and when you are
dealing with mixing up just a small
quantity of a pesticide a small error
can be a big error and you know it's
easy to go wrong so there was research
done out of Canada looking at dips with
soil X and I will say that for the
ornamental market currently there is not
a dip label yet even though the research
has been done but this spray rate for
the stuff oil is typically 1 to 2% where
the dip read is 0.1 percent that's a
huge difference from spraying to dipping
where they felt they got good enough
pest control without pausing fido on a
phyto toxicity you know damage to the
plant and do keep in mind you can have
photo toxicity that is not visible to
the human eye it can plants can be
stressed and kinam and it can impact
their growth without us actually seeing
burning or curling or spots or things
like that so that dots there now what I
always do we start talking about dipping
is we look at what the plan is and what
your target pest is to see what dips are
out there for you I
you do have to be careful with any kind
of oil and dipping roots because there
is potential for Fito toxicity on the
roots but again it comes back to product
and raids and temperatures and you know
as your plant stressed even before you
dip did you soak it too long because
it's a dip it's not a soak you know we
have to look at all these factors but
for some of the other pests
you know dipping in the botanic garden
something that's being done regularly
you can dip in in soaps and there are
once you go look at the labels and look
for the dip rates you can find these
recommended rates and like with the
Tanner guard which again it that that's
a whole nightmare because like down in
Colorado you can't use the Tanner guard
but you can do Tanner guard max but
you're not going to have a high enough
concentration but various bores really
to do what you need to do for that it's
getting unfortunately very complicated
but just saying that you can mix
products for dips it's best to look at
what your target pests are what your
plant is and try to find the right tip
for you and you may need to do some some
testing and and to grow out plants and
when you do dip monitor those plants all
the way through their lifecycle and see
if you do notice anything and in the
long run but dipping is the way that
many greenhouse people are stopping pest
from getting in the door I have no idea
that the dip rates could vary that much
when I did it I think I used the low end
of the spray rate and I didn't let it
saturate the soil to really get into the
root zone but you know I didn't know
what I was doing either so I really
appreciate that feedback that's really
interesting so can we talk a little bit
about some of the products that you may
or may not have experience with one of
the things that I think is important for
people to realize in the industry is
that products that aren't EPA regulated
whereas certain certain ones are like
I'll use neem is an example of that
they're claiming to be plant washes or
leaf shine products as a way of getting
around having to do or not having the
ability to get red
the EPA as a pesticide do you have any
experience or do you have any thoughts
first off on plant wash or plant shine
products and then can we talk a little
about some of the products you may have
used or seen other growers use over the
years it's it's a gamble you know using
products that have not been what I will
say is vetted it is a risk it's kind of
like going down to the farmers market
and buying herbal medicine and when I
say over medicine I'm not talking about
cannabis but you know what I mean it's
you know supplements because it's not
regulated so you don't really know what
truly you're getting because basically
you know you can break things down into
you know you have your government
registered products which have will have
an EPA registration number and that will
include again your name products your as
interact in products your synthetic
pesticides insecticidal microbial
products then we have what's called the
twenty five B list and these are
products that basically the government
said several years ago okay we know
these products are pretty much food
grade and if you make your pesticides
fungicides insecticides - sides whatever
out of them
we are not going to require you to pay
the millions of dollars to get them
registered but that doesn't mean the
products work that means you as a grower
you're just not going to kill yourself
or your employees by using these
products again it's a lot of food based
products but there is no there's no
testing really or no vetting through any
kind of agency for them and then there's
the well we're just going to not make
pesticidal claims we're going to go with
with we're calling it a wash kind of
thing which i you guys all know what's
been going on with the plant washes what
they're finding in them what they're
finding in some of these other products
I mean people are lying and they're
adding other pesticides into them to
make their products work better and it's
a risk if you are willing to take those
risks and possibly you know lose a crop
because of pesticide contamination you
know that's that's a risk some people
are willing to take but I don't think
they understand that there's on these
25b products there's no there's no not
there's nothing to be like proof of them
working or any testing or really
anything like that so it's it's it's a
tough it's a tough thing not to say
there can be these 25 B products that
can be good products but most of them
are all dependent on spray coverage and
how well can you spray and cover your
plant because if you can suffocate it
with an oil most likely you can kill it
but you know you don't always know
what's in these bottles you're getting
unless you actually are having them
tested to make sure of what they're
claiming is in there is in there because
again there have been too many
incidences now of these plant washes or
even some of the 25 B products where
people have knowingly put pesticides in
there to make them work better
interestingly enough so that stuff I
just talked about it used to be sold
years ago at a very dilute rate called
clean and shine and so it was a plant
cleaner and it was abused they would
spray down a lot of the tropicals to
wash off pesticide residues and things
like that but the rate is so low as a
foliar application it really didn't have
those insecticidal properties where you
need to be at like the 1 to 2 percent
concentration of the product and see the
insecticidal properties from it so it's
a gamble it's a complete gamble you know
if you got a product that it's not EPA
registered I would first of all have it
tested for any other pesticides in it
because again cannabis is too expensive
of a crop to take a risk on and then you
know you'd want to you know only test a
plant have a control next to it just to
make sure that you aren't going to have
any photo toxicity or other weird things
happening from it and also does it
actually
work I think what's happening a lot with
these these exempt products is is when
you have three or four plants and you
can get such good spray coverage the
water is doing a lot for you so I think
what's happening is that people that
just have a few plants or plants that
are well spaced and that are in those
plants looking over every inch every day
when they spray I think the water is
actually washing a certain percentage of
the pest off the plants there was
actually a study done I think it was
last year the year before where they
looked at you know Western flower thrips
and by getting good spray water coverage
they were actually able to pretty much
knock thrips back to the point of
conventional insecticides they were at
the same level but they were able to get
in there and get spray coverage on every
single leaf and really baby those plants
also in some of these products they have
surfactants surfactants are soaps so
it's almost like you're spraying the
plant tooth and insecticidal soap so I
think the physical action of washing
plus having a surfactant in there
sometimes I think that's what's
providing a lot of the control not
actually the active ingredient so with
one of my ornamental larger growing
operations we actually have them order
in and I don't want to get into brand
names but some of them are air-quote
popular cannabis products and we sprayed
them like we would regularly spray in a
greenhouse we didn't do you know dot
wand where you get under every leaf
because the reality is is and larger
commercial growing operations you can't
do that but we sprayed them and we
actually did a dipping too and we saw a
lot of photos photo toxicity and we
really didn't get the control that was
claimed by the products so you know we
just the the commercial ornamental
people and vegetable guys they're not
adopting the
a lot of these products because we just
don't see the efficacy with it because
they can't spray like the cannabis
people can spray and baby
each plant so would be interesting when
you spray brand name product then I
would spray you know another plant with
you know a surfactant and then have your
control and see if you see the
difference have a control would just
spraying water and see what kind of
results you get and please please please
stop spraying with paint sprayers I I
don't understand this trend either paint
sprayers are not pesticide applicators
they're not designed they don't have the
the nozzles
I think investing in a good piece of you
can get the right particle size you know
the the the angle nozzles and all that
kind of stuff is is really critical I
don't understand why people you know
have these plants with so much money and
they baby them so much and then they
cheap out using a paint sprayer to spray
their plants so do you have a
recommendation on that in like an
atomizer or a fog or anything like that
I think that this is when you talk to a
company that produces spray product for
what are you doing are you a greenhouse
producer are you a field producer you've
got to get the right equipment for what
you're doing and you know that the
different tips which this is really
where you get into specifics on that
I think DRAM is an excellent company
that produces really good quipment
that's pretty much the company that most
commercials commercial growers have
their products they see DRAM equipment
all the time in greenhouses but again
depending on how you're spraying and
what you're spraying and what you're
doing it can all be very different yeah
we buy their hoses I've had great
success with that company as well so
yeah they're nice people and they're
smart people Kurt Becker plug out to
that guy and don't bombard him with
emails you know Sara Lee but he is so
knowledgeable on spray equipment if you
ever get the opportunity to hear Kurt
talk it is you know I always learn from
him and
and he is he really knows his stuff and
he's not a bullshitter I'm sorry my lad
swear I just did sorry you're all good
totally fine
so I gotta give me beep over that when
you go back no I give all these the
explicit rating just in case so there's
no like talk about kids trying to learn
how to grow cannabis on a side note
though so I have a I have a greenhouse
and we grow a variety of different crops
and this year I got mites which I did
not do the right thing and fully
identify bee but I didn't plan on
treating them I was just going to let
the crop go anyway at the end of the
season so my question is overwintering
in greenhouses so for growers that are
growing cannabis and have the ability to
just open up that greenhouse in the
winter and let let it freeze or let
temperatures drop down to to lower
conditions is that a good idea does that
even make any difference in the
lifecycle for a lot of these pests it it
all depends on the pests also do you
have cement floors or do you have gravel
floors where you know if they're gravel
where they can get down lower and can be
protected which is different than a
cement floor which is going to be naked
and they're going to be exposed and also
how cold can you really get it I will
just say this somehow miraculously
outside you know pests overwinter every
winter even in some of the harshest
conditions but the difference between
outside and in a greenhouse is outside
you know days get shorter temperatures
start drawing dropping and all the
animals birds you know deer insects mice
I'll get their cue oh it's wintertime we
have to prepare for winter depending on
the insect or might they all overwinter
differently summer eggs summer pupae
some are adult and some can handle
cooler temperatures than others it's a
tough thing to do to really freeze out
pests completely especially when you're
probably going to bring them right back
in on your plant material in the spring
anyhow
yeah where my concern what also was that
we have some straw bales and
and I'm wondering if I'm contaminating
those straw bales with these mites is
that a canal
what are they gonna what are they going
to feed on I mean if you think about
mites or you know they don't have a hard
exoskeleton like beetles to help from
desiccation you know bring home a bean
leaf with spider mites on it which just
reminded me of spider mites and
refrigerator I forgot about crap they're
probably dead by now but bring home a
leaf with some spider mites on it and
you know put in a petri dish and see how
long those might survive
not that long they really are I mean
they're hearty but they're not Hardy
when they don't have good environmental
protection
I think plants Brie is more of an issue
but geez my spider mites are not going
to go oh look I want to live in a straw
hay bale where there's no food source
for me they can't overwinter just go
dormant or anything like that I don't
know enough about their lifecycle
honestly I need to do a little research
well the to spot spider mites they for
outside go into what's called diapause
and they start turning more pumpkiny
orangish in the fall and then they go
overwinter in that stage but again for
screenhouse you don't get those
conditions and you know with aphids a
Fitz feed on one plant but they
overwinter on an alternate host so you
got to know your pests and you've got to
understand its life cycle yeah you bring
up a fence so having a edible nursery on
our property as well we have a lot of
different plants and I always get a fits
on our nester ships every year and I as
it was explained to me the lifecycle of
an aphid part of it was that these ants
will farm them as a way of getting more
of that the sugary substance I think you
had a name for it
honeydew had the honeydew correct and
then I thought it was a predatory wasp
that was eating the aphids but I from
the talk I got the impression that was
actually wrong when you spoke about it
okay parasitic wasps predator it's a
parasitic wasp because we kind of break
down into predators and parasites or
redditors tend to you know they're more
like lace wings and ladybird beetles
that eat them where the parasites are
parasites you know I'm sticking my egg
in you and I'm going to you know eat you
from the inside out kind of thing so
with a foots there are many of those
parasitic wasps available for sale but
you've got to get the right pair of
sight for the right a food pest so you
have to know at aphid you're dealing
with and then you have to see if there
is a commercially available a parasitic
wasp for it then get it and be able to
release it so would I be better off just
hosing that down I I did notice the wasp
was landing on those things but it never
really got a head I guess of my aphid
population and I would put diatomaceous
out earth out as a way of helping
control the ants which is another thing
I wanted to talk to you about was de but
in terms of treating Athens is just
water the best option there in terms of
just hosing them off the plants depends
on what aphid species you have because
and I mean I'm black normally on
nasturtiums you'll see like black beanie
foods which is not something I've now
have heard of in cannabis yet I mean I
don't want to say it could never be
there but you know it that's that's a
different thing it it also depends on
your economic threshold you know plants
can have a low level of aphids and it's
not the end of the world especially for
outdoor production or if you're growing
nasturtiums just for their bloom
something like that I mean I grow
nasturtiums I let you know if it's get
on there and they don't for my landscape
it's not a problem because there's
enough predators that come in the
surfeit flies and you know ladybird
beetle are there's enough things that
feed on them but typically in a
greenhouse situation we don't really
want them in there I mean yes you can is
a physical action of washing them off
with water but nasturtiums they tend to
be on the underside to leave and it's
harder to get water coverage you gotta
you know the angled wand kind of to
spray underneath on there but in a
greenhouse you know we
typically are using more of the
parasites to manage them because the
parasites can fly around the greenhouse
and find that one aphid that's tucked
away over in the corner that you might
have missed so that's the advantage to
using the parasites is they can fly
around and find them so when you mention
these different plants we talked about
trap plants and indicator plants and
maybe pollinator plants what is there
anything that you would you would grow
in your greenhouse if you had if you had
cannabis that you think would be
potentially beneficial in one of those
aspects depends on what I was growing in
my greenhouse and my woodcut what my
cannabis grower or my you know a
nasturtium farmer you know it let's say
your let's say your cannabis grower for
the sake of the podcast so I don't think
the aphid banker plant system that's
commercially available as we're as of
yet we haven't proved really a need for
that even though I've seen it I don't
think it's worth the potential there
there may be potential with using the
purple flash pepper with aureus because
I've seen in outdoor cannabis production
aureus feeding on spider mites naturally
in that situation so I know aureus will
go to cannabis and feed on the spider
mites and the problem with aureus which
is also called the minded fire bug you
have to have a pollen it for it to
complete its life cycle and in most
greenhouses you don't have a pollen
source and so that's what this pepper
program does is you grow the peppers and
it provides pollen so that the adults
can have pollen lay their eggs on those
pepper plants reproduce and then they'll
leave and then they'll go out into the
crop and look for things like thrips
they'll also find things like spider
mites and other pests I've seen them
even you know feed on foliar aphids and
they can help really suppress pest
levels now granted I am way
oversimplifying this this is not a I'm
going to grow some peppers and just
throw them out there it is a
commitment-- you there's you know a
strict regiment on how you do this the
timing and all kinds of stuff which we
don't have time to cover today but I
think if any of the potential plants
bankers
I think that's the one that might have
the most potential for cannabis but you
know we need to you know get trials set
up and see if it works
have you seen anything with cover crops
with people running cover crops
underneath cannabis as a would that be a
potential detriment in terms of being a
plant host for some of these pests
I bet inside or outside production you
know I've seen it in bold I've seen
mostly outdoor production with cover
crops but I have seen guys running in
containers large containers or beds
using cover crops as a living mulch well
outside yeah outside I would be you know
you know they're doing it in big AG big
AG is doing it today and lots of
vegetables you see it in landscapes and
stuff and it's basically providing you
know food resources for other
beneficials inside you better know what
you're doing because again it could
become a harbor for your pests as well
and that's why you just can't say oh I'm
just going to throw this plant in here
because you know could be an alternate
host for disease again I alternate host
for your pests I would be very leery
about doing something like that
indoors yeah you know and unless you you
know are really on top of it would the
same be said for most mulches or even
mulching with the plant leaves through
the families that are dead directly off
the plant I would not want to do that
because if there's spider mite eggs on
there other pests and if they can find
their way off there and go right back up
onto the plant that's sanitation you
always want to get rid of any disease
plant material do not throw in a garbage
can and let it sit in your greenhouse
for a day or two it has to be out of
that facility you've got to get it out
okay and I know that everything that
you're saying is very general then a lot
of the if we were to talk about specific
pests or specific beneficial insects
they require a lot more knowledge than
you have time or energy to share today
on this podcast but
can we talk just briefly in just very
general terms about some few major pest
we talked a little about spider mites
already but would you be able to cover a
little bit about fungus naps
yeah fungus gnats used to be a big
problem in greenhouse production but now
that we have a steady supply of really
good quality beneficial nematodes it's
not so much of an issue unless you're
growing in you know some of these what
I'll call artificial media's and things
like rockwool nematodes really aren't
crazy about being in that kind of
environment I think it's a from my
experience it's easier to manage pests
when you're growing in you know cocoa or
you know what we'd call you know a
potting mix I know
for ease of growing a lot of people are
moving to these you know artificial
medias but it's it's harder to manage
the the pests there with the biocontrol
agents because they don't really like
being in that artificial environment now
granted from a chemical standpoint you
know it for the states that you know and
you got a look at your state and see
what you can do and that is it but you
know BT Bacillus thuringiensis Israeli
incest and that's the strand this is
where I see a lot of people making
mistakes there's multiple strains of BTS
and you've got to have the strain for
flies which is Israeli incest that can
still work for fly larvae management it
has to be ingested by the Flies but we
do have resistant populations out there
because it's been used so much that you
know it may not work but it is something
that does have to be ingested and
typically you know you need to really
wait about a week before you're going to
see results you'll see your results on
your sticky cards because you change
your sticky cards every Monday and you
date them you don't leave them out for
two three and four weeks so when I show
up we have no idea what's going on and
you're buying good quality sticky cards
from
companies like bio best has nice sticky
cards Kolbert has nice sticky cards some
really good quality products out there
I'm seeing the cannabis growers use a
lot of these they look like them they're
folded and you peel them back I like the
the sticky cards that have paper on each
side because you can peel it off one
week and then the next week you can peel
off the other side and move that paper
back to the other side so you can't get
two weeks out of one sticky card and
positioning is important depending on
what pest you're trying to target I mean
sticky cards that's like a whole you
know discussion in itself but for fungus
gnats that's really critical to know
what your population is and also when
you get you can get large sticky ribbons
that come on rolls now and they'll
they'll string them up through the
greenhouses for what's called mass
trapping and that's to remove a lot of
the adults and we do know that fungus
net larvae do feed on the roots of
plants and can convector plant diseases
so that's why managing them and really
getting their numbers down is really
important now I have a friend who took
his stinky cards and put them rather
than being vertically put them
horizontal beneath right beneath the
canopy and that's how he runs him in his
room have you seen anyone else doing
that as a way of catching things going
up and down well that's that's just
catching by luck as they you know come
up the way insects are trapped on sticky
cards is by the light reflecting off of
them and so there's lots of discussion
on outdoor productions which way you
position them and everything but you can
do that I still like the the horizontal
positioning near the soil surface that
will attract them up but again lighting
is a big part of it so would they get
more light because the top side would be
completely exposed to light it'd be a
flat surface and then the bottom side
would be completely shaded I guess by
catching things that are flying up and
then the other thing seeing the light on
the top
give it up describing it possible yeah I
know I know what you're talking about
I've seen like interior scapes did they
cut them in didn't
narrow strips to kind of hide them in
plant material but hey this is where you
could do a trial do you know some down
some up and see what you know works best
for you in your growing facility the way
your lighting is positioned okay yeah
see what you catch sure that would be a
really easy thing to try and compare and
check out so that was a little bit on
fungus gnats can we talk a little bit
about Roode a Fitz - just a quick brief
one-minute thing on rue David's one
minute okay well this is the rue David
that the cannabis industry is dealing
with from what I've seen it's also found
in the ornamental industry - and has a
pretty wide host range the problem is
again if you are on a system where you
know you overhead irrigate and they can
flow out the bottoms of the holes and
the pots or if you're an ebb and flood
system you just keep spreading them
around through your system and I had a
lettuce grower that had a different
species but still a rudy fit in an NF t
system and they shut it down scrubbed
everything put it back together started
from seed again and they were back
because all it takes is missing one and
this is what's very dangerous about
bringing in plants with soil because
it's easy to look on leaves it's harder
to find pests in the soil and so that's
how these rude aphids are spreading
around is through routed plugs so do you
have any quick recommendations for
people that they could look into if they
are dealing with Rou defense so if you
are not in a state that prohibits but
Anna Gardner my cotrol wettable powder
that works extremely well we know that
there's science on that there's there's
bio works has a sheet how to deal with
rude aphids using botanic garden but
unfortunately a gun certain states have
disallowed it which is it's very
frustrating because you know we do have
a good option out
err for managing them there has been I
know some people are recommending using
some of the soil to hypo aspis miles
which is now strahle elapses I just have
not seen it really suppress enough or
control route if it's again there is a
difference between oh if I put it in a
petri dish can it snack on a newly you
know birthed baby a fit and being able
to control a pest and people are taking
what they've seen in a petri dish on a
small scale and extrapolating it to
control and and it just doesn't work
that way
same thing with Rove beetles I do think
the roe beetles do predate some on them
but I've just not seen it I get to the
level where I would feel comfortable
still with it at and just you know we
are setting up some trial work looking
at nematodes but again if you're in a
rock wall system it's much more
difficult for those nematodes to be able
to hold on because nematodes are
actually semi-aquatic and they need to
be able to move on a water film and they
move extremely well and you know
traditional you know media and in that
situation if they could come in contact
with the aphid possibly it could kill it
but we don't know yet if nematodes truly
can do that and that's something we're
setting up a trial right now on oh
that's great that's great and I would be
remiss that if I didn't at least bring
up broad mites and Russert mites briefly
with you as well
just so just so I can avoid a bunch of
angry emails would you be able to touch
on those - sure um broad mites in and I
hate to keep going back to ornamentals
but you know what we're seeing in
ornamentals can affect vegetable
production and cannabis this was the
worst year abroad mites
I've ever seen in my life in greenhouses
and ornamentals and it was it was pretty
epic I think it was one
particular variety of plant that
cuttings were coming in from offshore
it's the same way cannabis is getting it
you bring your cuttings in or even your
rooted cuttings and the pest is at such
a low level it's not detectable and you
you know you pot them up or you see your
cuttings under a mist system and the
level stays at a dull roar a dull roar
and then all of a sudden turn around and
you've got a lot of deformed growth and
I think they have spread the broad might
spread from that one initial plant on to
lots of other crops so you know if you
bought you know planted hanging baskets
and brought them into your cannabis
operation there's a chance you could
spread the broad might that way because
broad might has many many many hosts and
it's not like where the cannabis Russert
might has one host it's it's it's very
it's much more what we call cosmopolitan
it's around in lots of different places
from my experience this year we know we
can manage broad might with a preventive
program and that's one thing people are
missing you can't contact me when your
plants are webbed over you can't contact
me when you have 10,000 you know him
present mites on a leaf and expect me to
be able to fix it
this is all about prevention the second
you bring a cutting in the second you
stick it the second you pot it I would
be putting predatory mites out on these
plants and assuming you're going to have
the problem if you do a preventive
program it's a lot cheaper than trying
to fix a problem and it's the same thing
with a hemp Russert mite which is moving
around through the industries we
discussed before so easily and it is
just spreading and spreading and just
assume you're going to end up with it
and so starting a preventive program
early if you go in too many ornamental
operations today when they stick their
cutting they start on predatory mites
right then their main nemesis is Western
flower thrips they
every year and it's worth the investment
to treat in propagation over trying to
cure it in finished product because when
you have plants that are small and
compact together it's really easy and
inexpensive to use the predatory mites
when you've got bigger larger plants
it's much harder to treat and the
cannabis industry is being too reactive
they've got to be more pro-reactive
and as far as which species it depends
are you an outdoor grow in Oregon are
you going in a greenhouse in you know
Oregon are you growing in a warehouse in
Florida you know you have to look at
your different growing conditions what
your pests complex is to be able to get
the right predatory mite for what you
need to do and then you've got to look
at is this ash a right is a hanging sash
a right is a sashay on a stick right do
you want loose product oh but you know
loose products you have problems
sprinkling on the leaf so you may need
other release system so it I don't make
it too complicated but this is why you
need to work with somebody that knows
what they're doing and unfortunately
there's not many people that do and
that's that's the challenge today
there's a lot of people that will say
they know and I wish I could clone
myself and you know every state could
have a dozen Susanne's to work but it
just I can't do that
technology yet but you gotta get with
something i somebody sent me a thing
saying you know that someone was
recommending a to camaris or spider mite
control that no no no I mean just no and
I've seen that somebody is making that
recommendations at selling biocontrol
agents to growing operations and that's
not that's that no no just it's bad
recommendation so just to kind of
summarize what we talked about today
these bio controls really do work are
effective but they require a lot of
knowledge and every situation is
different every growing environment and
every every pest requires
very specific controls and knowledge and
so as a takeaway I guess for growers
what I want to say is I don't want to
discourage people from using bio
controls we've established that it's
fairly complicated but there are
resources out there
you mentioned the insector ease and I'll
put up a list of those insector ease it
on the podcast page is there anything
else you'd like to share for people
though
just in general regarding bio controls
yes I think with the way regulation is
going and pesticide testing is going I
think that the cannabis industry is
going to be forced more heavily into
more bio control options I think it was
Delaware there's no pesticides allowed
at all on cannabis production I'm a
little nervous about California opening
up next year I actually think we're
going to have shortages of biocontrol
agents because even now there are some
issues with being able to get product
because the demand for the use of
biocontrol agents and greenhouse
vegetables and ornamentals is just
skyrocketing and that's due to again
they're not really able to manage the
pests with even the pesticide products
they have and you know fine give the
cannabis industry all these chemicals
that the other guys have they'll just
develop resistance to them also and then
you're going to be right back where you
started from where you're going to have
to be looking at bio control and some of
these bio rational products to be able
to manage your pests I will say that how
do why do bio controls not work it can
be again wrong product so you know you
don't know truly what your pest is and
you're releasing the wrong bio control
agent pesticide residue you've sprayed
something on your plant that can be
toxic and just because it's an
unrealistic product does not mean that
it is safe with biocontrol agents you
need to you know understand chemical
interactions and then product quality
and again it's getting product to you in
a timely manner that's viable and and
ready to eat
and I think that's you know a very
important
part of it too but I've seen some of the
I caught like to call them nozzle head
some of the most adamant nozzle head
people out there that would never use
biocontrol are now using biocontrol
because they realize they have to have
this as part of their pest management
program not saying pesticides are bad
I'm not saying you're not going to have
to spray if use bios and bios are not
right for every single growing situation
but for the things we know they can do
you know I think that there's there's
it's a really really good tool to have
as long as you use them right and
understand what you're doing and again I
can't put you know big bold font
underline flashing letters you've got to
work with somebody that knows what what
they're doing and you know I don't think
there's anything wrong with somebody
coming in and you know they want to work
with you you know ask them what their
qualifications are how long have they
been doing this you know what makes them
qualified because again I've seen a lot
of people a lot of growers unfortunately
get bad information from people who you
know intentions good or not are not
providing them good quality information
yeah and I would like to see people from
outside of just the cannabis industry
that are making these recommendations
people that have experience in like you
mentioned working with larger ornamental
greenhouses and in egg and things like
that on the on the entomology side yeah
the one thing I tell cannabis people all
the time is so poinsettias greenhouse
growers don't make money off of selling
poinsettias it's basically a way to keep
all their employees working through you
know the winter months and keep
everything going
if a ornamental person uses a product on
a poinsettia you know it has to work and
be a good product because a poinsettia
grower is not going to spend two cents
more for plant for a plant if it doesn't
work because they can't afford to use
products that do not work because
there's almost no if minimal profit
margin on things like poinsettias so
so when you look at what points edea
growers use these you know Bettina garde
they use root shield I've even had some
of them using some of the horticultural
oils we're using predatory mites we're
using parasites now granted some people
are still using traditional chemistry's
with a solid rotation program but many
of the ornamental growers are being
forced out of using the Neo Nick
insecticides which that pressures coming
from the big-box retailers that are not
allowing growers to use the Neo Nick so
they are losing that whole group of
chemistry's to be able to use which
poinsettias growers have relied on so
heavily so they're looking at these
other replacements and they're actually
going into using a fair amount of
biocontrol
options not saying they're never
spraying but you know these biocontrol
options are working for them and again
they don't have much wiggle room on a
plant as far as pricing yeah you know I
really think bow controls are that are
the future of the cannabis industry for
all the reasons you mentioned the the
tested ice pesticide resistant issues
the worker safety I think public
pressure is going to come in as people
learn more and more about the pesticides
that are being used and they really do
work especially when we're talking about
the mono cropping that's going on
obviously in the cannabis industry and
the fact that these large-scale
horticultural growers are using bio
controls like you mentioned really
speaks volumes because they don't have
the profit margins that a lot of people
do in cannabis they have to be really
smart with their money so like you
mentioned I really do think this is the
future and I hope that there will be
more consultants available down the road
as this industry blossoms so yeah I
think more people will get more
experience under their belt I just have
to be really lucky I just I got in like
I don't want to say ground level I got
in it you know sub-basement level to
this you know when bio control was
really uncool nobody was interested in
it and I just really was and you know I
felt this was the way the industry is
going to go because of you
just look at you know the pesticide
treadmill that you know people get on
and resistance issues you're going to
see more companies coming to the United
States bringing products in you look at
a company like beneficial insectary
they're based in California they've
really expanded their production violine
in California also they produce per
symbolist they are as far as I'm
concerned the best producer APRA
symbolist hands down and you can order
the Priscilla's right from them at the
insector e there and especially if
you're on the west coast I mean they
bottle in the morning and you get it by
next morning I mean how how can you you
know beat that on that kind of product
but they're working on becoming more
efficient at production so they have
more product available you know there's
there's more things happening but it's
just unless you're dialed into the
biocontrol industry it's hard to know
everything that's going on in it and
unfortunately we're a very very small
group there's just not a lot of us in
the biocontrol industry so yeah well
thank you again for your time today I
know you're busy and I I don't want to
take up too much more of your time so
thank you again and I really appreciate
this and I look forward to seeing you
hopefully at another trade show we're
talking in your future yes well and
thanks for helping having me and I'm
going to give myself one shameless plug
just so you know in March I am working
on organizing right now a we're not sure
if it's going to be a half-day I'm
trying to pull for a full day biocontrol
cannabis workshop and it's a they
haven't we haven't figured out a date
yet but it's going to be the early part
of March and it's going to be in San
Diego it looks like and we're still
trying to get that all together but I
think that it's something that if you
spend a day with me I'm going to make
your brain hurt by the time you're done
and it's it's going to be a lot of
information because you know I fire you
you've been to one of my talks I fire
information pretty fast at you but you
know if we're given this longer time
we can go more in depth on these kinds
of things no that would be invaluable in
fact that are there any other publicly
available talks that you're going to be
giving in the near future that you could
you could mention um I'm someone's
organizing one for Florida but you know
the Florida market for cannabis is so so
small that that's not you know not going
to have a lot of you know necessarily
draw for that but I do you know I will
say that I'm having more Canas people
show up at my ornamental workshops and
other other classes because you can take
you know biology information and
sanitation information and it does
transfer over I do
try really hard to keep up with a
calendar on my website on bug lady
consulting I think I have a link it's
you know where's the bug lady and you
can go up there and see things that are
coming in the future I'm going to be
speaking up in Boston I can remember
next month or the end of this month
actually I think on pesticide
compatibility and biocontrol information
and I'm also working on putting together
for cultivate which is the biggest
greenhouse trade show in the u.s. that's
going to be in July the Saturday of that
show I'm putting together an entire day
a workshop focusing on biocontrol and
focusing a lot on insect identification
and things like that so I do teach stuff
all over you know they said I've spoken
to canna con I've done some workshops
out in Oregon I've been in ki and I'm
just all over the place so well great
I'll definitely put links to all of that
on the podcast page so people can find
the link to your events and that that
one in San Diego sounds amazing so maybe
I will try and make it down for that as
well yeah and we're deciding right now
about how much we're going to do because
we want to do any kind of hands-on stuff
we're probably going to have to limit
the number of attendees because when it
gets so big it's really hard to do any
kind of hands-on anything so you know as
it as it progresses
you know but we'll have more information
we said our first call about it the
other day great well I look forward to
staying in touch and seeing what
exciting stuff you're learning and
working on and thank you again for your
time today oh you're very welcome and
thanks for having me you were listening
to the cannabis cultivation in science
podcast I'm your host Todd Hussey that
was Suzanne Wainwright evans also known
as the bug lady her website is
www.seannal.com page so you can stay up
to date with all the latest information
and podcasts right when they come out
I'm working on a few really exciting
projects so you'll want to be on that
email list there are a few new products
I'm going to be announcing soon that
could dramatically reduce your labor
costs and improve plant growth I want to
let everyone know that I will be pausing
the podcast scheduled for the month of
December as it's just too busy with the
holidays but we will be back up in 2018
with more amazing guests I'm also
tossing around the idea of doing a
listener content email episode where I
would answer any questions you may have
regarding cultivation and soil so send
me an email at tad at kis organics comm
that's t ad at kis organics comm or
anything through our website contact
page this is a great opportunity to fill
in the gaps between all the speakers and
information that's been shared already I
look forward to hearing from people I
hope everyone has a wonderful holiday
season and stay tuned for more cannabis
cultivation and science podcast in the
new year