[Music]
hello my name is Cleo tol I'm the head
guard for Paradise Organics and we are
going to be welcoming Tad hussy into our
farm to do a little walk through we are
a small scale
organic cannabis farm out of Livingston
Montana uh we currently are growing in
the kiss Organics commercial mix and our
living soil beds and we uh make our own
soil uh through just recycling building
I want to give a huge shout out to
Brandon at the kiss Organics team and
everyone el else at the kiss Organics
team for being very approachable and
helping me out um but yeah we are a
small scale farm and we got Tad hussy to
uh coming in and we're going to do a
little walk through the grow so hope you
enjoy
thanks how many different flower rooms
do you have I've got six flower rooms
okay
three bedrooms and you guys just kind of
retrofitted to this correct building
correct yeah
I yeah this is our little clone area
this this area works really nice it
keeps it really good and humid got the
Periodic Table of cannabis I don't think
that's uh really anything that's uh we
use it's just kind of cool um Cameron
the kid that I was showing you he's very
very good with keeping all of our clones
clean he's very meticulous with the
cleaning process with everything
everything he gets everything sparkling
clean there's it's and and just how his
attention to
detail is amazing so he's he's the Clone
man that's important got some new seeds
here these ones are just getting munched
by thrips thrips are the one thing that
I've been having a hard time getting rid
of as everyone does but some new seeds
some new genetics okay from CSI humble
but yeah uh we are required by law to
tag our plants when they get to 12 in
and I've gotten ticketed for having them
not tagged at like 10 inches so I just
tag basically everything you'll see the
tags in the dirt for a little bit once
the plant gets a little stronger I'll uh
put them up I used to clean these up
pretty pretty like immediately um one
thing that I've kind of done is I've let
the plants go a little bit longer before
hacking into them and it seems like it's
done better both for hlb spread and just
the Vigor of the plant okay
so as I was saying we are currently
growing too many plants in a and and
we've
got 4 to 500 plants in flower at all
times got about 1,600 in veg so these
ones the ones with a little discolor we
just get kind of we're constantly
keeping up with transplanting we're just
transplanting transplanting
transplanting transplanting all the time
and the ones that you see that are a
little yellow here uh they're just one
of these cultivars that gets hungry
faster you know they're they're
something that the blueberry Silver Tip
It uh it's it's really great stuff but
some cultivars just get hungrier faster
and as you see we got uh the dog punch
here that looks fine it's almost a
bigger plant than these but these things
are probably going to get transplanted
in the next couple
days moving on we will go to budro one
now you're not uh topping the plants or
uh anything like that I top the plants
for only certain cultivars when I need
to but usually um if if if they're
getting to a point where there's so much
of a Christmas tree I'll I kind of like
to low stress train them and give them a
little Bend before I top them just
because I'm scared of spreading hlv okay
you're
okay Stan this is Tad Tad Stan me nice
to meet you all
good glad you to have you here I
appreciate it thanks for the tour so um
you were saying that you were you were
able to control the hlv a little bit
better by hand pring rather than
pinching rather than using the scissors
that worked for you and I've had data to
back it up yeah like I've cuz we do I
try to test about 10 plants through Tumi
genetics every month or two just to keep
an eye on how much we hlv we have and
we're spreading and since I've stopped
cleaning up all the bottoms of my veg
plants as fast and since I've stopped
topping these plants with scissors yeah
I've seen less hlv and I've had less hlb
and I've got the data to back it up so
that's why it's like and I know some
Growers cleaning your scissors in
between plant cuts and things like that
too we have yes yes absolutely
absolutely and I've I've had to ride my
guys hard on it cuz it's a pain in the
ass but it is so important
yeah
this is a room that we just loaded um
I'm doing uh this is you're you're going
to see rooms with both HPS and LEDs what
we do right now is I just I put blue
lights down the middle for the first
couple weeks that really I mean the
plants are going to be stressed and a
little
upset initially right off the bat but
that white light helps them quite a bit
this was the room that I've had my as
perilis fail in and um I I know that we
have different opinions about our cover
crop inside I totally understand why
especially after having the is pods but
it was the cycle that I did not have
cover crop in here was when I failed for
ASP jillis which I forgot to mention
yesterday but listening to the Pod with
Steve Campbell pretty sure your podcast
he said something about like more cover
crop less asper jous which was it's
something where it's like maybe maybe
not it's such a strange deal this is a
room where we have mainly all LEDs but I
have these HPS in um kind of in between
and once these plants really develop and
settle into flower I'll turn those HPS
on they are orange lights if I turn them
on right off the bat it really kind of
stresses the plants out and they look
not very happy what's your uh what's
your target like ppfda a
canopy what's my target ppfd on the
canopy we try to well these these led
these I think you can have them a couple
uh like a foot and a half I try to not
have more than mic like for 1100 micro
moles I think is that comparable to uh
ppfd okay yeah it's the same thing okay
so you're about 1100 there another thing
that I was kind of thinking about doing
was removing the first little bit of
these root balls which I don't do yet
but um I haven't had aspar jillis fails
in this room or anything of it by the
way this is all kiss Organics commercial
mix
soil but as you can see we do finally
defoliate our plants I did finally and
this is kind of how we try to get them
all stacked up nice and we did just
water in here so there's water on the
ground but uh yeah
and I need to lower the lights and Bud
too a little bit cuz you see here these
lights are a little bit lower closer to
these
plants
uh yeah this has been one of our uh one
of our best rooms with the old uh kiss
Organics commercial mix what
uh how many days in the flower are you
oh let's look at the sheet I'll tell
you start date
8:22 so we are 1
month 5 days in flour
okay
so that's our mother area try to just
store genetics back here okay one thing
that I've done we spray this room every
3 or 4 days with hydrogen peroxide mix
it's
only 40 to 60 mil uh Ms in a 7,000 mil
tank so it's very small and a little bit
of prot too which is just a silica mix I
love doing silic mix sprays but that's
kept uh powdery mildew and every pest
out of my life and it's it was something
that I've struggled with for years and
years of spraying stff oil neem oil
peppermint tweetment tvia oil everything
and I was like I cannot get rid of these
things turns out hydrogen peroxide and I
and I never really UND or I never really
liked it was like seems like a bad
chemical thing but once I really learned
and looked into it's just liquid oxygen
and it's not it's not too bad so I I'm
very happy with the results that that
gives me it doesn't leave a residue on
the leaf either so how long does it take
you to get your plants to this size
they're what about 5T tall depending on
the cultivar we uh we write down the
transplant dates on the on the piece of
paper so this one was 718 and when it
got put into a one gon pot and then 94
it got put into this uh 5 gon pot so
okay two months ago this plant was Tiny
just just out of the cloner and it
depends obviously some cultivars take
longer than others and that's why I like
to have the yeah are you feeding them
any other nutrients besides what's in
the soil already what you're putting in
the
soil yes uh we have a book of compost
teas and if if uh depending on the
cultivar sometimes I'll know cultivars
eat a lot more and I'll give them a
little top dress um
but these are
te's I just a bunch of recipes that I
made this is one of our
favorites the hippie hater the hippie
hater okay it's uh and as you can see
our homemade tea tank you know it's uh I
used to have a 250 gallon one but I I
feel like the 120 just works a little
better for us right here our boards kind
of like everything on the uh walls I if
there's no water in a room we got no
water if it got sprayed harvested loaded
everything I just try to cuz having
information available for everyone yeah
is good it means that there's the lack
of communication doesn't happen as much
and it's like oh what do you mean you
watered that room we just watered that
room that doesn't happen when we have a
board telling exactly what's going on
nice
so everything that gets done whether
it's water pruning top dress we write it
down if it's in here we're writing it
down and the inspector loves this too I
print out every sheet of where it is
Phase date everything in here so when we
do get inspected it's easy everything's
right where it needs to be but this is
great if I end up having a problem or it
was a really good run I can uh go back
and be like what did I do differently
and also is I have the last couple years
of everything that we've done and I can
match it up to test results too and it
really helps me kind of follow
scientific method of control like taking
one thing out and putting one thing back
in actually seeing the result from all
of us here at Paradise Organics we'd
like to give a huge thank you to Tad
hussy and the whole team thank you for
watching and Todd that's a good wead
going right
there