hey guys so I want to share something
new we've been working on in the
background we've been working with a
grower who is in a very tight state for
uh standards and so they've been
independently testing a ton of inputs
not just from our company but from other
providers as well um I'm only here to
share the results from the ones from all
the products that we carry but really
important to try and get test results
and keep in mind too with these test
results they're going to vary a little
bit so this is just going to give you a
rough idea what's in the product but
this type of test that they're running
here is an icpms test it's a very
accurate way of finding out exactly
what's in a product you can see here
like with arsenic it's in the parts per
billion is how they're reporting it and
in parts per million so11 parts per
million is quite low that's a very good
number to see um and you can see here on
the lead 311 so it's a pretty clean
product from a heavy metal perspective
uh which is great and we don't have this
for every product but for all the
products we do have uh you can just go
on our website right now and check it
out and see what those numbers look like
so you can better manage your heavy
metals keep in mind that pretty much
every product is going to have some
level of heavy metals some are going to
be higher than others so you could
absolutely make a better choice in
regards to certain things like rock dust
or soft rock phosphate for example by
choosing the one that's going to be
lower in heavy metals same with gypsum
we actually have two different types of
gypsum we're going to be updating our
page with both a granulated and a
powdered gypsum from two different
companies with two different heavy metal
tests and you'll be able to go over here
and select which one you want um so yeah
I hope that folks find this helpful and
uh one other thing I want to point out
while I'm doing this is so we got these
tests originally from Delta Urban soils
lab they're an xrf test um they're very
affordable way of testing but one thing
to look at here is this detection limit
you can see here it has arsenic at 7 for
example that means if arsenic is below 7
PPM on these worm castings it's going to
give us a lower than detection limit or
or null result here um Seven's pretty
high though for what we're doing and so
like I just got a recent test and we'll
add this to the website too um you can
see here that the actual castings arenic
levels were
2.4 using icpms which again is going to
be um a much
more accurate way of testing so uh just
something to be aware of if you're
looking on our test always be sure to
check or any test really be sure to
check what the detection limits are on
the product or on the testing to make
sure that you can actually um test it to
the levels you want and while we're
talking about heavy metals I just want
to mention with water you need very very
good detection limits because a lot of
times the water tests are not detected
to the level that we need them to in a
commercial facility to make sure that
we're not bringing in Arsenic or lead or
cadm or something like that in our water
supply so hope folks find this helpful
it's a free resource uh it's on our
website and you know we list the brands
for a lot of these products like right
here it'll say Cascade minerals B salt
so if you can find this product locally
you'll have uh up-to-date independent
heavy metals test to go along with it
all right thanks guys