hey guys so today I want to talk to you
about pathogen testing pathogen testing
is a great tool to determine if you're
dealing with an issue like fusarium
pythium or hopen vroid hlvd is a
significant pathogen affecting cannabis
and the symptoms of hlvd are stunted
growth closis and necrosis in some cases
um commonly thought of as dutting is
what you hear a lot of people talk about
in the industry and it's important to
note that infected plants may not show
any visible symptoms at all which is why
early detection is crucial and it can
actually show up in seeds now too though
at much lower rates so testing your
plants is the best way to know if this
is this is a potential issue or to avoid
bringing something into your garden that
could be an issue down the road um so we
offer testing through Three Rivers
biotech the costs per test are only $15
per test but there is a five test
minimum um after you order your test
here's the supplies and the process for
submitting a sample so I got this in the
mail and I wanted to show you guys the
whole process and take you through it as
well as what comes in the kit and
opening it up I have my sample tubes
this is where I'll put my
sample I have an envelope for packaging
and mailing that sample
back and then I have my instructions
from them on how to take a sample and
I'll walk through this
today as well as my sheet for recording
my sample with the barcode that I'm
going to match up with the plant that
I'm
testing so there's a list of supplies
that you're going to need in order to do
this you're going to need scissors or
pruning shears bleach uh a spray bottle
paper towels a pen disposable gloves and
a cooler with ice inside or fridge
access I have a cooler over there but um
I'm actually just going to take the
samples and put them directly in the
fridge so the first step is to sterilize
your scissors in a 10% bleach solution
for at least 10 minutes and then wipe
dry with a fresh paper
towel and I've got those right
here so my scissors are now ready to
go the next step that they want you to
do is to fill out this form so I'm going
to write the name of this sample in this
case it's uh Gary pton crossed with
animal mints so I'm just going to put
GPX am M and then I'm going to take my
barcode
here and I'm going to stick it right on
the
form like that and then I'm going to
take the corresponding barcode so
0157 and I'm going to stick it on the
plant that I'm sampling today so I could
stick this on a pot stick or you can
stick it right on the fabric pot
here right like that so now that I've
done all of those steps the next step is
to put on your disposable gloves or you
can already have them on and um spray
your gloves really quickly with a little
bit of bleach solution 10% bleach and
I'm going to do it away from my
plants rub it all around make
sure my hands are
clean and then the next step is to take
my sample now for the sample
here you need your sample length to be
less than a/ quar inch so not very long
you want to get lateral Roots so we're
talking you know this is a quarter inch
here um the whole sample that's going
into the vial tube needs to be less than
a full inch so that's the important part
of this process so now I'm going to go
over here and take my sample so I'm
going to gently peel back the
soil to expose these lateral
roots and I'm going to take some from a
few different
spots in the
pot and I'm going to have to cut some of
these down because they're just too
long okay so now that I have my samples
and I've cut them down to the
appropriate
size less than a quter inch per sample
uh per route and then total sample size
of all the roots is less than an inch
I'm putting all of them into the sample
vial and then they recommend U moving it
up and down like that and then turning
it like 10 to 20 times just to make sure
that the roots are fully coated with the
sample solution in there that will help
stabilize it for the trip to the lab and
then I'm putting on the barcode that
goes with that particular sample and I'm
trying to figure out the best way to do
that here so I decided to put it on like
this and so that will allow the lab to
match that particular root sample with
that particular plant that I pulled the
sample from so I'm going to record that
on the sample sheet and then I'm going
to get that directly into the
refrigerator for 24 hours to let it cool
and then taking that and sending it to
the post office uh filling it out with
the address on the sheet and getting
that to the lab right
away and that's it this is really the
best and frankly the only way to find
out if your plants have pop and vroid
and it's really important to know what
what you're dealing with when we're
talking about pathogens so you can treat
it directly