so I recently visited Collective
elevation in Boseman Montana and I saw
that they had these awesome rolling beds
in the trays and I asked them about how
they built these and basically they
created these Unistrut frames here's an
example of some fixed ones that they
sent me also for this video and uh I
decided to try and make a rolling one so
this is also from them as well the
rolling one that they did here now my
first attempt uh was an utter failure um
I did not build it correctly and so I
wanted to make this video to kind of
show you guys what I did wrong and how
to do it
better so my first stop was Home Depot
you can get everything you need there
with the exception of the tray or flood
tables themselves um everything else I
got came from Home Depot and this is an
example of the Unistrut right here so
the next step was cutting everything to
the proper size that I needed uh for me
I found the grinder worked the best best
but uh if you're handy you may have
other options I did try a metal blade in
my miter saw as well but whatever you
decide to do make sure that you use
proper protective gear um for cutting
all the
metal now there's a few different ways
to attach these I went with these spring
nuts uh the first time I did it I did
not use these and it failed miserably so
I think this was a good step up and in
the right direction um and they're not
that expensive now the thing with them
that is a little bit tricky is you kind
of have to hold them put pressure up get
everything in position and then add the
bolt and then you're pushing down
against the tension of the spring uh
which is a little bit tricky um I'm not
going to lie this took me a little bit
to get it right um and this was
definitely a hassle because you're
you're pushing up with like in here I'm
pushing up with my left hand pushing
down with my right right hand and then
trying to tighten the socket at the same
time uh but once you do get it started
it becomes pretty easy and then you can
adjust it and line every everything up
uh just the way you want it and it does
hold uh really securely once you have it
in place so if you do have access or the
ability to use these you know and you'd
have a simple socket set um I definitely
think that's the way to
go okay so once you've built out the
basic frame like you saw before I added
these casters that I had picked up at at
Harbor Freight um a while back and so I
put those on there they're attached at
two points from underneath um and this
was the way I put on Wheels I think I
put on uh six wheels alog
together now I also want to give a shout
out to Greg lson uh he came up with
another design using these connectors
and he's using this in his facilities
he's able to get three connections then
with his casters and one recommendation
that he did make that I thought was a
good one was to use larger casters
that's something I didn't do and if I
could go back and rebuild it um I
totally would because uh once I got the
soil in there there uh after building
this bed um it was frankly really really
heavy and hard to move with that much
soil in there I put about a yard and a
half of total soil on here once I was
done uh but I want to show you guys uh
this is what it looked like with the
tray on there and then this is what it
looks like today with the soil um you
can see that it's it's working um it is
hard to move but because I don't have to
move it very far I'm just moving in and
out it's okay um I'm not going to be
moving it very often it's just when I
prune so um this is going to work out
great for me hope this
helps