if you look at your raspberry and you
say I don't know do I have a single crop
or do I have ever bearing all you have
to do is go to Prime canes if the prime
canes are showing flower buds or past
fruit then it's an everbearing if the
primes have no flowers or fruit then
it's a single crop so it's pretty easy
to tell what you've got I just don't mix
them very much uh I would rather just
have one batch of um the ever bearing
and what I often will do although I
didn't do it this year I didn't have
time I'll often take the everbearing and
prune them to the ground in the February
March completely and forgo that summer
crop and just look forward to the winter
crop the winter crop the fall crop the
September um October crop so that's one
way of managing is you can just take
them to the ground certainly an easy way
to prune you're just cutting them off a
ground level they come up they grow the
prime canes they bloom they bear fruit
and then the next year you just go and
you cut them to the ground