hey guys Todd Hussey here with kiss
organics and I'm here today to talk to
you about blue mats now if you're
unfamiliar with blue mats what they are
is an automatic watering system
it's an irrigation system that works
without the need for electricity and
keeps your plants an optimal moisture
contents throughout the grow and you can
you can adjust these levels yourself and
it allows you to grow really happy
healthy plants
I think watering is one of those things
it gets underappreciated by a lot of
growers and overlooked in a lot of cases
and it's one of the most important
things in an organic soil or an organic
growing system in terms of your overall
plant health and plant growth so what
I'm going to do for you today is break
down a little bit more about what blue
mats are show you a few different
designs and then show you how to install
them in your own garden now the first
step is to get the soil wet into the
right moisture content as if you had
just watered and we're gonna get it set
to what we consider optimal now with
soils like ours like the kiss organic
soils that are peat based which is what
is most most potting soils are you're
going to find that this peat can be
hydrophobic which means if it gets
really dry it's not gonna want to accept
water now I'm doing this on a
record-breaking day here in Seattle it's
like 88 degrees at out so I'm gonna
really let this water soak in I'm gonna
water another bed and come back and
water that it's a good watering
technique to know about in general it's
called the pulse watering technique you
can look it up but essentially let the
water soak in
because peat can get hydrophobic which
means it's not going to want to accept
water when it gets really dry and then
come back to that bed and then give it a
little bit more water this is really
important especially when you're doing a
container watering over numerous
containers now once that water is soaked
in and I've got that bed to the optimum
moisture content that I wanted that then
I can move on with what I want to do
next which is start installing the blue
mats now that I've let the water soak in
a little bit I want to test it to see
what kind of moisture content I have I'm
gonna dig down a little bit to see make
sure that the water is actually
penetrated beyond the first inch or so
and then it's actually down there and
then I'm gonna squeeze it not quite
enough to get a drop out of it that's
what I'm looking for
goodness just slowly want to break apart
there and if you do have a digital
moisture meter it makes it really easy
we want to aim for a hundred mbar this
is the digital moisture meter from bloom
at there are about fifty bucks and they
work really really well after I've done
that I'm gonna be soaking my sensors now
this is something you'll want to start
doing while you're wetting the beds and
doing everything else so I let them sit
for a couple hours and now I'm putting
them together what I what I'm doing
right here is getting all of the air out
and attaching them down below so you
don't want any air inside the bloom at
sensor itself and I'm tapping it to
remove any micro air bubbles in both of
the can both the top and the bottom cone
and then attaching them below below the
water level it's really that simple the
next thing I'm going to do is attach the
pressure reducer to my hose and then in
this case I also showed the optional
filter now if you're using tap water
from a municipal source like I am it's
probably not necessary you can just go
straight off of the pressure reducer so
the first step is coming off of the
pressure reducer with an eight
millimeter line in this case I'm using
the black tubing they also have an
orange Superflex tubing that you can get
if you are in an area that you're crazy
to move around more corners and such but
for my intents and purposes the black
line works just fine and it blends in
with my bed better so the first step is
deciding where you want the sensor in
the bed so in my case I'm putting the
sensor near probably about four or five
inches away from the base of my tomato
plant so that way I know that if if that
part of the bed needs water it's going
to dispense water throughout the entire
line off of that sensor so I just
attached the blue silk adaptor to the
blue soak tape and now that blue soap
tape essentially works like a soaker
hose so I'm running it over and towards
my plants so it's gonna get all of the
plants that I want it to reach in the
bed so it's only going to sense the
moisture wherever I put that carrot that
blue mat sensor everything else is just
going to go off of
point so originally I decided I was
gonna run it underneath the tomato cage
and then I end up coming back here in a
second as you'll see and pulling it back
out and putting it over the top but
ideally you want to have your design and
your layout figured out early and you
want to install it when your plants are
small now one thing about these systems
when you do first put in a smaller plant
is you may need to water hand water over
the top until that plant gets
established in the soil and has a larger
root ball and ability to pull more
moisture out of the soil but in this
case my plants are obviously maturing
they're fairly large I'm not worried
about them getting adequate and water
you know doing it this way so I'm laying
out my line I measured out about half of
it here because I need to loop it back
around so one thing that you have to
remember is it's only going to measure
wherever that bloom at carat or sensor
is so you need to make sure that you
come back around with your bloom at tape
or the blue soak tape to get within four
to six inches I'd like to go four to
five inches I'd say even to that sensor
itself the other way you can do that I
know bloom at themselves recommend
putting in a distribution dripper right
off of the end there before you put in
the three mil millon three millimeter
adapter but I've found that it works
better for me without using that and so
what you can't see right here is I'm now
putting on the end cap to the blue so
tape that keeps that keeps it from
coming out the other end and just laying
it down right there wrapping it back
around to that green sensor that I put
underneath the base of that tomato so
now it's going to water all three of
those tomatoes the cucumbers and the
flowers off of that one sensor alone and
there's so many different ways you can
do this design I'll show you a bunch of
different options here I did three of my
beds in this video so you can kind of
see the different ways I gave a few
different ways of doing it but really
you'll want to figure out what design
works best for you and your crop
depending on you know how thorough do
you need it to water how much of the bed
you need to cover and that's really
going to decide based off of your budget
the value of your crop and how you lay
it out but really important always
overestimate the length that you think
you need so you don't have to reorder
parts and just make be very thoughtful
about the way that you're laying it out
ahead of time but once you have a design
figured out it's really really easy to
set up
all right I've gone ahead and fast
forwarded to save you the time of
watching me lay out all the lines but
essentially what I did was I put another
sensor in that corner closest to the
back left tomato plant and then ran the
blue soap all the way down and around
the all the plants in the bed and then
back to that sensor again ending about
four to five inches away from the sensor
because it's really important that the
sensor the area around the sensor gets
moisture the same as the rest of the
roots and the rest of the plant because
that's what's gonna put water out and
sense when to release water into the
soaker hose itself and you can't really
see it but what I'm doing now is I'm
attaching the end of the line there so
this is my last bed and so off of those
eight millimeter sensors you actually
have it's it's sort of a pass through so
you have one end in and one end out now
the end coming out of that eight
millimeter line I need to cap because
otherwise water would just flow right
out of it and so I'm just putting a cap
on there right now to show that I'm
ending the line and I'll show you a
visual of that as well here in a second
so here's a quick shot just to show the
aesthetics of the bed in my case here I
put a 90 degree angle on the eight
millimeter line so I get a nice clean
line down and then just sent it down the
bed and then under the gravel and then
back up down the next bed so here's a
close-up of what the sensor looks like
and you can see how I ran the end of the
blue soak tape line back over to the
sensor itself so this way I will make
sure to keep that area moist and it'll
keep everything wet and watered but you
see you have the blue mat sensor
connected to a three millimeter adapter
to the blue soak tape and then the blue
soak tape that goes around the bed
looping back around and then ending
underneath the stake with a blue cap a
blue soak cap and then the other line
you see in there is just the black eight
millimeter line that connects my blue
mat sensors
here's another visual the same thing
just from a different angle to give you
guys another view of what's going on
and here's an end of that blue soaked
end cap so you can see it actually just
screws on to the end you just put it
right inside the sleeve and it fits on
really nice
so this was my pepper bed I did
something a little funky here I decided
to loop around the plant completely and
make sure that I got good coverage right
around my peppers without watering the
West rest of the bed because this bed is
going to be under that hoop house
plastic it's a little harder for me to
get in there and weed so by putting the
soaker hose just around the base of the
plant I'm hoping to reduce my weed
pressure in the middle of the bed
because that area doesn't need to stay
as wet and also make sure that my
peppers get really really good water
throughout the season because it's going
to be super hot under there and I want
to grow some awesome peppers I've also
extended it out to get the thyme and the
sage at the end of the bed so those are
getting good water too by running the
soaker hose over by the root systems
so here's a couple more traditional
designs that I've seen people use either
that spiral design going out to cover
about a four by four space or this sort
of back to back and forth wavy design
that I used on the other side so either
works really well it kind of depends on
your layout of plants and what kind of
coverage you're trying to get in the
area but here's just two more options to
consider when you're laying out your
blue mats so this is the soaker hose
here once I opened up the carrots it's
around a pepper right now and you can
see the water coming out of the soaker
hose itself this is what it will look
like when it's dispensing water now this
is where the sensor comes in because as
you close down the sensor and adjust it
which I'll demonstrate here in a second
it will maintain that moisture content
at whatever level you set it at so for
this soil because I know what it is it's
a it's a peat based soil that we make
ourselves we really like to keep it at
right at 100 mbar so that's what I'm
going to aim for and that's what I'm
going to set my sensors at now rain or
shine these things are working for you
day or night so your plant always gets
an even moisture level which is so
important for plant health so if it for
example
rains the next day those sensors will
shut off and so we won't get more water
into the soaker hose until the plant
needs it until that soil starts drying
out again
now the soaker hoses are great but
they're not for everyone some people are
going to want to use distribution
drippers and the distribution drippers
are the little brown things with the
black tip that you can see in this photo
you can put up to five per bloom at
sensor and they work really well if
you're dealing with containers say like
a five gallon container or a ten gallon
tank container because you can put a
sensor in and then run those
distribution zippers around the base of
the plant alright we're on to the final
step here and that's dialing in your
blue mats and getting the sensor set up
so I'm going ahead and closing up the
sensor because I had it open overnight
it doesn't put out enough water to where
I was concerned about over watering some
people even run these without sensors
all the time
so you don't even need them in some
instances but the first thing to do is
as you open it up if you're if you open
it all the way up and don't get any
water there could be a little kink there
in your three millimeter lines sometimes
that rubber gets stuck together so
you'll just need to slide the line in or
out a little bit and just on kink it now
in this case you can see it's not kinked
so all I'm going to do here is let it
get to where it's just dripping and I
want to have a drip just hanging there
at the top that's when I know I have it
at the right level so there we go you
can see I'm almost there and I just want
to get that drip hanging right there now
what I'm going to do is look on the side
of the blue mat there are these little
arrows and I'm going to move over one
two two arrows tighter so clockwise one
two two arrows now it really just
depends on how wet you want the soil to
be so in my case I only did one arrow
because I wanted to keep the soil a
little bit on the wetter side you can
also do two arrows but it also depends
on where you set the how moist your bed
is at the time of setting it and you can
use those moisture meters to make
adjustments now what I would do is I'm
gonna leave this and not make an
adjustment now for a little while you
want to wait at least you know probably
24 hours 12 to 24 hours before coming
back in and measuring with your moisture
meter and seeing where your beds at and
then if you do make an adjustment make
it a small adjustment maybe only one
carrot
the time so that you're not overdoing it
and constantly having to go back and
forth and fix it but provided you don't
bump the sensor it should water your
plant for the entire life of that plant
now it's really really simple I can't
recommend these units enough and feel
free to hit me up if you have any
questions my email is right there it's
tad at kiss organics comm and you can
I'm happy to help people set up custom
systems answer any questions and if
you'd like to order blue mats let us
know thank you very much