so I'm here with Suzanne Wainwright
Evans and we're talking about various
pests and we're gonna start off talking
about the rude aphid can you tell me a
little about that in relation to
cannabis yes I I don't wanna say
everybody has it but I think almost
everybody has it at this point and the
reason I wanted us to kind of start here
is because I'm getting contacted to
Instagram several times a day which is
fine but people are sending me pictures
of their rue de Foods and they're not
rude aphids in fact I've had a few
situations where people have actually
been treating for several years thinking
they had rue de foods and they're not
rude aphids oftentimes it's either
fungus gnats or now I'm actually having
a lot of people get mites confused with
rue de foods remember mites have eight
legs as adults when mites the first
firstborn they only have six but then
when they molt they'll get eight and
generally when they're first hatch out
of the eggs people don't see them they
don't see them till they're later in
life and bigger and then they'll have
eight legs where insects which is what a
Fatah R they'll always just have six
legs and then their antennae so don't
count their antennae as as legs and so
you've got to start there because how we
manage my tissues is very different and
how we manage Aoife tissues
I've actually I'm saving a whole file on
the computer of things people have
thought or rude aphids that aren't and
and the concern is as people are doing
all these bavaria drenches with or eyes
area using these two different fungi
which we're using for really food
management but they don't really do
anything for mites so it's just people
are wasting a lot of money and a lot of
products going out when it doesn't need
to so that's kind of why I wanted to
talk about him a bit yeah so tell me a
little bit about their about their
lifecycle you mentioned already the
adults the flying adults look a lot like
fungus gnats and people are confusing
those I know I've had a tough time
looking at a sticky card telling them
apart unless they were side by side so
what are some of the key characteristics
throughout the etymology
the lifecycle of this test so general
okay so with fungus gnats when they're
adults they all fly the larvae are white
maggots in the soil and they have a
blackhead capsule and that's how you can
tell fungus gnat larvae from other fly
species in the soil and typically they
bounce around on the soil surface and
they have this very weird little flight
pattern they do and that's why when we
put out sticky cards for fungus gnats we
typically have them closer to the soil
profile and not up in the high top part
of the canopy the canopy we is where we
put more for things like thrips but down
towards the soil that's where you can
find the fungus gnats bouncing around
he feeds most of the time they don't
have wings they develop wings when it's
time for them to disperse and typically
what I'm seeing especially in cannabis
but this can be true because there
there's several species of rude aphids
and there's some that attacked
vegetables some attack ornamentals some
attack cannabis but basically they all
kind of hang out in the soil until
there's either an environmental cue or
something like the population gets too
high and then it's time for them to
disperse and this is what's happening in
cannabis is people think oh my gosh and
flower we have this massive all of a
sudden Rudy fat issue it's been there
the whole time it's just the numbers
have been really low they've been
hanging in the soil reproducing feeding
on the plant not developing wings and
then when they get to a certain number
or environmental cues may play into this
too which we don't know yet but they
decide okay now we're gonna have babies
that are gonna develop wings and then
that's when you see them coming out of
the soil and dispersing and you may be
like oh no I've seen them crawling
around with no wings what you're seeing
are in matures that haven't developed
their wings yet I was just at a facility
a few weeks ago and we collected a bunch
of rudy foods and we looked at them
under you know my Dynalite by the way I
got a new Dino light I'm so excited but
you can actually see what are called
like wing pads and that's where the
aphid wings are gonna develop from
so even though you don't see full-blown
wings on him you can see on the immature
aphids where the wings are going to
develop and that's just something that
as you look at aphids over and over and
over again you can start to see them so
you can see these aphids that are
climbing around by the hundreds or
thousands if you look at them you can
see these wing pads and know that when
they're going to shed their skin into
the next life stage when they get to the
adult part of it they will have wings so
so take me through the lifecycle of the
Nathan okay start so for so for Rudy if
it's a little different than regular
aphids just a little bit but basically
if it's do a thing called
parthenogenesis and that means they do
not have to meet to have babies so
basically all their offsprings are
clones of themselves and this is why
there's a lot of problems with
insecticide resistance where people use
the same product over and over you know
natural pyrethrins if you use them over
and over and if mom developed resistance
since her offspring are clones of her
they're going to have resistance too and
so that's why it's very easy to develop
resistance in aphids and insecticides
and the female as once she be she is an
adult she just sits there and I'll have
live birth for the most part this this
is um in in warmer climates and inside
of greenhouses we generally don't see
them laying eggs there's in my entire
life I've only seen one species do it
and that's the cannabis aphid they're
kind of doing their own weird thing
so we'll just we'll talk about them in a
second but so inside your greenhouse
with cotton melon with your green peach
with even your Roode aphid what you're
seeing is just when female just having
live birth all the time and they're
clones of herself so and it just goes on
year-round now if you're an outside
producer of any plants in the northern
climate they do overwinter as eggs and
so when the days get shorter and the
temperatures start to fall if it's then
actually will produce some male
offsprings they'll mate and then the
females lay eggs and then they
overwinter as eggs and then in the
spring those hatch and off to the races
again but in protected environments
where they don't get those environmental
cues they just have babies year-round
and you know I work a lot in South
Florida you know outside just babies
year-round kind of thing so but for some
reason and and we're not sure exactly
why yet the cannabis aphid the actual
cannabis aphid not if it's on cannabis
but the species the cannabis e-fit it
actually it is laying eggs inside of
greenhouses but it's well facilities
that are using artificial lighting and
we're actually seeing cannabis eggs and
we think it's when people are changing
their lighting and temperature to
trigger the plants to flower that's
triggering the cannabis aphid to go into
egg-laying so that's like this one weird
exception we're seeing and I've seen it
in Canada United States southern western
United States Eastern you know kind of
all over this happening okay so would
these live births you get these little
tiny are they conservatives I don't
considered a larval stage at that point
or is it actually or immature but it
looks just like mom but it's a miniature
version because insects basically have
two ways that they can grow up and
become adults they have things like
aphids that when they're born they look
just like the adults they're just
smaller versions and each time they molt
they get a little bigger it's the same
thing with a stink bugs do that on the
flip side of that you have insects like
butterflies you know the eggs are laid
when they hatch out they're immature
stage does not look like the adult at
all and so they actually have to go
through you know complete metamorphosis
to completely change and so caterpillars
caterpillars do that flies do that
beetles do it you know ladybugs you
the larvae look like little black
alligators they don't look like ladybugs
and when people see small ladybugs and
they're like oh it's a baby ladybug it's
like no that's the full size once you
see a ladybug adult that they don't grow
any bigger than that because they're
immature stage are that little alligator
stage and so that's what's so important
to know what the different life stages
look like and you know that's what I'm
spending a ton of time teaching in my
workshops so if you do have an aphid in
an egg when that hatches does that hatch
as a little a little baby clone as well
and this is so when you have egg laying
generally there's a male and a female so
you can get some genetic diversity in
there okay okay that makes it but no one
has done this detail of work yet on the
Cannabis even because of all the
limitations of who can study it and
moving it and yada yada yada all that
stuff okay so in terms of plant health
and plant damage with the cannabis aphid
versus the root David what are are there
any distinguishing characteristics in
terms of how it affects plants or are
they still using the same mechanism for
feeding well they do they they all EFA's
have what's called a piercing sucking
mouth part you basically have the plant
wall here and their mouth looks like a
straw and they just stick it in and
that's why they start feeding on the
plant juices they don't actually chew
the plant or take away pieces of the
plant and this is why historically
systemic pesticides it works so well
because they're moving and the liquid
fluid of the plant and you know you just
tap your straw in there and you suck it
right up and that's why systemics do
work well on on a Fitz but as you know
one it can lead right back to a lot of
resistance issues and there's a lot of
crops we can't use systemics on and
including cannabis is when you
definitely don't want to be using a
systemic on but what I see with the ruh
David is an overall just decline in
plant health they just don't look as
vigorous the color can be slightly off
it just stress
the plant and usually when they're in
like propagation the numbers are so low
you don't notice it and it's overtime as
the populations build and as the plants
get closer to flower often you have
thousands of these aphids feeding on
their roots and it can really stress a
plant especially add in any nutritional
stress then you put disease strain you
know all these different factors and you
know typically people are pushing
cannabis plants pretty hard to grow for
certain characteristics that we want and
they're pushing with fertilizer and that
just adds into the stressors on there
but with the cannabis aphid they're
feeding on the foliage of the plant and
that caused and it's the same thing with
the other foliar a fat species and
they're again sticking their mouthparts
in but you can see more discoloration on
the foliage also um when aphids feed
since they're sucking up all these plant
juices they take them in a lot more
sugar than they actually need and so
what happens then is they're like well
I've got us extra sugar inside of me I'm
just gonna squirt it out and so they
actually will squirt out what we call
honeydew and it's the excess sugars they
don't need as part of their diet and you
actually get sticky on the leaf surface
and this is often times when you get
ants moving in because ants like to feed
on that sugar and if it gets really bad
you can get what's called [ __ ] mold
growing on it and oftentimes people
think they have disease issue but it's
actually all related to what we call
piercing sucking insects whether it be
if it's white flies and even some of the
soft scales can do it but I've seen it
in with white flies in cannabis so where
are we scouting for these various aphid
species well with the rooty that you
need to be scouting and probably I mean
I just think everybody should be
treating and prop I mean and this is
what people don't do enough treatment
and propagation they wait until the
problem gets too bad and it's you don't
want to wait to treat for the problem so
you need to be scouting but scouting
depending on how you're growing
can be very difficult people that use
the the large living soil beds you can't
really Scout fruit aphids because you
can't get in there and really see your
roots and once you get the Rudy if it's
in there they just keep building and
building and people end up fighting them
and basically they just try to keep them
suppressed in those soil beds you know
um with the foliar aphids you know you
go by and if you saw that video I didn't
Instagram while ago where you just bang
the plant onto the board a foods will
fall out too when you do that as well as
thrips and mites and so that's an easy
way to detect early populations on the
foliar feeding
even species so using a bang board to
get the bang a fit boom I see what you
did there so I know the ODA put out a
report on it I can link to that PDF it's
got some photos and things like that
have you had a chance to see that
advisory oh yeah yeah it looks pretty
good you something well I mean it's a
basic but the thing is is we still just
don't know a lot about it and back to
this whole egg-laying thing it's the
first time again I've ever seen a fence
lay eggs in a greenhouse and it's a
first time for a lot of people I showed
the images to other entomologist never
just like wooo because nobody's seen it
so it has a very unusual behavior about
doing that and we don't even know what
really will feed on the eggs
I would assume lacewing larvae would
feed on them because lacewing larvae
will eat just about anybody and anything
including their brothers and sisters but
it's something when you are scouting to
be aware of because you won't readily
recognize it as an aphid egg it looks
more like a yellow to black almost
really shiny Mike and Ikes candy huh
what about aureus would that feed on it
it possibly would feed on it too I mean
my dream thing to do is to you know get
a bunch of the eggs through a bunch of
beneficials instead of my scope for
hours but you've got to have the eggs
right at the right time you know it's
hard to do that kind of stuff yeah yeah
so what are some treatment options that
you're aware of for route a phase or for
the cannabis aphid you know and we've
talked about stuff
the Rudy Fed management in the past and
people listen closely because I had a
lot of people contacting me about it and
said I said things that I never sever
said so at this point in time as in July
11th 2019 we are not seeing success
controlling and with any of what I call
the macro biocontrol agents the ROA
beetles the mites any of those kinds of
things yes if you put a rue David in a
petri dish with row beetle it's probably
gonna eat it but it's not controlling it
if those things work to control it it
wouldn't be such an industry-wide
problem because everybody's dumping
loads of this stuff out what we have
seen that the best thing we've got going
right now are the microbial what we call
the enema pathogenic fungi they're fungi
that kill insects products like patan
Agard or my cotrol which are the bavaria
bassiano and that's the GH a strain
strain has been successful but what I'm
finding is when people say I'm doing it
I'm not getting control the probe
doesn't work they suck they're not
applying it correctly and also for the
ninth million times the Tana guard is
not a GMO product it is not genetically
engineered cannabis industry you know
what I need my 10 foil hat for this and
it's actually upstairs okay it is not a
GMO product
none of those microbe deals on the
market right now
now they've selected them by saying wow
this fungus works the best so working
these but it's not genetically
engineered and I got people you know
saying it and in it it's not true you
have to fact-check what you're saying
out there but that said the bavaria as a
drench application and remember the
spores have to come in contact with the
aphid it's not systemic and you have to
get contact for it to work we're seeing
good results with eyes area which is
another genus of anima pathogenic fungi
and that's in the product like PFR 97
but again you have to apply correctly
and get contact so how how are you
recommending applying this I know I was
just interviewing a buddy of mine and he
was using the hold on let me get this
right
the the DRAM BP for with an aftermarket
five headed telescopic atomizing Lance
for a lot of his spray applications now
that's spring not necessarily for
microbial applications but how are you
applying a lot of products you're
talking about well well so so the
microbials like the Bavaria or eyes area
so they work well on Rudy if it's not
foliar a foot so you it's it's kind of
somewhat complicated so the fungus when
it's in the soil does a good job in the
ribbits but for foliar aphids it doesn't
work that well cuz you really have to
tank mix the fungus with an insect
growth regulator which are IG r s IG ARS
basically disrupt insects from becoming
mature adults so basically it's like if
a 14-year olds getting hammered with a
compound that will keep them from going
through puberty kind of thing it's
basically what insect growth regulators
do and this is very very loose the way
I'm explaining this but what happens is
when you have an aphid if it shed their
skin a lot really fast the foolery fits
and that's where you get those white
flakes everywhere if you spray in here
lanza by various spore or your eyes area
and then it sheds its skin there goes
the spore if you tank making it with an
insect growth regulator it stops them
from molting and so that spore can't get
molted off and so if you're talking
about using these microbials for a
foliar application for a fadeev got to
have that IG are not necessarily for the
root avid species because you have a
hundred percent humidity in the soil and
the fungus works fast enough down there
but on the foliage you need that the
problem is
is when you look at insect growth
regulators most of them are disallowed
in cannabis production with the one
exception of as interacting and
depending on what state you're in if you
can use as interaction or not but as it
are actin is actually an insect growth
regulator that can be tank mixed with
the microbials for better foliar ef'n
management so as far as the sprayer your
buddy's using that's when you would use
that kind of sprayer but treating for
rudy if it's in the soil you need one of
more like the the drenching heads that
you know is like a heavy water because
you want to get a lot of water volume to
get the fungal spores down into the soil
surface and do the i mean its into the
media through through the soil profile
yeah yes thank you so what I'm wondering
though is how does an atomizer affect
these spores is it it's not damaging and
damaging them so the main thing that can
damage spores is heat and that's why you
have to be very careful with foggers dr.
Michael Brown bridge if you guys don't
know him you should know and follow his
work up out of he's with the Vineland
research and Innovation Center and
actually if you're coming to cultivate
this weekend I'm not sure when you put
the podcast up but Michaels gonna be
speaking on microbials this weekend at
cultivate as well as I am I'm doing a
presentation on how to integrate
microbials
with traditional chemistry's to use them
for bio control agents but Michael Brown
bridge has actually been doing study a
research up at the Vineland research and
innovation center looking at equipment
and how does putting up a very bacillus
and things like that through this
equipment and how does it affect it and
generally it's heat and pressure are two
of the issues but for just regular
sprayers it's usually not a problem it's
with these foggers where they have
really high PSI and you get the heat
heat cooks and kills them yeah I looked
at uh this was probably almost a decade
ago I looked at some compost tea through
and fogger and it destroyed everything
yeah even the bacteria was was yeah well
there's cold foggers and and DRAM makes
one and again that's a stuff if you
you can probably put a link in this for
the work that Michaels been doing on
testing the stuff okay all right so
anything else on Athens before we move
on to a different pest um I just you
know just ID I'm willing to help
everybody you guys know that because you
guys are taking full advantage of which
is okay but you know just count legs if
it has eight it's a mite if it's got six
it's a spider I mean it's a spider what
am I saying it's an insect if it has six
you know if there's you know antennae
insects have antennae you know just
basic things like that and that's why I
mean I'm not gonna completely promote
myself but yes come to one of my classes
that does basic insect ID so that you
guys can learn this stuff