can we talk a little bit about broad
mites sure great so what what can you
tell me about broad mites I know for a
while there they were like the latest
spider mite as and they were everyone
was diagnosing all plant problems as
being broad mites yes and in fact I just
saw some hemp images that you know it
was like broad my promit but it's not
we're pretty sure it's actually
herbicide damage and for outdoor
production people have to remember you
know spray drift is an issue and
herbicides drift we even had it at my
house this year the farm field up back
had sprayed and herbicide and it damaged
all our Tomatoes and we had herbicide
damage and our Tomatoes which looked
like broad my damage cuz I got all
excited thinking yes we've got broad
mites I can take pictures and videos and
it turned out to be herbicide damage so
I was really disappointed so let before
we talk about the actual life cycle in
identification for a broad minute what
are we looking for in a plant in terms
of damage I have always associated it
with sort of like incorrect me because
I'm probably wrong but I like twisted
new green growth it's a little bit
lighter than it should be in color well
on if you're speaking to cannabis
cannabis actually can have a really high
level of broad mites on it before you
see damage
you know I deal with this in ornamentals
and vegetables too and you just get a
few broad mites feeding on an impatient
and the leaf is completely gnarled and
destroyed cannabis actually handles this
past quite well not that you want it and
typically people don't realize they have
it until they do have really high
numbers and that's when you see that
slightly distorted growth a little
discoloration you walk by and it's just
like yeah it just doesn't quite look
right then you put it under your scope
and you're like holy crap you know and
then you know you have them and being
this is very what we call cosmopolitan
pest being it's it's probably in every
local garden center coming from every
major greenhouse because it's just been
a really bad past the last few years
luckily before it hit cannabis we've
been working on it a lot in ornamentals
and we've had a lot of trials and tests
and things we did and we found out
products like the SELEX work extremely
well on it
and that in combination with the
predatory mite q cámaras and so for a
lot of ornamentals now if it's if it's
an ornamental that we know can get it we
just treat it with q camaris we just do
it
as a preventative and it's basically
stopped the problem in ornamentals so
basically what you want to do then
you're saying is treat the plants early
on with something like a safar LX to
knock back the populations and then yes
follow up with an application of the
cuckoo mares yeah and I would say QQ
mares are so inexpensive I mean you know
they're just like a bread and butter
product it's easy to get again prices
low on it and Q cámaras being that we
know it does really good on broad might
it will also feed on first instar
Western flour thrips and a few other
trip species not all of them but a lot
of them it will snack on spider mite
eggs because this is something that's
been very interesting I'm New Guinean
patients we used to have a lot of spider
mite problems on in addition to thrips
problems and broad mites once we went to
using the q cámaras program we don't
have spider mite issues anymore on the
new guineas and we think that the q
camaris are stopping it before it gets
started
I would never recommend Q camaris to
treat for spider mites if you have a
population already but if there's just
one egg here and there and the Q cámaras
find it there's a chance they're gonna
just feed on it but again do not use q
cámaras as a control don't email me
saying hey I heard you say use Q camaris
to control spider mites that is not what
I said
so when we're targeting broad mites were
seeing these side benefits of other
things that will feed on and can stop
problems before they start
okay so I'm just gonna say if you're a
cannabis grower and you don't have
cucumbers in your program you're crazy
all right so if we're talking about
identifying broad mites they're quite
small very small and so they're really
hard to see you do need a microscope I
couldn't see them where the jeweler's
loupe myself what what identifying
characteristics and what do we need is
tools in the garden for people to be
able to really identify them well 60 X
magnification is generally where you
need to be around and this is where
again I love my Dynalite because my eyes
are terrible I'm I have old lady
eyeballs now and I like to be able to
take leaves and sit with my computer
with my Dynalite so it's this giant big
screen and then I can you know scan over
the leaf services with the Dynalite and
and then be able to see things close up
and then take pictures if need be well
one I use them for my classes but for my
growers they can take pictures and then
send them to me if they don't see what
something is but the broad mites
um they tend to be a little clearer on
their bodies and the the key diagnostic
feature we look for are their eggs
because they've got little white dots
all over their eggs where spider mite
eggs are larger and they're perfectly
round where these if you look they
almost remind me of like golf ball
dimples in a way they're very
distinctive eggs and if you see those
then we know that that's a broad my egg
the other thing broad mites do is the
male's will pick up and carry the
females around
so if you see am i running by and then
there's a female attached to it or it
looks like two are running along then
that's broad might also okay and so what
we're doing is we're sampling off of a
leaf that's probably new growth and then
taking that flipping it over and using
the Dynalite or a stronger and now I
haven't it's it's over there it's packed
to go for my workshop for Saturday the
new Dynalite I got is Wireless and so
you can have your laptop of your phone
setting somewhere you know a bit away
and you don't have to worry about the
cable or cord and you're able to
manipulate the Dynalite a bit easier to
be able to get into the plant can of
and everything if you don't want to cut
leaves off so yeah that's cool yeah
they're they're just expensive I love
buying but well but you gotta remember
I'm differ
this is I'm at a different job than you
are oh for sure I have a very expensive
phase-contrast microscope that would be
overkill for any grower you know I get
it
yeah you have to have the right tools
for what you're doing yeah okay so in
terms of broad mites
you mentioned cuca Maris you mentioned
self oil X I will say if you are under
warmer growing conditions which often if
you're in an in an indoor grow you're
not there is the option of using the
predatory mites were ski it's a lot more
expensive I always say start with Keuka
Maris and if you can get it to work you
can save a ton of money if not you can
move in this were ski but generally
Swersky is is for a bit warmer of
temperatures or if you're fighting white
fly at the same time that you're
fighting broad mites because sworsky
will also feed on white fly eggs okay
and are there any other oil-based
options or pesticidal sprays that you
can use that you're aware of for broad
mites besides folx
well I have a very good comfort zone
with that product because I have had
lots of my growers using it we haven't
had any problems with it and we know it
works I mean there are lots of other
oils you know a lot of the plant
botanical based ones but they get very
expensive and there needs to be testing
to prove they work as well I know there
has been some testing going on comparing
the different oils and the oils do not
all work the same I I don't want to talk
about somebody else's research because
he's gonna publish it but the oils do
not work the same there's different
particle sizes and I know one of the
things that I'm getting a lot of people
are like well some oil X it's a
petroleum product we're not going to use
it yes but here's my argument back fine
if you want to use things like plant
botanical oils to make those botanical
oils how much curb
footprinting and how much petroleum has
to go in to growing all those harvesting
all that to process it to make a small
batch I bet you if you actually looked
at the carbon the the the fossil fuel
inputs to produce those products it's
more than just using a jug of the some
oil because you think about how much of
these plants I mean how much lavender
how much rosemary how much all that you
have to grow to produce these oils it's
a lot of input and a lot of work to
harvest it and and do all that stuff too
so just saying that you know when you're
looking at you know a 1% spray rate on
some of these products and it's weird
because you know people are okay with
driving their cars and putting gasoline
in it but then they've got this weird
thing about using safai LX yeah I've
heard that so if we're if we're taking
you know we're starting early on in
propagation yep we're dipping our clones
or spraying them with the Ceph aisle and
then introducing the cuckoo Maris
hopefully to the crop fairly early on
like you said is that within like a few
days a week I mean it's right that thing
I mean the next day don't know okay
great okay and then how often should we
be introducing cuckoo Maris because I
assume if there's not enough food
they'll die off and then yes well and
this is the other thing that you know
ornamentals and vegetable guys have kind
of accepted instead of spring every week
or every two weeks they're releasing
bugs every week or two weeks you're not
building a population in there cuz as
you said there's not enough food so you
just have to do constant introductions
and this is all gonna depend on the
rates your pressure I mean and this is
what I got to work with somebody that
can help you put these programs together
because as I'm working around North
America you know people's pressures are
different in different parts of the
country and you know if you're in a very
cold climate and it's midwinter and you
know you get your spider mites abroad
might cleaned up you might not have to
read you might not have to introduce
anything else for the rest of the step
that until
you know it warms up outside if you're
in warmer climates and you know Vegas
Arizona Florida you know things like
that you're gonna have constant
pressures coming in and so you know that
you're more likely gonna have to stay on
a solid program okay and I guess my last
question about broad nights would be
what happens when you're in flower and
you notice that you have it are you are
you are you just screwed at that point
it sounds like because you're not
spraying Subway LX no you're not first
of all you should you know smack
yourself in the back your head for
letting it get to that point because
they didn't just show up
they've been there for weeks and weeks
and weeks and weeks and this is why
again I just you've got to be
preventative about this stuff again the
ornamental and vegetable eyes have
gotten it you know in propagation they
just treat everything like they're going
to get problems you can't wait and I
mean you just can't get enough Keuka
Maris out or Swersky out in in flower on
to the plant because the application
methods would just be very difficult you
did it with so much carrier on the plant
the sachets will not release fast enough
for what you need it's just it's problem