I want to talk about the hem press it
might I think another one that I've been
seeing a lot of with people it's pretty
easy to identify I think relative to
other other issues and other mites but
can you talk a little bit about it in
general well yes and no because again
there's still a lot we don't know I do
think there's a lot of bad information
they do not live in the vascular tissue
of the plants they're not inserting
their eggs into the vascular tissue you
know that again it's it's um it's
important to be getting good information
but the problem is is people the first
thing they do is they go to the Internet
and unfortunately there's you know a lot
of bad information on every subject out
there I think those are some of the
biggest misconceptions how do you get it
you generally have done it to yourself
because you brought it in on plant
material or possibly your clothing I've
been in enough cannabis facilities that
you know as you're walking down the
aisle your shoulders are brushing up
against the cannabis plants and you're
just acting as a giant vector spreading
then the mites or even insects down the
rows and you know you want to be able to
walk through a facility without dragging
your shoulders because even even if you
put on lab coat or a tie back suit or
anything and then you go out to the
lobby you take it off you still could
have insects on your skin and you know I
you need to be wearing a hairnet you
know but still you can spread things
around that way and and basically the
hem for us it might is a completely
self-induced problem because of poor
sanitation in the cannabis industry nuts
so we're not getting hemp Russert from
the outdoors it's coming plant to plant
transmission well if you are next door
to a hemp field that has it it could
theoretically blow in but you know back
to this whole the government's releasing
it out of the back of vans driving down
the roads you know that is just it's all
conspiracy series conspiracy theory
stuff and that the the other area
Fayed's they're using for weed
management it's not even close to the
same
species so that's not it's it's nobody
wants to take responsibility that
they've done it to themselves but that's
exactly what's happened with the
cannabis eat because the cannabis see if
it has now Albin down the eastern
seaboard how'd it get here through plant
movement it didn't fly over here from
California it didn't ride over on grapes
it didn't ride over on strawberries it
came on cannabis plant material and it's
the same thing with a hemp for us at my
poor sanitation practices I would say
that when I'm consulting we probably
spend seventy seventy-five percent of
our time dealing with just sanitation
and production facilities these days so
what are some good identifying
characteristics of impressive when you
see it again you need super high
magnification it's basically shaped like
a carrot where the broad might so much
more like jellybean kind of shaped these
are more shaped like a carrot so that's
one of the easiest ways to see it and
they're kind of creamy colored doesn't
have multiple stages of growth yeah well
I mean it's just like like spider mites
and just like broad mites and when they
first hatch out they're real tiny and
each time they molt they just get a
little bigger but again you know if you
see a carrot with a couple hairs of the
front end that's their legs I mean it
was just no mistaking it in cannabis
that's the only thing that looks like
that so far that we've seen in cannabis
with all this hemp going in outside who
knows what we're gonna see cuz we're
starting to see all kinds of new pests
in the outdoor hemp production and that
may end up eventually in some of the
indoor grows but for right now again
July 11th 2019 you see something looks
like a carrot it's pretty much gonna be
a hip recipe unless it's a lot bigger
and is a ladybug larva Oh a lot bigger
and looks completely different hey I've
seen that confused so I know I've had
trips and Russert mites confused and
yeah so with the hemp press it what sort
of treatment options do we have
once we fluently spotted it yeah well
first up again smack yourself in the
back of the head for bringing it in and
then after you do that
there's not a lot with you know and
we've talked about this briefly before
and some of the stuff I had higher hopes
I think for a lot of the predatory mites
I do not have a lot of confidence in the
predatory mites to manage it at this
point I think that under Sony as a
prevention still has some something
there but once you have a population
again
spraying soaps or oils I think are your
best options and you've got to get
really really good spray coverage I mean
that's what it comes down to is good
spray technique with good equipment not
paint sprayers spray equipment design
for applying pesticides
well the soil ex work as well yes it
works amazing again there's been some
work going on and somebody else is doing
it and I'm not gonna I'm gonna wait for
him to put all that stuff out but this
uh file did really well in his trials on
the impress it might extremely well now
I know some of these have a lifecycle of
a certain number of days or weeks how
many applications are sprays do we need
to be doing to really control any of
these insects we're talking well it's
all about spray coverage and that's the
thing and also with the eggs
so eggs oils kill eggs better than soaps
do typically you know there's always
exceptions but for the most part but
with eggs since they respirate so low
when you spray oil on it I used to
suffocate but if you have a very route
low respiration rate it's hard to
suffocate them but I know Cornell's done
a lot of work on Dan Gill ran looking at
oils and using them for a two spot
spider mites eggs and he said it works
extremely well the empress at my eight
eggs are so small and trans fat and not
transparent in their respirating very
low so they need multiple applications
of oil so you've got to look at your
temperatures you've got to look at your
plants stressed you got to be really
careful also you know sulfur and oil bad
bad bad bad idea I'm not a fan of using
sulfur if
sulfur will if used properly you can
really knock back and press it might I'm
concerned about all the software being
used because of resistance issues
potentially and also you've kind of
excluded yourself from using beneficials
at this point and also I had one of my
growers who was using sulfur and they
tested positive for arsenic and they
went and they tested the sulfur and that
seemed to be the source of arsenic was
in the sulfur product they were spraying
though yeah well I got a remember if
it's being used in on tomatoes and
things like that they're not heavy metal
accumulators so no one's ever had to
worry about testing that stuff before
and I'm not saying you know that all
software has arsenic don't you know in
this particular situation this is was
was their source so so I'm just I'm not
gonna say I would never recommend it but
I generally don't recommend it and I
think you're a lot safer for resistance
issues because it's gonna be really hard
to build resistance to oils cost wise so
foil acts
I think about 2 and 1/2 gallon jug is
like 60 bucks and you mix it up at like
a 1% so you're gonna make 250 gallons of
solution for $60 I mean the price is
there it's unrealistic so it's approved
for use in organic production I'm not
saying you can't use other oils it's
just I've worked for this oil for like
25 years so I have a good comfort with
it I mean that's that you know basically
what it is I haven't had Fido once it's
dry we can rerelease the beneficials but
you probably are gonna have to do a few
sprays back-to-back because you have to
get really good spray coverage and even
though you think you get a hundred
percent spray coverage you're not and
that's why if you do it again
you know you're gonna get more coverage
it's just like you know you paint a wall
a different color and you think you got
it then next day and you go by you see
spots that are really thin where the
paint wasn't thick enough that's why
going back and putting a second coat on
will make sure are you talking like the
next day or wait you know I'd give it a
couple days in between cuz you don't
want to just coat your plants in oil
either yeah okay now what about bringing
a plant into the facility let's say in a
plan
that you're bringing in you're like well
it could have hem press it might or it
could have any of the other pests we
talked about what would be your sort of
procedure for treating you know dunking
clones or cleaning up whatever it is
you're bringing it well oh you need to
have a quarantine area and this is the
problem I'm even seeing new facilities
being built that don't have quarantine
areas they just the the growing areas
aren't isolated enough so problems just
get spread around with dipping of plants
now you never any kind of oil products
you do not want to dip the roots in you
know the oils are better for the foliage
sorry my cats just jumping up he
bloopers sorry it's fine you coming for
his afternoon pets you never want to dip
roots and oils and you never want to
drench with oils you can you can use
products like the microbials are safe
for roots the Bavaria's the areas and
things like that but remember those
really don't treat for mines especially
hemp for us at night up in Canada
they've done a lot of research with
dipping cuttings for mums and for
poinsettias and things like that and in
their research in Canada they found that
dipping and a 0.1% oil solution of
foliage not the roots was a very good
dip rate for dipping these plants and
that way you do get a hundred percent
coverage and that's why when people
often take cuttings are doing this it's
still and I mean this has been going on
for years there's still this they're
trying to get it actually on the label
to say that and so it's technically not
on the label yet but it's the research
shows it works very well for a lot of
key pests and it has a very good level
of plant safety and you get a 100%
coverage because a lot of people like
well we can just stick them and spray
them but then you're not necessarily
going to get a hundred percent spray
coverage so it's it's kind of a tricky
situation there and we're waiting for
this
dip label but cannabis isn't on the
label either yes be because of the laws
with the EPA and things around
pesticides you can't recommend a dip
rate you can talk about the research
that exists in Canada but you can't make
that recommendation because of the rules
or regulations around and and some oil
acts can't make that recommendation
either direct use so I just write yeah
that's why there's all this dancing
around about it but according to
research a very good dip rate is zero
point one percent for supplamine dip
rates for other products and that's
you've got a this is what's good about
the software product is that got
research to back the stuff up it's been
trialed it's been tested and you know I
see a lot of claims from products and
okay you make this claim you say your
product annihilates him for us it might
where's a single trial you know it
annihilates spider mites okay that's
something a university could have done
or a third party or something where is
any any research on it and and it's just
not there and and it's tough to know
what to believe and what not to believe
yeah yeah so I I know I said that was
the last one I think I have one more
I have blue first I have I have an easy
one for you I think just in the sense
that I think I know what you're already
gonna say cuz we've talked about it but
plant parasitic nematodes like the
root-knot nematode what what options do
we have there none flamethrowers Burnham
this is my same thing in don't get them
I mean that's again they're not flying
in they're not walking in you brought
them into your facility now if you are
in the south because the Southeast
United States has a lot of root-knot
nematode and you're growing your plants
outdoors in the ground well that's not
your fault but when you get it in an
indoor grow or in raised beds you
brought it in I had somebody recently
contact me and they literally went
outside
and they just were scooping up soil
outside to inoculate indoors and it's a
total crapshoot you could bring in some
good stuff you can bring in a lot of bad
stuff too and that's that's the the risk
you take with doing things like that now
the University of Florida is putting in
12 hemp trial sites this year down
obviously in Florida under various soil
conditions and it's gonna be very
interesting to see and they actually do
have one of their new mythologists
working with them on this to see you
know what nematodes are picked up and
what becomes a problem for them but
they've got this really weird situation
where they're not gonna be able to
publish their findings because of it
being him so yeah it's kind of weird
they're not allowed to talk about any of
the work they're doing at this point but
that I'm hoping will give us more
information on blimps on you know what
cuz we don't even know all the nematodes
that cannabis can get at this point
I keep getting reports of stem nematodes
which I did have a grower that had some
samples and I was so excited because one
of the new Matala just agreed to look at
him to identify him and everything and
then I asked the grower to ship them and
then the girl just like went dark and
wouldn't respond to my phone calls or
anything I called over and over and over
again I guess they you know decided they
didn't want to be involved with that
which I can kind of understand but at
the same time you know until we can
figure out what we're really dealing
with you know it's gonna be harder to
manage it the pests I could probably get
you some root-knot nematodes know if
these were stem nematodes you're not
looking for root not know I we got
plenty root nods around okay I haven't
seen that one but one quite a couple
questions I did have around the root not
nematode so just for people who are less
familiar with it I want to mention that
when I've seen it the plant just
literally just seems to stop growing and
then when you pull up the plant you get
these galls or
not in the Ritz themselves they look
almost look like rhizomes that you would
see yeah
you know unwelcome roots on the knot I
mean not knotted roots root-knot
nematode and again it's not it's not
cannabis specific you know it's a big
problem on Tomatoes it's a problem I
think carrots get them there's several
vegetables and that's why you know
people still methylbromide soils to kill
these plant parasitic nematodes because
they are so so hard to kill and that's
why in states again like Florida if
you're gonna ship outside of the state
containers plant material you have to
grow up on tables off the ground to
prevent nematodes from getting splashed
into your pots so that's what there's an
actual measured height that they grow at
because water splashing can spread plant
parasitic nematodes now one thing that
my friend tried was heating their room
for an indoor facility to raise the
temperature of the room they held it at
130 degrees for an hour I've heard the
research says you have to get up to 170
but if you're able to maintain the room
at a higher temperature for a period of
time like that
I know thermophilic compost that goes
off a lot of the pathogenic bacteria any
thoughts on that well what is that your
air temperature is that the temperature
in the middle of your soil bed well in
this case I'm sure it was air
temperature but yeah and so you know
it's not even be close to that inside of
the soil in there so it's not and people
ask me about heating room I just I don't
think it's gonna work
don't bring the root-knot nematodes in
you're getting compost I think you
should test your compost for plant
parasitic nematodes you know this is
something that you know most
universities or in the state's you know
you can just send a little baggie in and
have them do a test because to me it's
not worth the risk
yeah now one one speculation they had to
so they they have my friend has a space
that does have the root-knot nematode or
it did have it they tried cleaning the
room they tried all these different
products they were never able to remove
it but what they have been able to do is
sort of knock the population down right
to where they can make it two to three
cycles before
it gets really bad again sort of thing
so they've had a little bit of success
and they they do bring in quite a bit of
the Steiner name of fealty a which I
probably didn't pronounce great enough
and there was there any chance that
those two could be competing for some
sort of ecological niche in the soil at
all are they just to toil and this is
where people have taken liberties saying
that the beneficial nematodes will
control plant parasitic nematodes I
talked to the woman that actually did
some of this work and this was at like a
Nimet ology meeting like 15 years ago
and she said what they found is in the
petri dish if you put and I can't
remember which beneficial nematodes they
put in there and I'm pretty sure his
root not is they just kind of slightly
moved apart in the dish remember
nematodes don't travel far they're so
tiny and people took that as well it
controls it it's again if that if it
worked you would see all the big farms
doing it and we wouldn't be so using
methyl bromide I mean that's all I can
say is if something works people do it
and you don't see big farms doing it
believe me
BASF they would love to be selling
nematodes for control a plant parasitic
nematodes because they'd be selling
billions of them if that worked
they'd be doing it okay cool
well I would love to follow up another
time and talk a little bit we didn't
even get to like spider mites or thrips
or no we can't cover that much in a I
know I know but that was great I really
appreciate it that was fun