[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge don't
forget to subscribe to the podcast and
leave us a rating and review you can
also sign up for our newsletters on our
website as it's the best way to find out
what new episodes of blogposts come out
as well as any discounts or coupon codes
speaking of discounts I've gotten a lot
of feedback from people who are wanting
to try out this style of cultivation but
they live on the other side of the
country or in areas where it's hard to
source many of these ingredients in
order to get people started I'm offering
50% off on a bag of our biochar or water
only soils for this month only through a
one plant your grow room and just give
it water and see how it compares to your
current growing method then at the end
of the cycle just reinvent that soil and
use it again
typically we see even better results the
second cycle just put the code living
soil when checking out on kiss organics
calm and let me know what you think this
is the second part of our interview with
Nelson Linsley of poetry of plants
Nelson is a cannabis consultant down in
California who has some unique
perspectives on cultivation as well as a
vast amount of expertise regarding
lighting technologies we pick up right
where we left off last episode and start
talking about how he's getting some
massive yields in this garden alright
let's let's change topics then yeah one
of the things I wanted to talk to you
about then was you do a lot of
consulting and one thing I haven't
mentioned yet in this talk is the yields
that you're getting which is really huge
I heard from David you are at 90 grams
per square foot is that right yes which
doesn't that translate to over four
pounds per perlite approximately I don't
ever measure by light that's that's what
that we've got to stop doing I agree
with you it's just that's the standard
the people know right it wouldn't be no
wouldn't be four pounds it was okay if
we're gonna look at it per spider it was
three point two five
five pounds per spider okay but it was
really three point two five pounds and a
4x4 a little bit less than a 4x4 because
it was a custom tray and the plants were
spilling out on the perimeter so we
could even say that if we're you know
that the canopy measurements and heel
measurements are a little muddy and I
try and be as transparent as possible
about that so that that was the figure
that we measured based on the tray size
at four by four okay but the plants were
definitely at that point falling and
toppling all over the place
the highest I've seen with organics pure
organics is around sixty grams per
square foot yeah it's really good it is
it's great you're obviously crushing it
on yield I just kind of wanted to get
into that a little bit in terms of some
of the methods that you're using there
you meant again we talked about this
hybrid method you're talking about the
lighting you've talked about a little
bit about temperature and humidity is
there anything else you want to touch on
there you got to have good genetics you
know I mean that's if you're if you're
taking a really beat genetic and trying
to get high yields out of it you're not
gonna get high yields out of it I mean
that sure that's like a you know there's
been a couple strains there's this such
an egg company up in Washington called
exotic genetics that I've gotten some
some some funny plants from that are
awesome they grow totally crazy and they
produce extremely high yields and then
I'll have a plant next to it that is a
fraction of that so a lot of the key is
really learning the plant having a
high-quality cultivar that's bred for
high yields right because not all
strains are bred for high yields you're
not going to get 90 grams per square
foot from you know San Fernando Valley
og plant you know or a Girl Scout cookie
or a Candyland I've never gotten that
and I don't believe anybody that says
they have because I know the plants
morphology so there's certain strands
where they've been bred in a way to
produce those high yields if the
environment is is is dialed in for it
and also plant second hand
very high light levels are gonna explode
be explosive and that's one of things we
can do with the LED lighting is when you
have that plant you create that
environment and you can just feed it
photons it you know I you know I don't
know where the ceiling is yet but I
don't think I've reached it I think I
can do even more but that's that is a
genetic genetics are you know I can't
take a lot of credit for it because you
know I think the plant does most of the
work you know to be honest with you as
long as you give the plant the right you
know stage to get going
and I'd never gotten those yields with
high pressure sodium or heli seeds I've
only got those yields with with like
really high high high ppfd LEDs just to
be clear on that with the one run where
that first happened because when I first
started growing under LEDs I was not
getting great yields but I was doing
things wrong and started making
adjustments to the environment the
number one thing was the vapor pressure
differential I would say that's a big
key that people miss is that they run
too low of a humidity and people are
scared to run high humidity of course
because of powdery mildew but if you can
find you can also test to see if a plant
is powdery mildew resistant there's a
company out of Boston called medicinal
genomics I'm going to put this down for
everybody if you're paying attention and
they sell a little device that you can
take you know some leaf sap or a leaf
tissue and it tests the DNA of the plant
and tells you if the plan has powdery
mildew in it and it tells you if the
plant is pad it has it has the powdery
mildew resistant genome and if it has
that gene so if you can find plants that
are powdery mildew resistant that don't
have powdery mildew in them that haven't
been expressed yet then you're not gonna
have any problems running a higher
humidity in those first three weeks so
that's something that's really key so if
you've got a plant that's got powdery
mildew in it you're gonna have that
powdery mildew probably is it's going to
express itself if you start to kind of
crank it and do any stress to the plant
so that's also something important for
people to know and there's technology
out there to tell you whether you have
powdery mildew in the plant which is a
systemic systemic issue so that that
that's the key for that and then running
or fertilization levels again some of
this stuff I've covered because you're
gonna have higher transpiration rates
and then gradually ramping up the light
and not going full-tilt right off the
bat so someone wanted to transition
let's say we have a grower that's been
using general hydroponics or advanced
nutrients and they hear this talk and
they say okay I want to start
transitioning over and considering
organics and considering getting off of
these bottle of nutrients where would
they where do you recommend they would
start sourcing some of these mineral
salts at a more affordable level Peters
and grow more are two companies that
make mineral salt blends that that you
can source and get bags of this
gnarly-looking blue powder that is has a
solid mineral salt formulation that can
be a basis for getting into it now I
still use the amended peat moss so I
really use those mineral salts as a way
to give it what I think it needs those
all those high yields I never went above
one point to EC that was it just to be
clear on that
and I've tried ramping it up and all
I've seen is negative results so I've
gotten the best results with a lightly
amended peat moss and with a grow more
people on our grow more in Peters blend
so when you say peat moss you're going
out getting spanked in peat moss like a
bale of it then and then yes bagmen peat
moss sorry to be clear it's [ __ ] no mitts
I was listening you guys talk about that
but it's it's the sunshine mix or Sun
grill okay you know it's got some
dolomite in it and some perlite and then
do you it sounds I'm guessing you iCal
to that it sounds like you're a big help
fan yeah I do add kelp I add a began ik
worm castings so there's no you know I'm
not using any animal products in the
soil
I haven't had good results with that yet
I know some people have good results
with bone meal and other kinds of things
I've just had better results not doing
that and using vegetable compost
interesting interesting yeah I
personally don't have any issues with
animal by-products but I understand that
some people do which is where this hold
fig anak industry came out of I don't I
don't have an issue with it either I
just
I've tried it and I've gotten better
results with the with the hybrid blend
right so okay that's that's what I'm
saying so I mean I don't think there's
anything wrong with it and I think it's
actually could be part of sustainable
agriculture it is now but I just gotten
the best results using that type of
amendment kelp what else some some some
mineral some of the glacial rock dust as
well a little bit of that yeah and just
keeping it simple right great so I just
wanted to give someone an idea of what
they could do if they wanted to start
experimenting with this sort of thing Oh
in silica that's the other thing I
forgot to talk about that and I see that
you guys offer a potassium silicon yeah
the potassium silicon thing is it's the
same no matter where you buy it it's
it's what's in dyna-gro protect it's all
coming from one company they're a lot of
the silica blast and all that they're
just adding water to it exactly so the
egg still 16h we carry it a lot of
people carry it there's nothing unique
about it but that is a good way to pick
up silica it's not fully organic well
where where it's so a quick question
work and this is something that I
haven't done enough research on but
where is silica where can we not I mean
silica sand right are we adding are you
if you're gonna go straight organic and
you don't want to use an ionic nutrient
or the potassium silicon how do you
provide silica to the plant and how
would you foliar feed that because
that's another strategy that I use as
well is I like to foliar feed potassium
so look at that that seems to do very
what the planet seems to do very well
respond very well with that
and interchanging that with the kelp
full foliar spray as well so we're
getting a little bit outside of just my
knowledge in my head here when I have
offhand in terms of the silica I know
diatomaceous earth is really high in
silica you mentioned silica sand I
believe those are in the form of silicon
dioxide okay which takes a little bit
longer to break down and I was asking at
this last trade shows at us asking some
of these guys you know that do this to
make the sand and the diatomaceous earth
how long it takes for the silica become
available and they couldn't really
me an answer yeah I haven't gotten I
haven't found an answer to that either
and that and that you know that's why I
haven't I stopped using it you know and
I went back to the potassium silicon
well I think it's gonna vary based on
how how much biological activity you
have in your soils so it is fair to say
that you can't just give a given number
but we could say that maybe it's
available within you know month to three
months or some sort of timeline is sort
of what I was looking for just a general
idea you know if this isn't gonna be
available for five years it's probably
not something a many use yes in my soil
so that's that's one aspect of it work
it artwork getting decent silica levels
just from the various combination of
amendments that we're using in our soils
but as you know silica has so many
benefits I'll actually attach a silica
article to this podcast so people can
read it
it's called silica the strange medium
element and it talks about all the
benefits of silica from drought stress
to actually mitigating trace mineral
excesses so if you have in the leaf
itself so it doesn't make that extra
manganese ore copper unable to be taken
up by the plant but what it does is it
actually spreads it more evenly through
the leaf tissue Wow so that you have
less toxicity effects from the excess
micronutrient it's really cool stuff so
well that big fan so yeah yeah cuz so
when I've been pushing the light levels
to see where the threshold is for
strains a lot of times I you know well
every time I'm spraying silica and that
always seems to mitigate any kind of
light stress if it's gradually coming on
if it's if it's gone full-tilt then
there's not a whole heck of a lot I can
do to bring it back but the silica is
something that I use in conjunction with
ramping up the light so that's something
I should mention I mean that's and and I
play around with dilution ratios you
know so I also sometimes go you know
three X on the dosage just to see what
happens and I haven't seen any negative
results yet by going a high on the
silica well you say three X are you
going off of the rates that say they
recommend with dyna-gro yes yes yeah
okay so just for people listening if you
do go out and
excel 16h well we do carry it on our
website when you go to mix it be sure to
add water to the container first before
you pour the powder in it's a exothermic
reaction
you'll get Heat you don't want to burn
through the bottom of that bucket we're
al aspirator wear gloves you know you
don't want to come in contact with this
material but you can mix your own you
know your own protect for a quarter of
the cost yeah so it's a really
affordable way of using using silicone
your garden absolutely absolutely and
you know and I would say if you're if
you're trying to scale your garden you
shouldn't be scaling it with bottled
nutrients that's one thing just a side
note so learn learn all those those
safety practices when it comes to mixing
your own fertilizers regardless of what
it is I mean you're gonna be if with
micro cores I and or micro eyes'll and
other other kinds of bacteria I mean I
don't know if all of that bacteria you
should be breathing in so you should be
wearing a mask you know you should be
taking safety precautions I mean maybe
you have a couple notes on that as well
tat as far as how people should be
blending their mediums blending their
fertilizers and you know being safe with
it because there isn't like necessarily
a you know with the pesticide industry
the label is the law and they give you
specific instructions but there isn't
really a lot of instructions on people
how people should be you know making
their soils making their fertilizers all
those kinds of things on on a bag or a
bottle yet yeah that's a really good
point you know I am a cooperative having
mixed soils without wearing a mask and
so am i you know i you're young you feel
indestructible you don't think about
that kind of thing as I've gotten older
now I start thinking about how to take
care of my body and what I'm breathing
in and I think it is important to wear a
mask just to keep the dust particles
yeah at the very least I mean a lot of
the stuff we're using in organics it's
not inherently dangerous per se but I
don't want to get into your lungs so
yeah that's totally agree with you yeah
it's not it's not it's not any you know
but you just don't want to be blowing
out smegma for like four days which I
definitely have had happen or I'm like
ah man why did I do that you know so a
funny story I actually we have a feed
store at
farm and we got dust mites which are
crazy it looks like this and you look
really really close and you can see him
moving around and they came in on some
feed and we had I kid you not 55,000
pounds worth of feed in this container I
know because I was counting as I had to
move it all out of the container and in
at night I was up to like three in the
morning moving feed and move it back
into the shipping container but in
between that what I did was I took
everything out and then I just blew the
dust out and I wore a respirator and
then I threw diatomaceous earth down and
then I blew that out again you know help
kill any dust mites and things like that
I didn't wear goggles and my eyes were
bloodshot for like four days what did I
do to myself so I you got it you got it
really think about what's in the air
around you when you're growing and just
be really careful because looking back I
was like yeah I should know better I
mean this is diatomaceous earth why am i
letting this get in my eyes yeah or oh
isn't isn't diatomaceous earth also not
something you want to breathe in oh yeah
no I definitely had a respirator on but
I've and then it wasn't enough
precaution yeah yeah enemies oh these
are so that's this is goes back to like
well that's that's a good thing to
regulate right that would be a good
thing because we want people to be safe
in the garden so there should be we
should have good safety practices in the
garden because we want to be healthy we
want to have a lot of energy and we
don't want to be sick you know you know
lugging plants around because we'll make
more mistakes you know that's that's
what I know and I'm not healthy in the
garden
usually the garden is a reflection of my
health when my Gardens healthy I'm
healthy when I'm not healthy my garden
suffers so you know yeah that reminds me
of something I wanted to mention earlier
when you're talking about protecting
yourself from bacteria and yes I do
agree with you on that when we're
talking about mixing things but when we
talk about getting in the garden and
using your hands and getting into soil
there's studies that show that there's
bacteria in the soil that actually helps
create and stimulate serotonin and
happiness and it can actually help with
depression and problems like that so
alright I try to get out there
my vegetable garden and let my hands get
dirty and experience that you know and I
think it really does it's very
meditative oh I hunted percent agree
that that is uh that's what I'm mixing
my soil so what we're talking about as a
couple things make sure that your mucous
membranes are protected like your eyes
and your nose but yeah man you got to
get your hands in the dirt if you're not
getting your hands in the dirt you're
missing out because it first of all it
just feels awesome you know and as long
as it's not the only times I've had
issues with my hands in the dirt is when
I've used like with that with the cow
with the cow manure compost because I've
had a lot of oil in it and it kind of
aid away part of my finger so yeah so
there's certain things like if you're
moving to the vegetable earthworms you
know castings and all that I've never
had that problem when I don't when I was
using specific types of animal compost
there was definitely some kind of oil in
it that was no good and you just have to
I'm not saying don't put your hands in
the dirt I think you need to put your
hands in the dirt I think that's
something that everyone on this planet
needs to be doing more but just just
just do a little research on when you're
mixing things that's because you're
dealing with higher concentrations yeah
I don't want people to get to take away
that all animal composts are bad I just
to be clear and I know you're not saying
I'm not saying that yeah we use a two to
three year aged fish compost that I'm
really pretty happy with for the most
part with our soils and I've seen some
great you know soils that were from
horse manure and things like that I'm
not a big fan of camp cal manure like
you mentioned for a variety reasons but
I don't really want to get into that
yeah I mean that much and that's the
only that's the only compost that I had
I've ever had an issue with and I do use
I do use fish comp I do use fish compost
as well so that's the oso and I'm
thinking animal I'm thinking of
terrestrial and I'm all I'm not thinking
about things from the sea thanks I've
never had a problem with anything from
the sea that's uh you know I don't know
why that is maybe it's just me but I
love kelp I love fish emulsion all those
kinds of things are great all right so
I'm probably gonna have to have you back
on cuz I feel like I could talk to you
for hours
yeah that's fine I love it
before we go I know you wanted to talk
pesticides let's let's knock that one
out because I think you have a really
unique perspective and yeah I kind of
want to come on get that out there sure
um so I said there's okay there's some
things out there there's some really bad
pesticide practices that have been going
on in the gray and black market for
because it hasn't been regulated and the
best place to find those practices is if
you just go on some of these forums and
they give you these dilution ratios that
are out of this world for pesticides
that are labeled for ornamental plants
alright and there's a reason why there
have been labeled for ornamental plants
because they've done a considerable
amount of research on those pesticides
and that those are pesticides that we
shouldn't be putting into our body for
particular reasons you know they could
have a long-term effect on our
mitochondria they could have other kinds
of effect on our body that we just want
to stay away from and a little bit of a
backstory my brother is a brain cancer
survivor and this is what kind of leads
into this little bit but my brother's a
brain cancer survivor and when he was
very I guess he was like three or four
years old his cannons brain cancer came
on when he was six he was three or four
years old he had this crazy seizure out
in our backyard well they had just
applied this organophosphate which most
of those are now been banned but they
had apply to an organophosphate to all
the trees in our backyard because there
had been some African beetle that was
destroying the trees so my brother had a
crazy reaction from it at a crazy
seizure and without any study and now I
don't we don't know I mean there's more
research coming out about why we have
cancer and a lot of thats leaning
towards it's a genetic thing that's
going on and I don't know if it
necessarily correlated with my brother's
brain cancer but you know my mother
bless her heart total environmentalist
you know went on a campaign against
these pesticides and the good thing was
she ended up working with Cesar Chavez
and was on Geraldo and also the kind of
stuff because all of the migrant workers
and that were picking all the grapes
were getting sprayed every day by
organophosphates and getting very sick
and having real
like bad issues because of that well
when I look at that now and spending a
little time in the chemical pest control
world and learning a little bit about it
I look at that there was like a lot of
really bad practices with the chemicals
all right and organophosphates are
primarily banned there's like one DeVoe
clavos which is the most hot pest strips
I don't know if you've seen those before
but those you can still get but most all
organophosphates have been banned
because they have the way that they
absorb into water all right so there's
certain kinds of pests sighs certain
kind of reactions and you don't want the
ones that kind of absorb into water
because that'll kill the amphibians and
if you live on stalks if you live in a
healthy land you're gonna hear the frogs
right if you don't hear the frogs then
you should go get your water tucked
because there could be some kind of
chemical in it because frogs and
amphibians they breathe through their
skin so they're gonna be the first thing
that dies if there's a pesticide problem
well when I look at this I look at is
like a methodology and a practice issue
not necessarily how do I say this all
right this is a tough conversation
navigate because there's a lot of
overzealous anti pesticide anti chemical
and what I want to say is we should have
an open mind to some of the progress
that science has made when it comes to
agriculture and also analyze the
methodology and the practices that are
being used and separate that from the
science all right because there's some
you know we one of the reasons why we're
using pesticides is because we're mono
cropping alright mono cropping isn't
really natural as it is but that's what
we've stirred out as of now on how to
feed all these people that have
populated this earth and the population
of the earth is expanding and then when
you go mono cropping outdoors and you've
got still the UV of the Sun it's helping
you out here and there and you've got
some other things that are helping you
out and then you bring that in your mono
cropping indoors it gets extremely
challenging to control pests and bad
fungals and there is and I'm not
advocating people go out and spray their
plants with pesticides it's not all what
I'm saying I'm more speaking towards the
community of people that are
anteye chemical everything alright and I
would just implore them to really do the
due diligence and do the research on
what's out there where the progress is
now and where it needs to go because
there's different kinds of biological
insecticides and biological fungicides
that are naturally produced like what is
it that chitin the chitin producing back
or the kinase bacteria that then
produces an enzyme that can be used to
actually destroy fungal pathogens I mean
this is a that would be considered a
biological pesticide and a lot of people
get locked into a language battle when
they don't understand that anything
that's used to kill a bug is going to be
called a pesticide I mean I have a buddy
that was spraying compost tea on trees
to bring them back to health and to get
rid of another beetle because he found
that this worked and he got shut down
because what they said he was doing was
applying a pesticide without an Ag
license well that got labeled by the
courts as a pesticide and that's a
compost tea so what people don't
understand is that we've got to take the
emotional emotionality out of the
conversation and look at all the tools
that we have do the scientific research
on how those tools can be applied to
cannabis in a safe way without jumping
into conclusions and without going crazy
about it because we might need some kind
of you know biological control or
chemical control to sustainably produce
some of these plants and doors now we
get into a whole other topic where we
don't need pesticides if we're
genetically modifying the plant now
people freak out about genetically
modified food again that's another
buzzword that I think has been misused
and I'm not talking about you know
glyphosate or whatever it's called and
mixing all that in but I would be
completely for splicing powdery mildew a
gene from a powdery resist powdery
mildew resistant cannabis plant and
splicing it into a plant that doesn't
have that resistance you know and I and
there are people that I've brought that
up too and they want to crucify me on a
cross for saying that and I don't
understand why because now we're not
having too
why those chemicals that are
questionably safe but there's just this
whole thought process that to me feels a
little archaic from where we're at right
now with the tools that we have in our
tool chest to create better crops and I
think that if certain it what happens
then is that the public perception gets
changed and then there then those
processes get shut down and we could be
missing a solution by pushing back on
that without having a pragmatic and
logical conversation about it analogical
study about it and and I don't think
those studies should be funded by the
people that are against those groups
because that's usually what happens
you've got people that are anti
pesticide they already have a bias and
they're gonna do a study and it's gonna
lean towards their their theory or their
a hypothesis and then you've got the
chemical companies that are doing the
study and they have a more rigorous
process of testing all of it but it's
still coming from them so people aren't
going to trust them because they don't
trust them already and people are gonna
trust the people that have a bias well
to me that whole process is completely
broken and we need to look at it
completely differently because I know
there's some really epic scientists out
there they're doing a lot of work so
people can get the mint minerals and
nutrition that they need from their food
and they're getting stymied by this
perception and I don't you know I would
say that if we can be charged it a
little bit not to the point where we're
not questioning it not to the point
we're not engaging with it not the point
where we're really looking into it but
understand that there's a reason why we
have pesticides now and we before we had
pesticides we had famines where people
were starving alright and now people are
like all pesticides are bad you know and
what they don't understand is when if
you eliminate the pesticide well first
of all and I know you've probably talked
about this a little bit they're still
spraying stuff or we call it organic
plant doesn't mean that it doesn't have
pesticides on it just means they can't
use specific pesticides and they can't
use specific inputs but they're having
to spray it more because from what from
what I've seen and what I've learned
they're having to do
more work and apply more chemicals to
that plant to keep the bugs from
proliferating especially when they're
mono cropping so there's two ways we can
go if we're going to continue to do this
large-scale food cultivation that we're
doing right now on this planet we're
gonna have to figure out a better way of
applying these chemicals or use
biologicals that are in some of these
bacteria some of these things that we're
giving in our compost tea that we don't
even understand yet right we're getting
accomplished tea and it's like solving
problems but the science isn't totally
there yet you know that look we don't
again we talked about the soil biology
and it's like this world that we're just
beginning to tap into well we need to do
more research on that that needs to be
coming from the system quote-unquote the
matrix we need to be working with them
so that can move out of the hippie
folklore move out of the esoteric and
move into the tangible move into the
practical and be used on a large scale
level and we need be looking at the
pesticide practice that are going on
right now and identify which ones are
really causing the problems and we need
to do that well we need to do that
without emotionality I mean that's my
whole thought on it because I think if
we can do that then we can find better
products better solutions if we're doing
this large-scale mono cropping model the
other solution is for local communities
start growing their own food and doing
that in a biodiverse atmosphere I mean
there's guys like Ron Finley in LA that
are gardening in the thoroughfare you
know in doing all kinds of work to feed
their their their local communities and
I really think that's the best solution
all right but people are lazy people are
accustomed to just getting what they
want when they want it and I don't know
how we turn that corner yet to get
people to be actually growing their own
food and cultivating it maybe on a local
level I mean I think that's because then
you can have a biodiverse amount of
crops there and they're all working
together and all this knowledge that
we're learning about the fungal Network
in soil the bacterial network all this
communication can be going well I've got
high quality food we'll be producing it
there and probably needing very little
pesticides I mean I have you know these
massive outdoor cannabis plants in my
backyard and I have not needed to apply
neem I have not needed to apply any any
kind of fungal control or
anything on it there in a biodiverse
space sometimes it'll be a bug here and
there I land on it and then I come the
next morning and there's a spiderweb in
between the branches eating all the bugs
that were chowing on it I mean we just
you just don't get that in a mono
cropping system so for mono cropping
that has to be coupled with some kind of
chemical control for it to be successful
I don't know any other way if we can
move out a mono cropping then we can
move away from some of these chemical
controls and we can use more of these
things that we're seeing that David
talks a lot about with the biological
controls and things like that with you
know predatorial insects which i think
is really fascinating so I just I'm
imploring the community to I love the
heart I love the passion but you you
have to couple that that heart and that
passion with knowledge and you can't
just read something on Google and assume
that it's true you've got to look at it
you've got to prequalify it because if
we don't do that we get lost we get lost
and we have to understand what's data
and what's a what's an agenda all right
we have to be able to to parse those two
things and and not all all am I saying
go ahead spray pesticides not amal am i
saying don't go spray pesticides what
I'm saying is that we need to have an
intelligent conversation about it and
it's extremely upsetting to see how the
pesticide and the pest thing in this
industry right now like all these guys
in social media if they've got if
they're dealing with some powdery mildew
if they're dealing with some spider
mites right everyone's afraid to be
honest about it because people will go
after them like vultures they're afraid
to talk about what they're doing so the
practices get hidden right so people
start doing bad practices again they
start spraying ornamental pesticides and
fungal controls to keep their problems a
secret well guess what if I have a
problem I post it and I show everybody
and I said look I screwed the pooch
you know I did I did something went
wrong here or this plant isn't a great
plant and I'll talk about it with people
and I haven't gotten any hate from doing
that all right I haven't gotten anybody
to come back at me like I'm saying look
let's be honest about
issues were having so we can work on
solving them together in an intelligent
way but not let's not pretend that were
that we're not spraying pesticides
anymore all right and I'm not saying I'm
spraying pesticides and I'm not spitting
they're spraying pesticides but I know a
lot of people are pretending that
they're not spraying these things and
they are I know it I've seen it all
right I can I know what's going on
there's there's a perception and there's
a reality and if we can be honest about
the struggles we're having I think we
can find a better solution faster
without poisoning people all right and
that's something that I feel very
passionate about I love what you had to
say there I don't totally agree with
everything you had to say okay which is
which is okay yeah that's great
that's what makes this such an amazing
world to live on the first thing I would
say is one you are totally right people
are spraying pesticides and there is
this fear that if they show any wear on
their social media or with other people
that their plants don't look perfect and
all their buds aren't amazing that the
perception of them as growers is that
they're not good growers and you're
right that's crap I mean I think people
should be putting that forward in my
vegetable garden right now I have some
plants they're doing a lot better than
others and that's just always the way
it's going to be yeah and that's part of
that process and when it comes to
pesticides though this is where I have
to have to disagree a little bit is I
feel like I've been burned too many
times by the cannabis industry and by
the pesticide institute industry to
where I don't feel like I can trust them
anymore I mean right the other day like
I was down at Home Depot well I guess
this was a few years ago now looking at
blueberry plants and they had signs on
them that said they's have been sprayed
with knio knio conoid so i don't know
how to pronounce your nicotine neo
nicotine or you go yeah neo nicotine
thank you and this is something that's
known to kill honeybees that are
supposed to pollinate the blueberries oh
yeah big problem I'm supposed to eat big
bran we don't know the effects of all of
these pesticides long term we talked
about cancer a little bit you mentioned
DDT and Rachel Carson's book Silent
Spring it's a great example of that like
it's why we don't have condors
you know yeah it's crazy to me so when
you when you say you know let's do the
science I agree with you but the same
time like there's companies that are
gonna take advantage of that we already
have seen that with Guardian might spray
in the cannabis industry that was a huge
one on the organic side because if
you're in a Gant grower you're probably
giving a sample at some time and you
probably spray it on your crop not
knowing what was in there
we've seen it you know outside of the
cannabis industry with roundup or
glyphosate and some of the research
that's coming out on that right now and
I know I know that's a big issue that
hasn't totally been settled in terms of
its effects on human development on kids
on pets on people's sensitivities to it
so I almost feel and I'm I'm in the
other camp there where like a fool me
once I just can't trust you because all
these pesticides are coming from big big
egg or big companies like Scott's
Monsanto Bayer Dow dad yeah and you know
honestly I don't trust them with the
future of my seed production the future
of what pesticides I can use I mean
Roundup Ready crops have been destroyed
India yeah a lot of farmers over there
they've been you know completely you
know burned into poverty because they've
had they're forced to buy seed every
year the the crop they have a crop
failure they're done I just I just
struggle so much with that know why I
agree with you well I don't think I was
being clear enough though
then it because I I'm a hundred percent
in agreeing agreement with you and I and
I think that goes back to the practice
right it goes back to how they're how
they're releasing these chemicals right
they're not doing and and whether those
chemicals should ever be released you
know and and part of that problem is
that they're trying to like find a quick
fix for a long term solution but what
does that do to the to the insects the
insects have a very short life cycle and
they evolve and now we have super
insects right and that's a direct result
of the pesticide use that's a bad
practice
all right that's a bad practice and I
interrupted you so I apologize for that
but I just want to I I I'm what I'm
saying is that we don't know on the
science end
how much of that is a tool that we can
use yet because of how bad the practices
have been with it but instead of
targeting the scientific research as
well all I'm saying and studying it
where we're glomming it all together is
what I'm trying to say
does that make though yeah don't
demonize the word pesticide rather
deepen eyes bad practices and using some
of these pesticides is what you're
getting at exactly because for me if and
I know it's happening right now even in
the 5:02 industry if you're using eagle
20 if you're using Avid if you're using
you know these sorts of products to me
you're just you're not a good grower you
know you you there are other ways and I
know that's probably gonna offend some
people but I hope it challenges people
to to say hey I need to provide safe
medicine I need to provide safe food for
people that are that are consuming you
know vegetables and stuff such so I just
I believe that there are good biological
solutions yep like what David talked
about absolutely I think there are
botanical oils and sprays that you can
use safely in the right concentrations
so I don't hate the word pesticide I
think it's a reality of mono cropping
like you said and frankly pesticides is
what saved the human race in a lot of
ways because we wouldn't be able to have
farmed on the scale that we have and fed
this many people without them yes die
and I think that's that's the point I'm
trying to make is that it's not it's and
I think it also comes back to the come
back to how little we actually know like
how we don't understand the butterfly
effect of all these actions yet and
sometimes they're gonna manifest a
hundred years from now I mean when I was
studying different pesticides one of the
things with DDT that was so bad about it
was that it had such a long half-life so
if you sprayed you know a crawlspace of
a home with DDT and you come back 30
years later there's still no bugs down
there I mean that's not probably a good
idea to be using something like that
because it's gonna affect things on a
very long-term level and
it's just the god it's such a sticky
conversation that's the problem with it
too because it's so charged and it's
it's more like we need to learn more we
need to understand more what's going on
we need to understand the insect biology
more we need to understand the fungal
biology more we need to study how nature
handles that and we need to learn on how
to apply that a more efficient rate and
that might come down to chemically
extracting some biological right and
then applying it and that could be
considered a pesticide and there it
could get to a point where things are so
charged around the wording on all of it
there's that there's really safe
solutions that are coming from the right
place
that gets thrown out B or they get
banned or not used just because of the
realm that they're in without the full
understanding of what it is and what
it's doing and if that makes any sense I
mean like what is and maybe you have the
answer for me for that but like what is
what is the heat and I don't know this
but I've used spinosad before for
controlling threats and I've looked into
the process of how spinosad were
discovered and how it's how it's been
made is there any study showing that
spinosad is harmful to human beings I
haven't seen any I've moved away from it
myself just because of the fact that
it's made by I believe Bayer or Dow it's
one of the two yeah and I just don't
trust those companies got it and I want
to I want to vote with my money and you
know I want to make economic decisions
that support my values and for me those
companies are not the companies that I
choose to support so but that's two
different conversations right so it
totally is and that's that's that it's
exactly what I'm saying like I don't
care about those companies that's not
like if those companies are I don't I I
can't make I don't know enough about
those companies internally because
really like we have an our perception of
what they've done but also I also know
that when companies get really really
big they tend to do bad things because
they can't see what the what the right
hand is doing or the left hand is doing
and that's a problem that's a business
issue that we have in this country we
have these mega
corporations that we're then it the
consumer or the customer is no longer
the priority it's the shareholders and
that's a that's a huge epidemic that we
have in our system in general but what
I'm saying is like that chemical now is
banned all right and where you can't use
it in California and I don't where's the
data showing that why we can't use that
that's what I'm saying like why did that
get taken off the list is it because it
came from that company or is it because
it's actually damaging to us and it has
there been any long-term research on
that well that's the problem I have so I
I'm not saying that it's good or that I
don't know if it's good or bad and I
don't know if anybody knows it's good or
bad or if it has long-term effect on our
environment and I would like to see that
data and I would like the people that
are writing the regulations to have that
data to make assumptions because we
really need is as many tools in the tool
chest as we can when when you're growing
at an indoor controlled environmental
space because problems compound and go
crazy now that that's my little segment
on the whole thing it's just where's the
data where's the data you know where is
the information on it and where who in
the people that are making these
decisions what are those decisions based
on if they're based on public perception
that's a problem to me all right that
public perception might be accurate but
most of the time I mean Nietzsche has a
famous quote like madness is uncommon in
individuals but proliferate in crowds
and masses you know so I want to make
sure that we're not steering towards
madness with all of this all right
I want to make sure that we're steering
towards knowledge and so if there's
something that's taken off I mean they
could say you know there could be
something that people are using on an
organic level it could be banned for
some reason and then maybe that would
take that would change the perception
and people will be like wait a minute
who's making decisions where's the data
behind it that's all I want to know and
that's really the point of me wanting to
talk about this is we need to know why
we shouldn't use it you know we need to
understand that fair enough I mean you
make a good argument I don't think we're
that far off in terms of our perception
we're just slightly on other sides of
the center there yeah I just don't have
enough trust in
the research I would be given and I
don't feel that we know these long-term
effects well enough to really know
what's gonna happen two years from now
five years from now you know are these
things bio accumulating in our bodies we
don't know so that's my whole thing is I
I'm all for research I'm all for data I
just have to know that I can trust that
data over time it needs to be
independent he's becoming not from these
big companies and we just need to make
intelligent decisions and I do I do see
what you're saying about regulation it
is it is a problem it is perception is a
problem I would just suggest that people
look into biological controls as a
starting point for pesticides and things
that are have been used for generations
like neem oil for example that we know
to be generally safe compared to some of
these new you know newer pesticides on
the market I totally agree and and we're
we don't have a choice anymore I mean
that's the reality so it's this is where
the law is going with it so that
industry is going to blossom at this
point and we have to sub and that is
where you know the the biological
controls is where we have to go to now
and we have to explore that and we have
to work with guys like David who are
doing that research and and make it as
good as we can you know and be able to
do that in a controlled environment
space but I just you know I'd like to
see a lot more data that's all alright
fair enough
well Nelson I really appreciate you
coming on the show today definitely
gonna have to talk to you further I
really enjoyed our chat and I look
forward to maybe you meet David and
giant a few other people all sitting
down in the same room one day and just
chatting because I love it you but you
bring a lot to the table and I will be
sure to let everyone know down in
California about what you're doing with
your hybrid method and consulting and
everything like that thank you so much
dad thank you for the opportunity I
loved it
that was Nelson Linsley from poetry
plants you can follow him on instagram
at poetry of plants that's all one word
you were listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'm your
host Todd Hudson don't forget that
there's more information and articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
is organics calm and if you enjoy these
podcasts please take a moment to leave
me a review on iTunes and send me your
feedback and suggestions through our
website contact page thank you
[Music]