hi this is tad with kiss organics and
i'm here with my wife robin and my
daughter kaya and you know we started
kiss over a decade ago with the idea of
offering smaller amounts of amendments
and soils online
and i didn't know if you're gonna make
it and we've had a lot of ups and downs
but i'm grateful to say that we're here
today and um really appreciate all your
support over all the years
and you know throughout all of this some
of the things that have been really
important to us
are
to give back to the community and to
help the environment and so you know we
started rose which was a trail a
non-profit associated with teaching
children about native ecology in our
area we worked with envirostars and
we've donated in the past to hope link
and last year
we donated to the flint unity project so
this year we've been thinking a lot
about this and want to do something a
little bit different
so what we would like to do is to help
five families or individuals uh with you
know products and services
uh from kiss that we can help you either
grow your own medicine uh grow your own
food but really just in the spirit you
know of giving back to those in the
community who are in need right
so if you or anyone you know could
benefit from this please don't hesitate
to reach out i'll have a link on the
profile page as well as on
kisorganics.com
it's a very basic submission and all
entries will be anonymous and we hope to
help some families out in this upcoming
season thank you again for all your
support and we wish everyone a happy
holidays