so I got to say this surprised me but in
a good way this is our soil mix just on
our regular soil mix with a little bit
of added molasses to it and I found the
best fungal strand that I found on EMI
samples so far in this batch but in
general I'm seeing a lot of strands
starting so when I'm comparing this I'm
comparing this to compost which should
naturally be higher in microbial
activity then that's soil mix but we're
putting a lot of stuff in our soil a lot
of nutrient sources a lot of ingredients
as a way of hopefully increasing that
microbial activity in our nutrient
cycling so we just zoom in here
no they're gonna flagellate see a lot of
bacteria cruising around well there's
another fungal strand starting up and if
we zoom it a little bit further 400
times magnification there you can see
what's really going on and that's the
thing about these living microorganisms
is this is really what we're trying to
promote in our soils for increasing
nutrient cycling so this is what makes
all those amendments that we're adding
to the soil available to the plants and
you can see there's a lot of good
diversity in the different shapes or
sizes or morphology as it's called so
I'm really happy with the way this
sample looks and again this is just with
a little bit of molasses added