[Music]
okay we're going to go ahead and install
our carrots into our bed here uh as you
can see now I've got the quick
disconnect coming from the water supply
a brake there and a brake here and our
end of line valve um that brake by the
way is totally up to you as far as where
you want to put them so that uh whole
piece of tubing will come as one piece
and then as you lay it out you'll simply
just cut with a pair of scissors where
you want to put your valves and your
carrots and uh and so on so first thing
we're going to do is we're going to grab
a carrot that's been soaking in some
fresh water for about an hour a little
bit longer than needed but I like to go
a little bit long so that's an hour and
what I'm going to do now you have the
water level right up to the top as it's
upright I'm going to go ahead and screw
that on so it's thumb tight not crazy
EAS and then as you'll see it's got the
te you already need to go into your
supply line so plug that in
there make sure that's
clean the other
side and then we'll go ahead and shove
that in so you could just see the
top we'll grab other
carrot this one I've already put the C
on put it on
there make sure we're
clean and I like to run kind of Cy caddy
corner and opposite so then what we're
going to do is we're going
to dial this one down tighten it we'll
open this one
up and we're going to turn on our water
and there you go the other thing to
remember is keep that that last valve
closed you make sure you get your good
water coming out of there now this is a
pressurized hookup um you might not see
this sort of stream coming out of
gravity but that's
okay I'm going to tighten this down and
do the hanging drip which I will show
you closeup of in a little
bit later on
so once we're dialed
in we have our drip little B
more little bit
more there we go we'll do two quote
unquote clicks one two and then this one
we'll just leave for
there and then you have your little blue
mat caps and these are great because
they sit and snap
on and that way if anything gets bumped
you're good now the next step is going
to be to inst install your drip tape the
fitting you're going to be working with
is this 3 mm by drip tape adapter I'll
show you how to screw this on in
another video as well so this simply
just gets plugged
into
here and then you would route this
around whatever you're
planting and then if you've got a steak
lying
around which we will make sure you do
put one on the middle there and I like
to
throw one on the
end and that's kind of it we can do the
other
carrot this one go
here and then similarly just wrap kind
of equal and
opposite and that would be about
it so as you can kind of see you're
going to make sure that you've got your
edges covered and you've got a nice
middle line to have irrigation through
the middle of the bed but most of your
evapo transpiration is going to come
from The Edge which is why it's nice to
have those blue soak drip tapes making
sure that they're covered
there all right I want to show everybody
what I was talking about when we're
talking about dialing in your sensor or
your carrot cuz they kind of look like
carrots I'm at my desk there's no water
hooked up here but if you would imagine
unscrewing this to the point where you
can move this freely through there then
you'd have some water coming out there
pretty steadily so what we're going to
do when we're actually setting these up
is we'll hold this flat parallel to the
ground and we'll tighten this valve down
until we have what we like to call that
hanging drip which is a drip coming out
of here about once every 1 to 3 seconds
once you have that you can use any you
know marker on the side of this cap this
fin is a really great one and then
you're going to tighten down this valve
to what I like to call clicks and a
click is there's basically these
triangles that surround the top of the
valve so we would tighten
one and
two and that's a neutral setting so then
we would take those cool caps
and those big gaps go around the hose
and that way if it gets
knocked nothing's going to adjust it
you're not going to flood or you're not
going to cut off irrigation so that's
how to properly set for a neutral
setting your carrot now if you need to
make an
adjustment remember if you're going even
between half of these two triangles
these clicks that's a 25% adjustment
right there which is a lot so if you do
need to dial it up if it needs to be
wetter then you would back it off if it
needs to be drier you would tighten it
down a little bit more I would recommend
not going more than half a click for any
one adjustment because if you do that's
you could get into some trouble as far
as uh over or under irrigating also make
sure that you leave enough time I'd say
at least a few days to see how these
different adjustments you would make
would
work before you uh adjust
again all right I wanted to show you
guys how to hook up your end of line
flush valve um there's also a note here
that if you do get the pressure kit with
the pressure reducer then this collar is
the same on the pressure reducer as it
is on the on the valve so to do that all
you do is to take this collar all the
way off it
unscrews thread that through
there and then that gets fitted on top
of that so that's nice and snug and then
you just throw that back on tighten it
all the way
down and there you go now if you are
using this as your end of line valve
then nothing would go here but if you
needed to check your pressure or make
sure that you do have water flowing you
would just turn that going that way
water would flow through and then you'd
be able to check additionally if you
ever need to expand your system add
another container or two um all you
would need to do is do the same same
thing on this side I pull that off put
the other supply line on this end collar
it back on and then this valve would
just stay open and then you would let uh
you would irrigate any containers
Downstream from
here all right I'm going to show you
guys how to hook up any of your blue
soak drip tape fittings this one here is
a 3 mm to drip tape adapter and then
this one here is your end plug which is
basically just the other end to make
sure water doesn't just come flowing out
of there but we'll use this one uh to
get that started you want to make sure
that this ring is all the way buted up
against where it was so you can't see
any of those threads so like that uh the
drip tape will have this kind of thin on
here the trick here is to fold that down
and you need to then throw that in but
this direction needs to be pointed needs
to be folded in the same direction that
you're threading your cap on otherwise
you'll get a leak so don't be too scared
to really clamp this one down so I'll
hold this and then I'll actually twist
this one so that's pretty tight and then
you also want to give it a good check so
I'm pulling on that pretty good it's not
going anywhere other end of the drip
tape would be the same just with this
plug make sure you're all the way up
against that side throw it on there fold
that flap in the same direction you're
twisting tighten her down give it a pull
test and you're good to
go