[Music]
Tad Hy owner of Kiss Organics um I host
a Canabis cultivation science podcast I
got started because my parents owned a
plant nursery growing up and um then my
father when they sold that after 30
years they started comp te business I've
been around sort of plants and soil
biology pretty much my whole life I came
into it after coming back from Australia
with a master's degree I got back into
the business and uh kind of been going
from there and I think uh the most
exciting thing for me is the opportunity
to always learn more with a new crop
which is cannabis that's really exciting
and the idea that we might be able to
bridge the gap between the research
that's happening right now in Academia
and what's going going on in the field
in cultivation uh with Growers so that's
uh I think that's the biggest challenge
and also the most exciting thing is like
we can actually participate in actively
learning more about this crop and that's
there's very few crops left that we can
say that about so that's it for me thank
you who'd like to go
next Brandon I yeah I can go um I'm
Brandon Hudson I work for kiss Organics
I do the bulk of the soil analys is
um I love cannabis I I I've I've I've
been around this plant my whole life my
parents grew weed um I had a teepee when
I was four made out of stocks from a
harvest so I've been around it my whole
life um I was talking to Tad's dad
yesterday I've just never had any kind
of uncomfortability about it or anything
it was just something that was like salt
and pepper in my environment growing up
and so you know it was it was always the
constant reminders don't tell anybody
and um so I've been growing uh as an
adult on my own for 39 years now this is
my 39th year and um I I've done deep
water
culture rock wool slabs cocoa all the
salt stuff and you know coliseums all
that um I've done large scale facilities
in South Carolina with with hemp both
indoor and
outdoor um
I would say the biggest challenge for
Organics would um heavy metals you know
we when we look at numbers that small
parts per billion we look at the almost
infinite number of opportunities for
um some sort of contamination along the
way in the testing uh even after the
sample's been looked at so um
that I I feel like getting some
real uh
National guidelines for how that should
be done properly how the testing should
be done properly um the the water all
that kind of stuff I feel like that's
the biggest challenge for
us cool Andrew like that hat Brandon I
had to represent man I'm trying to cover
up the six head so I don't blind anybody
so
um so I started growing
maybe 14 years ago in Alaska um I moved
to Alaska and I had just been getting um
really good Blue Dream from Cali medical
scene and then when I went to Alaska um
not as much Imports up there and the
people that I knew did not know how to
grow so very quickly we realized if we
were going to get good stuff we were
gonna have to grow it
ourselves um first uh apartment someone
just brought over a bunch of plants I
threw a light into a closet I was doing
Pete Moss and compost teas and some B
guano teas and then um we got evicted
from that apartment for growing and so I
ended up realizing I had to rent a house
then we got into a house and started
um getting some cool genetics over from
Amsterdam and uh some of the stuff in
the
overseas like Attitude seed bank and um
you know then I started to realize how
important genetics were because the
first time I ever grew I think it was
choc Lou crossed with kosher kush um it
was just a part of anything I'd ever
smoked before and uh I knew I wasn't
that good at growing so it had to be
something else and then slowly but
surely just kind of Switched craft and
went more and more organic organic um
less bottled nutrients until uh I
actually learned how to grow in living
soil through Tad's podcast and then um
ended up meeting Tad and coming to work
for the business so it's been a it's
been a great ride and I think my biggest
um struggles over the years was learning
how to water in living soil um it's so
different when you switch from a sterile
media um I'd always had great success
with bottles and then my first grow um I
overwatered pretty bad in living
Organics and the the plants just looked
horrible good thank you and and Ben I've
seen them lately they don't look
horrible
anymore yeah uh my name's Ben um it's
kind of funny I I spent a lot of time
learning about stuff so I haven't
actually grown too much I actually
didn't even jump into this industry
until about
2018 and before that time I was
legitimately underwater I was scuba
diving and hanging out with my eels and
doing my research on Marine
ecology so uh long story short we moved
up into the Olympia area um my
brother-in-law at the time uh still does
but is expanded owns a tier 2
cultivation facility and I called him up
and I said hey I'm looking for a gig but
in the meantime would you like
scientific eye on any of this stuff and
he said well that doesn't exist
currently in the industry so sure so I
was like okay and then uh I took a year
essentially of just keeping my mouth
shut acting like a gardener learning the
plant learning the system um I was a bit
lucky with the fact that they do uh grow
in living soil um organic sustainable
kind of approach and that soil was Kiss
organic
that's how I kind of met Tad um it was
actually pretty funny I remember when
Nate and I were talking the owner of
gold leaf he was like yeah I'd love to
have you up here but you you know you
gotta kind of have an idea of what's
going on so if you could this while I
was still living and working in Santa
Cruz he said yeah take a listen to this
podcast uh it's by a friend of mine
named uh Tad hussy and so I at that time
I was still in Academia so I have a a
whole booklet of just all the notes from
all those first I don't know 30 40 50
episodes and I was just trying to study
and learn like I knew how and then yeah
um I started really kind of getting into
the growing in
2018 um my kind of soap box flash
feeling about cannabis is uh funny
enough I think it's going to be one of
the main crops that saves agriculture I
know that sounds kind of hyperbolic but
um we're lucky enough to have a crop
that's got so much margin that we can
really play with stuff um whether that's
irrigation lighting you know all these
other things a lot of other Industries
don't have that kind of margin
to really push and test the limits um so
I think when things start getting more
complicated as far as
growing kind of crops Outdoors that
we've normally done um I think people
are going to have to look at how to do
things indoors
and those who want to do things
sustainably and organically will have a
very logical place to look and that's
folks like us um the hardest thing about
growing cannabis this was something that
I wrestled with doing during my learning
my heavy learning phase which is um
especially coming out of a place that
was always looking for primary
literature um trying to find empirical
data and research about cultivation
practices is
it just doesn't exist it's starting to
now um sure like medicinal and you know
psycho effects like there's plenty of
research on that but actually how to
benefit the plant more and get you know
more holistic properties out of it um
there's very little on that so that was
frustrating but it was also very
exciting where we got of get to you know
Forge that road um and do it so it's
been fascinating it's been exciting very
rarely I feel very lucky to have landed
in an industry
that you know doesn't have a whole lot
of previous work on it so um it's it's
great it's super exciting and I'm feel
really lucky to have landed where where
I am thank you Ben um so we have another
question from Margaret um she asks what
cultivars do you prefer to grow and why
and how do you find determine then test
out cultivars um it's probably a good
one for Andrew and Brandon so um
Andrew would you like to
start um yeah or Brandon can go my my
answer might get pretty long here this
is kind of like my uh my jam to my
peanut butter all right okay sounds good
yeah I I can I can give my short answer
and then Andrew can elucidate on that
um I'm primarily growing
indoor so that is a huge Factor just
immediately right out the gate for what
cultivars I'm gonna grow you know you
have to look for something that is a
manageable struct structure and time
length based on your environment so you
know you always want to match the hatch
and so if you're gonna if you're in
Southern California and you want to grow
some Haze plants outside that makes
perfect sense to me you'll have a long
enough season you'll have the right
weather probably kind of what Ben was
alluding to earlier like we're going to
be indoor for growing eventually it just
the weather's getting just too
unpredictable um but so with me you know
I I'm trying to be able to provide
information and support for facilities
most of those facilities need an eight
or a nine week production plant so a lot
of my decisions are are made so that I
can support The Growers so I stick to
you know those eight nine week plants
for the most part um there's there's
some stuff like GMO there's some hazes
that um I love they just take too long
so that is a situation where it might be
worth it for me to grow one plant
outdoor pull tarps on it something like
that but for the most part I'm looking
for something that will finish on time
and something that has a short structure
but gives me the yields that I'm looking
for and then beyond that it's just a
matter of personal taste um some people
like the you know the real sedative
couch lock stuff that I don't really
enjoy that I I I don't I'm already
hungry and tired I don't need more of
that in my life so um I I like energetic
laughy uh communicative strains I like
strains that um I can do math on I like
strains that um
I hate to say it but it's really hard to
get high I just you know I I smoke too
much and so I've got a really high
tolerance and so I'm really looking
for Tarpin I I just it's a piece of
candy it's just like it's candy
throughout the day that I just love the
taste of it um I feel like I can smell
good cannabis and it just changes my
mood um just that just being in a room
with a bunch of good cannabis I was at a
harvest yesterday Tangi turps for days
you know as far as as far as you could
smell it was just Tangy turps and it was
great you know and I did you know I
didn't even feel like smoking I was just
in a great mood and um so yeah so for me
I'm trying to basically I'm I'm trying
to match my environment I want to find
something that fits the space I can get
an adequate yield um and we're always
looking for I love Justin McGill's dad's
like three-step joint process of like he
likes to take a dry to and get that just
that pure turpine then he said he likes
to light it but he'll just light it like
this he won't draw through it because he
say he likes to do the wave test like as
though he's at a concert he's like I
want I want to have that best smelling
weed in the concert and um so I I you
know I don't tend personally to pick for
medicinal value although I do use
cannabis for for pain P management I've
broken most of the bones in my body and
um it helps with migraines it helps with
all that stuff for me but I'm not
specifically chasing any one medicinal
canono profile or anything like
that can I just add something really
small to that
um one one other consideration to think
about is we know that there's certain
plants that now have genes that will
make them more resistant to powdery
mildew for example or when you go into a
commercial room you'll see some plants
that that won't Express H and vroid but
others will and so because of the
genetic variability in cannabis um
selecting plants that are better for
your environment like Brandon alluded at
can can go a long ways towards finishing
I mean here in Washington with all the
rains we get Outdoors is really
challenging so um that's just something
that I want to always keep in the back
of my mind when I'm picking what
genetics I'm gonna run yeah yeah and
just to Dove tail back into what tad
just said if I go into a
room and there's you know like I was in
a room yesterday with probably 12
different Cult of ours big big room
and let's say 11 of them are are doing
great and one of them's for whatever
reason you're seeing a trace element
issue or I think it's the white star dog
over at moo that always finishes with a
manganese very visible manganese issue
for me if I've got a plant that's I
mean it would have to be real roadkill
skunk you know it would have to be like
one of the Holy Grail cultivars that's
gone now for me to be willing
to deal with or baby a a cultivar that
was you know not responding well within
the average targets that we that we work
with so that's another consideration I
if I have outliers that just don't
perform well in my environment my mpk
whatever I'll I'll get rid of
them Andre do you want to jump
in um so I'm a little bit unique um most
people with
my kind of disposition towards cannabis
don't enjoy it um but I'm very very
sensitive to sedative effects kind of
like what Brandon was saying I I wake up
tired and hungry I don't need any help
in that in that
department um so for me I'm looking for
things that really invigorate
and uh seeming to help with
creativity um inspirational motivational
things
um uh things of that sort and then along
with some kind of overall feeling of
Wellness or like he said like Giggles or
you know if I can determine that then
that's usually what I'm looking for in a
cultivar but what I found is I the
modern-day genetics don't usually offer
that for me if something is going to
flower in 8 to nine
weeks um it almost
always uh leaves me dragging so um I
personally prefer combinations of land
race and what I would call legendary
varieties varieties that just have
outstanding flavor resin
production um varieties that have stayed
and stuck around uh through all the
different um hype kind of cycles that
that cannabis goes through for example
um chem 91 and Congo lease or the any
African really I love the different
African varieties um but the chem 91
cross with Congo they just go very well
together the African land race provides
a unique energetic almost heart racing
sensation while the chem adds a certain
potency and flavor um just mix really
well together and it levels out the chem
so the chem doesn't take you under if
you smoke too often but at the same
time
um the African can be too intense for
some people and they don't want to
feel that like hot heart racing
sensation um I have to admit I like the
Speedy paranoid side of weed so I'm just
tell on myself I like that so no me too
I don't like if if uh if I smoke I want
to like go for a walk or like like you
said go do some math or like maybe even
think about the next uh cross I want to
make or what genetics I think are going
to go good together but if my mind is
hindered or I just feel overall
lethargic um it's not fun for me and so
um another thing I love are hazes for
that very reason a haze is one of the
very few cultivars that already has
potency and almost a spiritual effect
mixed with some kind of psychedelic high
it's ve hazes are very different from
anything I've ever smoked um and then me
and Brandon have also found that when
Sour Diesel is mixed in with the true
Haze genetic um just the flower
structure increases the smells are way
better the flavor is off the s um it's
really hard
to come up with something that does
better than a sour diesel Haze um so
those are things like I would keep in my
garden forever and then I like to
experiment with other land race
varieties just to see what it is like
personally I've found Pakistani crossed
with
Honduras um crossed with Congo will give
you almost a psychedelic Haze effect but
it's much more like a soft Daydream and
then it can just totally blot Out hours
from your day so for me it's really cool
it's a really unique experience it
doesn't get heavy but I don't always
grow that because I don't want to lose
hours of my day um good one for like a
will do that amnesia amnesia hay will do
that to you like six hours later you're
like I know I did something but I don't
know what with
who yeah so it was pretty fun I'm sure
it was fun trying to to find the balance
between
um something like Amnesia Haze where
it's like your whole day is gone and
then something like um Honduras where
it's like two hours are gone and it's it
can be good and functional for a Sunday
when you don't have to get anything done
um but I'm not going to grow it time and
time again because it doesn't have the
same energetic productivity like um an
African mixed with a haze W um and then
when I'm hunting seeds like how do I
find determine test out a cultivar I'm a
huge fan of micro breeding so I always
run tiny pots first so if you're um
looking to really stess out a population
micro breeding is very useful or if
you're looking to let's say hunt 12
different cultivars and you have 12
seeds of each you can do all that at one
time in a 4x4 tent and then you can look
at these different variations and once
you put them against the whole
population a lot easier to see a
standout whereas if you're only growing
four plants in a bed and you have
800,000 seeds to work through it's going
to take the rest of your life and each
seed is like a lottery ticket so you
might not find anything worthwhile and
you might think you found something cool
when really that's not even what that
line has to offer um you just had a
really good grow so um of course a plant
is going to look great and and smell
great if your grow is on point um which
is why are you flowering all those out
like immediately and then revegging them
or are you like growing them enough to
clone them then and then because like if
you just flower it out don't leave
anything to Red you're going to lose
that right ideally um you would clone
before flower but okay if you're low on
space and all you have to work with is a
4x4 t0 you can rev you just have to do
what I call a quick flip if you take
them more than two or three weeks in
depending on the variety it's going to
be very hard to bring them back out but
if you have an eye for it and you can
determine a few characteristics that
you're looking for you can call out a
lot of the population in that first two
weeks just based on your runs uh things
that are like Brandon said showing a
random
deficiency um things that just don't
want to get going things that don't
stretch at all or things that too much
um you can really see a lot in the first
two weeks of flour and then when you
bring them back you can up pot let's say
you go from 200 down to 20 after those
first two weeks it's a lot more
manageable to clone the LA the resulting
20 plants and then continue testing
further on so you can at least pick out
your girls in a type of structure that
you want and then you can dig back in
and really look for that Stand Out Among
those 20 maybe let's say one gallon pots
or a bed um I saw really interesting
yesterday just on the r topic So
Justin's been running this grapefruit
strain for over a decade and they they
re they used to revet revet revet and
it's at a point now where it will only
throw on three leaves no matter how
mature the plant gets no matter how big
the mom gets and so they're actually
going back through tissue
culture
to I guess reverse that so that the
plant will grow properly and that's
that's how they're going to get around
it so I just thought that was really
interesting because I've always had
pretty good results luck with um reving
plants but in a perfect world I prefer
to take label all the moms take cuts off
of them I've got my cuts flower the moms
out then you know decide who I want to
keep and and I never
I i' I've kind of fallen in love with
this super silver haze Sour Diesel but I
try not to fall in love with any one
cultivar I you know I just threw that
whole pillowcase full of seeds out there
just to show like I've got a lot of
genetics like I've got millions of beans
and so I'm always popping something new
always hey Brandon can I ask a question
yeah yeah hey um why would you okay so
if you're you're you're popping your
seeds and you've got your mom's why
would you um flower out the mom and keep
a pet why wouldn't you keep the mom and
flower out of
cut you could do either way you could do
either way I a lot like in my when my
facility I had a 3,000 foot head house
that was always super short for space
and I had a 60 by 120 Greenhouse that
there was always you know I had roll so
I had most you know I had like was like
88% 92% of the floor was accounted for
but I still had big a on either end and
so I would just drag a mom over and and
flower her out that way I'd get a big
yield you know it's a nice big healthy
plant I don't have to worry about it
since it's not sitting in the best
environment like you don't want to Stack
a bunch of young sensitive plants in
front of the wet wall in South Carolina
like I I got you yeah yeah I've just
heard some people say you know some um
conflicting things about you should you
should you should always flower out the
mom and and keep a cut and I've always
been accustomed to keeping the mom the
actual um know the seed stock the mom
and um flowering cuts off of that so
that's a question the mom is seed stock
she's going to have the F1 Vigor which
typically means she's you know GNA stick
around but I don't keep my mom's
for probably three months I six months
is the max but I think three months is
probably better just to
keep propagation numbers up and that
kind of stuff you're not car load or
something along with it so I just think
that that that works a little bit better
for me which you could do either and
then like I don't know at the uh this
was months ago but I had a thing on
Instagram and I don't know if we did it
on here or not but I was showing where I
took a bunch of cuts and immediately
threw them into 1212 so I was rooting
under 1212 but I also got to
see you know I sexed all my my
Greenhouse run that way so there's just
there's you know there's so many ways to
get there with this plant you know it's
just gotta yeah cuz the mom is first
generation the first cut that comes off
the second generation right well it it
depends some people you know I got a
buddy in Detroit who at this point has
had this lights plant for like 37 years
he's had the same
mom wow horrible idea to veg a plant for
37 years like yeah
I mean good on him like that's
incredible that he's been able to keep
that PL alive but I just I don't think
that's smart but I think must be he's
romantically in love with this
plant must be like Oak at this point
yeah well oh oh this it's like this big
around yeah and it's probably you
probably couldn't drive a nail through
it oh no no I mean the number of times
he's had to chop it off it's like eight
feet tall but I mean it just it look
like like a it's like a stump and then
like a porcupine it's crazy that's crazy
this sounds like an urban myth man like
one of those stories you hear no I oh
yeah no I I'll have to I'll reach out to
him and get some pictures because that
be cool that would be
awesome this guy he uh I met him at a uh
Bob Weir Show in Detroit in like
and um right after I had been attacked
by a giant Pink dragon that came out of
the
sunset yeah yeah so he he uh he saved me
that night I had I got a really crazy
story I don't think I should record but
I I'll bring it
up on Hangout story go ahead then then I
want to add something but go ahead yeah
I'll was just going to throw in there I
don't know again like I don't know if um
if there's too much interest in like the
facility side of things as opposed to
just like your own personal like grow
and exploration but uh a little context
from the facility side of things um I
guess the commercial is we're always
seed testing we're always pheno hunting
because if you stop moving in this
industry you're you're behind
yesterday so um if you do have some
space it's really fun to do um obviously
as long as you're not going to be you
know putting any stress or strain or
pollen on the stuff you don't want it on
but um as far as like figuring out like
you know for us too then from a facility
standpoint like we need to try to do
this as quick as possible um and just
getting to that flowering stage to
figure out if it's a male or female can
take a long time and use up a bunch of
resources that theoretically 50% of
those plants will end up dying anyway so
we do sell these Leaf Works kits these
gender kits um in fact I'll throw them
into the chat right now link to the
website if you're curious um so that way
you basically just take a little
leaf smoosh Leaf in there and then send
it and mail it in and uh they'll get
back to you and went and let you know if
you got a male or a female well before
you need to take that thing all the way
to flower to figure it out on your own
um so it helps that process a lot faster
early on and that way you don't have to
have as much space in your veg or your
pheno hun space right because you can
weed those out no pun intended um a lot
quicker had 100% with them yeah only
I've used them the only thing I've ever
had happen is I did have one plant Herm
that I said but that's not the Test's
fault that the test read correctly so
yeah since we're talking about moms I
know there was another question about
moms in general in terms of how to best
keep them and what size container and
some of that I thought that might be a
good transition um and and like you guys
touched on the Woody stems is a big
thing over time these plants every time
you take a cut you know you're gonna end
up with more offshoots and it just
becomes a a nightmare over time of a of
a plant um plus I think the the health
of the plant and the viability of the
plant goes down uh over time with just
continual wounding and pruning um when
we talk about a long time but uh in
terms of how people are storing these
plants most of the facilities we work
with are organic so um most of them are
in a range of containers ranging from
I've seen them as small seven gallon
typically 20 or 30 gallon pots uh
Collective elevation if you go check out
that tour on YouTube they did it they
did two plants in a 4 by8 bed with a
trellis and it looks awesome um I I
don't know if the workflow on that is
better but but I have to say it's one of
the coolest looking mom rooms I've ever
seen um so you should definitely check
that out but the The Challenge on the
fertility side with moms is what I
wanted to touch on before you guys jump
in and that's that's really interesting
because you know a lot of us with the
with the soil beds you know the way that
we like to grow a kiss with with beds
and reimen the soil with soil testing
every cycle that's really challenging
with moms especially if you keep moms
for more than a cycle or two because
it's uh one there's not going to be a
lot of soil left in that pot it's be
mostly root mass and two managing to
fortil in that pond with top dressing is
really challenging um in terms of
keeping that Mom healthy and and healthy
moms is the most important thing for
your facility uh having success and even
for hom Growers and having Success
Through flour is starting with like a
really healthy clone if I don't have a
healthy Mom I'm not going to start my
next cycle uh it's that important
um that's where little things like uh
fish
hydracy um a bottle nutrient program
with light doses com in really handy or
um even something like Jacks like a
conventional salt based fertilizer in
small doses uh those things are all just
really effective ways to keep your mom's
healthy I would much rather you know for
example run jacks or use a bottle of
Nutri UT line to make sure I'm keeping
my fertility up in that 30-gon pot my
mom looks healthy then madly trying to
top dress as I see deficiencies knowing
that they're not going to get into the
plant for another seven to 10 days and
now my plant's stressed and I'm gonna
have to take cuting off of it so it
becomes a
real hassle and it's to me it's not
worth it um so unless because every
genetics are gonna they're all going to
be a little bit different so I can't
just say here's a top D kiss kit for
your mom's um and it's going to work for
all your moms because of the wide
variety of genetics that we have so um
that's a that's that was a good question
that was asked in our in our Q&amp;A list
and that's sort of how I would address
it um do someone else want to add
anything or com on that yes can can I
add something oops sorry okay go on you
can go hey you you you guys should check
out a Grassroots superfood Veg it's it's
fish hydraulis State it's a powder it's
a fish hydraulis State base it's got
camag bunch of other nutrients in there
and that is exactly what I use to feed
my mom's I've got them in um 15 gallon
uh fabric um Grassroots pots and uh
they're
probably uh they got to be about three
foot by three foot by four foot tall and
uh I have zero issues I feed them once a
week um with their with their superfood
and then I hit them once uh once a week
with um what is it Pacific uh Grove fish
hydraulis State and uh yeah Z gr
nutrient
deficiencies
and I mean faster growth than I've seen
in um in h and faster growth than seeing
in a soil situation with um bottled
nutrients just my
input no how long are you running player
what's that how long are you keeping
those moms alive so and I kind of wanted
to try him in a couple minutes ago too
because generally what I do is when I
find a pheno that I like um it is my fir
my my F1 my first generation mom I
probably keep it around for like six or
seven months and then I take a cutting
off of it and I Mark the Tad Second
Generation and then I'm able to keep
that around for last like SE some of
them upwards of a year um but I kind of
see around like eight nine 11 12 months
they kind of start to get finicky and I
think that's that whole fertility thing
um that you're talking about not to
mention trying to up poot from a 15 or
20-gallon pot into like a 30 40 it's
just it's not feasible yeah for me when
I when Dwayne put the question forward
because I work at kiss and because I use
kiss soil I know and because I regularly
rotate my mom at least every three
months I know that I can keep a a nice
vigorous healthy plant that was vegged
in a one gallon I can throw that into a
10 or a 12 gallon smart pot and and I
can run that and kiss biochar water only
CGM for 3 months and I'm not going to
see any deficiencies that plan will be
fine uh as far as the nutrient side of
things calcium and phosphorus are the
two that I try to make sure on point for
my moms just as far as having the best
propagation results you know so those
those are the two elements that show up
as being an issue if somebody is just
you know if you're if you're not if your
clones are not rooting first thing you
want to do is get a scope out and look
at your moms and make sure you don't
have russets or something horrible like
that going on um that that's definitely
you know something that can happen
you'll see propagation numbers drop off
with russets but you'll also see it drop
off with calcium you'll see it drop off
with
phosphorus um and then when the the
environment of the of the propagation is
not ideal you've got super low uh
relative humidity or something like that
but for me because I'm doing regular
rotating my mom's I I like a 10 or 12
gallon smart pot I
like like at least
450 for my ppfd I'll go as high as 600
um for my moms I feel like that's that's
adequate and um you know it just I just
try to make sure I have enough to cover
my needs I try to make sure I've got
cuts that I don't need need sitting
around um and I try to make sure I've
got Cuts before I need them I I would
always rather have a plant that's a
little bit bigger that I can trim back
yeah that nice big root mass because
when you've got a small shoots and a
giant root mass and you throw it into a
bed it goes crazy um I just did the
opposite big shoots almost no roots and
you know lost power for two days so it
got cold and so everything's just moving
a little slowly this
time but as far far as you know metrics
that's that's you know what I'm shooting
for for a
mom yeah for for us at the facility it's
um we really don't like to let them go
more than really three months maybe
four the big imp reason for that is um
obviously we've got a whole area ready
to go for clone so why not use it for
just moms as
well um and the thing to think about too
guys is plants are a lot like us in some
respects like the hormones change over
the years guys it sucks but it happens
um when they're young and ready to grow
they're going to be moving stuff all
over their body so taking cuting from
anywhere is going to give you a really
good shot at getting some really
vigorously ready to go babies um once
those moms get Woody and older it takes
it's a lot harder it's Fighting Gravity
more um those things get woodier it's
hard those and just the the the the
hormones change right the plant changes
all that stuff changes so it's a lot
harder to clone off of an older plant
even if it's the healthiest prettiest
happiest looking thing in the world just
because the starting materials that you
want in a clone aren't going to be there
in abundance as you know using from a
younger mom so um it that it helps to
keep them young for sure as far as your
success
rate yeah and I think it's it's also
good to um take into consideration that
we we are growing in
annual so even in the best of conditions
let's say Southern California you start
your seeds in February they're flowering
in August so that's six months and even
by then I I think that's a bit of a long
you know most people are looking at May
to August which is three months um and
that plant's just ready to flower like
it doesn't want to keep growing it wants
to flower um so I've found that
I take biocharge soil and I'll either
add a couple cups of Bloom booster or
I'll just specifically add fishbone and
gypsum and then um I keep my mom's in
one gallons it's definitely the bigger
the pot the longer you can keep it happy
but in one gallons every two months um I
take the most atypical branch and I take
it down about 8 in and then I use that
to reset um I found that they don't
skape a beat as long as you use
enough plant material and it has
dominance because there's going to be a
higher concentration of oxin and you're
kind of taking this the brain center of
the plant at that point um and then when
that goes into the soil and that Roots
the amount of growth you're going to see
come off of that clone after it's rooted
is way more growth than you would see
from trying to keep a mom for six seven
months but it is more work to
continually reset and if your watering
not on point those one gallon pots can
can really kill you so I would say beds
are the best but who's got beds
available for each mom you know what I'm
saying now you made me feel better I'm
in like two gallon pots resetting like
every two to three months basically just
trying to get two runs out of them so
I'm glad I'm not the only one I I i'
I've done it with Jack and Solo cups you
know like I was just doing
hydroponically you know so I mean Hing
on how you feed it there's really no
limit um we had a question on IG um from
ecothrift um saying I'm noticing a
turned away from the standard 18inch
Grassroots make uh towards shallow 12 in
and 10 in and I've also seen few
facilities used taller 24in Beds which
seems excessive so the question he's
asking is um when planning to use beds
what consideration should be taken into
account for the bed
depth 10 to 12 inches it's just for me
the analogy I always use is if you've
got a a tall beer glass and then a short
wide Scotch glass and you have them full
of sand and you pour water into them and
come back in a half an hour that tall
beer St it's going to be pretty wet at
the bottom and pretty dry the other 2/3
that Scotch glass because it's short and
wide is going to be much more uniform in
the moisture and so it just makes your
moisture management that much easier
we're also dealing with really rich
organic soil which holds a lot of water
and has a lot of weight to it um adding
another 12 Ines another 6 in adds you
know a lot of weight and a lot of water
weight and so um yeah for me I like a
shallower bed I was gonna chime in we
haven't uh we haven't determined what
the minimum depth is for growing in beds
and constantly testing and recycling the
soil so but what we have found is
facilities like gold leaf where Ben
works as well as a research scientist um
10 inches has been sufficient and we
there's multiple places we work with
that have gone with 10 in and that's
just a nice one because if you have a
12in bed you have a nice little twoin
lip um to keep things from spilling out
and uh I I don't see any advantage
really to going a lot deeper than
that you know we we haven't done a side
by side uh here here at my place I'm a
little bit deeper than that but only
because I had an excessive amount of
soil and I just wanted to fill the bed
up more because the beds were so deep
from Grassroots but I don't think I
needed that much
soil yeah does anyone want to add
anything to that just you can oh go
ahead BR say if you want to buy more
soil from Kiss we're happy to do
that but a lot of I end up talking
people they're like okay well I've got
18 or 24 inches and we end up talking
them out of buying a bunch of soil just
because it's going to make their life a
lot easier as the grower you
know oh also I'll mention the math works
out really well so a 4x4 works out
perfectly for a half a yard of soil
so yeah like Brandon said we've had
people call up and say I need 100 yards
of soil and then we redo the map and
we're like you only need 60 you know and
that's yeah thousands of dollars in
Savings in freid and and and cost on
soil um on that note that's also why I
personally prefer the shorter blue matte
carrots because I know that was a
question someone was asking me about too
I don't like the really deep carrots
because I want to know my soil moisture
uh closer to the surface for the most
part um unless I have a really really
deep bed but even then I haven't seen
any data to support needing a deeper
carrot um so I almost exclusively use
the short carrots with cannabis if we're
talking about like a fruit tree or
something then that's a different
conversation but soil is going to dry
out from the top first I want to keep
that point moist so um that's sort of
where I want to be sensing soil tension
um Ben do you want to touch on that at
all yeah for sure
um the thing too to think about again
from a facility and production
standpoint is depending on the size of
bed you're growing in you're going to
likely be bringing in six to nine maybe
12 gallons of soil every transplant
round because you're going to be adding
those one gallons if that's what you're
growing in so if you do start your beds
with less than the lip then you're going
to actually get quite a few rounds
before you have to deal with taking soil
out of the bed because you've you know
continually added more um as you go
through the rounds same thing for soil
moisture um you guys can think of water
as kind of like a a pyramid so when it
drops onto the surface it kind of does
this kind of thing so um at some point
if you have too much you know volume in
your beds because of how you know the
the cycle of the plants in you know 70
some odd days um you're just not going
to be accessing that bottom Horizon of
your soil it's just going to sit there
maybe go anerobic if you're not careful
so it it you know you're you're
basically making things easier on
yourself um for a few different reasons
by not just going like yeah I'm G to
have an 18inch 16inch bed um we at Gold
Leaf the the max will do is 12 inches
and that's after probably a half a dozen
maybe eight or so rounds of just adding
nine gallons every ch transplant to each
bed and then eventually we'll take it
out what we do with that we'll actually
let it rest we'll put it back in a a
tote and take it outside and let it sit
for a year and then after that we'll
actually reuse it and turn that back
into
a you know veg mix that we'll reuse to
shuffle in with some new stuff and um
just kind of keep it sustainable as
possible were you doing the bottomless
plots or planting directly in your beds
it's a really good question Tad and I
talked about this a couple hours ago we
just go straight into beds um it's a
trial that we're going to try to get
going on here pretty soon um I know that
uh Green Life Productions does great
with that um methodology of just
plopping those things right on the bed
um my questions that we want to
investigate are one like how much uh
height do you lose if any you know
you're sitting on top of a bed now um
and secondly I really want to get at and
I haven't figured out how we're going to
do this yet but I would really love to
figure out the lag time
between you know when you put that pot
on top of your soil surface versus
getting that rizosphere already down
into a network of roots and microing and
all sorts of stuff that were there from
the previous round and how fast can
those handshakes happen and does that
show up in your results
um whether that's yield or quality you
know cannaboid all that kind of fun
stuff but that's my kind
of that's my thinking as far as the
reason why I'm not out here just you
know slinging them because I I really
don't know yet if you're the time it
takes for those roots to be like oh yeah
this looks cool and get down into there
versus just them already showing up
there yeah I mean anecdotally I would
say from my experience there's a little
bit of a difference but also I kind of
like the idea of removing the root mass
every time too because I'm scared of
hlvd and stuff that's right yeah and we
do that when we go straight into the
store we'll pull the main root ball up
we'll shake off most of that dirt though
because that's the gold that's that you
know handshake between micro risal and
all those inoculant that we want to try
to keep in there and then recharge them
with some amendments and plants are in
the next day Justin has large beds moo
Farms he does not
uh so he always he ends up with an
excess amount of soil as well so he's
probably at this point got 20 or 30
yards of soil that he's moved out of the
facility and
he's he's afraid of bringing that back
in because if he did have like let's say
you had some rude AIDS or something like
that um you're potentially bringing it
back into your vegro so that's one risk
or if you know it's going outside you
could be bringing in rips or you know
other exterior pest potentially back
into your room so he made a decision to
always use fresh soil to start his veg
because um you know your veg is has to
be your your mother's and then your veg
has to be the cleanest place in your
facility Gold Leaf less stressed about
it they move it out for a year tow it up
it stays in the back in but um that is
something to consider in your decision
making on reusing soil once it's you
know once your bed gets too full so I
just wanted to touch on that sorry go
ahead Louisa's got a potato farm next
door and
potatoes rud Aid they go hand inand like
peanut butter and jelly and so after
getting bit by root aphids in the
previous grows he's decided not to risk
it we could finish up about watering um
we had a lot of questions about blue
mats a lot of which you've already
answered but do have a question from
Nathaniel um his question is about
watching after transplanting um he asks
um about how to water before and when to
do water after he fills his plants often
stall at transplant um and also he asked
when to add blue mats R transplanting
should you wait for roots to get to the
bottom or should you add blue mats right
away and always keep so saturated I can
start with that if you like all very
very good questions um and it's going to
be maybe a little bit of a frustrating
answer because so much of it depends on
your environment and your grow room
whatever you're doing it in because it
really is a matter of how much those
plants are transpiring and how fast
they're going through whatever water
you're giving them um at the
facility our flower rooms will get hit
they'll um the previous day they will
get hit with a good a a good flesh not a
crazy flesh but we will try to move some
of those sodium that built up sodium I
mean we're you know for what it's worth
again at Gold Leaf I think we're coming
up geez Tad what is it I think nine
years of reusing the same soil um we're
getting there so sodium can show up
every now and then because we've been
using the same medium over and over
again so we will do a flush in which
case those beds are Ultra wet we don't
really have that um impact too much
though they'll still go in the next day
um they get hit with a compost te right
after transplant regardless so those
beds are very very wet um and based on
our environmentals the size of the rooms
air flow all that stuff it's actually
not until 10 more days until that soil
is back within range to where we want to
put those blue mats back in and that's
been all figured out just by um trial
and error of you know using the moisture
meters and you know testing a bunch of
beds
and figuring out the Sweet Spot of that
80 to 100 maybe 140 M Bar and that's
when that kind of levels out and then
the blue mats go in
um when to put blue mats in again that's
going to depend heavily on how much
water you're adding pre during post
transplant and then you're really just
going to want to keep an eye on the
moisture levels in the you know whether
you want to spot check like randomly so
go to a container or a bed and just say
literally throw a dart and be like I
want to know what it is here and then I
want to know what it is here um and then
another really
valuable method to doing to keeping an
eyon moisture level is you know get like
a plastic uh Chopstick and put a little
piece of flagging tape on it and just
stick it in the bed or in a container
somewhere at the exact same spot and
then that's your senting spot so every
time you want to take a mo you know soil
moisture reading if you got a meter you
go right topstick put it in the exact
same spot so that way you have a
consistently consistent spot to get a
sense of how fast water might be moving
through um so there's there's there's
pros and cons to both of those different
methods as far as figuring out exactly
what your soil moisture is and when to
install blue mats um that's that's
pretty much it and in that process
you're going to learn a lot about your
room just by experimenting and figuring
out when do I put that one question
you're going to be like holy smokes like
I watered these beds to 20m Bar give you
know for
example and then I'm on day seven and
we're you know at
50 right and that really is the kind of
like holy smokes this they don't need
that much water or oh my God you know my
room's super hot I'm on day four and I'm
at 160 like whoop oops so that's that
kind of experimentation um that you know
just the question of when do I put blue
mats in and really be a very powerful
learning experience for how your plants
interact with their
environment and I did just want to add
real sometimes people U miss a step on
transplanting
because their plants are slightly
overwatered or very saturated before
they go into the beds so I always let my
V plants dry down before transplanting
into the bed um that way they're like
hungry for the water and any soil
without root mass is probably going to
hold or retain extra water so having
those plants be really hungry for water
drives the roots down further into the
bed faster and you're going to have a
less likely time of overwatering like
Ben said even if it's really wet
bed the plants will have a time to
bounce back back as long as you don't
continue watering if you're watering
every day and the soil's
wet those plants could have serious side
effects if not slow down growth
altogether yeah good point Andre oh I'll
go real fast Brandon but basically I
just want to say some best practices
with transplanting um make sure to
transplant the optimal time for that
plant which means the roots are just
reaching the edge of the pot they're not
starting to wrap around or girdle I see
photos all the time on social media
where people like look at my healthy
roots and it's really just root girdling
because the roots have already started
circling around and if that is the case
because it happens um you need to really
be aggressive and actually cut and break
up those roots otherwise the plant will
continue to struggle because where
growth happens is or where nutrient
exchange happens is at the root tip so
if that root tip is circling back into
the plant it's not able to access all
the soil and from coming from Nursery
background you know when you buy a
nursery plant a lot a lot of them are
already girdled and so if you just take
that plant it's called a rose or an
arbid or whatever and just plant it
right in the ground like that you can
come back six months later and that root
ball will look exactly the same because
the roots aren't able to work out into
the soil um we don't have that same
issue in cannabis indoors because we're
using all the same media but if you do
plant outdoors same sort of thing make
sure to mix in some of
your native soil with maybe some 50/50
with compost and create a transition
into your native soil if that's what
you're going into rather than into your
beds um also like Andrew mentioned the
other thing that's really important is
making sure that your plant is not too
wet going in because you want to water a
transplant that's just really important
so that means your plants have to be
ready to accept water I mean they don't
need to be super dry but they should be
ready for a watering event at the time
of transplant so plan that and then
after you water them in Thoroughly you
are waiting longer because just right
after transplant your plants aren't
going to it's going to take a while for
those roots to really start growing that
plant to take off so that's going to be
probably the biggest Gap that you have
in as a from a watering perspective for
the entire cycle of the plant um short
of when you first plant your rooted
clone the same sort of same sort of
principles so Brandon go ahead I just
wanted to get that stuff in there oh no
just the you covered it but in the same
way that we're trying to coax you know
roots to come out of a plug we want to
do the same thing when we're planting
and so I I think Andrew and Tad covered
that the thing too guys if you are going
to be transplanting from one container
pulling it out of that examine the roots
look at it and also um keep an eye on
that the soil moisture of that that pot
or that container that you're going to
be going in right because if you that's
dry enough and you water your bed it
might not be getting anything right that
soil that in the the the first container
might be hydrophobic to the point where
everything else and you're planted and
everything right so it looks good but
that Cube might just have shed water
already and you wouldn't know it
so you want to make sure that you're at
the appropriate moisture level in your
veg pots before you go into your beds
otherwise you're going to think you're
doing fine and that might be another
reason for slowdown too if if people are
you know thinking that well I want my
plants to be thirsty and they dry them
out a little too much and then you're W
you're watering but that stuff's not
even really registering to the
plant so Brandon posted this in the chat
and because I know people aren't going
to be able to see the chat uh when they
watch if they come back and watch the
recording I just want to get that into
the into the recording which is that uh
if you want to do a light compost tea
area compost tea or a light fish
hydraulic application for that watering
event that you do at transplant that can
also help too just give them a little
bit of available nutrition as they're
switching over into the new transplanted
soil I think that's a great idea yeah
that was just a challenge for me when I
started with Organics because I wasn't
used being you know having salt
experience I was like what what's this
stall out what's this one week two week
stall out I don't have time for this
that the air rated compost tea and fish
Hydro just gets me right through
that um Ben there's a question for you
in the chat um what is your facility's
protocol for bringing in soil uh
bringing in soil back in from outside do
you do any IPM are you re amending that
soil before you store it outside uh so
those Amendments have time to break down
are you watering in any microbes to
facilitate the breakdown yeah it's a
really good question um we do a couple
of things first is when we put it
outside we do tie the tote up so it's
not just got all sorts of nonsense
falling into it um we let it a solid
Year and that thing will freeze and then
get really hot and that whole cycle
happens when we do come bring it back in
uh we do make our own lactobacillus so
we'll put some of that through there and
then um it will get recharged with some
amendments um and then the other thing
that's helping us is it's not like it's
going from a a rested state to an empty
bed it's also going to be going back in
with the native soil that's still being
used in the facility so there's going to
be a lot of already happy microbes and
good things that's already there you
know to compete any with anything that
might be bad that's coming in but that's
the other thing to think about with
Organics is you know a lot of these big
bad microbes that we talk about they all
have competition in our system so yeah
they they're probably in there but
they're at such a low population number
relative to the other things just
because they're all competing for the
same resources um we don't really ever
see any flare ups of anything too gnarly
but um yeah super good question so we do
do a lab uh we recharge with microbes
the compost teas that we add so we try
to bring out those the populations of
the really good stuff and you're I mean
I think it's a Fool's errand to try to
make sure that you're not going to have
any bad guys in there because we're
talking
about you know trying to do this
organically um but you know as long as
you're giving helpful Warriors enough
food rest and whatever um they should be
able to outcompete anything um that's
you know going to G to end up biting you
in the
butt I think regular applications of
either trichoderma or lab or rotating
them is something every facility like
you could get away with not doing it at
home because if you lose a 4x4 it's not
the end of the world but a
facility there's it would be part of my
protocol that I was doing one of those
every week just it's it's going to out
compete and there's some you know like
one of the things that uh lactobacillus
one of its exit dates one of the things
that poops out is oxay oxas helps Drive
tpping uh and triome production so
winwin but definitely do be doing
something to keep your soil microbes the
good guys able to out compete the bad
guys we've all got everybody in this
chat's got fusarium and betrus on their
face
right now you cannot exclude it just out
compete it we have a question from Keith
um how do you use the pce test to help
you create a soil prescription how does
knowing what is in the soil solution
help you know what to put in the
soil this one's from you for you Brandon
um so I'm looking at the pace test I'm
I'm using both I I use the mic 3 the
soil report as kind of my my savings
account and then the paste reports
what's available now that's what's in
your pocket or in your wallet purse
whatever and
um the paste I I'm mostly looking for
Bad actors
chlorides um I'm looking at
um sulfur on the paste as opposed to I
don't look at sulfur on the mik 3 I just
want to see what's available uh sulfur
something that like phosphorus I'm also
looking at the available
phosphorus um they're they both can sit
in the s for a long time before they're
liberated so I really want to see what
that available level for both of those
are uh I really want to see that
available phosphorus so I can compare it
back to the reserve to see how
efficiently you're cycling if you've got
a really nice Reserve but you've got
really poor cycling and or or low
available phosphorus
then we're going to look into why it's
not you know is the temperature is there
just not enough biology is it not the
right biology um you know microbial Mass
Mammoth p tribus uh I think somebody did
ask about different uh phosphorous
solubilizing bacteria and those are
three good ones uh I've seen really good
stuff already from the microbial Mass
the folks that are using it uh microbial
mass is also supposed to liberate
calcium so another win-win um but I I
want to see those numbers um I want to
see if you you know like I saw a bunch
of tests today with really poor Reserve
but better than normal um available that
tells me that the grower is feeding some
sort of their phing with phosphoric acid
they're feeding with fish hydrate but
they're doing some sort of suppl Al
feeding and so that just tells me
something about the grow so I can kind
of understand what that grower is doing
a little bit because I personally am
trying to set my grow up for a onetime
pre-plant uh Amendment application and
that's it then you know I'll do my
little potassium thing at the end of
week three but you know that that's how
I'd like to do my fer fertilizer routine
so I don't have to worry about it I can
just kind of forget about about it um I
also you know and
then the the real money on the the pace
report is the cat ions and um one I'm
looking for the the actual balance of
what your plant is seeing I'm looking
for the you know to try to hit my target
metrics but to make sure you're in
Balance um it's going to give me some
information if you're seeing something
weird on your plant that's where I'm
going to look at it and I do look at the
the mik 3 for the Caton numbers but I
you
know we can go back to book club and you
know doing doing Steve Solomon's
approach which is you know I would agree
that that's the right approach for
outdoor
grow um we're going to balance off of
that we're going to look at sulfur
phosphorus everything on that but with a
potting substrate where
the total exchange capacity is just not
accurate we we can't balance that way
and so we need to see what's available
to the plant and the pace report gives
us uh a way to do that and a way to make
sure that there's sufficient nutrient
and balance so um we had a couple of
questions about phosphorus cycling uh I
think you've covered some of it Brandon
um and we have talked about it in the
book club the recordings are all
available B in patreon um Pete asks um
what are phosphorus sources and bacteria
that cycle
phosphorus um and Greg also um he's
noticed through rounds of amending that
his beds uh in his beds that phosphorus
never seems to cycle at a rate we'd want
to see it at um and he ask if there's an
any option to do something like verac
composting with bone meal to really
Target casting
that would be high in phosphorus while
trying to minimize heavy metal
inputs jump in that and then I think Tad
was just talking to Bryant about some of
that um the as far as the the specific
biology I think we already touched on
that uh stuff like uh microbial Mass
Mammoth P those are bi that's bacteria
that specifically targets phosphorus
solub uh solubilizing
um so that would be what I would use for
that phosphorus
sources um you know we talked about this
in book club but you know in the pursuit
of you know and it was my challenge
thing is heavy metals so in the pursuit
of managing heavy metals we've really
reduced our Rock inputs our soft rock
phosphate it's still a really good input
I don't like to do guos just because
it's not sustainable um there's a bunch
of environmental impacts and potential
um
uh bacterial um infections that can be
passed along that way I just it's just
not it's not the path forward um uh
fishbone or
Bine um those are those are really good
sources um they're going to bring in
nitrates as well um so you just need to
make sure that you're balancing you know
that you're managing your nitrates so
that you're low enough at the end of the
round that you can use bone meal or
fishbone meal to bring in phosphorus
that way you don't have to lean on
softrock my favorites cow fos just based
off the California registry it has the
best heavy metal numbers so that's the
one I would use there and then as far as
compost and vermac
compost um that does seem to be a you
know obviously that's going to be very
labor intensive and would depend on if
you
know you know Greg is somebody that's
you know obviously capable and would be
willing to to do the labor to do
something like that uh you know homow
you just might not have the space to do
that um you know and so it might just be
better to really super load up your
reserves you know go way over your
Target and then just do weekly
applications of microbial mass or
Mammoth P um but uh I have read stuff uh
I've not personally done it but um
we talked about that book club as well I
think uh last week or the the one before
where uh Steve was suggesting putting uh
phosphorous sources into compost or
vermac compost so that it would be you
know we're talking about particle size
and the more something's broken down the
more readily available it will be and
that sort of stuff and so it would um it
would follow that adding phosphorous
source to compost would make it more
available
and so that would be a a good longterm
project uh it wouldn't be a quick fix a
quick fix would be something like uh uh
Pacific grow seos just a liquid low
nitrogen um cheat and uh pH and with
phosphoric acid is a great way to have
available uh P so I think I answered all
that um yeah that's great thank you um
so we're trying to wrap up does anyone
have any final questions
I do did we get even close questions
yeah we're about we've covered about
maybe 50 60% of questions um that came
up so I mean we by all means we can do
this again or we can try and cover some
of the questions either on IG or on on
patreon um I mean we have a lot of Food
For Thoughts so one one note to add just
because um well two notes so the first
thing on the Foster thing um from a
plant perspective if if your plant needs
available
phosphorus phosphoric acid is the best
option even though it's not organic just
in terms of the plant the plant doesn't
care if your nitrate comes from calcium
nitrate not organic or um you know fish
meal for example um so like I just want
to mention that so when people are
thinking about options now fish
hydrolysate is stabilized with
phosphoric acid that's sort of the cheat
on the in terms of the national organic
program of what they allow because it it
stabilizes the the fish
so that some people are GNA be like nope
I'm not going to touch that because it's
not truly organic and I totally respect
that I think that's fine um but for
people that are less concerned about
that sort of organic you know synthetic
conventional argument um phosphoric acid
is the is the easiest way to get your P
levels up
and Banos is too is another one but
there's a lot of reasons not to use
those but I see when people add Banos
into their soil their available p is
quite High um and then just the other
thing I want to mention to you guys
totally unrelated to Q&amp;A but we just set
up the Discord so you should be able to
like share your own grow on there and
people can comment on it U so people can
have their own uh you know posts or
channels and then um we can all chat on
there better than patreon because I'm
gonna something that we want to add I'm
going to send out an invite for that to
everybody
tomorrow sweet I'm looking forward to
seeing everyone's uh grow on there too
yeah did did you guys want me to touch
real quick on a lwh heavy metal um
compost mix that people can try
sure yeah um so you could just use Pete
Moss because um Pete Moss is usually
very low in heavy metals and then we've
also found that um base of pee Moss
which is probably going to be what's in
your growing media anyway so it'll mix
well if you're using it to a mend um and
then you can just add
fishbone
gypsum and um insect brass and all those
have very low levels of arenic um gypsum
will have a tiny bit of lead so if you
are worried about lead um leave the
gypsum out but if you add something like
agline
or other calcium sources most of those
come with some arsenic so it's kind of a
battle you got to pick most of the time
between arsenic or lead um unfortunately
calos has a little bit of both which is
why we've been reducing it in our mixes
and leaning on the fishbone um because
the fishbone is just super clean and the
insect frass um that we have right now
is super clean so you could get a very a
high phosphorus based casting with um a
good reserve of
calcium that is virtually arsenic free
with a little bit of lead from the
gypsum and then if you take out the
gypsum there is calcium in fishbone and
worms naturally coat their calciums in a
calcium bicarbonate so there should in
theory be enough calcium without the
gypsum but the extra calcium in sulfate
that comes with the gypsum um I I love
that combination when we're talking
about cannabis so personally if I was
going to set up like an ultra clean
vermac composting setup I would amend
Pete Moss with insect frass fishbone and
gypsum uh add my worm population once I
made sure that that was not enough to
heat up the Pete in any way so once I
know that it's a safe environment add
your worms and there there's really not
going to be much of a um resting period
needed for that for that type of a
mix and you can hit us sub if you want
to know the brands that we've tested
because depending on where the gypsum's
mined will'll have different levels of
heavy metal so don't just think that all
gypsum's the same that's throw that out
there yeah sorry these are specifically
the products that we stock are the ones
that we've tested I couldn't speak to um
every brand and gypsum is one of those
things where the lower the quality the
more heavy metals you'll see so don't uh
skimp on the gypsum just because you
think you can get it from the paint shop
down the
street good tip well you can always get
the brands that we carry but yeah sorry
go ahead Louisa no I said I was just
saying those are good tips and uh it's
probably a good place to finish and uh
like Brandon said we'll you know we'll
try and address the other questions that
came in uh some some way somehow and uh
yeah we look forward to doing this again
soon thanks everybody for
coming yeah that was fun thanks guys
thanks everybody uh thanks you guys
thanks for the great
questions take care bye bye
[Music]
bye
h