process you're going to learn a lot
about your room just by experimenting
and figuring out when do I put that one
question you're going to be like holy
smokes like I watered these beds to
20mar give you know for
example and then I'm on day seven and
we're you know at
50 right and that really is the kind of
like holy smokes this they don't need
that much water or oh my God you know my
room super hot I'm on day four and I'm
at 160 like whoops so that's that kind
of experimentation um that you know just
the question of when do I put blue mats
in can really be a very powerful
learning experience for how your plants
interact with their environment