hey guys so I probably spent an
inordinate amount of time thinking about
soils and potting soils and soiless
recipes and things like that and I'm
currently in a conversation thread with
some really smart individuals uh Steve
dver uh Steve Solomon and some other
folks talking about some recipes because
uh one gentleman reached out um wanting
to try a recipe that he saw online and
it just it made me think a little bit
more about this and I wanted to just
share some considerations that people
should have when creating their own
soils so uh first and foremost um I
believe that soil should be formulated
around your compost because most people
you know whether it's cou mix or some
other recipes it just says you know Pete
Moss or coca cor uh pmus or some form of
variation and then compost well your
compost is a huge factor in determining
your overall fertility and it can change
dramatically it could be high in nit
rates the C to n ratio could be off um
it could be very high in potassium or
phosphorus or potentially even a trace
mineral it could be high in chlorides or
salts um and that could be an issue too
so the quality of your compost is
important but just not the not only just
the quality but the balance of those
minerals will affect what you want to
add to it because if I take a compost
that's already high in let's say
potassium and then I add a whole bunch
more potassium to it um I'm going to be
creating um some some nutrient
imbalances um potentially some
antagonisms and my plants aren't going
to be as healthy as I may want them to
be so first and foremost now when I go
to formulate a soil it'll take me a year
or two before I'm really comfortable
releasing a recipe um internally you
know in terms of one of our own soil
mixes because I want to mix that soil I
want to test the soil multiple times and
then once I feel good about about the
test results I want to run plant trials
so all of this before I would ever
release a mix uh to the public so that's
probably Overkill you know and if you're
uh you know a hom grower and you just
want to mix your own recipe you don't
need to go to that extent but a soil
test is really the only actionable
information that we data that we can
collect to allow us to make improvements
on our soil mix so keep that in mind um
so if you if you want to do it um
optimally then plan on budgeting the $60
for a complete test at least once so you
can at least say okay oh wow this
doesn't nearly have the nitrates that I
thought I did or ammonium is high I need
to let this cycle for a while uh before
I plant into it I'm going to have issues
so all considerations and and in some
cases we find you may even need to flush
because you may have added too much and
some of these online recipes that I'm
seeing um wow one of them uh Steve dver
calculated out the pounds of amendments
that that they were recommending in 4
cubic feet of soil and it was it was
almost 54 lb that is way too much
fertilizer or amendments for essentially
30 gallons of soil um we have created a
nutrient pack and I created this years
ago as uh sort of the similar kind of
thing like hey what if you know shipping
soil is expensive what if someone wants
like the nutrient mineral portion of
what we put in our soil so ours weighs
about 14 lb for cubic feet I happen to
have one here with me so I'll just show
it to you here this is our nutrient pack
um like I said it's about 14 lbs and
again it's just my best guess at what um
you would need if you were using a low
fertility soil mix initially like a
let's say like Happy Frog or Pro mix
would be good starting points um or if
you're mixing your own using high
quality compost but again I don't know
what that compost fraction is that
you're using so your results can vary
wide you know very widely and uh as C
would always say like no one's actually
growing a cots mix but him because you
don't have his vermac compost I think
that's a really important point when
we're thinking about mixing our own
soils is you know that compost fraction
is the most important the most important
fraction from a biological perspective
but also from a nutrient perspective
because it's going to either be bringing
in or not bringing in quite a bit of
fertility that you'll want to account
for with the Amendments that you're
adding so I don't want to discourage
anyone from mixing your own soils I i'
say go for it just be aware that you may
have have a lot more variability than
you realize in your final results and uh
the best advice I was ever given and I'm
going to pass on is less is more you
know always undershoot your targets you
can always add more nutrients during the
cycle but it's really really hard to
deal with issues if you have um
toxicities or too much of anything um
and then test your EC test your pH those
are going to give you some more
actionable data to decide okay I've
added enough fertility I may not know
what that fertility is but I know that
I've got approxim how much I want and my
pH is within the range that I'm aiming
for so those are all good tools and then
just to show you guys I just finished
tring this um I turned this off because
I didn't want a bunch of noise in the
background but I am setting up here uh
some under canopy air flow that I'm
pretty excited about so yeah hope
everyone has a great day thanks for
checking out the video