we're talking about moms I know there
was another question about moms in
general in terms of how to best keep
them and what size container and some of
that I thought that might be a good
transition um and and like you guys
touched on the Woody stems is a big
thing over time these plant every time
you take a cut you know you're gonna end
up with more offshoots and it just
becomes a nightmare over time of a of a
plant um plus I think the the health of
the plant and the viability of the plant
goes down uh over time with just
continual wounding and pruning um when
we talk about a long time but uh in
terms of how people are storing these
plants most of the facilities we work
with are organic so um most of them are
in a range of containers ranging from
I've seen them as small seven gallon
typically 20 or 30 gallon pots uh
Collective elevation if you go check out
that tour on YouTube they did it they do
two plants in a 4 by8 bed with a trellis
and it looks
awesome um I I don't know if the
workflow on that is better but I have to
say it's one of the coolest looking mom
rooms I've ever seen um so you should
definitely check that out but the The
Challenge on the fertility side with
moms is what I want to touch on before
you guys jump in and that's that's
really interesting because you know a
lot of us with the with the soil beds
you know the way that we like to grow a
kiss with with beds and reimen the soil
with soil testing every cycle that's
really challenging with moms especially
if you keep moms for more than a cycle
or two because it's uh one there's not
going to be a lot of soil left in that
pot it's G be mostly root mass and two
managing the fertility in that pot with
top dressing is really challenging um in
terms of keeping that Mom healthy and
and healthy moms is the most important
thing for your facility uh having
success and even for homeowers and
having Success Through flour starting
with like a really healthy clone if I
don't have a healthy Mom I'm not going
to start my next cycle it's that
important
um that's where little things like uh
fish
hydracy um a bottle nutrient program
with light doses come in really handy or
um even something like Jacks like a
conventional salt based fertilizer in
small doses uh those things are all just
really effective ways to keep your moms
healthy um I would much rather you know
for example run jacks or use a bottle of
nutrient line to make sure I'm keeping
my fertility up in that 30- gallon pot
my mom looks healthy then madly trying
to top dress as I see deficiencies
knowing that they're not going to get
into the plant for another s to 10 days
and now my plant stressed and I'm gonna
have to take cuting off of it so it
becomes a
real hle and it's to me it's not worth
it um so unless because every genetics
are going to they're all going to be a
little bit different so I can't just say
here's a top dress kiss hit for your
moms um and it's going to work for all
your moms because of the wide variety of
genetics that we have so um that's a
that's that was a good question that was
asked in our in our Q&amp;A list and and
that's sort of how I would address it um
do someone else want to add anything or
yeah for me when I when Dwayne put the
question forward because I work at kiss
and because I use kiss soil I know and
because I regularly rotate my mom at
least every three months I know that I
can keep a a nice vigorous healthy plant
that was vegged in a one gallon I can
throw that into a 10 or a 12 gallon
smart pot and I can run that and kiss
biochar water only CGM for three months
and I'm not going to see any
deficiencies that plant will be fine uh
as far as the nutrient side of things
calcium and F PR are the two that I try
to make sure on point for my moms just
as far as having the best propagation
results you know so those those are the
two elements that show up as being an
issue if somebody is just you know if
you're if you're not if your clones are
not rooting first thing you want to do
is get a scope out and look at your moms
and make sure you don't have russets or
something horrible like that going on um
that that's definitely you know
something that can happen you'll see
propagation numbers drop off with
russets but you'll also see it drop off
with calcium you'll see it drop off with
phosphorus um and then when the the
environment of the of the propagation is
not ideal you've got super low uh
relative humidity or something like that
but for me because I'm doing regularly
rotating my mom's I I like a 10 or 12
gallon smart pot I
like like at least
450 for my ppfd I'll go as high as 600
um for my moms I feel like that's that's
adequate and um you know it just I just
try to make sure I have enough to cover
my needs I try to make sure I've got
cuts that I don't need sitting around um
and I try to make sure I've got Cuts
before I need them I I would always
rather have a plant that's a little bit
bigger that I can trim back yeah that
nice big root mass because when you've
got a small shoots and a giant root mask
and you throw it into a bed it goes
crazy um I just did the opposite big
shoots almost no roots and you know lost
power for two days so it got cold and so
everything's just moving a little slowly
this
time but as far far as you know metrics
that's that's you know what I'm shooting
for for a
mom yeah for for us at the facility it's
um we really don't like to let them go
more than really three months Maybe
four the big imp reason for that is um
obviously we've got a whole area ready
to go for clones so why not use it for
just moms as
well um and the thing to think about
twoo guys is plants are a Lot Like Us in
some respects like the hormones change
over the years guys it sucks but it
happens um when they're young and ready
to grow they're going to be moving stuff
all over their body so taking cuting
from anywhere is going to give you a
really good shot at getting some really
vigorously ready to go babies um once
those moms get Woody and older it takes
it's a lot harder it's Fighting Gravity
more um those things get woodier it's
hard those and just the the hormones
change right the plant changes all that
stuff changes so it's a lot harder to
clone off of an older plant even if it's
the healthiest prettiest happiest
looking thing in the world just because
the starting materials that you want in
a clone aren't going to be there in
abundance as you know using from a
younger mom so um it that it helps to
keep them young for sure as far as your
success
rate yeah and I think it's it's also
good to um take into consideration that
we we are growing in
annual so even in the best of conditions
let's say Southern California you start
your seeds in February they're flowering
in August so that's six months
and even by then I I think that's a bit
of a long you know most people are
looking at May to August which is three
months um and that plant's just ready to
flower like it doesn't want to keep
growing it wants to flower um so I've
found that I take biochar soil and I'll
either add a couple cups of Bloom
booster or I'll just specifically add
fishbone and gypsum and then um I keep
my mom's in one gallons it's definitely
the the bigger the pot the longer you
can keep it happy but in one gallons
every two months um I take the most
atypical branch and I take it down about
eight inches and then I use that to
reset um I found that they don't skipe a
beat as long as you use
enough plant material and it has
dominance because there's going to be a
higher concentration of oxin and you're
kind of taking this the brain center of
the plant at that Point um and then when
that goes into the soil and that Roots
the amount of growth you're going to see
come off of that clone after it's rooted
is way more growth than you would see
from trying to keep a mom for six seven
months but it is more work to
continually reset and if your watering
is not on point those one gallon pots
can can really kill you so I would say
beds are the best but who's got beds
available for each mom you know what I'm
saying
man