uh something I was thinking about the
other day I posted this on social media
I got a wide variety of responses and I
wanted to hear your thoughts about
cannabis leaves praying are you familiar
with what I'm talking about when I say
that it's this uh sort of 45 degree
angle Leaf angle that you get and this
has always been associated with a very
happy plant you know you're getting good
uh turity in the in the stem apparently
um what are your thoughts on this
because
one of the thoughts I was had as I was
in my room looking at this and that the
plants were getting way too much light
at the time and they weren't perfectly
happy in my opinion but yet they were
doing this praying motion I'm like this
is this is a less than optimal angle for
for receiving photons too versus you
know having them be completely flat um I
don't know what are your thoughts about
it yeah so um forgetting the term is but
to me that would be because there's not
enough air flow um and so what the plant
is doing is it's trying to uh raise up
or expose more so the the bottom surface
of the leaf to get those stamata exposed
and get more air flow and eliminate some
of that um the the humidity that's
sticking right around the the stamata um
and so yeah I I would think that it's
it's caused by not enough air flow going
through the facility or another way to
think about is the the VPD isn't high
enough um either too much humidity or
you know what what have you but
basically the plant's not transpiring
enough it wants to raise the leaves
expose the stamata more so to the air
flow to help drive a higher
transpiration gradient