all right hi i'm chad hussey with kiss
organics and i'm here today with
suzanne wade wright evans of bug lady
consulting
and we are here to uh talk a little bit
about
different tools for scouting and
bug identification so things you might
want to consider when looking
at bugs suzanne you want to start off
and talk about
some of the tools you use when you're in
the field well the first
most important thing and i always tell
everybody to have
is a nerd bag that you can put all your
tools in i'm a huge fan of
the fanny pack because you can snap it
on and it leaves your hands free
to do things because sure enough if you
don't have the tool with you you're
going to need it and this way you can
carry everything with you
rei does not make this bag anymore but
you can find it on ebay occasionally and
i think this is about the perfect size
for carrying almost everything you need
i've i've had this probably 20 years
and has all kinds of stuff in it which
the different tools
i think first and foremost the number
one most basic scouting tool you can
have
is a 10x hand lens this one here
which i really like has
a built-in led light it's especially
helpful
for if you're in a darker situation um
for either like if you're looking at
plants in the interior scene or if
you're in a
darker grow room but also as you get
older
um having more light for your eyes is
really super helpful
and these are really inexpensive to buy
everyone on your team should probably
carry one always put them
on a lanyard because if not they're
really easy to get lost but this can
give you that quick
first initial look at something to make
the decision on do i need to collect a
sample
then to use with my microscope or your
other
usb microscopes or your other tools so i
have a question about this so
you have the 10x there i know they come
in variety of different magnifications
is there any advantage to having other
magnifications or do you just find
yourself using the 10x are there any
insects you're not going to be able to
see
let's say with a cannabis crop for
example uh with a 10x lens that where
you need something better
so i also have a 20x and i have a 30x
and i always come back to the 10x
when you get to the 20 and 30 the lenses
are a bit smaller
and you don't have the biggest field and
you also have to make sure you have
enough light but
even though my eyes are pretty bad at
this point
um i can see hemp russet mites with this
10x hand lens
um on the leaf and that's about as small
as you're going to need to see
from an insect or a mite standpoint okay
so um i have another thing here that a
grower recommended that i thought i'd
get
it's like it's from carson um
it's just another tool for looking at
them do you want to talk about the pros
and cons of something like this i know
you've never used this one i just showed
it to you five minutes ago
yeah um i think if you
had a stationary leaf
maybe if you were looking you know at
powdery mildew or something
and you wanted to come down over top of
it um that would work
well to look down i mean it's good that
it you know has a built-in
led light and you can focus and you can
zoom but if you're trying to hold leaf
samples out of the greenhouse i think
it's going to be
a little more challenging um
to work with from that standpoint i mean
i know it does have significantly higher
magnification
but i this would be something you'd more
use at a desk
with samples and also what's challenging
too
is if you have small leaves and you try
to get these
over top of them because sometimes it
can be challenging with the dynalite
to do that um and the field of view in
here wasn't super big i mean
would i buy one probably because i
collect all this kind of stuff
but i don't know how much i would use it
from an insect and might standpoint
yeah so one thing i want to talk about
when it comes to stuff like this you
know this was under 20
it was on amazon when you're talking
about buying something
for magnification a lot of it comes down
to the quality of the objective and
correct me if you disagree with anything
i say here
so it's the amount of light that you
need relative so as you go to higher
magnifications you need more light so
that's something to keep in mind too
when we talk a little more about
microscopes but um the quality objective
on something like this with it with a
cheap
20 tool is not going to be that great um
so you're not you're not this is not
going to replace a higher quality option
if we want to really look closely at an
insect or even take a picture this isn't
going to function for that
and you know like like you said suzanne
you've been using these loops
those are your go-to things you know
having
like you said a graveyard of these back
home and ending up still using the loop
every day uh that's something to
consider
you don't need all of these gadgets but
they're kind of fun to play around with
too so let's move on to
uh the the next let's talk about what's
in your bag besides just
these microscope related scouting tools
because you had a few other things that
you pulled out
let's talk about that before we talk
about the dyno lights okay
so this is definitely a critical part of
my
tool bag is i get these
vials um you can order these from
bioquip
which is an insect supply company it's
it's
it's if anybody ever wants to send me a
gift card to bio cliff i'd love you
forever
i love shopping because they've got all
the
entomology tools you need but i just
order these vials i pre-load them with
alcohol
and then these cards i absolutely love
um what what alcohol are you using in
these and where do you get it
how much of these these things cost oh
the vials
yeah pennies they're super cheap okay
and then
what type of alcohol do you like right
now with covid any alcohol i can get
okay because it's been a real issue
trying to get alcohol
if your alcohol is way too high um it
can evaporate really quickly because
if you don't get nalgene caps
the alcohol does evaporate but generally
for what i'm doing where i'm just
collecting samples
ferrying them back home i'm going to put
them under the microscope i'm not
storing these for years for museum
specimens if you need to store them for
a long time
you need the nalgene caps from
um to to do that to keep it from
evaporating
but this kind of in a way kind of goes
with this
so these are actually white balance
cards from amazon
they're actually up to nine dollars now
a package i think
okay they used to be like five and in
this you get
three of these cards and really what
these are used for
is um white balancing your camera
and you know if anybody's ever taken
pictures under led lights you know what
happens and that's why you white balance
your camera so that your colors are
normal but what i found
is these make a great tool for
sampling and scouting for insects so i
hold this under a plant and then i just
bang the plant
and then aphids uh thrips
mites things like that can fall on here
now
in the pack you do get gray black and
white
cards i used to use white all the time
but now i use black i find it just it
works better for my eyes to see them
but if i get if it falls on here you can
take a paintbrush and again i buy these
by the 50 pack on amazon and you just
dip the the paint brush and alcohol and
then you can go on this plastic board
and you can pick up the insect and then
dip it back on the alcohol
and now you've got your thrips your
mites your aphids and the alcohol and
you don't
damage them so you can collect
the insects off the board and put them
in the alcohol and then you have your
samples
that then you can either put under your
microscope for identification or
send off to extension or someone to do
your identification
on them this also is a great way just to
scout
even if you're not collecting specimens
just walking by and knocking your plants
i actually
have a video on my instagram account
where we were doing this in an
ornamental greenhouse and you could just
see the thrips
raining out of the plant even though you
looked at the plants they looked good
but we didn't know the thrips are there
until we knocked the plants and they
fell
on here and then we could see them very
clearly this will help
speed up your scouting and make you more
accurate this is one of my
favorite things and i always carry them
with me
i do have to say though i've got tons of
gray cards left because i end up leaving
these with growers all the time
and now i have like this more of gray
cards because great cards are the worst
out of the pack to um see insects on
i also like because people say oh you
can just do it on a white sheet of paper
well i like this because you can clean
this with alcohol at the end of the day
so there's no sticky on it
this particular size i like too because
it fits in most cargo pants pockets
or your back pocket you can get these
cards in like 8 by 10
too which might be more effective for
some people with larger plants to
collect a larger area
but i absolutely love these cards and i
think it's an essential part of your
your scouting toolbox that you should
have
so anything else that you have in there
uh that you want to talk about before we
go dive into
you know more microscope related no i
mean i always carry tweezers
i always have sharpie markers um
chapstick of course but a ziploc baggie
ziploc baggies um binder clips
um i actually have a tiny screwdriver in
here here's the stray gray card
um and you know i also have a notebook
in case i need to write anything down in
it um
sometimes i have petri dishes in here
too because if you take leaf samples and
you put them in a ziploc baggie you can
get a lot of condensation build up in
there or if you put them back in your
pouch they can get smushed so petri
dishes
will not smush your leaf
and they're not sealed tight so you get
a little more breathability
in there with them but they do take up
more space um
in your bag now if you were working at a
facility
versus coming in to consult you may also
have
um a way of writing stuff down like
charting
where you're see where you are in the
facility and where you're seeing this
plant issue and i know you've talked in
the past about using some sort of marker
identification whether that's like a
colored plant steak or some way to note
where
you know the color red means thrips
irrigation flags are the best because
they're cheap you can order them in lots
of colors and they're easy to see and
you can just stand them in pots
um and we use those regularly in
ornamental production and you'll see
where they'll have pvc holders for each
of the different color flags on a little
cart
and you know it could be there's an
insect problem there's a mic problem
there's a disease problem there's an
irrigation problem
but you have to come up with your own
system for that
and as far as record keeping there's
actually
more scouting software and companies
that are becoming available
um that really have got my interest
because it's going to give people the
opportunity
to really map out their greenhouse or
map out
their grow and then identify and
keep good records on population
densities and what they're finding
so you know if i'm home in pennsylvania
but my growers in colorado i can go in
to their daily scouting information and
i can see what's going on
from remote and that's one of the things
because i have been
going through demonstrations with all
these companies that provide scouting
software
and they said it's important to have
remote access for the consultants to be
able to get in and view things so i can
see if there's a problem
they have ways that you can take
pictures and then fold them into the
scouting reports
and this summer at the cultivate show in
columbus ohio i'm actually teaching a
full day scouting workshop
we're going to go out into a greenhouse
we're going to use these different
scouting tools we're going to have
demos of different software and then
we're actually going to have
um a setup where we're going to have
lots of pest insects
in a classroom setting to work on
identification
so you could have like a essentially in
the software and picturing something
where you would have a zone
like zone a for example and you could
you could mark that with mites and then
you could post a photo
of that might and then remotely someone
like yourself could go in and confirm
the identification and then
work with that scouting team to come up
with
a plan for releases or sprays or
whatever
mode of treatment yeah well it's
interesting too because over time with
these on these programs you can build
heat maps
and you can be like hey why do we always
end up with spider mites in that back
corner and why
over there you know after two years do
we always have powdery mildew here and
you can start to see trends
in pest management and help you figure
out how to mitigate those problems to
prevent them from happening next time
cool all right well we're getting off
topic like like we always do so
uh let's talk about um the next
series of things so you identify
something with the loop and you want to
get a closer look at it you want to get
identified you need a tool to take a
photo
some way to capture the image that
allows you to or even just take a closer
look yourself so
for that you've recommended dino lights
and just you know dynalite does not pay
me i
just love dynalite yeah i just
i yes i own four of them now
so i will say that so this is my dyno
light this is the mid
tier option um this one was around
400 i believe we do carry them on our
website there's a 200
option that also works it's just a
slightly lower megapixel account
i don't have one of those here suzanne
has the
fancier one and there's even fancier
than this one she was telling me
but in terms of scouting
this is more than enough for the average
facility even the 200
one i think we could safely say would
work for facilities
um you don't need these unless you want
to do like real insect photography
um well and i will say this one
this does disconnect and you can make
this
wireless okay i i love you dyna like but
i don't like that
on this because anytime something is
wireless there's a little more of a
delay in taking photos
and i want to see instantaneously the
picture i just took
and realistically i mean if if you
needed to if you were going to do
electronics and you're crawling through
an air conditioning shaft i could see
where you'd want it
wireless but for what we're doing i
don't think
that extra expense is necessary yeah
these plug into
tablets they plug and you can so mine
this is an adapter so i can run it into
my mac
uh suzanne uses it with her windows
laptop we're gonna
show you um an over the shoulder look
next
uh connected to this video where we'll
show this and some other microscope
options
but i just want to talk about these
before we really dive into it um
there's other brands that make lights
that look a lot like this
uh but the big the big deal here is the
quality of the objective and the quality
of the
the build itself to know that it's gonna
last that they have support for
they have good software for capturing um
the image and uh anything else you want
to say about i think they have the best
photo capturing software for this kind
of stuff
um on the market and you can put
notes with the images so in the so it's
like in the metadata
in there because i think it's really
important to make sure you track
when you take an insect image what's the
host plant where you took it
and all that kind of information because
when you take macro photos
if you go back and look in the year it's
hard to tell where you were
landscape images yeah you know where you
were macro stuff and you think you're
going to remember the plant cultivar
you're not so i think that's really
important and again
as you said the tech support i found
extremely helpful
on these and you can connect these to
your smartphones too
with um an adapter on the end again i
actually use this through my laptop
often and then i even love it more when
i hook it up to my flat screen tv
so you you can see it
super big on the screen because i like
seeing big bugs cool
all right well let's pause this and come
back with uh it actually hooked up to a
computer so we can show it
all right so see then you have the fancy
dyno light there can we talk about the
can you want to talk a little about like
what someone who's buying just a
less expensive you know middle of the
road well they're
not the middle of the road they're still
fancy pants road they are
sure um what i like about the dyno
lights is
you have your magnification and focus on
one wheel
um and i'll show you that in a second
where you can zoom in
and focus right on this one wheel but
they also have this soft touch button
and if you kind of i've learned if i
angle it just right when i'm holding it
if i hit it with my skin
just by brushing this it takes the photo
in the past
you would have to manually take the
photo on
your computer so you'd get it held then
you'd have to go hit and
it can jerk things so having this soft
touch
button was one of the biggest
advancements um
i found having this on these units
um and um i don't know maybe tab will
show you a close-up later but you can
see all
the led lights inside of there
through the software you can turn the
lights
off and on and you can control how much
light you have
and you sometimes can see the leds
reflecting if you have very glossy
insects
but they actually do make diffusers that
pop into there that if you're really
worried about
seeing the individual lights which
sometimes i am for photography purposes
but not necessarily for identification
purposes um
and there's there's two levels of focus
two with them
so you can zoom in and then there's a
further zoom too
i find with mine where if i want to
really zoom in where it'll kind of come
into focus
at two different levels um let me
so you're kind of moving around i'm
going to zoom in on your screen so
people can kind of
see what's showing up while we're while
you're talking about it so
that's a boy and that's a girl okay so
right now you have two spotted spider
mites on your screen you can see what
they're seeing
and that's a boy two spotted spider
white and that's a female
over there and then you can see there's
an
egg right up there but but that glow
you're getting in the egg is actually
the
led lights reflecting back yes here let
me zoom in a bit
over here i'm you know i need to look at
my screen
no no you're fine yeah so what what
she's doing right here is just
kind of holding it either right on or at
a slight angle and then with her thumb
adjusting the magnification yeah so you
can see right there
those spider mite eggs right in there
and again you can see that weird
lighting ring in there a diffuser can
stop that but again for scouting
purposes now we know there's spider-mite
eggs
and a leaf like this that has several of
these
um mite eggs it's going to be a problem
here in a
you know very near future in a day or
two
with an explosion of spider mites on
this cannabis leaf
and again here you can see the spider
mites walking through them so i can get
her
sitting right there and you can see her
distinctive
you know two spots on her back and
that's how she gets her name's
name they don't always cooperate but as
long as you can see them
nope now she's running away but you
could take one of these and drop it in
alcohol or drop a drop of alcohol in it
and then take a look
yeah that is closer if you really wanted
yeah and you were also saying just since
we're talking about too spotted on this
that um
they can have different coloration yes
and we were talking today about aphids
in particular but that you cannot use
color as a way of identification
with some of these insects which is
important to note
yeah and you can even see it doesn't
show so much
on your screen but how this is way more
green and darker than actually this one
you see an adult male sitting right up
here
just sitting the males are skinnier and
pointier on the back
side there so that's the the male
sitting right there the male two spotted
spider mite
and actually the one above it if you
count it's a very young spider mite
it only has six legs when they're first
born they only have six legs
and then as they grow up then they'll
have eight legs like an adult so that's
an immature two-spot spider right back
there with its uh six legs
and that's the molting remains down
below there
yeah these are the cast skins off uh two
spot spider mites
and almost they almost crack in the
middle and then they come
out of the middle of it and then the
front and the back half of their molt
left behind
and this one down here um
is getting ready to mold because i was
telling you earlier
they get this weird kind of sheen to
them and kind of do this resting things
before they shed their skin
okay great and then since we this is on
the cannabis leaf by the way
i also have this stand here i just want
to mention it as
i bought it suzanne has one neither of
us particularly like to use it
i'm missing a part on it i just noticed
just now that it actually comes out a
fork that
holds the light like this and then
there's this
lever here that allows you to raise it
up and down but we
we both much much more prefer to just
use it
in our hand rather than using the stand
so if you do decide to get something
like this
i would hold off on buying the stand
until you know for sure it's something
you want to use
but today we were looking a little bit
at some soil trying to find see if i had
we could find any mites and some soil i
had outside
we pulled a bunch of leaves out of the
yard we found some
caterpillars stink bug two spotted
surfer fly
surfing fly which i posted a video of
and uh
anything else about this particular the
dyno light before we move on to other
microscopes um
the one thing about this is it comes in
like a plastic
little sleeve and a bag i always put it
back in its plastic
sleeve and bag um this one's yours and
you do not have the plastic insert in
there
oh well but it's fine because i just
keep it clean in there because you don't
want to get goo up in your lens i'm i'm
captain anal about
keeping my lenses clean because that's a
good pointer okay
when you know when you're taking macro
stuff
a tiny little speck becomes a huge spec
yeah
on your screen and so it's very
important to keep all your equipment
clean so i always keep it in the little
slip-on sleeve and then keep it in the
bag
um and i fly with these well now that
i'm back traveling again
every week and i just i have them in my
backpack and it travels with me fine
i've never broken a dynalite with all
the flying and throwing in the overhead
bin and everything
well we don't have a dissecting
microscope here uh
that's back at suzanne's place maybe
we'll add a video to that here on the
end
possibly when she gets back home but i
do want to show you guys uh just the
more
traditional compound microscope
okay take two let's talk about uh
my microscopes here so this is a phase
contrast microscope this one's made by
meiji it's
japan this is what i use for looking at
compost tea or soil samples in a lot of
cases
not great for looking at insects not
this
design but my meiji dissecting scope i
have meiji too
and i love it that's great for looking
at
anything bigger than an aphid anything
smaller you almost have to slide them
out and use
a compound microscope like this so this
is a phase contrast microscope
which allows you to see things that are
similar to fraction than water which is
really nice
when we're talking about something like
compost tea because we're it's literally
in a liquid liquid water so
you don't need this necessarily though
if we're talking about
uh you know someone who wanted just a
hobby
grower who wants to look at you know
look at microbes
suzanne you mentioned one from celestron
celestron celestron
that you really liked yeah and i'll put
a link to that model up i think she said
he said it's around 350
yep so that's a great option for people
when we're talking about
quality of microscopes the things to
consider uh
first and foremost is the quality of the
objectives that's these things down here
these are the lenses essentially that
are that are magnifying
what you're going to see through the
image here so um
you're going to take your objective and
multiply it by your eyepiece and that
tells you your total magnification
most eyepieces are 10x you can get
things like a barlow lens here that's
going to give you a smaller field of
view but like this will multiply it
another three times
i rarely use this in here but it can
slide into the eyepiece too
um having a trinocular microscope
is really nice i would not buy a
microscope unless it was triacular
anymore today yeah so this if it didn't
have this it'd just be a binocular or
they have a monocular with one lens
some microscopes have built-in cameras
already
this setup that i have here was pretty
expensive
it's probably about six or seven
thousand dollars at the time
um you know this little adapter here
allows me to hook up a canon uh
digital camera so i could do photos and
video
um and again that comes down to the
quality of the of the camera cause some
of my built-in cameras and i've seen the
quality
really vary sometimes it's not good well
and often times well built-in cameras
you're not going to be able to improve
your camera over time i would never get
a built-in one because
photography is is greatly improving
fastly you know going mirrorless now and
a lot of the
the dslrs on that also
when i was researching microscope
cameras um
you kind of have to make your decision
do you want really good video quality
which has a lower frame i'm sorry a
higher frame rate so it's more seamless
but you do that you give up
quality on the still pictures but if you
want better still pictures you're going
to get jerky videos they
i really struggle to find a good camera
that does
both of them so you kind of make a
decision on your camera on what you want
to do
yeah and then some other things this
isn't so much on how to use a microscope
but some of the other
parts that come with the microscope to
consider uh you know there's different
filters
filter lenses that may make it easier or
harder to see certain
certain things i like to keep this blue
one on here i find it makes it easier
for me to see things
um and then i think one thing i hadn't
talked about was the
the light the wattage of the light or
intensity of the light is huge
this is a 30 watt light versus a lot of
them are 20 so it just it pushes up more
like because as you go to a higher
magnification you need more light at the
same time
being able like to dim the light which
is the switch right here
when i'm looking at a compost tea sample
and i want to keep things from drying
out and keep it alive because i want to
look at it longer i'm going to dim the
light to the lowest level but that still
allows me to see my sample
in this case here i just since we're
talking about it
slide cover slip i cheat and do two
purse line
i don't know if that's uh a bad thing
but it saves me a little time so i also
you know you're gonna have you're gonna
need cover slips um
pipettes are handy and then this is the
uh immersion oil which allows you to use
the highest magnification
um in this case it's a 100x which
which translates to 1000x by the time
you look through here now
for me like you mentioned earlier you
spend most of your time at 10x or the
jeweler's loop
i spend most of my time at uh 20x
and um what's this other one here
oh 10x so 100 and 200 times
magnification is where i spend
90 of my time it's only when i want to
really look at like some bacteria or
something really really close that i
ever even go up to 400 times
magnification
um you certainly i never even use the
100x
i've never needed it so what do you what
do you have to say about microscopes
well i mean when i was researching
because i had my meiji dissecting scope
and then i wanted to get
um a similar setup to this
i went and talked to a lot of the
microscope companies because i don't use
this setup nearly as much i do my
dissecting scope and the one thing that
came back over and over again is eye
strain
and that the better quality glass
you have in your scope is going to have
less eye strain so for researchers who
spend like eight hours a day to scope
that's why they have these you know 50
60 000
microscopes because it greatly reduces
eye strain
for me you know if i'm looking at let's
say a thrift sample
i may spend 10 minutes looking at it so
i wasn't as concerned so that's why i
feel i didn't have to be as
in a high price range but having the
moving stage
was really important for me um
because i actually spent i still have my
um microscope from when i was a kid
oh okay yeah and i look at that thing
and
you know that you had just two little
clips that you had to slide
the slide around with your hands and it
was a monocular
and my dad actually installed a dimmer
switch on the light so i could adjust my
light
okay um yeah i found it the other day
wow i've kept it all these years
but um the moving stage really makes
your life so much easier to be able to
do the fine adjustments
on there and again that's with that
celestron scope i really liked it had
the dimmable lights the adjustable stage
you can go all the way up and do the oil
immersion
it comes as a tri-ocular
which you can it comes with a cap on it
you pop it off
and then you can attach whether you want
to do
you can get microscope cameras that
almost look like dino light it's a tube
that just drops in
dslr or you're going to use one of the
forms of the the digicams
that you can get adapters but you're
right the adapter tubes since they often
have to be custom made
when three to five hundred dollars and
so every time
i had to get a new camera because you
know gotta have more megapixels wouldn't
have a better camera
it's another three to five hundred
dollar investment every time you upgrade
so it does um get expensive
and the quality of the metal is
important and i don't want to knock any
microscope companies
and scope but i bought just a stand from
amsco
but then the third time i'm using it i
went to twist one piece of metals and
snapped right in half it's made from
what i'd call chineseium
and it's like that plastic metal hybrid
i don't even know what it is and there's
like no fixing it now
so you know william's gonna have to
drill it out and try to
fix it for me um because i have some
very jerry rigged equipment at home
for doing you know the macro insect
photography work i do
the other thing that's really really
important
is to keep your microscope covered and
keep it cleaned if you want to get your
microscope
serviced um where you know it's good to
do
like every 10 years they clean and
everything um it's about 300
to get your microscope serviced yeah
this this one's due
i'm finding i'm seeing a lot of things
that i shouldn't be seeing yeah i
mentioned that's
and the other thing i don't have here
that i left over my actual microscope
stand
is kim wipes and those are wonderful
because they allow you to clean
surfaces without damaging the lens um
because you have to have special
cleaner for that too um
i guess the one big takeaway i want for
people to think about
is that there's no perfect microscope
for any scenario so for me
because my interest was soil-based
microbes
and for looking at like bacteria fungal
hyphae looking at compost teas
this was the setup that made the most
sense for me now if i was more into
insects like suzanne then a dissecting
microscope would be a more useful tool
beyond you know what you can see in the
dyno light right
and you know with the dissecting scopes
too
you can get more magnification
by you can buy extra magnification that
screws on underneath so you can get
higher resolution it's basically
where these microscopes have the oculars
all built and you can rotate you just
unscrew them and add them on so you
can improve your magnification and you
know you can easily see spider mites and
things like that
with that but with the dissecting scope
you can put like a branch you can put a
leaf you can put three dimensional
objects
with this you have to slide mount things
and i see a lot of compound microscopes
at facilities but people are trying to
wedge a leaf under and it doesn't work
that way
if you're going to look at leads and
things like that you really need
the dissecting scope you do because the
lights coming from below
so if that light's not getting through
it's going to be pitch black looking
down
now you brought up one thing i have
cheated before when i need to use this
scope and i didn't have like a dyno
light at the time
you can't take a flashlight or even your
phone light and shine light from above
to allow you to get enough light to see
what's on there
what's on the slide if you're using a
leaf or something like i was trying to
see a broad mic at the time and i didn't
have any other tools and so this allowed
me
to it was really hard and a pain in the
butt but just a little like
tip the other thing i will say is if
you're spending
a sizable amount of money on a
microscope talk to the manufacturer
they let me they let me borrow this
microscope i mean i
paid for it um but i had a time period
where i could try it out and see if it
worked for my use because
i wanted to make sure you know that was
a chunk of money i was going to be
spending it's a huge investment
you know in my case this is a lifetime
investment that i'm going to use
for a long time i want to know um the
quality of it
the and what it actually looks like when
i'm looking at what i'm going to be
looking at in this case
you know compost teas um am i going to
be able to see everything i want to see
so that's absolutely an option there's
sales reps out there that will
bring one out and let you use it prior
to purchasing even
um so i just want to share that tip
yeah i was fortunate because i go to the
entomological society of america
conference each year and then the trade
they have the microscope vendors there
and i went around and talked to them um
because when i was gonna buy a compound
scope i was expecting to spend several
thousand dollars
and the celestron guy is like try if you
don't like it
you know you can always you know return
it but i i've been i've had it now i
think two years
and um again i i don't spend hours a day
at it
but for what it is it's it's it's been
great
mom i really like it having an
adjustable eyepiece too
is really really important um because
you need to be able to adjust these
until it's almost like looking at those
old
3d things where you stare like a image
and no it's like uh yeah you know those
popular photos where the image would pop
out if you like your
eyes like relax oh no no no no the books
the pictures yeah yeah the um and not
everyone could do it well that's what i
kind of equate to like these eye pieces
like you have to give them you almost
have to relax your eyes and then get
them to fit perfectly in order to get a
really good image and so having this be
adjustable is important
and if you're going to buy a microscope
get the tri-ocular and stop holding your
camera right here
and trying to get those janky pictures
through your cell phone
if you're gonna do it go ahead and get a
camera that mounts on it so you can get
better images because it's really hard
to identify those half out of focus in
focus
holding my cell phone over the holes
well
the dynolite solves all that you
shouldn't be taking insect photos with
this
um anyway i mean if you want to look at
fungal hyphae and you want to look at
bacteria which you wouldn't be sending
to suzanne anyway
um then you would use this type of
microscope yeah but you can save money
200 for a dyno light and then get a high
quality
image where you're not using your cell
phone um that allows you to actually
capture an insight right
good enough to identify yeah um
so do you wanna do a quick summary here
before we
sign off sure must have tools
in the growers 10x hand lens if i show
up in your facility
you do not have a 10x hand lens you're
going to get a very disappointing look
for me
okay 10x hand lens um
some board or some way to to identify
and
to identify insects and knock them off
of plants right and collect them with
vials
vials and alcohol alcohol some type of
marking tape if you need to flag plants
i think is really important
um and again the dynalite you can
hook up and use while you're actually
scouting i
have challenges with that actually on
the facility sometime with having the
phone
having bright light trying to flat
surface because it's you can't really
use a dino light
like with loose plant leaves it needs to
be on a solid surface
soon then you can use it with your phone
i think you're better off collecting
your leaf samples and taking them
back to your little setup
very rarely would i ever recommend
anyone buy
an actual microscope like this um
or even a dissecting scope unless it's
something that you're really passionate
about
or really interested in i don't think
most facilities need to have a
microscope for what they're doing
um i just want to i think there's
there's other things you could spend
money on within
the ipm world or the scouting world like
a dyno light that would be much more
useful than
um something like this so here we go
all right