so I get asked from time to time what
lights am I using in my grow and what
light companies do I recommend so I've
worked with a few different light
companies over the years and the one
that I'm using in my grow right now is
bios I love their lights they're a
smaller company uh NASA spin-off so the
lights are well engineered I love that
NASA connection I just think as a nerd
that's so cool um some of the highlights
about these lights so not only do they
have very very good uh power levels
efficacy all of that they have this uh
glass cover on the lights I think that's
really really important because if I I
just cleaned my lights today for example
and you know the amount of dust and
overspraying stuff that can end up on
your lights can really affect the
overall uh par ppfd levels that you're
getting down here and you may not even
realize it and you don't want to be
cleaning exposed diode so that to me is
number one when I'm looking at an LED
light uh
secondly customer service and uh
warranties are huge because the light is
so wellb built they have a seven-year
warranty I don't know if anyone else in
the industry even coming close to that
and uh I work really closely with my rep
uh Jennifer she's wonderful and so uh
she helps me with lighting proposals
technical questions and I can you know
we have a great relationship I can just
shoot her a text so I love having that
one toone close relationship and I
haven't had any issues with the light
but I know if I do they're going to take
good care of me uh this light here to
tell you the difference this is the ti2
so this light's been out um I mean don't
quote me on this but for a few years now
um my only complaint with this light is
it's a little overbuilt it's just it's
really heavy to lift up and down um that
makes it a little bit unwieldy but
that's cuz it's built like a tank like I
feel like I could drop this light and it
would still work just
fine but moving over here they just came
out with this light last year um I was
fortunate enough to get one of their
prototypes um but this is the this is
the BIOS Endeavor I love this light it's
a six light bar instead of the ti2 which
is an eight light bar over there you can
see the difference but the power levels
are really really close I'm running both
of these I think they're 650 watt if for
some reason you needed like an 800 watt
light then you'd have to move over to
the ti2 cuz this one's only 650 but it
weighs 11 lb it's so easy to move up and
down it folds out um so installation
took me all of 2 minutes it's pretty
much plug andplay and I just I love the
form factor um the plants as you can see
are doing just as well under it as they
are under the
ti2 so I just wanted to mention that we
work with bios directly so if you wanted
a lighting proposal or an estimate on
one of these lights if you wanted to try
out the Endeavor or the ti2 in your
garden or you're interested in the Luna
or some of their you know top bar
Greenhouse lights uh just hit us up I'm
happy to get you over the spec sheets
any information you may want on them and
even help with a lighting proposal or
design for your space specifically all
right thanks for checking it out