all right so I'm here with Julie gresh
from bioworks and she did a presentation
yesterday on neem and azadaractin and I
put up a quick post on my story and
there were a lot of questions about it
so I tracked her down and I thought we
could do a little
short little mini session on Neiman as
direct and so thanks for taking the time
to do this
and thank you Ted I appreciate it
um yeah so why don't we start off with
how the neem tree gets processed just a
real quick explanation on that so the
seed the fruit is small almost Olive
shaped and it as it progresses to
maturity it goes to this nice yellow
orange color and it will fall from the
tree where it's harvested and
the neem seed has after the fruit
um
flesh has been removed you're left with
the the kernel and it does have a hole
on it which needs to be removed like a
pistachio
so once that's removed you get the the
kernel or the seed which is either
solvent extracted or also pressed to
remove the oil and from that oil you
have that the raw oil it you have an
additional
process where it's separated into two
different products one is Asda actin and
one is clarified hydrophobic extract of
neem oil since that's a lot of words and
most people don't like to say a lot of
words it is shortened off and down to
just saying neem oil
so it's really important to note that a
neem oil product does not have acid or
actin and a nasider actin product does
not have neem oil however there are some
combo products that may have both
depending
um so
it's important to make sure you look at
the label to ensure that you are
when you're wanting to purchase do you
want a neem oil
for Suffocation or do you want acid or
actin that will have additional
insecticidal capabilities
and those neem oil products are
typically formulated in an oil like a
sunflower oil and those will then help
facilitate the the application and the
spread and the absorption of that
chemical into the insect's cuticle which
there can be some contact
efficacy but um mainly it needs to be
ingested for maximum efficacy
as interactive the azador ACT incorrect
okay so with the neem oil it's
Suffocation or cuticle disruption which
you're gonna have a little bit of that
with the azidaractin products as well
because oftentimes they're formulated in
oil
but not neem oil so what what is
uniquely special about neem oil then if
as a compared to other oils
if anything so they're
um there can be so Anem is the neem
oil comes from a Botanical source so you
can have a product like soft oil X that
is
made from a Horticultural mineral oil
and that is different than something
that is botanically produced so it's
produced from something in nature this
neem tree the seed that we talked about
so in a um
each of those can be highly efficacious
and it will have their place and you can
oftentimes even use those in rotation
just depending on you know what your
goals are and what insects may be on the
label or even what diseases or mites are
on those labels so again make sure you
read the label because not all of them
will be targeting the same insects mites
and some of these products are also
fungicidal
so I would say there are differences in
the oils and a reason you may choose say
a neem oil over
a Horticultural mineral oil is that it
is plant-based and there is going to
it's going to be
more
complex I would say than something that
is more of a pure
mineral oil
and there's going to be several
compounds that come from the tree with
that
um but again there it it's it's
fundamentally different you know from a
Horticultural mineral oil from a neem
oil so try them both
see what works best for you sometimes
like I said they are used in rotation I
wouldn't tank mix them but they can be
used in rotation especially if you're
trying to Target specifically things
that are on the label
okay and uh neem oil is uh EPA regulated
products or registered products sorry
and some of these other oils like some
of the time all time products lavender
those are all 25b products so there's a
little more regulation around neem
as well so your acid or actin products
your neem products and your combo
products will all be found listed in at
the Environmental Protection Agency EPA
and
um
there are a number of
neem and acid or actin-based products
that do have hemp on the label and you
can go on to the EPA website and look
for product search as a directin or neem
oil or clarified hydrophobic extract of
neem oil and it should pull up and hemp
and it should pull you up that that
short list I think there's around 10 to
15 different
[Music]
um
uh labels that are listed on the EPA now
at the state level there may be
additional products that the states have
approved for use so do look at your
state to see if you you do have maybe
more options now as far as the 25 B's
those are
um
considered safe by the NOP or national
organic program
and because those are considered safe to
humans and crops
they have less regulations associated
with them many of them are essential oil
based and as Tad said they could be a
time oil based or peppermint oil
rosemary oil sometimes you'll have a
combination of many of these different
oils they do have an odor to them and
they can work through
um not only just the Suffocation but you
can also have some Direct effects on the
insects it may disrupt you know some
sort of insect physiology just depending
on what oil it it essential oil is in
those 25 B products
there's also an odor associated with it
some people depending again on the
central oil can think that it is a
pleasant odor other people don't think
it's a pleasant odor that does seem to
be a little bit dependent on the people
but it's it's not an offending like
maybe a chemical smell would be so
um but again those are 25b products and
they're not registered with the EPA so
there are less regulations associated
with them
um maybe many of them don't even have a
PPE requirements although I would always
tell you that it's important to wear PPE
such as gloves while making the
application maybe just like a a dust
mask or something so you're not inhaling
particles and that sort of thing safety
should always be first when dealing with
any kind of spray so in addition to the
Suffocation or maybe some sort of
physiological effects with the insect
that odor can make insects not also not
like it and so they may
disappear they may try to go to a
different plant they may leave the if
it's a greenhouse if it's a grow
obviously you know there's only so far
for them to go but they may not come
back to the plant so they would then at
that point starve so there's a neem oil
might have that effect too
and one thing on 25b products I want to
mention is there's no requirement for
any efficacy data on them so I could mix
in my garage rosemary oil
uh peppermint oil and and slap it on a
label and make a product and and pretty
much say that it kills these things but
I don't have to actually prevent private
data so as a consumer you guys have to
be very careful
absolutely and thank you for bringing
that up what
you could do what you just said and
um however companies
that produce 25 bees have scientists
research and development that formulate
these products together and have very
specific ratios and there is
um for the
reputable companies there is or should
be some research and development that
has been done to ensure that you have a
good Emulsion of the essential oils with
various formulation components that is
going to make a good product and most
importantly that that product will not
say burn the crop or cause any other and
correct phytotoxicity crop tolerance and
potentially a number of other things and
that's obviously really important you
don't want to burn your crop so if you
mix something up in your own basement
and try to apply it to your plant it may
not mix in water very well it may want
to just float right up to the surface a
lot of the essential oils are very
volatile and so if you put it into water
it may just volatilize and go poof so
many of these essential oils have been
formulated to almost encapsulate the
essential oils so it doesn't volatilize
until it gets to the plant where it's
going to have that efficacy
so it's more complicated
than just
you know putting putting some of these
things together and applying it to your
plant there are dangers with doing that
um and I think mainly you know crop
damage being the the biggest concern so
so getting back to the neem stuff
we carry a cold pressed neem product
um
you don't know that know that but we do
uh and um one of the things around that
as you mentioned it does have a level it
can potentially have levels of azure
direct and I know originally I had the
manufacturer send me
stuff and it showed you know the PPM of
azure act and in the product so when you
said Nemo didn't contain Azure actin
that kind of surprised me and then you
mentioned this cold pressing
um
so
I I guess my question around that is the
neem cake and the neem oil if it's cold
pressed will have
some as a direct and level but it'll be
exponentially lower than the pure acid
or actin product is that correct so the
the cold-pressed name is basically
that kernel that we talked about earlier
it's pressed the seed or the kernel is
about 40 oil so with that comes all of
the
um
compounds
um that are in there and acid or actin
is actually Collective term
um because it is Botanical you have more
than just Hazard act and Aster actin is
the most insecticidally active and
highest concentration of those various
compounds that is now known as acid or
actin so you get depending on the seed
quality you can have anywhere from 300
to I think 2500 parts per million as a
directin from
a cold-pressed neem oil or the raw neem
oil and so for instance with an azador
actin product it can be anywhere from
0.15 or less if for homeowners
up to about six percent acid or actin
and so like Tad said it's exponentially
higher for an Azar actin product
um with with as a interacting in it now
with your cold pressed neem oils
you're only going to have a few hundred
to maybe a few thousand parts per
million astero actin so your main mode
of action really with a cold pressed is
going to be the Neema oil it is
basically more of a neem oil than it is
an acid or actin product but you do you
will have some of those still in there
and potentially get a little bit of
additional benefit than a pure
neem oil product because those those
Tetra terpenes haven't been removed and
one other thing from Suzanne it was that
beneficial insects you may need to wait
to do a release with some of these more
uh pungent oils because the beneficials
may not want to uh colonize or infect on
the leaf surface as compared to like a
horticultural oil so I just want to
throw that in for folks because that's
something
Suzanne has shared research on in the
past yeah so your essential oils and
your neem oil products or anything that
has a lot of fragrance to it or may have
a mode of action associated with
repellency
not only may it repel the insects that
you don't want but it may also repel the
beneficial insects now
um
those benefits those those effects are
typically fairly short-lived so
um maybe a little bit longer than what
you can smell because insects are very
sensitive to the odors and so on the
leaf surface level you may have
additional
um
odor and repellency then what you can
detect
but I would say that
um if you're planning a timing is
everything with making spray
applications of biopesticides and using
beneficial insects so it in it's
important that as you plan out your
program
um and if you are wanting to if you see
an increase in the number of insects
that you want to maybe Target with the
spray and you want to use a neem oil or
a 25 B product and you're using
beneficials as well and you don't want
to kill those beneficials typically the
best timing would be before your next
release
so that and I would for your neem oils
for 25 bees I would leave a good I would
say at least three day buffer maybe
longer three to five day buffer before
you you make your next release just to
ensure that you're not killing off those
beneficials that you're releasing which
you don't want to do is release and then
do a spray because even a water spray
can kill a beneficial so just being very
cognizant of the timing of your
applications of both your bio pesticides
and your natural enemies is going to be
really important and that's the best way
to develop these programs to ensure that
you get the best bang for your buck both
bio pesticide and natural enemy
what are the risks associated with
azador actin products I know
um they're harmful to Aquatic
Aquatic Life marine life so you don't
want to use them around water are there
any other are they the mode of action
with them is a is are there a neural
disruptor
they are mainly as a direct and huh
anti-fedient what yeah there's
anti-fedient and repellency properties
those are typically dose dependent and
short-lived so typically
um as we just mentioned with the natural
enemies
the higher the dose the longer the
response may be and that typically is
only going to last a couple of days at
most
so the other mode of action specifically
with acid directin is that it's an
insect growth regulator which means
they're mainly targeting juvenile
insects and
those
um
those juvenile insects are
um your target so you want to make sure
that juvenile insects are there at the
time of application and that you're not
targeting your adults because adults
will not be impacted or much less so
um
I went off on a tangent what was the
original question uh any risks
associated with azador acting thank you
um so
um
mode of action is insect growth
regulator so
um
I'm sorry you can come back to it
yeah ask another question because I um
or ask the same question again just so I
can just as interacting products what
are the are there risks associated with
them
as opposed to like using neem oil or
Seth oil or some of these other uh
pesticides
so nemes neem and Azure actin products
are a safe
really low mammalian toxicity as Tad
mentioned if you apply any product that
is oil based to water it's going to
create an oil slick so it's going to be
toxic to fish also invertebrate
um uh insects in the water will be
harmed by the asterect and
so that's a concern if you directly
spray the beneficials there may be some
impact
just because it's a spray if the if your
beneficial insect sips from the plant
there could be some
impact to the more impact to those
insects than the insects that purely
just eat insects as a food source some
beneficials will sip from the plant
um
so there could be a little bit of more
impact for those but for the most part
most beneficials are not harmed by as
direct and if it is
um
if it is a neem oil though of course
there's that Suffocation factor and or
formulated in an oil there is a
Suffocation Factor so once again you
want to try to minimize as much as
possible contact with your natural
enemies to avoid that risk
um
great well I think we covered quite a
bit
um so I really appreciate it thank you
for for doing that today thank you Chad
I appreciate it