all right so I'm at one of the big box
stores today and I always like to look
at plants and I'm doing that and these
are showing a classic nitrogen
deficiency they're yellowing from the
bottom up they have pale green growth
and at this point I think it's probably
I don't know the how these plants are
match one they're they're a little dry
right now uh but my guess is when they
are watered they're probably over
watered and they may have leeched the
nutrients out or they just might have
ran out of nutrients pot it's a pretty
small pot so what I would want to do in
a case like this is apply something like
a fish hydrolate um compost tea or
compost extract even some Le shap from
your compost bin which would all be
organic options to get nutrients in
there right away and get some available
nitrogen I wouldn't
do something like fish meal or fish bow
meals just going take too long all those
dry
AMS and here's some larger ones and you
can see here these These Are A much
darker green and they actually have
release fertilizer and there little
green dots that's probably the
difference why these look good and these
are also not organic so they're able to
do that um if anything I think these are
maybe a little heavy in nitrogen but you
can't really see that um color coming
through it slightly downward facing
leaves um is usually a side that too
much nitrogen and they're very dark
green aware other