all right I'm here with Charles with emo
and one of the questions I've been asked
a lot about the product rout that's used
for propagation is can I use it in a
cloner uh can you go ahead and answer
that for us please yeah absolutely dad U
so the short answer is yes absolutely
you can use root um in a cloner um you
do want to of course make sure that you
are um introducing root in a way that is
going to uh give the microbes some time
to um form the symbiotic relationship
with the plan and and really be
introduced in a way that sets them up
for Success so um we do recommend
dipping in root um before putting into
the cloner um not adding root into the
res um some Growers like to actually
leave their cuting in root um for you
know a a few minutes before putting them
into the cloner um as I said before I
kind of really give the the microbes a
chance to to get involved get that gel
um nice and you know coated on the end
of The Cutting uh I think you know the
reason that people tend to wonder about
the the um introduction of of root in
the cloner is um thinking that it's
going to wash away uh as soon as the the
cuting are put into the cloner and so
again one way
to just kind of balance that out is to
uh do the dip before putting them in and
uh potentially leaving leaving the
cuting in uh a cup with roots uh for a
couple minutes before putting them in
your
cloner and then I assume Clean cleaning
the cloner really well at the end of the
cycle to avoid any bofilm buildup
absolutely absolutely always want to you
know make sure you're you're doing uh
those sorts of best practices to to
clean clean the cloner um
uh of course you're you're introducing
beneficials with root and you want to do
that in in a way that's going to create
the most benefit for your plant uh but
then to make sure you're kind of uh
doing a thorough clean in between runs
uh so you don't have anything hanging
around
there and for Growers that are using uh
some sort of product for sterilization
like bleach zerol hyen peroxide based
things um how how should how would you
best incorporate something like that
into using a product like
root yeah absolutely so of course
understand a lot of Growers you know
want to make sure they're taking as many
precautions as possible to um you know
reduce pathogen risk in their cloning
operation and you can absolutely use
those sterilization products in
combination with with root but the key
thing is that it's it's not a direct
combination right because those um those
products of course are designed to kill
microbes and so they will interfere with
root if you mix them directly together
um so if you're using a sterilization
product we would recommend having a
water dip step between you know taking
something out of your cup of of hydrogen
peroxide and going into root again
before you you make that transition you
want to take it out of your cup of of
hydrogen peroxide or wherever whatever
sterilization product you might be using
dunk it in water and then put it into
root um so you're not getting that
sterilization product directly into um
root do you have any tips or tricks
regarding mixing root because we when we
receive it I realize it's going to be a
powder um how do we how do we best make
it into a gel for utilizing U with our
plants with our cuting yeah absolutely
and as as you know Tad we we put the
microbes in powder form because that's
the best way to keep them um stable uh
and and uh avoid anything uh damaging
the microbial consortia in transit um
but of course that means also waking the
microbes back up mixing that powder with
water um to turn turn root into the gel
that you ultimately want to
use couple things I would recommend
there um one is that if you notice you
know any kind of clumpiness in the
powder um when you open up the pouch uh
we would recommend you know seeing what
you can do to kind of break up the
chunks before you mix it in with water
um I'd also mention that water excuse me
warmer water um is easier for that
mixing you don't want to use hot water
right really hot water like boiling
water will will um damage the microbes
but warmer water will help the gel to
dissolve a little bit more easily um and
we're actually finding that um it looks
like the the mixing process is a little
easier if you uh pour the powder into um
the glass that we include uh to kind of
mix things up first and then add water
to the filthy here line as opposed to
filling up your glass jar and then
adding the the uh microbes to the
water and just one one one quick
addition to that um it the uh sometimes
you will still see a little bit of
clumpiness um when that gel is forming
but even the bigger clumps will will
ultimately um get incorporated into the
solution is is what we see and what we
hear from Growers um so sometimes just a
little bit more time um and you'll end
up with that nice gel consistency that
that we
expect and just from my experience with
compost teas and microbes I assume it
it's perfectly okay to shake the glass
jar pretty vigorously to get good mixing
yes 100% um good thorough Shake is is
definitely uh the way to
go all right cool anything else you
wanted to cover
today no you know I just say again I
appreciate the the questions that we've
been getting around root um you know
glad that there's a lot of excitement
around a you know microbial alternative
uh for for uh cloning and um don't
hesitate to to reach out to us um you
know through through kiss or or through
our Instagram as well um at
amo.com