last night
so sorry click yeah no problem so we had
our first snowfall last night but that
doesn't change the topic of of what I'm
going to speak about uh what I want to
present to you is the updated soil food
web uh this is a uh uh a a talk that
basically goes through the science
behind organic gardening and at the end
of an hour you're going to know
everything you need to know uh to be a
fabulous organic Gardener and reasons
why you would not want to be uh a
chemical Gardener but in any case I call
it the updated soil food web um let's
see if I can get this to
work H with all the practice we had in
co uh I guess I got to put play yeah
yeah that might make some
sense all right there we go now I have
to do an adjustment h crazy um I don't
know if you can see that uh I I am the
author of uh let me just get this I'm
sorry about this
folks again with all the practice we had
during coid you'd think once it's over
we'd get it right okay so um I am the
author of uh uh the teaming with
microbes series uh and as a result I had
a Trilogy uh and I called myself Lord of
The Roots because I thought that was
kind of funny uh um and then uh these
are the the books in the trilogy GE is
doing it again
uh I can fix
that sorry folks so the trilogy it turns
out uh was not enough because we did
have coid and I had nothing else to do
so I wrote a a a fourth book uh and now
I have a
quadrilogy um and the the books
basically deal with the fact that plants
produce exudates things that drip out of
the root system uh by using their
photosynthetic energy and by putting
together the nutrients that it obtains
from the soil and these are the exudates
a great picture of the exudates and
these exudates attract
microbes and these microbes uh are what
run our Gardening System now you know I
could talk about it using this slide but
it's a little ununderstandable so let me
let me go this way uh make it a little
bit more understandable about 50% or so
of the photosynthetic energy of a plant
is used to produce things that drip out
of the roots you're sweating your sweat
is the exact same thing it's an exudate
these exudates drip out of the roots and
they're designed by the plant to to
attract bacteria and fungi because the
bacteria and fungi don't uh produce prod
their own carbon they love these
exudates because these exudates are full
of carbon so they're they're right there
next to the roots in what's known as the
rizosphere and they're eating away
having a great time and then Along Comes
their predators nematodes and protozoa
and the nematodes and protozoa eat the
fungi and the bacteria because they also
need carbon and there is carbon
contained now in those fungi and
bacteria as a result of eating the
exudates uh and the Nemos and protozoa
devour these fungi and bacteria uh and
then they excrete the excess that they
don't need and what they excrete turns
out to be uh plant usable nutrients they
break down the fungi and bacteria into
nutrients that are usable by the plant
they actually have an electrical charge
put on them so that they can go into the
the plant and that's that's basically
the soil food web uh that we that we
learned in 2006 it was popularized by uh
a woman named Dr elen Ingam uh but even
that's a little too confusing uh so let
me let me let me show it this way and
then then of course you've got the the
the little guys the Nemos and the
protozoa get eaten by bigger guys all
the way on up the chain um so let's
let's look at it this way a bunch of
trees it's a Friday afternoon this is
Fox Island uh and these trees are
sitting around talking to each other uh
through the worldwide web and one of
them says let's have some Japanese food
tonight and and a little one says we did
that last week let's have some Mexican
and the third one says no no let's have
French but the big tree wins and so
they're going to have Japanese food uh
these are the roots of those trees let
me put them in root position and and all
that they have to do in order to get the
Japanese food is produce an exudate that
they drip out into the into the soil
right there in the RIS spere and they
attract the Japanese fungi and bacteria
that they that they are going for now if
one of the plants had said American food
and and and they decided to have
American food they would change the
exudate the plants are capable of
changing the exudates uh and dripping
them out and attracting American food so
they can change the exudates in order to
obtain nutrients and results that they
need this is this is an amazing thing
because we look at plants they can't
walk they can't run away uh they can't
gather things but they can uh produce
these exudates which do all sorts of
things uh for the plant right there in
the soil so this is the soil food web uh
that we learned back in the very early
days this is the basis of teeming with
microbes my first book which has been
translated now into 10 languages not
because it's a great book but because
this is how the we we we learned that
the plant feeds itself not through
Miracle Grow you know not through Peters
uh but through their own natural system
and it it got the name micro mediated
solulab isation of soil
nutrients 2006 so this is teeming with
with bacteria and it's again a very
simple system the little guys get eaten
by the bigger guys uh and there's all
sorts of of of consumption and Decay and
you end up getting nutrients uh which go
into the soil and go into the plants
it's a very simple system all right so
then uh several years later uh it became
very clear that we needed to amend that
view because there was something else
going on involving those fungi so it was
called micro risal fungi SYM symbiosis
now you remember those bacteria and
those fungi that that are attracted by
those exudates well some of the fungi
don't get eaten instead they get called
by the plant the plant sends out a
signal and they enter into the plant and
they move between the cells of the plant
and they transfer nutrients which they
obtain from the soil uh into the plant
in return for the exudates that they get
so this is a picture of micro risal
fungi entering into a uh a root and
getting in in into the insides uh and
it's just a it's just a a fascinating
thing and it turns out that about uh 90%
of plants form this symbiotic
relationship and we've known about it
since the
1890s uh but we were never able to
really duplicate the fungi and so it had
no commercial application and if there's
no commercial application scientific
research often slows down to to a
standstill um this is a picture of a of
of one of the seven different kinds this
is an important kind that Associates
with your trees and around all your tree
roots are these hyle sheets these fungal
hyle sheets and then some of these
fungal go inside and they and they form
uh structures in between the plant root
cells uh and and they're very elegant
now they've been very studied uh there
are some 300 or so different kinds we're
capable of making eight to 16 of them I
don't I can't remember what the exact
number is but they they sleep around and
so one particular type of Micro risal
fungi will will infect and that's the
right word uh many different kinds of
plants this is the kind that uh does the
again the trees uh and then uh this is
sort of a depiction of what what is
really going on you have all of these
wonderful small micro risal fungi that
are able to go out into the soil in an
area where the uh plant root itself
can't reach because it's too big and
they collect phosphorus and water uh
these are the things that they bring
back and they bring it back to the plant
and the plant says thank you very much
here's some exate go back and get me
more and they have this wonderful uh
symbiotic
relationship uh and and it's a good
thing they do because again the the root
itself goes into the soil uh but it it
forms a depletion Zone uh and and so by
having these micro risal fungi go out
into the into the soil it extends the
reach of the root itself uh which is an
important thing obviously because you
don't want plants growing in the
depletion Zone because there only other
choice is to just simply grow Down
Deeper uh and and leaving all these
great nutrients there all right so this
is how a micral fungi Works in if you
don't have a telescope to watch it so
you've got a bunch of seedlings two of
them sitting out in the sun again Fox
Island uh and one of them says GE I
would really like a baloney sandwich and
so uh what does it do well it mixes up
uh the right exad dates it puts those
exudates out into the soil and it
attracts the kind of fungi that it needs
to make a baloney sandwich which it does
and it delivers it to the seedling the
seedling now has established this
relationship the relationship continues
and the seedling grows as a result of
the work that the micro risal fungi is
doing in return for getting those
exudates so this is a very important uh
addition to the basic 2006 soil food web
picture uh and uh these these micro
risal fungi do some really fun things uh
they can they can associate with an
individual plant or they can associate
with more than one plant and form that
web uh it's not quite the it's not quite
the worldwide web that that been
described in the news but you do get
sharing between uh individual micro
risal fungi and and different
plants all right so that was about 2010
that was called micro risal fund
fungal
symbiosis uh and then we started to
learn about something known as endic
bacterial Sy symbiosis and this is the
basis of my uh uh fourth book uh this
would be the second book I would read
incidentally after teaming with microbes
if you were reading the series because
it's such an important new addition to
the way the soil food web works so let's
let's get into that uh it's called endid
meaning inside Endo fidic plant inside
the plant bacterial
symbiosis uh and it features something
known as risasi root eating uh a
discovery that was made back in 2010 in
Australia by a bunch of scientists
working at the University uh Southern
University I think it was and uh what
they discovered was was uh that there
were bacteria just inside plant roots
which they thought occurred as a result
of plant root cells engulfing these
bacteria uh and they called that Riso
fagi and unfortunately they ran out of
they called it Riso Fiji or something of
that sort because they had an Australian
accent but uh I call it Riso fagi uh and
and unfortunately they ran out of
funding and so the whole concept just
sort of languished until uh 20
2018 uh when uh scientists at at ruter
University picked up this discovery and
and using new kinds of microscopes
really figured out what was going on and
it is a Whopper uh so let's let's go
into it so again some of those fungi
don't get eaten they form the micro
risal fungus that are attracted by the
exudates and some of those bacteria they
also uh don't get eaten uh they form uh
what's known as the resid fezy cycle um
so I want to first point out that
bacteria incredibly small this is the uh
uh proverbial uh
pin and there are the bacteria on the
tip of the pin uh so they're incredibly
small they're everywhere they multiply
every 20 minutes uh they're fascinating
uh and we don't we don't really study
enough we study dinosaurs we don't study
things like microbes that are important
um but but these are really incredible
so I want you to keep this picture in
mind as we go through some of these next
next slides uh so the bacteria are
attracted by that exudate and here are
some bacteria Bunches of bacteria that
are attracted to the root tip of a of a
plant uh and they're they're there and
they're devouring up uh the the days now
a lot of these are going to get eaten by
nematodes uh and and protozoa but but
this is before that that has
occurred and what happens is uh uh they
form a bacterial slime when you have a
bunch of bacteria they they form a slime
in order to be able to hide from their
predators and in order to be able to
trap food sources and so uh that's why
you brush your teeth in the morning they
have a slime on it you have to use
energy in order to remove that slime and
it's a real protective layer these
certain bacteria these rasop fagi
bacteria are living in the slime with a
bunch of other bacteria some of which
are going to get eaten and they smell
something very familiar they smell a
popcorn smell uh and this popcorn smell
indicates to them that there is a empty
slime facility right next door and they
should go live there because there won't
be so much competition and so they move
into that new slime area attracted by
this smell only uh if there isn't a
slime area what they end up doing is
breaking through these very thin walls
at the tip of roots very very thin walls
and they break through it thinking
they're going into a new slime colony
and they break through these cell walls
and they end up in a particular spot in
the cell that's known as the par plasmic
space now I'm throwing a lot of science
at you so again I try to make it easy
the
parasmo this is the guts of the cell and
there's this little area around here the
easiest thing to think of is tofu this
is the cell wall this is the guts of the
cell and there's the water all the way
around there that's the
these bacteria back through they smell
that popcorn smell they're attracted
Again by the plant itself just like the
micro risal fungi are and they back into
this periplasmic space where they find
themselves and in the perlas space they
can they live and they multiply because
every 20 minutes they multiply so after
20 minutes of being in there they're
doubling their numbers and they're
cycled there's a little cyclosis going
around inside the cell that moves moves
stuff around uh and this moves as well
and so here you can see uh here's
another picture different kind of
bacteria different kind of plant cell
but these are those uh um endic Riso
ryop fagy bacteria all right so they're
inside there and when they get in there
the plant goes H I don't really I I got
to be careful I don't want these guys to
take over and kill me and so the plant
sprays the bacteria with something known
as a Ross a reactive oxygen series um
Ross is quite simply uh what causes
sunburn when you get sunburned it's
because your cells are producing uh a
Ross to protect themselves from the UV
rays well they produce a Ross to protect
themselves from these bacteria and in
fact I even found a Ross with a sunburn
just so that we could tie everything
together all right anyway uh they this
Ross has the effect of stripping off the
bacteria's cell wall and so the bacteria
end up without cell walls and the plant
cell absorbs the nutrients that were the
bacterial cell wall and use them to grow
which is a pretty amazing thing now the
bacteria as you can imagine
uh that they don't like to get sprayed
and it's it's it it does a couple of
things it it it stresses them out uh but
by the same token I should add it also
stresses out the plant and if the
plant's not careful and sprays the wrong
or the too higher concentration of Ross
uh it it hurts itself and so by spraying
the Ross on the
bacteria it has to strengthen its own
cell and so the plant becomes stronger
as a result of these bacteria and so
they get this induced stress resistance
which lives throughout the plant for the
rest of the plant's life that makes the
plant stronger now it also turns out
that the bacteria don't like it and so
they do two things the first thing they
do is they produce ethylene ethylene
causes the plant cell it's a phyto
hormone and it causes the plant cell to
stretch and then they also produce
nitrate uh so the ethylene and the
nitrate uh
react and and weaken the
Ross they produce different things that
weaken the Ross so that even though
they've lost their cell walls they're
not going to get killed by uh continued
application so it weakens the Ross uh
and these walless bacteria continue to
cycle in that parap plasmic space and
they continue to multiply as they
produce this stuff the cell is
stretched uh and they take a little bit
of carbon these bacteria uh and and they
they form a cycle uh which is very very
important uh in order for the bacteria
to keep alive and in order for the plant
to keep alive these Cycles form uh and
the cell continues to stretch the
bacteria continue to multiply and they
produce their ethylene and the uh
protection that they produce is actually
nitrous they take nitrogen from the air
now they're inside the plant and they
fix that
nitrogen uh to to form nitrix oxide uh
which also weakens the Ross and so they
got this ethylene and this nitrious
oxide weakening the Ross what they're
doing is they're fixing nitrogen in
inside the plant cell just like risia
bacteria do uh but this is completely
different this is inside the plant cell
and it turns out that if the razif fasy
Cycle's going on up to
40% of the nitrogen that a plant uses
I'm going to repeat that 40% of the
nitrogen that a plant uses comes from
this internal nitrogen fixation which we
had no idea was going on before 2018 so
if you haven't ever heard of this before
it's because no one has in fact I would
say you're probably you're
probably a group of uh 4,000 people who
may know about Raz of fagi but
everybody's going to learn about it so
what you've got again this is the
depiction this is the parap plasmic
space the bacteria are moving around and
they're being cycled around and inside
uh the from the par space is a membrane
and all the goodies that are inside uh
the chloroplast and all that kind of
stuff so but we're interested in this
area right here and you continue to get
growth as they are as these bacteria are
cycled around
multiplying uh and again they're very
very very small uh and they they
multiply and they begin to form
structures like this this is a
multiplied walless bacteria um and
they're they're all throughout the thing
and then they to form like this they
begin to to conglomerate you get more
and more of them because you continue to
get this multiplication and they begin
to clog up the the pathway so to speak
uh and and back up against the the the
wall of the cell uh and when they back
up against the wall of the cell the
ethylene concentrates against that wall
and forms a
tube and these are the tubes that are
they're being formed off of the main
cell of a of a root
tip if you look carefully here you can
see this is this is with the tube see
the tube being formed and it's just it's
there you see a little bit of the tube
here it's not a brand new cell it's part
of this cell right here it's this little
hair that grows out of the root wait a
minute it is it's a root here
so here's a shocker folks every single
root hair you've ever seen has bacteria
in it why do I know that because the
bacteria are what cause root hairs we
were all brought up to believe that root
hairs grow so that the plant can get
nutrients they go out into the soil blah
blah blah well that's not true they grow
because they're putting these bacteria
into them they're getting bacteria
filled uh they happen to be very thin
walled and I did a tremendous amount of
study again because it was Co and
because I I had the ability to be able
to do it these are very thin wall
structures and they open up and so
there's no wonder that if you read
teeming with nutrients one of the other
books I wrote which talks about how
plants take nutrients in the nutrients
are able to move through these
incredibly thin walls and so they do
take up nutrients but they are formed by
bacteria for a completely different
purpose because what happens is they
continue to multiply as they move into
these cells so they're in the cells and
they begin to multiply and they get
glomerate up at the tip and this blue
indicates that there's nitrogen being
produced uh from these little guys
that's the dye and then all of a sudden
they are blown out of the tip of that
growing tube which we call a root
hair and they go back out into the soil
and here they are conglomerating in the
in the tip and boom out they go and here
they are blown out into the soil these
are walless bacteria so are these uh and
and they grow back their cell wall and
in two or three days they move back into
a new root cell and form new root hairs
and it doesn't happen just once as that
root hair grows you get explosion after
explosion after explosion and and then
they go back into the soil and they grow
back their cell wall this is this is
completely amazing stuff to most people
they work they eat they travel they
repeat they go back is in an incredible
system it's now called the Razzo fasi
cycle it has been observed obviously uh
in many different ways if you remove the
bacteria you do not get root hairs wow
unbelievable uh so what we used to think
is that is that the the plant by
producing the exudates and putting the
exudates out into the soil was sort of
farming uh you know and then and then it
would it would Gather in in the fall it
would bring in all the nutrients uh and
and and that was it but we what we're
learning is they also are hurting uh so
they're ranchers as well as farmers and
they go out and they bring these
bacteria in they Shear off the walls uh
they eat a an occasional leg of lamb uh
and and then they put them back out into
the paddock to grow back the wool again
uh it's absolutely an unbelievable thing
it's known as Razo fagi you may not have
ever heard of it you will hear lots
about it because it turns out that it's
a very useful research tool and
potentially an unbelievable substitute
for actual chemical fertilizers so
that's what the world's been looking for
for a long time now those razazi
bacteria that move in are Endo fidic
bacteria and as these roots begin to
grow you end up with little cracks in
the main root itself and because
bacteria are everywhere and because
bacteria are always looking for an
advantage over other bacteria so that
they can go to a place where they can
breed without predators and where they
can eat without competition these there
was a bunch of bacteria uh that would
have been eaten perhaps by uh nitos and
protozoa that sneak in the cracks that
form when these root hairs form as well
and so they sneak in they're very very
small and then they're capable of moving
throughout the plant in the phome or the
xylem uh and even in the a aop
apoplastic Pathways in between cells and
so you end up with endic bacteria
throughout the roof root and they move
into the plant itself some move in
through stomata but most of them come in
through the root
system uh and some of them end up in the
flour and as the flow is forming seeds
they get trapped in the seed and they're
inside the seed so that when the seed is
planted in new
soil the seed brings with it the kinds
of
bacteria that it needs in order to grow
properly again an unbelievable Discovery
uh there are corn plants uh species that
are 400 years old and if you plant one
today it has the same bacterial mix or
very close bacterial mix to what it had
400 years ago because it carries its
seeds this is this is probably where
trir comes from not the soil but the
microbes that are that are in the plant
that come from the soil and get passed
on uh it's it's an amazing amazing thing
while we're studying and so you get you
get the bacteria they get trapped uh
when the plant germinates the bacteria
move into the soil uh as some of them
end up as Riso fazzy bacteria some of
them end up as endophilic bacteria uh
and it's a beautiful beautiful system um
these bacteria these endophytic bacteria
are capable of producing hormones and so
they produce uh the key hormones that
you need for plant growth now the plants
obviously can produce these as well but
when they get assisted by uh these uh
bacteria it's a it's a wonderful thing
and and why would a bacteria do this it
would produce these things inside a
plant because it's it's tricking the
plant into allowing it to live inside
the plant so it's the plant says oh yeah
I get some oxin out of this well gee I
get some ethylene out of this uh and
I'll let these guys stay here uh you
know and the bacteria gets to live
without the competition it gets a a
source of food without competition and
everybody lives happily ever after um so
you end up with uh all sorts of things
as a result of these bacteria the stress
that's created uh causes some wonderful
things to happen uh this induced
systemic resistance but you also get all
of these things uh occurring as well as
a result of these bacteria moving in and
I might add some some fungus
particularly yeasts do the same thing
they're not micro risal they act like
these bacteria and and they they go
through an endophytic uh phase of their
life um and these endophytic bacteria
help plants to deal with abiotic stress
they can they can lower the freezing
point of water or raise the freezing
point of water excuse me uh they can
help a plant deal with salt uh with
flooding uh with drought they can they
can help plants deal with with pathogens
that are attacking them uh the the the
plant can selectively allow in a
bacteria that's able to take out uh some
of its pathogens it's it's a it's a
wonderful terrific uh uh uh defense
system if you can get the bacteria to do
your fighting for you you all you give
up is a little bit of space and maybe a
little bit of
carbon some of these some of these uh
bacteria are capable of doing things
like cleating iron and so uh they'll
enter into a plant root they'll live
inside the plant and when the plant is
is either got too much iron or doesn't
have enough iron uh they can hop out
into the soil where they can gather up
all the iron together or arsonate
together so that it doesn't go in and
poison the plant uh so they they do all
sorts of uh wonderful things um there
are Tad and I were talking just the
beginnings of endophytic bacteria that
are that are producible and are
available these top ones up here are are
are things that you can get uh at uh
cannabis grow Stores um they're
beginning to be use them this one fixes
nitrogen uh there's different kinds
depending on what areas you are you you
live in there's one from Brazil and
Russia etc etc this one is one that
people are beginning to look at uh the
these can be stored relatively easy this
requires freeze drying so that people
are trying to figure out how to use
these things but what big industry has
discovered is that that it's possible to
find and to isolate endophilic bacteria
that do things to your plant that you
need them to do so for example if you're
growing a tomato and you you end up with
powdery mildew all the time on that uh
if I if if research has it proper
they're going to find the right
bacterium to to put into the soil so
that it goes into the plant and fights
off that uh powdery Milo so that you
don't end up getting that problem
they're not doing it for me and you
they're doing it for the big guys but
it'll it'll it'll come down to our level
no question about it and these three
are already on or getting close to our
level uh just as ryia bacteria have come
down to our level you can find risia
bacteria nitrogen fixing bacteria
wherever you you buy legumes as a
inoculant for your your peas and and
other legumes um so the really obvious
takeaway plants really are in control
whether you whether you go by the
original soil food web or you move all
the way through to the modern view of
the soil food web which includes the
razif fagi they're in control and we
like to think we're in control but when
we think that we end up taking actions
that are not necessarily in the soil
food web's best interest we interfere
with the way the soil food web works and
we end up having to do a lot of work
ourselves as a result of uh taking away
the ability of these invisible microbes
to do the work for us so plants are
definitely in control uh and and they're
amazing uh which is really the most
amazing uh takeaway they they do things
we we just completely had no idea that
they were doing we keep getting better
and better at microscopy and as a and
and staining and as a result we're
beginning to see what plants can
actually do uh this is where I usually
pop in and say we've got to stop
teaching our kids about dinosaurs
useless we need to start teaching our
kids about microbes because they impact
everything we do um and they're
beautiful they're absolutely stunning
and gorgeous and we can make them every
bit as interesting as you know as the
tyrosaurus Rex and all that other kind
of stuff it's amazing to me that a four
or fiveyear old kid knows all the
dinosaurs knows even how to spell some
of these incredibly complicated words I
can't even say and yet has no idea what
a bacteria is um chemicals obviously
have a negative effect uh on endophytic
bacteria they throw things out of
balance uh so you got to be very careful
how you use it um you got to use the
best practices possible all of the
things that that keep a soil food web
alive also help the razoes cycle and
endophytic bacteria uh mulches leaving
leaves alone using compost um uh even
compost teas compost extracts these are
all things that that help the soil food
web are considered to be best practices
no Roto tilling which breaks everything
up uh and destroys the soil food web or
at least uh impacts the soil food web so
that has to rebuild itself and you lose
that time um so all of these things are
important you have to feed the soil the
soil is everything um you can test
things my favorite test these days is
something called a microbiometer yes you
need to have an NPK test every now and
then so you know what your soils have in
it and what they're capable of doing but
but you need to know whether what you're
doing is helping uh the the soil food
web or whether it's hurting it uh go
look at
www microbiometer
docomo test you use your cell phone and
you can tell whether you're increasing
or decreasing the biomass uh you know
the bacterial and fungal biomass if it
increases you're doing good and if it
decreases as a result of what you're
doing you're doing something wrong um
and don't disturb the soil uh prevent
compaction no tilling be careful your
soil is the most valuable thing we have
uh don't sterilize seeds that's a silly
thing to do uh and don't don't
necessarily use sterile soil either uh
those seeds uh contain the bacteria that
your plant needs in order to live when
they germinate you want to have them be
able to to do so use mulches uh they
provide organic material which all of
the soil food we have needs don't Roto
tilt don't toss use soil reuse it it
contains EX Ates it contains bacteria it
contains organic material and compost
compost compost beautiful stuff use it
all the time um make compost out of the
same plant you're growing uh that that
you know it contains a lot of the
goodies uh that your plants used and
would use again um and and uh test your
compost some plants because compost has
different kinds of bacteria in it like
verac compost and some plants like
thermal compost more which ones I don't
know we got to do the research and this
is a you know home scientific experiment
H but you're going to find that your
your broccoli is going to do better in
one kind of compost versus the other
because the bacterial composition is
different and you'll get different Endo
fiic bacteria uh along with the ones
that that come along with the seed uh
that that you're planting um so a not so
obvious takeaways you got to read these
books books folks not because I wrote
them but because this is the science
behind organic gardening and if we've
learned anything it's that we need to be
organic gardeners we have way too much
plastic in our lives we have way too
much plastic in our soils for example we
don't need to add
chemicals we we just have screwed things
up so badly we know it we know it's
caused bad things start with teaming
with microbes move to teaming with back
IIA learn how and then go to endophytic
uh fungi and then learn how the plants
use all of these things to grow if you
do these things you will be a much
better Gardener chemical gardeners are
not good gardeners to learn how to use
the soil food web on the other hand is
how you become the very best guarder you
possibly can be and I say is this the
end probably not there is no question
some other thing is going to be
discovered uh who knew uh in
2017 that you could get 40% of the of
your plant's nitrogen just by simply
making sure that the Razo feezy cycle is
going on no one and so there's got to be
more stuff out there there are people
looking for this stuff all the time uh
if you're taking notes uh write down the
name of Dr Elaine Ingam she is the guru
of the soil food web uh write down the
name of Dr James White he is the
gentleman uh at ruter University who has
really refined the razif fazzy cycle um
and that's it folks I appreciate your
attention and be happy to answer any
questions you
have ah thank you I can't hear you but I
see you're
clapping
oh any questions I can hear you oh okay
where there any questions I can relay
or
one
out plant a row for the hungry oh how do
you find out about plant a row for the
hungry oh I'm glad you asked that um uh
plan R for Hungary is sort of a
self-service uh uh program that the we
we used to be the garden writers of
America we're now the garden Comm Garden
communicators International and if you
go to Garden communicators
international.com uh you'll find a a a
page that talks about plant a row for
the hungry all you have to do is share
food with somebody else uh as a club for
example just to encourage everybody to
plant one row in their Garden The
Gardener takes that food either to a
neighbor that needs it to a church or a
synagogue to a food bank there are
places where you can take food to a
prison uh the prison gathers the food uh
uh we've got hardware stores that gather
food we've got nurseries you know garden
nurseries where you can bring in excess
food they'll take it to the food bank uh
there's no rules to this other than you
plant the row you distribute that row
somehow and and nothing slips between
the lip and the cup there's no money
involved there's no administrative
Services involved this is a peopo people
campaign and it is unbelievable if you
just Google plant a row for the hungry
how many different programs people have
come up with we do it in Canada now as
well uh they're beginning to do it in
England 35 million people go to bed in
North America hungry every single night
or at least not knowing where their next
meal is coming this is such an easy
thing because G share and because most
of us tend to just sort of leave stuff
in the garden you know when the snow
comes for the Moose to eat uh and that's
a stupid thing to
do yeah um would you expand on the value
of cover props that are nitrogen
pictures and how they actually make the
nitrogen available are you able to hear
that Jeff uh not really uh was talk
about nitrogen fix in crops can you
expand on cover crops and how they make
oh cover crops sure yeah well cover
crops are are are mostly legumes uh and
they produce they they produce the
nodules that that you're familiar with
and inside those nodules they produce
nitrogen a little teeny bit of that
nitrogen leaks out into the soil and
it's used by whatever plants would grow
in there but but what what happens is
the the cover crop dies and when it dies
the nitrogen that's in the cover crop
itself particular in the n in the
nodules goes into the soil and is then
usable that's why you can plant a cover
crop in the fall it's producing those
nodules it's producing nitrogen for
itself and then in the spring you you
you you Tamp it over or you or you just
rake it rake it over maybe a little
light tilling uh and that moves that
material into the soil with it with the
dead plant and provides that nitrogen
releases
it clovers are the most common one you
hear out too right right and by the way
I just I've been testing a new Clover
it's called micro Clover it's not really
new uh but it the the new trend uh is is
for people to put in uh not Lawns but
Meadows to turn their lawns into Meadows
and and one of the easiest ways to do
that is to is to add tremendous amounts
of clover this micro Clover is it only
blooms once a year it's beautiful stuff
uh it's worth taking a look at uh but it
pumps in nitrogen like crazy and in
addition to using it on my lawn I've
used it at my tomato plants and I gotta
I gotta tell you uh it makes the most
gorgeous tomato plants I've ever seen
this mound of beautiful Clover and then
after I I harvest the tomatoes like I'm
going to kill it so next year they're
going to get the benefit of this
nitrogen um how do you suggest using
compost if we're not tilling just as a
top dress yes um the compost and you
really don't need very much an eighth of
an inch uh is is enough uh an inch is
wow a tremendous amount if you put it on
top of the soil uh it the microbes in it
has as well as the rain Etc uh work it
work the microbes down into the soil
down into into the growing zone and
couple two three four or five months um
so yeah just put it right on the surface
um it has a in places like Anchorage and
I you know you get a little bit of cold
weather um it acts as a little bit of an
insulation layer we we like to put the
compost down and then put leaves on top
of it as mulch uh so that it holds the
temperature in the soil uh to to 29 to
30 degrees in our Frost Zone um and it
and it and it just it it raises the
frost zone so that we don't get quite as
deep of frust Etc I love compost it's
great stuff and Tad makes some very good
compost by the
way if I can follow up on that I've also
read studies though that are showing
that we're getting too much organic
material in a lot of our garden soils
because of all the comes we have yeah
I've read some of those those too uh you
know I'm not it's hard for me to let me
put it this way most most soils most
regular soils has about one one to two%
organic matter really good
organic garden bed might have up to 5%
organic matter um you know can you have
too much organic matter I suppose you
could if you weren't getting soil
structure you know if you if it was
replacing individual but it's hard for
me to to see that I mean I can see how
how maybe if you use uh manure in your
compost you may end up with too much uh
you know
phosphorus
um or too much potassium that would be
probably a more thing but yeah I don't I
don't buy into it
frankly thank you that doesn't mean I'm
right but I just don't buy into it I I
put as much compost down as I've grown
in in directly in compost uh i' i' I had
organic matter all the time I never rake
a leaf uh unless it's for putting down
on the garden I grow potatoes in just
leaves which is all organic matter they
do just fine so yeah I have a hard time
but again these are scientific papers
people Linda Chalker Scott Etc you know
they write these things and there's got
to be some validity to it but but I I
haven't had that
problem
yeah I saw a picture of red worms and
I've never fully used to Advantage the
um castings that I generated in my worm
bin what's what's a good way to
distribute that
stuff and what is the value of the worm
casting as far as who's living in can
you hear that yeah so in other words how
do you collect the worm castings and and
and what do you use them on no how do I
best use them I've got masses of them
she's got a lot but how do you how do
you best utilize them and what's the
value of them right well I use them in
two different ways we we also keep worms
in fact now that we see the snow I'm
gonna have to move it inside um you can
use them in in by putting them in liquid
um and and sort of making a worm compost
extract and using using that liquid on
Plants um I don't know I don't know
really why I do that but sometimes I
do otherwise I I put it right on my
plants now you got to be careful because
they will contain you know little worm
cast little eggs um and so uh you got to
make sure you got the right worms you
don't want that new worm that's moving
in that does the fast squiggly Wiggly um
I'm not a particularly big fan of of
adding night crawlers if you don't
already have night crawlers in there
um the red wigglers see seem to be safe
uh but but I sometimes I wonder whether
we're really you know doing the right
thing by using them uh but but using the
castings themselves does make a lot of
sense uh they contain a concentration of
the nutrients that is higher than what
went into the worms so it's I don't
remember exactly what the numbers are
it's x amount of times more phosphorus x
amount of times more nitrogen x amount
it's got higher concentrations of the
nutrients that you want for your plants
and that's why it's so
good there there is research on uh
adding worm castings to potting soils
for example and they found up to like uh
I think 15% by volume and again this
depends on the quality of castings and
things like that but they actually got
increased biomass production growth
disease protection um so the wor
castings have a lot of benefits in in
soils in general yeah yeah yeah and I
would think they you know because they
contain so many nutrients they raise the
bricks the bricks of the plant and if
the bricks of the plant is over nine or
10 uh you don't get insects anymore so
yeah it's it's great stuff it's it's
every bit as good as compost it's just
con one's thermal and and one's
biological so there's a different mix of
bacteria in
them any other
questions okay all right well thanks
Jeff we we let you go then but I really
apprciate my pleasure my pleasure
anybody has any questions let me know
and I always tell people if you buy
teaming with microbes and now I'm going
to add in teaming with bacteria and you
don't like it I'll buy it back at three
times the price because I think it's
that important that you read it and if
you want to read in French or German or
Slovakian or Turkish Portuguese or
Spanish we can arrange to get you that
copy
so and audible now huh oh yeah it's on
Audible it's on discs is the same person
that read John Stewart's book reads
mine oh
cool all right thank you very much folks
what a great audience thank
you