so today I'd like to talk about soil
testing now soil testing is very
important so we know what sort of
fertility exists in our bed sure we
could go with a generalized fertilizer
recommendation or guess based on uh what
our plants look like and what sort of
symptoms or deficiencies they're
displaying but if we really want to dial
in our fertility and know exactly what
levels of nitrates phosphorus potassium
calcium magnesium all of these things
are in our soil then we have to do a
soil test it will also tell us pH uh our
the EC of our soil and a bunch of really
useful metrics for dialing in our soil
for our next cycle of
plants okay so the very first step would
be to go onto the website at kis
organics.com you're going to click on
the amend Tab and then go down there
until you see the soil testing and
consultations so on that page we have a
list of options of various types of
tests that we offer all of these tests
are through Logan labs and the price on
our website is going to be exact same
price as through Logan directly so if
you can order through us it does help
support us now we offer everything from
the complete soil test with an analysis
all the way through to checking your
irrigation water for suitability uh
tissue testing and then final finally a
standalone analysis if you have a soil
test from another lab or if you have a
Logan test that you got independently we
do charge a little bit more for the
analysis if you don't order the soil
testing through us so if you plan on
doing both then the best op option is
this very first complete soil test so
you just add it to your cart go ahead
and check out as you would normally and
then what will happen next is you'll
receive an email from us typically the
same day or the next business day at the
latest and it'll come from orders at
kiss organics.com so be sure to check
your spam folder and on that you'll see
you'll get an attachment that will
already be filled out you'll just put in
the sample ID in this case we use Garden
one and then we also have the
instructions as well as how to fill out
the submission worksheet and how to take
the sample that you'll receive digitally
as well so let's talk about what tools
you need for a soil test now you will
need a plastic Ziploc bag that you can
ride on and tape you'll need gloves
because the moisture from your fingers
can impart sodium and other minerals
that can affect the results of your soil
test and you'll want either a stainless
steel Trel or your hand just you can use
your hand if it's potting soil like this
which is my reference or a soil probe if
you want to get one of those they're
like $20 or you can make one out of
PVC okay so I just switched to an empty
bed because I thought it would be easier
for this demonstration I've got my
gloves on and I grabbed a clean bowl
that I can mix the samples in so I'm
just reaching down with my hand I'm
pulling out a handful about a 6inch
depth I'm going to do that from multiple
places in the bed so I get a more
homogeneous sample now you can sample
multiple garden beds at the same time
that's definitely an option
you can just mix all the samples
together and get a rough idea of where
your soil is in your garden overall now
if you want to send in multiple samples
you absolutely can too that's definitely
an option but if you're trying to save
money in a lot of cases you can just mix
them together and the samples will be
close enough or give you a pretty good
idea of where your fertility is in your
garden so the next step is to mix the
soil even more thoroughly together just
to make sure that's it's fully
homogenized you can do this regardless
of the size of your sample or how many
samples you take you just want to make
sure to mix it thoroughly prior to
putting it into the Ziploc
bag I'm going to put a generous amount
into the Ziploc bag the lab says they
want at least two cups I always put in
extra it doesn't hurt anything to
include a little extra in your sample
and that will guarantee they have enough
especially if they have to rerun a
test next you want to label the soil
sample to make sure it matches exactly
what's on the submission sheet this is
especially important if you have
multiple samples so that there's no
issues of things getting mixed
up and then the final step is just to
tape up the soil sample uh making sure
to add extra tape right along the Ziploc
seal as well as taping the bag to itself
just to make sure that nothing spills
out during the shipping process I found
the best way to ship these soil samples
if you're just shipping one sample is to
use a USPS Priority Flat Rate envelope
or padded envelope and and then if you
have multiple samples then you could
move up to like a medium flat rate box
unless you're really close to their
location this tends to be the most
affordable way to ship these products
and don't forget to include your
submission sheet along with the soil
sample in the in the envelope or in the
box and you should be good to
go so after the lab receives your test
they will reach out to us with the test
results and the same day that we get the
results we will send them on to you if
you have an analysis as part of your
package that you ordered through kiss
Organics we will also send you that
comprehensive analysis as well uh here's
a sample of an email that you would get
from us they typically come from Brandon
and they include some resources on our
website that you can check out as well
as some additional notes just the high
Lev stuff of what we saw on the test the
test themselves this is the standard
test this would be the mik 3 extraction
this is going to tell us everything
that's in the soil from an acid
extraction action perspective and then
in conjunction for the complete test we
also have this saturated paste report
the saturated paste report tells us
exactly what's available to the plant
right now and so between these two
metrics we're able to make really good
actionable decisions about how to remend
our garden
properly and then once you have your
analysis you can go back to the soul
report analysis page on our website
where we list a bunch of helpful
information like cups to pounds uh
here's an example of what a analysis
will look like though it'll be
customized and the recommendations will
be made for you either in pounds or cups
as to what you need to amend your soil
specifically with uh along with all this
information and this is freely available
on our website even if you don't use us
for soil testing you can still check
this out as a potential resource and
then I also want to mention we have what
we're calling The Usual Suspects and
these are the things that we typically
like to use in our recommendations um
and you can also go on our website and
click on like Target phosphorus Target
calcium whatever Amendment you're
looking for and find um the same sort of
recommendations there um in terms of
products that you can use in your
soil and that's really all there is to
it so please reach out if you have any
questions and we look forward to working
with you you can check this all out on
our website at kis organics.com or reach
us through our contact page you can give
us a call or shoot us an email thank you
very much