hi everyone
my name is lindsay i'm the marketing
manager for core cannabis at the green
organic dutchman
um i just wanted to welcome you uh to
this event we're
really grateful um to the kiss organics
team for
you know co-hosting this with us as well
as for your time
and letting us show you through our
organic greenhouse that it really means
a lot to us
um just a couple of housekeeping items
before i throw it over
to tad and david first all of your
microphones are muted
but that doesn't mean you can't ask us
questions um there is a question
box you'll see at the top right of your
screen or your phone
if you click on that you can post your
question and we really encourage you to
do so i know the guys are really excited
to
take your questions the next thing is
is we ask for your patience so we have
done
all of the work to try to make sure that
the internet is working smoothly through
our greenhouse
but sometimes we do have some
connectivity issues as we move from room
to room
um we ask for your patience this usually
only takes a couple of seconds to get
back up and running
um so we thank you in advance for that
um like i said
we're really excited to get started and
i'm going to send it over to tad now for
a proper introduction
and thank you chad for again joining us
on this tour again we're really excited
to have you here
thanks lindsay my name is tad hussey
like she said i am the owner of kiss
organics and the host of the cannabis
cultivation
and science podcast uh and really
excited to do this tour
i've i've been wanting to see this
facility for a long time
david is an old friend who i met at
cannacon
how many years back when he was working
over at whistler medical
and that's when we first started talking
about uh this concept of living soils
in commercial facilities and really
scaling it and and this is the largest
scale
facility out there as far as i'm aware
of and certainly the only one i know
that's certified organic so really
excited to tour it and see it
uh david has a long background in
agriculture
working uh and getting his degree at
mcgill
he's been working in legal cannabis in
canada now for quite a few years
and uh has been working as with tgot as
their head grower so i'm really excited
to turn this
tour over to david and get this thing
kicked off all right david
uh awesome to finally be able to show
you all of that
uh yeah thanks for setting it all up and
it's looking forward to show you
everything that we already kind of
touched on to but also a bunch of other
things that like uh
you can always see physically here so we
talked about a lot of stuff consensually
but it's nice
to be able to exchange it hopefully your
stuff some great advice for me at the
end of this because that's always what
happened every time we chat so uh
thank you for all i thank you for
everybody uh for joining us uh
like that mentioned uh coming from an
act background like chad a little bit
i've been working in beagle canvas for
over seven years in canada right now
that's not so long but it's still uh
it's still a long time
things have changed so much and uh so
much progress so much exciting project
that's our second one we're doing here
since uh we've been exchanging the qtad
and uh yeah we're looking forward to
showing you all that
um so yeah right now we're in the
gardening area just before we go into
the greenhouse
we're what we call our support building
so we're harvest drying processing
packaging shipping and receiving
a lot of hands so every employees come
in this facility
uh through this hallway and we have to
change
both for a region of ibm also
regulations so different prosthetic
patients have our stuff
uh on the cannabis and uh i'll have more
suspense and also for patients
and users um
so yeah so so so david this is a dual
purpose
concept in the fact that not only are
you is this regulated but it also allows
you to get out of your street clothes
and reduce the amount of pests and
potential pathogens that are coming into
the
okay facility we changed that get sticky
mats from the four
foot steps and some rooms and all that
so yeah because the
the increase of uh hem production and
other cannabis to
uh back east canada stated they're
really
present on outdoors worlds and indoor
growth so that's one of the first line
of effects we have
to make sure we're gonna drive the least
amount possible of stuff
by changing completely and we have a
cleaning service and coming for several
tracks for us
and send them backs and it's both from
the ibm
purpose but also for compliance with the
health canada which is
lifelike us by sending us to produce
legal cannabis in canada for medical and
recreation
so the products and channels are the
same but to whom we sell at the end will
be different so for medical station
we'll ship directly
to their personal address and for
recreational we will
ship to retail conventional wars
and across canada
so yeah we have a lot of staff going on
right now today
we also have a harvest going on in there
uh we're running some uh the
oyster streaming equipment we'll be able
to show you a little bit of everything
okay great david uh there is a request
on the uh
q a that you speak a little bit louder
it's a little bit more background noise
so just
for future questions if you could try
and do that but let's go ahead and move
on
thank you for letting us know awesome
and bear with us a little bit of
connection issues but uh
keep reminding me of that please and
i'll do my best to
repeat or anything so we'll we can take
our time for the tour today guys so uh
make sure that everybody's getting all
the information and
uh views that they want
okay great so now we're just heading
down i believe to the mother room
and uh everyone should be able to
hear us okay and we have talked to david
about speaking a little louder so you
guys should all be hearing that
you may need to turn up the speakers on
your uh
your computer or your phone just
slightly um because there is a little
bit of background noise so
we will do our best here and
um
i hope you guys can hear me all the way
to the greenhouse
we've got several different things that
are happening here today department
there's a lot of cleaning tools
but we're going to go where our clothing
and genetic bank is
[Music]
uh
and just to remind you guys we will get
some freezing on the video as we move
from room to room so we just have to be
patient for the wi-fi to reconnect
there
okay guys i think i think we should be
good for wi-fi now i'll just wait for
your
confirmation class but
we are now in some other room
oh david there was a there was a quick
question someone asked if there was that
was a uv
light on the wall that we walked past i
missed it but when we were in the
hallway do you know what they're
referencing
uh yeah i think those one are just
little uh regular fly hatching like not
necessarily uv but you got the same
light and restaurants and kitchens
it's just to attract a little bug that's
may add them there
so it's just a good general sanitation
program on the sunny
on the processing side of the village so
it's not necessarily for a
specific existing candidate's idea but
it's just good
educational practices
okay the connection here is is okay is
there somewhere else in the room where
it might be slightly better if you move
over or no uh i i think we can
try to go down the aisle a little bit it
might be the room
okay all right
super awesome custom-designed
controlling fence for a large volume of
soil
that's one of the innovations that we
did here that is
you know
[Music]
we'll do our best with that and we'll
move to a different room if it gets too
chubby
every rooms are designed the same way uh
this room is a bit more
quieter than the others but also a bit
smaller because
our mother
so david how many different uh cultivars
do you have approximately
in your mother room i think right now
we're
about 25-ish we're not flowering them
all there's about eight
uh that we are flowering uh and uh
on the rotation there's others that were
test uh flowering there's stuff that we
used to grow and we just keep
one or two plants we have there genetics
uh
gene pool for either breeding or for uh
bringing back later uh but
i know i think we have
one of our cbd hotels here on this side
this is charlotte angel and this is uh
rockstar tuna
uh okay great and then
you mentioned uh you mentioned the
amount of soil that you have there so
how are you managing the soil in your
mother room for these mother plants
it's pretty much the same thing as we do
before
playing it safe right now we're learning
how to use we've only been growing this
greenhouse since uh
last october so it's not been a fully a
year for
us yet uh so we're learning still but uh
so far that this comes in here for a
year
it's doing very well uh we have a lot of
good rooms as well and even in uh solids
and
older and subdressed several several
times so
for the mother room so far we're going
to keep on our ears for four to
six months we kept them from longer uh
and we replaced them but we kept a few
of the older mom
or a few moms that got really big we
literally cut it down completely to see
how it would regrow
and it's growing growing back very well
and uh
even some of the moms that we remove and
i don't know just give you an example
here if you want to look down in this
there used to be a smaller mother there
and now the
the roots of this mother is a bit older
they're uh
starts colonizing the old triangles this
crop could be good for a tree to form
others
when there is just one of their solar
system
[Music]
and we have a lot of turnover of organic
matters still through a lot of a
composting or a meeting and uh exterior
requires a lot of enzymes it breaks old
organic matter
so the only thing that we really have to
do with our soil here is to
top it up because it kind of shrinks
with all the microbial activity
and so right now we have a cloud that
went above the greenhouse so the light
sensors
i adjusting the setup level that we see
in there so they just went off and went
back
up so it's a bit of a cloudy day today
so far they're rolling over and
indicating that well as a real-time
uh adjustment of the lines you didn't
see no freedom
so so david how about this just because
the connection in this room is not quite
as good
uh can we move on to the next room and
then uh possibly i wanted to ask you
some of these other questions
in the that people have in the other
room where we might have a little better
connection
yeah well we're going to go for that
we're going to go in a room that just
started early i'm going to get the unit
just so i walk through the hallway
because it's a bit noisy and i'm going
to
be back about a minute
so while david's muted here uh for those
of you
if you can still hear me uh i just want
to mention what he was saying there
regarding the
lighting was when the cloud came over
then the lights come
on to add supplemental light to maintain
the par levels at
optimal levels for the plants that
they've set so they can control
all that with the greenhouse lighting
which is which is pretty cool
and i happen to just know that they're
using fluence lighting
uh in the greenhouse i don't know who
the manufacturer is
on those uh rolling benches but david
can answer that when we get to the other
room
as well as the greenhouse manufacturer
so why don't you tackle those two
questions when we get there david
and we'll go from there cool
[Music]
good back done i just
yeah just just be really loud yeah i'll
try to be uh
so right now we're in a room where we're
growing uh i think it's gorilla glue
number four in here
uh those plants got slipped into flour
about
five days ago or roughly a week ago
and then let the lights put on on a bit
of a cloudy day there's a forecasting
thunderstorm here this afternoon the
clouds get pretty dark
it looks like we're almost getting into
the evening kind of light setting so the
lights are kicking on right now and you
were right there those are like a fluent
uh bio engineering lights
working with fluids for several years
they've been enough to partner with them
uh the quality of their light as far as
the spectrum goes really good
through the efficiency it's awesome for
a full of life
but a big part of it with the the
customer services and the furnishings
where i was able to offer us it was
really really awesome to work with and
uh
they made a custom produce for us
which is uh uh kind of a saddle that
amounts of existing structuring frame of
the greenhouse so
you can see that there's two lights side
by side it's kind of a custom product
that is that we get up with them
the same way that we give up those
been in the greenhouse business for over
uh 60 years in the netherlands i believe
and uh the greenhouse manufacturer in
the set itself is kubo it's a kuvo
burrito so
this greenhouse is very unique and the
amount of technologies and
data points that we can get on that but
also it is just a general
uh design phase so we have a fully
sealed green island here so
typical greenhouse what you guys are
going to see usually together there's
vents on top or vents on the sides uh
in this kind of like a little greenhouse
if it grows and rows of greenhouse
you're gonna see air movement
from the top and from the end uh this
basically our warehouse with a glass
roof
we cannot open the sides or roof ducts
so we have a
giant hvac system that you can see in
the back those
cabinet looking thing in the back maybe
trying to get closer at some point uh
but those are uh
giant hvac systems i think you gotta
i can't remember how many tons of asics
but uh
uh it works and uh that's the most uh
amazing i know what has been surprising
but like
uh and uh
all the stuff something that the real
greenhouse uh over
50 years never failed to green off like
this
it's always been kind of standing
quality but a fully closed one
uh the first one uh and it's working so
far
so in the greenhouse industry generally
in the summer you're going to apply some
products to reduce the amount of heat in
your out
uh some uh people people are calling
climbing the greenhouse putting cool
white or rid of these regular sun
there's a bunch of different products
out there
so basically plus the slice just come
into your greenhouse
and reduce the heat but uh
also bring some light this year uh
i think i called off the other custard
just before they came to spring arena
because we thought we could get away
without it and
we've gone through uh the worst parts of
summer as far as
humidity goes for us here in uh ontario
uh we're just sort of niagara for people
who don't exactly know where we are
uh basically between toronto and niagara
by lake ontario
and it's very hot in humid summer but we
were able to
get away without having to reduce your
light levels in the greenhouse just
using
the cooling capacity that's built into
the greenhouse and it's been
amazing so i held up the helicopter half
an hour before it came
but until that i did we have an amazing
light level in greenhouse wildlife
college here uh we have uh chelsea on
the camera we have
casey one of our climate control guys
working with prima
control system i believe we're about 27
degrees
uh in this greenhouse 28 right now
and it's very very comfortable
the other very interesting thing about
this greenhouse that is that uh
the weight of the air is other reasons
that work whatever living falls through
it
i'm just gonna their air gets comes in
from the back of the green out
there um either from outside and then it
gets full you can condition
proper relative humidity temperature and
velocity
and then we're going to pull it through
the canopy from underneath
we have those big inflated balloon uh we
call them slurp because it's the thing
that the dust guys are using for them
uh which basically they're incorporated
big line
and they blow hair from underneath the
cold air through the canopy
so we really manage the microclimate
inside of our canopy
and frost climate
but i bet if you want to make a messy
turn out of it for me
instead of having one giant bed in
between
a bit of an airflow and then a little
bit of leaf wrestling here
you know that until the airflow's really
moving
so so david is the reason for the bed
shape because of this unique airflow
system that you're trying to do to get
the air in coming up
through the canopy from the bottom up
yeah we've
well it breaches to design our larger
bed if you go with
four feet bed with the amount of
transpiration the amount of water we get
is the middle of the bed
so which would be the uh feet
in uh you don't get so much little
compartment
in a lot of molds and some bugs and a
lot of uh
bridges like that so you have to grow
the plants a bit taller
bring them harder so it's a bit of a mix
of different reasons
from uh managing the plants the
ipm the workflow s time set that gave
rise to
this solution and it's been working
beautifully
so so the connection's a little bit
choppy so i just want to make sure i
understood that correctly so you're
running
this shape and depth and size of beds
because it allows for the airflow
it allows you to work in between the
rows and manage the beds and it also
limits uh mold and mildew pockets that
you may experience
in a wider bed is that all correct
exactly so if i'm going to ask
how to just show them if you can just
show the entire
so you can see that the leaves are kind
of rustling in there in this area
if this was a solid piece here and there
we won't
get air flow on the side of the bed and
we would have a micro climate that would
form in here
and that would be aggressive for ibm and
uh
and also flight quality
and then uh david i want to ask you
about co2 levels
what are you running in these rooms and
how are you managing that
so for a co2 level it has a lot to do
with
the amount of light that we're getting
so
if we're solely on natural light there's
a level for that we're adding uh we're
trying to follow the
uh light saturation service and match
your suit with that so basically
depending on how
bright it is we're going to add the
proper amount of students for that
it's a bit of a fine-tuning process but
we took a simple approach that occurred
so
we changed it throughout the week so as
far as the plants are growing
uh but basically we have the opportunity
to go from anywhere from uh
ambien where mds co2 level is a little
bit higher
uh than normal because of resources
roughly 500 50
depending how much we uh recirculate
otherwise we can go all the way to 1500
[Music]
but getting at those levels they're uh
depending on the air
you have to get into uh more
recirculation modes
of the air because if you're flushing
your alzheimer's it's about a few
huge levels of volume in this room the
interesting part of the future is that
it gets injected and those slurps are
below the table
so we deliver it through the canopy as
well
so just to finish on the air uh movement
system
here's that so once air goes through the
canopy with
enriched skewed units there's two things
that can happen to it
we either can't recirculate it so we're
gonna same thing as a fully
closed indoor garden so we circulate
here in the room or we can
access it through our
giant exhaust line in there and there's
a
bunch of charcoal filter there so we
don't really smell anything outside
so it can be a fully steel greenhouse
garden
or we can exhaust by forcing air for the
canopy and get rid of humidity or high
temperature
when there's something critical
happening we can have an air cooler and
change this greenhouse
every five minutes great
great so i want to highlight a couple
things because like i said the sound is
a little bit off one
taylor kirk asked about the helicopter
comment and
basically what you were saying there was
you have a helicopter that would come in
right before the hottest times of the
year to spray
a coating over the top of the greenhouse
if i understood you correctly to reduce
the amount of heat in the greenhouse and
you called it off because
this year you were able to manage it
effectively through
uh your air conditioning and airflow in
that system is that is that correct
uh in greenhouse too uh
usually we use a helicopter because the
greenhouses are too big there's like a
nectar and a half here under
uh one of my first job when i was a kid
was playing the greenhouse
with a like a internet i really like the
other capture now it's plus better
solution so it's just basically a
coating of uh commercially available
products that will let the good total
systemic active range of the light go
through
it will bounce back uh more uh infrared
light
to reduce the amount of infrared that
will warm up the greenhouse but
you reduce uh from about 15 to
percent of your natural life depending
on how fixed you make
uh
okay well thanks david and uh i wanted
to go back i'm trying to get as many of
these questions in as i can
uh our good friend jaya palmer was
asking if that was a bean plant
he was asking yeah that was a beauty
plant we saw in the mother room
and uh what the purpose another person
asked if that was for spider mites can
you just touch on that really quickly
that's exactly what it is
for uh we got one over there
it's not a very happy looking one but
let's uh
we put those plants in there if they're
a little indicator plant so spider mites
will go
on those bush being planned first and
they
are actually if we see spider mites on
those
really we know that we need to increase
the amount of
beneficial insects that we have to grow
to manage and
spending vitamin so far we've never seen
that here
uh so it's been really good for us uh
and uh yeah it's just a bit of an
indicator plan
uh and uh yes
leaders push me find the symptoms
wonderful and then the yellow tape i
assume
is yellow sticky tape to catch flying
insects and pests in the room
this is referred to in the ibm world
so basically this is my insect from
fungus mass to
flying in to uh just regular
uh outside stuff and chris dude
do prefer to move on but we're
just going with those we're still uh
[Music]
doing our best and with the minnesota
part of the work organization
[Music]
yeah so uh very good so mass trapping
that makes a lot of sense you're just
trying to catch as many as you can it's
not so much
as a scouting tool because you're not
changing them out frequently
but uh i assume you're doing separate
scouting then
on a regular basis that's which is very
important
yeah cool moving on start sleep
and stay clean and you can only do that
from personality
william cowell was asking how often does
the soil need to be changed
[Music]
so you have the ability to change the
soil if you need to because those are
manageable sized
containers on that road however the plan
is to never
change the soil unless you absolutely
have to but rather to
manage the soil fertility through adding
in various amendments
organic matter over time as the soil is
going to continue to improve
uh through you know improving the soil
ecology is essentially what you're what
you're saying
yeah exactly
disease sometimes a little bit but we
have such a
competitive thing right this philia uh i
don't know
uh a little bit the one length perfect
here and there
it doesn't spread out to the rest to
grow uh
we use a lot of products like root
shields next to us
early on and all that uh
at this scale we don't expect it's
completely perfect but like we're really
happy with where things
[Music]
he's going to show you uh listing system
and we have the greenhouse there's a
pretty high-end and uh the first time
we've decided it's really awesome
so we can basically turn this entire
room into a cloud of
fog if you want to
it's really good for us when we're uh
trench cleansing
or when we want to add an advanced level
but we have this like
super beautiful high performance and it
looks to look like
uh the mist things that you're gonna see
some of the grocery store produce aisle
very very fine and uh it's been working
wonders bro
that's really cool that's a really cool
feature so uh
ben asked how are you dehumidifying by
venting only
[Music]
so the dnp station uh we have used
aviation dramatically in our hvac system
but it's going to be depending on how
much fuel we are running
what's the outside temperature how much
like green damage
capacity do i get from outside
uh depending if if it's winter because
cold uh
air outside it all we have to warm up
this air in dry air
and then it's radioactive so the
strategy for summer and winter is
different
but it's based on west coast high
temperature
because if you flush it all the air uh
if you're pushing out our
suits it also means that sometimes we
get to have uh
80 percent of new air and really 20
we're here a bunch of stations this is
where
software products are somewhere like
three of us that are
gonna get built from a private
controlled point of view but also
an energy illustration when you use an
entertainment agreement
with synthetic stuff with labor so we
basically humidity knows how much you
need you can make aware of the
dry air control can be expended our unit
electricity while we get it for free
from outside over
certain place and what does it trust us
as far as you can go
so when we're in the early veterans room
we said we
very cool well david i have some more
questions for you but why don't we
tackle them in the next space
if we want to keep this moving along
yeah uh
you guys been able to you know
distinguish them a little bit and uh
yes it is it is coming through you can't
see that that's very cool that you have
that
that ability um
and so basically you know while we're
switching i can do some talking
but uh what what you're sharing with us
is essentially that uh you're using a
chart when you talk about humidity and
temperature in that relationship you're
looking at the
vapor uh vapor pressure differential so
they're relative to each other so you're
managing that
you know when you say you're talking
about where how that outside air gets
you know conditioned or prepped before
coming into the greenhouse and also
looking at how
uh you're managing the air in the space
and choosing to vent
you essentially have complete control
over all of those aspects
uh when we're talking about air and
that's all related to the
the temperature that you're uh you're
dealing with so
i just kind of wanted to highlight that
a little bit
um it looks like we're frozen here right
now as we're switching over to the next
uh
wi-fi section but hopefully we'll be
back on soon
um assuming you can hear me while we're
making this switch
uh for everybody uh david there are some
great questions people are asking
um it looks like you're you're slowly
coming back on here can you can you hear
me david
like you're still a little bit choppy
here
oh david hold on your uh your video
hasn't quite caught up yet
i think we're back you're back right now
okay
yeah so uh i heard your comments about
epd
tv a little bit louder david sorry to
interrupt
yeah yeah so we're uh we're managing the
vpd like you explained
what the mystics have done and you have
out of an air refresh and everything
that we have
ranked again and then depending on our
energy strategy
least amount of energy to be as
efficient as you get in here operation
costs but also
it's just good things that you use in
switzerland
you have a lot of flexibility in green
and this is what's
so what room are we in right now david
an executive room
in here right now we have about
four thousand types of red times here so
we'll show you some above a little bit
so you get an idea of uh
what it looks like and uh
yeah so right now we're about to say 18
to 21
flowering in here
okay so you're you said there's 4 500
plants and you're around day 18 in
flower
is that correct yeah roughly okay
you know a lot of people are asking
questions about the soil
uh some of those questions are uh do you
put
worms in your beds and uh
does the soil get turned over when you
go to re-amend them after harvest
yeah so there is no uh
worm in the beds at the moment it's
something that we
would like to test at some point in time
we did some tests a little bit in the
past in uh
other other places in my room smaller
fiction
forums were great uh the old bed turned
into uh basically warm casting for after
a while
but
we are uh we had so much form that i was
wondering
how the fertilizer would not go into
work biomass instead of going into
flying violence
so we uh walked into a bit more about
that
and uh you can added the worm with
managing the irrigation
uh you can have like longer irrigation
we're kind of gonna
bring your warmth down into your bin
i've heard if you get to like a lot of
quality irrigation your surface is going
you can manage your population like that
it's something i would love to be able
to try but at the moment we're
using more good high quality warm
casting in some of our comfortable
disease
but we're still at like physical warmth
in the vids at the moment right now
okay so you are using worm castings with
making compost teas but though
they're not necessarily seeing a lot of
worms in your beds at this point in time
yeah yeah yeah we got some warm guesting
at some point that was full of warm eggs
and uh we have another uh the initial
facility we started here
there's so many warmth in those beds the
bloods are looking great too uh but it's
just something that
before we can fly this starts to scale
yeah and i would add when you're working
with these you know so-called living
soils
if you are managing your irrigation and
you use worm castings you will get the
eggs like you mentioned and a lot of
times worms will show up after a few
cycles in my experience
in your beds but i think that's an
interesting thing to look at is at what
level of biomat worm biomass are we
you know potentially beneficial or
possibly at some point it could become
detrimental if it's literally
all worms um moving on though
some people were asking uh if you turn
the soil when you go to reamend it
and uh do you share it all how you are
what you're amending with
is that something that that you share
information on
not so much there's a lot of uh straight
secrets there's
a lot of good things you can do i know
that you probably have like a lot of
information about this on your
website there too about the real man man
and the top dressing and all that we
have our own way to do it
we will add job dress uh just recycle
that's gonna be mixed into
uh planting oils and stuff like that we
don't get to survive the whole during
those in those dropping trucks because
it would be
like an incredible amount of work for us
but uh we stopped dressing to get mixed
in the first few inches of the soil
and it seems to be working very well for
us so far
[Music]
wonderful and uh how often are you
testing the soil
we're trying to do it like about twice
per flowering cycle
okay yeah and some okay so i just
anyway i'm just going to close the
blinds because i want to show you what
it looks like when we can turn
this room into a nice mode okay while
you're doing that i'm going to
tackle a couple other questions here
someone asked if you created your soil
or if it was outsourced i happen to know
the answer to that
this is the soil that you formulated and
created yourself
um you and i actually have had
discussions and you know in regards to
some of the theories and
optimal target values and things like
that regarding these soils based off of
soil tests
and then stephanie also asked you use
fertilizer or only rely on organic
amendments
well essentially these organic
amendments are the fertilizer for
feeding the microbes in the soil that
are then cycling
a lot of these you know meals and
nutrients things like alfalfa meal or
kelp meal or whatever
nutrient source you choose into um
plant available fertilizer so i just
wanted to tackle those two really
quickly for you
and i think uh for yourself that i think
you've been working with black swallow
soil
which are like a bunch of very great
guys that just make sure you have i
still have to get some of your
just to try for fun uh with your mix
available in canada for those guys right
yeah yeah i appreciate you mentioning
that so uh we did come up with a
commercial soil available through black
swallow living soils those are wonderful
guys over there
and uh i would love to run a trial at
some point in your uh greenhouse
but uh yeah i worked for a couple years
with them with formulating uh
a soil that would be commercially
available for canadians
uh as well as the us here so yeah
um did you want to talk about the blind
system sorry beautiful
uh yeah so right now if you guys are
looking above me uh it's
the blackout surgeons are getting rolled
out
so basically this is for a live solution
at night and also if you control the
total period
so this is now during summer time we're
able to flower cannabis
uh in the middle of summer just like the
summer solstice so we
have those lines coming in and out
depending on uh
when it works if we have it so we can
flag out at the news western rooms that
are
in the sun in the morning and some rooms
that are in the sun in the afternoon to
manage a workflow or
uh managing them here so take a few
minutes as well this is why i wanted to
close them
earlier but it's actually quite
impressive how dark you can get it
also the neighbor likes it because it's
a
huge speaker flying that's leaving out
those fluent led that we're running
right now
we have 800 red cpfd of supplemental
light
so that gets quite bright especially at
night
uh here when there's snow cover at night
and it's a cloudy uh
night there's so much slight reflection
in the clouds
back into the snow so those greenhouses
get really really really bright
right so it was a shaker and taking away
the slide solution
and uh above the shade version i don't
know the blackout circumstance above the
[__]
[Music]
that does a little bit of a heat
trapping to keep the greenhouse warm in
the winter
or uh bounce back some of the light that
produces yeah
so it's basically a translucent
uh curtain up there and it's really nice
maybe the younger plants who are uh
reducing the light levels for a very
bright day when the
some of the planets get may get
stretched from wiser from
anything else that's the first thing
that we do when we defend the stress a
little bit
just reduce the light level it allows
them to catch up a little bit
that's that's really cool so just to
highlight since the connection's a
little bit rough
you have a shade curtain and a blackout
curtain
so you have the ability to totally
adjust your light levels and then those
fluent lights
you said go up to 800 ppfd as
supplementary light for days when you're
not getting as much solar
energy or light as you would like and
then i assume those lights are dimmable
so you can they're not coming on at 800
uh ppfd immediately like
if you only need 200 ppfd then they'll
come on to adjust that and that's all
computer
software controlled is that right yeah
yeah we could uh uh
we could as we have those lightnings
here they have a built-in option where
like
inside different status systems in real
time and stuff like that
we're not currently doing it but it's
part of the continuous improvement
project here
so right now they're just on or off but
we can do sections or roads
that's what it's uh looking like when
the blackouts are closed
oh that's cool that's very cool yeah i'm
gonna turn them back on so we can see
again
that happens pretty quickly too
that's amazing that you have such fast
control over the system it's so
responsive
yeah it's awesome it's awesome and uh
really when the last gap is closing it's
been really good so
it's also really uh really cool for us
for heat management
we can like have different type of
overlap from the
shade curtain and the black upgrades
let's say uh when we're
treating this room with uh
stuff like bavaria uh great finder trip
so we can reduce the amount of light
during the treatment uh increase the
humidity for a day or two
just to give a chance to benefit cells
uh to reproduce and really uh kill the
best insects
uh and uh this is like managing your
light levels with that
testing system uh learn how to work this
with this awesome green one that's uh
that's part of the most excitement that
we have
part of persuasion 2 sometimes and with
complexity from
troubleshooting with what we're able to
do with this greenhouse which is just
so cool and there's a lot more that is
coming up
it's really really exciting we've been
working with a lot of people who give up
new tools um
i know that you personally met a good
friend of mine uh
which means give us a bio fertilizer
beneficial bacteria
i think we missed it in the other room
we had a
giant composting brewer it was going on
in there
so
we had a really awesome greenhouse that
was delivered to us
and we just needed to do some small
finite legislation
to make it like so exciting for
organic production there's stuff in here
now that kind of you're going to have to
go
and walk with me one day
yeah uh so david let's talk a little bit
about
microbes you mentioned uh francois
and i know that he did some research on
some insect frass
back in the day for you and found it had
some you know good calcium
solubilizing and pea solubilizing
microbes
i know you're working with a couple
company now on the microbial side you
mentioned compost tea
what sort of microbial additions are you
doing
in your in your rooms right now well
we're uh we're doing composting and we
build a
good mobile uh
the bottle reactor so we can basically
uh make our own hydrolyze and
whatever we want so this is pretty uh
it's pretty cool to use
fiddle with that uh the other stuff that
i'm sitting here we've been really cool
with working with uh there was a
still splendor promoting rhizo bacteria
that we started to work with frank
uh when we were in whistler a while back
and we did some trials and all that and
now we have a
commercially available product with that
which is very close to uh this like
uh i think a lot of people in this state
know uh diamond p
uh that would be not available in canada
she's gonna make her own solution
which is different in battlefield got
more mode of action but basically we
have selected isolated and
tested then it's very competitive
environment which is only with soil
so we see benefits of using uh this
product now it's called uh microbial
mass
and uh i'll a little bit if you um
like that really good one respond to
these socialized
cinematic civilized phosphorus they
stabilize
calcium and also uh that's where a
friend of really delivered designing
microbial tests
and he added some bacteria uh enzymes
and side arrow forms mineral cores are
little chelating agents for stuff like
copper iron manganese
virus and micronutrients so uh
with more organic fertilizer organic
amendments
it really helps to mineralize them and
give us a good
growth rate for information that's one
of the that's composed
um
and how we deliver that to the soil how
we keep them alive in the greenhouse
within others
amazing
wow so you're using a just uh just a
highlight because i said it's a little
tricky to hear you uh
you're using everything i know you
mentioned root shield which is a
trichoderma you mentioned
uh bulvaria those products are more for
ipm or pest prevention whereas you have
other things that you mentioned like the
compost tea
or this microbial mass product which i'm
really excited to test out
and then learn more about and and
possibly even offer here in the united
states here soon
those products are more for plant growth
or overall plant health so
sort of a two-pronged approach there on
the microbial side which
i know you and i have talked you feel is
just as important as a lot of the
uh nutrients and fertilizers that that
you're doing in the facility
um but let's uh let's keep the tour
moving along uh one other question that
guy
asked here and i'm trying to get to as
many questions as i can people
uh i'll do my best uh he asked
is with the pure size of this facility
how do you manage all this green waste
and i thought that was a really good
question because you must be producing a
lot of biomass
yes we uh just come posted on site
so basically we have a chipper like a
big wood chipper so we will stamp
the waste in there mix with some teeth
and just get our teeth to teenage your
ends getting disgusting
so basically we send everything to the
difference because it outside
we are not reusing this compost in the
grove or
uh issues stuff like that but we do have
a community farm
on the uh on the side here this is where
this temple is getting used for
workers to uh we offer a little
community vlog here so people can use
that
uh cannabis comfortable instead of an
easy way to fertilize our garden in this
cover here
wonderful so real quick david you
actually sound pretty good right there
so let me just ask you a couple other
quick questions
uh people are asking about irrigation so
one question is do you run compost tea
through the drip tape
um and then the other questions are how
are you managing soil
moisture and irrigation in these rims
so uh yeah we will run compost through
the drip tape but we'll just need to
make sure that uh if you want to do that
just going to make sure that you get a
drip tape if you're not
your compost you will get filtered
through the proper micro size before you
get into
uh your irrigation tubes too so for you
to figure out with the equipment that
you're running
uh and also flush your line after
that's how we're doing we apply it by
hand too and
head application works great it's
awesome it just takes forever when
you're watering
one of a football field and a half by
hand uh
so and how we manage the irrigation
there's a couple strategies that we can
do we have
soil moisture meters uh we also have
uh the total amount of light that the
plants are getting every day
and uh we are in a water-based and the
amount of irradiation we get so
we know that the plants that they get so
many so much energy and that's where you
have to start to think about the
greenhouse
uh wax per square meter uh if the plants
are getting
so many watts well then it means they're
going to need so much water to
make up for the uptake of that and or we
can just have to
deplete on the timer so every hour we
water
uh four minutes four times per route
that's an example of a common strategy
here so basically it's a lot of them
walk in your greenhouse
you walk in check walk and check
everything so you then you can find
a different type of growth different
spray and also different seasons
uh ideal uh
stream scenario would be uh there's a
bunch of companies out there that do a
real-time irrigation system basically
you have a
soil moisture sensor that can stop your
climate control software
so argus rivas damatec a bunch of other
stuff but if you can
set thresholds in the same way then you
can oh if the room reach a
35 degree exhausted while the soil
moisture level reach this limit
water in so let's get into more
precision agriculture
they certainly have that endorsed shirt
and field crop which is
working really really good especially
you can have
different zones in your greenhouse which
is awesome uh right now we are in the
north side of the greenhouse and it's
getting a little bit less
light in winter than the south side of
the greenhouse so this is stuff that you
use learn how to work with your facility
but it's
just trying stuff and testing it
very cool so uh let's go ahead and move
on to the next
uh the next space i'm excited to see the
plants as they
move further into flowering here it's
it's kind of fun we're just gonna move
uh across the hall and we're gonna see
if plants are gonna be harvested in
about
two three weeks from now
[Music]
oh that's cool wow
so a couple people have asked about your
pruning if you're doing any lollipopping
how you're pruning your plants could you
touch on that that's a cool shot
can you touch on your pruning for me
david yeah
um
bit of a challenge for us not too much
but
my approach to pruning is during fetal
diet collection
uh trying to go to france or kind of a
self-ruling or self-defeating
hey david yeah i hate to interrupt you
it was it's really hard to hear you i
think you were saying that you're trying
to select phenotypes that require
less pruning because of the amount of
labor involved on the scale that you're
at
um yeah but it's just a little bit hard
to hear you can you uh
can you just maybe talk a little louder
moving forward here yeah yeah
so uh i'll get tyler to keep giving you
a shot of the plan so i'll try to
talk a bit louder but yes this is
exactly it but if those are the
different phenotypes that uh
reflecting so this type of planet
architecture here that's never really
been pruned that's never been really
believed
uh it's giving us like very good yields
to where we have some plants that are
really dense and foliage really packed
in contact with
plants that are stretching a little bit
look like they're doing better for us
uh this is what we've been trying to
select for in here
uh pruning takes a lot of time so it's
uh
that's one aspect of it but the second
one is also
timing it's all about trying to
blend this and the flesh is looking
really good
with them at the right time give them a
little white room as we're planting them
uh so that's what it is so every time we
have a plan in our hands we're drinking
make as many action or a
task that needs to happen with me like
tough relief a little bit and prune at
planting room but
putting our veggies plants in there
they're about uh
uh 18 to 24 centimeters tall
so uh we don't have to test them as much
later on
phenotype selection is a big one too so
that's how we approach it it's not been
perfect and we're large learning and you
have to grow the scale
but we've been pulling some really good
um
numbers anyway out of here the main
difference we've seen
is a bit of modernity because the plants
are getting less light
they are uh not as the bottom part of
the glass does that thing aside so we
tend to keep this stuff for
an extraction or for a
hash making production which is a new
thing that a new
project that we've been started we've
started here
cool uh so a couple other quick random
questions uh is the excess water from
the irrigation
reclaimed or recycled do you have a lot
of excess water with the way that you're
managing
these plants for these beds
[Music]
and those gutters are recollecting the
water
[Music]
allows
we
uh
it's a little hard to hear you david but
i think what you're saying is you
collect
both the rainwater and the runoff the
runoff through a gutter system
the rain water through the ceiling uh
and it's all filtered and collected and
then recycled when possible
is that right yeah yeah even the
condensate
gets reused very cool
and then another random question i know
we talked about that microbial mass
product
uh i don't believe it's available in the
us yet as far as i know
um is it available in canada can you can
you address that for
the listener it's available in canada
it's available
with the quality wholesale which is the
commercial
hydroponic uh gardener
suppliers they have a bunch of uh good
stuff and they're
starting to carry our microbial mass
product but we're
we're just rolling it out into space too
and we'll make sure that uh we'll give
you a few simple
assassins you can give them in your butt
pass or something or people going
together to get at least to try and
but it's it's a really awesome product
we're really happy with it
and uh yeah it's been been really good
wow that's a cool the coolest part about
it too is that
we had a lot of commercial tomato
growers or field potato growers that
tried it i didn't work for commercial
act too that's one of my favorite things
when we
work with cannabis specific inputs if
they work in commercial ag and it makes
sense for a guy to throw
potatoes or tomatoes in a greenhouse you
can monetize that it means that for us
and cannabis it's a really good input to
do that
yeah i think that's a key point um i'm
about to record a podcast with uh
suzanne
uh the bug lady and that's something
that i think that we're gonna cover when
we talk about evaluating a product the
fact that
we want to look for products that are
out in commercial egg or make sense in
commercial egg
because if it can make sense on a lower
value crop then it certainly can make
sense for cannabis
so i think that's a good thing to
highlight there that you pointed out
uh what can you tell us a little bit
about what you know
what day in flower you are and what
cultivars you're running in this room
uh so in this room we're about in the
beginning of week seven and you still
have about a few weeks ago that they're
really uh finishing right now
we have some uh global fish frost
[Music]
you know outside something we got
something that's really cool it's not
exactly and above a question
it's kind of a look to it we call it a
west coast bush and it reminded me a lot
of a lot of this great equation we're
going out with
i'm as a little nostalgic from the
beautiful one silver you're still lucky
to live sad right now
um
we have another really cool screen in
here it's just been a beautiful pinot
noir
from the process that we did that's
called organic
it fire beautifully he's got a big
structure we've got a really good
yield on a surprisingly good deal
about twenty percent for us so we're
just rolling those frames
you seem off do pretty well and uh we've
got a beautiful
beautiful bucket left-handed nose from
here uh
and there's there's good trichome
development as well so we're looking
forward to
the uh what we're going to get in terms
of harvesting those who improve
and we've just got you to uh
fine-tune recently as well so we're
getting some really nice uh
increased growth from that
so about two weeks and you think they're
going to finish
uh much taller is this about the height
your plants have been finishing
no they're going to finish at this size
yeah they're they're they're the threats
here mostly
getting some uh hardening and
swelling it's
we have a room that's supposed to be
going for extraction it's a cbd crop
and especially in the summer you know
plants tend to stretch a lot of
that we have the use we have to give
that a requirement strategy and growth
strategy to
take that into account because the same
strain looks a bit different in winter
than summer
we have a fairly good idea we want to
tackle that now
but that's part of growing with the
season and the greenhouse as well
so david take me through your
re-amendment process and harvest process
so you're going to come in here
pull the plants are you pulling out much
of the root balls
what does that look like how soon are
you replanting
uh we can replant it after a harvest
there's a bunch of different uh liquid
and dry amendments we can add ketograms
so basically we're gonna come in there
we're gonna cut the holes line down uh
then we're gonna remove the root balls
and by the rhubarb we're gonna remove
something this big the big stock that's
not gonna break down very fast
uh then we're gonna do a tough dress and
we're gonna flatten it there
the following day we like to do a little
bit of a compost here
some stuff that's going to activate the
microbiology so we're going to have a
breakdown up here we're getting better
as faster as this and by the time that
one recovered from the
subdressing the whole plant when we
removed the stock to
the roots tend to die and break down way
faster
so it's fairly simple actually the way
we've been doing it
but the biggest one for us is managing
the very first to make sure we can
transition from one room fast enough and
we're getting into a very good base
uh room right now so this room is going
to be in the uh
our target is nc only for a day or two
and then we can reflect in it
wonderful i know we talked about
microbes already but a few people have
asked if you're using
any like probiotic korean natural
farming
indigenous microbe sort of strategies
in this facility uh
not not exactly like that no
i like those ideas they're great we have
a lot of
uh compliance and anything every food
and stuff that we have to go with with
this legal commercial scale so can use
good compost and richness serve you have
to
prove that they've been following
certain uh terrible temperature and all
that
for us to go harvest wildlife growth
they're
probably very highly beneficial uh plan
out
we would do that if you were to uh but
we do
use different composting different
type of amendments and that will
nourish biology or
glitter composting that's basically how
we've been adding vitals
you have like several different type of
composting
contributing to powering or badge and
stuff like that
so this is how we
so so what i'm hearing is you're not
necessarily opposed to it but also i
would think on the scale that you're at
you need to have very controlled
inputs to know what you're adding into
your garden um
because it is such a massive scale too
so that would just be something i think
that would factor into in that decision
show you maybe a bit of the bed area and
the cloning area
uh the last step is going to overheat in
the sun right now
and uh we're not moving around it's
getting pretty odd for us
going in here all right let's keep
moving
it's just hard to want to leave the
flowering room there it's uh it looks
great in there
um yeah well wow
and it keeps looking better and it keeps
looking there's new personalize that
we're using
it's fine-tuning everything and also
this is the first time you go as great
as this
we always learn a little bit uh but like
the potential between some of those
realtors yielding agency goes to the
missing
tests are and came back into uh
above like 30
oh that's great that's great we might be
jumpy a little bit but
uh can hear you guys to see what i'm
talking about
we're just gonna walk to a different
building uh where we do propagation and
bench
okay well i'll i'll read some more of
these questions that people have been
asking
uh one of them being i know uh they
they're asking about odor pollution
do you control order pollution as part
of your licensing rules company
standards
if so what size and quantity of carbon
filters are you running for this room
i know you had mentioned uh that you do
have carbon filters that the air will be
scrubbed before being exhausted
but i didn't know the size of those and
someone else had also asked how many
lights are in a room and that was
another question that i wanted to throw
out there
oh is that a is that a compost tea
brewer right there that you just we
walked by is that your bioreactor
[Music]
okay it's a vixen tank all right
sorry it's noisy in there i'll let you
keep walking david sorry
so when you get to the next room maybe
you could answer those two questions
uh about number of lights and uh also
size of
carbon filters
you said 800 lights is that right
holy cow wow well 400 or 800.
there's two lights per saddle between
the fixture
but it's a supplemental uh and that's
the number that really matters
is because it's the supplements elevator
directing
the brand so with no sun when the
blackout curtains are
closed uh we have eight of the rest of
these
are those the vipers that you're running
too yeah
the viper x-flex viper x plus
man fluence is a lucky company to have
your business that is a huge order
yeah so those are led lights for people
that are wondering
um they're from fluence who is now owned
by ozram
uh they're they're an led
manufacturer uh they make wonderful
lights
yeah and points also have great customer
services
horticultural uh consulting thing and
it's been uh
we've been working with them for uh
i've been working with them for six
years
there's just a good company they've got
a lot of really good critical signs
information about dds you need to
highlight an entity dvd on their website
so
they're just like really approaching it
from the commercial act
[Music]
to show that you kind of like which they
do as well
but it's been really good
very cool
man this is a huge facility yeah
good workout weekly kilometers
you push your work a couple kilometers
[Music]
uh
david i'm losing you for just a moment
here uh so let's just hold off while it
reconnects
uh on your end at least with the
propagation space
um if you could give us just one second
here before you start up
if you can hear me
all right looks like we are still
waiting
uh one other question that ben asked
oh you're back i'll let you go and
continue and then i'll come back to
ben's question here in just a little bit
here so yeah right now we're in uh what
we call the farmhouse building
uh
[Music]
what do here this is where we have a
vertical uh growing process
uh and we are uh cloning vertically
and uh virtually
so so david i know i know you're moving
from space to space and this is just not
a normal thing that you would do but
we have this tour uh when we talk about
propagation though and your employees
would you have specific employees that
would pretty much stay in propagation
and other ones that would stay in flower
to sort of avoid this
cross-contamination
from an ipm perspective yeah yeah we
actually absolutely do
uh we have teams that are like
they learn in passive propagation
transplanting and all that or taking
more care of the mothers or taking more
care of the young plants so
if people can stay on the path for
longer until they get really good then
they can train someone else
but yeah so we also have a
weekly pass report and stuff like that
too so
i know there's some room that if uh
there's potential trips or spider mites
and stuff like that
i'm not gonna go in there and um
go to another room and get a little bit
of some
potential fast issues today the
greenhouse we didn't went in there so we
stayed in the clean room we also moved
from
uh the youngest room to the oldest room
as well instead of like
starting to a room that's just about to
be harvested and then people in a young
young room that's just clean and
pristine so this is why we
did this we're this way as well today
that makes a lot of sense yeah thanks
for explaining that
so where what are we looking at right
now right now you're looking at
uh some of the vertical algorithms so
this is the process we're throwing in
here for
cbd extraction uh
[Music]
it's uh it's one that we really selected
for biomass
i don't know if you can see very well
next to it
yeah that's cool you know this is the
first
vertically integrated living soil system
yeah
i've never actually seen on a commercial
scale yeah
a little access card is the size of your
credit card uh
i got big fat sausage figures so
sometimes it puts things out of
perspective
but this one is uh yeah it's really good
and this is not like
necessarily desirable for smoking and
all that but as far as biomass go
for extraction it's kind of a loose open
flour dries fast
there's a good cbd content it mills very
easily so for extractions that pinot's
been like awesome
the other thing with this what's that
cultivar before you move on
does it happen charlotte angel it's from
dutch fashion
cool yeah so and the other thing that
tyler if you can take just a step back
that we have in here uh
this system here this is how we've edged
plants but this is uh
mobile so the lights and irrigation is
stationary but it's all right we can
take it
wheel it to the harvest area or wheel it
to
uh whenever plant and veg we live to
your place where uh
we take 200 plants at a time and they're
going to get transplanted in greenhouse
so this is
another thing that we work with with
fluence but also
bob hoffman from shenandoah growers
which are the largest commercial ever
producer
uh in the states we grow organic basil
and the bus butter stuff
came up with this system and bob's been
a pioneer in the
horticulture and greenhouse in the
innovation
he knows more about information more
about agriculture they'll ever know
probably but
that's one of the really neat little
things
that was not that expensive but really
increased workforce
very cool
so this room has been in a two-level
room for sparring
[Music]
right now but this is what we were
seeing earlier today
before people just come in here if they
did
and we will especially if we know it
could be an explanation
yeah what size are those plants in terms
of the container size that they're in so
you're vegging
in your abigail don't want to
get a little a little bigger than we
wanted to but it's been in there for
about
three weeks now i'd say uh they want to
get out of there absolutely a bit longer
than when we ideally want and that goes
back into my
my timing question uh sending comments
uh earlier uh but we see like a super
beautiful
uh recovery of those clones so when
everything is right
10 12 days after we transplant them to
clones they're like
the roots have only did one to turn into
pots and they're
going in 16 18 days dearly
cool dylan's asking what the capital
expense was for this facility
i'm kind of curious about that too is
that something that's public
uh yeah it's gonna public information i
think uh
uh tomorrow last night
70 million i said 70 million
yeah there's a lot of processing and
packaging stuff that we're done touching
and that's that
and that was so there's no driving room
there's the new driving technologies
we're trying to install continuous
drying lines too using vacuum
uh there is no packaging so basically we
start everything from easier and we do
the final packaging
that's going to get shipped so there's a
lot of infrastructure that's built
around that it is more than just
growing and drying and selling involved
trying to be as integrated as possible
for the whole entire process
yeah and uh one other random question uh
those those fluency lights put out 800
ppfd but what are your targets for veg
and flower in terms of uh
in terms of lighting uh
so in a very sunny day in the summer in
the greenhouse
just natural light can be get up to 1600
cpfc
and this year was really interesting
because uh i've closed it there was no
traffic on the road
so we just used highlight levels in
april because the air was so clean there
was no suspended particles in the air so
we've got really cool
really clean lights this year and i was
interested that we've seen
uh so we can go all the way up there so
of course we're not turning the lights
on
when we have like 1500 epson extra light
but this is not
also powered
[Music]
okay so you're aiming for a thousand to
twelve hundred
your lights can provide up to eight
hundred so you're counting on the
sunlight providing
at least 400 per day
when there when everything's opened up
yeah and how
we're moving toward daylight and the
girl as well
it's more measure of the life
attenuation just
one time the planet can take maybe into
2000 maybe if you're light but for half
an hour to an hour if it's cold in that
and it gets stretched so if you can have
like syria
so you're looking at how much light
they're receiving over a given period of
time or daylight
daylight interval yeah
yeah so your lighting company helps you
with calculations and all that stuff
which is an important thing to point out
that's great if you're using a light
company
like the product itself is great but the
warranties
and the customer service
[Music]
yeah so your lighting company should
also help you with your layout
uh based on the their knowledge of the
lighting they should help with
calculating out a lot of this stuff
they'll be able to tell you
what light levels you'll receive um
under this layout
so you you don't have to do that work
and a lot of times they'll even help
with the rebates and stuff with your
local
uh state and county rebate stuff so
that's important
yeah and then how large is the facility
overall what's your
square footage about uh
wow
cool i'll let you continue on yeah well
that's
uh mostly it for now for the grow and
all that
there's the propagation
[Music]
well you know i think that was uh i
think that was pretty good that was a
wonderful tour it's great to see the
facility and i hope to make it up there
someday and
i know you're constantly learning and
innovating and
uh one thing i'd be curious about is to
hear what sort of uh plans you guys have
with the research that you are doing
how much of that is going to potentially
be published or is that all staying in
house
or uh are you guys running a lot of
trials these days
yeah we're we're running a lot of trials
on different things and stuff uh
so are we can you hear me right now we
can hear you great in here actually this
is the best game
perfect yeah so yeah we're running a lot
of trial but it's all internal
and uh it's good to
share with other uh
and like i foreign believe that with
sharing we everybody does better and we
learn more
but as as nothing planned so far we
don't have uh
research or university partners yet
we're in talk some of them uh
but it's been uh uh yeah
as far as like as and also as
competitive things are getting to i know
there's really other
uh canadian organic greenhouse producers
that are listening here and we're all
like
doing our old things and all that is a
bit of a professional secret
that's going on here there too so
there's a bit of all of that but it's
still uh it's still ag and
uh renaults management and all that too
so we have a really awesome
beautiful facility and uh we're learning
how to work with it
a lot it's some really really good good
stuff more than
we want to publish a lot of stuff i'm
also
an internship program another stuff like
that uh
we've hired a lot of uh there's advice
after cultural university called welcome
nearby
here we have our students coming out
there
i'm lizzy david a little bit louder
sorry
yes sir it's going to use learning
opportunities for us we're
hiring uh people that are coming from
the research side that have a good
mexican strong background but we haven't
published anything yet
ourselves yet okay
wonderful um i'll let you do the
publishing part that
we're working on we're trying to come up
with some research too you know i think
that's uh i think that's important part
of the process
as you know and and i appreciate my
conversations with you and even you just
opening up the facility to let us tour
it i think is a big deal
i know a lot of facilities uh aren't
open to that especially on your scale so
i think it's great um good we're proud
about what we're doing we're excited
about it and we're
learning a lot and that's what keeps us
engaged so that's the
that's part of the the love-hate
relationship with
agriculture sometimes but it's mostly
been treating us very well so far and
super exciting
what we're coming up with this fall this
winter is going to be
really awesome cool uh so one other
question i had on here from guy
that i thought was a great question he's
in new zealand uh lucky
lucky him uh during the process of the
design
what is the one thing that you had to go
back and retrospectively change
increase to actually meet your demands
or needs was there any one thing
if you could go back and wave a magic
wand you'd say oh this is something i
wish i'd done or
hadn't there's something i wish i hadn't
done videos
and cooling capacity you should always
over build a little bit on that if you
can you're never going to have
too much uh and power
or keep in mind like the general
small day-to-day functionality as well
because you're you're going to rely on
this scale with a lot of uh growers and
tables and you may get better you need
to make a facility functional for them
for what you're going to do with your
groceries so that thing can make you
grow
flexible or don't max out the product
you need to buy your powers of
hardest things so it's like oh you're
going to need 19 megawatts a month
but you buy or you build for uh
like you know the half and then future
expansion if you want to change things
and
your secondary good thing about the
immediate part of it but also one thing
coming up eventually
yeah change a few things but nothing
dramatic nothing that's crazy
all right and then my very last question
what's it like
growing this much cannabis and being the
world leading organic
uh you know cannabis grower on the on
these on this indoor facility or hybrid
facility
here for the last uh months and it's
been awesome
uh so much to learn about growing and
other stuff it's been a very spiritual
innovation and
innovation that we're doing in this
large-scale market cannabis has been an
amazing
driver for uh
[Music]
ripple effect in the rest of the world
to better everything
uh that's when it's really awesome
so just uh
yeah it's a ton of work but uh i mean
i think it's amazing it's no longer a
proof of concept this idea that we can
reuse soils in a controlled environment
agriculture
this is
i uh we do it this way and we have to
give up these tools
that's what's really impossible
together
yeah and the just the highlight for
listeners the idea behind this is that
by not
by reusing the soil that allows uh
like a company like t-god to not have
the labor of moving
a massive amount of media in and out of
facility they're not utilizing something
like rockwool which is not sustainable
and actually quite damaging to the
environment
and also so not only are they reducing
their labor but also their cost for
fertility the
amount of inputs that they're using for
fertilization
is so much lower than more traditional
methods of cultivating cannabis so
uh yes it's a it's a tough concept it's
a lot of work what they're doing but
overall it's saving them a ton of money
and a ton of labor and uh is much much
more sustainable than
the more conventional models that you've
seen out there so i commend you guys for
pulling it off
well it's been like we have a really
awesome community
people that we share your podcast this
is one of the best sources of knowledge
that i can
pick on that i i've even i know you're
you're
you know most familiar you're recently
congratulations
such beautiful information there's such
good stuff out there
i don't want to tell all the competitors
but it's out there and it's so good and
i'm doing a great job with that
discussion was like i said there are
just look at my phone quickly i've got a
bunch of friends awesome thanks for
joining us
um
looking to do it but um
it's a great community of growers and
i'm honored to uh know people like you
it was wonderful working with tgot and
putting together this event
and the facility tour and i thank you
all for your time and uh
and i thank everyone that came along on
the tour and we're gonna do our best to
share this tour after the fact but uh
yeah thank you and uh i appreciate it
and i look forward to coming up and
touring soon
likewise guys if you have more questions
reach out to that or
reach out to you you got uh
wonderful i'll let you get back to work
david thank you for your time today
and uh we will talk
joining guys have a good soon all right
bye
you