I've just come to the realization how
how important it is to test your soil at
the same time like so we test we kind of
follow what your guys' sop so just for
the audience we work very closely with
Tad and his team with Brandon uh we
submit a soil sample around uh after 8
weeks in flour so we're kind of getting
the same snapshot in time of where rooms
are we try to take different points in
the room just to try to get a general
idea um and then we go off of uh
Brandon's recommendations or working
with them being like hey we need to get
our yields up can we bump you know X Y
or Z up um so I think it's uh super
critical especially in a commercial
setting where you're trying to hit
certain metrics um you need to be doing
soil testing and you need to be making
sure that the inputs that you're using
are uh clean and
tested