so someone commented on one of my recent
YouTube videos with a great question
they asked one what are you doing in a
garage and two why didn't you prune the
plants better and so it got me thinking
and I wanted to give a thoughtful reply
uh so the reason I'm in a garage is
because this is a tester room that I set
up to try out new products um different
ways of growing and also have a place
just to shoot videos so I want to be
able to demonstrate how simple and easy
it is to grow plants and an afford
manner without a whole bunch of products
uh secondly it got me thinking about why
I prune cuz subconsciously I wasn't
really concerned with how much pruning I
had done in my room and I wanted to talk
to you kind of about why that is so why
do we prune well one of the main reason
we prune is for Pest and pathogen
pressure by reducing the amount of leaf
mass that we have here we're we're
effectively reducing habitat for Pest
and pathogens we're also increasing air
flow by doing this and by increasing air
flow there's no pockets for you know
different microclimates for powdery
mildew or other pathogens to start
growing and things like that um another
reason that we prune is for herbivory
this idea that insects are chewing on
the plants and so when we create a wound
here by cutting off this fan Leaf um
essentially what we're doing is we're
triggering SAR which is systemic
acquired resistance the immune system of
the plant uh and that has a ton of
benefits too so these are all various
reasons why we prune one other last
reason I want to mention is that some
leaves lower down on the canopy are not
photosynthesizing as effectively as
leaves up here towards the top of the
canaby so things that are shaded out
down here potentially are nutrient sinks
so by removing those they're no longer
required by the plant to put energy into
maintaining that leaf though as we
remove leaves we have to keep in mind
that some mobile nutrients are able to
be pulled from lower families if the
plant found a deficiency or needed them
so my thought on it is I have sufficient
airf flow you can see down below here I
turned it off but I have some under
canopy air flow going you know I have
other fans throughout the room so I have
really good air flow um and then it
comes down to to me time and labor and
this is more of an issue in a commercial
facility but I've been really busy
lately with work and family stuff so I
haven't had the time that I've wanted to
come in here and necessarily remove all
the lead
that um may not be required but I
haven't felt any pressure to that either
because like I said for the reasons
below I feel pretty confident in where
I'm at right now and where my canopy is
to where I'm not really worried about so
much the pest and pathogen issue and I'd
rather not um spend that time pruning so
that's kind of a little bit behind it
and for a commercial facility you have
to realize like there's a tradeoff there
like how much do I need to prune to
reduce P Pest and pathogen pressure
without causing so much labor
that I'm raising my labor cost so high
without really improving my yield so
there is always a tradeoff there and
pruning can almost be more of an art
than a skill and there's certain things
that we want to consider when we're
pruning um but overall that that's sort
of what's going through my head when I
think about like when to prune why to
prune and and how to prune oh and one
last thing to mention it's another thing
is to open up the plant and allow for uh
light to hit various Bud sites if
there's tooo many large fan leaves
blocking those those buds just don't
seem to develop quite as well so hope
this is helpful thanks for checking it
out