hey guys it's Dad here with kiss
Organics I want to do a follow-up to my
trivia post yesterday this was the photo
in question and you can see the unique
swelling and no the nodes on this plant
it almost looks like uh Galls some
people guess that it was super cropping
however these plants have never been
super cropped and we do have a positive
HP lvd test or hlvd that's the Hop
latent's thyroid that is supporting this
result
you know many of you are familiar now
with hops Layton unfortunately it's
becoming more and more common and I'm
happy to do a separate post talking
about spread and decontamination and all
of those things as well
I was waiting to make this post because
I wanted to get a second confirmation
from Dr Jack Munns over at Three Rivers
biotech that's who does our testing for
us through our website and I did do a
podcast with them a little while back so
you can go check that out if you want to
hear more about virus and virus testing
but we are seeing with the hlvd a
variety of symptoms in cannabis plants
you know the plant may appear healthy
while the viroid lays dormant until the
plant appears to encounter some sort of
environmental stress and then we see
symptoms ranging from loss of potency
yellowing misshapen leaves stunting the
plant's inability support itself and
just a general brittle or weak stem
structure and in some cases the swelling
at the nodes so it's really important
that you are observant of your plant
that you do consistent testing in order
to make sure that you have confidence in
clean material and one of the
interesting findings that is coming out
in research right now
and this is something that I just did a
podcast with Suzanne Wainwright Evans uh
the bug lady sharing some of the hemp
research that she heard at a recent uh
private hemp conference and that's
essentially that the root tissue may be
a more reliable source of viroid testing
for hplv
then the up above ground Leaf biomass
and what their findings were were
essentially that
um and she'll she gives a number in the
podcast interview but essentially many
of the plants tested negative for the
viroid when they tested the leaf tissue
and then they would test the root tissue
and they found that the roots would test
the root samples would test positive
whereas none of the plants that where
the roots tested negative did the leaf
tissue test positive so there's a lot of
there's a lot of reasons there to test
the root tissue to get a more reliable
result potentially
um
so I thought that was really interesting
research that interview is already
available on our new patreon
um the raw footage but the actual
podcast interview will be coming out uh
probably this week or next week at the
latest so if people are interested let
me know I can try and track down more
information about uh
this viroid viral disinfection best
practices and put together another post
or even maybe another podcast around it
but reach out if you have any questions
and I just wanted to share and and for
those of you that participate I just
want to say thanks you know whatever the
the guess is or the comments
um you know it's really about just going
through the mental process of thinking
about how to approach your garden what
some of the variables are what some of
the things it could be
um so honestly you know if you get it
wrong don't sweat it I get these things
wrong all the time I'm constantly
learning and I hope we can all continue
to learn from each other so thanks
everyone have a great day