hey Tad here with kiss orenics I want to
tell you about a new product that we've
released recently it's our new blo
booster it is a 286 and I wanted to show
you a couple ways you could apply it to
your plants so uh first off I have this
jalapeno pepper uh large Plant small pot
so I've got about a tablespoon of our
Bloom booster and I'm just going to
sprinkle it in on top and then reach in
here with my hands and scratch it into
the
soil just like that into the top upper
layers and then I'll just follow it up
by watering it
in and that's it now even better if you
have a little bit of soil or compost or
worm castings like for this cannabis
plant here uh this is this is a great
example here I'm just going to take
about 1/4 cup it's about uh half a cup
per 5 gallons of soil so I'm use about
1/4 cup
here and mix it with just a little bit
of
soil mix that all together
just like that and then I can just pop
dress this onto the top of the pot and
then water that in too this is going to
give you a nice phosphorus and
pottassium boost for your plants and
allow you to grow a really good healthy
plant get a better yield and go all the
way through to harvest in a much smaller
container with the lowest heavy metals
of a commercially available uh organic
Bloom booster on the market that I'm
aware of all right thanks for checking
it out