hi guys so something I wanted to talk
about today was non-target organism
effects it's something that I always
think about when I'm deciding what
product to use in my garden and what I
may be spraying or applying to my soil
so for example when I sprayed these
plants uh when they were in veg I
sprayed them with mon Monteray
horiculture oil this is also known as SE
foil X it's an oilbased product there's
a lot of oilbased options out there and
they work primarily as a suffocate which
means the Insight can't develop a
resistance to it just it's being
suffocated now other products that may
be applied to the soil to treat fungus
gats or some other issue like that could
potentially have non-target organism
effects meaning you may be killing the
fungus gats but you're probably also
destroying other biology especially
things that are biofumigants so keep
that in mind that could damage your
nutrient cycling or perhaps make the
plant or the soil more susceptible to
Pest and pathogen
after the
application um that's the great thing
about beneficial insects when we apply
beneficial insects you know pests can't
develop a resistance to that they're
being eaten by the uh by the predatory
insects so all things you want to think
about always keep in mind non-target
organism effects when you're pick
picking out you know some sort of
application that you want to make in
your garden all right thanks for
checking