hey guys Tad here with kiss Organics and
today I want to talk to you about
organic amendments and organic inputs
what I have in front of me here is the
uh majority of things that you'll find
in organic fertilizers I'm going to talk
about each one sort of off the cuff I'm
not reading a script so I may not catch
all the bullet points that I want to but
I will try and add any notes as well as
the actual NPK uh the nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium of the various
products that I'm talking about I'll add
those to the video uh later because I
don't have those all memorized so I'm
just going to I'm just going to run
through them I'm this is going to be one
really long form video I'm going to try
and bookmark the different spots so you
can look up particular amendments if
you're curious about them uh and
initially what I have out right now is
all things that contain uh NPK so these
are going to be your major nutrients
I'll do another one with um calcium and
limes um as well as mic micronutrients
I'll do one on compost and I'll do one
on some Blended fertilizers so it's a
lot and I only had so much room in front
of me and a lot of these things look
very similar so bear with me as I try
and go through them now before I do one
of the first things I want you to think
about when you're thinking about organic
fertilizers is release rates and one of
the primary variables with release rates
is particle size um and solubility so
some of these things are going going to
have very large particle size like this
neem seed meal or neem cake versus um I
don't know something like this
pottassium sulfate or Epsom salt um
magnesium sulfate fully soluble in water
um or even if we're talking particle
size like this kelp meal is very very
fine um and I've seen kelp meals come in
a variety of different um particle sizes
so the smaller the particle size the
greater the surface area and the easier
it is for microbes to break them down
and make them plant available now this
is a this is a very general broad
statement that I'm making there's some
Nuance to it um there's a lot of
variables that will come into play like
what microbes are in your soil uh what
moisture levels are in your soil what
temperature is your soil uh all those
things are going to play a role in terms
of nutrient availability but that's the
first thing I look at or think about
when I'm when I'm looking at an organic
Amendment uh before I look at mpk I look
at particle size so keep that in mind
but let's start off talking about uh
primarily nitrogen amendments so what I
have closest to me here first is organic
alphalpha now organic Al falam is
something that I like to use in all of
my nitrogen recommendations um it
doesn't contain a lot of nitrogen so
you're not getting a lot of um NPK out
of it per se but it's a wonderful
microbial food it feeds bacteria archa
fungi uh which in turn will feed
protozoa and other microorganisms so if
you're big on the soil food web thing um
adding organic alala meal is a great
option uh for you just be be careful
because if you add too much um it can
cause the soil temperature to heat up as
these as the bacteria reproduce rapidly
um and that could potentially um pull
nitrogen from your crop roots or um
potentially cause issues uh in that
regard but in general it's a really good
safe amendment to use and something that
I like to use in all of my
Gardens okay moving on so next what I
have here um I believe this is the fish
meal so a fish meal um it's primarily
nitrogen it's derived from fish as you
may as you may know and um it's a fairly
small particle size here it's it's one
of the more expensive nitrogen options
uh there's nothing wrong with it it's
just you're going to pay more for your
nitrogen if you go with fish meal Some
people prefer um ocean-based products
over um things that might have come from
our industrial solder houses and things
like that um but in terms of cleanliness
of the product um you know heavy metals
um exposure to uh I don't know growth
hormones chemicals things like that um
it's it's not necessarily any cleaner so
keep that in mind because I have heard
um some some organic um companies
pushing that that sort of message and
agenda and it just the the science
doesn't back it up so um if you want to
learn more about that you can go and
take a look at a video I made on exactly
that topic um I'll try to link to it in
the comments but again fish meal
primarily nitrogen um and and so if if
you're if you're looking to make
something that is
um not using things like blood meal
feather meal that is a good other
nitrogen Source option okay next I have
uh soybean meal so soy meal is um a
great option for folks who want to
create sort of a vegetarian or vegan mix
um or don't want to support our
industrial uh fishery commercial fishing
or um industrial
slaughterhouse um you know Loops of of
uh food production for our country so if
you do go if you do want to use um only
plant-based inputs that's a great source
for nitrogen so you could use something
like the soy and the alphalpha keep in
mind with any of the um
plantbased uh nutrient sources that they
can vary based on the fertility of the
soil and how that crop was grown will
impact the fertility of the uh final
product itself so you may see some some
variability there but you can usually
get a prettyy rough idea by looking at
the label as to what you're actually
getting for nitrogen but just keep in
mind those labels are not 100% accurate
so if you're using those and purely
those for calculating out what your NPK
is going to be I can tell you right now
it's not going to match up the way you
think it is we always soil test
afterwards and are always shocked with
just how different it is when we start
mixing and making soils from um what we
expect using an NPK
calculator okay moving on uh neem cake
or neem seed meal uh the one that we
have right now this is in the form of a
pellet a compressed pellet but you can
also get it uh at least we've got in the
past as like a powder uh one of the
things about the neem cake is it is the
um it's what the residue that's left
after the seed is pressed to extract the
oil so depending on how thoroughly they
press the seed uh that will determine um
what a a dant content may be left in the
neem seed meal and as a duratin is a um
insect growth regulator um there's
synthetic versions like azamax or
azatrol that you may have heard of some
people like to use neem oil as a
um as an as a foler spray to deal with
various insects um I have used the neem
seed meal in the past it's been a number
of years now because I think there's
better options out there but I have used
it at a rate of two cups per five
gallons of water that I bubbled for 24
hours and then watered over the soil to
deal with a really bad fungus snat in
infection that I had at the time or
infestation um so it it can be used for
that um it is going to give you a little
bit of nitrogen but there's a couple
reasons why I tend to not use as much uh
neem cake and also the corja cake which
I'll talk about next um and that's sort
of twofold so the first reason and again
all of this goes back to using the cots
mix um and and Clackamus coot uh back in
the
day but the reasons I moved away from
these and I still use a small amount but
um very small amount compared to what CS
mies was or what I originally used um
and the reason why is one uh the fossil
fuel cost so just to get the product
here um to get the neem cake here from
India is very expensive and it has a
high fossil fuel cost to do so I just
think there's better nitrogen options um
out here on this table that are more
sustainable because I can Source them
more locally um I did hear there was
going to be some neem production
happening in Florida which potentially
would be a little closer and again I'm
making this video like you live and our
sourcing things in the United States or
let's say North America um if you live
in India neem cake is a wonderful option
for you for getting nitrogen it's been
used for you know I think hundreds if
not thousands of years by Farmers for
cultivation um of crops so moving on oh
the second reason and this goes for both
of these sorry is um
from talking to a good friend of mine
she was Consulting with a farm in Oregon
and they actually failed for um a an his
a pesticide that is a chemistry that has
not been allowed in the United States
since the 1970s and so this Farm was
very confused as to how they could have
failed on their flow for this pesticide
and basically what had happened as they
tracked it all down was the neem oil
that they were spraying on their crop um
contained uh low Trace levels of this
particular pesticide um I don't remember
what the pesticide was off top of my
head but I know that it's not something
that's been available here in the United
States for you know 40 years now 50
years almost so uh the fact that it was
on the crop pretty much means that the
the farmers that were growing the neem
tree somewhere in that production chain
uh it got exposed to this pesticide so
uh that's something with the um neem
cake the Kanan cake that's just
something to be aware of as a
possibility and it's one reason to have
a very clean Source but also realize
that you know like I said there's
there's better options we can find here
locally um okay moving on this is
probably my favorite Amendment uh right
now that I like to include in all of my
Gardens and all of my soil formulations
and this is insect frass now the great
thing about insect frass well there's a
number of things really um the first one
being is it's closing an ecological Loop
so a lot of times these uh these meal
worms are eating a waste byproduct uh
and then converting that into grubs
which are then sold as a high protein
source for animal feeds um and then this
fras is sort of is their poop and and
leftover exoskeletons anything that
remains there and the wonderful thing
about insect fras is I have yet to see a
sample um and I've probably looked at
three or four different sources now over
the years and all of them have been very
clean on heavy metals now in addition to
the low heavy metals which is really big
um for those of you that are in
regulated States growing cannabis um but
even for people with our own Gardens
just for our own health um having
something that's really clean that is a
um has you know uh nitrogen phosphorus
and potassium and it's it's kind of a
more balanced fertilizer option um and
then has microbial life in it as well
and because it is a it is an insect
manure essentially that's what frass is
and it contains high levels of kiten and
um so potentially that kiten um could
help with disease resistance um so it's
not going to hurt to use it I wouldn't
use it as my main form of uh you know
integrated Pest Management but having it
in your mix is certainly not going to
hurt anything and it has all those other
benefits so insect frass one of my
favorite amendments right now okay
moving on blood meal blood meal is a
very uh fast relase available form of
nitrogen it's kind of gross to work with
um you don't you want to keep it very
dry until you're ready to use it um but
if you need nitrogen it's it's a good
way to get a faster release nitrogen um
right away and so this goes back to that
whole idea of uh using utilizing
slaughterhouse products um the the
reason you might want to consider it is
because you are closing an ecological
Loop this would be the best use case for
that material is to grow more things
with it rather than ending up in a
landfill or getting dumped or polluting
our environment by ending up in um you
know um our streams or something our
water supply or something like that so
by extracting and making you know a
fertilizer out of it that's really the
highest use case uh for a product like
this but again I understand if there's
people that don't want to use it now I
have seen research and there's not a ton
of research on this topic unfortunately
but the research that I have seen that
does exist shows that that that the
blood meal is actually very clean so it
doesn't have high levels of heavy metals
it doesn't have high levels of um any
sort of like growth hormones pesticides
uh you name it it's actually a very
clean product um same with the uh bone
meal as well which I'll get to but um
yeah it's definitely something that you
should consider and you also will pick
up a little bit of iron from it too
because it is it is actual blood so
that's another nitrogen Source um again
I don't use it in my garden uh all that
often but I don't have a problem with
people that that do chose choose to use
it is a good option um okay moving on so
I have a couple things in here that
aren't necessarily NPK but I had already
poured them into the bucket so I'm going
to talk about them uh this is
agricultural sulfur so agricultural
sulfur it's these little tiny prilled
pellets in this case um you can add it
to your soil as a way of lowering your
pH and so if you have a pH above let's
say 73 74 and you need to lower it this
is a good option it's not going to be a
immediate it's going to take a little
bit of time um so keep that in mind as
well but it is it is a good way to
slowly lower your soil PH in addition to
that sulfur is U associated with a lot
of uh tarpine production so having
adequate sulfur is really important to
get all
the flavors and and odors that you want
in you know whatever sort of flower that
you're
growing so keep that in mind um and it's
uh it's really hard to get too much
sulfur now the only risk with sulfur is
raising the EC the electrical
conductivity of your soil so high that
you may put osmotic pressure on uh your
your plant roots but you're not going to
um you're not going to see a sulfur
toxicity in cannabis it's very um
tolerant of high sulfur so I don't
usually worry about that um next and
again this one I I kind of poured it out
before I decided to do primarily NPK but
I'm I'm going to leave it in here this
is biochar so talking about
biochar it is uh one of my favorite
amendments it's right up there with
insect frass I include it in all of my
soil formulations and the reasons why
are because it it has a ton of benefits
it's going to sequester carbon it um it
helps with overall plant growth and
yield it's Habitat for micro probes it
sequesters heavy metals it does just a
ton of really great things and we found
that using it at a rate of about five to
eight% by volume we see uh just we see
better growth in yield and I was kind of
surprised by this I didn't expect to see
such a dramatic Difference by such a
small addition but I the the research
really supports it and one thing to keep
in mind and this is something I'll talk
more in depth about when I talk about
compost but not all biochars created
equal and so you want to make sure that
you're sourcing it from a company that's
that's Burning uh clean wood and
actually pying that material that means
burning it at very very high heat and
low oxygen conditions otherwise what
you're ending up with is something more
like ash that can contain heavy metals
and other contaminants so having a very
uh consistent clean source is super
important and then particle size plays a
big role too like I talked about with
surface areas so having some smaller
particle sizes it can act act as an
aggregate in your soil and give you your
soil more tilth more texture um so the
one the size that we use is is fairly
small it's not a um powder it's probably
um I would say the size of like a maybe
like a grain of rice to give you sort of
a a size
analogy okay moving on here let's
see believe this this is feather
meal uh the feather meal is sourced from
um as you can expect from the poultry
industry uh feather meal can
contain uh more contaminants than these
than the bone or the blood but in
general is another great option for
nitrogen sources um I IID originally
read that that feather meal was a slow
release nitrogen Source but what I'm
finding in practice with soil testing
things like that is uh it comes down
more to particle size at least in this
case so um yeah again it's just it's
primarily nitrogen and there are other
options if you choose not to use you
know anything from the uh uh
slaughterhouse
industry okay let's see
here this is uh crab or crustation meal
and crab en crustation meal is a good
source of nitrogen as as well it's also
going to contain high levels of kiten
from the shells that's in there it's
going to contain some more calcium for
the same reason and I haven't talked
about calcium you will get some calcium
from the insect frass uh as well and
just to go back to the insect fras
depending on what insect it was you know
whether it was mealworm or black soldier
fly um I think there's even a Cricut
frass that can be it's commercially
available now they're all going to be
slightly different NPK slightly
different um microbial consortia
different calcium levels those sorts of
things but um yeah keep that in mind so
anyway getting back to the crustation
meal this is going to be a combination
of a variety of different crustations
typically um crab Lobster those sorts of
things and it's just ground up and so
you can add this to your soil again
primarily for
nitrogen okay kelp meal what we have
here now kelp meal is an interesting one
because it has a ton of plant benefits
there's a lot of great research on how
wonderful kelp meal is for plant growth
and plant Health um it
contains like 70 different elements in
it it's pretty phenomenal it's just kelp
is this amazing Dynamic accumulator now
because it is so good at
accumulating nutrients uh primarily
micronutrients um it is also high in
heavy metals primarily arsenic from what
I've seen on tests so uh you can use it
I like to use it at lower rates now um
especially for people in states where
heavy metals is a
concern but um if we just look at it
from a plant growth perspective it is a
wonderful input and something to use in
your soil so just keep that in mind um
if you do use it you can use it at
pretty low rates you don't necessarily
need to use the high rates that we
originally were using when we were
making Coots mix
okay this next one is uh known as keg or
suo or sufate of potach magnesia uh it
has a bunch of different names it's
going to be very high in Sulfur
pottassium and magnesium and it's not
going to be in the right ratios for what
you want of those elements so keep all
of that in mind if you decide to use it
there are rare use cases where I might
use it but I don't use it all that
frequently um typically and the reason
for this is because I have access to
things like potassium sulfate and
magnesium sulfate uh Epsom salt which
are both very very affordable and I can
control the levels of potassium and
magnesium I'm adding separately it's
kind of like using caleg like I would
never use caleg because I'd want to add
calcium and magnesium separately and it
different ratios depending on what what
my soil report or what my plant may need
so it's the same sort of thing with so p
Meg or keg um that being said you know
if you do need to pick up some potassium
and a little bit more on the magnesium
side then uh it is a good option for you
so just keep that in mind the one other
thing about it is it's very soluble
which I like so you will get a faster
release rate with it and with these
particular amendments um particularly
anything that's a sulfate here like
these they are refined but they are
approved for use in organic production
so something like the potassium sulfate
it's a these are mined products that are
then refined and then allowed to be used
if you have a soil test showing a
deficiency so really all of these
products to a certain extent have some
level of processing or refinement that
happens in order to get to the final
product you know in this case it's
pelletized in these case they're made
into meals um so just keep that in mind
when you're thinking about an amendment
and deciding whether or not you want to
use something in your garden so next we
have potassium sulfate this is uh 0050
it's 50% potassium um really easy way to
get available potassium and that's so
important um mid to late flour that's
what's really going to bulk up your
flower give you that nice density that
you want you know I see these um PK
boosters and stuff on the market in the
Cannabis industry and I think a lot of
that really probably comes down to um
people having inadequate calcium
uh either from overwatering because it's
highly leech so if you're if you're
flushing your soils and Watering your
soils to run off a lot you could be
removing nitrates and potassium and so
later in flour um you may need to add
some more or it's just one of those
things that you're plant is is utilizing
it at a fairly high level and so you
want to make sure you always have
adequate potassium in there and this is
one of the easiest ways to get it in
organic system is through uh potassium
sulfate so week three is a nice time to
do a light potassium sulfate application
and that would just be mixed with water
and watered in um and it's pennies so
it's very affordable
input next we have uh magnesium sulfate
or Epsom
salts uh rarely do I need to add
magnesium I find with most uh living
soils we have adequate magnesium already
um but if I ever do see as Soul report
or need to add it um Epsom salt is the
easiest way to do it because it's very
soluble I can just water it in I'm not
using very much um and it's it's very
easy to source so it's a wonderful
option for you if you do need to pick up
magnesium in your
garden okay moving on so I
did this was crab meal you know this one
oh this is fishbone meal sorry they look
very similar here and I put them all out
and I didn't label them so I'm I'm
trying to test myself to see if I can do
it all visually fishbone meal is a uh
again it's from the commercial fishing
industry it's um it's high in phosphorus
but you're also picking up some nitrogen
with it so um you you want to just be
aware of that uh with the the phosphor
the phosphate in it um it's it's a good
way to pick a phosphorus uh it's not
perfectly clean on heavy metal tests
from what we've seen so um unfortunately
there really is not a perfect
phosphorous source that either isn't
going to give you calcium or potentially
um bring in some heavy metals so just
keep that in mind now there's certainly
ones that are cleaner than others and
there's one that I'm getting tested
right now that I'm super excited about
that may actually be the Holy Grail of
phosphorus inputs uh that's derived from
algae but I haven't gotten the test back
yet I'll keep you guys posted um in the
meantime we do like to use fishbone meal
so your options for phosphorus in
organic system are fishbone meal bone
meal and softrock phosphate those are
going to be your main sources um and
I'll I'll talk about the other two next
here um but yeah fishbone meal again
sourc from the ocean not as clean as uh
some people may make it out to be
actually I think the bone meal is
actually cleaner when we talk about
heavy metals and we talk about
um uh you know things like um growth
hormones the pesticides fungicides all
those things it's not in the bone meal
um so you don't have to worry about
there's no GMOs making it into the bone
meal um there's research that shows that
doesn't happen so uh things from the
ocean not necessarily cleaner than
things from the land if we're talking
about products like this now manures on
the other hand and compost absolutely
you're going to see higher levels of
contaminants in those so we'll get we'll
get to that but bone meal was the next
one this is it here uh one concern that
people have with bone meal is mad cow's
disease uh really hasn't been an issue
but it is a preon it's
um it is something where I just if I am
using well any of these amendments I'm G
to wear a mask and wash my hands and
things like that but um the the statist
statistically it's there you know you're
more likely to get in trouble driving
your car or doing your daily task than
you would from that but that is some one
fear I've heard associated with bone
meal so I just wanted to bring it up
um so yeah we have bone meal fishbone
meal and then lastly softrock phosphate
now softrock phosphate is a Min product
and so um it is going to contain higher
levels of heavy metals so keep that in
mind um this particular one that I have
here is calos it's one of the cleaner
soft rock phosphates that I've seen it
is a larger um particle size here so the
availability is going to be a little bit
slower so we usually use a combination
of the fishbone and the um softrock the
cow fos in our mixes there are other
ones like for trell that we've tested
and um they have higher levels of heavy
metals so we primarily recommend the
ones that we found or have lower levels
of heavy metals if that makes sense so
that's that's sort of the overview of
NPA and again this is not exhaustive
this isn't have everything but this is
the majority of what you'll see in in
your um amendments so I'm going to clear
these out I'm going to replace them with
some other amendments and I'm going to
continue the video here shortly all
right I'm back and I've got a new set of
amendments laid out here but I want to
start off talking about limes now
because limes all look relatively the
same uh I didn't bother putting them out
it just look like a whole bunch of white
flower laying out here but I want to
talk about the differences because it's
really important to get the right lime
or the right calcium Amendment into your
soil for the effect that you're looking
for so the the first one I want to talk
about is agricultural lime now
agricultural lime is great if you want
to raise your soil PH it's primarily
calcium carbonate so um it will have a
dramatic impact on soil PH um so if
you're low this is the way to go and
again the ones that we like to use are a
very very fine flow that's going to
impact your release rates but you could
consider using different particle sizes
to get different release rates on the
calcium but calcium is one of the most
important things to preload and have
high levels through veg and flour um so
that's agricultural
lime next I have Dolomite lime now
Dolomite lime is calcium and
magnesium uh carbonate so what this does
is this is going to have uh an even
greater effect on raising soil PH but in
addition to that it's going to provide
you with magnesium now what I found is
in most cases when you're mixing soils
you have adequate magnesium and you
don't need to add it so I rarely use
Dolomite lme because I prefer again I
think I talked about this before but I
prefer to add my magnesium and my
calcium as separate amendments um and in
the correct ratios that I'm aiming for
and and Dolomite does not do that so
there are some rare cases where we might
use Dolomite rot lime if we need to
raise soil PH add calcium and magnesium
um then it is a viable a viable option
but other than that it's not a terribly
popular amendment that I like to use a
lot so one of the next and one of my
favorite calcium amendments is gypsum
also known as calcium sulfate so the
great thing about gypsum is it buffers
soil PH and that it's not going to have
a dramatic impact on it so the calcium
being a cation and the sulfur being an
annion they offset each other and you
end up with a relatively neutral um
impact on your overall soil PH so why is
this important well if your soil pH is
already 68 to 72 let's say and you don't
want to go any higher then you can add
Gypsum to your soil to get more calcium
in there um and the nice thing about it
also is the fact you're also picking up
sulfur and you really don't have to
worry too much about a sulfur toxicity
the other cool thing about gypsum is the
solubility ility level of it frankly
it's just not terribly soluble so the
solubility of it the release rate of
gypsum is is relatively slow meaning
it's going to give you pretty optimal
release rates of calcium throughout the
growth cycle so if you're starting out
and mixing a soil and you're starting
with Pete Moss for example that has a
very low PH you'll typically add
something like the egg lime and the
gypsum so you get different forms of
calcium in there this is going to raise
your pH this is going to not raise your
pH but give you release of of calcium
throughout the entire cycle so those
work well now some people have been have
recommended using oyster shell flour uh
it looks very similar to the
agricultural lime and frankly the gypsum
the the difference there is it's derived
from oyster shells but it's also a mined
product these are these are bed deposits
that are mined it's not like they're
pulling this out of the ocean and
getting you like the oyster shell flakes
that you might have used if you had
chickens for example so it's also
primarily just calcium carbonate as well
with a little bit of impurities so um if
you cannot find agricultural lime
affordably then this is a good
alternative for you but I wouldn't go
out of my way to try and find oyster
shell flour to replace agricultural lime
as they're going to have very similar
effects again it's going to raise soil
PH and provide you with high levels of
calcium
and then lastly here I have W asite
that's calcium silicate now well last
night's a little bit harder to find for
folks but if you are able to find it
it's a wonderful option and something I
definitely like to include so if I was
formulating an ideal soil mix I would
use a combination of
gypsum and will last T night with
probably a little bit of agricultural
lime now the big difference here is
you're getting silica which has a ton of
plant benefits I know I've talked about
in the past um it it really is the U
magical um nutrient element when it
comes to growing plants silica helps
with drought stress it helps with
disease resistance it helps with thicker
cellular um thicker cell walls it helps
mitigate uh micronutrient toxicities if
you have a little too much Boron or a
little bit too much manganese in your
soil it it just has so many different
benefits um for plants now all that
being said um calcium silicate will give
you that calcium and also silica so it's
a wonderful option now it does raise
soil PH but much slower than
agricultural lime so if I have a soil
test that shows a very low soil PH let's
say it's like five five or six and I'm
like wow I got to get this up uh before
you know right away for this next cycle
I'm not going to use W last night I'll
use agricultural lime or oyster shell
flower is something that's going to
raise my pH much faster but if your sole
pH is close to being in range you just
want a little bit of upward pressure on
your pH then W Las andite is a wonderful
wonderful option to consider so those
are your
limes uh Let's
do let's talk compost next so not all
composts are create equal I could do a
whole thing on compost you know let me
know in the comments below if that's
something that people are interested in
but um
the way the compost is made what the
feed stock is how that compost is
treated can have dramatic impacts on the
biological and chemical and physical
properties of that compost so there's a
lot of different types of compost um out
there you'll see you'll see different
ways of making it the main three forms
of compost are static composting that's
where you throw stuff in a pile and let
it sit for a year or two and it just
breaks down slowly the advantage of that
very little labor the dis Advantage it's
not going to kill off weed seeds it's
not going to kill off pathogens uh the
next option is vermac composting or worm
castings and I show you some examples of
those here and I'll put them up on the
screen here superseded over the video
hopefully so you guys can see some
close-ups of what I'm talking about but
um worm casting is where you use worms
to break down the M material it's called
vermiculture or vermac compost uh the
castings is essentially Worm poop and
those tend to be some of the highest
quality from a biological perspective
worms are just very good at breaking
things down into a very plant available
and plant friendly uh
forms but the last form oh and I want to
mention that worm castings do not um
they do not kill weed seeds and they do
not kill um pathogens so the one option
that does do those things is
thermophilic composting or thermal
composting that's where you heat a
compost um up by balancing the carbon
and nitrogen ratios to 161 degrees for
48 hours and then um well sorry above
141 degrees but below 165 I believe is
the um current standards for composting
and that thermal process and turning the
pile will allow for the aerobic
microorganisms to create this exothermic
reaction it heats up the pile as they
reproduce rapidly and that kills off the
weed seeds and kills off the pathogens
in there so so
optimally and it's very hard to find
commercially uh you would do a
combination of these things where you
would take a compost you would thermally
heat it you would then let some worms
work through it or maybe a static
statically compost the the material
longer after it's gone through this
thermal process and that's going to
create your most biodiverse high quality
compost from a from a biological
perspective now what's available
commercially for compost is mostly worm
castings and thermal composts uh because
of that pathogen requirement that you're
you're usually have to deal with so what
I what I find on the market typically
for commercial compost is pretty poor
and so I've searched around our area to
see what's available and um in the
Northwest these are the best composts
that I found so uh the first one is this
o mountain fish compost it's a it's a
2-year aged fish compost it's a very
dark Rich uh color to it um it has a
fair amount of nitrogen it's reasonably
low in heavy metals they do use a little
bit of postc consumer waste so there's
yard waste in there unfortunately um so
I will on occasion come across little
bits of plastic or other things in the
compost um but the big thing that they
do well I think and frankly the quality
has gone down a little bit in the last
few years I feel like um is they age the
compost for a minimum of two years after
thermal composting it and that's the key
difference I think in quality because a
lot of the commercial composts that you
see on the market um are really only
composted for like 60 to 90 days they're
turned really quickly and so you just
don't end up with something that's
necessarily a finished product and that
can cause issue with um there being high
levels of ammonium the nitrogen still
cycling the biological communities in
those composts are just not as evolved
or as uh beneficial for plants so if you
can find yourself a high quality compost
and as a side note if you're formulating
a soil mix it should always start with
the compost these recipes I see online
where people just list a bunch of
ingredients those recipes your results
are going to vary um absolutely because
everyone's compost source is different
and compost brings in a fair amount of
fertility and so you need to account for
that when you're mixing and formulating
a soil mix so that's the oie fish
compost uh one that one that we
discovered in the last couple of years
is this Lane compost they are out of
Oregon um I'm really excited about it I
really like the the look of the compost
um and what we've done with them is they
have a fish compost as well I really
like fish composts in general but they
can be high in heavy metals so what
we've done with the lane compost is
we've taken their um garden compost and
their fish compost post we have it
specially Blended just for us at 50/50
and we've had that tested for heavy
metals and for fertility and then we've
created soil mixes around that blend and
this is something that I like because
it's significantly lower in heavy metals
and we're seeing good overall plant
growth and health from using the lane
compost again they do use a small amount
of uh postc consumer waste but I think
less than what I see in the oie either
that or they're they're uh filtering it
a lot better but um
I tend to I tend to like this compost
myself a little bit better than the oie
um so this is sort of my go-to for the
most affordable high quality compost
I've seen um available here in the
Northwest and we do sell all of these
composts on our website if you can't
find something locally that you want to
use in your
garden um the next one that I have is
the highest quality commercial compost
that I've found um it's called SE Coast
compost they're actually doing a
biodynamic process which you can read
about it's um it's it's a variety of
different uh preps that they do
specifically for their compost um they
do also use fish products uh to make
this compost and there is no postc
consumer waste so there you don't have
to worry about Plastics or any sort of
trace residues of things that gardeners
might have thrown in their yard bin that
may not have broken down um as rapidly
as you may have liked so that's where
the SE SE Coast compost shines um and
for our cannabis Growers that are in
regulated States for heavy metals we now
do a blend with this compost because it
is by far the lowest heavy metal compost
that we found um on the market so it's a
it's a wonderful alternative it's just
it's just more expensive it cost us more
to ship it here because they're a small
outfit uh on the coast of or of the
Oregon post so the shipping cost is
higher and the cost of the compost for
them to make it and produce it is higher
too so um if you have a little more room
in your budget and you are concerned
about heavy metals or Plastics and
things like that this is a wonderful
option um it's what I'm currently using
in um my garden since we've discovered
it and started formulating with it over
the last couple of
years all right so moving on to worm
castings so we call this our fungal
compost this is really uh a worm
castings product though we take a
combination of a few different worm
castings and composts we add nutrients
to it things like um organic alfalfa
meal for example as a way of Awakening
and invigorating the biology
specifically the fungal communities in
the soil and then we use this for making
compost tea now we call it a fungal
compost but it contains all sets of
microorganisms and it's something that
um that we really like using like I said
in compost tea but you can also top
dress your plant with it and things like
that as a way of increasing your soil
biology so that's what this product is
now we do have a worm castings that is
made from African worm castings and this
is the most visually appealing compost
um worm castings I've ever seen the
African worms take a little bit larger
poop and so you have these little tiny
uh very rich fertile balls that um you
can see and I'll try and put a photo up
of it U but this is a very clean uh nice
looking compost um that is made from
African worms that is is really great it
has good biological activity uh and
we've used it for years similar to the
fungal compost in fact this makes up a a
portion of our fungal compost recipe
okay so again to recap if you're
thinking about a compost do your
research uh get a chemical analysis from
the company get a heavy metal analysis
find out exactly what's in it ask them
what they're using to make the compost
and make sure that what you're starting
with is high quality the compost
fraction I can't emphasize enough just
how important it is okay moving on
though to what I have in front of me
here this is kind of what's left of
amendments I have on this side some um
some
Blended craft fertilizers and then over
here I have some trace minerals and just
a few things that I haven't I didn't get
to talk about in the last video because
I ran out of space
so let's start with the trace minerals
so first one over here this crazy
looking uh blue crystals this is copper
sulfate so copper sulfate is a a great
opt option if you need to raise copper
levels in your soil if you do you're
using the tiniest amount of the stuff
we're talking fractions of teaspoons in
most cases for hom Growers because it's
highly concentrated and you you don't
want to overdo it now there is good
research to show high levels of copper
will help with some uh disease pressures
apparently um on the pathogen side but
again with all of these trace minerals I
would say be very very careful in fact
with our soil test testing analysis that
we offer through kiss we don't
automatically give Trace mineral
recommendations and the reason for this
is because we typically don't see
deficiencies in living soils related to
trace minerals it's usually something
more like their watering or your uh
macronutrients you know nitrogen
potassium calcium phosphorus um those
sorts of things that you're going to see
the you're going to see issues with so
rarely is it trace minerals and once all
of those things are dialed or if we get
a leaf tissue analysis that definitely
shows us that we have uh a trace mineral
deficiency then we'll begin to address
it
now some people don't want to use this
because you know it's blue crystals it's
obviously been refined and processed it
is approved for use by the national
organic uh the NOP the national organic
program uh for organic production if you
can show you have a defic based off a
soil test now for those people that
don't want to use something like that
hold on let me show you what else there
is so there are products like this
product here so
this this is a liquid fertilizer this is
biomin boron and so what they're doing
is they're taking that copper sulfate
they're Keating it so bonding it with
like an amino acid or or or some other
organic molecule and then uh essentially
selling it to you as a lower
concentration in this case liquid form
of copper so you would use this at a
slightly higher rates so it's easier to
dose and there's a number of companies
that offer products like this I just
happen to have the biomin one with me
but uh you can't find that so that is
another alternative again also approved
for use in organic production
okay moving on to
manganese now we have started adding
manganese to our recommendations in very
low doses um it's one of the one it's
one of the safer trace minerals to add
uh so if you if you were going to go
down the rout of trace minerals I would
start with manganese now these are two
different options for manganese you can
see one's a very fine powder and one is
a a little tiny ball essentially now for
these sorts of amendments if you're
adding them to soil I like to mix them
with water and then water them in to get
a more even application because again
we're talking parts per million on these
things so we use the powder primarily
and I think for my last um my last soil
run I added two teaspoons per yard of
soil so again like like I said very
small small
amounts all right so moving on here this
is zinc sulfate same sort of thing as
the others it's just a white powder um
you would use it in very very small
amounts uh next we have iron sulfate or
Ferris sulfate now iron is tough because
iron is just not available in the pH
ranges that we like to that our plants
are going to be happy in Iron becomes
most available I think in a in a pH
around of four to 4 and a half which uh
frankly is Not Practical for growing
plants um once you get to higher levels
it it it oxidizes almost immediately
so uh there are some ways around this
you could Bryant so doctor Consulting
he's he's talked about creating little
pockets in the soil near the plant roots
where you put a bunch of iron sulfate in
there together um as a way of maybe
allowing plants to access iron when we
see
low iron that's where that's where you
see um a lighter yellow color around the
growing um center of the plant um plants
will typically outgrow it so I I rarely
do a lot in regards to addressing iron
just because it is so it is so tricky in
that regard and and we seem to see we
seem to hit sufficiency already in most
cases but one of the ways that you can
you can look to do that is through iron
sulfate
okay so I think that's the main trace
minerals other than Boron I don't have
boron in front of me but it's going to
look very similar to the zinc sulfate
it's a white powder um Boron is one you
want to be especially careful with uh it
is needed for plant processes but in
very very low rates and so we we rarely
add um we rarely add Boron and if you do
be aware that there's a big difference
between Borox or sorry borax which you
can find in the grocery store people use
it for laundry and cleaning um solubor
which I believe is like six to eight
times stronger levels of boron so you
want to make sure you're adjusting your
application rates accordingly or
something like this um which I think is
only like 6 to 8% Boron
so again just make sure you don't over
apply Boron because some of these Trace
Min minerals can actually cause soils to
be um infertile or inhospitable to
plants uh by overdoing it okay moving on
to
Mineral applications in the form of like
rock dusts and these these other
products
so first off we have Jersey greens sand
um I believe it's higher in pottassium
now as a general rule with these Rock
dusts I first started using these at
fairly High rates because of the work of
Steve Solomon and Clackamus cot saying
that trace minerals are really important
to plants and we want to make sure to
have good uh good levels in there by
getting a lot of natural rock dust and
things like that into our soil so
originally I was using these products
more I've since backed off quite a bit
for a few reasons um one they're really
heavy like shockingly heavy I mean it's
rock dust so uh they're going to raise
the weights of your soil which for us is
Big because we're shipping soil in some
cases to people um so if we can lower
our weights that's good uh the biggest
reason though is because of heavy metals
all of these Rock Dust anything that's
derived from you know uh that's mined is
going to have levels of heavy metals and
rock dusts are going to have it in
higher levels than some of these other
products like gypsum and things like
that so where the where the rock dust is
aligned from will have a dramatic impact
on the chemical composition of the rock
dust so of the rock dust that we sell
and use the one that I like the best is
this
balt and it it has the lowest levels of
heavy metals um it's paramagnetic some
people uh believe that that has plant
growth Properties or plant Health
properties um if I were to use a rock
dust that's the one that I would use and
again I I was using them at much higher
rates I don't use them at nearly the
rates I used to um anymore and the other
thing with this and something I've
learned from working with a lot of soil
scientists and experts expert
agronomists uh from the podcast is that
these these Rock Dust are not typically
very plant available in the period of
time that we want results in so we're
talking months to years uh potentially
decades for some of these things to
break down whereas we have access to
other ways to get these minerals much
much faster uh with releasing rates that
we can understand and control a lot
better so of the of the minerals and
rock dust and things that you see here
uh I have glacial Rock Dust which again
fine powder especially important I think
with these Rock Dust is the particle
size and surface area uh in terms of how
quickly microbes can break them down so
if you can get a much finer powder or
micronized version it's going to be more
much more available than larger chunks
or larger particulate size uh we also
have azomite that's a aluminous silicate
that's also a mind
product not something that I use I know
some Growers really like it it's just I
think there's better ways to get trace
minerals than than azomite uh and it
will bring in other things that you may
not want like aluminum and other um
other heavy
metals let's see here oh here this was
the example of the the
um the African worm castings that I
actually put into a thing here so let's
see moving
on okay humates these this is from a
company called Live Earth this is a um
mind product as well humates are the
humic acids and humates are in theory
what happens when a plant material is is
broken down um through that composting
decomposition process and what is left
at the end is uh higher in uh chelation
property so it's it's better able to
bond with other minerals and nutrients
um and has some a variety of plant
properties now most humic acid products
are um their mind typically and are
typically extracted from leonardite uh
but which is a particular Rock mineral
there are other ones that are derived
from Plants um but yeah that's
essentially what you're looking at there
there is a lot more research in the last
decade around humic substances and their
plant benefits I would throw the caveat
out there that um you do have levels of
humic substances if you're using compost
already you may see benefit to adding
more uh but the research that I've seen
is a bit varied so it's not something
that I use a ton of but I can I I do
appreciate that there is research to
support the use of humid substances in
your garden and I am hoping to get an
expert on to talk more in depth about it
here in the
future okay next I have molted barley so
the idea behind malted barley grain is
that and this is this is all from
Clackamus cud this is where this all
started it's that the nutrients all the
nutrients that the plant needs is
contained in the seed and if we take
that seed and we Sprout that seed and
then arrest that sprouting process
that's what essentially malting is that
we use for beer making and other uh
other beverages essentially what that
does is that that stops that enzymatic
process at its highest level so when we
originally started what cute had
everyone doing was sprouting seeds and
then grinding them up and then apply in
that as a way to raise the en enzymatic
levels in your soil and pick up a
variety of different um
enzymes now we've since moved on to Malt
to the malting this is just much simpler
and easier and it's done professionally
for you consistently because if you let
the seed go too long or you don't apply
it right away you can't end up with
alcohols or other things that could
damage your plant now I did some
research I did some trials sorry I
didn't do research I did some trials
with this in my garden and I didn't get
the plant response that other people
have claimed they have gotten uh so it's
not something that I use but again I
just want to share why Growers are doing
it and the I the theory behind why they
might use it I would love to see some
actual research come out on this uh in
the future
but that's that's that's where the
malted grain comes in and that's why
people use it and so essentially you
would just grind it up in a blender and
then uh top dress it was and over the
top and you should see better overall
plant growth and plant health and some
people claim their plants just explode
in growth again I did not get that
response myself um but that doesn't mean
it's going to be the same for
everybody okay uh corn gluten meal I
just threw this one in here it really
doesn't belong I just um forgot to do it
in the last video and I had some it's
not something we sell a lot of uh you
will see it sold in big box stores as a
weed uh pre-emergent so when cor corn
gluten meal it's hard to say is applied
to Lawns at the right time in the spring
it can help prevent weed seeds from
germinating so it does have um some of
those properties but it is also a source
of nitrogen so I just want to mention it
but it's not one that I recommend or use
a
lot okay so now what I have left here
are all various blends of um uh organic
amendments and sometimes that's easier
for folks you know if you don't want to
go through the the trials and
tribulations of mixing your own and you
want something that you know is going to
be consistent or give you an expected
response this is this is a good option
for folks so the first one I have here
this is what we call our micro Catalyst
this does have some nutrient level or
fertilizer level in it but what we use
this for is after testing a variety of
different recipes and products products
we ended up using this microb Catalyst
as a um essentially a micro catalyst so
when we make compost teas for example in
a five gallon Brewer we would use a half
a cup of this with a tablespoon of
organic Alfalfa as our food source and
we get a much better overall um growth
of mic microbes across all sets of
microorganisms and better U diversity in
biomass than if we were just using
molasses that being said head if you
live somewhere where you have easy
access to organic black strap molasses
that is another alternative that you can
use for making compost tea molasses is
also sticky it's hard to deal with this
is just much easier and so that's one of
the other reasons that we really like it
so that's some that's the microb
catalysts that we
produce uh next one I have here this
lighter colored one is our Bloom booster
that's this product right here the kiss
Bloom booster is something that Andrew
on our team team worked really dedicated
uh two years almost in formulating to
get just the right ratios of organic
mment to give us the highest levels of
available p and K just a little bit of
nitrogen and then um the clean absolute
cleanest heavy metals report in regards
to uh organic Bloom boosters that I've
seen on the market it's so clean on
heavy metals so if you are worried about
heavy metals which frankly it's
something I think everyone should be
thinking about or if you're in a
regulated state where you're tested for
heavy metals this is a wonderful
option all
right so this product here this is
Solomon's mix and what this is this is
Steve Solomon's recipe for making a
complete organic fertilizer
now one thing I want to mention with
this is this is designed for growing
mineral
nutrient-rich mineral dense vegetables
it's not made for maximizing your
cannabis Harvest or yield and Steve
acknowledges that
so it doesn't have the same ratios or
levels of fertility as some of the other
uh ones I'm going to talk about here but
what it will do is it will give you much
higher levels of trace and minerals uh
Steve is a big proponent of using these
trace minerals in low levels as a way of
raising the overall nutrition of the
food and while there isn't a ton of
research on this topic um there there
are a lot of Growers that are using this
for their vegetable gardens if they
don't aren't doing soil testing this is
sort of his best guess recipe for what
he thinks your garden might need so
that's the Steve Solomon
CF now this this is our mineral mix um
this is if you want to get a combination
of you know these limes and some rock
dust and those sorts of things uh
without buying all the
individual products so so if you want to
get some calcium as well as some trace
minerals in the form of rock dust again
Rock Dust are not my favorite but we do
make this product um and it is available
for for people who are looking for
something like that so for example if
you had a garden and you already had the
macro nutrients and you just wanted to
add some more uh trace minerals and you
weren't in a rush for them to be a
immediately available to your to your
vegetable garden for example this is
this is an option in that
regard and then this last one here this
is our nutrient pack this is where we
started as a company I formulated this
and we've made little tweaks to it but I
formulated this 15 shoot maybe even I
think yeah probably about 15 20 years
ago now and what this is is this is the
nutrient portion of our
soil mix for our water only and our
biocharge soils so if you can't you know
or if if shipping soil to you is not
practical because you're on the other
side of the country for example and you
can mix your own soils but you don't
want to guess at the minerals and
nutrients that your plant might need um
this is a great way to do that so we
have a whole example on the page of a
walkth through how you would use this
product it can be top dressed similar to
the our balloon booster and both of
these products are registered for use in
organic
production for folks and this is
something that we took a long time to
come up with so if you're re amending
your soil or you're mixing new soils uh
this nutrient pack is a great option and
that's this product right here oh it's
heavy there we
go okay so all that being said I have a
few other products kind of floating
around here that I wanted to touch on uh
before we go so
first off I have this uh this is from
dinoo this is micro risal fungi now I've
done a lot of videos and I have a blog
post on micro isal fungi but I want to
talk a little bit about it in here
because it's it's sort of part of what
people do when they're growing plants
so microanal fungi is a particular
species or spe or um classification of
fungus that forms a symbiotic
relationship with the roots of our
plants um there are a variety of
different species of micro risal fungi
and they can be very plant specific so
for example in this product we have
glomus
inates and glomus masier and those two
are have a relationship with um fruit
trees cannabis most vegetables not
brassicas though
um and the way you would use this would
be a one-time application directly to
your roots of your plant when the plant
is Young so for things like lettu uses I
probably wouldn't bother with it for
things like tomatoes peppers maybe your
cannabis plant um what we'll what you'll
see by adding a product like this is
higher uh uptake of phosphorus and other
nutrients um better drought resistance
and and ability to cope with different
environmental uh abiotic stresses so
micro isal fungi is great the one thing
about it is for people who are concerned
about heavy metals uh in regulated
States I've kind of shied away from this
because there is research that shows
that uh micro isal funge will increase
the uptake of heavy metals which makes
sense because it increases the uptake of
and flow of nutrients into the plant it
is a very um mutualistic uh relationship
that it has with your plant and your
plant roots so
uh those that's the one case use case
where I wouldn't use it
now when shopping around for a micro
risal product there's a few things to
keep in mind so you may you may look on
the back and see propagules or cfus or
um Spore count and that's where things
get really confusing
because there there are different types
of micro isal fungi like I mentioned um
some are Endo micro isal fungi which in
the case of most most of our plants uh
like this um like fruit trees vegetables
things like that that's what we're
looking for and these glomus species
fall into that category there are other
micro isal species that are Ecto microa
and those actually form a sheath around
the outside of the roots whereas these
infect inside the plant you cannot see
endom micro risal fungi on a plant root
without staining the roots and looking
with a microscope I hear people say oh
that's you know they see you know little
white fuzziness around a healthy root
and they say oh that has micro isal
fungi that's not micro isal fungi that's
just healthy root hairs in the case of
vegetables fruit trees things like that
now if you have a conifer then Ecto
microa is the type of Micro isal fungi
that you want and so when you look on
some of these labels you may see you
know in this case we have 700 propagules
per gram of glomus inates that's a
pretty high level assuming that this
package contains what it says it does
and that's a whole another thing within
the gardening industry is you can't
necessarily trust these labels to be
accurate now I trust this company but
that doesn't mean I you know there's
research through the Oregon Department
of egg that shows that many of these
companies and what they list on the
labels are not always 100% what's
actually in the product but you may see
one that shows two million uh spores or
cfus per per gram of uh micro risal
fungi but if it's Ecto mro isal fungi
it's not going to form a relationship
with your cannabis plant and so you
can't really count those towards you
getting a good infection level so it's
important to buy the right type for the
plant that you're growing I can't
emphasize that
enough now uh in addition to that this
product is you know glomus intereses
glomus masier uh you may find another
product like um pumpkin Pro for example
that may have uh glomus atates also
called Riso fagus irregularis uh just to
further complicate things um if it's
made somewhere else by a different
company that's producing it it's going
to be a slightly different strain and
when that happens you may get slightly
different results so I did a whole
podcast with the the creator of this
product and one of the things that he
talks about is the the the strain that
they're using of glomus andin was
developed out of
uh Israel and it's a very uh it came
from a very harsh environment so it's
very good at dealing with a variety of
environmental conditions including um a
lack of water like drought stress and
things like that so when you see any of
these microbial products what we're
talking about here is they're one
they're not going to be all the same
even if they have the same name like
tricoderma you know you're not
necessarily getting the same strain
species of tricoderma from if you're
buying it from different companies so
you may have to try different ones to
get different results um but you just
have to keep in mind too that these
these these will give you
um these will give you good results if
you use them correctly but it's
important to do your research okay
enough on
that what else do we have here
oh so this is our uh compost te kit not
gonna spend a lot of time on compost te
this is where our company started before
I ever got into these amendments um I
have a wonderful blog on compost te if
you want to read more about it um and
I'm happy to answer any questions
compost tea is not a silver bullet as
some people may tell you but what it
does do is it increases the biological
um activity in your soil potentially
because you're adding a lot more
microbes and it can increase nutrient
cycling I think that's the key thing to
think about is is increasing nutrient
cycling in your soil and so our kit this
is what we'd use in our 5 gallon
microbat it's a compost which contains
the biology then we have the food source
to feed that biology it goes into the
Brewer which creates the optimal
environment for these microbes to
reproduce and then we take that tea and
apply it to our soil or to our plants
um again it's important to understand
that compost tea is not the Cure All for
everything but certain in certain um
cases people can get pretty dramatic
results from it it is going to give you
a little bit of fertility primarily
nitrogen um when you add that so it's
something to account for too when you're
making and using compost
teas okay this is H egil 168 or
potassium silicate this is what many of
the silica products on the market are
derived from this is just a uh powdered
form and the advantage being cost so you
can take this and make your own silica
own gallon of silica out of a pound of
this uh for you know Pennies on the
dollar compared to what they charge to
to give it to you in a fancy bottle um
it's uh 32% potassium negligable amount
though when you think about how much
you're using so I would take something
this size add it to a gallon of water
and then
um shake it really well and then use it
at a rate of a teaspoon or two per
gallon of water of that liquid
concentrate that I've made so again
you're not using very much but this is a
great way to get silica consistently
into your plant it's something you could
water with um you know every watering or
every other watering throughout your
plant's life cycle to get a lot of the
benefits of
silica let's see so over here I have the
Pacific grow Oceanic fish hydrate they
also make a product called sea fos The
reason it's not sitting here is because
I I used it recently with my plants um
it's going to be a little bit higher in
phosphorus because it's stabilized with
phosphoric acid um but fish hydrate caos
these types of products are sort of your
cheap bloom formula or grow formula
liquid formula it's one of the few
liquid products that I really like to
have on hand because all the stuff I've
talked about so far it takes a little
while you know it can take five five to
10 days for you to really see a plant
response after fertilizing and if you
have a plant that's low in nutrients we
don't want to wait that long we don't
want to let it suffer for that long
because that's going to impact its
overall health make it more um more
susceptible to diseases more susceptible
to pests because it's stressed out and
it's going to impact our overall yield
so in those cases if I see I have a
nitrogen deficiency for example if I'm
seeing a lighter yellow plant yellowing
leaves at the bottom I'm going to hit it
with something like this and maybe do a
top dressing of a nitrogen Amendment at
the same time as a way to get some
immediate end of the plant and then I'll
probably do a few feedings of something
like this to kind of spoon feed it or
the other way I use this or the sea f is
if I'm halfway through the cycle and I
realize I under amended my plants then
um I can kind of spoon feed them you
know essentially like I would if it was
a bottle of nutrient to get them through
the rest of the growth cycle or if you
have really little plants um you know
seedlings things like that this is
another great way to dose fertility at
low levels for your plants so the one
the one bad thing about fish hydrate is
it stinks it smells like fish it's a
really strong smell that's the one
downside to these products but other
than that I really like to use
them um microbial products
so we primarily are using microbial mass
now and actually the founder of Mammoth
P um Colin Bell who I've had on the
podcast a good friend of mine he's over
there at microbial Mass too and I
actually knew the founders of microbial
Mass way back in the day when they first
we're getting started uh and they're
great folks Mammoth P was sort of that
first product on the market they're
actually no longer around this is what's
left of my Supply and I just had a had
one here so I thought I'd show it to you
but by adding specific microbes in this
case uh PS solubilizing microbes um
we're going to get better nutrient
uptake and there's there's actually a
fair bit of research around using these
sorts of microbial bio stimulants um
that are very targeted versus something
like compost te which is just a shotgun
approach of microbes we're just putting
out all the microbes that were in the
compost and seeing which ones uh the
plant might want whereas here we're
we're targeting it with very high
concentrated levels of specific microbes
that we know do specific things um again
I'm showing you Mammoth P only because
I'm using this up and then I'll be um
switching over to microbial Mass which
we do have available on our
website um let's see what
else okay one last thing to talk about
is silica so I've already talked about
the benefits of silica but one of the
things to know about silica is
availability and if you want to do a
deep dive on this I did a podcast with
Dr Wendy zelner she is a silica expert
and uh explained it much better than I
will in this video but essentially
there's three different sources of
silica that we can use in our garden and
they have different availability to the
plant so one the most so the first one
be Amorphis and that's what this um egg
sill is and it's a very uh it's one of
the most plant available forms of silica
uh because it converts it to cicc acid
and then the plant can take that
up uh the next one would be um biogenic
silica and that would be something that
just essentially it's plant derived so
you you hear of silica derived from Rice
holes or from um bamboo that would be a
biogenic source of silica and the issue
with um with that is just you may be
picking up heavy metals and it's not
going to be as available as Amorphis
forms and then the last form is quartz
and quartz is literally Rock and that's
what these sorts of um products are and
I'm not picking on this company they're
very nice they sent me this product um
the one problem I have with these
products is we don't know when or how
available they actually are from my
understanding from talking to Dr zelner
is we're talking period of months to
years before this silica becomes
available and because there's so many
variables in terms of when it would
become available like um you know how
much weathering has occurred the
particle size the moisture level the
microbes in the soil uh where we really
just don't know when we're going to be
getting that silica or those trace
minerals so keep that in mind with
products like
this uh let's see okay so so I have a
few IPM products that I just keep in my
garden pantry and so I just wanted to
add those to the end of this video just
because I like to use them um oh but
before I do I forgot about dious Earth I
meant to put one put some in here it's a
white flower looking product there is
actually good research that shows that
dious Earth will provide available
silica uh I believe it was Dr um
Nicole go apologies for that Dr Nicole
goce did research and showed a 70%
reduction in powdery mildew by using
dious Earth and wellas night I think as
SI sources um but again I'm doing this
off off of memory so I I will I will
have to check and double check that one
but that is another option for getting
available
silica okay so moving on to
IPM what I have here yellow sticky card
most of you guys are familiar with these
what I want to share and this particular
one is from catchmaster I really like
this brand um and I've talked to the
owners of the company the nice thing
about this is it's
um sticky cards have g a lot better you
know um this adhesive while sticky it
doesn't stay stuck to my hands I don't
end up with this glue that I'm like
picking out on my fingers for the next
you know the next day or so if this gets
in my hair I can I can get it out pretty
easily with a little bit of soapy water
um whereas some of the brands out there
that use a a lower quality adhesive will
will have issues in that regard but it
is enough to catch insects so that's the
key there how much and what type of
adhesive do you want to use to catch
insects without without being really
hard to work with and things like that
so these cards as you can see they have
um see if I can show you
here they have perforations on them this
is the back side U of the card the front
side has has the the black better let me
see if I can pull it off here so you can
see that there this is for scouting so
you can keep you can keep track of what
sort of insect pressure you have you can
use these cards for Mass trapping but
the main benefit of these cards is not
mass trapping it's to keep track of
what's in your garden right now is it a
fungus net is it a rud Aid is it a
beneficial is it is it just not a pest
at all just something flying around that
happen to get into my room it's
important to track these and change
these out regularly so
I can't tell you how many grows I've
gone into where these things are just
covered with fungus knats or they've
been up for months that doesn't give us
any good information you need to be
changing these out
consistently so that's what these sensor
cards are now if you do need to do Mass
trapping I'm only sharing this because
some people weren't aware that this was
a thing you can buy the same material in
these giant rolls so you can string this
across your whole garden and this this
is for Mass trapping so if you just are
trying to catch a lot of fungus snats or
root aphids or whatever flying winged
pest that you have that's hitting your
garden this is the kind of this is what
you want to use something like this so
only I'm only telling you so people know
it's
available this would not be my only form
of dealing with a insect in infestation
though either this would use be used in
conjunction with something else now
Laden flour you can't spray maybe
something like this comes more into play
otherwise Mass traff ping and
conjunction with various sprays uh is a
great way to help control these things
or drenches you know we might use
Bavaria we might use um isera there's a
there's a number of
microbial uh products that we can apply
specifically for dealing with certain
insect issues but when it comes to
sprays I want to show you the two
products that I keep in my garden and
that I'm the most excited about so the
first one is this montere horticultural
oil this is also known as s X this is
just the homeowner size I don't need a
giant size for my small garden this is
this is more than enough um and this is
mineral oil based now some people don't
want a mineral oil based product and I
totally get that um keep in mind though
with this this product there's a lot of
good research in terms of what sort of
residual it leaves behind um as well as
when you know what it's going to do so
this is primarily suffocant it's going
to suffocate all the insects um that
that it comes into cont tack so this is
a really good knockdown spray and you
can also use it for dipping and a
variety of other things without risking
phytotoxicity but for folks who don't
want to deal with a horticultural oil um
or something that might be derived from
mineral
oil this is a new product and this is
just a sample size here uh that being
said this sample size is 3.6 flu ounces
um this is enough for 30 or 40 gallons
of spray solution now right now uh sorry
product's called EPA Shield I probably
should have led with that um it's from
bioworks it is a really um it's a really
cool Plant Botanical product that
they've that they've uh they've created
and formulated and it uses much lower
concentrations than any other Botanical
product on the market um so you have you
have virtually no risk of phytotoxicity
and it's there's a ton of research
behind it so I I I normally don't get
behind 25b products these are products
that are using ingredients that are
shown to be exempt
from the uh EPA registration list uh and
the reason why I don't like these is
because anyone could mix something
together and call it a insecticide and
and and if they're using 25b products
they can register it and and sell it
whereas there's a ton of research around
EPA shield and data to support the
efficacy of this product and I'm hoping
to have some something this size
available to you guys here really soon
because right now the only available
sizes are quite large and much more than
the average hom grower whatever want or
need but this stuff smells amazing as
well so yeah this is probably my new
favorite go-to spray now the one thing
about that Dr Michael brownbridge was
actually just telling me
yesterday uh suffoil X or monor
horiculture oil is actually effective at
um dealing with the the egg stage of
thrips now thrips lay their egg they can
lay their eggs actually inside the leaf
tissue and this will seem to block that
little hole that allows them to breathe
before they emerge from the leaf
tissue so that's where something like
this would win out we're not seeing that
same effect with the EPA Shield but EPA
Shield has really good efficacy ac
across almost all U cannabis pests so
you can go to the website at bioworks
and check out uh the entire label on it
there but again really excited about and
these are the two products that I like
to use in my garden
so all right I think I covered the
majority of organic inputs that you can
find uh that are available for your
garden of course there's other ones out
there feel free to ask any questions
below in the comments and I'm happy to
try and answer them as well um but yeah
if you want to start playing around and
mixing your own soils or utilizing
organic amendments um this is a great
way to get going I hope that was helpful
thanks guys