hey guys Tad here with kiss Organics I
wanted to share this talk because I get
a lot of questions about what inputs are
safe to use in your garden and I hear a
lot of talk about this on social media
uh online as well as in other groups so
this is a talk I put together for the
living soil Summit this year in prump
Nevada and I wanted to re-record it here
to share on YouTube so the question I
was looking at is what inputs are safe
to use in your Garden um there's a lot
that goes into what products you choose
to use to grow your plants with and it's
important to be thoughtful about those
choices so let's start by looking at
some common agricultural fertilizers the
industrial meat industry is awful and
there's no denying that these animals
are fed GMO grains and antibiotics or
crops that have been sprayed with
glyphosate which is also Roundup
therefore these fertilizers will be
contaminated with GMOs and antibiotics
and pesticides and you're contaminating
your crop when you use these inputs in
fact blood meal bone meal and feather
meal are not truly organic one could
even say they're fake organic because
they come from the waist streams of our
industrial meat supply
chain so what are the Alternatives
amendments like fishbone meal or fish
meal are much better because they're
from the ocean if you have a good source
like wild CAU fish then you're not
utilizing uh then you are utilizing
cleaner amendments in your garden and
you're not supporting the horrible meat
industry and you're doing better by the
environment it's an allaround win now
that's a really compelling argument
right there it aligns with my values as
someone who cares about Organics and the
environment but what I wanted to do
today is take a deeper look at these
claims and see what research exists to
either support or refute this idea let's
talk about the conditions under which
animals are raised in the meat industry
to be honest the they're not great this
to me is the best argument for not using
these inputs however I also look at it
from a sustainability perspective if we
know that these fertilizers are safe
that they're low and heavy metals that
they do not contain GMOs or pesticides
and are very affordable then it makes
sense to me to be closing the loop as
realistically they're not going anywhere
whether whether these waste products end
up in compost fertilizer or even a
landfill and I know many folks in the
room are into biomimicry essentially
doing what they think Mother Nature
might do and I can't think of anything
more natural or higher use than using a
dead body to recycle the nutrients to
grow something
new so what about the fishing industry
is it superior to the meat industry well
most folks are familiar with the issues
associated with Farm fish farm fish are
raised in high density conditions
similar to the meat industry Farm fish
have a higher rate of disease and can be
higher in contaminants due to their
diets they make up more than half of the
fish consumption within the United
States between 70 and 80% of the fish of
the seafood consumed in the United
States is actually imported but this is
a bit of a misleading statistic because
a portion of it is caught by American
fishermen exported overseas for
processing and then reimported back into
the US
uh and they use open net cages that can
leech chemicals into the ocean putting
ocean Wildlife at risk and damaging
ecosystems and farm fish have been known
to escape their pens which can spread
disease to Native populations because
Farm fish are regularly fed antibiotics
because of their greater propensity for
disease and parasites uh many Farm fish
are genetically modified as well and can
contaminate native populations like I
mentioned above and their waste can
produce phytoplankton blooms which
destroy local ecology so we can safely
say that farm fish are not a reasonable
alternative to the meat
industry so what about wild CAU fish
then you know it's estimated that 80% of
the world's natural fish stocks are
fully to ere exploited depleted or in a
state of Collapse by catch is a term
referring to The Unwanted fish or other
Marine cat creatures that are caught by
commercial fishing
practices sometimes the amount of by
catch that is captured killed and
discarded can be as high as 80% for
certain Fisheries so this is something
like if they are fishing for a
particular fish species like salmon and
they catch an octopus or some other
animal that would be considered by catch
and scientists agree that a cur a
current exploitation levels that many
important fish stocks will be removed
from the system within 25 years and
lastly there's a massive fossil fuel
cost associated with wild C caught fish
both in the fishing itself and the
transportation of the fish that import
exportation associated with processing
that I mentioned before so basically
resources from the ocean can have
negative impacts on our environment and
challenges to sustainability as
well so I wanted to try and see what
research there was out on this so after
a little bit of digging I found a paper
entitled chemical characterization of
commercial organic fertilizers by Kurt
mhler that was published in 2015 in the
archives of agronomy and soil science uh
in this paper the authors talk about how
there are a wide range of commercial
organic fertilizers but not a lot of
research as to how heavy metals organic
pollutants like forever chemicals pcbs
pesticides and antibiotic residues
persist in these fertilizers and how
much variation you might see in these
fertilizers and it took me a while to
track down this paper as it wasn't
easily accessible online but it did
appear to address some of the original
idea of whether or not these fertilizers
are safe or should be avoided for the
reasons that I mentioned at the
beginning of the
talk so what they did was they took a
collection of uh 77 total fertilizer
samples across a range of products
ranging from feather meal bone meal
cocoa shells cloverg glass cloverg grass
pellets flax meal corn gluten-based
fertilizers and many more you can see
the list
here they analyze the material on a wide
iety parameters ranging from pH EC salt
content organic matter percentage NPK
trace minerals along with heavy metals
pesticides antibiotics GMOs and pcbs
those forever
chemicals here's some of what they found
and feel free to pause it if you want to
go back and look at the data but
depending on the product they
essentially found varying levels of
heavy metals based on the product Source
basically all the fertilizers had some
levels of heavy metals though many were
below the detection limits of the
equipment used in the
study and here's some more of that
information uh relating to um organic
persistent pollutant content and the
number of positive tests for salmonella
and pesticides in these
fertilizers so I wanted to highlight
some of the author's comments and notes
in the study as they're related to the
safety of these different fertilizers
and here they State the concentration of
persistent organic pollutants was close
to the detection limit on a very low
level for All sample IED sampled
fertilizers so basically all the
fertilizers had very very low levels of
these pcbs um so there wasn't a big
difference between whether they were
plant-based or meat-based but they were
low across the board so that's that's a
relatively good sign in saying that from
a p from a perspective of uh pcbs pretty
much all these fertilizers were safe um
an iotic compounds were not found and
all the samples were GMO free I think
this is an important statement because
um some of the argument I've been
hearing against using some of these
fertilizers is that they're going to be
tainted with antibiotics and GMOs and
that just simply wasn't the case in this
study based on all the samples that they
took of you know specifically the blood
meal and the bone meal and only some
residues of few pesticides were found in
the few wastes of the food processing
industry incl including The Malt colbs
residues of the corn maze processing
grape pomes cocoa shells and potato
peels so the only fertilizers that had
any pesticide residue were actually the
plant-based ones which makes sense um so
pesticides is not a concern with the
bone meal or blood
meal as
well um here's another here's another
section that I thought was really
interesting so the toxic element
contents of most sampled commercial
organic fertilizers were low compared to
values found for Source separated
organic Urban waste compost or
digestates poultry man manure or other
livestock manures so essentially what
they're saying here is that all these
organic fertilizers are much lower in
heavy metals compared to your compost
Source uh specifically they single out
poultry manure or other livestock
manures uh down below but essentially
most of these animal-based composts are
probably a much greater risk for
bringing in all of the things that we
talked about at the beginning of this
talk than your fertilizer however there
were some exceptions there was high
cadmium content in the waste of the corn
maze the maze corn processing probably
related to the high cadmium contents in
the soil so for any plant-based
fertilizer if that plant has the ability
to take up those heavy metals and
there's heavy metals in the soil that
it's grown in it could potentially be
contaminated and that's something to
consider as well um but there wasn't
High cadmium content in the bone meal or
the blood meal or any of the meat-based
one now there was high lead contents in
Horn and Hooves which could be related
to contamination during the product
drying process using open fires in the
source countries so the way that they
Pro they the authors suspect that the
way that that product the horn and who
product was um processed is actually
what's leading to the high lead not
necessarily the initial U parent
material that was used to make it the
horns and hes themselves and the high
toxic element in micronutrient contents
in the potato peel based fertilizer
might be related to higher concentration
of these elements in the potato skin and
the nutrient grading of these elements
from the periphery towards the center of
the tubers so the idea here being that
the skin of the potato contained higher
levels or higher concentration of um
toxic elements so in this case heavy
metals or micronutrients than um the
actual flesh of the of the
potato as well as potentially some soil
residues adhering to the skin of the
potatoes from processing if that's soil
had higher levels of micronutrients or
heavy metals and then the low
micronutrient content in animal
fertilizers derived from slaughter house
activities was likewise noteworthy so
they tend to be primarily just
containing those Mac nutrients listed
above they don't have a lot of
micronutrient content which is fine
because that's something that we can
always pick up another
way so the measured contamination of the
sampled commercial organic fertilizers
with Organic pluts was several orders of
magnitude lower than the values reported
for organic Urban waste composts again I
just want to highlight it compost is
probably a much bigger risk and and
source of contamination in your garden
than any of these commercial
fertilizers they also state that the
lack of any contamination with
antibiotic compounds in fertilizers
derived from animal slaughter houses is
surprising AS application of anotic
compounds has often become an a replied
procedure in conventional animal
husbandry in the last decades so they're
saying yes they they recognize the fact
that many of these animals were probably
um treated with antibiotics but they
were not finding any actual antibiotic
compounds in the feather meal fish or
feather meal bone meal blood meal um the
ones associated with this
study um however only the minor ratio of
the supplied anabo compounds is absorbed
by The Animals 40 to 90% is excreted by
animal feces therefore the highest
pollution risk with antibiotic residues
can be expected in livestock manures as
confirmed by several
studies so this makes total sense this
IDE aide that antibiotics are ending up
in your blood meal or bone meal is it
doesn't seem to be the case really those
things are moving through the animal
systems just like with humans and ending
up in the waste product so it's really
this poultry manure uh compost or maybe
Poulter manure fertilizer uh as well as
cow manure horse manure where you'd want
to be more concerned with antibiotics
and you may want to look for an organic
Source input source to avoid antibiotics
contamination and now contamination with
pesticide residues was only found in
waste with a lowlevel of processing like
the grape The Malt and the cocoa shells
and many of the compounds found are used
during the storage of feed stock
materials so they may have been treated
with insecticides while they were being
stored um and many of the detected
residues of insecticides belong to
pyrethroids and they list below and and
some even a fungicide in the case of the
great pomade so again these plant-based
fertilizers were more likely to have
pesticide or fungicidal contamination
there was none found in any of the
meat-based
products and most of the commercial
organic fertilizers were derived from a
very complex industrial processes
including Heating and drying at the end
of the processes essentially this leads
to deao
pasteurization so this pasteurization is
going to kill off salmonella ecoli and a
lot of these pathogens as very few are
able to survive uh pasture the
pasteurization process and so then they
State therefore the hygienic status of
most of the commercial organic
fertilizers derived from these complex
processes in the food industry can be
assessed as High um there was one sample
of bone meal that tested positive for
salmonella probably resulting from a
reinfection after the heat treatment so
there may have been something in that
particular process that allowed there to
be potentially uh indicator bacteria for
salmonella in it
now what about mad cows disease this is
another thing I've heard associated with
risks with using bone meal and I would
state that with any um organic
fertilizer that we're putting out uh one
should use proper PPE and in in the case
of things that are dusty like even
alphalpha meal for example you should
wear a mask or respirator to prevent
this stuff from getting into your lungs
especially so though with these
animal-based ones because there are uh
things called prons which which are
resistant to heat and normal
sterilization processes that can make it
through um this whole process that we
just talked about and there were four
deaths in Great Britain uh in the mid
90s from using bone meal uh from cattle
that had mad cows
disease but um they banned in 197 1997
the FDA banned um using protein made
from ruminants like cows fed to other
ruminants like pigs um and the primary
source is in commercial feed of cattle
to to an from an infectious
Source now one thing I learned that I
wasn't aware of is that mad cows disease
uh occurs spontaneously at very low
levels in all cattle populations but
only five cases have ever been have
discovered and reported in the United
States uh ever so it it's happening at a
very low level and it's a very low risk
so you're I I would think that eating
um eating uh meat in a lot of cases if
you're eating anything that has may can
potentially contain brain or spinal cord
tissue that's a much higher risk than um
using bone meal in your product but I
just did want to address that because it
is something that people um bring up as
a potential risk but I in terms of the
risk level of it I just want to state
that it appears to be fairly low so what
about blood meal this was another
interesting one because I
saw on a website um from a popular
company stating that blood meal is full
of antibiotics and pathogens and so I
wanted to research this because that to
me is pretty scary and I don't want to
use anything like that uh so I did I
wasted a good morning one day before the
summit trying to find anything on Google
Scholar that related to blood meal
containing pathogens containing
antibiotics or anything about blood
meals a fertilizer uh that might relate
to this and I was unable to find any
research to support these claims in fact
um it was only listed on this one
website which I think it's been
subsequently removed now and one other
website that used it as a citation to
spread this message and this was I I
show you here one of the web the two
websites I mentioned so what I want to
say is there's no research that I've
been able to find to support this claim
and it would go directly against the
study that I mentioned uh in this um in
this talk and manure-based composts and
Commercial organic fertilizers may be
way more problematic than your blood
meal one paper found that I found showed
that repeated applications of chicken or
swine Pig based uh manure um incre uh
fertilizers increased antibiotic levels
in soils but then most most of it
dissipated over the course of a couple
months but not completely so even worst
case you are getting antibiotics they're
not persistent ing terribly long in the
soil which I thought was was interesting
enough to share these amox are poorly
absorbed and metabolized so much of it
isre excreted in the waste of animals
and humans and there's very little
research on the impact of Veterinary
antibiotics on soil ecosystems
unfortunately so what if we want to
avoid animals or fish Al together or
look into alternative options in the
ones I've already
mentioned what about what about
then well neem has a massive fossil fuel
cost relative to other products uh you
know we're shipping it all the way from
India it has the potential for heavy
metals and pesticide residues even on
organic products um I've mentioned this
before on on the podcast in other talks
where
um Su my friend Suzanne Wayne rght Evans
had worked with a farm who had failed
for a uh a chemistry of pesticides
that's no longer allowed for use in the
United States and hasn't been allowed
since the 70s um and and they tracked it
down after their cannabis crop failing
Unfortunately they tracked it down to uh
the neem oil product they were using and
so essentially that neem seed meal had
been crushed the oil had been extracted
and there was enough residue of
pesticides that had been sprayed onto
that neem tree that it made it into the
oil and then contaminated the product so
basically the point here neem is not a
perfect option or solution either so
what about soft rock phosphates well
it's a minded product so it's going to
contain heavy metals uh there's really
no way around that um and it has large
fossil fuel costs not only the mining
process itself but the transportation of
the product so um you know there may be
mines that are cleaner in other
countries outside of North America but
the cost to get that product here is a
massive fossil fuel cost that one should
account for when considering what
products they want to use in their
Garden if you want to be ecological and
sustainable uh same goes for guos you
know um they work but large fossil fuel
costs associated with them they're
harvested overseas they damage the local
ecology with that harvesting in many
cases um and they're not
sustainable so what are more sustainable
options or
Alternatives how about Al
alpham alphalpha has massive water
requirements now don't get me wrong I
love alala it's something that I use in
almost every Garden prescription that I
make um but it has a relatively low NPK
it requires a lot of uh water to grow it
it it is a wonderful microbial Source
but it's not perfect and I guess that's
the point I really want to
make so if we want to talk about you
know sustainability then we really have
to look at reducing our carbon footprint
and our inputs this means learning to
cultivate with fewer inputs and not
falling for the marketing around hype
products uh or things in the bottles
that we may really not need and so if we
want to talk about sustainability insect
frass to me is really one of the most
sustainable nutrient sources available
uh on the market today unfortunately
though it does have limited sources and
it has variable quality um but it is the
most sustainable option for closing a
loop in our food supply because we can
feed our food waste to these insects
they can process it and then their
essentially their manure uh tends to be
very clean it tends to be um have
contain good microbial activity in
biomass and it it it tends to be a
pretty good product well what about
compost and manures those are also a
great option however they can contain
Plastics antibiotics pesticides and
pathogens so really if we want to talk
about what
I mean if we want to look at what what's
organic and what's fake organic truly
our compost and manures have much much
more risk associated with them and much
more contamination associated with them
and I think that's just something that
we need to recognize when we're making a
decision in our garden and I say this as
someone who loves compost highly
advocates for compost we just need to be
careful with it and not demonize certain
products over other products um
based on an agenda that may or may not
be
accurate compost is probably going to
contain heavy metals so we need to use
it sparingly if we're in a regulated
state or if that comp the compost inputs
contain heavy metals um and ultimately
where where we land is trying to Source
things locally and so even folks that
purchase soil from us that we we ship to
them we then try to work with them to
use the fewest number of inputs as
possible in order to grow uh healthy
products and should try and Source
things as much as they can locally now
the limitations with locally sourcing
things is limited options you may not be
able to get all of the products you want
or clean versions of those products
locally um and that's just the reality
of the situation and that may lead you
to having to purchase some things online
and have them shipped to you but the
best thing that we can do is reuse our
soil and reduce our inputs while
maintaining
fertility and the the point of this
whole talk is really not to say that
like one input is better than another
I'm not here to say that blood meal or
bone meal or feather meal are superior
to Fishbone meal or fish meal or other
sources you know I could have made the
same talk around M products like rock
dust or Pete Moss versus Coco core or
just about any other input in our garden
I wanted to put together this talk as a
way of encouraging Growers to think
critically and separate out a marketing
message from reality a lot of times
these messages are crafted to sell you
products by allowing a company company
to differentiate themselves around the
message and sometimes these messages or
concepts can be really powerful because
they tug on our emotions or fit with our
values but when you dig just a little
bit deeper the reality of it can be
entirely different so in closing I want
to challenge you to think critically and
deeply about how you cultivate this
plant be open-minded to new ideas but
also do your own research and don't
accept anything that you hear at face
value regardless of how authoritative or
knowledgeable this person may be or how
many followers they may have on social
media so whether you practice jadam or
knf or biodynamics or soil food web at
the end of the day there's wisdom and
misinformation in every one of these
methods it wasn't until my good friend
Tim Wilson called me out about some
things that I was saying about compost
te that I had heard from the foremost
expert in the industry and challenged me
to test it out for myself that I became
a more critical thinker and it made me a
better grower you can always trial new
ideas or products in a test plot in your
garden too if you make a hypothesis and
take a scientific Approach at the end of
the day though regardless of what method
you use or what amendments you choose to
use in your garden there's a million
ways to grow this plant and as long as
you're being thoughtful and with an eye
towards sustainability then it's all
good in my book thanks for checking out
this talk please reach out if you have
any questions I really appreciate it