I do not think that there's a critical
growth period that's been identified in
cannabis production when calcium is
needed the most and in fact it seems to
me like it's needed throughout the
entire growth cycle so again there's
just a difference there it's not an
apple it's a cannabis plant so I
generally believe that it's especially
needed in veg I think it's critically
important
to maximize calcium uptake and veg it's
hard to overdo it in organic production
i' I've never seen it overdone um and so
I think the reason that that it's that
it's so important in veg is not because
it's a critical point of influence it's
just because you can't get it back once
you're at week four of flour you're not
gonna you're not going to catch up if
your calcium uptake wasn't high enough
and what I've sort of seen through years
of working with cannabis Growers is the
highest yielding plants have to have
enough calcium going into
flower and I also believe that the
lowest disease pressure and just the the
the best Vigor and general plant health
comes from sufficient calcium levels so
the reason I like focusing on veg is
because you don't you don't want to play
catchup with calcium like you mentioned
it's movement is in the the
transpiration stream the water going up
through the xylem and so um you just you
just want to maintain that that stream
of calcium throughout the entire cycle
the entire life of the plant