hey guys so I know some of you are new
to this Channel and I just wanted to
talk a little bit about who we are and
what we do so my name is Tad hassy uh
the company that I work for is kiss
Organics and we do a variety of things
within the Cannabis and gardening
industry uh we manufacture soils what
people call living soils for example
these plants here uh have gotten nothing
but water for the entire cycle so far
and uh the goal with our company is to
provide uh affordable and simple
amendments and programs that are organic
that can allow you to have a lot of
success and grow highquality product
without spending a lot of money so we
don't have a complicated uh method or
system set up what we're looking to do
is really just make a highquality media
that allows you to grow a healthy plant
and use science-based agronomic
practices uh in our decision-making for
your garden so reach out if if you have
any questions um we do Supply everything
from soil raise beds uh we work with
lighting companies we do uh we work with
biob on beneficial insects so we have a
wide variety of offerings on our website
and uh vast experience across all of our
uh all of our employees and staff so
thanks for checking it out and thanks
for checking out our page