hi this is Todd Husky with kiss organics
and I'm here today to take a look under
the microscope at mammoth pee and see if
there are ways that we might be able to
extract and replicate some of these
microorganisms just to make the mammoth
Beagle a little bit further okay this
week we're here with mammoth P this is
directly out of the sample bottle that I
received this bottle I've had for at
least a few months now it's just been
sitting in my lab this is at 400 times
magnification using a phase contrast
microscope you can see there's actually
a fair bit of active motile bacteria
running around and what I'm guessing is
a little piece of alfalfa since I know
they use alfalfa and they're in their
process up in the upper right hand
corner of the screen
so what we're going to attempt to do
today is in distilled water mix and
micro pee with a few different
ingredients and see if we can't
replicate some of these organisms to
make our mammoth pee just go a little
bit further okay we're back this is
about 12 hours later this is the mammoth
pee again with nothing but distilled
water so after 12 hours you can see we
have what appears to be more active
microbes even without a food source now
we're go on to check and see how
different food sources affected these
different microbes
okay here's the mammoth P again this
time I've added a small amount of on
sulfur blackstrap molasses as you can
see quite a bit more activity with the
added food source
pretty much the whole slide looks about
like this okay we're back this was the
microbe catalyst added to the mammoth P
and around 16 hours in and you'll notice
here on quite the same levels of
bacterial growth as we had using the
molasses but what you do see is a much
greater diversity of microorganisms
which is really what we want we can't
guarantee that that molasses is growing
out all of the of the P solubilizing
bacteria that mammoth P is adding into
the mix and while we can't do the same
with the microbe catalyst at least not
with the we just direct microscopy we
are able to at least determine that the
there is a much greater diversity in
morphology looking at this sample which
I find encouraging okay here's the
alfalfa at 16 hours with the mammoth P
in distilled water and that's as you can
see there's pretty good bacterial growth
again more than the control in the piece
to be a little bit more morphological
diversity than we saw with the molasses
but not quite as much growth so I'm
wondering if all self is a little better
food source especially considering they
use alfalfa as part of their there's
part of their process if lecturing
process or I'm wondering if I can up the
amount of microbe catalyst that I used
as a way of getting a little bit more
bacterial growth while still maintaining
that diversity of microorganisms so keep
in mind too that this test is not
completely conclusive we can't determine
exactly which microorganisms from the
micro-p are being being replicated and
if we're losing any in the process so
the next step would be to do some plant
trials
to determine what sorts of plant
response we get from a mixture like this
that's been that's been brewed
okay so this is just mammoth tea and
distilled water at 28 hours no food
sources whatsoever as you can see we're
getting quite a bit of motile bacteria
not as much biomass as the other slides
but possibly a little better
morphological diversity which makes
sense assuming that all of these
microorganisms are these different
bacterial species are in mammoth pee I
think it speaks to the quality of the
product in regards to there being a lot
of good biological activity this
particular sample that I pulled was from
a sample bottle that I've had for at
least four months just sitting on a
shelf in you know normal room
temperatures by comparison here's the
mammoth pee with the molasses and
distilled water in 28 hours and as you
can see there's quite a bit of bacterial
biomass but it appears that we don't
have the same level of diversity that we
were getting by feeding in a more
diversified soup food source like the
microbe catalyst but we do appear to be
feeding at least one species of bacteria
that seems pretty happy so this is
pretty much what most of the slides look
like they'll have just a few pockets of
that really high high density that we
saw right at the beginning of this slide
okay here's the mammoth P in distilled
water with organic alfalfa meal at 28
hours as you can see we do have good
bacterial growth and maybe a little bit
more diversity than we're seeing
compared to the molasses not as much as
with the microbe catalyst but a little
bit more motile bacteria and not as much
biomass as the molasses was creating but
maybe a little bit better morphological
diversity
okay we're back with the mammoth P and
distilled water with the microbe
catalyst at around 28 hours we're seeing
a lot more bacterial biomass and a lot
of it is as you can see starting to
cluster around certain parts of the
microbe catalyst some of the organic
matter in there disappears so this
appears to be a pretty good food source
option for at least some of the bacteria
bacterial species that are in the
mammoth P I'm seeing some morphological
diversity but maybe not quite as much as
we had in the original sample which may
lead me to believe that not all of the
various pieces all utilizing species of
bacteria are being are being multiplied
but I think it definitely is worth a
shot and I think this is a great way to
possibly extend your mammoth pee a
little bit further
you