okay let's talk about flushing and by
flushing I don't mean removing a bunch
of nutrients from the soil at the end of
the flower cycle as a way of improving
the quality of flour that's really a
hydro concept and doesn't apply to
organic living soils when I say flushing
what I'm talking about is running a
bunch of water through the media through
our soil as a way of reducing levels of
certain nutrients that have gotten
excessive either over time or due to
your amendments or inputs over over the
course of a cycle this is typically
Associated on tests with sodium chloride
or nitrates uh sodium is not an
essential mineral for plants they don't
need it and it will cause plant stress
and potentially raise the EC or soluble
salt level of the soil creating osmotic
pressure in the root system this will
stress your plant so we want to keep
those levels as low as possible uh
typically sodium comes in with water uh
fermented plant extracts teas um it can
come in with a bunch of C based
amendments uh and it's just something
that you want to Monitor and will show
up on your soil test
chlorides plants only need a small
amount I typically associate this with
water but you can see it in high levels
with some amendments and other things
too and then lastly is nitrates um I see
a lot of tests with really high nitrates
and this is pretty common because people
want to people want to feel like they're
feeding their plant and they want to
feel like they're contributing to their
plant growing bigger and rather than
leave a good thing alone they add more
teas whether that's a compost tea a
fermented plant extract a um
you know whatever kind of tea nutrient
tea um and these are all bringing in
nitrogen on some level most likely and
those nitrates are going to cause high
levels of nitrates are going to cause
excessive um Spa inter node spacing
that's the distance between your nodes
here that can get really big um you'll
typically see uh excessively green
plants and that clawing of the leaf
surface and um you're opening yourself
up to more Pest and pathogen pressure
and you're reducing your yield s
dramatically so just by flushing that
bed and removing the nitrates you should
see a dramatic Improvement in the
quality of your crop so when we're
talking about flushing and how to flush
what we're going to do is we're going to
run a whole bunch of very clean water
that's not high in sodium or chlorides
through our soil typically at 10 or 20%
of the total volume chlorides are a
little harder to move out than sodium is
but we want to try and flush that stuff
out retest see how our levels have
dropped and then re amend any essential
plant minerals that might have been
flushed out as well uh unfortunately
it's way too common that we see tests
where we have to recommend flushing that
doesn't mean you're not going to make it
through the cycle if you don't flush it
just means that we want to we're not
going to be quite as optimal as we want
to be and it's something that you want
to manage with your inputs and with the
quality of your water over time so hope
that helps explain it and thanks for
checking it out