when to put blue mats in again that's
going to depend heavily on how much
water you're adding pre during post
transplant and then you're really just
going to want to keep an eye on the
moisture levels in the you know whether
you want to spot check like randomly so
go to a container or a bed and just say
literally throw a dart and be like I
want to know what it is here and then I
want to know what it is here um and then
another really
valuable method to doing to keeping an
iron moisture level is you know get like
a plastic uh Chopstick and put a little
piece of flagging tape on it and just
stick it in the bed or in a container
somewhere at the exact same spot and
then that's your sensing spot so every
time you want to take a mo you know a
soil moisture reading if you've got a
meter you go right topstick put it in
the exact same spot so that way you have
a consistently consistent spot to get a
sense of how fast water might be moving
through
um so there's there's there's pros and
cons to both of those different methods
as far as figuring out exactly what your
soil moisture is and when to install
blue m