every time I water my plants I think
about root hairs when you pull a healthy
plant out of a pot or out of the ground
and you see those tiny fuzzy white
strands coming out of the root those are
your root hairs root hairs are lateral
extensions of a single cell and the
primary source of water and nutrient
uptake root hairs are the main interface
with the rizosphere the area around the
roots and where interactions with
microbes and soil minerals occur so why
root hairs every time I water
well I'm not really thinking about root
hairs so much as I am about root hair
death now root hairs have a limited
lifespan and plants are constantly
generating new ones as old ones die but
there's also things that we do as
Growers that kill root hairs effectively
limiting water and nutrient uptake to
our plants stressful conditions like
extreme soil temperatures nutrient
deficiencies or toxicities and watering
play a key role in root hair Health but
here's why I think about it when I'm in
my botney professor Don Marshall used to
say that overwatering and underwatering
cause the same above ground symptoms in
plants so you cannot tell if a plant has
been over or underwatered simply by
looking at it why because both over and
underwatering cause root hair death and
the plant is not able to uptake
nutrients and water as efficiently until
those root hairs regrow so understanding
the why or the mechanism behind what we
do as Growers can be useful and improve
our ability to grow health healthy
plants so next time you're watering I
encourage you to think about root hairs
and root hair death and the role you
play in your plant's health