hey guys Tad here with kiss Organics
Happy New Year I wanted to do a
follow-up post from last week talking
about suff oil X so when I got these
plants in at the beginning of the cycle
uh they actually came in with thrips and
fungus knats and so I wanted to do
something to treat for that and this is
a good idea anyway even if you don't
have any pests that you know about um
just as a preventative because a lot of
times you can't see them so uh in this
case I use suff oil X and I applied it
three times a couple days apart to help
break the insect life cycle and then I
followed that up with some beneficial
insects and beneficial nematodes so I
want to talk a little bit about why I
choose to use this product in my garden
so first and foremost I just want to say
I'm not sponsored by uh these companies
I by St oilx I don't make any money I
don't sell the product I just think it's
a great product and uh it comes
recommended to me by a good friend of
mine Suzanne way W Evans she is the
anist when it comes to the canvas
industry and other Horticultural crops
um you should absolutely be giving her a
follow um you can check her out buglady
suzan here on Instagram so suff X is
also available as montere horticultural
oil uh I picked this up online because
my local Home Depot didn't have it but
you can probably find this at a garden
center um or somewhere locally if not
it's widely available online it's going
to run you $15 or $20 for something this
size and when you have a small garden
like me you know there's only 12 plants
here I don't need a huge bottle of suff
oil X so I'll be referring to a suff oil
X for video but it's Montery Garden
horticultural oil
too good pointer if you're looking for a
smaller size so why this product well
it's a it works on a wide variety of
insects um it controls AIDS uh mites
soft bodied insects uh they're all on
the label uh in addition it helps with
things like scale and powdery mildew it
works as a suffocant for insects meaning
they can't develop a resistance to it
and it works for fungus by uh not
allowing them to attach to the leaf
surface so very very effective kind of
your all-in-one spray
for uh fungus issues and for pest so
that's one reason I like it right there
it is EPA registered and arm relisted um
so it's been approved in for use organic
production since 2009 and um because it
is EPA registered the company had to
show a lot of research regarding
efficacy on the product now a lot of
products on the market fall under an
exemption called 25b that doesn't mean
that they're good or bad it just means
that they don't have they don't have the
same regulation or um research
supporting their use in agriculture so
those are things with like th oil in
them Rosemary um lavender mint those
sorts of those sorts of oilbased
products so they don't have to show that
the product works they don't have to
show that uh you know what levels are
safe in regards to
phytotoxicity um they they just the the
ingredients are considered generally
safe for uh human use or for
agricultural use so um they just don't
have to provide the same level of data
so when we talk about uh being a
science-based company ourselves we want
to use products that have the highest
level of research and data to support
their use so um that's one reason I
really I really do like this product now
um one of the other reasons I like this
product is because of the way they
emulsify it it makes it really really
easy to apply and I'm able to use lower
amounts of oil relative to other
oilbased products because of the
emulsifier in here keeps the droplets
smaller so it's better at suffocating
insects than other products um it has a
very low REI level or REI at uh 4 hours
so the return inval is quite low
um according to everything I can find
online it's very safe it's
non-toxic and um the MSDS which I was
reading this morning uh really doesn't
show much of anything I mean you don't
want to consume it you don't want to get
in your eyes I always wear a respirator
anytime I spray um and I I highly
recommend that for everyone but in
general it's a very safe product um we
don't always have that same level of
information about a lot of the 25b
products out there and and one one
person commented on my Instagram that uh
they were worried about the fact that a
lab claimed that it lasts for 90 days
the residue of suox lasts on the leaf
surface I could not find any information
about that online um if someone has that
data I would love to see it
uh but I don't spray Stu oil X and flour
anyway so as you can see
now I'm in the flour I have pistols and
I'm not going to be spraying really
anything on this crop uh from here until
finish if I saw something pop up at this
point I'm going to um I'm going to be
bringing in beneficial insects to deal
with it but as you can see the plants
look great and you know as long as I'm
not spraying onto the pistols themselves
I I really don't see any risk I don't
first of all I don't really believe that
there is a lot of residue on these
leaves um from everything I can see with
SE oil has very low residue in general
but um even if there was on some of
these older fan leaves you know I'm not
going to be processing or consuming this
so I don't really see any risk there
there's not going to be anything on the
buds themselves so uh that's another
reason why I think it's perfectly okay
to use seoil x so just to highlight the
difference between seoil X and some of
these other products that I'm spraying
um suff oil X is going going to be sort
of an all-in-one uh Silver Bullet in a
lot of ways for most pests and
pathogens it's very very safe it's uh
allowed for use in organic production
and I don't have to worry about um
phytotoxicity efficacy um residual
things like one of the things that
Suzanne talks about talked about on the
podcast is with neem oil the uh residue
from the neem oil on the leaf surface
itself will actually prevent benefit
beneficials from returning to that leaf
so so pest may get back in there before
the beneficials do so that's a risk
associated with using NE oil versus
using um suff oil X
so I hope that I hope people find this
video informative feel free to comment
below uh with any questions and thanks
for checking it out