foreign
[Music]
good morning everybody we're actually
going to kick off a little early here we
actually got the uh the studio opened
earlier than planned but in all good
faith we are going to kick off I'm
really stoked you guys so we have a few
things on the docket we have several
guests which are popping in just now
that are going to be joining us here
really quick want to get into some
housekeeping before the official starts
so
um welcome my name is Lance Lambert I am
your host I'm also the chief marketing
officer here at Grove bags um based out
of California our headquarters being
based out of Ohio and really stoked
again for doing a webinar Centric around
4 20. um and we're going to get into
that in just a minute you'll see for the
attendees that are already here there is
a q a section on the left hand side of
your screen so if you have any comments
or questions feel free to pitch up in
there anytime we have a few of our
teammates that are already in the
attendee list that can answer any
questions that you might have
um feel free to pop those up anytime
we'll also reference a few of the
questions if we have time at the end of
the session we are trying to keep this
at about 15 minutes though because we
know time is valuable and everyone has a
lot going on
um so with that uh we'll get into
obviously again like we discussed
talking about a little bit of history of
420 a nod to uh this traditional uh
official holiday at least to our
industry and our community and then
we're going to segue into why all these
folks are joining us which are some
awesome faces um some good friends some
new friends that I've gotten to meet and
make out of this actual
um video that we put together this
documentary uh we'll get into the why
the how the where the when on that and
then obviously get ready for the
premiere which is occurring officially
on 420 here so very stoked for that
first let me do some introductions so
you guys know everyone in the room I'm
first going to introduce a strong excuse
me Strong's vanderplug who's with a
paragraphic he is the man that was
behind the camera the director the
producer of this documentary for those
that haven't heard a paragraphic it is a
phenomenal YouTube site Channel rather
that has some great content oh my gosh I
think his top video is about 8.6 million
views so definitely have a pretty
engaged audience there and cover some
really cool things I actually got
familiar with his content before I got
familiar with him and we became friends
but was really impressed with his
storytelling capabilities behind the
camera so I'm stoked to have you here
strongs we'll also go down the list here
we have uh natal partansky so not often
that you have a rocket scientist
um in a webinar
but um no tall you have a phenomenal
history of anyone that's not familiar
with him definitely look up he's done
some great uh articles lately that cover
his background and his transition into
our community he's with sorting robotics
also based out here in Southern
California then we have Katie Enright
from Lavinia so very happy to have you
join us as well a new friend to me which
I got to meet thanks to the documentary
I'm looking forward to hearing a little
bit more about your story next we have
Evan enemen of sans Lane also phenomenal
Insight that you shared during the
documentary I'm not gonna give too much
away you guys we'll share the sizzle
reel on it but um but he has some some
really great Insight on the industry and
what's going on in the documentary next
is uh Kevin sorakowski
um he actually represents appreciation
extraction but has more recently gone
into Consulting
um very familiar with that and he has a
plethora of information again love his
angle and his perspective on some
insight uh throughout the documentary
then we have Corey xyla who is with
Tioga greens another interesting story
these individuals are coming from all
different angles of this community uh
for specifically Corey owns a dispensary
right outside of the gateway to Yosemite
National Park here in California which
is pretty interesting and some of the
brands you represent and the people you
meet from around the world and you
touched on that as well Jason Washington
um I believe he might have his camera
off but I think he's hiding behind The
The J
um so Jason D Washington is with culture
um Beyond being a social Equity license
holder here in California he has a lot
of things going on the International
Space also has some presence in Montana
but a lot of great Insight on what's
going going on not just domestically but
abroad which he touched on as well in
this documentary last we have Jack
Grover who is our founder and CEO Grove
bags again plethora of information and
background very passionate my just like
myself he actually started out as a
grower was so passionate about the plant
and wanting to support it it came up
with the technology we now offer today
in our packaging
um so stoked to have him on as well so
perfect we'll thank you all again for
being here and for several of you I know
you're probably familiar with the story
but I thought I'd kind of start off with
the the history of 420. and it hits a
little close to home for me uh being a
NorCal kid actually grew up first in
Marin County for those who don't know
that's actually Where it All Began so
420 started in San Rafael at San Rafael
High School uh if you're familiar with
the Bay Area essentially if you're in
San Francisco you'd cross over what we
call the gate or the Golden Gate Bridge
that's Marin County come into Marin and
you kind of Pop right into San Rafael
just north of Sausalito so great little
town this is back in 1971 a group of
five friends they catch up and hang out
the statue every day after school it
kind of ended up being a bit of an
adventure they do these uh these these
kind of safaris as they call them they
ended up coining them one of The Safaris
they got best known for is finding an
old uh grow operations out in Stetson
Beach on the hillside that supposedly an
individual is tied to I believe it was
the Coast Guard that had this little
grow up on the hill not far from his
office they never did find the Grove but
the rest is kind of history as far as
how one of the individuals end up
becoming a roadie for the Grateful Dead
in the 70s and then 420 ended up on a
flyer I want to say it was back in the
80s and uh and it just kind of
perpetuated from there so it's an
interesting past and and I think the
thing to call out is the fact that it's
it's very close to home as far as where
law the culture and craft is Right
Northern California everyone knows of
the Emerald Triangle that is Mendocino
Trinity and Humboldt counties
in my opinion I'm totally biased I think
the most beautiful side of California is
North of San Francisco from Stetson
Beach to Crescent Bay and that obviously
is where the triangle Falls in
um but 420 has really become recognized
not just domestically but
internationally and you guys saw the
footage and a few of you were there I
know Jason was there Corey was out there
I know some individuals made it out to
spanavus which is an annual
International event started out as a
protestable now it's a balance of
consumer and B2B that takes place out in
Barcelona Spain and it was interesting
to hear people reference and talk about
420 coming up is that something for
those that don't know it wasn't really
on International radar even a handful of
years ago you want to go over to Europe
you want to go over to Thailand or down
to South America and hear people that
were tied to this plant reference this
very popular domestic holiday that we
have so 420 has definitely come a long
way and so with this documentary and and
again we'll get further ads out later on
you know we felt that it was an ideal
time to actually launch this during 4
20. and while it talks a little bit more
so about the current state of our
community of this industry that is legal
cannabis it's still something that all
of us acknowledge as being that big day
every year so it felt just fitting again
when Strauss and I connected on on the
release date for it to literally be on
420 because so much goes on and all of
you know that I'm sure some of you are
going to New York for the big event out
there or going to Green Street out here
in LA
uh or maybe even you're going to hippie
Hill up in San Francisco which is one of
the longest running 420 festivals but
there's always something going on
but with that I kind of want to jump in
and I want to find out from our our
panelists I guess if you will kind of
what 420 means to you and then kind of
segue into that what got you into this
space what got you into this community
this industry what you're passionate
about and I think it's fair to start
with ladies first so maybe if we kick it
off with you Katie if that's okay hello
thank you so much for having me
definitely
um so it's really interesting 420 has
always meant a lot to me because it's my
little sister's birthday my parents
anniversary and then my other sister's
anniversary so even from like four years
old 420 was always a date that we really
celebrated
which is kind of fun that now I'm in the
industry and so I celebrate as well
I actually studied Theology and um
almost became a nun so my way into
cannabis is a little bit different than
probably most
um I was training for my second marathon
and um my first marathon I had a
terrible uh
time I mean it's just not something your
body is designed to do and I was having
um you know back pain knee pain all the
pains and um for my second Marathon I
was determined to not have as much
trouble as I had during my first so I
started to incorporate cannabis in my
recovery and started to actually uh you
know
formulate a plan for Recovery in my
training
and I started to make my own balms just
in my kitchen for myself
um and then you know do infusions of
essential oils and I did a bunch of
research and I watched like every
webinar every tutorial everything you
could possibly imagine and
um I literally was just making it for
myself I realized you could totally use
this to enhance your sexual experience I
tried it and it really worked but I was
using coconut oil as my base and coconut
oil isn't good for a lubricant so I
literally the next day went to three
dispensaries in my area to try to find a
product that would enhance my sexual
experience that wasn't coconut oil based
and it didn't exist
um so I just started making it for
myself in my kitchen and for friends of
friends and then
um all of a sudden somebody came up to
me and was like are you the weebu girl
and I was like
I am that's amazing this needs to be a
company like if if people are hearing
about the product and requesting it
um and then I just started out on this
journey to start a company that enhances
people's sex life through cannabis
and it's interesting that point because
like you said there's people don't
realize that this is uh medicine on so
many different levels I'm an avid
Advocate and as is I Know Jack and Corey
from a medicinal standpoint first but so
many different ways that it can be used
in so many different things that it
enhances I think people forget that it's
not all about the the psychological you
know there's so much more uh physically
that it can contribute to as far as a
better lifestyle so it's awesome to hear
and thank you for the back I love the
420 like you said you'll never forget
this day there's always something going
on for you right so I've been a good
segue then too uh is to Corey so Corey a
little bit of background you've got an
interesting one so definitely love to
hear yours as well yeah so
um 420 for me
um means a couple different things I
guess I'll start with the way I got into
cannabis first and that'll kind of play
my story into 420 for me
um I grew up skiing as a professional
athlete and when I was injured at age
around 14 I want to say in middle school
I broke my neck and I found out I was
allergic to opiates and as we all know
our country is the biggest uh pumper of
opiates and narcotics for pain instead
of resorting to the more holistic way of
things and so luckily my dad is a uh
he's a dentist and he has medical
background but he's definitely more of
the holistic way and definitely grew up
in the Grateful Dead area he's all peace
and love and has a lot of friends that
are have been in the Cannabis industry
forever and one of his friends just
always had suggested that I use low THC
High CBD for my pain and that's really
how I got into cannabis and um I also
noticed though that it really helped
with my mental psyche and just like
competing and stuff getting me in the
right State of Mind Muscle Recovery was
much faster just like Katie had said you
know I started using rubs back then for
pain relief and things like that just
making them at home like she said and
that's really where cannabis started for
me and just kind of really exploded from
there I saw the benefits of it and how
it helped people
and then after I kind of tapered out of
my skiing career I started a medical
cannabis doctor offices in remote places
and so I would work with like five
different doctors I'd set up satellite
offices and kind of started the future
of telemedicine and people being able to
get their recommendations in remote
towns so I learned a lot from all the
doctors and what different cannabinoids
and terpenes really help with different
ailments and things like that and so
I've kind of taken that side of things
and brought it into my dispensary like
Lance said which is and uh is located at
the end entrance to Yosemite National
Park right on Highway 395 and 120 and so
our whole program here is more about the
healing and helping of people and of
course we have products that get you
high as well but we're more of the
compassionate side and it's very
interesting like you'll see in the
documentary the doctors around here at
our hospitals and just main doctor
offices will actually send people to
come talk to me instead of prescribing
them Pharmaceuticals these days so it's
pretty cool that our community in these
little small towns have really looked
outside the box of the normal of just
prescribing pills and looking to more
holistic treatments for people it's
awesome you know we've helped a lot of
people have gone through
serious chronic pain to stage four
cancer we've had people that have been
able to recover from stage four cancer
and beat it using RSO in different
various ways
um yeah and then for 420 for me it
usually means nowadays a pretty crazy
day at our business but a time to give
back to our community so I love it um
I've got a good relationship with all of
our Brands and all of our brands have
been very supportive this year you know
they send us lots of products so it's
just a good time of year to really
support the people that support us and
you know if people don't have money on
that day we don't care you come in with
a dollar you're going to leave with a
fat bag of cannabis products and um yeah
it's just about giving back and
camaraderie between people and just
helping educate people and showing love
I'm gonna go the other extreme because
this is I love just to show the again
the diversity of everyone that was
involved in this documentary but natal
and I kind of joked around about it but
I mean honestly man like you come from a
totally different place but I know
passion in your association with the
plant played a role as well
yeah I mean I was kind of thinking about
that as a scores going over his
background I was like wow I I'm very on
the other side
um so yeah
I I thought about this question a lot
um like what 420 means to me and I guess
the first time I ever heard it was when
I was in college and
um and some guy's like dude it's 4 20
and I was like I have no idea what
you're talking about you know and so uh
it was it was very much back then
because it was like 15 years ago and
even in California 15 years ago uh
cannabis was still very deeply
stigmatized and and I was one of those
people on the other side of the fence
where I was like yeah I don't really
know and
um and the 420 number in me back then
kind of meant like
the the stigma that's still kind of
surrounds today like oh you know this
like illegal substance that's like
negative and has all these negative
effects and over the course of you know
the past 15 years it's evolved for me
it's changed from
um oh that's what the guys in you know
High School do who like don't do it
don't get good grades right like I don't
hang out with those guys
um but then like as it evolved in
college I became much more familiar with
the plant and I actually ended up
preferring it more than alcohol when all
my friends were binge drinking and like
throwing up and like dying in the corner
uh I was like yeah I just want to like
chill you know this is what I think it's
useful for and then I'm a scientist so I
started looking into more of the science
behind it and I was like oh this is it's
actually very interesting and
and for the longest time
um I wanted to do something in the space
but uh when I thought of cannabis it was
like this illegal thing and I wasn't an
aerospace engineer like I worked at Nasa
like I can't you know I can't really
um you know go on to that other side of
the fence and
um and then when it became legal like
420 changed for me right it's no longer
like this thing that like is a taboo or
prohibited for me to engage in and then
a few years went by
um and I started this company and then I
was much more familiar with it I had
friends that were starting companies
around it and and then 420 now instead
of being this like negative connotation
it was a change in the Paradigm and an
opportunity to explore in new avenues
and now like when I look at cannabis
from a science perspective like I went
to the emerald science conference a few
weeks ago and
there's actual real science like being
done with cannabis and like quantitative
measure it's not
um we're no longer in the world of like
some guy who's like yo my indoors so
fire cures cancer it's like no like
they're actually testing synthetic
cannabinoids to like shrink tumor cells
so when I think of 420 now I don't think
of it's those guys in the back of the
class you know [ __ ] up it's like no
420 is
the future it's actually a completely
different perspective on how you can you
know build your life and how it'll
change other people's lives above and
beyond California United States globally
so
that's kind of my perspective when I
think of 420 I don't think about it
negatively I think about analysis it's a
positive future
and we've been I know we've done a few
of the canopac events together in in
year one individual that I can always
find next to the infused beverages along
with myself because I'm like you I kind
of I'm a little critical I know I'm
opinionated of it but I do reference
alcohol as poison but I also gave it up
as well I saw there no Health attributes
or anything that is beneficial to me so
I transition My Lifestyle as well you
know so I know we have always have that
kind of similarity but yeah you make a
valid point too there is um and I'll
have to share with you guys there's a
DOT org site and it has all studies on
record dating back to 1970. a lot of
them of course being private private
university because of the the position
of schedule one for the last several
decades but it's quite intriguing and to
your point Israel being the capital of
both science and medicine and going over
there and learning at the Cannabis in
Cancer University being myself a cancer
survivor hearing what they're doing to
your point at all the fact that they are
literally finding cultivar specific
solutions to combating certain cancerous
cells prostate colon and Brass being the
three cancers that they were targeting
because they're three of the biggest
Killers but seeing that they're actually
to your point being able to eradicate
those cells with cannabis blew my mind
and I say if I ever came out of
remission that's that's the first place
I was going to versus the the Western
medicine so I think it's awesome I
didn't hear that they're doing so much
research there like they even did a full
factorial study for insomnia where they
tested uh you know 600 different
combinations of THC CBD and CBN and it's
like that's real science like for me in
this industry that's what gets me
excited yeah 100 and again that's that's
another good transition to Jack and and
to be candid and most people that know
me in this industry in this community
I'm all about endorsing not just the
brands I believe in in the products and
solution but the people that are behind
it and I think that's a good segue to
you jack in in your background and what
motivates you to get into it and
obviously how you kind of had that pivot
and ideology towards cannabis many years
ago before getting into it so maybe if
you could share a bit of of your
background in that regard yeah um
absolutely Lance um
I like uh no tell from a pretty
anti-cannabis place and you know float
to look to the people using them like I
don't want to be like that that guy or
that that person
um it's a very very negative stereotype
very
um you know anti-intellectual
perspective on it um and then it really
wasn't until my brother went out to
whoever suffers from real severe
cerebral palsy went out to California
um and driving medical cannabis the
first time and got tremendous relief
from it that I really got interested in
and opened up my eyes to it so I've uh
was was growing in Ohio back when that
was you know probably worse than dealing
heroin
um I uh so I've been growing for uh just
before I had a driver's license
um and just been around the plan my my
whole life so for me 420 is really about
the patients the people who who truly
get you know who don't interests and
diet enjoy it or get anxiety relief from
it or a little bit of pain relief from
it like me because you know I've had
back surgery or spinal surgery and
everything else you know I certainly
consider myself patient but I think it's
the people who you know have had chronic
conditions whose life has been life
quality has been substantially improved
by our industry and the the people who
sacrifice a lot I mean you know we're
here you know being able to talk about
this on the internet and revealing our
faces and talk about the businesses that
we have and the exciting things we're
doing in the industry a lot of people
sacrifice a whole lot for us to be able
to have the the privilege to do that and
you know not not all of them you know
have straight great strains named after
them or are memorialized or have a great
legacy into today's industry you know
it's it's certainly not Steve D'Angelo
um you know who I'm talking about
um but it's it's it's countless people
who you know weren't just like
incarcerated or you know worked
tirelessly by the Midnight Oil to you
know create and innovate great products
that you know will bring a lot of help
and a lot of value to people like you
know Rick Simpson Oil or something some
of these other great things so that's
really what for 20 is to us at growth
bags and uh to me as somebody who you
know got interested in cannabis for for
those reasons obviously it's a huge part
of my everyday life now
um you know both professionally and
personally but uh that that's what we
try to focus on for for the holiday
awesome very good and I also want to
hear from uh Kevin so Kevin stratowski
you know that's you brought a great
perspective and definitely some some
interesting intellect uh to the
conversation in the documentary but uh
the same question for you as well you
know a little bit about what 420 means
for you and how it impacts you and your
in your current life and in profession
absolutely yeah so thank you for having
me
um I I had kind of a funny uh entrance
into cannabis uh by happenstance uh
which would I guess we would call the
Legacy market now
um I had a friend that uh for whatever
set of reasons uh had some plants that
he was worried about keeping in his
house for uh another set of weeks right
so he called me and didn't want all that
work to go to waste and asked me if we
could throw them in my basement I said
sure why the hell not so we threw him in
my basement and um did a couple day
crash course on growing uh back where I
think I just watered it and dunked some
or tossed some super thrive on it
um but uh you know just started to
really kind of I would say at that point
I got re-interested in it um but I
dabbled a little bit in high school but
uh at the time whatever cannabis uh I
was getting uh wasn't really helping me
or affecting me in the way I wanted it
to it actually gave me a little bit of
anxiety and I didn't really like it
um you know looking back on that I think
it's because we've progressed so far and
now there's other options but it kind of
reinvigorated my passion for the plant
and kind of got me to try a few more
things uh you know try some new material
out you know gets
different consumption methods things of
that nature Edibles and and I really
found that
um for me it became this thing mentally
that was so important to me because um
you know a lot of people have body
ailments that they use it for different
objectives
um I haven't had those yet I'm starting
to feel them now at 35 but I've been
good so far so for me it was a mental
thing I I have an overactive mind and it
really kind of just allowed me to slow
down a bit so uh fast forward I ended up
starting a CBD business
um ran that for a bit and at the time my
friend Nick was uh starting a
Manufacturing Company Precision
extraction Solutions uh he asked me to
come on board as like the fifth or sixth
employee and uh kind of built the
company from there and fast forward I I
started branching out getting involved
in some retail and some other parts of
the industry and and just I mean fell in
love with it and the people and um kind
of decided more recently to go off do
some independent Consulting and kind of
build my own businesses
um which kind of brings me into I guess
uh you know what does 420 mean for me
personally
um it is my dog's birthday Mason for
real
birthday not like somebody filled it out
born on 420 so fittings
um but uh it's a day going back to the
mental thing and I know Corey mentioned
that I believe uh it's a day for me to
like relax slow down a bit and uh just
really appreciate what's around me
um it's a time to celebrate the plant
and kind of How Far We've came in the
industry and I can tell you from a
business Point uh it's fun because uh
we've been blessed and been able to get
three retail locations planted
provisioning in Michigan we have them in
Whitmore Lake flint and Bay City and uh
for me it's a time on that side of it to
kind of say thanks to our customers and
again Corey had mentioned this as well
but like bring people together have some
fun I mean we do like create we do
giveaways vendors food trucks promos we
get the radio there uh like Lance said
as well community and cannabis and
basically bringing them together so
awesome man and you and you rocked it
over a Precision extraction by the way
man it's sweet that you're still consult
for them but but obviously you killed it
over there so it's great to hear what
you're doing as far as your new Ventures
and opportunities thank you it's been a
wild ride yeah you're probably an
understatement right and Evan uh don't
know definitely last but not least but I
want to hear a little bit more from your
side as well uh we are now connected via
the documentary but I really love uh
some of the things they put in
perspective uh in this documentary about
the industry as a whole so same question
goes to you
I appreciate that
um yeah I guess my relationship with
cannabis has been a really interesting
one just growing up the East Coast
having the kind of use consumption
growth or anything always been
underground and something that you just
don't talk about that's a lot of things
that is a format of an East Coast
culture
um but I moved out to California about
12 years ago and prior to that I had an
experience with a friend of mine who
um would would kind of joke and poke but
one time he made this comment that I you
know I hadn't had my medicine and I
didn't really think about it it actually
kind of set me off a little bit more
until I moved to California and actually
understood what plant medicine really is
and what community really is all about
and and actually understood what he
meant as a joke was an actual real thing
and and going to some of the points that
were made
um you know I have a very active
um non-linear you know way of thinking
and so uh consuming has always helped me
to slow down my process slow down my
speaking understanding how to interact
better with people and and so that what
would happen as a very
um sort of friendly poke from uh I don't
know if it was friendly at the time but
a poke from a friend
um turned out to be something that
ultimately I learned very deeply about
over the course of time and my
connection to getting involved on the
business side was a little bit
fortuitous just as result of
relationships over time and working in
various Industries and entertainment
um media and with celebrities being some
of them and turned out got involved with
who some may call you know Beacon for
the industry in some ways in that Snoop
Dogg and from there and since about 2012
2013 have been involved in a lot of
different ways and ultimately for me it
comes down to really two aspects and
that's hospitality and ultimately
caregiving and to learn that very early
on in my life both my parents are
caregivers in different ways
um understood the value of what those
connections really mean and and getting
involved in
um the business side of it has somewhat
created a little bit of a challenge
because there is somewhat of a conflict
between what people see as an
opportunity to make a lot of money and
and all that might be true it's not the
intent that I've ever started out with
my intent has always been to provide
some value or some quality of care or
something that I can give to others and
ultimately the return of that if done
well is some potential return and that
could be Financial or otherwise so 420
to me has a little bit of a mixed bag if
you will on the one hand it does bring
Community together in a way that most
other holidays may not and and that's
really unique and interesting and
hearing some of the
um folks on the panel that do a lot of
giveaways and help people who may not
have the means to you know acquire plant
medicine on their own that's the
beautiful side of it on the other side
you know I see this tendency towards
trying to take as much from a consumer
as you can and and some of those
opportunities uh happen around 4 20.
some of them happen throughout the year
but but that holiday if you will some
people seem to point to as a way to
extract Extra Value from consumers
knowingly or unknowingly and um
it creates a little bit of a challenge
for me to to feel very free and
comfortable celebrating
um that day and more so the plant
interestingly enough for for me in the
business that we're in it's not just
cannabis it's really around all plant
medicine and
you know having Bicycle Day the day
before and then obviously 4 20 on on the
day after I think it's just an
interesting
um point to recognize how important
um plant medicine community and
caregiving really is uh psychedelics
will be able to play a much more
significant role in our lives as we
start to see
um those plans those substances being
more widely accepted as well and there's
a nice parallel between what happened
with cannabis and what's happening now
in the Psychedelic movement and
community and and um you know to me it
always comes back down to you know
developing at least this point in my
career
developing brands that can be the
carrier for that purpose and ultimately
that is to
um you know connect people more have
people feel more
deeply to heal in whatever way that
means and ultimately to thrive and you
know cannabis and plant medicine is a
way for me uh to be able to do that and
and um you know for me to to Really
share that with others so I appreciate
you having me on this on this uh
documentary and also on this webinar
yeah a great Avenue and you make some
excellent points that's you remind me of
saying I always say that you know well
alcohol I've always felt the alcohol
helps you lose yourself cannabis helps
you find yourself but I think to your
point psychedelics fall into that same
linear with these neural paths that
otherwise aren't aren't being used so
and you make an excellent point too for
people that come out to California
because we forget you know even before
the legalization via prop 215 in 1996 we
had prop P back in 1990 which was only
uh in this the city and county that is
San Francisco but that's back of the
brownie Marion the Dennis Peru but you
make a very valid point because Dennis
was always an advocate for medicinal
never for adult use of recreational he
always he always LED with medicinal at
all ages all levels because of that
potential but he really he really held
the line he was always 215 over six over
prop 64.
um so very interesting point you make
about how you know the people are most
passionate have made the biggest
movement it's always been for those
right reasons like you said for the
community and for the healing first not
for the profit and and for the
capitalism which um in my opinion I'm
with you should always come second
secondary so it's awesome strands I
didn't forget about you you know but I I
did want to ask you because of being an
individual that just in in recent years
I mean well I know personally you've
known of the plant but you've done
several documentaries prior to this one
you've done uh I believe Hydroponics you
actually covered aquaponics which is
awesome this is this country's not very
apt to aquaponics but you've covered it
both from urban grow commercial grow
um and then now kind of covering it kind
of holistically and across the board on
all aspects
um how has it been as you kind of segued
more into the space in general so so
maybe not so much just on 420 but as
you've covered it from behind the lens
uh from a very objective perspective how
has your kind of mindset towards this
space changed over the years
so I grew up on a farm in Iowa so
agriculture has always been kind of in
my in my mind and my background my last
name is Dutch and it means of the plow
so it's like literally in My DNA like
farming is just part of me
but you know I grew up really really
conservative it was always the joke oh
you're so straight edge
um so it wasn't even until film school
and college here in Arizona which is not
you know a place that's at the Forefront
of any of these movements you know
really pushing things forward but it's
not also you know too far behind we're
always kind of playing catch up in
Arizona and it was around that time that
you know there was shows like weeds uh
coming out or there were some
documentaries that were really like uh
kind of prominent at that time and it
was this awareness around this plant
that for my whole life had been you know
pretty misunderstood and it was through
content and media that I started
exploring that just how can a plant be
this bad this dangerous from like what I
grew up with what everyone's kind of
told the common knowledge right and it
was content that changed that shaped
that for me
and then over the years it's something
that I've always just been fascinated
with like watching things grow whether
it's a tree in my backyard or growing
tomatoes or vegetables or cannabis it's
just another plant to me and I found
that through all the documentaries we've
done all the people that we've talked to
It's oddly a part of almost everybody's
life whether they admit it or not a lot
of people are still have that you know
that shame that stigma of why I don't
really want to show this I don't want to
talk about this uh it is a part of me
and so I think there's just this still
this level of misunderstanding around
the plant and being able to tell some of
those stories on the cultivation side so
that was the the first cannabis
documentary we did it was on a home grow
for a caregiver operation just from a
house residential house and we premiered
that on 420 a couple years ago and so
growing growing up and in college at 420
was always just like a joke
um you know I was like oh it's 4 20. um
but now you know more recently learning
kind of the history of it I'm just just
always
I don't know appreciative of like the
fact that it's such a humble beginning
and I think that is what resonates the
most with me that it's now this kind of
you know
worldwide phenomenon
from something just so simple as just
you know the the humble roots of it so I
think I always like to use the analogy
of planting seeds uh in in any part of
life you plant seeds and some of them
will grow and some of them won't you
never really know what you're going to
get at the end of it but if you do your
best and you take care of it and you
tend to your garden you tend to your
farm
um you'll have this amazing Harvest at
the end of it and I think that's true
and what I want to do with content
planting seeds because you don't know
you don't know the person the one person
might watch it and that person could the
Ripple effects right the butterfly
effect it's just uh you can't even
capture you don't even know right but
you just put out their good content good
work good energy if you put good into
the world I think it kind of perpetuates
more good and I think that's kind of
what it's it's all kind of shaped up uh
to me and that's why I like to make
these documentaries on the business of
cannabis the cultivation of cannabis but
also just other stuff about making
sourdough bread or growing Gourmet
mushrooms it's all part of this world
where we're making things we're doing
good try to make the world a better
place for us locally and then I think
that ends up spreading far beyond what
we even are able to uh consider and know
thank you you mentioned sourdough but
that's one we've talked about on more
than one occasion how much successive
has come from that documentary now
timing might have been a factor I mean
I've always been a
one in the kitchen to cook and I do love
doing anything in my hand so gardening
cooking fixing hot rods but man the
sourdough Trend really took off during
the pandemic and talk about timing and
now that that company is thriving but
for the right reasons to your point I
think we discussed that you know it was
100 organic uh figuratively and so you
know for them to just have that
documentary come out the right time and
now to hear the people from around the
world come and visit this Bakery in
Arizona that happened to be in this
documentary that you created but this is
a different category right I think you
touched on you know we I'm not going to
speak for everyone but it looks like
most of us are gen xers right around
that range I'm on the younger end
um but you know we grew up with the
stigma associated with the Dare program
Nancy Reagan which you know Darren uh
they started Daryl I think it's Daryl
walk start out here in Southern
California but anyway the Dare program
but even to your point like the Boomers
and the whole Nixon era in 71 because
you brought up a good point
um Evan in that you know psychedelics
and cannabis they they were being
studied by the US government until Nixon
started his one on drugs in 71. you know
there's actual studies on the books from
the government study and these these
different uh substances and and before
they obviously weaponize them but there
is still that stigma right and you see
that so much more prevalent here I still
am surprised by going to a trade show in
the Czech Republic and I remember
walking into the facility and there was
a pop-up daycare and I was like Wow
Child Protective Services would be all
over this if this was back in the States
here they're being grown-ups about it
they're being professional and taking
this serious and they're like hey we we
have a career this is our business this
is what we do you and we have children
that need to be tended to you know it's
really interesting how that stigma like
you said as much as we feel it's being
better suppressed than before it still
exists you know so thanks for being able
to tell the story and again I I feel
like you really tell from an objective
perspective which which is I think that
much more valued and appreciated by the
audience so we've talked enough about it
I know of Adam if you possibly have uh I
guess it'd be a trailer if you would
queued up but let's let's show this
really quick I'm I'm super stoked about
this game live
cannabis has been around for thousands
of years the stoner stereotype still
persists to this day just because we're
cannabis operators we're not criminals
and we never have been
about three quarters of the population
of this country feel that it should be
legal at some level in some states it's
the number one cash crop businesses
coming out of thin air to service the
Cannabis space our goal is to
sophisticate the Cannabis industry we
are currently building that technology
that doesn't exist a lot of people don't
realize that this is a challenging
industry it's akin to dancing and kite
in a hurricane
[Music]
thank you
shocks people how sophisticated these
companies are I just love the challenge
of really helping to change people's
minds around this plant
[Music]
Ed dancing with a hurricane I love that
quote Jack because that's one thing we
all talk about just on on the phone with
uh individuals she's been in the
industry for several years been a part
of the community and is not as much in
touch with it as she has been over the
last decade and she said yeah a lot of
crazy stuff is going on and it's true I
mean it's it's tough times for for many
aspects of the the community
domestically here in the States but
specifically for our industry it's a
little bit of a reset that we're going
through again but I think you made a
pretty interesting uh metaphor there
Jack in reference to where things are so
just to kind of talk about a few of the
touch points that you all spoke on
starting off with that one Jack is it
where do you feel like things are as far
as current state I mean it feels like
it's tougher forever for us but things
are still moving in the right direction
as far as cannabis goes correct in the
United States there's some encouraging
signs that we'll have a uh you know nice
you know nice little rebound we're
covering stabilization this summer
obviously things have been extremely
challenging uh particularly California
Nevada and Michigan Massachusetts you
know Oklahoma the the program got you
know so messy there that they actually
voted against recreational marijuana
which I think was a big shock and a
moment for a lot of us to stop and take
positive market and where the markets
developed on the other hand I mean the
international Market's booming you know
there's um
the same proportion of the U.S
population uh that has access to
cannabis that's the same portion of the
gold population soon and I'm very
excited about what's happening in South
Africa and Thailand and in Colombia
um Australia really especially in Europe
all over the world you know in terms of
Germany announcing that they're going
towards more of a homegrown method
um you know it'll be interesting to see
how that plays out but that that's
excites me that's empowering the
patients and trying to empower
um
uh the local uh the the local cannabis
economy and the local Canada's ecosystem
and culture within there so I think
we're really uh at the NASA stage of the
gold market but that being said you know
I say we're dancing kit in a hurricane
because we have rapidly changing you
know commoditized pricing coming coming
into play of the market and a lot of
people have been arguing for years you
know what kind of industry is this what
are we doing are we farming are we this
or that and you know I've said for a
couple years I'll tell you what kind of
industry are we are 95 97 of this is is
uh Agri commoditized agribusiness and
cpg
um and it's really a fight to get out of
that and stay out of that and I still
believe you know walking around
benzinga last week I think you know
two-thirds of the companies I saw at
least won't be around in in three or
five years and then I say I have some
pretty big ones that are notorious and
I've raised a lot of money and that's
because the situation is still so fluid
in the industry's so fluid and there's
so many regulations like Banking and
everything out that are are so moving
under our feet I think you know we're in
a flu business in a rapidly growing
rapidly changing rapidly rapidly
maturing industry in a very over
regulated market
um and it's it's an interesting time but
you know they're in there are things to
consider like I don't I don't I question
how many California Brands would be
surviving right now for products we're
moving through the back door and it's
coming back from the business
you make a very valid point because
how long are we as an instrument gonna
talk about brand Equity yeah you know
does does anybody actually give that
much of a of a [ __ ] about a brand or do
they just want a great experience
and and that's like you said some of
those Ransom backdoor deals I surprised
to see what I thought was was knockoffs
of California brands on the other side
of the world in Thailand only to find
out those really were the the brands and
the product coming from California so to
your point it's this whole Global
movement and I agree kind of like
education in this country we're behind
that that International stage I mean
I've seen more cannabis than most people
if it's a if it's a true world-class
exotic you know and I I've recognized
product from certain rooms in other
parts of the world that's not to say
that I haven't been in Thailand and it
seems from the best rooms I've seen in
the world there or you know a lot of
these other markets I don't think you
know it's true anymore of that if it's
not growing in Northern California it's
you know it's at the very best uh uh
step below step below that
um I don't think that's true anymore but
yeah I mean we're in an intense Global
Market where you know people are
fighting those stylish Brands and
flowers moving all over the world
whether it be Barcelona or Thailand or
cannabis clubs and you know on the
Canary Islands of which there are 700
yeah there's a lot there's a lot going
on the international State and you
mentioned Germany which Germany has been
leading but we know also obviously uh
the Czech Republic Czech is moving
pretty rapidly as is Switzerland and and
so like you said you know Europe with
gosh double the populace of North
America right 734 million plus people in
the EU alone that that's a big audience
that's a big consumer base it already is
consuming today and I think that's one
thing that's covered in the documentary
like there's already the consumers
there's already the demand it's just
creating that infrastructure right so it
definitely shifted quite a bit I think
kind of tied into that too you know Evan
um you know one of the the quotes that
actually was in the the quick trailer
was
um touching on the stigma so how much do
you think the stigma has played into
where the U.S stands versus some of
these other countries that have made a
total 180 right I mean from capital
punishment to completely legal in a
country like Thailand which we would
have never fathomed five ten years ago
how much is that playing a role in where
we are positioned as a global leader or
maybe not when it comes to cannabis in
the legal state
dominant Market dominant IP uh dominant
techniques
um
plot leadership I would still say is
very heavily the U.S uh but it's it's uh
it continues to become a global and
international movement I think um you
know Canada certainly fall through a
substantial you know and what seemed on
some animal had to start but
um I think many of the world's great
cannabis companies probably have not
been started yet
I would say The Stereotype has been
somewhat broken down but still not fully
yet you know you have a lot of people
who have been able to share their
stories more freely in the last 10 years
at least in the US not not speaking
internationally and that's made it
easier for more
NASA scientists into this space and
others who who might feel a perceived
risk if they come out I mean I I
experienced that myself in the early
days where you know I had challenges
because I was actively involved and very
vocally involved in the Cannabis
industry and it's unfortunate but it is
where we are and I don't know if that
stigma is what's holding us back as much
as
um
hour and grain stubbornness as a society
in the U.S to think that we're right
about everything in fact when we're
generally not I mean the whole War on
Drugs came from us and sort of reverting
back from that is going to be really
difficult in many ways at least if we're
thinking about a
functional Democratic Society you know
sometimes we can question whether we are
that or not
um it's definitely created some barriers
but I don't think that's ultimately the
reason why we still have those issues
today
um
I'm not a politician I don't ever want
to be a politician but yet I know
everything is political
um which means that everything is is
sort of driven by a profit motive
especially in this country and that's
really where I think a lot of the
um you know the the headwinds are still
um you know we can talk about religion
and other issues and those two have
various aspects of of a headwind for the
the community and and the plant itself
but
I think it's more of a profit motivation
or lack thereof to actually solve
societal issues using plant medicine and
using our ability to heal one another
um is is why we're still in the position
we are domestically internationally
I'm not as familiar with how other
countries are are fully embracing the
plant but certainly it's at a federal
level which makes a lot easier to move a
lot quicker and those political
processes are far different than what
we've been experiencing in the U.S
good point and you're right and some
especially at commonwealth countries I
find you know because take like
Australia for example which is
essentially if England and the U.S had a
had a child that's why that's how I kind
of see the way that they function right
because they they love barbecues and big
V8 engines but they also do still have
their tea at two so but I see them very
much to your point they fully embraced
our War on Drugs to the point of where
they're doing swab testing on road sites
after events out there which I've been a
part of and it's crazy to think that
they still have that mentality of this
being that schedule one because myself
being of all things the criminal justice
major in college I'm kind of like you
know how natal was like something was
amiss I never saw why cannabis fit in
schedule one along with cocaine and
other substances it just never actually
gosh cookings too
um a PCP of methamphetamines you know
never quite made sense to me on how it
was classified but well being a brand
holder well I know we're kind of a
little over but Katie how does you know
as far as where you are and what you're
doing what you're offering what is the
one thing that you continue to lead with
in order to move forward in the current
state of cannabis you know is it
conversation is it
yeah so we we decided to to take to
really taboo Industries and combine them
into one so we have not only uh Sexual
Health and Wellness but then cannabis as
well so for us it's been uh there's just
so many hurdles to jump through
um just in terms of you know in the
documentary it says like just simple
advertising like we can't do Instagram
we can't do uh Google ads we can't you
know it's it's really very very
challenging and so I think building a
community is kind of the key and that's
something that we're actively
um building is a is a is a positive
Sexual hellness Health and Wellness
Community but it's hard it's really hard
in terms of even just the the
regulations you know we ordered
packaging and by the time we ordered
packaging they had changed a lot and the
packaging that we ordered we could no
longer use and had to order new
packaging
um which is
which is kind of all part of the
industry I think all of us have had
something like that happen yeah the
moving Target for sure definitely well I
know we're getting close on time but
want to Circle back to Easter on so you
know this has been again it was a really
different angle that was taken with this
documentary is a little bit more of the
reality right the real side of things
like you said you cover different
aspects
um but as opposed to uh you know and I
think it was mentioned some of the early
documents one of the first documentaries
I was tied to in the industry was uh it
was rolling papers which was one that we
did with the Cannabis out in Colorado
this is back in 2014.
um that was more about the buzz and the
energy and the hoopla and all the money
and everything this one took a little
bit more of a surreal look at it
um what do you think the follow-up is
you know if there was to be another one
in a year what would that look like do
you think compared to to what we covered
here
certainly to talk more about the
international and Global stage as it
relates to how everything's becoming
connected now I mean I intentionally
wanted to focus on
the US for this one but I think there's
more stories to be told there as well as
just some of the interesting stories of
the people who were
kind of risking it all doing things when
it was uh much more highly punished than
it is now I think is another area that's
you know you can never tell enough of
those stories I think because those are
the people who you know deserve a lot of
credit for what they did the risk they
took and the sacrifices they made so I
think there's always more stories to
tell because it occurred to me as Evan
was talking
you know the War on Drugs is often
framed as a failure and we've failed
with the War on Drugs but it's very rare
if if not ever that I've heard it framed
as it was wrong
um almost as if it would have like oh
well if it had been a success it would
have been you know it would have been
worth it if we were able to achieve this
win the war on drugs
um but I think moving forward uh I think
a lot of that the damage that has been
done needs to be framed as like this was
wrong it was like this was bad
um and we need to kind of come to terms
with that I think as a society and a
culture for however many you know
everyone who kind of bought into that
belief that all all these people are are
evil and criminals and we need to punish
them
um and kind of like make amends for all
of that I think there's a lot more
stories that could be told there
yeah I mean I think it'd be a very valid
point I didn't know until more recently
I mean I I knew all the way back to the
anslinger days but I didn't know it was
Napoleon and it was the French that
actually started the the true war on
cannabis that blew my mind when I went
that far back into the history books and
learned about that's where it really
started but to your point
um I I hear it as well the failed War on
Drugs versus the fact that the war on
specifically this drug should have never
happened because it was weaponized to
Target minorities obviously during the
inslinger era but also during the Nixon
era into a certain extent I believe the
Dare era as well with the modern day War
on Drugs that we all grew up with but
again really appreciate the storytelling
I appreciate all of you for being a part
of it again I think it was such a props
to strongs for such a diverse group of
individuals with with so many different
backgrounds in so many different
motivations that tie to what makes you
passionate about what you do because
that's one thing that again I really
applaud an individual it's coming from
the outside in and being able to top
people that put passion in Community
First and an industry of profit second I
think that's as much as we'd like to
thank everyone in this community is Good
Vibes we know there are players who are
just out for that extreme capitalism
that haven't touched on
um so definitely appreciate all of you
taking the apartment and looking forward
for the documentary the debut and for
people to find out the true story not
the Hollywood Story but but the true
story of what the current state is uh
for our community our industry so thank
you all again for coming out I hope you
have a fantastic 4 20. uh for those who
are tuning in I definitely appreciate
all of you joining us today like I said
take a little different angle doing more
of uh kind of a nod to the 420 into this
documentary but thank you all for tuning
in we'll be doing another webinar next
month so definitely be sure to join in
with us again thank you all and have a
good rest of your week until next time
[Music]
thank you