welcome to Cali High episode 66 a garden
chat with Nat and Hallie Pennington
I'm your host chenzo and in this episode
we return to the world of cannabis for a
talk with Nat Pennington and his
daughter Hallie Pennington of the
Humboldt Seed Company about the origins
of cultivars registering strains in
Colombia searching for land races in
Jamaica the development of triploids
which I found out has nothing to do with
three leaves old strains new strains as
well as scratch and sniff cannabis and
more
stay tuned
Cali high is stoked to be here with Nat
and Halle Bennington today of the
Humboldt Seed Company how are you guys
we're doing well excellent a beautiful
spring day in Humboldt and spring is
finally here in California as I'm sure
uh it's there for you as well oh yeah
it's Big Spring after the all the rain
yep just trying to
get the bugs down
I know the bugs are going to be bad this
year yep yep
we uh decided to do the
the interview in our
our little kitchen Garden outside of our
cabin out here at the uh anchor Farm a
Humboldt seed company we've been here
since Hallie was a little tyke and um
right now
there's a bunch of other folks in the
kitchen they're cooking up some
something special so I I knew it would
be too crazy loud in there so hopefully
everybody hears it's okay I'm sure it'll
be okay we'll fix it up so a little
Sunday brunch going on
yeah yeah I think they're
there oh
the pantry area and they found some cans
of chickpeas that needed to get used so
yeah I I used to have an Armenian
girlfriend and her mother taught me how
to make hummus yes nice long time ago
we have our own garlic every year we do
like a little garlic
Garden we've been saving the seeds for
too long that I can remember and uh so
this is the time of year where it's like
you got to use it or else it doesn't
stick around much longer and and we're
about to harvest the other big patch of
it over there too so oh how cool I'm
trying trying to grow some food as well
so far I've only got arugula basil uh
cilantro and Italian parsley
but it's a start about to start
somewhere yeah well when I moved out
here in 1995 the first thing I did just
right down the road in the little town
of Orleans in Humboldt County is where
most of the farmers market Farms are for
humble and Humboldt has of course
Humboldt State University which is now
Cal Poly humble
and Arcata it's one of the bigger
farmers markets on the whole West Coast
as far as at least it was at one point
in time it was the biggest in the
country
uh
so when I came out here I was 18 and I
needed work I'd you know basically
hitchhiked my way out here and and I
worked on these Organic Farms down there
in The Big Valley and that was really
like what made growing cannabis
uh sort of natural for me was not like
necessarily going on to the you know
the internet sites and like having to
you know buy all the fancy ingredients
but just like knowing the basis of
organic farming was really I feel like
it made a huge difference for me I was
like well this stuff is seems a lot like
the tomatoes and all we did to those
because this that and the other and boom
we had tomatoes Galore so I'm gonna try
that next thing I know it's like yeah I
got a lot of ganja out of that
yeah I've been trying to not buy any
more soil and just re you know keep the
soil alive and you know maybe add a
little worm castings or whatever needs
to be done I've even tried some compost
pots and uh I got a 45 gallon pot that
I'm composting in but yeah organic is
the way to go I believe
yeah always tastes better that way yeah
you know and I I heard that um it's
better for you
we're always talking about the Tomato
analogy you're like yeah that tomato
that you see in Safeway looks perfect
and
I mean I can see right through it to be
honest I'm like yeah tasteless it's
shaped nice there's no like it's not a
single spot on it or anything like that
but I can see like
literally I can see the weird mealy
texture inside of it yeah one of my
biggest
Pepe growing up with him out here is
pricey salad or something like that and
it says heirloom tomatoes and you're
expecting these beautiful like super
flavorful amazing tomato and you get
served one of those like nasty mealy GMO
tomatoes and I mean it just the most
disappointing thing after you've had
like endless perfect fresh tomatoes all
summer long so yeah well
yeah I I like heirloom tomatoes if
they're really heirloom you know they
they seem to be the better tasting of
the ones that I find at Whole Foods or
somewhere like that but uh and maybe try
growing some tomatoes and I mean I
we always said like cannabis is the
garden gateway drug and it's like seen a
lot of people get you know grow some
some weed plants because they you know
want to smoke their own which is awesome
there's no nothing wrong with that but
it's I think it's cool that it gets
people just back in touch with you know
playing around with growing things
nature and all that good stuff and yeah
we've got basil and Arlo Garden here
we've got our Auto flowers right behind
us I don't know if you can see them but
we'll go on we'll go on a little tour
okay if you will walk around the spot
excellent
so you know I I've been doing my
research as usual and uh
well
what really uh something that caught my
eye was uh your five questions with
Forbes Magazine but
that was cool I have more than five so
let's let me start here
um I read somewhere that you were
registering strains in Colombia now are
are those like Colombian strains or your
strains and how do you register a strain
in Colombia
so yeah that's
have been definitely putting ourselves
out there across the country
um
earthquake alert
well it's a good thing you're outside
yeah I
it's a 6.0
off the coast of Northern California
but uh we're not there we're inland
it's far enough and humble that this
earthquake's probably not affecting us
but that's yeah that's a pretty
significant earthquake it looks like
it's happening right now
in uh
maybe near you know our office on the
coast and well I hope everybody's okay
well we'll find out I'll ask my wife to
check get up on everybody out there so
we don't have to interrupt the interview
I mean as people might
know earthquakes are kind of a normal
thing yep I've lived through two big
ones down here
Egypt just recently had some decent ones
uh I'm talking about what was it uh
71 and 94.
right right when like freeways fell down
and you know you know
so Ali you were there for the the one on
the coast what'd you that was the Wild
Ride wasn't it yeah definitely we've got
a few good ones in the last few years
honestly there's been a few that are
that are like are long drawn out ones so
it'll be just shaking and oh for long
enough for you to sit there and be like
all right
[Laughter]
the earthquake
all right here we go get that back okay
professional camera adjuster
um did it turn upside down on you or
anything no uh I I think I saw the
little
the stand that you're
putting your phone on
yeah we did we have our phone on a
little stand
okay all righty
so back to you um registering strains in
Colombia
yeah so as cannabis kind of becomes you
know
legal or whatever regulated across the
the globe we obviously want to
participate I mean we feel like we
definitely have something to share
an offer and so
um
in Colombia it's they they have this
very onerous process that it's a lot of
comp or a lot of countries I think
should probably try to avoid but it's
what it does is it makes it if you want
to produce cannabis
you have this very long several year
process to
get your strain or cultivar they would
probably call it uh registered and so
yeah we did initiate that process we do
have one our blueberry muffin is
registered down there but it's it's uh
it's a little bit ridiculous because as
I'm sure anybody who's interested in
cannabis in the United States is aware
we're as breeders collectively you know
whether just in the U.S or even
internationally we're like very quickly
coming up with new varieties so if you
have something that I mean our blueberry
muffin seems to withstand the test of
time but generally
you know two thumbs up on that one
that lifetime the lifespan of a cannabis
variety or strain is not
necessarily super long unfortunately so
it had been I mean the OG Kush of course
was popular forever but I mean of course
there's going to be some Classics that
always stay around I think you know our
blueberry muffin was a great option for
this project because you know that's one
that I'll smoke probably until I'm you
know about to grow basically so but
there are things that you know we at
least have new better crosses of new
versions of and even for the blueberry
muffin for example you know we've we've
made our blueberry cupcake lines and so
we're always hunting and looking for the
next best thing and yeah it's hard to
commit to you know the one thing and
so I think it's interesting I think you
know the the guess is is that either
that's going to be one of those rules
down there that doesn't always just you
know that a lot of people just
collectively decide to ignore
and but nonetheless yes that's been an
effort to get some things registered
down there and and a valiant effort
that's that's been you know Ben Ben Lynn
kind of has been
going out and
sort of reaching out to some of those
International markets but they're which
is great but you know we've seen a lot
of them are as sort of volatile or even
more volatile than what we see in
California and the US in general where
you know you can make your very very
best guess about what the smartest
move is to have a
you know at least sustainable business
and you can totally be it's
but I think it's a great for us to dip
our toes into in a sense because also
like as you mentioned it's so volatile
that we don't know that you know in the
next few years regulations couldn't
require that you know all over the place
for us to even do interstate so yeah um
you know for gear up and be prepared to
end up in that position if we absolutely
have to I mean by all means I would like
to have witness as much paperwork as
possible but that's just not the reality
anymore of this industry yeah hey were
you able to like locate any of the old
good Colombians trains and bring them
back
yeah there was some um I know Ben
brought some Colombian strands back we
went down to Jamaica if people watch our
YouTube we've got a cool uh video about
collecting land land races uh in Jamaica
and
you know the interesting thing about
that is is that things have changed so
much in the last 20 years that while it
is really cool to incorporate those
genetics into
new efforts and new breeding
techniques and practices
um
for us it's what we are very comfortable
growing the land race genetics ourselves
because we don't
have expectations we don't
depend on producing flour and having it
be a certain way
to make our living where because we're
strictly looking for seeds and new you
know
you see though it's getting windy a
little bit you've seen varieties but
anyways
land races are
are great and they sound very romantic
of course you're like you know oh I know
this land race from from Columbia or
Jamaica that's been around forever and
the problem is is that you know we
haven't even had the concept of seedless
cannabis hasn't really been a thing for
that long and so
except for in Thailand
the seedless they yeah that was the
first seedless I ever saw
right right
um
yeah yeah it's high sticks yeah that
they must have just been really on it
with that huh oh yeah from Thailand
right yeah and you know
um I've grown what what was purported to
be
land race tie and it's nothing it's like
something that Mom like the hemp from
the Hmong tribe mixed with something
else and it's you know but the funny
thing is and I was arguing with somebody
about it and telling them they don't
know what they're talking about
like five days later I'm in Whole Foods
I'm waiting for the elevator to go up to
the bathroom and some guy comes in and
we start talking and he says he like
lived in Thailand for a while and I so I
asked him and you know if he speaks time
we start speaking Thai to each other
waiting for the
the elevator and then
we have this whole conversation in Thai
and then we go to the bathroom and come
back down and he takes me out to his car
and he's as old as I am right and spent
time in the military and has been living
in Thailand for like the last well maybe
besides the last two years about 10
years before that and a long time before
that long story short he opens his trunk
pull there's a big bag he pulls out two
giant nuggies I smell him I haven't
smelled that since 82.
right and so he's like kind of a ski bum
guy and I probably won't see him again
until
like the snow is melted but he's got the
seeds and I know where he's we talked
about where he sourced him he got him
from uh
uh chief of police in a in a location I
will not divulge at the moment
but uh it's the real tie and so
uh maybe we'll one day we'll get that to
you that that's something worth having
well we we had we had tie strains
about
supposedly of course but um they were
the one of some of the most Frosty
beautiful
cannabis buds that we had on the farm
that year and I was be thrilled and you
know cross some things into them but but
then of course you know we got into the
world of of testing cannabis potency and
they were testing like 13 a lot of
people you would assume that the frost
and the trichomes that you see on buds
are
somehow correlated to the potency the
THC potency at least I should say and
that's that's not the case at all you
can have some of the most Frosty
beautiful looking flowers come back
testing you know 10 percent
um it's always disappointing when that
is the case and but they you know they
probably have cannabinoids in there that
we just don't know we're not smart
enough to look for yet and that's the
thing is that that's the huge problem
with basing any kind of decision on the
laboratory results that we have right
now in in like you know wanting to
it's tough for us with breeding it's
sort of like you know having to choose
between
you know whether we're making our
customers happy
or we're following our passions or we're
and you know clearly there's no denying
that cannabis that doesn't test very
high doesn't sell and right so if
growing commercially
then why in the world would you grow
something that you can't sell and that's
that's all just very basic logic yeah
and there's no getting around it like
unless you're some kind of an
independently wealthy trust fund you
know people are always like giving us a
hard time like
you know oh why do you you know worry
about the THC or whatever and we're just
like because we just don't we're not we
don't have tons of money right we're not
like we're doing this as a business
it's a business and unfortunately like
we haven't taken any investment money
and we don't have
even if we had you know like our
investors would be even more on us about
doing just high THC varieties so but I
mean the overall goal is the business
needs to at least pay for itself yeah
right yeah involves having some high
testers in the Arsenal if we didn't
break even we would you know we wouldn't
just it just wouldn't happen because we
wouldn't have the work people working we
wouldn't have the you know I mean the
goddamn licenses are so freaking
expensive and
but it's getting a little better they've
realized that they you know made some
mistakes I think at the state level and
at the even at the local level but yeah
I saw something about taxes being
bundled into a different um
category or getting rid of some and just
making one the United cannabis Business
Association down here was
working with this I think it was a state
I don't know exactly the outcome of that
there's good things happening there's
good stuff whether it was it's too
little too late is yet to be seen I mean
I it there are so many big Mega Farms
like you know there are
many that are over 100 acres at this
point and
um
there's just a lot of like real irony in
the industry that you just it makes you
wonder whether there is a greater
sort of plan to just kind of take it
away from people that may have been
rebellious in in
the original growing of it you know sort
of oh yeah well once people just get
their hands on
what's that I said once politicians get
their hands on it I think you know which
they kind of already have since they are
in charge of legislation and things like
that it just kind of uh ruins the whole
uh Cosmic Vibe of it
crazy now because you know we're seeing
like even
what 40 minutes down the road from us
there was a facility built out that I
think took around 18 million dollars
investment and it's now going up for
auction at 3.5 million and so if you
think about it like that opens the door
for all these people that just kind of
walked right in and be like all right
you know this is nice this is already
all set up you're not a great day
well it was 40. crazy they took 40
million in Investments to make it and I
I mean it's worth what it's worth it's
like unfortunately that
36 million dollars is
those investors
are bonds you know it's gone I mean yeah
you're right though somebody could jump
in and
swoop it up and at least make it you
know fairly profitable if they only have
to pay 3.5 right I know it seems bizarre
it's such a bizarre thing I mean
yeah but you know there were
I would say like the pendulum swings and
so humble we still have this like
incredible knowledge and wealth of
experience of people that have held out
here
and
we lost some of them though to like
really easy mistakes and I mean when
when people were around us like taking
millions and millions of dollars in
investment money
we were somewhat kind of like oh crap
you know are we gonna be able to
survive
even though we're in something
I'm so sorry that's all right even
though we're something that's like
here Holly maybe you can help
I'll just hold it for a minute like even
if we had a
weren't like a totally different Niche
um
it still was scary you know I we were
like shoot what are we gonna do you know
and one of the sad things was that the
um I think that'll work great
one of the sad things was that the
the county and some of the
elected officials were kind of like took
those projects more seriously than the
small local
person that had been here for a long
time and
and so we we were kind of always getting
you know our applications and permit
documents and things were getting sort
of
uh attention last so let's just say or
or cast to the side
somewhat it felt like and and the ones
that were like oh yeah we just got you
know got another 10 million dollars from
some
rich person that and
you know so now we've got we'll do
whatever you want us to do as far as our
applications and blah blah blah 10
Consultants writing the whole entire
thing for him I mean you should have
seen this first initial application that
he submitted and he wrote pretty much
all of it himself it was like a binder
this thick yeah it was like he wrote an
awful
it was beyond Master's thesis it was and
you know I I had experience writing
grants and writing
environmental documents and reports for
the Klamath River and the salmon and all
that stuff so yep thank God I had that
because a lot of people that
that didn't you know
the Consultants are are helpful and
great but sometimes you know they just
you know they're
they're not like
if your project doesn't make it through
they're not out of a job they have 20
projects right so there's not a lot of
real care and knowledge going into it I
mean I don't want to
I mean there are Consultants that could
have done way better than I did but it
the fact that I didn't I think made when
I would call the county and say what's
going on I haven't you know heard back
or or I just want to you know you to
tell me that at least I'm in good
standing now because you know you
haven't been communicative and and I
know I turned everything in that I was
supposed to and I see
you know Joe down the road just got
hauled off in handcuffs last week and I
don't really want that to happen to my
family and I so am I good or what and
they'd be like
obviously here's your application oh
okay you are your own consultant or
you're writing all the documents I'm
like yup and they're like
actually yeah you are good they're
always like we've never seen it done
like this but we can't poke any holes in
it so that's cool uh you know I wrote my
own uh conscientious subjector
application for the U.S Navy as of the
first Buddhist uh conscientious
subjectured on the grounds of Bad Karma
and I actually succeeded
um no lawyer would take my case but what
you know so yeah
um
so
another thing I read
that you've developed scratch and sniff
cannabis samples is that true now
is that
a long time ago it was actually my wife
Amber in there you remember when yeah
sounds forever well it didn't really
take off the first time though you know
I think we're a little ahead of the
times Maybe
I'm not trying to brag it's actually
it's a freaking pain in our ass we're
always kind of like a little ahead of
our time
was it the tissue culture lab in my old
bedroom when we were doing we were doing
tissue culture in 2015-16 and it we kind
of realized at that point kind of like
ah this has some good utility but it's
not like and now it's like you know been
the hottest new thing to do across the
entire industry for the last right three
years to get a lot faster money if you
want if you mention those words little
buzzwords
its advantages maybe it's a clean a
genetic or just to preserve something
for a long period of time for any kind
of like you know scale production it's
just uh not the most practical option
it's onerous and slow and it takes a
really long time for the plants to come
out of tissue culture whereas like with
seeds they are actually cleaner than
tissue culture
entirely like nothing tissue culture can
still have hop latent virus whereas the
seed is very very unlikely to have it
inside the embryo yeah
and then you know seeds come out of
their shell
raring and ready to go
and catch up and surpass clones as far
as like how big you can get a plant in
no time
and uh
tissue culture kind of like creeped back
into reality you know it's sort of like
needs to wake up it has a long long slow
wake up but we don't want to just sit
around a dish tissue culture I mean if
there's a greenhouse right over here
that if my Wi-Fi was a little better I
I'd just go walk with you but we'll try
it but anyway
um
we had blueberry muffin in there and
what was it that it made me ask Amber
anyway so my wife Amber was like if you
could just make a scratch and sniff
with this smell here and
because it's such a potently smelling
strain and um
she was like that would just people
would love that and I was like oh man
you're right and so I just said
you know and the first time we did it we
did it with the magazine and we we had
uh the Turpin extraction which you know
Ben has done super into the Turpin
extraction he does that a ton and so
that's been amazing but you know got
that and then found a place that would
you know do the process of actually
turning it into something that lasts a
long time in the scratch and sniff ink
type form
and uh it's a fairly natural process and
it really you're just taking the plants
essence you know the essential oil and
and
putting it into a
you know a format that
is not only is like lasts a long time
and easy to share but it also doesn't
have cannabinoids in it because
that's the only thing that really leaves
behind so it it really takes all of the
the essence the turpins and the Esters
and and the flavonoids and all the
different things there are so many
things beyond turpins that make up the
real smell of cannabis right and it
carries all of those
but it won't carry the the waxy
uh compounds that are cannabinoids and
so leaving those behind
may affect the
smell ever so slightly but but we feel
like
I mean you get the benefit is that it
it's completely and totally legal as you
know a non-thc
you know whatever it's not even happen
this doesn't have anything in it that's
a controlled substance so maybe there's
a perfume in line in the future
we did we worked with a brand that made
a perfume line and a cologne line out of
our cannabinoids we're out of our
turpents excuse me the blueberry or what
hey what was it fog and trees yeah yeah
that might have been a tad bit ahead of
it it was ahead of its time yeah
you know part of it still had such a
stigma around it almost and I I first
smelled it and I was like this smells
amazing I love it I love the idea but I
also was just imagining whoever squirts
them on their wrist and then hops in the
car and accidentally gets pulled over on
their way to work
I was like ah this is gonna be a hard
one to explain in some situations
hey when you guys so we did to your
original question okay we're we're like
the tangent Masters here that's all
right I like tangents
I I told Hallie because I used to do
interviews for the salmon stuff and have
sometimes these like
you know press would actually want to
like rattle you and stuff and I'd always
be like you know it doesn't matter what
they ask just talk about what you want
to talk about
so apologies that that probably carries
over sometimes well we did do a salmon
uh interview one time if you remember
about that yeah well you know now the
dams will officially be 100 out of the
Klamath River next year right end of
next fall yes so the first stand will be
gone this year at the end of this fall
you can't really do a lot of this stuff
over the winter just because of the high
flow and but then by next fall
um they will have a completely
free-flowing Klamath River
wow and yeah like that as I've told
people a million times these are like
Antiquated dams and they don't produce
but like the power grid when Pacific or
was in negotiations with us we would
talk about that and they would you know
we had a guy take us to the side and he
was like you know what if we were to
just shut off the the uh
breaker for Klamath Dam projects we
wouldn't even see the needle on our
overall grid move like it would move as
much as
you know
like it's nothing he they were basically
like it's and and the fact is that every
single year
we have to build 13
facilities that produce
the equivalent amount of power as those
dams so people are always like oh you're
taking out all these you know like what
what they would call renewable energy
and it's like
you know this this destroyed
like the entire salmon run the third
largest salmon run on the west coast of
the United States and
you know where every single year we have
to build for 13 of these things and to
get that salmon run back we have to
build 14 one year you know like what the
[__] that doesn't you know there's
nothing no difference there and they
don't store water
they they
you know they don't control floods
because they have to be maintained full
for the power plants to run it's just
this whole
terrible design of you know the
1930s 40s 50s I mean no
you know no disrespects to those
Engineers but they just didn't think
about this kind of stuff back then it
was just like you know oh there's more
salmon than you could ever want I mean
they had
you know like if you go into the I
always say like back then there was so
much salmon that they never could have
dreamed that it would be a a problem
it's happened so fast if you really
think about it like
fail too I mean that's not that much
time realistically from 1930s so now
it's devastating what has happened so
the impacts the negative impacts to
benefit ratio is just it's like you know
completely uh out of whack in life yeah
the last time that I even you know went
further than knee-deep in that River
just because it's so disgusting I don't
you know I don't let my dog near it
because if he drinks the water he can
die in the summer
yeah
but we wrapped down it but I don't mean
I don't I don't but at certain times yes
at certain times there's like warnings
and it's like you know and it's because
of this these unnatural algal blooms
that happen in the reservoirs right
right that will be gone so it's really
exciting for us and it's it's exciting
for I think a lot of the Pacific
Northwest because you know people just
don't understand
I mean we're in California but we are
part of the Pacific Northwest here in
Humboldt County and that's I mean we
have redwoods and we have you know
coniferous forest and you know look
right behind us you know that's
and obviously it's not rainy all year
and we still have like that's one of the
beauties of humble and why I think
cannabis became so popular from here is
you know we have this very unique
um climate that is
you know partly
cold nights and you know last night it
was probably
50 degrees 40 degrees
we had a little campfire and had you
know s'mores because we had friends over
but uh you could do that all summer long
and humble that's one of the things I
love about Humboldt is like it always
cools off enough that you can
enjoy enjoy the evening enjoy the
evening
and then you know today it doesn't feel
like it's going to get quite as hot but
yesterday it was got to the 90s I'm sure
so um plants love that
so I was going to ask you guys
um how many states are you in and does
the market different differ from each
state to state I mean
it definitely is pretty different in
every state it's one thing that we've
kind of had to adapt to I mean there's
some places that have legalized and gone
in that direction but haven't really
ruled out regulation and so you know as
someone who's trying to establish uh you
know very serious brain somewhere it's
hard for us to jump into those doors
like you know New York for example has
been a little bit of a tricky one we
wouldn't want to you know get a property
or make any big decisions until they let
us know you know what is going to be
okay and what isn't so yeah
yeah we did do
a little satellite in New York and kind
of had a nursery operation and made it
so that people could get
seeds in as legal of a way as they could
or even gets plants in as legal of a way
as they could in New York last year
so many people like the state didn't
really have it together I mean it's not
their fault it's no one's fault but it
just like we were kind of ahead of our
time a little bit I think and yeah and
you know we didn't need to have that
significant of a
of an offering over there and and so you
know we were there though and we
definitely met a lot of people and it
was really helpful for a lot of people
that we were there it made it so that
maybe we broke even instead of you know
making any money but that's just the way
it goes sometimes and
um
uh I think you know you live and learn
and it's like
it's all just part of the process of
there's a lot to complain about we have
a lot to
be thankful about I think in some
respects just
being that we have this Niche and that
we
you know like
I started
reading cannabis in in
1997 in Humboldt and is my youngest
daughter here hi there
so you know that was
[Music]
great timing you know what I mean I had
and
uh saw that there would be a need to
have seeds and new types of cannabis and
so
really followed that passion and stuck
to it and
established
go ahead sorry sorry what were your
original cultivars that you started with
way back then
well it was somewhat before they really
had I mean before cannabis was had so
many names you know it was kind of like
still pretty clandestine and
so
some of the very best things that I
came across as breeding and selecting
and selling cannabis
in the medical you know
framework that we had here in California
for so many years
um
were were not things that came to me
with strain names they were just this is
these are really good seeds from
from you know Joe up in Oregon and these
ones came from Southern humble and it
was you know Ed's favorite last year and
it was purple and you know a lot of them
had different scriptures and stuff and
of course there were varieties around
like train wreck and there was no such
thing as OG Kush and there was no such
thing as
um
you know there just wasn't very many
strain names and so we did have you know
they're a thing became popular that they
called Salmon Creek big bud and you know
it
it's like probably not a name that
people would choose these days because
it's like
you know it's so
you know it's it was a type of weed that
made big buds and it came from a place
called Salmon Creek in southern humble
yeah and that was that was one of the
most
you know sort of famous places where
weed came from
and of course I'm sure people wrote on
their bags a lot of the times Salmon
Creek big bud and then a lot of
helicopters went up Salmon Creek because
you know I would always imagine like a
lot of a lot of weed is you know getting
picked up going across the country with
that
you know that I wonder where this came
from oh it says it came from Salmon
Creek and it's big
yeah yeah some of the first ones we
worked with didn't have names and then
you know we obviously had train wreck
and we just got everything we literally
that's one of the beauties of
of Humboldt is that like really it's
been such a massive hub for cannabis
that pretty much every kind of cannabis
has made its way through here
um and people brought some of the first
Afghani
cultivars that people actually brought
back from Afghanistan like I I have a a
friend whose father was here in the
early 70s and
specifically went on a mission to go
find seeds in in Afghanistan and Nepal
and in India and brought them back and I
mean he could be responsible for
you know 80 percent of modern cannabis
just doing that one trip
yeah and I mean that's his status dad
will never let I begged him before like
please
do an interview or you know tell your
story of of doing that and it's just you
know those guys
had their fun and they have those
stories to share with people that they
know and trust but they're not
not always super excited to you know
really you know
I did interview Bobby ackerly of the uh
Brotherhood of eternal love of a few
years ago who had gone to Kandahar and
driven uh Volkswagen van full of
Afghani Primo
back across Europe and then shipped it
to the east coast and drove it here and
those guys also brought seeds yeah and
some of the uh you know Legends of Maui
Wowie ended up being like crosses
between The Afghani and the oaxacan or
whatever but yeah well if you still I
mean if you go back that far
try to make keeping the seeds out of the
Cannabis was not
everything had seeds in it except the
Thai wheat Thai sticks
yeah which that's really interesting
that you brought that up
um
yep but yeah uh
you know we figured out kind of mastered
the whole sensimilla with seeds or
cannabis without seed in Humble yeah
I first saw it around like 79
like the first California seedless it
was like four times as much as Colombian
yeah instead of 500 a pound it was 2
000.
yeah but um so here's something
interesting what about the development
of triploids we we were talking about
that a little bit right
so
triploid is is fairly high-tech seed
technology
um I mean
technology I guess yeah it you need a
flow cytometer to be able to to check
and make sure that they they are
actually as you say they are and um
so so that's pretty high tech and and
they're sterile
well they they should be sterile in
theory they are not always sterile we're
finding out but they for the most part
if your goal is to grow
seedless cannabis which obviously is the
goal of most commercial people
um
then
then yes it's a better much better
option for
not having to worry about that yeah
that's also I mean there's other
benefits as well it's supposed to
increase the yields on average I think
you know it was found to be like around
at least 20 percent
yeah so it's still you know there are
some people that have been
making triploids in hemp and it's still
definitely in its sort of like infancy
for especially for cannabis uh for THC
cannabis
but
um it there are a lot of indications
that triplets will
potentially produce sort of superior
commercially more commercially viable
options than
so then diploids and for folks that
aware of all this it's been around for a
while like you know seedless watermelons
or triploid they're
um bananas strawberries actually are
octopoid a lot of the time but ploidy
is is how many sets of chromosomes are
in the nucleus of each cell and and
that's not
including reproductive cells which are
usually just haploid which means one
um
single chromosome but uh
that
the way that you make triplets is you
you can use uh
I mean they occur in nature so they'll
also occur naturally
um it's a much lower uh you know you're
it's really rare to find it but be
reliable for breeding yeah it wouldn't
be reliable and you don't
it doesn't carry on past that unless you
quote it so I got some out of the Squirt
from last year believe it or not my
friend I turned them on to some teams
that's actually a different
what you're referring to is when you see
the three leaves
right that the three
and and what that's called is the world
taxonomy and people often assume that
that is is triploid and it's it's not
it's um
just that really common early mutation
in the beginning of a plant's growth
where it'll produce
the three first sets of true leaves and
then oftentimes it'll just eventually go
back to normal yeah to where it's you
like the you know parallel opposing
nodes
so triplet is is entirely different it's
not something that you can observe
externally at all it's something that
you would have to have a flow cytometer
to or or
do genetic sequencing to be able to see
it and uh
so it's it's beyond my pay grade it's
funny because there's popular cultivars
that have been released by like
well-known breeders and they didn't even
have any idea themselves that it was
just a naturally occurring triploid and
so that was maybe part of why was their
selection you know it was probably a
pretty dense Fielder yeah uh they're
like you know obviously drawn to it for
a reason but you know then again it's
not something you can observe with the
naked eye
we discovered that the Mach 1 is a
triploid and
nobody had any idea
which one
Mac one
calculator stream and I I don't did
Richard end up reaching out to yeah and
informing him of that yeah I don't think
he even knew up until uh the scientists
there we work with
like hey bud I happen to test this Mac
one and then
next thing you know turns out yeah so so
do real triploids have also three leaves
no no nothing it has nothing basically
you know especially in a vegetative
state it's there's really not any
identifiable markers that you know you
could tell them apart they have the
exact same leaves you know same
structure overall but we are starting to
monitor basically just to see if they
really do have more overall bigger and
also of course you know yield so we
produced about
what are we up to like 10 different
types of triploid varieties and we're
testing them out right now all across
the state actually across the country
it's gonna be your first year we're
bringing the triplets into our annual
pheno hunt process which is always
a big thing for us it's probably my
favorite
I want to participate in that is it you
know it probably can be one of our first
real field tests where we get to see
them next to a population of you know
diploid cannabis plants as well
um I knew we we talked about this and
the selection process is somewhat
limited but
how did you select males when you did
right well yeah so as people probably
know more and more seed companies have
joined us in doing the femini seeds
it's
we've kind of you know we've been doing
this for
25 years at least so that technology
wasn't as prevalent before and we didn't
utilize it for the first 15 years of
breeding
and
so we selected males
in the day we we rub the stems you know
when they're about this tall and I I
still do this to be honest but when
they're like this tall you go out and
you just like rub the stems and there's
like little they're they're actually
trichomes that are
having a different function and you get
kind of the idea of the I mean you can
absolutely tell you know one of them
will just smell three times stronger
than another exactly
I thought that's what it was
I mean just just obvious things too like
you have some that are you know almost
double vigorous than another one and
that's gonna be an advantage that you
might want to select for and you know
structure it's always there's always
good things to look at but it's it
doesn't really compare quite to being
able to look at two female plants with
you know beautiful flower and you know
and then you imagine the exact traits
that you want to see out of that cross
right away
yeah yeah well
do you get what she's saying about the
feminized process why why it's so
advantageous aside from the fact that
you end up with all female seeds which
kind of makes it easier for the for the
grower but you want to explain it again
I mean really yeah it's the fact that
when you're breeding with uh male on
female uh you're only getting that
female flower visual of the female plant
and so there's always this portion that
is kind of a mystery you're doing your
best educated guesswork there obviously
if we look at it and make sure the
structure is great you know it's nice
and vigorous pest resistant whatever
aside from those things you really don't
know what it would look like as a female
yeah so when feminized breeding came
along it really it just gave us the
opportunity to actually you know set our
eyes on you know exactly what we're
crossing together every single time and
for brand new crosses that's really
important especially you know for so for
people that don't understand
how do we know exactly the female what
she looks like when we're making
feminized scenes because we're going to
yeah because we go Fino home to it
beforehand and so we have that but then
we take that that selection that we've
made and now we put
silver on it and it it actually
effectively changes it to a male now but
it has the same chromosome the same DM
DNA that's the plant that we looked at
two months ago right but now we've
turned it into a male plant and so
therefore it makes pollen that
excuse me that has the the DNA of that
beautiful flower that we just looked at
to three months ago or whatever I mean
I'm kind of it takes a long time to do
this [__] but you could do it in three
months in theory but it's usually harder
anyway so we then reversed sex and now
we've got this planet that's putting out
pollen that has female all-female XX
chromosomes too so that's the reason why
when it lands on another female plant
the stigma and the ovum the ovum all on
female plants has XX chromosomes as well
so you don't have this coin flip that
you have with regular plant breeding it
took you know I I was at UC Davis doing
salmon genomics with some of my best
friends there that are professors there
and we
would talk about this stuff and you know
I'd just go over and over again what are
the potential problems with breeding
this way because I didn't want to
jump fully into it like we have without
understanding if it was going to
negatively affect the species or if I
was going to be doing something terrible
and it was just not really negative if
you you could do it wrong and there can
be negative you know you can create more
hermaphrodite
uh traits in cannabis by doing it
incorrectly and but we learned quickly
how to do it properly and we don't do
that and so we don't see I mean we keep
really really good data about any
reports that come back from the our
customers about hermaphrodites and the
percentage of of hermaphrodites in
regular plants is
irregular breeding is just as high or
sometimes even higher I mean not only
that but of the feminine sorry corrupt
but uh we do pretty extreme stress
testing yeah on all of our breeding
Chambers as well and so you know
throughout the entire process we're
almost weekly checking on the plants and
if there's you know anyone that has a
room site on it it immediately gets
taken out and that way it's not going
into production at all yeah yeah and you
can't you can't stress test the male
plant for hermaphrodites it's like so
that's another I mean it just goes on
and on the reasons that we prefer
feminized breeding over regular breeding
just have it ever seem to stop it's just
been ridiculous how much better it is
and it you know some people are like oh
it's not natural and I'm just like I
mean it's colloidal silver you can use
oil silver
like I I dropped that in mind I got
earache and I use it I get you know like
if I have a sore throat occasionally I
use it for that and it's just like
literally I
it's not dangerous it's silver you know
you put it in our silverware and put it
in our mouths every Thanksgiving or
whatever you know so in in your current
market breakdown
between
feminized Autoflower and regular seeds
what's the percentages there
well you mean feminized Autoflower
versus
oh well yeah okay so you have of the
three types of seeds you have regular
seeds you have feminized seeds and you
have Autoflower seeds which are also
feminized right yeah so how does that do
break down as far as what people are
into
we're like 90 people are buying 98
feminized now for the most part and we
still get people by the regular because
they want to do breeding they want to
you know have their first foray into
breeding and and I would say you know if
you're trying your first foray into
breeding maybe it is easier to do
regular breeding I mean it is it
definitely is and it's easier but I mean
I still would
you know maybe say it's not a bad thing
if you jump right into feminized
breeding and we're always going to
maintain a regular line here that you
know we're always going to try to keep
that around so we do do regular breeding
we have what do we have now maybe ten
down to 10 to 12 regular streams at this
point uh uh-huh and like you know
50 of the other so how about the new
strains what what are you excited about
now
all of them I mean I mean
that's the art is gonna be really good
which one here I don't know if you've
even announced this anywhere yet but we
just finally picked two official names
for uh
their Seasons drops
the orange cream pop is coming that's
coming up we're breeding that one right
now I kind of wish I'd walk you over
there to the field and maybe what I'll
do is I I might try to send you some
pictures I don't know if you can yeah I
can edit them into the the episode do a
little video if I walk over there
without we can walk over I'll show you
part of our orange cream pop selection
and we have our jelly donut selection
happening over there then we have the
Clones
um
and so you know be a little window into
how much work goes into making something
but this one would be great the orange
cream pop is
three years in preparation to actually
put it out to the public and so this is
you know I know
um the guys that we actually did the
scratch and sniff with
um Burris place and one straw Farms down
in Calaveras which if you want
um hallel send you we're doing this
massive Fino hunt this fall
Fino frenzy was your name
I think it's a fun name it's nice and
catchy you know
but we're basically opening the doors
for our normally it's more of a private
group you know hunt but we're gonna
fight some of our just industry friends
our local colleagues and of course some
press folks as well I'd love to come
we're gonna get out into these fields I
think we have 10 Farms that we're going
to be doing it with maybe more and I'm
losing track already but uh you know
it's gonna be a ton of Finos and you
know a lot of selecting to do we're all
gonna have our little rating sheet with
about 10 different categories that we
try to observe and you know of course
we're not doing this on every single
plant but you know once you're walking
through and you start to notice what
really catches your eye then you know
everyone kind of gets in on it and we
always go back at the end we'll revisit
probably like you know the lot of 20
that somebody rated good everyone turns
into their sheet we're like these all
got you know nine through ten let's all
go check these out again as a group and
so yeah yeah we did this in 2018 we did
10 000 plants I remember I think we had
six seven Farms that year this year we
haven't settled on the exact number that
we're gonna Fino hunt it's to me it's
not as much about that as it is just you
know getting a broad spectrum of
genetics I know we're gonna look through
some of the stuff that we did with the
Scentsy seed bank and maybe try to see
if there's some skunk old school skunk
genetics we can find
um we're just gonna really open it up
but also keep it tight you know our
phenotype rating sheet is still it's
always been available for anybody to
download we pretty much still use a lot
of the same variables that we did in
2017 16 17 18 and that was kind of when
we formalized our Fino hunting processes
and uh
yeah I feel like everybody in the world
now is Fino hunting is such a
a popular word to use
it comes down to
we're really doing it in such an
in-depth and scaled way that uh well I
don't think there's any way we can do it
better yeah well ten thousand I mean in
California hello
and that was kind of like you know we
knew that the [__] was about to hit the
fan and California was going to be a
monster of cannabis and cannabis growing
and and that's you know whatever it's
like be careful what you ask or you
might get it and so in that not in that
feeling of that coming down the pipe I
was like
here we go let's freaking do it let's
you know the good part is that we have a
lot of different we can look at a lot of
different kinds of weed
around the state with all of our
Partnerships and stuff that we have so
let's you know make a final one out of
this massive industry and so year one of
California legalization we were out
there
you know looking through 10 000 plants
trying to find and
you know I mean that's been huge for us
since then we've had
even some of those varieties that first
year still are big for us and we've
we've refined them I mean whenever you
find afino it's like now you found a
clone that's the beginning of your job
as a breeder like that is literally
step one and it's like ridiculous
that we're in because so many people are
just like oh you know I gotta I found a
cool clone I'm gonna you know get really
they're releasing that rich and famous
you know you know it's funny because
you'll see things that get released once
and that clone people love it and it's
you know we have beautiful clone lines
of course that we've found in this
process too sure the problem is is
sometimes when you get these things
uh you know we'll get these genetics and
people will you know our local friends
and farmers will be like oh I've been
running this lately and I've been loving
it and maybe you guys should check it
out try it and the problem is is you
know sometimes we'll make a little Fino
hunt cross just to see it and you plant
these things and it's like there's
genetics and things coming up out of
these random you know basically clone
lines that you never would have thought
it's like you have like you know a short
little Stumpy sativa or I mean Indica
look and want a long stretchy sativa
looking one that's like all across the
board you're gonna see Grandma great
grandpa smell like you know
anything that you could throw in there
it's like when you breed those clones
that's one famous phone yeah it's like
basically like you you actually open up
what's inside of that genetic and you're
getting this whole mess of muddled
things more than just the one clone yeah
this is like before we release something
like he said with the orange cream pop
it's been in the works for three years
and that's because you know we want
people to be able to say it's a someone
trying to do their first time breeding
or a gardener that just really likes
stable genetics I think we all kind of
want our stuff to smell uniform enough
but you know we're not gonna just set
them up with something completely random
every time we call those Fino hotlines
because that's that's what they are yeah
well you know little kitchen Garden here
behind us and it's it's a mess it's not
our focus at all but I still want to be
able to have a BLT in June in July and
be like yes this is the the best time to
have a BLT and if I planted a whole
bunch of Brandywine Tomatoes which are
like my favorite big juicy heirloom
tomatoes and instead I got one that was
kind of like a brandy wine and I got
cherry tomatoes and I got those weird
ones that are meant for so sauce and I
got these other ones you know I'd be
pretty pissed at that Seed Company I'd
be like damn there comes my BLT you know
like yeah
don't mess with my BLT right now but how
dare they throw in a Marzano yeah that's
what it is yeah yeah we love those too
but oh yeah
um we may have to do another little stop
in a minute here but um yeah
why don't I take the show for a walk up
over to show off some of these new
varieties that we're working on people
can get excited about them for next year
and uh you know I'll just do solo
because I don't know if the internet
really is going to reach over there
we're actually getting some new
repeaters and routers so that it should
be good up there that's cool should we
try it then
you know
or do you want to just film and then
send me films
I I definitely can do that I can
definitely film and send you films so
okay I'll keep it to like five minutes
tops and you edit down whatever you want
but Hallie and I'll go walk over and
show
um
you know show what's happening okay
excellent all right I hope you guys
enjoyed the podcast the Cali High
podcast we talked about
the the jelly donuts
it's a new one
these are jelly donuts
for selection right here we've already
selected out quite a few of them
this is our
receiver number one and then
the receiver number twos and then we
have clones
of course would be most of the receivers
and
then orange cream pop was another one
that we mentioned this is a block of the
uh
orange cream pop
in development
and we'll be selecting out of these
we've already pulled some out
moving on to hibiscus there's some
hibiscus here
and what do we have here
through the C4 this is a new thing that
we haven't even
named yet
some humbled headbands
what do we have here
this is uh granny candy another strain
we're working on we might call it
berries and cream we haven't exactly
decided yet
new genetics sort of in trial
good old lemongrass that's one we've had
for a long time
nice and beautiful
and squirt
I'm gonna redo that one this year
time to make some more squirt for the
world
and more orange cream pop lots and lots
of orange cream pop we love that one
it's really good
orange cream pop is one we're really
excited about
all right anyways
um
there's a lot more that I can show you
but
this is the farm here
watering or garlic Plantation over there
our metric Center tool center
it's another Greenhouse
more seedlings coming
nothing more important than labeling
incredibly well when you're a seed
company
and uh
we're doing some projects
looking for the very best strains for
extraction purposes
with a bear
extraction over here so we've got
strands from four or five different
breeders
all just hunting what's the best to uh
to do
um
mostly uh
live resin
washing
some more hibiscus here
hello jellies
we're staggering everything this year so
we don't have just uh
you know
everything coming at once
it's pretty important
staggering it's crucial
all right
thank you guys for coming along with us
today
once again signing out from the
greenhouse up in Humboldt County thanks
for joining us on the Cali High podcast
good job chenzo we love it keep up the
good work man
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
you've been listening to Cali High
episode 66 a garden chat with Nat and
Hallie Pennington
special thanks to Our Guest Nat
Pennington and Holly Pennington of the
Humboldt Seed Company
[Music]
I'm your host shinzonico also known as
Vincent nicoletti
the Humboldt Seed Company can be found
on Instagram at the Humboldt Seed
Company
foreign
https colon backslash backslash Humboldt
Seed Company
High's theme written and recorded by
Vince nicoletti Jordan Webb and the rear
blade
Kelly High podcast and theme are
copywritten
and the kalihai logo is trademarked
featured music for the credits I don't
know what to say by Vince nicoletti
please donate to Cali high at
patreon.com calihila
please like follow And subscribe to Cali
High on YouTube
email us with any questions to
calihighpodcast gmail.com we're on
Instagram at calihila
on all podcast platforms and audio
pretty much
Kelly High's the chinzonico production
stay safe and be blessed
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]