hello October 30th another field notes
this is from our Afghan uh selection uh
this is uh one more variety and this is
called Baja Rock
Baja Rock
and uh what's really interesting about
this particular Afghan is all the other
Afghans we grew were The Squatty really
dense thick uh extremely Indica like
structure but this Barack and we had
another one we already harvested
have more what you could be considered
more of a sativa type bud structure
where they're just a long
thin Spear and then the leaves are also
uh thin instead of the big wide Indica
type leaves so this seems to have more
of a sativa influence uh and then also
what's really unique about these flowers
is they're just very open and Airy and
separated so I don't know if you can
come in on this and where you can see so
it's almost like foxtails of foxtails of
foxtails all on this big giant spear
so and who knows maybe this would be a
good
uh like hash washing
uh uh trait just because it's so open
and all the crystals there would be
super accessible but anyway so this is
just very unique for an Afghan to have
this structure uh the nose is
is nothing
I mean it's pleasant but it's not
mind-blowing and loud or
yeah it just kind of smells clean and
fresh but not super loud but who knows
once it cures out the flavor could be
amazing and the effects could be
absolutely amazing just while it's
growing it's not it's a crazy crazy loud
smelling plant but it is gorgeous and I
think it's about
it's hard to tell when these are red but
uh and I don't see a speck of mold so
yeah looking good just another very
unique cool plant that we'd never know
about unless we tried growing it so here
it is and again thank you to everyone uh
in Afghanistan because these genetics
are incredibly impressive so it's just
an honor to be able to grow these plants
here in Santa Cruz and just so stoked
that there's amazing cannabis breeders
and cultivators all over this planet so
hopefully someday we'll all unite in
some way but right now we connect
through seeds and genetics so anyway
oh it's October 30th if I didn't say
that already anyway Barack