[Music]
hi
future cannabis project i'm a guerrilla
grower from
balkans europe i grow different things
vegetable trees and so on but
this video is about my hidden cannabis
garden
i grew on a nearby hill about
an hour from my home
mostly in native soil
which is a kind of a red clay so
[Music]
the only amendments i use are the
cow manure from the local
from the local cows the water i use is
mostly fabric
water uh a small amount of water is a
rainwater i collect on the hill
i've been growing mostly bag seed
last few years which is a albanian
weed you buy on the streets
this year i'm trying out something
different
but first some videos of my last year
i had three plans two made it
[Music]
do
round about summer solstice is also a
time
when wild fruits start to ripen
like these blueberries
and wild figs which are my favorite
they're abundant on the hill
so it's something to munch on while i
like by
carrying water on my back
last year i harvested the plant around
50 15th of september
maybe a bit early a week
or two because i had a terrible rain
for a few days and heavy winds but
mostly it's in
hot and arid environment till october
that's why i decided this year to try
auto seeds i bought the cheapest
outer seats i can find about 5 euro for
bean so far they're doing great
as i said in native soil and
mostly rain these last days they grew up
very nice
and they're loving the sun which i think
is the
greatest factor in
growing these plants