[Music]
welcome to cali high episode 33
recorded on 420 live from jamaica
with billy mystic wilman
founding member and lead singer of the
mystic revealers
billy is also the proprietor of
jamnesia's surf camp
in bulbay jamaica
where the newest generation of reggae
greats learned to serve
[Music]
let's talk to billy
this is
okay cali high is blessed to be here
with billy mystic wilmett
founder of the mystic revealers
good morning billy how are you
wonderful wonderful glad to be alive and
covey free you know absolutely bro
yes indeed so can you tell us our
audience a little bit about yourself
[Music]
all right well
i'm male 1
[Laughter]
you know i'm i'm about coming on up to
62 years or past 61 on my way to 62 now
mama musician
slash
actor
surfer slash daddy slash grandpa slash
uncle slash
brother slash great grand uncle all kind
of things
but i think probably my biggest
international claim to fame is as one of
the founding members of the group mystic
revealers which
is not by any means a very
well-known reggae group but we are
authentic and
we have um
we are known in the music circle in
jamaica for what we have done we had a
few hits over the years
that um transcended the jamaican
marketplace and
exposed us to marketplace in europe and
and japan and north america south and
central america as well
you know yeah
the group the group um was assigned to a
number of recording labels over the
years
so we've worked with with labels like
local labels like carrion
we've worked with oneness level jimmy
cliff oneness label we've done work
internationally with
with
atlantic records and with mesa with russ
records
uh we've worked we've got a release more
recently through vp records as well
yeah so
musically that's basically a little bit
about me um otherwise i'm the father of
five married to my wife claudette we've
been married
for about
42 years now
you know five kids five grandkids you
know
and the blessings that's quite
so
have you always lived in jamaica
yes all my life i was born here right
here in bulbie i grew up in bulbier
right here you know yeah yeah
um yeah you know when you say
people are following you you seem to be
fairly well connected in the reggae
scene and i was just wondering how come
i never heard of you but i've been
listening to your your tunes lately i've
been really loving them um oh great
thank you before we get into the music a
little more i i just was very fascinated
that you have a um surf school there on
the beach right there
yeah right here right here at johnny's
yeah you know we have a surf we've been
i've been surfing since the 60s you know
yeah so surfing i've been a surfer for
way longer than i even was a musician
you know we didn't get the band together
until about 1978.
all right so we got the band together
you know but
for at least 10 years prior to that i
was surfing here in jamaica so surfing
was a
was a a part of who i was you know the
park growing on the beach here and
there's the sea is rough here in bulbay
most of the time
so we're going to swim and catch the
waves which we didn't know was surfing
at the time because we hadn't been
exposed to surfing you know we didn't
know anything about hawaii and
and california and that sort of thing we
just knew our little local knowledge in
the 60s and we knew if you swam with a
wave and you swam fast enough it would
pick you up and take you along for the
ride
and we got little pieces of wood that we
could hang on to and swim and we used to
call them belly boards lie down on our
belly and come in so we got into surfing
from that time you know yeah so over the
years
um
this on the journey we've been through
my wife has always wanted to have some
kind of
tourism offering you know but she was
more thinking of like a place up in the
mountains a kind of holistic life sort
of thing
um but because we weren't financially
well off enough to
maintain occupy and maintain two
different properties on
opposite end of the island opposite
sides of the island
um we had to narrow down our vision
so the idea during my touring around
when bands started to tour i was exposed
i got a chance to go to california we
were touring the east the west coast of
the united states and
we i've been surfing all my life and by
this time i was like about 30 years old
32 years old with kids and everything
finally getting to go to california
and travel up and down there and saw the
surfing environment saw the surfing vibe
you know i mean you said whoa you know
people up here would really appreciate
what we have in jamaica because in my
mind by that time i had been exposed to
surfing now i had gotten magazines their
uh vhs cassettes of surfing were
available on the market and as a surfer
i'd buy them i take them home to soda
cheese so we kind of saw the waves that
were being pursued internationally and
the quality of the waves but were under
the misconception that this is how the
waves were always in these other places
we didn't realize that wow
the images we are getting from these
world-renowned surf locations where
those images of the best days of the
year we yeah we grew up thinking like it
was like that every single day of the
year in hawaii or california
so when we found out that that's not the
case and it came down to start a reality
we realized we had a really a wonderful
setup in jamaica with like 300 days of
surf a year you know i mean no crows
lots of different spots with high
quality surf
you know i thought and say well you know
maybe if we open a little surf camp
i'm sure we could find enough people to
fill our few little rooms that we could
create on our little space where we
could put some tents and things like
that you know people would come and tie
up a hammock for ten dollars a night and
it would supplement our income you know
so let's go for it and we establish the
surf camp and it grew from just being a
little place of our own
to world-renowned amnesia that people
from all over the world come here for
surfing music
skating
you know and rastafari reasoning you
know
and
how do we get there we you're outside of
kingston you're saying
well we are close to the airport in
kingston when you land at the airport in
kingston at
norman manley international airport in
kingston we're just about 15 minutes
from the airport it's an easy drive out
to the camp we have um
airport shuttle that can meet you and
bring it out to the camp you know yeah
we have a few rooms it's very it it's
very simple you know there's tiny little
rooms with some beds in it a little
cupboard space shared bathroom you know
we offer meals
and you know it's just a feel good like
somewhere to be in jamaica where you're
not at all inclusive yeah you're not in
the tourist trap you're in real jamaica
well i can take downtown to
to the recording studios and if you want
to go to the bob marley museum you can
jump on a local bus and go there like
how normal people do so it's a really
nice immersive um experience so the
germany very cool that's very cool i
you old
hope to get there and i'd love to be
staying there
for come on dog bro
yeah
so you were saying that
we talked yesterday a little bit and you
said that the big waves come during the
uh the winter when or the when the
hurricanes are happening right yes
that's a summer season yeah yeah yeah
from june to the beginning of october i
guess and how gnarly is it
oh it can be super gnarly super super
super duper gnarly i mean life and death
you know your life is on the line when
you're out there in early yeah
waves the size of two to three story
building you know but it's all on
youtube and the internet if you search
for if you just do a google search for
surfing in jamaica you'll find us
because we're like
the main place so you can't miss us and
there's lots of videos and
photos and stuff up there you can see
what it's like you know people don't
believe i was just the other day there's
uh some famous surfing guys called the
godowska's brothers from california from
encinitas
you know and
they they
they were they came down here and were
surfing with us and the last hurricane
season we sent back some video for them
and they were telling us man this looks
like sunset beach hawaii you know it's
exactly like sunset beach so
yeah we took it from them that that's a
good comparison
that's cool bro
i can't wait to check it out someday
so
um what instruments do you play mystic
um i don't like to claim to be a
instrumentalist but i
i am
i'm a mainly a singer songwriter
and i use a guitar
to do my songwriting
so i'm not a guitar virtuoso by any
means
i do play with the band and most of the
time when you're recording the rhythm
guitar is usually me sometimes i'll add
a few little phrases here and there
um i do play bass you know this is
probably my favorite instrument even
though i'm not the bass player
um
i would say it was my favorite thing and
i've you know i do a lot of percussion
work
as well yeah you know i like the
percussion on your music yeah but i
would not i would never knowing
the musicians that i do
in the reggae industry and their caliber
of talent yes i would never be so
forward as to present myself as a
musician i much rather say i'm a singer
songwriter
well that's cool
so
uh
who are your musical influences
i noticed you have quite a like a range
of of
types of
songs very cool yes yes
mystic revealers we were
one of the reasons why
many people didn't know about us
is because
we're very difficult to put into a box
you know
we're not you can't just say we're roots
or we're dance hall or we're
dub or we're you know
we are musicians you know
i'm a songwriter who
writes
emotionally in terms of how do i feel in
the moment just you know growing up in
jamaica you're exp you're exposed to
international music you know when i grew
up there was just two radio stations it
was rjr and jbc and it was
am frequency very poor quality sound and
that sort of thing you know
so you all the only thing that was
played on jamaica radio was recordings
that were
the best quality possible so most of the
music you heard on the radios in jamaica
was hit parade music from not america or
britain you know and not enough and some
productions because there was one or two
major recording studios back in the 60s
that who had the capacity to produce
music at the level that when the record
was produced you could actually put it
on a turntable and play it on an am
frequency and send it out there and you
could actually hear what was going on a
lot of early jamaican music was
um the iconic music was recorded in in
very low quality recording studios you
know two track and four track and eight
track and a lot of that music was was
not able to be presented on the radio
yeah in those days they would call that
music dancehall music it wasn't a genre
it just meant that music that was not
really fit for airplay and not fit for
airplay because of lyrics or
content but just due to quality
so those music now would be played on
sound systems in the dancehall because
that's dancehall the sound system is uh
is the signal path for a sound system is
way different than a radio station the
radio station just takes the signal from
the needle puts it through an amplifier
and send it out in a mono signal out
over the airwaves
with a tone you can either tone it high
or low or in the middle
the early recording the early um sound
systems had a crossover system
where they took that
the signal from the needle on the
turntable
and they put it
into a
four band
splitter that would
select the frequency you could say okay
we select the bottom end all those
frequencies
right send them to nothing to our
equalizer you know
it's like you could set
the parameters
of the audio signal so you had they
would set it up so you had base
coming out of this
thing it would go to an amplifier of its
own and be connected to the base beams
then they would have low mid frequency
coming out of
out of another
thing it would go to amplification
equalization and go to the low mid
speaker cabinet then you have the high
mid that will go same procedure so it
was a four band
wow it had four bands of separation so
when the record was being played
you had more audio control in the sound
system than you did on radio radio
basically just had to be good on the
record
if it wasn't it wouldn't sound good
right the sound systems they could put
this record on that was made in some
chinese studio and if the low mids
needed boosting they could lose it if
the bottom head needed boosts you know
the high ends behind me the vocals was a
bit low they could turn up the high mids
and not affect the bottom end responses
you know so with that four-band
crossover that they implemented
it allowed the music to be played and
heard on a much higher quality than it
could possibly be heard
on the radio and this is living in
bulbasa
where i grew up now we're just it's a
sound system place we have liquid copper
island in the sun around me theater
paradise scope a lot of these places
back in the day where the sound system
would come to play that room we would
come up from country
and
a lot of the top sound system like in
the 70s socialist roots and and stir gav
and all of them type of sound system
always used to play in the area yeah
yeah so in those early times i was
exposed to this type of music
that was on the radio
because the quality and not meant to be
coming from abroad and i would be
hearing all of the local stuff that was
being played by the sound system that
you would not hear
under it
so i had a very wide listening scope
that affected me
so if i was going to narrow down now and
say who were some of the people whose
music affected me
yeah well i used to love listening to
music
i used to love listening to
freddie mcgregor
dennis brown
alton ellis
gregory isaacs
you mondell some of the younger ones are
in that time also you know i mean yeah
buddha is kinda
israel vibration
you know well
these are the groups that i would listen
to and love you know a lot of the music
that was being played by jollof music
you know a lot of the 12 tribes of
israel artists you know on orthodox
labor
it's funny you would say that because
yesterday somebody was telling me
about uh israel vibration
yes israel vibration and a lot of other
acts that came out through not that
musical outlet which is the twelve
tribes of israel and the music body of
the twelfth tribe of israel you know a
lot of those acts then is brown freddie
mcgregor god these artists come out
through here you know yeah
tribe of israel you know so yeah all of
these artists were
musicians and artists that we were
exposed and familiar with
in terms of international of course it
was all the rmb artists
you know influenced us you know
all of those rmb groups you know yeah
well i certainly saw in terms of reggae
we used to love we love when steel pulse
came on the scene
you know and as well that was very
interesting for me
because
steel pulse didn't sound like a man who
was trying to sound authentically
jamaican you know
as what was a ban that was in england
but was probably the most authentic
jamaican sound band at that time
yeah we admired steel pulse because
that thing was different and it did have
an international flavor to it that made
it different
absolutely yeah my granddaughter can we
say me say hi
she's beautiful yes so you know um as
what i'm still cultural to other
international groups of course africans
like lucky dude as well you know fella
foote you know we had a sophisticated
listening ear yeah so um and i of course
have only vote um third world or one
third world you know and of course bob
marley and wheeler so
i had a lot of influences musically and
when you listen to our catalog you will
see that all music does cover a wide
range of genre feel you know yes
that's why i asked that question you
know i saw i saw some motown influence
in there i saw some roots reggae i saw
you know various but eclectic mixes of
yeah
you know
um let me ask you who are the members of
the mystic revealers beside yourself
well right now the the
remaining members of the office myself
um
lira edwards are lying on base and
nikki nicholas henry are nikki symbol
and drums
remaining
foundation members of the group you know
well that's cool
but but when we were recording this our
latest album i did go out and try to get
some of the other musicians who had
played with the group over the years
because you know
since about 198
or so
the three of us have been
members of the group you know the group
i just said suddenly
in the late uh 70s
so it was like
we had been through a few drummers
previously and a number of different
keyboards and so on but by 88
um
it was myself and lion
who had founded the group in the 70s and
then
johnny came on board about 88 so 87 he
came on and since then it's been the
three of us and there's been a large
number of
people who have come out on board and
changed you know different lead
guitarists come on different harmonious
singers you know yeah well the players
seem to be really great um
last year you released ja ja people was
that your first album in like 23 years i
know you did some singles in between
yes we did a number of singles and i
think vp had put out a
compilation of
hits from our catalog also oh yeah i saw
that
right yeah yeah this is the first album
in about 23
yeah
24 years probably well it's a great
album and i recommend it to my listeners
wholeheartedly
um
so
who is singing you know i
i i know you uh and that you have um
herb must legalize now was released in
yes and you got chronics and you have
cabaca pyramid on there
it's it seems like a big party at that
recording
yeah
yeah well you know gymnasia is
is is a
a seed bed for
uh young talent you know yeah so that's
really why all those artists are a part
of it most of those artists are artists
that have some historical connection
with japanese you know all of this new
uh
reggae revival movement
sprung out of the germany's
reality at the gymnasia experience you
know yeah
so it was easy getting all those guys on
board you know all personal friends
everybody was under our personal friends
of ours yeah well that's a great out a
great tune by the way
so i have one little question
yo yo
uh on your
1997 song warning
yes who's the girl singing
chachi
yeah
she's a ethiopian girl
who was
in the island at that time
and we were at carrion records um
here in the studio and we were all
hanging out here and we got together and
do that you know
it was wonderful experience yeah
beautiful voice great tune
so where did you record jaja people
well jaja people i started you know um
we hadn't done anything for so long and
i've still been writing songs and at
this shoot i have this huge backup of
songs even now i have at least another
album two words of songs that have been
written
so i wanted to put something out so i
you know i decided
i'd been so long the ban had been active
you know we were doing a few little
shows here and there and rehearsing just
to keep
keep our fingers up to speed you know
so
i said you know we want to put out our
album i want to put an album i want to
do one thing more you know yeah yeah so
i start without returning
so it started because i know a lot of
people in the industry and over the
years we've gained a certain amount of
respect in the industry i was in a
position where i could basically call
our members of the jamaican music
fraternity
yes sir
to come and uh and be a part of what i
was doing you know yeah so that's how i
started doing it and i started recording
i recorded about four songs and had a
lot of other work
um
a lot of other preparatory work and demo
work being done yeah but um
about two years ago we had a fire
my house burned to the ground and we
lost everything i lost a lot of a lot of
mystic revealers memorabilia all our
photos i had like our very first test
press of our very first release you know
i'm sorry to hear that
yemen
all my posters from the tours and
international tours over the years
everything i had collected around the
group all the cassettes all the cds all
the dvds all the live video i was
performing internationally everything
was in storage
at the house and it all went up in smoke
you know and a lot of the stuff that i
had been working and at the time also
yeah we lost it so
i've ended up saying you know what
i'm going to just go for it i look up
and say how can i i said you don't know
what is
people making music
stuff fun and fun you know i must be
able to just make some music here i'm
tired of this yeah you know
so
i had garage band on a tablet and i made
a few trucks i put a few trucks on the
garage band and say
you know i think i i don't care even if
it's on garage band i'll put it out you
know i'm gonna do it so i just want to
get this music out here
so i made a few demos on garageband and
i was listening to it i say
you know if this technology is available
on this tablet i'm sure there must be
some
available technology that's
maybe on a production level you know yep
so i did some research and i found out
that yeah you can do stuff and i can and
i got access to
a
program somebody suggested a program to
me a music song editing program
i downloaded it to my laptop
i went out and i interested about a
bearing job 18 xr 18 which i said which
i would recommend to anybody interested
in recording
give me a 18 input
uh ability so i could actually record we
could set up the whole band and record
live it had enough input into the thing
as usb connection to the
laptop so that basically gave me a
studio right on my veranda
and most of the tracks i think about of
the 12 tracks i think probably about
eight or nine of them were recorded on
my veranda here in boulder you know
really so yeah and voice right there i
mean if you had access to the original
tracks i could
solo vocal tracks and you could hear my
grandkids running around in the
background you know so it's a
it's a very natural
song we use but i mean everybody who
asked me where did you record this and
nobody believed that it was on the
veranda because the audio quality
still tends to make you think it was
recorded inside a countrywide studio
yeah i i thought it was in one of the
studios in jamaica and you have horns on
there that sound amazing yes i use a lot
of hands i use
i'm for life horns yeah and i've always
been friends right one second
i used to be very upset we got a record
company
um it would mean three more tickets and
we were already a huge aggregation on
stage like he had nine people on stage
plus school yeah when we went on tour it
was a big undertaking so
heinz
as well from the record company was like
hey and we need a bus that sleeps 16
people as well and you know it was so i
ended up touring a lot without hans but
i always loved arn's you know so now
when i was at this situation here we are
in coving we are all locked down
i'm recording i can call deal if moa d
in computer and for me
we know a lot of people in the industry
exactly and they have nothing to do
everybody's stuck here and nobody's on
tour anything so i just access a lot of
the people who
um
i've worked with in the past you know
got keyboardies but we coming only
keyboards for me you know
i'm bridging ice socks put on hands for
me and stingray them put on hands for me
you know yeah well they sound great you
must meet us meet them help me out so
you know china
do some production with me on one of the
songs as well sitting on the beach
we did that at china's place that was
one of the songs that wasn't done on my
veranda but was done on his veranda you
know
so you know it was a very
very it was a very entertaining
experience for me you know to make this
album and it's the first album i've had
so much say over the finished product
you know
before we are some young group and
you're assigned to atlantic records and
they will just say hey why don't you
work with mike he's a great producer he
worked with so and so and so and so and
so yeah yeah you could have him on the
album and he comes in and you give him a
song and he says why don't you put a
bridge here a bridge would really be
nice here listen you could go to from
that you could go to a d minor there and
then
next thing you know
writing on your on your album and the
song don't sound like what it sounded to
you but
because
this record company is spending 50 or 60
000 on your production you can't just
say [__] you because you don't have a
you don't have a million selling record
you know under your belt where you can
dictate to them yeah they're promising
to make a star out of you you know so
you so this new album i didn't have to
deal with any of that i couldn't i
didn't have recording studio class i
didn't have to book studio time ahead
and be out of there because there's the
next group is outside waiting and we're
already one hour past our checkout time
and they want to come in and record you
know you could just wake up at three in
the morning and go out on the veranda
and say i'm gonna try those harmonies
again tonight you know what i mean and
that gave me such amount of control and
because
i was the main mixing engineer as well
you know along with me and my son and
elect you know we did most of the
production work so it was really
you know relaxing and very low stress
environment to create the music so well
it has a really great vibe very
very happy eyes with the finished
product you know yeah it's got a great
vibe and i i really like blue nile i
like a lot of the songs but i mean blue
nile somehow just hit me
yeah that that that was recorded at
draft and that was one of this song that
was recorded that drafter mikey bennett
studio great friend of mine collaborated
over the years he's worked on a number
of my recordings over the years you know
yeah we worked on that one to get a
draft on studio and that was yeah that
was exciting hans weren't done there i
did hands elsewhere you know some of the
things that recorded one place mixed at
a place and
finalize at on my veranda you know some
of the times that
ended up getting mixed on the veranda
that were recorded in some of the other
studios you know are you getting airplay
um we get an airplane on surprise we'll
never get getting airplay but jamaica is
so technically
up to date now you know i mean everybody
has
a program that you can buy
you know yeah they have some sort of
service you know they have a promotional
thing and it includes x amount of
players per week and yeah yeah x amount
of radio stations and it costs 2 000 u.s
dollars for the first month and then
whatever whatever and you know and when
you pay them then all of a sudden your
your music starts playing mysteriously
on a lot of radio stations you know yeah
so
we haven't we don't have that kind of
budget behind us so as i say i made this
music
for a special people who would go out
and discover it and have it like a like
a very precious thing that's not readily
available something you've never heard
about and wonder why you know this is
this is the avenue we're going down with
our thing so we're hoping that maybe
because we don't have that type of
support in terms of promotional support
around it we're more going for maybe a
long-term gradual snowball effect
because the songs being the fact that
they are not
tied to any
production sound traditional sound like
it's not chokmak or it's it you know
it's not
a producer song yeah yeah it's our song
which is unique so whenever if you hear
it this year or next year or the year
after it's not going to be so easy for
you to time stamp it because it's on
some rhythms that were produced in
2018. so now yes time stamp with 2.98
it sounds like it would be a great uh
big hit in hawaii i mean i took a trip
to hawaii and you know turned on the
radio stations and they're all freaking
playing reggae
you know
and i have a friend over there really
judah really judah i think he's
c kcr c or something like that radio you
know kawaii
yeah even though song players doing
yeah yeah big up to really judah but
then support you know that's cool
um
so you know some of the rhythm sections
almost sound like like they were
recorded together live were they or they
just are live it's our live recording no
we don't really use any loops the only
song that was used with a drum machine
and looping was kiss for me which we did
with
with natural light
yeah they
i wanted something on the album young
and feeling like what was going on
locally at the time we did the album so
that that would be able to timestamp the
album for me
you know that collaboration with what
the youngsters who were on the cutting
edge of producing this kind of trap type
song thing you know yeah yeah the
traffic i just gave them that and they
they did that so apart from that
everything else is live
it's live recording live drama beasts
drama country off our rollout and we lit
the reading man if it's not steady we
because we're not under student time
pressure we were able to say all right i
don't like that take let's go again
let's go again yeah maybe not today
let's try it again tomorrow all right we
can we try it on the weekend you know so
we are time to to do that sort of stuff
so the album is a lot of a lot of one
take yeah you know but the vocals are
one tape vocals
most of the vocals were the guide voice
that was laid at the time when we were
laying the rhythm yeah um
a couple places maybe we would have to
punch in a few little fat spots but we
tried not to
interfere with the production very much
you know i mean i mean a lot of spots my
son was concerned about my voice going
flat at certain points and i told him no
i want to keep that i want it real i
don't yeah i don't want some some
something that we'll go back and punch
that in and punch me in there and punch
me in there and punch me yeah yeah yeah
yeah that's slightly flat this is a
little bit late going into this life now
let's do it it's a real thing it's like
a live show i wanted to feel real live
you know so yeah almo it was as a result
of that
that concern why the album has this feel
that it does you know yeah it has a
great irie vibe
if i understand ivory
so
do you play
uh reggae festivals or are you planning
to after things open up after this
pushing a q-tip one foot up my nostril i
just can't
manage the the covey test where they
push that thing way up
like it's a brain test they want to see
do you have any brain up there
all the way okay yes you have some brain
when you impact on your your brain are
at the top of your skull i can't handle
that bro
i cannot unleash
i mean they try to put something up my
nose and i eat my drug i just grab it
out i know it's a natural reaction i
have it it's not if it's not like a a
swab in the mouth or something like that
i don't think i'm going to be traveling
any time soon
how are the vaccine distributions in
jamaica yeah man
what's in people out here yeah yeah
people lining up for it but not me
yeah
okay
i mean i'm too old now i've lived so
long that i you know i don't want to
take up too much space for too long on
the planet they're talking about the
place being overpopulated i don't want
to live to be too old and become a
problem
so
i hope that y'all will protect me and i
know that none of us were born into this
world to live forever and we all got to
come somehow and go
somehow
so i want to be
as happy about my time here as possible
and enjoy it as much as i can you know
so yeah so i kind of staying away from
the covi thing
yeah and the vaccines and all that
because
i don't see it around me you know maybe
if it gets a lot more serious and people
actually are dying that i know
and i see sick people around me and
every day i hear about somebody else
from my community who has gone to the
hospital and may not return but i don't
have any proof of any of that from where
i am i hear it on the radio oh there's
all these people but
you know i don't i'm not experiencing in
my my community of bulby i don't see it
and funnily enough bulbay was ground
zero the first
the first case that was identified in
jamaica was identified just about a mile
down the road from me and
so far i i
i don't really know anybody who has died
or anything i know some people who have
had it
you know who have been tested positive
and were isolated and when i spoke to
them they said well if nobody had told
them it was kovi they would have just
thought it was just an ordinary flu
because one of their symptoms were any
different than a normal flu closer yeah
well not stable
and it's not dangerous you know i'm not
saying it's not dangerous and people
shouldn't be
be concerned you know i'm just saying
that me personally
i i put my my faith in the most high you
know and if yeah
was lined up to take me out i don't
think a vaccine is going to be able to
stop it from getting me you know well i
think if you're out there surfing your
your uh endorphins are going to keep you
immune probably
maybe
you know so let's talk herb for a minute
since it is 4 20.
yeah blessed 4 20. yeah bless up
um
how long have you been partaking of the
sacred herb
um you know the first
i mean of course as little tiny kids we
would find jamaica is everybody smoke
weed so yeah yeah when there are little
kids
i figured that maybe in north america
the equivalent would be a bit of finding
somebody's cigarette butt and lighting
it up and taking a pull on it
so
that is basically all we really started
as kids you know yeah yeah so much weed
being smoked all over the place
sometimes you're lucky enough to find
like a joint that somebody lit and it
went out and it fell our last and you
end up finding it so from we were very
young we got into that type of thing i
would say before i was
10 or 11 years old we had already
lit up and pulled something and cast and
that's other thing but in terms of
actually getting access to weed for
myself and and
partaking and
saying that i smoke weed and being able
to declare that i was
probably about 14
years old 15 years old
yeah i think i've been smoking since i
was 12.
yeah
so
um how what has the herb in jamaica
changed over the years
over the years well in the beginning you
used to smoke a lot of seedy bush you
know yeah yeah
yeah
yeah i didn't even know how to
make a joint you know when i was smoking
yeah yeah it wasn't one you found we
were smoking a chalice you know yeah
yeah
so it was not very high quality weed you
know it wasn't a connoisseur thing
you know it was
uh much more like smoking a cigarette as
opposed to doing jobs
yeah yeah so the whole the whole
experience of marijuana in jamaica was
a much more casual leisurely
undertaking as opposed to like let's go
down in the basement and get high you
know it was yeah yeah yeah it wasn't
that kind of energy so in jamaica when
you said drug
nobody thought marijuana yeah they
thought lsd
you know cocaine
you know pcp something you know some
kind of manufactured thing was what yeah
so marijuana wasn't even included as a
drug in our mindset because
grandpa small grandma small uncle jerry
small my
father
everybody exposed to it and
it wasn't like people were having to
hide as i say in the basement to go get
a toe you know people would smoke
mr brown was a policeman live across the
road and him smoke too
no smoking uniform you know but when him
at home his son smokes and he doesn't
lock up his son you know what i mean so
it was a much more socially acceptable
uh pursuit
in jamaica so we never really had that
kind of
connoisseur type thing like wow this we
got to go hide and get high as quickly
as we can and then get out of there
before the cops find us you know yeah
yeah it wasn't that type of environment
yeah so nowadays with with the new herb
thing and high times magazine and all of
this we've seen a lot more of those
designer
marijuana know what it is you know and a
lot more people
are smoking marijuana nowadays and used
to so you find out that most of the new
users of marijuana are very much into
the quality
and high-grade type of thing right and
elders obviously love good marijuana
absolutely i'm not out there to get this
thing that you take one pull and you
gotta go to sleep you know yeah
so let me ask um
two things i have a question about one
do you know about the lamb's bread
technique
i wasn't really a herb plantain but i
know that lamb's bread in those days it
was it was like you know when you see it
we we'd have a lot of crystals on it
in those days
when i was back talking about the late
60s early 70s when people tell you about
lamb's bread
you said lamb's bread
but really what it was coming from was
lamb's breath
really the breath of the lamb yeah yeah
yeah
like when you
put your mouth over the under on on a
glass and you see the breath show
those crystals you know yeah on the herb
on the hair of the herb and you see
those crystals it was like condensation
of the lamb's breath you know
so that was one of the i said some
people call it lamb's bread
yeah you know yeah there was a lot of
things but lamb's bread was for us was
just it just meant very high quality
weed to most of the lay people you know
it was right and as i said i wasn't a
herb farmer
yeah so i wouldn't know what were the
procedures that would categorize one
weed as lamb's bread and the other one
as whatever you know
you know we know that centimeters no
seed you know yeah in 1975 i came to
jamaica
and i went to negril and i met a
rastafarian named referred ward
and
he took me up to his grow and he told me
that lamb's bread or breath was
when you would cut the top just after it
started butting you tuck cut the top
eight inches off put it back in the
ground
and it re-roots like a clone anyway
yeah it's possible it's possible and i
would not tell you that you're wrong you
know you can't educate me as much too
because you know if i was
right now i just let us go get we don't
smoke weed i'm a bread drink bring our
burger weed and we'll we'll sew it up
and we'll smoke it at the chalice i
would give thanks and if there's a
tremendous amount of seeds we would cut
up the weed and put it on the board and
set it at an angle
oh i had seeds too bro
every bud had seeds when i was a kid
yeah
we had mexican we had colombian we
didn't get jamaican on the west coast
but uh
yeah yeah yeah they had it on the east
coast i believe
so
um
i've heard about a legendary strain
called the cotton do you know anything
about that
no you know
you know what happened to me you know
when i stopped
getting
really into
all the different varieties and yeah
um about 10 or 15 years ago
i was exposed to a tremendous amount of
insecticide inhaled a lot of insecticide
in a room
oh yeah and almost died from insecticide
twice since that time i can't smell or
taste anything
so when they
when they bring the weed to me and say
how does this smell i can't smell it you
know oh i'm sorry to hear that
yes so
you know right now with the smoke we
like cigarettes yeah always the best
i always overload the child son
you know so it's more like a habit to me
no you know i'm constantly
on a certain
level mentally
i just stayed here you know yeah
well i don't have to go and pursue to
get high you know i guess i'm
high 99 at the time
[Laughter]
i hear you bro well listen i want to
thank you for this interview and it's
been really nice talking to you and i
hope to get to your
amnesia surf
camp there bro come on yeah and if you
check out japanese surf ig every sunday
we have a live stream i represent
various artists who more than likely
you've never heard of as well you know
but like as i say although the japanese
experience
came out is that if you're a regular
aficionado you will know because
chronics is a product of
james
protege
i love those guys
kabaka pyramid yeah
i mean all of these
iconic artists right now if you do get
the opportunity to interview them ask
them about their japanese experience and
if they have one you know i will i've
been trying to get to interview chronics
and protege
and uh
you know um i was hoping that uh
oh protege's mom might help out on that
end but um
lorna bennett
yeah mine all
went on a stage in his life it was right
here at my place his mother was sitting
right there and everybody said go go on
the stage go and he was really shy he
didn't want to go off
so the first time he went on the stage
in his life was that japanese
well this last out last year of covid
lockdown i have derived
countless hours of pleasure listening to
both those guys you know yeah
and everybody else too you know
really like the new third world album
and now i've got
your album the new album
so i'm stoked over here in cali so maybe
um we'll do something in in the future
and uh check back in with you
yeah man of course
and
any time it was great
can i call you on can we do a live ig
later maybe
yeah no problem link me up i see you
know
how late do you stay up out there
um
usually i
go to bed around 1 30 two in the morning
oh wow okay so i'll call you bro
all right
did you learn how to roll a reefer or
sleeve
yeah yeah i had to learn i had to learn
when i
when i went to college i had to learn
okay
charlie's was too much when i went i
went to the jamaica school of
agriculture here in jamaica so oh wow
you know yeah yeah for a long time i
never needed to roll a spliff it was
just because i was studying at night
and it was too much work to set up the
while stopping so okay i'm not having to
roll this week
i'll give you some special tips when i
meet you
all right i'm pretty good now though you
know i've had a few years since then you
know since college years yeah a lot
about you know 20 or 30 years of
practice role in this speech yeah my
brother taught me when i was like 12 and
he was the best roller i ever saw and
then
my son i i i'll put you up against my
son because right now my son
they look they look like they came out
of some machine or something yeah okay
challenge accepted i can't wait to get
to gymnasium
hey i have a question can you fly into
jamaica with some herb
um people have you know yeah because i
don't think the in
immigration and customs here are
expecting that at all yeah yeah
yeah interest
okay well billy
mystic
thank you very much
and uh
this is cali high out and i'll talk to
you later
okay
ciao bro
much love
blessings
let me turn this thing
[Music]
well every man has a need for a place to
call home a place of his own where
there's a crown and a throne
where he can praise his god and he can
serve his king and he can chant can give
his arms and not fear a thing where
people can live and make their dreams
real everywhere you go there is a love
that you can feel and the ground beneath
his feet holds his forefather's bone and
his history goes back for centuries
untold bloon
[Music]
by the banks of that river
to be
[Music]
[Applause]
you