all right well welcome back once again
to royal ground radio again live from
mjbizcon 2021 podcast row i'm michael
beck i'm rick elliott and we are joined
by some long time friends and
collaborators in the industry
brian and jeremy from bosque genetics
thanks guys thank you guys thank you
appreciate it yup glad to be here yeah
man long time ago abuser man since uh
day one you know so yes exactly yeah i
remember though yeah well the first time
i think it was uh you called into the
office and we and we spoke for a while
and i was just planning a trip down to
the vicinity area yeah so it worked out
perfect we met up been friends ever
since oh yeah we winded up actually
finding out and realizing that we had
mutual friends yep dragon with matches
that we talk about the industry you know
the big web man it is it is i know i
love i'd love to get up and see him
again man it's been a while see him all
the time and he's still the same tell
him i said what's up
best friends with a cartoon character
he even comes with a cardboard cutout
man
i've woken up in that spare bedroom
before with that cardboard life size i
would say cardboard cutout of holy and
it's interesting when you wake up a
little shaky you don't know exactly
where you are where you went to sleep
and you wake up with that thing next to
you yeah yeah
that's awesome man that's awesome yeah
man
ganja claws yeah yes so yeah and then
now you're in with the grow-off
competition which is pretty amazing man
i'm definitely uh i've been seeing all
your instagram posts over the years
you're definitely getting better and
better every single year the [ __ ] you
guys are producing just straight fire
obviously you've got jars in front of
you here's already dipping in and the
entry right here man so we're excited
you know we uh take our samples next
week to find out what you know what it
comes in at and uh we're excited to find
out what the strain is i remember going
and visiting you last year's competition
right yeah and you guys were ahead of
the game you had already harvested
smart even
with that one man we uh we jumped the
gun you know on getting it out there
before the competition was over and
there was you know
but it was fun we made a little uh you
know jar that had let our
customers you know chime in and guess
what the stream was too so yeah but he
was stoked to uh participate so one of
the coolest things about the grow-off is
this mystery genetics and getting a
genetic that's kind of new to market
that hasn't really blown up yet you know
getting access to that cut
i just love
a lot about the grow-off competition the
data analytics the kind of
actual scientific data but really for me
the coolest thing is like what stream is
this yeah i don't know i'm curious this
is the first that i've actually seen
finished flower we were talking trees
farms and seeing the plants live on the
vine
and the smell yeah was like
sweet papaya punchy
yeah but it had a little bit of like
dirty acrid putri
but it's crazy to see all the different
growers you know too i mean both indoor
outdoor you know the techniques the
nutrients that everybody use you know
lighting i mean everything affects the
way that this flower turns out you know
so it's
it's neat man i will say as as you know
a company that we sponsor him every year
what are we on four or five years now
yeah at least and for many of those
years i've had the the honor and
privilege to go to a ton of these
contestants farms and facilities and see
them yeah and it is really fascinating
to see the differences on how they're
being cultivated
you know sometimes really different
sometimes you get there and i'm like wow
this looks like a completely different
strain in some ways i agree i agree
everybody has their own method this
tweet everybody has their own way it's
you know it's your way is the best i
mean there's a lot of input from the
industry and a lot of nutrients that we
can use and a lot of lighting we can use
but what ultimately it comes down to is
being comfortable with what you're doing
and loving what you're doing and being
happy when you're done you know that's a
true success you know
definitely people in it for the business
and for the financials of it and the
game that they believe is there but you
know people that are true to that i
think are going to be more successful
because this makes me feel like i'm a
kid again man like the excitement is
like opening up presents on christmas
you know so it's that's
that's the joy for me i like i like
growing cannabis you know so every
strain is is
important you know
so what sort of strains are you working
on you guys are obviously breeding doing
all sorts of genetic experimentation
like what is it that's popping out to
you right now what's the avenue that you
want to see genetics steer towards i
love gas i love ogs i mean that's i love
that dominant you know force in the in
the strain you know so for me i mean
most of the stuff that i've i've played
with in the past is all og dominant you
know
um our cookie land that's it's got uh
the uh
the forum cookies uh candy land and
ocido and that there's heavy og
influence on that too so uh the phenos
we're finding i mean i'm finding a lot
of gas a lot of uh you know cookie
structure i mean but uh
i like it all man i'm i'm a seed order a
little bit you know
yeah it's amazing and like we were kind
of going through a few of these phenoms
earlier at the booth you were showing us
some of this amazing flower and
i just love getting into that like fino
hunt type of mindset and you're like oh
i really i can taste the candy land here
yeah it's forward i can smell it more
this one's you know this is og boss like
og cut through it's winning the battle
here and then you had what was it the
five i think you said yeah the number
five is my favorite that's that to me is
the powerhouse it it'll stop you
mid-joint you know and make you think
about it
like when we were smelling it on the
floor i'm like i can't pinpoint it like
this emoji
no yes and there's some sweeter notes
but it's really unique
i love it man i mean i i still have
crosses with the old train wreck you
know i got train wreck for brian you
know yeah matches so that that got
incorporated into some of the the lines
and and so i mean we found some crazy uh
phoenix
is a staple of my youth in cannabis one
of my my long time i've held that strain
longer than any strain i've had
throughout the years i mean i held it
for over 15 years i think you know i see
it occasionally in outdoor farms up in
humboldt you know i think last year i
went to two different farms up in alder
point yeah and they were running some
train wreck and it is something that
happens when you're about 25 feet away
from that road that you're like oh damn
i just got like the whole deja vu
man it's it's still one of the all-time
favorites i agree
yeah it's one of my favorite profiles
also one of my favorite smokers yeah i
like the way it is exactly
the feel
it's clear i love the train ride yeah we
think you see it brought back into a lot
of breeding programs in the near future
there's already some companies that are
using it and working with it because it
has a lot of traits that benefit you
know different kinds of strains you can
mix with this so you we think you'll see
in the future train wrecks like to come
into breeding programs and start coming
back around
it is pure you know it doesn't have a
lot of influence from the the newer
genetics so it's nice to mix the old the
new and you know have that ability to do
that man i love that you mentioned that
new school genetics i talked with my my
old man about this and yeah he's back in
michigan does this little tiny medical
thing and you know got old school
strands and i'm like
check out the new school genetics
there's a difference here it's not just
like a new strain yeah it's a new type
of genetic profile we weren't seeing
these cookies gelato type
nuggets the bud structure the way that
they grow i mean it's yeah everything
out there that i'm seeing i mean hats
off to all the breeders that are doing
it you know i mean it's a lot of work
you know the guys that are really like
like humble seed company for instance
those guys put a lot of love into this
plant you know and and the amount of
seeds that they're planting and the
farms that they're working with and and
you know building in that network you
know is amazing we had the monroe grown
radio uh the beginning of season two i
believe yeah yeah and we were talking
about some of those female hunts ten
twenty thousand plant you know hunts um
you know nat obviously he's been in the
game and doing this for a while super
passionate and then his daughter ali is
just you know she's amazing amazing just
super brilliant yeah and uh and just
right there in her dad's daddy's doing
god's work man i mean
it's amazing to see it well that's one
similarity i see is the passion like
that's what really spoke to me about
what nat and hallie do is that they mean
it with every fiber of their being and
that's one thing i've seen from you guys
from the get-go too is like
you want to blow people's minds and you
want to make yourselves proud of what
you do and that's what separates any
truly successful business
or process
yeah we put the plant first i mean
that's that's the
that's what's carried us through the
last you know 20 plus years of our life
you know so i mean that if we take the
focus away from that then nothing
nothing works out you know if you're
looking at the other side of it the
money and and all of that you know
that's that's the wrong thing to look at
you know something that we talk about
quite a bit on this on this program is
that uh you know the hustle with
integrity yeah you know coined by fat
bold clothing you know good big shout
out to brian swizzler for that one man
but we can't stop saying that and
bringing that back up in the
conversations because
that is something that attracts all of
us man that hustle with integrity you
keep keeping your good intentions
you know when we're driving the
direction of this plan you know going
forward and being able to dodge the uh
the ill intentions you know because
there's a lot of them always is going to
yeah no doubt i think you focus on
trying to be great at your craft no
matter what your craft is whether it's
cannabis painting
your you know music or whatever it is if
you're trying to truly be great at your
craft that attracts people which which
in turn will attract the financial that
people are looking for that comes with
that but you should focus focus on
that's what you're trying to do and
accomplish and be better at it and make
that better and truly enjoy what you're
doing you know and all that will come
later you know a lot of people are
successful you know chasing the dollar
in a sense you know what i mean they
figure out their path or their brand or
whatever they do that makes them
successful makes them money and that's
their place that's okay you know but
just for us we just try to focus on on
you know perfecting our craft and
staying genuine as cultivators and
trying to really you know dial in
staying true to a legacy grower but
bringing science into it and being able
to bridge the gap between both and be
able to communicate in both worlds you
know and and be successful with that
we're not trying to do a large grow
we're trying to blow things up you know
we're trying to be a small you know
boutique things it's amazing to have the
access that we have now to technology
and what we can actually bring into the
equation you know to uh assist with the
growth you know whereas yeah it's got a
lot more data today you know it was it
was difficult to do that so the other
day that was great data driven was
hanging out at the local hydro store and
yeah and the owners bring it for an hour
when there was no searching
comparing forums you know like that
stories from family members or
especially multiple generation growers
that you know uncles are our parents
that have grown in their life and passed
on stories that we've sat around as kids
listening to you know as they smoked or
you know told us about the plan or
different methods that i still believe
in as in like the old
hippie style method compared to a
scientific method because i think you
got to stay genuine to the passion and
the love to really understand you know
where this originated at and started and
got to this point you know what i mean
so yeah a lot of old stories from family
members and you know they could use
to be able to put a number to you know
what we've seen for all these years you
know and that's that's really the
awesome part of it is correlate the
numbers with you know the results well
that passion fuels the request for data
so you like you're like this is better
yes what did we do differently exactly
let's get a soil sample let's send it to
the lab let's check tissue samples every
week you know it's tissues every week
we'd send nutrient samples every week i
mean wow that was kind of our routine we
ran well water with the last grow we
were at so we had a moving target we
were always chasing you know what was
going on with the the chemistry in the
ground you know so it was uh it was fun
it was a major learning experience you
know it definitely uh
brought out the best in us
yeah yeah you know it makes you better
and if you approach it in a positive
sense that trying to better and learn
and accomplish and beat that then it
just makes you better at what you're
trying to do you know what i mean before
you know it especially growing your
whole life that's the goal is eliminate
variables you know and make it as easy
as possible so you can be happy and
successful at the end if you fought it
the whole time it's you're stressed out
you burn out you're tired you question
what you did and so it's eliminate those
variables you know and learn you know
what to do so that you don't have those
issues and in the beginning and prepare
you know so that you don't have those
issues and then after that especially
the right environment and the dialogue
environment really gives different
strains you know the opportunity to
thrive and grow and a lot of people will
discard different strains because they
didn't you know do well but they didn't
have their environment dialed or they
had other issues or spikes or you know
water issues or different issues so and
they would ultimately go to the strain
and kind of put that off so you know
some strains don't get him be able to
live and be able to show this one was
tough the first i this is the second
plan i grew the first one was uh i
didn't have the same results
get some of that just dried in the back
seat of the car on the way over
here so incredibly fruity it lost a
little bit of that future yeah yeah
you'll smell it you know in the end you
know but it is it's fruit fruit up front
wow and almost like a minty fruit yeah
that's fantastic i i love what you're
saying about
data and testing and testing your well
water and yeah that's something we're
focusing more on too we just brought in
a soil lab called imperial analytics
okay so that we can have soil samples
sent to us yeah we can test and process
it and send you your fertility back so
you can actually compare that with your
sap testing and be like okay my soil's
got this
but my plant's missing it what's going
on what's my uptake issue or
i've got way too much k in here yeah i
don't need that i'm wasting money
dumping all this extra fertilizer in so
we want to help kind of feed that
knowledge quest and yeah kind of data
fuel for sure it's important you know we
take
50 leaf samples per zone off nine flower
zones plus three veg zones a week plus a
well water sample a b c plus a mixed
sample and everything mixed together and
then a runoff sample and then we'll
compare what was in our plans completed
runoffs and adjust a mix that that ryan
developed for the last couple years and
adjust that mix to benefit you know what
i mean we always had adjustments to make
with that you know and that's
ro is obviously different you know
that's obviously beneficial because you
strip all the elements out and you know
so you know i love i mean for a crop
that's this valuable
you know in the grow that we're building
i'm i'm going our own all right yeah
we're not going to you know deal with
the vehicles eliminate that where we
live especially we're surrounded by
agriculture i mean i want to say yeah
your water water challenge we've got
changes where nitrates have changed
overnight where we've got you know
oh yeah a lot a lot more build up in
nitrates more uh chloride i mean it's it
was it was a struggle you know different
times of the year
water is shallow you know it's 120 feet
deep so i mean
it's a lot more influenced by what
happens above you yeah so yeah and we
adapted and we'll be able to adjust and
learn a lot of things and be sure to
also
class with the water that we were
pumping out
six or seven hundred parts per
yeah that just reinforces that
you million
importance not only testing your soil
testing your sap but test that
irrigation water that's another service
we offer at imperial too so yeah that's
awesome so and then it's coming out of
the same lab as your soil test so you
data as well we're not doing tissue
are know your
that's a bigger nut to crack and yeah
when we brought the lab in we really
wanted to focus on providing ourselves
the services that we needed a quick
turnaround tomorrow
it's 100 critical we take a line sample
and we need to have that information
immediately like you as a grower yeah
you're like i need this snapshot and i
need it now before i do something else
that changes it especially when you're
growing something like rockwool where
you get a lot of results fast or you see
a lot of
changes fast you're dealing with an
issue you want to get results right away
so you can make those changes hopefully
you try to catch those issues way early
on or you eliminate those issues from
the beginning like we were talking about
you know the last ship samples out so
you're dealing with lead times you know
they have to ship it out and wait for a
third party to process it and send it
back to them you know so finding the
right lab is is one of the key factors
in this where you can get the results
fast you know i mean that's that's
something we i think that you know the
lab where we kind of we live out will be
great you know because where we're at
kind of the labs are pretty far this is
the way so it's more challenging or even
in this lab eventually you know
something you can do just for your own
testing somebody that can do you know
on-site you know you don't test them to
keep on top of those kind of things so
yeah and that's the challenge and that's
why we
at royal gold we're like we have to
maintain this lab that you know the
local people dirty business soil
consulting they were
done with the lab moving on to their
education and like crop consulting were
putting that first and we're like we
need this for us but we need it for the
community we need to offer this service
we talked about just bringing it
internal and not allowing people to
submit samples anymore and we're like no
yeah we need to provide this for people
and it really has come a long way really
quickly i grew up working in ag man i
worked for a soil laboratory for three
years you know so all i did was take
soil samples petiole samples leave
samples and process data and
you know correlate that to what we had
to give the field to you know get it
back to where it needed to be so i mean
that
that i grew up at a young age seeing
that and the importance of it you know
in the field you know on a grand scale
of you know tens of thousands of acres
you know so
yeah it is no different than what we're
doing you know and people on that level
of ag they don't cut corners on them
they do not at
a core all
of their program that hundred dollar
test could save you a thousand dollars
and miss applied nutrients
yeah
and that's where the other thing that's
really important is
methodology like testing the native soil
here in las vegas is a different process
they're testing a potting media they're
testing a hybrid media and that's where
i think you know cultivators like
yourself you know what's in that soil
you know all right hey i need a native
test on this because it is not a lot of
organic matter this is a mineral soil or
hey this is all potting media i need a
potting media test because it's
different extractions to show you what's
available what's already in the media
before you put your plants in you want
to
levels of what you know what you have in
there exactly yeah which compounds or
which macro or micro nutrients you're
having or
those kind of things you know so it's
important you know it's also
quality of the plan you know not just
you important for
financially but if you're trying to
produce the best quality you can and do
the best you can and you want to check
all those things and you want to make
sure that you have all that dialed in
right you know because when you step
back and you're done and there's
something that you're not happy with you
automatically start thinking about all
those little details yeah and you're man
i wish i would have done that or man i
wish i would have did this and this and
that so the next time what you do is you
do those things and over the years and
over the different grows and gardens and
that you put in you slowly eliminated
and changed and adjusted to where you
just automatically do all those things
even though it's a little more it might
cost a little more or whatever in the
beginning you do those because in the
end
you're going to have a better product
and you're going to be happy with what
you did you know and so
you learn that over time
yeah we're on mj biz here las vegas 2021
what do you guys think how's the show i
think it's great man i think it's great
man i'm happy to see everybody back here
and you know
taking a couple years off i mean it's
it's nice to finally get to see the
familiar faces and you know
been in the industry for a long time so
you know i've known you for a long time
rick and getting to hang with you guys
anytime you know we're we're around as
always we appreciate you coming here and
doing this with us it's been great
definitely man i appreciate it thank you
so much what's the hot new thing we
should be looking for from you guys out
there in the world people out at home
checking this out listening what seeds
are are going to be the hot fresh thing
to keep an eye for the drop our cookie
land is is the one i'm focusing on now
you know that's that's uh the f3s are
getting ready to come come next you know
this was the f2 that jeremy has in here
but uh the cookie land and all the
crosses that we've made with it
the grow is is getting built as we speak
so uh
we're hoping you know may of next year
is kind of our eta of being operational
and then
just you know watch our watch our social
media and you know stay tuned to see
what we end up doing there because it's
going to be a fun one where can people
find you online at bosque genetics
is my main account uh that that'll be
you know for the grow uh bosque cannabis
and bosque consulting um we we do
consulting as well so i mean that's
that's the other side of here right now
for sure for me it's uh
we're fixing to come online and we want
people to be aware that we're coming out
to do the best we can and the best we
can put out there and so be ready and
because we're going to do
our job to make sure we provide clean
um healthy good cannabis for people you
know and multiple different flavors
genetics you know bring genetics to the
forefront you know and and keep on
working we got a lot more than this i
mean that's just that's my main focus
right now that's that's the the point of
the spirit yeah the point of the spirit
for sure for sure man i'm
[Laughter]
[Music]
you know
the look and a lot of frost and the
right smell and the terpenes i mean some
people can't deny it you know even it's
green purple whatever
if you open it you're true it's kind of
sore a smoker those people are gonna you
know at least try it and i want to get
the good flavor and a good clean burn
and you get that good xl flavor you know
and it just you know all the things that
happen when you smoke good flour you
know it's undeniable so i think that as
long as we put out a good brand a good
brand a good quality flour that's truly
quality all around not just bag of peel
but also a nose to it also flavor you
know great xl a great high to it clean
height to it i think that it a lot of
people are going to come on board with
that and so as long as we do our job and
and make sure that we're doing a good
job when we're in our garden and making
sure we're carrying ourselves correctly
and doing the right things that we
should do in our garden and trying to
put all those years of experience into
that and are disciplined in what we're
doing i think that it will just all come
with it you know as people learn about
it and start smoking our flour i think
that it will definitely grow
we want people to try it you know
[Music]
as a good friend of ours says the proof
is in the puffins
you know we come from i worked at a
hydro store for four years you know what
i mean ryan owned a hydro store for a
while you know we we've been doing this
for a lot of years you know i mean we
come from that that industry so we all
know that a lot of people say
that they do this or they produce that
or everybody produces fire everybody
we tell everybody
put it on the table you know what i mean
we'll put it on the table we have no
problem putting it on the table so if
anybody else can put on table and it's
not that we're trying to be cocky or a
competition in that but we're confident
in the way that we carry ourselves and
what we're doing
man well thank you guys so much for
coming and sharing this passion with us
i've always been impressed by what you
guys are bringing to the table and i
can't wait to see the final fruits of
this candyland
mash-up project and
again thank you guys so much thank you
very much appreciate it
thank you very
it much seriously that was so much fun
[Music]