what's going on
everybody I am finally back from
Southern Humbolt from receiving my
Gan
certification and now I'm just here with
the the catfish tester
group weighing in on my catfish thus far
we're at like 8 n weeks of veg and I've
been keeping things pretty small they
started out in like little Solo cups I
moved them up to half gallons and now
they're finally in the two gallons where
they'll finish
um it's been like maybe 5 days since I
transplanted into the two gallons and
this is the growth that I've gotten from
the catfish thus far that one in the far
back is one of the last cfish and then
you know it's right here this one's a
different
variety but as you can see the catfish
is rather uniform outside of some height
differences I got some shorter
phenotypes here in the front it looks
like and then the taller ones in the
back and we've just been really running
with them they manag to stay healthy um
you know this tent is a little bit
overcrowded so I am having to do some
folur just to make sure I'm I'm on top
of everything things are like sprayed
There's an actual IPM regiment going on
um just with NE oil and the FP the
fermented plant extracts that I
use but for the most part everything's
looking healthy like I said I'm I'm just
getting back so this is my first update
myself and the rest of the tent I have
again some Kim dog Special Reserve from
Peter some kimd rainbow belts um that
I've been running you know pretty much
you know I've been running the rainbow
belts cross dag on there every time I've
pop seeds so these are right here and
then as we move and shift over here
we've got the Hollywood uh the hollyw TK
M10 in the back that's also from dgg
dolo shout out to Peter um here up here
we got the Moses and you know this
little one was rootbound when I
transplanted and I just decided to try
to transplant it up to see if it would
go it's struggling clearly but that's
okay we are probably going to get that
one out of there um this is this whole
Moses uh Platinum Kush line has been
[ __ ] with me um they went rootbound
pretty early I've been really trying to
figure them out but that's the fun of
running a whole bunch of varieties and
cirs even though most of them are
somewhat related in some regards um
these have been giving me the hardest
time though as you can
see uh we got the comfort food over here
that's cat
too and again we got some Mass medical
OG cush by prayer
glue but now the star of the show are
definitely probably the TK the hollyw TK
M10 and then we got we got the
catfish and I just I'm really proud of
these happy and excited to see the flow
got a couple of different fenos as of
right
now but you know we'll see how they
express once we flip on the flower I
think Thursday of this week that's the
update for now man y'all take it easy