hey everybody this is steve cantwell
i want to share a bottomless pot
technique with you guys um this is our
27th cycle um this planted earlier today
i had my growers take me one bed just to
demonstrate this for everybody hope you
guys enjoy
all right so this is one of our beds
after a cycle
and what you're seeing here is two
cycles worth of pots on top of the soil
and i'll explain the reason behind that
so this pot here with less dichondra has
less cover crop in it um this is from
the cycle the last cycle that was just
harvested um you can see here the same
thing
let me skip one and go here
and what we do is we create a grid
of 18
and or 12 plants per cycle so this one
is a 12 grid plant so if you look 1 2 3
5 6
7 8 9 10 11 12. that's all one grid and
then this is at my 18 plant grid one two
three
four five six seven eight nine 10 11 12
13 14 15 16 17 18. and what i do is i
use this grid to rotate my crops so
basically
my indica dominant strains for the most
part will take 18 plants
a bed to fill the canopy in the amount
of time i have to fill the canopy
whereas the 12
grid plants are like more sativa if you
will
in structure and they only take 12
plants
to fill the canopy in the space i have
on the time i have allocated for veg
so
by by putting the 18 versus 12 on every
other cycle i'm forcing myself to rotate
my strain to rotate my crop if you will
so i'm not growing the same cannabis
variety in the same bed over and over
again and potentially stripping the soil
of what it is that that plant you know
actually likes
so what we're going to do today is
we're going to remove
uh the the pot from two cycles ago and
replace it with a fresh plant again this
is the pot that was just harvested we're
gonna give it one cycle to break down
and then this is the pot from one cycle
ago
that's ready now the reason we do this
is because if i were to try to remove
this pot with fresh roots it's it's
already it's still anchored to the bed
this will create a big mess a big
disturbance and to be a lot more work
whereas this pot that had a cycle to
break down its roots are broken down it
lifts right up
with minimal mess minimal disturbance
couple things to take into consideration
if you're going to try this out with by
cutting the bottoms of your old pots out
definitely do it before you plant into
those pots don't grow in pots with
bottoms and then cut it out um
because you're going to shock the plant
by doing that
and you're going to
only get the benefit of not having to
dig holes versus the less transplant
shock um so if you want to get the full
benefits of it both less reduce labor
and reduce transplant shock then cut the
bottoms of your pots out before um
planting into them before planting your
clones or your seed into them um also uh
if you go with uh grass roots like these
are grass roots pots if you go with
grass root pots
over um a plastic pot the plastic pots
will hold moisture a little bit longer
on top of the soil so you can just water
them every other day where the grass
roots pots you're going to want to water
them um almost every day the first like
five to seven days until their roots
start to transform
okay guys so check it out
all i'm gonna do is pull up on this pot
i could already feel it just lightly
ripping off the soil
then what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna take
my hand put my hand underneath it
and lift up
all the old grooves everything's there
intact then i just take this i'm going
to throw it in a wheelbarrow and that
way i can harden off and put it into a
tote and then reuse it
now i'm going to take
the
the fresh pot one thing you want to do
um is not water these pots the day of
planting i think my growers pranked me
knowing i was gonna do this video and
they heavily watered these pots
um
before leaving them for me
it just makes it heavier a little bit
more challenging but this is basically
what you're gonna get
wiggle it into place
if you have time kind of push the molds
up against it
but that's basically as simple as it is
um you remove one and you replace it
with another it's about as easy as it
gets uh again i'm not digging a hole and
having to move a bunch of soil i'm just
lifting one pot and putting back another
one
so this is the pot that we just removed
uh one thing i wanted to kind of talk
about was the potential um we haven't
done this yet but the potential to
remove it and place it directly on a
saucer and plant directly into it again
without having to dump and mix
i'm not sure if this is the best idea
for you know 20 cycles
but something if everything's running
smoothly you might be able to get away
with for you know two three maybe four
cycles before having to actually dump
this out and re-amend your best mix
if it calls for it um so it's just
something to think about again i'm not
sure if this is the direction that this
tech is gonna go
so now i'm going to show you guys how to
fill these bottomless pots in case you
ain't figured out yet um so you're going
to take a saucer and take an empty pot
place on top of the saucer i'm doing
this with one hand obviously i'm
recording um they're just going to fill
the pot
you'll want to then shake your pot make
sure if it settles
leave a little bit of room for a walk to
catch water and top dress
and then basically
plug your clone so one question i get
asked a lot is how to take care of the
bottomless pots prior to placing them on
the beds um so as you can see here we're
just sitting on a rack on a saucer under
some led lights um they're here for
about
two to three weeks just to get some size
get some root growth um we water them
about every other day um
you know they we call it rain we just
rain on them
from time to time but for the most part
um
treat it like you would any other pot
i just want to close out this video um
by reiterating some things that i talked
about
first off keep in mind again that this
technique was designed for commercial
scale to reduce labor
along the way we discovered some
benefits as far as less plant shock that
anyone can benefit from at any scale
so just keep in mind that that's the
main focus of this so if you're having a
one lighter at home and you like digging
holes more power to you
keep in mind our soil is well maintained
well aerated um
we're going to grow healthy plants
regardless this is mainly for us in our
situation
to reduce the amount of labor going in
and out of each one
another thing if you go with the
grassroots fabric bottomless pots um
versus a hard pot with a cut out bottom
keep in mind with the grass root pots
you're gonna have to water a little more
frequently i'd say uh at first every day
every other day
um and then once the roots sow
themselves into the beds uh as long as
the beds are moist and wet you're good
but again the first five seven maybe
seven to ten days uh you're going to
want to make sure every day every other
day um we've kissed the top of the pots
with some water
just until they sew into the vents
one more thing i i can't say for sure
yet but it seems that topping the plants
right after placing them
seems to help the roots transfer a
little bit faster into the beds uh and
we get faster growth rates by doing that
as well um it's something i'm still
in the testing phases of but something
we've been noticing
hope you guys like what i shared with
you today
if you guys use it like it don't like it
whatever hit me up keep me posted um i'm
definitely curious to your guys's
success all right take care