i first wanted to start out by letting
all the viewers know
about you know bricks because there's
i used to test bricks with a
refractometer
um at home and what i would do is i
would eviscerate all of the plant
material and then i would squeeze
usually using something like a garlic
press
the juice on the refractometer to get a
bricks measurement now
that was something that i advocated and
i had also
you know before i before i knew you know
a long time ago you know i would say hey
if you can because the information out
there was that if you can get your
bricks percentage above a certain
percent
that plant sucking insects
would no longer see your plant as a food
source
now
we know
you know that this is actually an
incorrect mode of thinking and an
incorrect approach to the science
yes
yes uh
you know bricks is just a sum it's it's
a it's the sum of x plus y equals z it's
z
so
unless you understand what you're
what you're adding up to create the sum
um it's pretty difficult
to make a statement to say if your
sum if your bricks equal a certain
number that it equals uh
healthy plants or
decreased pests if you don't know your
ingredients if you don't know what's
making up those brick
so
for example
same with total nitrogen um you can get
your total nitrogen number and
go wow i've got some really good
nitrogen what is what is in your total
nitrogen again that's just a sum x plus
y equals z total nitrogen is the z
what makes up if it's just
mainly all nitrate that's not being
broken down and that is the main
ingredient in your total nitrogen then
no your your total nitrogen number is
not good even if it's falling into the
adequate ranges adequate
you know category so efficient
looking back at brick you know there's a
lot of things that can
increase your bricks um to give it that
high bricks but um
the number does not
account for or equate
healthy
so for instance
chloride and cannabis is a chloride
accumulator it does a great job of it
it's very good at
accumulating it if you have
significantly high chloride that can
your bricks
and then you will have a high brix
number but that doesn't necessarily mean
you have healthy plants or they're going
to be um
they're going to be
decreasing pests
things of that
another thing that is a accumulatory
right is if you were to look at your
cation exchange if you just looked at
the number and not looked at the cations
the positively charged elements that
make up the cation exchange
that that number means nothing i mean
you you could have um a ton of potassium
equating your cation exchange and then
what does that do for you that that does
not you're just looking at your cation
exchange you have to look at all the
cations in it right that's
again another sum number
so when people equate bricks
has the same definition no matter if
you're looking at say grapes like a
berry like a grape or you're looking at
leaves it's the same definition
it it's
soluble solids
so the definition doesn't change but
what you're measuring does so in grapes
most of your soluble solids when
measuring bricks is sugar
but when measuring leaves that's a
completely different story that is
that is a growing photosynthetic
part of the plant there will be sugars
in there of course absolutely
there could be a ton of other things in
there as well
and that and that brings me to the ref
the refractometer for people who are
trying to get bricks numbers
at home using
an instrument that's usually meant for
alcohol to measure the
brix levels to see how you know the
potential of what's convertible
into
another compound
when you miss a uh eviscerate
leaf material you're not getting just
you know what is available as far as
what's in the plant which would be you
know your what what substances would
that would occur in the the phloem and
xylem of the plant
right you're getting
the chlorophyll you're getting all of
the vacuole fluids you're getting all
the fluid that's encapsulated in cell
membranes so
you're also getting things
that have already been complexed and
stored
and when those are broken down
via
you know a maceration
you get all of that stuff and so when
you're
squeezing this green pigmented liquid
onto a refractometer to try to take
bricks reading what you're essentially
doing is
you're getting a collective sum
of
everything that's in that tissue
potentially
and you can't
determine
what
what it is that way right you can't
determine what you can't separate out
it's not a true brix reading because a
lot of the stuff that would be
considered bricks like sugar content or
the nutritional content
is there's so much more in there there's
so much contaminants in that so it
doesn't even equate to an accurate piece
of data
um
i mean i am going to do a little plug
for new age here this is exactly why
in sap analysis do bricks and sugar to
give you an understanding
of what part of the bricks is the sugar
or if your sugar is too low
what is making your bricks high why are
your bricks high well let's go and look
at the nutrients that are out of balance
um that's why stop analysis is so
helpful in
looking at especially bricks and
understanding what's
what are the ingredients of it what are
you measuring if your major is your if
you're measuring a whole bunch of
chloride
um
probably want to know that if you're
measuring
sodium you're probably
possible absolutely if you're in ground
and you've litified your water and your
aluminum is off the chart you probably
want to know that as well
um
there's a whole bunch of things like you
just said when you're men
the um the leaf
that you're throwing in at ingredients
that are definitely not in the fruit
um that wouldn't be found in the fruit
or at very very low quantities
um
so
it's the same definition
absolutely this definition it's just it
means different things when you're
measuring
uh different parts of the plant
i mean you can equate bricks if you were
measuring roots
of the roots you can squeeze roots we've
done it before
berries but you wouldn't equate the two
they're completely different parts of
the plants
so then you have to make a data set for
that too i want to back up and say you
know what you can still use a
refractometer because it's a data point
but you need to understand
you know how to apply that data point
because that data point isn't going to
be the same
as what you would do with a bricks
analysis from new age labs right it's
not going to work that way it's going to
be a different data set that's not going
to necessarily correlate to what you're
getting from the lab like you might be
able to use that for your own
you know baseline if you're creating a
data set right where you're creating a
standard across the board and you use
that in conjunction with these other
data points then
you have an applicable resource but
however if you're just
if you're using it to say hey my plants
are going to be immune to pest pressure
at
if i get a reading on
a meter like you said because you don't
know
what those are you don't know what's in
that
and that's why the sap analysis for me
is so interesting
one of the things that we've talked to
about in the past is
what you just mentioned the bricks
versus the total sugars right because
you know that if this much of the sugar
content is the bricks then you know that
the rest of that percentage is going to
be
the mineral content the mineral
nutritional content right that's stored
right that's available right
and if you have
really high potassium
high nitrogen high chlorides high sodium
that's going into the bricks
that's the other part of the bricks
also if you are
using a refractometer at home in the
field you need to use the same source of
light every time don't do it some of it
inside and some of it outside all needs
to be inside choose um a time of day so
it's
roughly the same lighting if you are
going to be outside if you're going to
be outside
not do it on a sunny day
in a cloudy day you need to do it
in in the same type of light
that's the one thing about the science
is you have to be consistent in them and
because if you have variables while
you're collecting data
those variables can essentially change
your outcomes you are collecting leaves
and you're an outdoor grower um collect
all your leaves on the sunny side
um or all of them on the shady side but
don't
do one or the other because you really
want to understand how your
um plant is photosynthesizing and for
stop analysis that it's all on the sunny
side but sometimes plants cannabis
plants can get very large so if you are
collecting and you're doing
at home or in your greenhouse or or
somewhere
consistency i just can't even tell you
is the key
um if you're going to be watering every
other day then take your leaves and take
your samples um either before or after
your water and always do it in that
manner always take it in the morning
always apply the same pressure so that's
really hard if you're going to be using
a garlic press
don't have all of the people that work
for you try to use it on a different day
have one or two people or do it yourself
and try to maintain the same amount of
pressure maybe put a cardboard or
something in it that you can try to
monitor the amount of pressure so are
you going to break the vacuoles every
time or you're not going to break the
everything so there's all
things to think about when you are
collecting your own data that come into
play even just collecting
yeah and so
when we're talking about
um having high bricks on
a sap analysis now i know that brix
levels change throughout the day
um depending on you know what's going on
if there's more light less light
lighting has a lot to do with it
environmental factors like temperature
and humidity
and also
what's in the soil you know what is
available to the plant so
when we're looking at a sap analysis and
we're looking at bricks versus total
sugars and then
you know the
the nutrition
what is one of the things that we should
always be
mindful of when it comes to sugar
content versus brix levels
in a sap analysis
and you've taken a young fully developed
photosynthetic leave and an old yet
viably
your
young and old leaf pairing your sugar
should always be equal to but really
higher in the new leaves
always
if that is not the case there's a
photosynthetic problem
so if your
sugars are
lower
in the new leaves which means they're
higher in the old and you have a high
bricks that means photosynthetic
broken somewhere
and your bricks
are being made up of something
and so in that type of situation where
you're seeing
happens a lot quite a bit
it's
that's why i wanted to touch on it you
know because
when you see this type of interaction
taking place
you can
you can go to a certain mode of thinking
and say okay well
something's not photosynthesizing why
are we lacking photosynthesis and you
can go to the
my immediate thinking is going to the
first five photosynthetic nutrients and
so we look at those we look at those
first and we say okay how how does our
nitrogen look how is the nitrogen
stimulation going do we have
things like molybdenum are they
completely gone we're looking at
molybdenum on the test too because i
think that's another indicator if you
have high molybdenum it means that
there's
a there's a gap
in the metabolic process an enzymatic
process that's happening with the
reduction
of
nitrate
ammonium into nitrate
um we're looking at the iron right
because that's another photosynthetic
chemical we're looking at magnesium
magnesium
you're looking at sulfur
um to make chlorophyll so if you're low
on mag you can just stop the train right
there
yeah
and four nitrogen equals a chlorophyll
so
that's the game that's how that's played
and if you are missing your mag and you
have a whole bunch of nitrogen um
that's going to be
that nitrogen to cycle through and of
course very hard
and then it and then what happens on the
on the
sap test is you see
that nitrogen go higher right it builds
up
because it's not able to convert
the
so we see the nitrate or ammonium go
higher
not the total because when we're looking
at the total nitrogen that could be
amino acids and proteins the nitrogen
complexes that are
stored inside of the plant right
anything that has a nitrogen molecule
attached to it shows as total nitrogen
and then we're looking at ammonium and
nitrogen nitrate we're looking at you
know
ammonium
nitrate is reduced
into ammonium and then
if those are building up in tissue and
we have a low accumulation of total
nitrogen
what do you think that usually indicates
um
that
indicates that your nitrogen is not
being broken down so it's being taken up
as nitrate and ammonium
and then it's not being broken down
going in down the um
nitrogen reductase pathway into amino
acids and what you really want is
proteins
so when that occurs i
so
magnesium has to be there if it's not
then
you've figured it out that's that's easy
um what you also need what you already
said you need molly you need iron
um iron
can be rather difficult to get into the
plants and many times that's kind of
picking points especially in veg because
the plant is creating structure
and um
so much of the iron is used in the
nitrogen reductase pathway at that time
you're growing your plants so what does
that mean you always have to replenish
it unless you're growing and you have
great um microbial
uh
pathways going on in your soil and
you're able to
take up the iron if you're in ground um
iron is usually always there but it's in
the wrong form so usually it's usually
as in it's usually as an iron oxide
right and the same thing with manganese
which is another
um
i think you said it was the king of
micronutrients right
i'm micronutrients for sure if you are
getting adequate iron and adequate
manganese and you're getting them up
through your roots and your ground it
usually means
that you have uh really good soil
microbes or you're using a product
that's heavily chelated and it's
actually getting into the plant those
are the two ways of
getting
to
and iron's really tricky especially in
these peat based modified mix
mixes because of the fact that
when we're looking at oxidation
chemistry for iron
it usually falls
into an unavailable state at the ph
ranges that we're cultivating these
plants in as soon as it hits moisture or
it comes in contact with oxygen it
oxidizes and so it becomes unavailable
very very quickly so being able to have
like you said uh something that can
chelate these the the iron and keep it
in reduced form or if you can get a
specific set of microorganisms one of
the things that
i see though is the type of
microorganisms that you would need to
keep iron reduced are are reductive
microorganisms and these are usually
focused or anaerobic organisms and
because what they're doing is they're
con
that
they're
able to function in
these really like low or no oxygen
conditions and that's the kind of type
of condition that iron needs to stay in
its reduced form to be available however
those conditions don't typically last in
these systems because they're so highly
aerated and because
um they don't stay anaerobic in in a
typical field condition where you have
set like total saturation of soil for a
period of time that stuff does become
available and if you have adequate soil
carbon you're able to kind of keep that
in a chelated form um the humic and
fulvic acid amino chelation through
bacterial secondary metabolite
production those all keep iron in
available forms same as manganese same
as things like phosphate or any of those
minerals that have to be in a reduced
form but as soon as you get more oxygen
as soon as the water starts to evaporate
the soil chemistry completely changes
and the things that are available in a
reduced form become less available and
the things that
are available in a more oxidized form
become more available
got it
that's so
so
hurdle
just because just because
a zap analysis tell you that you're low
on iron and manganese it's
that's just fool correct now it's the
grower that needs to figure out how to
get it in
yeah and that's where we use the science
we can look at science but we have to be
able to figure out how to apply it again
i'm a big proponent for the humic and
fulvic acids
but
one thing that i've been really diving
into is soil carbon as a nutrient that
plays a integral role
in things like uh
carbon phosphate clustering that's
something i'm learning about going down
some rabbit holes i'm going to be going
out to chicago
next week
i'm going to be learning some stuff from
somebody who was a private consultant
for nasa
and
he's going to he you know
gonna
show me some interesting things that i
don't think a lot of people know yet but
what i'm seeing from doing some r d is
soil carbon plays a huge role in
keeping things in
uh chemically available forms for the
plant
and so
one of the things that i'm wondering is
can we use
you know sap analysis
can we see
all right it's not just step analysis
can we use soil testing as well to
get a
better understanding of
how the carbon is affecting the dynamic
of the chemistry in the soil
well
the answer is yes you have to know what
you're measuring so
you know you measure low carbon high
carbon
soils and plant uptake
always have something to
um compare it to
that's really you're gonna where the
triangle is the delta the change
that's really
what you're looking for
yeah at that point
so
you know the whole we are you know we
got way off topic and we were talking
about bricks one of the things that is
really common is
pest and insect pressure and the belief
is if you
if your plants are at a certain
percentage of
bricks and it's really hard to you know
beast
give a complete definitive answer i
think because
bricks as com as measuring just the
sugar content or bricks measuring
the the total nitrogen
content because i know that
nitrogen and the types of nitrogen do
play a role
in
um insect sucking pests what's what's
kind of your take on
the the role of both nitrogen and then
complexed
carbohydrates and sugars that are stored
in the plant
uh
and insect pressure do you have you seen
a lot of data that
you know that that correlates those
things
so you know i've been doing actually a
lot of research on that um i'll be
speaking about that
based on the research i've been doing
later on this winter
um it's not a one one size fits all that
everybody likes to have
black and white statements really
there's there's a whole
whole gamut of things that needs to fall
in place which is why plants are so cool
but um
yes
virgin is not breaking down if it's in
nitrate high nitrate and
high total and or high ammonium than
the nitrate portion and
tests
but that isn't
a number because
high nitrate and high ammonium is going
to be different for everybody because
it's based on the difference compared to
your total n
so you can't just throw out at 500 parts
per million of nitrate because if you
have 2 000 parts per million of total n
well that's 75 percent conversion you're
doing okay but if you have
a thousand parts per million of total
and now you're 50 conversion now that's
a problem
but maybe your plants are older maybe
they're younger maybe there's a
different uh maybe you're
you're throwing in all kinds of curve
balls so there's not really a center
that i say that if your nitrate is at
this number you're going to have
problems you do
have to compare it to your total n which
means every grower is going to be
different
also
for for sugars i've been doing quite a
bit of research i've done
one
um research project on its own
and came
in results again that i will be sharing
and i'm looking into how
um manganese works in to
the system about
um
sugar reduction and looking into your
different types of sugars so it's not
only
high sugar but what types of sugars
um
so manganese does come into play there
as well
and really what i have seen
that
probably makes the biggest difference is
to start
early
if you're going to plant plug plants or
you're going to be planting plants with
roots
start them
early don't hit them with a whole bunch
of fertilizer as they get older give
them the nutrients that they need
now those are the plants that i see have
less bugs left less aphid people did
root dips they started early they
started right as the plant was forming
and that's
that's what i did i had
i had lettuce i had plug plants and i
did micronutrient root dips and there
was one set
in my uh that i did i i did the whole
experiment by myself
um did it in triplicate there was one
one part of the experiment that had no
aphids that was right next to a
multitude of plants that had stopped
and why was that and the one major
difference in all the sap analysis was
manganese
and it's not just administ because i
added manganese everything i added it to
everything
but the one thing that really really
shined the plants that got the manga
through the roots that was able to be
chelated and taken up when the plants
were young
those are the plants that didn't have
aphids everybody got
is
you know on their life cycle they got
foliar they didn't want to kill it
but it was starting early and that's the
plant signed and they were right next to
the plants that were covered in aphids
and i i looked
out um
all the way through the whole entire
research
one set
of study plants
had one to two aphids and mainly zero on
on plants right next to that were
crawling with aphids
and that's what i found out mayonnaise
is magic i think the way you apply it
and i think it's early on
you don't not wait until there's a
deficiency you add it up front
yes uh you want manganese kind of
throughout and one of the benefits of
manganese is that
so manganese again is tricky right
because it needs to be in a reduced form
and it causes it in it and it creates uh
you know
manganese oxides
in soil that are unavailable and it also
competes with iron yep
so one of the things is trying to be
able to get these inadequate quantities
inside of the plant can be difficult
because you're dealing with the soil
chemistry so high organic matter
actually
inhibits manganese uptake because it it
causes oxidation but there are
beneficial microorganisms specifically
the bacillus and the wrath of
pseudomonas which actually can
keep manganese in an available form can
increase the availability of the
manganese but also what mayonnaise does
too is it increases it it helps
facilitate the uptake of other
micronutrients
is one of the benefits that you get from
the manganese so i i would assume that
it's not the min just the manganese
itself but the
but the but some of the properties and
the benefits that the manganese are
doing inside of the plant being to
help the plant get
the other micronutrients from the soil
which are also going to benefit because
it's going to increase plant defenses
with all those other chemicals that are
being
taken out all those other plant
nutrients as well
right
no i
that's what i don't really think when
you ask that question
what do i think about nutrients and what
needs to be applied to decrease your
pest it's not i don't think it's one
nutrient but it's a plan or
never seeing it
ever
once you see a deficiency already you've
already lost
how how many i lost time you've lost
time and you've lost sufficiency right
as far as as far as the metabolic and
the internal processes of those plants i
i think that
it's really difficult to always be
especially in a natural setting right in
agronomic conditions it's going to be
even more difficult than in these types
of modified conditions that were
operating in cannabis
but still looking at the way that
chemistry and biology keep things in
available in unavailable forms and being
able to switch the soil from modes
where
you can go back and forth this is going
to be available this is going to be
available because there's
it's like you know you see those ph
rings people like oh this is the perfect
ph range because this
is more of it this is kind of available
this is more available and you're just
trying to get everything you can but to
get maximum sufficiency you need to go
back and forth and back and forth and so
you need these type of oxidation and
redox states happening in these mixes
right you need to be able to figure out
how i can do this artificially how would
nature do this
in this environment that we're
creating for this plant and that a lot
of times is going to be through
dropping ph ranges maybe you're using or
um an organic
you know like using the fulvic and humic
acids or using biology that's going to
drop here
and then maybe having
something else that's going to increase
using you know high potassium inputs
that are going to
increase
the the soil ph and
make other things more available adding
carbon that's going to be able to
chelate these things naturally and keep
them uniform
it's really interesting and that's you
know the the
i think the most benefit that we get
from sap analysis is that it gives so
many data points but it also lets us
preemptively come out a problem because
if we know that
something is pulling from a lower
portion of the plant then we get to
address that before it actually shows
visual symptoms
and i think that's one of the things
that
a lot of
growers
are usually addressing issues as they
see them come up if you can see the
issue before it's visually
present then you're able to mitigate
some of that stress that's going to be
associated with the efficiency system
yep absolutely you're seeing a
deficiency symptom
your plant is
is it's sad
it it's it's gone through weeks and
weeks and weeks of struggling right
that's
how much
how much uh sugar
um how much photosynthesis potential
have you lost how much um you want to
have your greatest genetic potential
because um in this crop it's all about
genetics and crossing and varieties so
if you're
if you're deficient in something
you've lost your greatest genetic
potential of showing it
and now you're just trying to keep pace
when you're trying to look at new
varieties and and what they can do and
uh potency when you're deficient you've
lost
the ceiling at that point
you're not going to reach that highest
genetic potential because you've already
you're you're you've brought your
ceiling down
and you know what's really interesting
too is we're looking at
the testing from like commercial
standpoint where you can take an
analysis of a certain cultivar even if
you're only increasing the the
let's say you're getting an increase
as a percentage in quality and both
yield if those are both only two percent
but you're running thousands and
thousands of plants
that two percent can
can be a huge huge
uh difference in potential income
versus
what it would cost to say you know test
uh
do a collective data sample of a test
testing or a collective leaf sample and
send that in
that's one of the biggest things that i
see is especially when you start to
scale these systems
and you want to go bigger and bigger you
have to have
these data sets you have to have these
data sets to maintain quality control to
maintain
uh yield potentials
people are using us um
especially
also to decrease their inputs so
think of large grows to
your inputs by ten percent especially as
the
sky rocketing the potassium or
phosphorus is skyrocketing those prices
are are real i have growers that are
very concerned
um
and this is mainstream ag but still it's
going to trickle down on the differences
um in fertilizer price last year versus
you know 2020.
and if you're over feeding in certain
areas uh they want to know that they
want to have that reduction in 10 so
they can reallocate that budget it
normally goes to the micronutrients
usually if you have an
access
you can
you know stop applying 10 to 15 to 20
percent people reallocate in these two
areas
they reallocate in their micronutrients
first and then they put more money into
their soil biology whether they're
organic sustainable
um
uh conventional it doesn't matter those
are the those are the realms that that
falls
into there and that's
that's one of the the
things that actually got me started into
organic cultivation was
the cost-saving benefit but
it's exponentially increased when you
have
especially when you're doing like you
know soil testing saturated paste and
you're doing sap analysis because i can
know hey i don't need to over apply this
these are my target ranges i don't need
to go over this it's a waste of money to
add this to the soil because it's not
going to give me any additional input
and i can
know
you know pre
you know for me i use all dry mineral
amendments so we can order things and
bolt things cost maybe 15 to 35 dollars
for 50 pound bags we can order them all
at once and have a supply for x amount
of time
add those as we need them we don't need
to there it takes the guessing out of it
too right there's no guess work involved
you know hey i need to add some gypsum i
need some
you know because calcium is low i need
to increase calcium or i need to change
the percentage of my cations and i need
to increase potassium to make sure it's
above magnesium things like that it's so
much easier when you have data sets to
decrease those costs
absolutely and
again with this crop with so many
varieties out there um really good to
have your own data sets right so collect
your own data
grown
um strains throughout the whole entire
because different strains feed
differently for sure i come from the
baby
as mother plants very similar to
cannabis very
very very similar they cut them they
sell clones same exact situation i've
seen varieties in a trial plot that all
the same amount of nitrogen and you can
just see it's like christmas lights
certain rows are lighting up with
deficiencies right next to a row that's
perfectly green and those are things
that you want to know you want to have
beads in the same greenhouse or the same
plot you don't want running a
place trying to
um
feed
very very different strains different
amount of
inputs that's yeah that's like running
around drunk
you know what i've seen it through doing
the sap analysis that's the best way to
actually look at a specific cultivar's
nutritional needs because if you have a
baseline that works pretty much across
the board
but you see that things like phosphate
are low or that it's still trying to
move phosphorus from the lowers to the
top or if you see that it's moving right
you know moving nitrogen you can
for when it comes to things that are
mobile
even things that are immobile
you can know i need to add this this
needs to go higher
on this particular variety across the
board um
i've seen it
what i see a lot of times is phosphorus
requirement is greater for varieties
that
stretch
yes
absolutely cause yes yes
absolutely and the phosphor phosphorus
requirements can be
vastly different
that be different and
the other thing about phosphorus going
back to sugar is that if you don't have
enough foss your photosynthetic your
photosynthetic engine will be broken
at some point along the way also if you
get really low in foss it's very very
hard to catch up
and that's the biggest that's one of the
biggest thing that people don't
understand is that
you could have a sufficient amount but
as soon as you run out it could take you
know
weeks
for it to
get back on track
from not having that adequate supply
that it needs well because as soon as
your foss runs low it starts the plant
will start stealing from the older
leaves
and as that progresses um the lower
leaves get
lower and low low in amounts and your
your photosynthesis also can start to
shut down so when you add foss
the plants what it's going to do because
it's a mobile element it's going to send
it to the new leaves so the old leaves
are still going to maintain
and be low for a quite a significant
amount of time depending on how low you
are so you're really going to have a
very hard time catching up in the old
leaves when the plant keeps sending the
new
it's it's very very difficult to catch
up and many times um people can't and
when your plant goes low and fast again
that's the photosynthesis and then your
sugars run low and that's definitely not
what you want to have happen that that's
not the
that's not the train that you wanna
you wanna be on
so i had a question that uh came in on
the the comments and it was asking can
that can low phosphorus cause purple
streaking in the stems and i will answer
that that's yes
low nitrogen typically number one
um cause of purple streaking in stems is
gonna be uh cajun imbalance
it's going to be the imbalance between
calcium magnesium
and uh
potassium
sodium too if you have high sodium and
it's blocking that out that's what i'm
seeing also low nitrogen can cause it
and then low foss can cause it to
be careful when you're looking at your
if you think that you're low
nitrogen and you don't um
you don't have a water filtration system
you can actually have really high
chlorides they have they
they look the same
so
if you are having water filter then make
sure and check your water filtration
i've had multiple people say there's no
way we could have chlorides coming in
said when's the last time you checked
your water they went to water
that's one of the things that i usually
tell people that they need to do if they
have if i see high chloride on soil and
sap uh our saturated paste testing
um is fire bicarbonate and sodium
because those usually come in through
the water or they come in through ocean
inputs a lot of times
cannabis needs chloride all plants do
it's a synthetic element
but when we're not growing when we're
growing
to cultivate and we're not growing in
the wilds
as soon as your chloride
starts to become uh not a photosynthetic
element anymore but a toxin the plants
are putting it down to the lower leaves
it can withstand quite a bit of chloride
but in many cases
um chlorides are in like 4 000. that's a
significant amount of chlorides and your
plant will push it down and when they're
in when it's done pushing trying to
um
keep it away from the baby parts it will
push it to the older leaves and when
that fills up it goes down through the
roots and out through the root exudates
and what is that going to kill your
biology so it is a domino effect
yeah not only that but
chloride is an anion so it will
negatively affect
the uptake of other anions if i'm not
mistaken it's the biggest one the plant
is so good at accumulating it absolutely
and
because of the inputs that we have and
the water that we use commercially
there's going to be chloride usually
accessible too much to to the extent of
uh being a toxin
99 of the time there's a few areas that
people are low in chloride and that's
always fun and the doors wide open for
them to use inputs but usually most
i'm i'm one of those fortunate people i
have pretty low chloride bicarbonate and
sodium so
i'm able to do things like c90 every
once in a while which is a dehydrated
uh you know ocean input that can help
increase biology
um
is good and the really you're one of the
awesome that you're able to use it but
it does have a high
element of sodium but because you have
low sodium you're able to use it but i
would really caution people that if you
haven't ever taken a test before if you
don't know
um don't know your plants be careful
about adding c90 because if you have
even adequate medium sodium that that
could they can climb i usually i
recommend it usually as a
foiler application where you can use it
foilerly
and then i think on my actually on my
directions for use on the stuff that i
saw on my website it says that you
should have a soil test done to know if
you're gonna
be able to drench it or i'm actually
coming up almost coming up on an hour
here and i have a podcast coming up
cheap home grow podcast
um so i think we had a question about
defoliation and the effects for uh
acquired nutrient needs
one of the things that i've seen is
defoliation is kind of tricky because a
lot of times in cannabis we
prune up the bottoms and some of the
mobile nutrients
if you're not adequate and what's
falling into solution
the plant
oftentimes
will
take from the lowers but if you have no
lowers there you've pruned everything
off and then you're you haven't
addressed the issues that are
in the soil
then it can cause problems
so the best course of action and one of
the things that we do at our farm is
when we do defoliation we always add a
micronutrient solution to the soil
to kind of counterbalance
the
the stress
that is going to occur
you know
in an ideal world we could do testing
you know weekly and be able to but one
it's it it would it's not cost effective
and two
it takes time when it comes to shipping
to doing the lab stuff so we get these
snapshots and we have the snapshots we
have to make
educated decisions off of what we can do
best
for us uh
from my experience
being able to supply a light mixture
even a full
solution you can do things like
a fully chelated mineral mix
using amino chelation for instance to
add after you do your defoliation to
help
you know
decrease the stress load on a plant
that's
yeah because if you're going to be
taking away nutrients via the older
leaves adding it back is is obvious but
that's an obvious solution and something
that you need to look at basically if
you're going to defoliate um you are
opening up the plant for um
quicker
uh nutrient
uh deficiencies basically because they
pulled away the bank but i understand in
areas there's need for it just
be very proactive
and you're adding it back into the soil
as
as fast as you can
so i appreciate you coming on the live
um i hope to continue working with you
and doing some more step analysis in the
future
um if you want to let the people that
are watching kind of let give them your
your information where they can find you
so they can follow along on the science
that you're doing as well
and then we'll
we'll uh sign off
yeah yeah wage laboratories uh in in on
instagram it's the full long name new
age laboratories uh we are also
written up um cannabis uh science and
technology there's an article um in that
uh
magazine um it's on our linkedin or uh
sorry
i am on linkedin as well it's on our
instagram as well so you can look up
that article it's a few pages long
but um let me know if you have any
questions and i'll try to get back all
these um
these comments and things like that i
know that you're busy going on a podcast
brandon
thanks for um thanks for coming on here
and then i'll probably just upload this
video so people can watch it yeah great
okay all right have a good night thanks
for thanks again okay always good
talking to you great talking with you
all right bye