so that's a great transition point like
to jump us forward a little bit because
i could sit and listen to these stories
of black bear and dead to her all day
but
i want to talk a little bit about
cultivation and how
we got to where we are now with you out
doing the designing cult and consulting
so
i first visited your farm scarlet fire
farms out in willow creek
what was it probably seven years ago now
or so yeah it was 2015 2016. yeah i
believe when we were filming an episode
of growing exposed which you can check
out still on the growing exposed website
it's still out there and
features brian
telling you some of the secrets that you
may have to pay him a bunch of money for
now to get them out to consult
so there's a lot of really cool things i
learned that day
but
one of them was that we owned the same
piece of land
i owned it apparently directly after you
in willow creek
and
you know that was one of my first
outdoor farms in humboldt and we
connected over the fact that well there
was no sun for about five months
and
you know among other things it was my
first exposure to
scaled up knf
making your own nutrients all the way
from scratch
literally you guys were
fermenting deer carcasses you were doing
all sorts just to harvesting your own
seaweed yeah we're trying everything
and that's where all these kind of new
modalities of cultivation and
permaculture and sustainability are
coming from as those days of
experimentation what led you to that
moment you know because i'm
you went down a long road of cultivation
with two lights in a closet apparently
tell us about some of that road
um as far as the you know the k f or
actually the modern nature farming which
is more of a you know
current way of explaining it was just
really intriguing to me you know i
started was introduced to a friend um
ancient dank on instagram and i was just
like kind of watching some of the stuff
that he was doing and it's like this is
so crazy like
why shouldn't why let's try this i mean
we're in the woods we can
grow what we need we can harvest what we
need let's give it a try you know and it
was kind of on the cutting edge you know
it was on the edge of like a big change
anyway so it was like how can we make
this change even more exciting all right
um
so yeah uh
of course with all the experience you
know the years and years of cultivation
i've tried pretty much everything you
know i started out with general
hydroponics you know the the green and
the green and the red
and then you know i tried
once they changed into the what is it
the
um
i can't remember their organic product
that they put out but
anyway we just changed into that oh
general organics general organic there
you go that's a slipped my mind yeah and
i was going hard with that one you know
that one worked real really well but as
we were kind of scaling from inside
to outside it just didn't really seem
like it would fit to be using bottles
you know expense purposes waste purposes
all that kind of stuff you know it's i
felt like when you're indoor you're kind
of creating this like little world your
little laboratory and you do all these
different things right because you have
to you're creating your own environment
so you know you feel like you're forced
to use bottles and whatnot and then also
the lack of knowledge that was out there
open for everyone to to have
so
again once i moved out into the
larger scale outdoor and i could do it
year after year during the wonderful 215
era
[Music]
we could start logging data and start
seeing different changes on what we were
using and you know it just when
suddenly realized we were dumping like a
thousand dollars of liquid nutrients
into the into the reservoir for one
feeding app you know in the height of
the season you're like holy [ __ ] i i
feed quite a lot you know
this can't balance out properly right so
i mean i feel like
as we were getting pushed towards this
legalization and regulation i think we
were also getting pushed into like real
business life yeah price yeah was slowly
sliding down year after year after year
yeah overhead was going up up up because
for whatever reason every reason land
costs were going up
you know yeah we went through and you
know a gas spike back then too so you're
dealing with that and
you know so um
yeah i just feel like i was like okay
well let's make some changes because you
know the prices are dropping and there's
more competition
and so let's see if we can create our
own niche
and that's really kind of what got got
me down that road i really enjoyed it um
i feel like
nowadays everybody's so
hell-bent on data and
analytics and all that kind of stuff
that it really started getting a little
strange for me personally like i'm
making all these beautif these wonderful
things they all smell absolutely gross
the plants seem to love it
but what are we actually putting into
the plants because we don't have any
we're not getting tests we're like you
know if if we're ferment if we ferment
this product for three days longer than
we did the last time it could be a
completely different thing
right
what's coming out of the inputs right
how quickly there's a lot of questions
yeah and in my experience
sorry modern nature farmers but in my
experience i saw a yield drop
now i did see a quality increase
and we're always more interested in
quality than quantity right
but breaking the balance striking the
balance is key and in a changing uh
climate that you're dealing with and i
mean family and all the different things
that you generate as you grow
yeah um it was just you know it was
i had to
take a step away from that and kind of
go back to a more
conventional form of
cultivation
um
makes sense yeah and it's a lot i mean
now i'm seeing that it's a little bit
easier for me to relay what i'm trying
to teach these different farms that i go
to when i can have a product that's
basically you know the exact same thing
every time
repetition is key when you're trying to
push a product into market
especially now where it's not like oh
well this guy's buying it this time this
guy's buying it the next time it could
be going anywhere
you're probably
needing to fit into a niche in the
regulated market where you're selling to
the same set of people that take it to
the same set of dispensaries
you know even if it's kind of a
revolving cast it's you know it's an
established cast and you have to have
consistency
so
did that lead you to
really kind of going back more almost to
salts or did you end up seeing more like
hybrid technology or
what's
what are you seeing now as the
consistent way to get that output
well i've always tried to follow the the
natural input mindset you know
organic whatever
organish
but i've always kind of stood along
those lines you know once i got away
from the general hydroponic or the you
know the the hydroponic the whatever
yeah
the go boxes that's how i always
remember it general organics because
they had those boxes yeah that's crazy
yeah so i always try to stay with the
natural stuff i've never really been
into salts
as like you know a nutrient base and i'm
sure that there's a lot of
place for that in the new industry
because
you know there's a lot more data
collected there's a lot more
instruments designed to read that data
that you know you're trying to find
um
but i've always wanted organic because i
vote i'm a smoker
i'm like
when i'm growing weed i'm only smoking
my weed you know i mean there's other
people that i know that
i hold in a high regard that i would
smoke theirs too
but
i'm growing for myself number one and my
family and my friends you know so i
always wanted to be at least natural
um
we all want three pounds of light but
do we want to smoke the weed that is
typically created off of the three
pounds of light
not every time not every time right so
yeah that's why i always just stuck with
organic type nutrients and
natural inputs
awesome
were you still making teas and doing it
that way are you more into amending
well i like to do a soil amendment
you know i'm really big into soil
analysis
so you can track what's being put in and
what's actually being used up um i'm i'm
a big feeder i like feeding the plant so
i'll do
a
light amendment mix you know i'll juice
up the soil a little bit but then i like
to do a feeding and my my choice of
product these days is bio biz because
it's very natural product they've been
out in the game for
they're celebrating their 30th year this
month wow um and
most of their product or their products
are derived from beets sugar beets
and it's a fermenting process that they
use too so it's you know
in a fashion it is similar to the modern
nature farming
but
with the consistency of a bottled
product
yeah it's got a ton of sugars there's
some kelp
yeah it's i mean it's it's a it's a
great product i really like using it
it's very
forgiving you know you you know it's not
that's one of the things i've learned
with salts is that it's not very
forgiving and typically the environment
that you have to create to
utilize salts efficiently is not
necessarily the
environment that i'm trying to create
yeah being like rock wool and things
like that well you eliminate so much of
the microbiology which a product like
biobiz especially
i always really liked that as a liquid
when i used liquids too it was one of my
favorites
because the biology aspect you're
feeding the soil yeah if you start with
an amended soil like
power flower back in the day i loved bio
biz with pi power flower because that
you know rich sugary
it's kind of a mild nutrient really it
really is kind of a mild nutrient it's
definitely not something you're going to
burn a plant with i mean you could
probably pour the product straight into
the plant it wouldn't
it wouldn't burn the pro the plant we're
not recommending that at home but you
probably could
and that's always been my mo when it
comes to feeding though i've never been
a huge fan of pushing the ppms to the to
the brink into the stress point like i
like to get close
right you know but i've always kind of
been more more or less on the like you
know on a moderate strength nutrient
regimen and then obviously i've always
been big on t's too which i feel like
naturally kind of get your get that
extra charge in there yeah you know but
through a fermentation process yeah
absolutely um what i'm seeing
with everybody scaling so large so fast
that i'm seeing people start running
into problems with teas and things like
that because there's
employee turnover there's you know
whatever the different factors may be so
so typically when i go to a farm
i'm not pushing t's and things because
that's a whole nother learning curve
that somebody needs to learn he's like
let's get let's get the ship rated you
know let's get you going
and once you start you know seeing some
you know ground being covered and seeing
some increase in some things then let's
veer off and try some high-level stuff
right yeah create a sense of stability a
platform to build on that's right
something we say all the time to you
know we get phone calls from new growers
daily at royal gold and it's like hey
start simple
don't like try everything at once
because how do you really know what
you're doing at that point like you
don't know whether this product worked
or that product worked or this one is
effective or
what burned your plant if you're
throwing all of these things at it all
the time so
i completely agree with that perspective
of like
whoa whoa whoa let's strip out the duff
let's get to a baseline
and create some new avenues towards
improving it it's it's k it's the truth
um i hear a lot um you know cut your
costs on nutrients cut your costs on
food and honestly like if you want
optimum
results would do you starve
you know would you starve the cow if you
want the best meat no you probably would
i see what my biggest thing that i see
when i go to all these different farms
that i've been is procedure
they just lack procedure
which causes
more labor cost and chaos and chaos so i
feel like my mindset when i go to farms
is typically let's get a procedure going
we're not going to starve your plants
because it costs money to feed them
we're going to starve your labor
because it costs money to feed that too
because it does yeah you know we get
complete procedure in place
you know you have these milestone
targets that you're going to have to hit
every single harvest so after the second
one it's muscle memory
and then you guys are off and running
and
yeah that's that's really interesting
because with feeding and i'm you know
kind of equating this in my head as we
speak
there's
diminishing returns at some point yes
you want to feed you need to feed i'm a
big plant feeder i want to push it
but there is a point especially at scale
where it hits diminishing returns
where okay i'm giving plants nutrients
now
that they aren't able to consume in a
realistic time it's washing out it's
being consumed by microbiology that's
not effectively contributing to
real-time plant growth
you can overdo it
and the same is true of labor and that's
something we're seeing in humboldt
county big time
in this
crazy press on mom and pop farmers that
have been doing it forever
they're having to eliminate labor
everywhere nobody can afford the labor
because it's a diminishing return you're
paying all this money for these people
to be out there
stripping the plants giving all this
care
but
the cost per pound is so low now we have
to find ways
to prop the farmers up and they have to
find ways to cut those costs and
there's a diminishing return in over
feeding and over labor and over
application of anything yeah right
that's a good good generalization of it
for sure absolutely
no it's true
um
yeah i think that
there's so many the stakes are so high
now
right you know
there's no time to mess around
there's no time to have that bro that's
you know kind of a lazy guy but he's
your bro
so like you know i'll keep them on
you know there's those days are it's a
shame but
the culture is being stripped away
to
you know
some degree
and that's and that's where we're seeing
it right
yeah and i
like what you said there it is a lot of
people that are making hard decisions
for people that they care about and
saying hey man
i'm sorry i can't afford to employ you
anymore i can't afford to have you live
here on the farm and like work hard for
the pushes but like kick your feet up
for you know four months of the six
month
grow season and
they're hard decisions being made
by people that really care about each
other and that's one of the things that
we're really fighting hard to kind of
help
right the ship with measure s and now
everybody's trying to get to sacramento
to start looking at taxation because
these are
decisions that are affecting
the overall impact economically and
socially of cannabis on the communities
in northern california
[Music]