welcome to the Church of
C welcome to Kelly High episode 68 soy
Cowboy part two the conscientious
objector after enlisting in the US Navy
and spending a year at the Naval Air
Technical Training Center in Millington
Tennessee I managed to get station close
to home at the Naval Air St Point muo
search and rescue division while there I
put a band together with three friends
and three female Thai background
singers during my fourth year in the
Navy and a few years with the band I got
orders to a munition ship that would be
going to the first Gulf War I found this
turn of events unacceptable according to
what I believed and applied for
discharge as a conscientious
objector this episode has been one of
the most difficult to write and read due
to the heaviness of the material and so
I tried not to edit that heaviness out
the story deals with internal struggles
in the band and a personal relationship
that developed as well as my ordeal with
the United States
Navy
[Music]
two years after that first so Cowboy
performance KCRW I was still in the US
Navy an enlisted man with the rank of E5
Aviation Electronics technician second
class
nicoletti the year before I had
graduated from the University of lever
with a bachelor's degree in business
management briefly i' thought about my
possibilities as an officer in the Navy
but due to my age of 32 only cryptology
was open to me and I would be taught
Russian and I wasn't into Russian or
cryptology even though I do love
[Music]
languages and other significant events
were developing in my life as I said in
episode 64 relationships developed in
the band and let me reiterate it is not
good to be involved with band members of
the opposite sex because if the
relationship falls apart someone will
have to leave the B and and in our cases
it wasn't the guys that left which meant
new background singers would have to be
found and
auditioned
take
[Music]
I something smells
good and so I must now confess to being
the first to have a relationship with
one of the girls after a soy Cowboy
rehearsal at my mom's garage one day I
asked candy out to lunch and somehow
that took off she had an apartment on
Serrano in Hollywood and I began
spending nights there and driving to
work 60 Mi to point meu in the mornings
and 60 Mi back in the evenings in my VW
van take
[Music]
home the band played new gigs and I was
writing more songs however my
relationship with Candi began to hinder
the smooth functioning of the band as
Candi developed a sense of Diva ship at
performances she had a commanding stage
presence setting her apart from the
other girls she had experience as a
singer and some notoriety in the local
Thai community at times she would carry
on a bit of banter on stage with Joe who
by this time had fully embraced his role
as the band's front man and who by now
was usually wearing a cowboy hat and
Boots making him appear taller than his
6'5 stature well boys you
ready let's Saddle Up This beast and
ride it
huh and as evidenced by that first show
on KCRW Joe had developed a stick around
his brand of Tai Western Exotica and was
at times quite
humorous but underneath the humorous
banter between Joe and candy there was
tension on the way to a gig One Time
Candy decided she was hungry and had to
have some pad tie at a restaurant while
the whole band was waiting for for us we
got to the gig about 45 minutes late and
what was left of the crowd was restless
and the rest of the band was
[Music]
Furious a year into the band's
progression from that first kcr W gig
opportunities
developed T dandar Singh the famous
director then a student at artart Center
Pasadena approached us about making a
video of lily pads and rockcod as his
graduation project from the film
department he had enlisted a whole crew
of other Art Center students to help
[Music]
himboy however my relationship with
candy was full of Sound and Fury and on
weekends we would go to the Thai temple
in North Hollywood called wat Thai and
get food and hang out a bit with friends
but we frequently fought over my
autonomy she didn't want me going
anywhere without her which I found not
acceptable as a condition for a normal
relationship and so ironically I married
her in a
dream and
far from here
[Music]
here
please set me
free from these
chain
iar
fre originally when I listed in the Navy
I had signed up for six years made way
through the fourth year after having
been working at the search and rescue
unit at Point Meo helping save lives I
was given orders to a munition ship
based in San Diego this this is when
George Bush Senior was making plans to
invade Kuwait and Iraq to stop Saddam
Hussein's aggression
there a munition ship is a cargo ship
that stores all the bombs and missiles
my helicopter would be loading those
Munitions onto other ships such as
aircraft carriers which essentially
would be assisting in killing people
quite 180° turn from a search and rescue
unit where my efforts were saving
people's
lives
[Music]
and all the while soy Cowboy set list
was growing as we wrote more
songs one day Chaz called me up and told
me he had come up with the framework of
a song he thought would work for the
band I went over to his place and he had
come up with a rhythm track featuring
acoustic and slide
guitars from his living room in Studio
City overlooking the valley we started
jamming on it I came up with the piano
part and the arrangement
jelled we recorded it and a new Rhythm
track was
born I went home with the cassette of
the rough track on the piano were some
postcards from changai a city in the
north of
Thailand the company that made the
postcards was called Art card Asia
it made high quality postcards with
beautiful photos of life in Northern
Thailand there was a postcard of poppies
being milk somewhere on a hillside in
the Golden Triangle an area in Northern
Thailand that borders blos and Burma
there was one of monks walking down a
street in their orange robes one of a
mountain Sunset there was one of
elephants and one of Mong children in
Hill tribe Village
setting they stirred memories of dark
Intrigue and dangerous
Adventure I started writing the song
became postcards from changai and was
the only song Chaz whose real name is
Charles po wrote for the band and
remains one of the most iconic soy
Cowboy Tunes to this day with no typ
parts at
[Music]
all poppies and elepants
really
sh back to my
orders I knew I didn't want any part of
the loading of bombs missiles and
ammunition a seed of an idea began to
form in my mind I would become a
conscientious objector as a Buddhist on
the grounds of Bad
Karma at that time there was only one
conscientious objector lawyer in Los
Angeles and after speaking with him he
wouldn't take my case I called Kenny
Miller the band's first manager who was
in law school at the time and he said he
didn't think it could be
[Music]
done but my convictions were just and my
intentions sincere and so I refused to
be
discouraged in the days following I went
to the law library on Bas and read every
previous case of conscientious objection
from all branches of the service there
were applications from chrisan
Christians of various denominations
Mormons and Jews but no
[Music]
Buddhists the application for
conscientious objection involved writing
responses to questions and then sitting
for interviews with various naval
officers the Navy chaplain the Navy
psychiatrist the judge African general
commonly referred to as a Jag who was
the Navy lawyer the base commander who
was a full bird captain and my immediate
supervisor Don oeline who as I mentioned
in episode 64 was a cool
[Music]
guy I wrote the application and gave it
to Personnel about a month after having
received orders to the mician ship the
application put a halt to my transfer
and unfortunately the advance I had
received to move to San Diego where the
ship was based would have to be paid
back before my time at point meu was up
in case my application was successful it
would be subtracted from my salary
leaving me with no pay until it was paid
off which essentially meant that my Navy
paychecks were a thing of the
[Music]
past that meant candy and I would have
to move out of the apartment on Sano I
would clandestinely move her into my
Barracks room and hope no one found out
luckily at the time I had no roommate
and it was a large room as Barracks go
with three
[Music]
beds when word of my application broke
around SAR Hilo half of the guys were
asking me what do you mean Bad Karma the
other half were telling me right on
nicoletti go for
[Music]
it during this time I was driving down
to charmley park a little north of zumma
Beach and South south from the base it
was a great place for meditating hiking
and reading a book I bought at the bod
tree Bookshop in Hollywood called the
Buddha and his teachings by a monk named
NADA the chapter on Karma became my
favorite not just because my application
involved Karma as a reason for my
conscientious objection but because it
broke Karma down into various categories
and explain the various aspects of
actions in life as they related to the
whole of one's exist
[Music]
distance and occasionally I took one hit
of weed at the beginning of a weekend
because drug testing was random in the
Navy and there was always a possibility
of getting busted on a p test that would
be
unacceptable the hit was however very
therapeutic those afternoons alone in
charmly park sitting on a rock amidst
the grass and trees with a view of the
ocean below were beautiful and poignant
they were grounding
and had a way of putting me in touch
with my
life at the end of the last month on
Serrano candy and I moved out of the
apartment and put some things in storage
and then I moved her into the
barracks the room was close to an exit
and the building itself was quiet we
managed to pull it off for about a month
and then one day while I was working
down at SAR Hilo hanger there was an
inspection of the rooms by a master
chief I can only imagine the expression
on his face when he opened the door and
found Candi
there when I got back to the barracks
after work Candi told me what had
happened and there was a note to go see
the master chief who as it turned out
was a kindly Filipino guy and he
politely told me that I had to move
candy out of the barracks he didn't
write me up or sign any
punishment and right around this time we
found out candy was
pregnant I told my mom about the turn of
events and she told lesie our nextd door
neighbor the next thing I knew lesie had
offered to loan me her Toyota camper it
was a small pickup truck with a camper
mounted on it it had a bathroom a mini
fridge a sink and a stove and the bed
was over the cab of the truck it was
kind of cozy a little cramped but candy
and I managed to make it home for a
while at night I'd pull into the Navy
Credit Union parking lot
and plug into an electrical outlet
there there were RV stations down toward
the beach on base and we could empty the
Wastewater and fill up with fresh
water this lasted for a while it was
like an adventure like camping out it
was 1989 and during this time I started
being interviewed about my application
for conscientious
objection
first was the Navy chaplain Who as a
religious man questioned me about the
sincerity and origins of my Buddhist
beliefs when I had originally done my
readings at the law library on base I
noticed many of the previous applicants
had letters from clergy testifying to
their
veracity I had had years of association
with the Thai temple in North Hollywood
and knew a few of the monks personally
even before I met
candy I had formed a c team with Ed
Stone who was my mentor in the early
days of Thailand and we competed at
tournaments at wat Tha as the temple was
called to craw is a game like volleyball
but played with the feet and the ball
was made from woven cane strips
resembling a soccer ball about 6 in in
diameter it is played over a 5 foot high
net also at wat Thai I had taken a Thai
language class for foreigners and I won
a trophy for being the top student
student in that class I met two guys Jim
FID aaly and Michael didrick who were
fans of soy cowboy and who became close
friends after that
class Michael Dietrich was and is an
animator who drew many iconic flyers for
the band years later he won a few amys
one for Phineas and
Ferb Jim faly was an artist who held
events and parties at his large Loft
downtown off Molina Street near the
Fourth Street
Bridge rest in peace
Jim the mind is
incomprehensible exceedingly
subtle it wanders whatever it
desires
therefore let the wise aspirant watch
over the
mind a well-guarded mind brings
happiness and so when I was putting my
application together I asked Som an
English-speaking monk of Pakistani
descent if the Abbot who did not speak
English would write me a letter Som
talked to the Abbott and he asked me to
give them a framework for a letter and
they would add to it and the Abbott
would sign
it and as I sat across from the chaplain
I noticed he had the letter from the
Abbot in my file
[Music]
I explained to him while having been
born into a Catholic Family I always
believed in
karma which was basically a summation of
all of one's actions good or bad and
then having married a Buddhist after I
joined the military my beliefs in
Buddhist tenants had become stronger I
told him working at SAR Hilo was in line
with my beliefs because I was helping
save lives on the other hand working on
a munition ship preparing for war was
totally against them in other words
helping any war effort was not right
action according to the Buddhist
eight-fold
path before we go too much further allow
me to outline some of the qualifying
criteria for applicants according to the
armed services
directives one burden of proof
applicants bear the burden of proving
their claims of conscientious subjection
as grounds for
separation they must show by clear and
convincing evidence that their belief is
honest sincere and deeply
held two applicants proof of moral and
ethical
beliefs applicants must show that moral
and ethical beliefs are against
participation in War of any form primary
factors a a primary factor to be
considered is the sincerity with which
the belief is held great care must be
exercised in determining whether
asserted beliefs are honestly and
genuinely held sincerity is determined
by a partial evaluation of the
applicant's thinking and living in its
totality past and
[Music]
present B care must be exercised in
determining the Integrity of belief and
the consistency of application
C information presented by applicants
should be convincing enough that their
personal history reveals views and
actions strong enough to demonstrate the
belief in which the conscientious
objection is based is the primary
controlling force in his or her life and
that expediency or avoidance of military
service is not the basis of their claim
and D the conduct of the applicant in
particular his or her outward
manifestation of the beliefs asserted
will be carefully examined and given
substantial weight in evaluating the
[Music]
application the Navy guidelines also
state that after the interview the
chaplain will submit a written report
including the chaplain's opinion as to
the nature and basis of the applicant's
claim and sincerity and depth of
conviction the chaplain's report must
also include reasons for the conclusions
contained within the
[Music]
report I had submitted a clear and
well-written application which addressed
these issues of belief history and
development of belief in my current life
demonstrating adherence to my
belief three of the questions to answer
on the application were what do you
believe about participation in war
two how did your beliefs develop and
when did they become incompatible with
the military three how does your life
reflect those
[Music]
beliefs over the next few months the
Navy psychiatrist interviewed me to
check my mental health the Navy Jag
interviewed me so to see if he could
poke any holes in my story and lastly
the captain of the base interviewed
me he was an understanding man and
during the interview wasn't
condescending in any way his questions
were much the same as anyone else's and
pertained to verifying the sincerity of
my
application when the captain's interview
was done I felt a sense of closure I was
fairly certain my application would be
successful
music
in October of ' 89 I was informed that
my application was indeed successful and
I was to be discharged in
December on the 13th day of December
1989 I was honorably discharged from the
United States Navy and awarded their
certificate of honest and faithful
service along with a Good Conduct
[Music]
Medal it was a quiet Affair at personnel
and having been honorably discharged I
remained with all benefits
[Applause]
intact
I never regretted my time in the Navy
especially working at SAR Hilo point meu
with such outstanding people let me
first shout out to Senior Chief Don
oeline a great supervisor and a very
cool human being as I mentioned in
episode 64 he helped me with some
difficult troubleshooting on the
intercom of one of the H
46s he was an avionic Tech as well with
many years of experience on the
helicopter he approved every reasonable
request I had such as appearing live on
KCRW in the middle of a work day a great
guy who had a sense of humor that was at
times insightful and at other times full
of
irony I remember reading him one of my
essays written during my undergraduate
studies in business
management
there was a pilot Lieutenant Commander
as he was a Vietnam era helicopter pilot
who could be seen wandering through the
offices in our Hangar collecting
aluminum cans out of trash bins for
recycling he was the ranking officer at
SAR Hilo and yet somehow you knew he was
never going to make
commander and yet so did he I
believe Mr as drove a 196 Ford Falcon
Ranchero and it was one of our
Pilots Mike chinsky one of the rescue
swimmers and a friend of mine with whom
I am still in touch related the story
about a flight he was on with the
lieutenant commander piloting one Sunday
they were about 100 miles out from point
muu when a filter chip indicator popped
yellow with a hint of red on one of the
Transmissions if a transmission fails on
a helicopter the rotor sees up and the
helicopter drops like a
stone as wanted to put the helicopter
down in the water but Mike was sure he
didn't want the embarrassment of having
to be rescued by the Coast Guard and so
he talked Mr as into flying low and slow
back to point muu and somehow they made
it and there was the hot shot an apis
grad Lieutenant JP McAn he was a partyer
a good pilot and your All-American type
I remember being weightless once in the
back of the helicopter with Manan at the
stick
I had friends as well who worked with me
most of whom were risky swimmers I was
more of a runner and I got a whole group
of them running up to the radar towers
with me we would take two cars to the
top and leave one there and drive back
down in my VW van and park next to a
farmhouse and run up the road to the
towers the radar towers are on the
Northern tip of the Santa Monica
Mountains overlooking the base below and
the Pacific Ocean to the South and West
Bill Darlington and Joe hollandsworth
were two of the rescue swimmers who
became my good friends Joe used to come
into town with me in the early days of
scouting for singers and we stayed at my
mom's house after night spent eating
Thai food and drinking
beer bill was the guy who originally
started jogging with me to the radar
towers and who convinced the rest of the
guys to come along
we are still in touch to this
day I must also thank the civilian women
who worked in the admin offices of the
hangar and who took care of paperwork
for the
division there was one who taught me how
to use a word processor so I could get
my assignments done while I was working
on my undergraduate classes at the
University of lever's on base
extension I also use their computers to
write my coo
application I can't remember their names
by the day of my discharge Kenny Miller
my friend who had now become a lawyer
and who was the band's first manager
sublet me his upstairs back house on ker
by ventur and Sherman Oaks and candy and
I moved
in soy Cowboy stayed together until 1993
and briefly got back together for the
second album in
2012 taram made the video lily pads and
rockot in 1990 and then in 1991 went on
to direct the video for Losing My
Religion by RM and won the 1991 MTV
Award for best
video he still makes commercials to this
day you might have seen one recently
about a trojan horse being rejected and
falling off a cliff after being unmasked
by the it
lady he also made a few featurelength
films one with Jennifer Lopez in 2000
called the
cell an Englishman named caruzo Fuller
signed us to what turned out to be a bad
record deal little did we know his
record company based in England had no
distribution and his main goal was to
sell us to a big label something that
never
happened but we were happy to get
advances and somehow Overlook the Clause
giving carizo the rights to the songs
for 20
years we since have recovered those
rights and would appreciate it if you
stream soy Cowboy
247365 during the recording of the first
album Candi got into an argument with
Joe and got herself kicked out of the
band I felt curiously relieved and knew
our marriage was going to be the next
thing to
go however candy and I have an amazing
son Andrew who is now 33 and living in
New York City
after candy left the band A friend of
Pras named Sarah joined the band at that
time she worked as a waitress atlai
restaurant on Van eyes near Ventura
Boulevard Sarah was the tallest of our
background singers and somehow I ended
up in a relationship with the tallest
guy in the band Joe which lasted about a
year or two and didn't end well
[Music]
either Tim had a brief fling with Leela
which blossomed on a NorCal tour and
didn't last long especially after Tim
met Leela's husband who we knew nothing
about and who luckily knew nothing about
Tim as it turned out in the end I wasn't
the only guy in the band that violated
the sane policy of no relationships with
band
[Music]
members
love it when Night Lights slow down in
the baby Street below it seems as though
they are my friend calling me back again
and
again I Left My Home In all I
know to live beneath the warm light
glow light come tonight and so do I
something
yeah
come so do
I impossible to
[Music]
explain warm bright
lights
[Music]
you've been listening to cigh episode 68
soy Cowboy part two the conscientious
objector this is the sixth episode in a
new series called a work in progress a
retrospective of
Adventures written by Vince
nicoletti C High's theme written and
recorded by Vince nicoletti Jordan Webb
and namir
blade cigh podcast and theme or
copywritten and the logo is
trademarked please donate to cigh at
patreon.com calhigh
laa like follow And subscribe to C High
on YouTube and we are on YouTube at C
High
8901 email us with any questions to C
High podcast at
gmail.com or on Instagram at calhigh laa
on all podcast Platforms in audio Cali
high is a chen on eco
production stay safe and be
blessed