[Music]
ah yes oh when you wake up and you feel
like you need a little upper or when
you're down and outer and you need to
get a little higher if you feel like you
need a blessing now and you're feeling a
little high today welcome to the church
welcome to Cali High episode 63
serendipity
in this episode chenzo meets his new
partner Molly and flies to Miami to meet
Rick hirschman founder of the now world
famous Rick's Cafe Negril and then a
chance encounter on the Sunset Strip
with two guys sporting dreadlocks who
turned out to be two of the world's
prominent reggae musicians Stephen
katkori and Richard Daly of the band
Third World
lastly a blessed memory of smoking with
bunny rugs
it is a story of his serendipitous chain
of events linked by my time in Jamaica
and the threads of that experience
weaving the tapestry of life
episode 63 takes place the year after
episode 61 Jamaica
and is the third in a new series called
a work in progress a retrospective of
Adventures
episode 63 is dedicated to the memory of
Molly Harper William bunny rugs Clark
and Rick hirschman of Rick's Cafe Negril
[Music]
after coming home from Jamaica in 1975 I
rented a room in a house in Laurel
Canyon owned by a guy named Reuben who
had made his fortune as a clothing
designer with a small shop on the Sunset
Strip during the 60s and who now rented
out the rooms in his house
the house was on little Laurel Canyon
between the Canyon Country Store and
Mount Olympus Drive
there were two girls and a guy renting
rooms in the house as well
one of the girls was named Molly Harper
a pretty Midwest girl from Peoria
Illinois who had moved to Hollywood in
search of a more Cosmopolitan lifestyle
while living at Rubens I sold cannabis
to make a living
Molly Harper had no job apparently but
liked to shop and go to auctions
exhibits and museums she also liked fine
dining
she read voraciously and while never
having attended college she was well
educated she drove a powder blue Volvo
and frequently wore a long black pleated
Kenzo dress with gray shoulder straps
she called the Kenzo dress her uniform
[Music]
Molly was fun to hang out with and had a
great sense of style and was
knowledgeable in the Fine Arts and Music
we hit it off
she turned me on to David hockney Robert
rauschenberg and George Gershwin she was
22 and I was 19.
I eventually found out the source of
Molly's money which had been a well-kept
secret and a mystery to the others in
Reuben's house
Molly had collected a bunch of money
from a settlement after being hit by a
Cadillac while on her Vespa
the impact broke her femur and Center
flying 100 feet
the mystery of Molly's money remained
unknown to me however until we went into
business together
Reuben's house was a wild Affair Reuben
was an older Argentinian gay man with a
tall young Afro-American lover named Don
who lived in the house with ribbon on
the weekends the whole house would go
out to gay bars in Santa Monica
Boulevard and as I was interested in
Mali I would go along it was a wild time
I was always pretty sure I was the only
straight guy in the club which didn't
seem to matter and I had a blast with
the girls
one day in late spring of 76 I got a
call from Rick hirschman it had been
about a year since we had met and hung
out at his now famous Rick's Cafe in
Negril Jamaica
Rick was now calling from Miami and said
he had good Colombian and did I want to
come to Miami and pick up a load I said
sure
for a while Molly had been watching my
business and was thinking about a
partnership to keep her money from
dwindling
this was the perfect time
we became 50 50 partners and by that
time we were also lovers
[Music]
I arranged the deal with Rick and bought
two brand new blue Samsonite suitcases
the kind with the three-digit combo lock
took a bunch of cash and flew to Miami
Rick picked me up at the airport and
went back to a house on a canal
somewhere in an affluent Miami
neighborhood
the sunlight was so bright tropical and
blue kind of blew my mind compared to
the California sunshine
foreign
grade greenish Brown Colombian who
wasn't the best but it was good I paid
365 per pound
the block wasn't too pressed the buds
were uniform and intact and in fact they
had a pleasant flavor and were strong
we took apart the bail in sections
sealed them up in black trash bags and
packed them into the two suitcases Rick
drove me back to the airport and I
checked my two blue Samsonite suitcases
filled with Colombian weed right at the
counter
in those days there were no x-ray
machines or sniffing dogs and I picked
up the suitcases from the turnstile at
LAX
Molly was waiting with the Volvo and we
drove back to Laurel Canyon mission
accomplished
that was the beginning of my partnership
with Molly which turned into my first
marriage and at the time of this writing
our son Eric is 42.
Molly is sadly no longer with this
I sold the 36 pounds and we moved out of
Reubens and rented a house on the corner
of Mount Olympus Drive and Laurel Canyon
we had a good thing going
one day soon after moving to the new
house I went down to get an avocado
sandwich at the source a health food
restaurant on the Sunset Strip next to
Carney's
in those days it had a big dirt parking
lot
while in the parking lot I noticed two
guys about my age with dreadlocks
I asked them if they were Rastafari and
from Jamaica
the answer was yes on both accounts and
I immediately invited them back to my
house to smoke a spleet
back at the house we introduced
ourselves rolled a few with the
Colombian from Rick and smoked them
these two young Jamaicans were Stephen
katkori and Richard Daly guitarist and
bass player of the band Third World
the band is still touring today and in
2019 released more work to be done their
21st studio album which is nominated for
a Grammy and produced by Damian Marley
I didn't know they were musicians
and after smoking they asked me if I
wanted to come down to Island records on
Sunset at Genesee a few blocks away and
listen to their new album which was
their first
Island Records was in a tudor-style
two-story house with a brick foundation
and a red tile roof with brown trim
we went in and there were records lining
the wall in a hall which led to a living
room
we walked in and sat down and Cat pulled
a green album from somewhere titled
third world
I was blown away to have met some cool
guys from Jamaica and they turned out to
have a reggae band wow
kept at the record on the turntable
right there in the comfortable living
room of Island records and we listened
to third world's first self-titled album
The Green album
some of the songs on that album are
brand new beggar cere masagana and
slavery days
it blew my mind in a way I wasn't
expecting
right afterwards I went to tower on my
way home and bought the album
it quickly became a hit with all my
friends and Associates and I could
hardly go anywhere where there wasn't a
copy of that album front and center of
everyone's record stack or on the
turntable
the next year cat and Richie called me
when they got to town and I went to see
third world perform at the Starwood it
was a local Club down at Crescent
Heights in Santa Monica Boulevard
I remember being impressed with the band
and as a keyboard player was really
fascinated with Michael ebo Cooper's
reggae style keyboards
he was the first reggae keyboard player
I had ever seen
by this time the original lead singer on
their first album Milton trilli Hamilton
had been replaced by William bunnyruggs
Clark
the day after the show I helped Richie
buy a miniature TV from sami's camera in
Westwood and later that evening the band
came over to my apartment
said it was 96 degrees
in the shed
Molly and I had moved from the house on
Laurel Canyon after a slightly
unfortunate run in with the cops and
were living in an apartment up on
roscomare Road in Bel Air
now a little background to this story
by 77 most of the Colombian herb flow
was shut down by the U.S Coast Guard off
the coast of Florida
which spawned a cocaine epidemic and the
first California seedless was making its
appearance at four times the price of
seeded Colombian
I had a couple of ounces
the buds were beautifully multi-colored
green gold and red and they had a citrus
floral fragrance and taste they were
Stoney too
times were spare compared to the
Colombian days I was selling smaller
amounts and making less
there I was with a few ounces and the
band comes in and everyone introduces
themselves bunny rugs the lead singer
asked if he could roll one
I handed him the bag and before I knew
it he had rolled a half ounce Spleef and
was lighting it I bit my tongue and we
smoked that hundred dollars belief in
today's dollars that would be 489.76
however the price of cannabis today is
so different the analogy is flawed
but today I am still honored with the
invaluable memory of smoking with bunny
rugs
years later in 2014 I sat with bunny
Ricci and cat in a motel in Burbank when
they came to play Reggae night at the
Hollywood Bowl
we reminisced and laughed about that
Spleef
a few months later I went to see third
world play in Agoura Hills
they had a new singer AJ Brown
while the show was playing Heather third
world's manager told me bunny rugs had
died
that was a shock
when I saw him before the bull show he
was very sick unbeknownst to me
R.I.P William bunny rugs Clark
when I get to heaven we'll smoke a giant
Spleef
is today I stand to the victim
after our deal in Miami Rick Hershman
moved up into an apartment building down
the street from our apartment on
roscomare and lived there a few months
he was having hard times with a heroin
problem
as many people were back then
since then I lost touch with him and
haven't been able to track one word of
his whereabouts or existence there's not
one photo I can find of him anywhere
online
and I have a hunch he is not with us
anymore
R.I.P Rick if that's the case
I would like to know for certain however
if anyone listening knows about Rick's
existence or demise please contact me
I have interviewed Richard Daly twice
for Kelly High episode 7 and 32 7 is
only audio but 32 is a zoom interview on
YouTube
last year I was about to drive to Ojai
to interview cat
but was positive for covid and wasn't
able to do so
we'll try to get that one soon
[Music]
the only one you're not the only one
yeah
[Music]
it is
you're not the only one
you're out there somewhere feeling
lonely
you're not the only one
so come on inside and tell me how you're
feeling
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you've been listening to Cali High
episode 63 Serendipity Serendipity was
written produced and recorded by Vince
nicoletti it is the third in a new
series called a work in progress I want
to thank third world for permission to
use their music we heard bits of sedema
sagana 96 degrees in the shade and
you're not the only one featuring Damian
Marley
incidental music by Vince nicoletti
Kelly High's theme written and recorded
by Vince nicoletti Jordan Webb and nimir
blade
Kelly High podcast and theme are
copywritten and the logo is trademarked
music over end credits I don't know what
to say by Vince nicoletti
please donate to Cali high at
patreon.com calihila
please like follow And subscribe to Cali
High on YouTube email us with any
questions to Cali High podcast
gmail.com we're on Instagram at calihila
and all podcast Platforms in audio
Kelly has a chenzo Nico production stay
safe and be blessed
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you