[Music]
ah
yes
when you wake up
and you feel like you need a little
upper
or when you're down and out
and you need to get a little higher
if you feel like you need a blessing now
and you feel a little high today
welcome to the church
to kelly high episode 53 i'm your host
chen zonika and this week our guest is
michael katz executive director of the
mendocino cannabis alliance considering
recent media reports which have
described a collapsing cannabis industry
in california due to over taxation
we reach out to mendocino cannabis
alliance's executive director michael
katz for an update on this potentially
devastating news we find out why the
cannabis community of legacy farmers in
northern california are up in arms about
cultivation and excise taxes and other
challenges they face we talk about the
equity grant program and the
difficulties it is having due to
mismanagement and understaffing in
mendocino county katz has many years of
experience in the cannabis industry
and the pr industry as well and is the
mca's first full-time executive director
okay callie hi is blessed to be here
with michael katz of the mendocino
cannabis alliance how are you michael
all right thanks so much for having me
it's great to have you man and thanks
for appearing
um
so
first question who is the mendocino
cannabis alliance
sure so the mendocino cannabis alliance
is the premier cannabis trade
association in mendocino county it was
founded in 2019 a coming together of two
different trade groups in mendocino one
that was focused primarily on business
development economic development getting
the mendocino name out into the world as
far as quality of products and branding
and marketing and the other one was
focused more on local and state policy
advocacy efforts and so those two
organizations combined to form mca in
2019 i was fortunate enough to have
moved to mendocino in 2018 and been
involved as a founding board member in
that organization and then uh came on as
full-time executive director in november
of 2020 we represent uh
over 130 individual small businesses
the vast majority of which are licensed
small cannabis cultivators here in
mendocino but we also have members who
are in other sectors we represent
several retailers and distributors just
folks throughout the cannabis supply
chain
and folks who want to see
our cannabis communities survive and
thrive in this challenging time so um we
have great members we have great
sponsors who help to support our efforts
and you know we're
fortunate to be able to have a full-time
executive director which is me uh
working to advocate on behalf of our
members uh because there's a lot going
on and and it's hard for folks who are
farming and who are involved in the
other challenging parts of the cannabis
business to focus on all of these things
at once yeah i hear you and the reason
we're talking today is pretty much taxes
and we'll get to that in a minute
so
now
you're the mendocino cannabis alliance
what is the mendocino cannabis program
so the mendocino cannabis program is the
county department that administers the
mendocino uh cannabis program
which is which is the program through
which
our licensed operators have been
entering into compliance so
their the program opened and accepted
applications from people who had
previously been cultivating cannabis
throughout the county and then those
operators have been in this uh
application
gauntlet since then four years four and
a half years many of them
still trying to get to a county annual
permit but the program has changed
departments several times it began in ag
they were accepting paper applications
at that time then it moved to planning
and building services and that they'll
you know there's a lot of lost
applications and
people having to submit four or five
times the same paperwork uh and so this
is the latest iteration of how the
county is managing cannabis and uh it is
a stand been made into a standalone
department uh and so they are kind of in
charge of administering the cannabis
program on behalf of the board of
supervisors
right
okay so we're gonna come back to them
but let's go on to last week there so
last week there was a protest in
sacramento to bring attention to the
strain on farmers in the industry in
general caused by the what cultivation
tax and tax in general right
sure so it was uh the the rally last
week was put on primarily by supernova
women which is uh an equity advocacy
group based out of the bay area and we
uh as mca were able to participate
because origins council who is our state
level advocacy organization made up of
trade associations from six different
heritage cultivating regions was a part
of organizing but at the lead of
supernova women and so there were two
primary requests at the rally last week
one was a removal of the cultivation tax
and one was uh a removal of the excise
tax for equity retailers uh throughout
the state and so you know those are
there two areas where we see
extensive taxation that does not occur
in the unlicensed market that is you
know really putting the license market
behind oh yeah and at a competitive
disadvantage and so you know the the
equity community the people of color uh
and the bipac community who have
struggled severely at the hands of the
war on drugs have a lot in common in
that arena with the small operators who
have been subject to the war on drugs as
cultivators in the northern california
region you know humble the mendocino
have some of the most uh
examples of paramilitary activity uh
towards the eradication of cannabis uh
in the state and so you know ongoing to
this day
ongoing you know sadly um and so there
is you know there's still a lot of
issues to be worked out but it was it
was very
uh uplifting and inspiring to see these
communities come together at the state
capitol and call for this essential tax
change together
and so for our listeners can you just
tell us how much is
the cultivators tax per ounce
so right now uh per pound of cannabis
it's about a dollar it's about 160 a
little bit over 160 dollars per pound
and that went up just this when the new
year started it went up from what was
about 155 dollars
and so that tax is actually tied to
inflation and whereas a year ago
when or more than a year ago when it was
being considered to implement that
increase of tax it was not increased
this year the increase went ahead and so
unfortunately because of the
corresponding market crash what it means
right now is that that tax of 160
dollars which maybe that used to be on
product that was selling for anywhere uh
at a thousand dollars a pound or over
you know so that's still a 15 you know
15 to 20 percent tax right there has now
shifted to since product is available is
selling on the market for between three
and five hundred dollars in some cases
we're looking at a fifty percent tax
uh on that product and so that's
unsustainable it would be unsustainable
in any industry but it's particularly
unsustainable in light of all the other
fees and licensing requirements that are
put upon these operators and
specifically in mendocino county none of
these cultivators have sites larger than
10 000 square feet so it's the smallest
of the small cultivation that is still
being treated like the largest of the
large and they don't have the resources
and they don't have the runway to you
know wait this out yeah and uh they
don't take into account the law of
supply and demand on the price
with the tax so it's just a fixed tax
yes and that's a challenge for us in
mendocino as well uh in our local tax
ordinance we have guaranteed minimum
requirements owed to the st owed to the
county
uh annually and so you know if you have
a 10 000 square foot permit but you're
only cultivating 5 000 square feet
you're still responsible to pay the full
minimum tax on the 10 000 square feet
whether or not you you are even
able to sell that product whether that
product experiences crop loss that tax
is just required to participate in the
program but the payment of that tax has
not resulted in any real services or
support for the folks who have been
paying it
and is there any other agricultural
product that has cultivator tax
not that we're aware of no yeah
and
okay that's kind of
unfair and so the excise tax then is
also your ex asking for that to be
removed as well yeah so the excise tax
is interesting because it comes at the
end of the supply chain but it has to be
paid before the product actually is sold
right so when a distributor is
transferring a product to a retailer
they're responsible to pay in advance
this 15 excise tax and it's either based
on a complicated formula if it's uh
wholesale pricing or a slightly less
complicated formula if it's retail
pricing but it breaks down to roughly a
wholesale product is going to be
marked up 27 percent to cover the excise
tax and the price the price at retail
winds up being marked up about 15 but
the result of this and all of these
taxes that we're talking about wind up
with prices to the consumer that are you
know 30 to 50 percent higher than
they're paying in the unregulated market
and so when we're guessing or estimating
that maybe there are you know eight or
nine
illicit shops compared to one license
shop and those options are providing way
discounted prices with products that to
uneducated consumers just look like
licensed cannabis products you're
putting the licensed community at
incredible disadvantage especially when
the intent of prop 64 as it was voted in
by
the people of california was to provide
a sustainable transition for these like
these existing businesses and to create
a california cannabis industry of small
and medium-sized businesses right now
instead what we're seeing is an
extinction event after extinction event
of these smaller businesses and if
there's not drastic measures taken soon
at the county and state levels we're
going to see a lot more people have to
leave the licensed market
and the black market is thriving at
least it is down here i got to tell you
i've you know in my
in the course of my job i've
tried to get interviews with some of
these people there's illegal distro
warehouses where there's
thousands of pounds moving you know with
several different distributors
sure yeah well first i just like to
recommend um you know uh it words uh are
so impactful these days we tend to try
to
uh not use the term black market because
we find that it contributes actually to
a culture of white supremacy like the
idea that like black market bad white
market good right right so you know
terms like illicit market unregulated
market traditional market just as a
general uh you know word across that out
of my question
yeah and then
yeah listed traditional unregulated
but yeah the the truth is that the
unregulated market has you know a
fraction of the
resource has a fraction of the
restrictions and bottlenecks that are
placed on folks in the licensed market
and as you point out i mean there have
been articles that have come out about
these so-called burner distros where
folks full well are operating businesses
that are not intending to be compliant
and you know ultimately potentially
impacting small operators who are
because as you know as we know as you
may know uh it's the distributor who's
responsible for remitting the
cultivation tax from the small farmer to
the state so if a distributor is
operating illegally and not remitting
that taxation ultimately that can come
back to harm the small operator and from
the articles that have been out there it
seems that this is uh there's awareness
that this is happening but there's very
little being done to to stop it you know
and so
we have been advocating for more and
more direct access opportunities for our
small farmers not to have to go through
this very convoluted expensive and
unreliable supply chain and be able like
any other small farmer in any other crop
or industry or sector to be able to sell
directly to consumers what they're
cultivating you know cannabis small
cannabis farmers uh
any cannabis farmer who can't afford uh
to set up a retail license
is
basically unable to
receive the full
value of their product at market they
are
by necessity required to work through
this entire supply chain that separates
them from the consumer and separates
them from the value that they're
producing and it's creating this uh you
know this untenable and unsustainable
situation yeah well wineries can sell
directly to the consumer you go to a
wine tasting event at the winery and you
can buy the wine right there right so
sure
[Music]
yeah sorry about that rural living it's
okay i just kept rolling what the hell
i'll edit that out later
so
yeah i was i was just kind of like
throwing out that rhetorical question i
mean the california wouldn't put up with
an illicit alcohol market right
sure well i mean i think that it is
important to note that we are still at
the very beginning of the end of
cannabis prohibition like cannabis right
prohibition exists we are not outside of
that paradigm just because we have a
state regulated program it's still not
legal in any uh meaningful sense i mean
there are there have been reductions in
criminal
charges that can be filed but that has
not solved the problem of people of
color being incarcerated at greater
numbers because of cannabis uh than not
and so you know we're still not seeing
the social justice or racial justice
that we would want to see from a truly
legalized cannabis community and so
uh yeah the the struggles that we face
are substantial and they're based
largely on that fact so it took a while
for
direct sales of alcohol you know that
was the thing too it didn't happen
immediately and yeah the cannabis
industry has many different uh voices in
it who are representing many different
constituencies you know we have the
small operators the legacy operators
we're trying to make the transition into
the new market you have the that
includes in both you know the rural and
urban areas of the state
all of whom were negatively impacted by
the war on drugs and continue to be to
this day
but you also have the kind of new
industry the outside capital the more
traditional business interests that are
trying to capitalize on a perceived
green rush and what that has done you
know with the oversupply and the the the
fact that the one acre cap that was
built into prop 64 was never
uh enforced or or in or made reality um
you know what we're seeing that right
now with the crash in the market and
unfortunately it hasn't led to
lower prices for consumers either
and it hasn't led to uh a reduction in
the illicit market and so you know it's
important to take a really
50 000 foot view of this system and see
how challenged it is and
we
and the different constituencies
certainly have different opinions on how
things should go and so it's really
about working with legislators and
regulators and trying to push the needle
in the right direction for for our
communities
and
how successful do you think your efforts
are going to be with getting rid of
those two taxes the excise and the the
cultivators tax
well i think that there is definitely
been a appetite expressed by the
governor's office for tax reform in
cannabis
uh you know it's it's a really
challenging time historically when it
comes to tax reform in cannabis in
california specifically around the
cultivation tax uh the challenge has
been that that money is earmarked
towards certain uses
and so the groups that align with those
uses you know labor uh for example um
are very
it's very important to them to make sure
that revenues that they have come to
count on are not decreased so that's you
know the in the governor's messaging you
know we understand that there's a desire
to address this but they're looking at
also having to maintain revenue
neutrality which is you know you know
somewhat of a challenge yeah we we're
hopeful that due to the budget surplus
the year-on-year budget surplus and the
fact that there is uh you know all of
these resources available that in order
to
save
this community that is so endangered
right now it's the
uh the heart and the backbone of
california's cannabis industry uh
drastic actions need to be taken so you
know we understand that there are
important goals and that it's important
to weigh them with the realities on the
ground and make sure that we don't lose
this industry before it's too late to
save it
well
it
seems to be in danger i noticed that
that
media is reporting the cannabis industry
is on the verge of collapse due to over
taxation where do you think we go from
here to solve this problem michael
well i think it's a combination of
things you know it is the state level uh
and there will be legislation that's
coming out for this year that is going
to address many of these topics you know
uh they're they're they're the
legislators and the regulators are very
aware of the challenges we have been
very vocal about our pain points at one
point the state uh was very clear about
asking for those and so we've been
providing them obviously there have been
there was a rally in sacramento last
week
there's a continued effort to engage
with the dcc and cdfw and um you know
related end agencies and with our
legislators and so we're very grateful
to origins council which as i mentioned
before is a trade association made up of
six different trade associations and
those are from humboldt nevada county
big sur trinity sonoma and mendocino and
together we actually create the largest
cannabis advocacy organization in the
state and so origins council is working
diligently on these key points because
they really affect hundreds and hundreds
and honestly thousands of stakeholders
that are in the licensed market right
now that are you know really need the
support of the state to be able to make
it through this transition yeah
well it's in the origins council they
also were we're working on an
appellations
program right
sure so yeah janine coleman who's the
executive director of the origins
council she is a co-founder of the
mendocino appellations project and was
integral in the working groups uh with
cdfw and the california growers
association uh
discussing appalachians and so yeah
origins council has been uh and the
leadership they're in have been a
strong voices in advocating for this
program and we're excited to see uh
certain uh regulatory uh updates being
considered you know the goal is not to
rush to market with uh this program the
goal is to
bring it in with all of the appropriate
safeguards make sure it's it's really
viewed uh internationally and
nationally as as the as a real thorough
program based on internationally
accepted standards yeah uh that will
give it some teeth you know and really
be able to put increased value behind
the products of our communities that we
already know are so valuable yeah that's
cool
so coming back to mendocino
what about the equity grant program
funds and who are they
designated for and
how is that going
sure so the the local equity program
is funded by the state and the equity
programs statewide are designed to
address negative impacts from the war on
drugs
and so
every county
or municipality has the opportunity to
provide to the state what's called a
needs assessment to determine what is
the need of the community how much uh
how much impact has the war on drugs had
to this community and what are their
needs to be able to try to alleviate
some of that damage and so through that
process which was spurred greatly by mca
our organization and
hannah nelson who is a
mca senior policy advisor and also just
a decades-long advocate uh in the legal
realm for civil rights and yeah i read
some of her writing
yeah she's she's an incredible
incredible advocate and our community is
truly lucky to have her
um and so
we
um
had put forward
uh proposals as a community uh through
mca as to how the equity program uh
should be administered and ultimately
the county went with uh some different
suggest different uh a route and to this
point there have been several edits made
to the program but unfortunately there
the funds that are earmarked to be
distributed uh among
our community have yet to be distributed
so there have been there are several
rounds of funding
our county was granted 2.2 million
dollars in the initial funding round and
to this point uh not only have none of
those funds actually been distributed
but it's
possible that by the end of february the
state has the ability to pull those
funds back if they have not actually
been provided to equity operators and so
we have been advocating for the removal
of barriers to get those funds
distributed
but you know certainly right now the
goal of the equity program is not being
met because the funds that are they're
not the county's funds they're the state
funds that are earmarked for these
individuals and the the program to
disperse them as set up by the county
has proven to be uh you know
yeah unable to meet the task at hand and
so
while there are people who have been
involved since february of last year in
this application process who still have
not seen a nickel and are still being
asked to resubmit documents yeah and
this is the mendocino uh cannabis
program uh administrators it's a
combination so the mendocino county
hired an outside group called elevate
impact
and they are the group that's the
external administrator now they
receive payment for their services
whether or not our grant funds are
distributed to my understanding uh and
about 10 of the grant funds is
allowed to be provided to the
administration of it so it's a
combination of that that outside entity
working uh with the mendocino cannabis
program but then beyond that there's
also the county council and the
different departments within the county
risk assessment all these different
things that are you know kind of
responsible to create this this chain to
enable the release of funds and
unfortunately it came to our attention
that that process to develop those
agreements even was not begun until it
was time to start giving them out to
applicants yeah and so we're behind the
eight ball uh a hundred percent and
really need swift action to make sure
that these funds are not lost and that
future funds that come in are able to be
distributed in a in a in an efficient
and effective way so they can meet the
goals of the program so did i hear this
correctly so the the outside entity that
came in to administer the program
gets like 250 grand to administer to the
program whether they even give out any
money or not
that's that's the agreement that they
have is that they are able to
you know receive up to 10 of the grant
funds to administer the program they
have several grant administrators
working on underwriters working on the
program uh you know emailing with the
applicants but there have been no direct
grant funds released
and what's the name of that entity uh
that is uh their elevate impact
men and the you know in in mendocino
county the website is elevate impact
mendo
uh and in you know they also apparently
uh operate equity programs in other
jurisdictions i'm not 100 familiar uh
what their track records are there you
know it's they're they're all very nice
people but we have yet to see any money
actually hit there hit the hands of the
applicants and it's certainly not all on
them it's a it's a function of the
county's program being understaffed
unfortunately you know unprepared to
address this as it was coming in with
all of the other things that are
happening and so there really is a
global uh issues there are global issues
that really need to be addressed and
this is just a symptom of those yeah
well
interesting i hope this all works itself
out and
i know that
any uh
recreational user as well as a medical
you know cannabis user
is experiencing
prices that
are unsustainable for them as consumers
even you know absolutely yeah people
have less and less resources yeah and if
we want to see the you know small
businesses survive in california
especially let's remember small cannabis
businesses do not have access to federal
relief funds right so any funding that's
come in as part of pandemic relief has
not gone to cannabis farmers let's also
remember they can't write cannabis taxes
off yeah 280e at the federal level
cannabis operators can't write off basic
business expenses that every other
business is able to so they're really
getting siphon they're really getting
siphoned from all sides
and what we need is is relief and
support you know for these small
businesses otherwise we're going to see
mass changes to the socioeconomic
fabrics of these small rural areas
and that you know that's going to be
really hard to address even harder than
it is today yeah well it's a big part of
the economy
well michael i want to thank you for
coming on cali high this morning
and we're going to check back in with
you
probably in a few months and see how
things are going is that okay
absolutely we'll be happy to keep you
posted hopefully we'll have some good
news at that time yeah i hope so and
hopefully i'll get up there and
check out all 150 of your farms
yeah it's beautiful up here in like you
know mid late summer
come on up we'll show you around okay i
will do that
excellent well thanks so much for having
me all right michael have a great day
cali high out
peace bro
[Music]
you've been listening to cali high
episode
with our special guest michael katz the
executive director of the mendocino
cannabis alliance i'm your host
chenzonico
michael katz can be found on ig at
mjk ultra
mendocino cannabis alliance can be found
at ig
at mendo.cannabis
on the web
mendocannabist.com all one word
outgoing music old cowhand from the rio
grande by johnny mercer performed by soy
cowboy from the 1991 released soy cowboy
kelly heist's photographer is haneen
nicoletti kalihi's theme written and
recorded by vince nicoletti jordan webb
and namire blade
kalihi's theme
podcast and logo are copywritten and
trademarked please donate to cali high
at patreon.com
calihighla
please like follow and subscribe
to cali high on youtube
email us with any questions to
calipodcast gmail.com we're on instagram
at cali high la
on all podcast platforms in audio kali
hai is a chenzo nico production stay
safe and be blessed
[Music]
cat hand
from the rio grande
that's me
yeah
and i came to
town
just to hear the van
[Music]
i know all the songs that the cowboys
know
about the big crowds
[Music]
oh
hey
[Applause]
[Music]
things
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
you