[Music]
welcome to Cali High episode 64. soy
cowboy
this is the fourth in a new series
called a work in progress a
retrospective of Adventures
in this episode I joined the Navy get
stationed at Naval Air Station Point
Magoo and decide to put a band together
with the help of some friends
this episode ends in a recording of the
first performance of the band soy Cowboy
live on Tom schnabel's Morning Becomes
Eclectic at KCRW
thank you
prologue
during my travels in Thailand from 1981
to 1983. I fell in love with Thai
culture and Thai music
at some point I realized the sound of
the female Thai voice had a captivating
quality about it not only in song But
even in speech
it was something about the way Thai
women emphasize tones differently than
taiman which made their voices Musical
in 1985 I joined the Navy when I needed
a job in the Colombian weed business had
dried up
by 1987 I was working as an avionics
technician on four h-46 C Knight
helicopters at the search and rescue
division of the Naval Air Station Point
Magoo known as SAR Hilo
this story takes place while I was in
the Navy
[Music]
spring 1987.
I was jogging around the half mile track
at Naval Air Station Point Magoo looking
at the radar Towers on the hill and
thinking what a beautiful day
it was a clear spring day and the sky
was Azure blue with fluffy white cotton
ball clouds dotting the sky
the night before I had been talking
about my idea for a band was my good
friend Kenny Miller
the band would have Thai female
background singers
and it would be a blend of cultures a
yin yang band
with American guys and Thai girls
we were thinking of what to call the
band we both laughed as Kenny threw out
the name soy cowboy
it was a pun on the name of a side
street off of sukumvit Road in Bangkok
that happened to have a bunch of go-go
bars on it
f-14s were using afterburners to launch
themselves Skyward in one of our
helicopters was Landing back in front of
the Tsar Hilo hangar
a few more laps around the track and I
remembered hearing a jazz version of
Johnny Mercer's old Cowhand from the Rio
Grande on Tom schnabel's Morning Becomes
Eclectic
on KCRW
I knew the song from The Dan Hicks in
his Hot Licks album striking it rich
and then it hit me
old Calhan from the Rio Grande would be
soy Cowboys first song
the vision popped into my head fully
formed and somehow I knew it would come
to fruition
[Music]
back at the barracks I showered put my
work uniform on and drove over to the
SAR Hangar and removed and replaced an
iff box on bloodhound 14.
Bloodhound was the call sign for our SAR
helicopters
after filling out the maintenance action
form I got Senior Chief Don osheline to
sign off on the job and he checked my
toolbox all tools accounted for and I
was out of there
it was Friday and I hopped in my VW ban
and drove off the base and hopped on the
101.
when I got to my mom's house in Encino I
called Tim long who had been the bass
player and fellow collaborator and a few
bands I had been in
I told Tim what I wanted to do he said
he was down with the idea and knew an
engineer we could hire who also played
drums his name was Joe remerson
I asked him if Joe was tall he said yes
I told Tim I knew Joe briefly from North
Hollywood High School
the next part of the puzzle was where to
find a Thai girl to sing on the tracks
I drove over to Tim's house in Studio
City which is up a driveway that went
South from Ventura Boulevard
Tim was subletting the place from
Charles polacek AKA Chaz whereas he
became known on stage Wade Charles the
23rd
Chaz lived in the unit above Tim's and
was a talented guitar player who had
been in a few bands with Tim and I
we were up in chaz's apartment
overlooking the valley below and I gave
them a fully inspired pep talk about my
idea
they were mesmerized beautiful Thai
girls in a band sounded great on paper
after a while the spell wore off and
Chas became non-committal
even with Chaz on the fence Tim and I
still had to find at least one Thai girl
to sing on the recording and so we
embarked on a talent scouting mission
we started frequenting Thai restaurants
and talking to Thai girls
most of them were amused by the idea but
couldn't sing
finally after count Miss pad Thai's and
singhas later we found a girl her name
was Ari she was a pretty girl with a bob
cut and she looked great in a cowboy hat
we found her at chitlada West the Thai
restaurant right below Tim and chaz's
[Music]
I borrowed fifteen hundred dollars from
the Navy Credit Union and we arranged a
date for the recording with Joe
he booked a little back house Studio
behind a house just south of Wilshire in
Beverly Hills
the studio is called the cottage it was
small but had a great Vibe it was in a
lush backyard shaded by jacaranda trees
and the interior was wood paneled with
comfy chairs and a couch
on a Saturday morning in late spring of
87 we recorded the Rhythm tracks Tim
played bass and acoustic guitar Joe had
the drums programmed and I put down the
piano track
in the afternoon Arie arrived with her
husband and we started knocking out her
yippee-i-o-kayes
[Music]
then we asked her to compose some Thai
lyrics to go along with the end of the
song and while she was doing that I
played a keyboard slide on a Yamaha DX7
I nailed it in one take
by then Ari had come up with the lyrics
she did a great job for being on the
spot
my favorite line translated to
Old Uncle Cowboy stay a while come
listen to a song and play some music
Marie sang her lyrics and then recorded
the spoken word at the end of the tune
and then we realized we had no lead
vocals so all three of us Tim Joe and
myself recorded a lead vocal
I had Joe put a rough mix of all three
vocals on a cassette and Tim and I took
it to my mom's house
I knew right away that Joe was the lead
singer from the moment I heard him put
down his vocal but to keep things fair I
had my mom pick
Virginia had been in Show Business and
was unquestionably qualified to make the
choice
she listened to all three versions and
picked Joe's vocal without hesitation
and that's how Joe remissa got his first
lead singer gig
we finished the lead vocals and mixing
back at the college a week later
Joe's vocal had an element of humor and
playfulness which later manifested
itself in his stage persona
after recording the song we scheduled a
promo photo session at my mom's house
and shot a few Polaroids with all of us
wearing cowboy hats
later that week on Friday I typed an
introductory letter to Tom Schnabel and
drove to Santa Monica with the letter a
Polaroid and a cassette
KCRW was in a basement on the campus of
Santa Monica City College
I walked in and asked to talk to Tom
Schnabel he wasn't there but an
assistant showed me where his desk was
and said I could leave the promo pack
there
I neatly arranged the letter in the
middle of the desk and put the Polaroid
in the center of the letter waited the
down with the cassette and drove home
[Music]
the next night I was celebrating with
Kenny Miller who had just taken the bar
exam
we were in his hotel room in Pasadena
and the phone rings and it's my mom
telling me she just got off the phone
with Tom Schnabel and he was planning to
play Old Callahan on Morning Becomes
Eclectic that next Monday
that Monday Tom played the song
that was great
and then a few months passed and I was
talking to Kenny Miller and he said
what's happening with soy Cowboy you
seem to have dropped the ball
that hit hard
it was a Monday and I was at Sick Bay on
base at NAS Point of View getting some
dental work done
I picked up the phone in the hall and
called KCRW and asked to speak to Thomas
Schnabel
Tom got on the phone and I told him who
I was and right away he was asking me to
bring the band in for a live performance
I said sure but I need a couple of
months
he put me on the phone with Ariana
Morgenstern his producer and we set a
date for the show
okay so I got us a gig but there was no
band
we had made one recording of one song
and now we're going to play KCRW live
the big question was who was we
[Music]
I called Tim and Joe and they agreed to
do the show
we were able to talk Chaz into playing
guitar as well
she would program the drums on his drum
machine
and we needed to find a few more Thai
singers
Tim and I were back Talent scouting for
female Thai vocalists
LA and in particular Hollywood had a few
upscale Thai restaurants with
good-looking waitresses but could any
sing and did they want to be in the
world's first High Western band
a term later coined by Schnabel himself
[Music]
Larchmont kawanga and Pico Boulevard
we visited Tommy tanks on Melrose gelato
West blows apartment on Ventura
which has its own little story for
another time
Thai Town further down Melrose and a
restaurant next to Jumbo's Clown Room on
Hollywood Boulevard east of Western
can't remember its name but it is now
called krung Ted
we found a willing waitress at Chandra
on Larchmont named Tumi talbotom
y was beautiful and had a koi sexiness
about her
she was always Pleasant and had a
radiant smile
we found an actual singer at Thai Town
on Melrose Thai Town catered to ties
mostly and had live time music nightly
singers mostly female were accompanied
by a Cheesy organ played by a Thai guy
with a drum machine
one Friday night during this time after
driving into town from Point Mugu Kenny
Miller and I watched the show at Thai
Town while eating
the singer was singing traditional and
popular Thai love songs
Before Time music became sappy
westernized pop
and there wasn't an eye in the
restaurant that wasn't watching her
Kenny was mesmerized and he said I'd
marry her
[Music]
Tim and I came back the next week we
talked to the singer candy manacy was
the name she went by
and she said she'd give it a try
and now we had three singers Ari Tumi
and candy
meanwhile I had rented a small room in a
house in Sherman Oaks that I would use
on the weekends from a friend of Kenny's
whose name eludes me
the house had a piano in the living room
and no one was ever there except me
usually
I remember writing our first original
song lily pads and rock cod one Friday
afternoon after driving into town from
the base
song was written in under an hour music
and lyrics Just Came to Me
[Music]
flatbeds and watermelons on a dusty road
why does it seem
I'm looking for something
[Music]
started rehearsing in my mom's garage on
Alonzo place in Encino
Mumsy was used to bands rehearsing in
the garage and would come out and watch
at times
but scheduling six people was a
nightmare and during the six year life
of the band's first Incarnation it never
got any better
at soy Cowboys height we had eight
people in the band three girls and Five
Guys rarely was there a rehearsal with
everybody there
in mom's garage we worked on Old Cowhand
and a new song called Lily pants
we threw in a Marty Robbins song Saddle
[ __ ] and another newly Written song
Back at the grace Hotel
to do the KCRW show I had to get
permission to take the day off from my
immediate commanding officer Senior
Chief Don ocheline
a very cool supervisor who helped me
with difficult jobs let me read him
essays and who was also an avionics
technician
I looked at the reason for the request
and approved it laughing in his unique
and ironic way
thank you
the day came we played KCRW
the show was Tom schnabel's Morning
Becomes Eclectic and you had to get
there early in the morning and the band
easily checked the eclectic box
everyone was nervous
this was our first gig and we would be
live on the radio
we dragged our equipment down into the
KCRW basement located in a building on
the campus of Santa Monica City College
Tom introduced himself and his producer
Ariana to the band as well as the
engineer Jeff
we set up in the studio and it was a bit
cramped with cables running everywhere
it was Showtime
Tom started talking about cassettes that
he had received and
and now here's the recording of soy
Cowboys first ever gig and the first of
many KCRW shows
courtesy of Vince nicoletti and I
put it into the machine and I listened
to it we receive a lot of cassette tapes
um most of them not really solicited
that we hardly have a chance to listen
to being an Eclectic station with a wide
format we get tapes in all shapes sizes
colors styles from uh real B grade stuff
to occasionally and a very sort of not
that often really something really good
Vince nicoletti's
tape and music was one of the good ones
and certainly one of the most unusual
ones that we've gotten
for one thing it mixes country and
western music with Thai vocals so
without further Ado I'd like to welcome
you Vince nicoletti and your band soy
Cowboy to the station hey Tom how are
you uh Jeff let's raise the volume a
little bit up there so we can hear
everybody talking I would like you uh
first of all to uh
maybe explain tell us a little bit about
your band and maybe introduce the
members before we get going well
to do actually
two parts of my soul into some music I
went to Thailand and fell in love with
the culture and the people and when I
came back here you know I left part of
my heart there so uh I decided that I
could put it together in this little
project here so that's what I've done in
I've gathered together a great bunch of
people here and we have a great time
doing this little project well it's the
kind of music that we like as well so
what he's trying to tell you is he's a
wacko and uh he's a he's aware of it
what a what a voice that's that's that's
beats there
all right Vince wanted to why don't you
uh
yes well strike of the band also
introduced the band members and then
let's go into our first tune we have
four Tunes uh that you're going to
perform for us so let's move on already
this is uh Joe ramersa hello hello he
sings and plays drum machine drum
machine this is uh Tim Wong
yes aka the lengthy one
this is Wade Chows on guitar here he's
our Hired Gun for the day
and these beautiful young ladies
are candy hi Ari and Tumi
welcome to the station
uh so let's see you have one two three
four five six seven so it's a it's a
seven piece band seven person band it is
indeed all right
all right I'll shut up let's hear some
music courtesy of soy Cowboy
thank you very much Tom
well boys you ready
let's Saddle Up This beast and ride it
huh
[Music]
okay
[Applause]
[Music]
and I learned to write
before I learned to stand
I'm arriving for who is up to date and I
know every Trail in this Lone Star State
cause I ride the rage on my Ford V8
again
[Music]
[Applause]
you got it [ __ ]
[Music]
[Applause]
yep that's me and I came to town
just to hear the man
I know all the songs that the Cowboys
know about the big Corral where the
doggies go cause I heard them all on the
radio
[Applause]
yep
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
say bye bye
okay
[Music]
them doggies are sounded good
the group is soy Cowboy here at KCRW
89.9 FM people want to know if you guys
are performing any place
well Tom we're working with Brendan
Mullen right now and getting a show
together at the lingerie and he's trying
to organize a
kind of a genre around this idea so
probably sometime this fall
early thank you Vince next up by soy
Cowboy I guess we have lily pads and
rock and roll
I love it oh that's lily pads you know
rock cut you know
it's a story about Lily
you know when I first left the states
and hit Thailand I was just still
looking for something always looking for
something
so
I taught my horse to swim I waterproof
my boots and swam to Thailand and
oh and I got to Thailand I was
might be at hungry so I went looking for
a chili dog and that's when I found her
it was Lily
it's Lily beds
[Music]
I still hear her now
thank you
flatbeds and watermelons on a dusty road
why does it seem like I have no home I'm
looking for something
what are you looking for
[Music]
lily pads
dancing in the stream live she takes my
money more foreign currency
to life some bananas into the pie
[Music]
to the skin of the Moonlight at night
merciless is a slap at the Sun hits my
face causing such a disgrace
foreign
[Music]
please
it's painful to leave here but I really
must get out the fruit is delicious but
there's a bad taste in my mind
[Music]
takes a color from an old Polaroid
fade yes it may but there's really no
way I could go back in time
there's no way
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah we
[Music]
you're listening to KCRW Santa Monica
and Morning Becomes Eclectic I'm Tom
Schnabel with me in the studio
performing live for your listening
pleasure is soy cowboy
next up oh okay go right ahead this may
or may not have been written by Marty
Robbins
[Music]
thank you
really call me a dripper they say I'm no
good and I never amount to a thing where
I may be a Drifter and I may be no good
but there's joy in the song that I sing
[Music]
a night I will rest beneath the blanket
of blue I doubt if I ever will change
what I might even dream of a lady I knew
might even whisper her name
[Music]
[Applause]
well I might even wind up in Idaho
and visit a cute little miss
a sweet little Someone I used to know I
might even stop long enough for a kiss
at a train
[Music]
settle trails
I must freeze a breezing out right where
I please that'll drown
[Music]
ing
I'm sorry did I did I interrupt you Tom
that last time not at all okay sorry
we needed a place to stay
anybody ever hear of the grace Hotel
don't all answer at once here
I never heard of it
okay well
it's gonna be last song here as soon as
I get my drummer ready drummer's been
drinking too much I think
we give you drummer
uh This song is called back at the grace
Hotel this is another Vince nicoletti
original
thank you
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
to the left
Germans to the right
I'm such a young
I'm all right you know I'm feeling cool
it's a 110
down at the grace
[Music]
[Applause]
back at the grace
Old Town
epilogue to this day Tim Joe and Chaz
are some of my closest friends without
their help and talent I never would have
been able to pull it off
sometime after the show Tom mentioned
the high production value on the
recording which was due to Joe's
engineering
Tom Schnabel and I became good friends
and still are and while I always tried
to get Joe to go back to Thailand with
me it was Tom who ended up on that
Adventure a few years later
from that first show on KCRW silly
Cowboy found a video director cool gigs
and La clubs and eventually a record
deal
but first I had to deal with the US Navy
and it was inevitable that over the
band's first six years some of the guys
would end up with some of the girls
which can be a recipe for disaster
we eventually got a real drummer
none other than Brian glasscock a truly
lovable Englishman who had been in the
motels
I nicknamed him phallus cristalis
there were eight girls in the six year
life of our first go-round with soy
cowboy and I would like to thank every
one of them for their time and hard work
there was a re and I don't remember her
last name Tumi talbotom
candy manicy also known as Ganda pitakun
Moy and I can't remember her last name
sorry
prinya kusuponan
Sarah see himan
Lila utasing and and suksaman
Hari wrote the lyrics for old Cowhand
candy wrote most of the Thai lyrics for
the band after that
prinya and Sarah contribute to writing
after candy left the band
I want to thank them mostly for going
along with such a wacky one-of-a-kind
project
thanks from the bottom of my heart
stay tuned for soak Cowboy part 2 coming
soon
[Music]
[Applause]
you've been listening to Cali High
episode 64. so a cowboy fourth in a new
series titled a work in progress a
retrospective of Adventures
written produced and recorded by Vince
nicoletti I want to thank all the
members of soy Cowboy Tim long Joe
remersa Charles polacek
Brian Glascock Ari Kanda Peter Koon Tumi
talbotom Moy prinikusu punan Sarah
sihaman Lila utising and an suksamran
featured music old Cowhand by Johnny
Mercer Saddle [ __ ] by Marty Robbins
lily pads and rock cod and back at the
grace hotel by Vince nicoletti
incidental music Vince nicoletti Kelly
High's theme written and recorded by
Vince nicoletti Jordan Webb and namir
blade
Kelly High podcast and theme are
copywritten and the logo is trademarked
music for the end credits
I don't know what to say by Vince
nicoletti
please like follow And subscribe to
Kelly High on YouTube email us with any
questions to calihighpodcast gmail.com
we're on Instagram at Kelly highla on
all podcast Platforms in audio
Kelly Heiser chenzo Nico production
stay safe and be blessed
[Music]
all right