[Music]
hello
and thank you for joining us today my
name is chad westport
and today i'm going to show you how to
take clones taking clones is a
relatively simple process
a process that every grower should know
and the reason i say that
is because if you know how to take a
clone then you're able to
keep a single seed going for many years
and in the case of finding a winner or
something that works great for you
it's a really handy tool to have and
speaking of tools
i like to get all of my tools laid out
before i actually start cutting on the
plant
that way i can take my clone dip it in
what i need to
and stick it straight in the medium of
choice and today
i'm going to show you two different
mediums i'll show you how to do it in
soil or cocoa
and then i'm also going to show you the
aeroponic cloner
soil and cocoa pretty simple process it
requires only a few tools
and i do like to get those laid out
beforehand
i'm only going to be taking clones off
of one plant today but when you're
taking clones off of multiple plants
now is the time to label them accurately
and do be sure to use a pen
that isn't going to smear or run off
with water because these are going to
get wet
and the reason i have three out today is
we're going to try three different
styles we're going to try dipping
one into clonex gel which is a rooting
hormone
we're going to dip another into aloe
vera which is kind of your organic or
natural
hormone rooting gel and then we're going
to do one
without anything and we're just going to
see which ones root first
or root best or have the best growth the
other tool that you'll notice here
is a fresh clean razor blade this is
something that you want to do
on each plant that you take clones from
i use a clean razor blade on every plant
for my ipm
because i know that pathogens can spread
easily through the sap of plants
and if i take a clone from an infected
plant and get the sap on the blade
and then go to another plant cut into it
i've just transferred my pathogen and
that's bad news so
good ipm says fresh razor blade for
every plant
i also have ph water it's important i
want to make sure my water is ph
and that's going to give the roots a
best chance to take off
i have pre-watered my soil mix and the
reason i do that
is to grow roots you're going to want
water but you also need oxygen
and i've found that if you dip straight
into the dry soil
and then you water it there's a chance
for pockets or dry spots around the stem
and we don't want that so i always water
it ahead of time
get the soil nice and saturated but not
soaked
and then i stick my clone right in
so let's get started and look at the
plant and see where we're going to take
our clones from
generally you're going to want to take
your clones from the lower portion of
the plant
now if you clean your plant up before
you put it into flour
meaning you take off the lower branches
that's a great time to select your
clones
and that's exactly what i'm going to do
here there's some that are a little bit
too long
there's some that are a little bit too
short everybody's going to have a
different size
of clone that they're going to take i
prefer to take them a little bit on the
smaller side
that just works for me and i go from the
lower portion but again because i'm
going into soil with this
i want to make sure it's a little bit
longer so i can get some depth down
into the soil compared to with my arrow
cloner
because i don't have 101 camera angles
i'm going to do this
in steps one two three four but it's
basically one
fluid movement from the time that i cut
it
to the time that i dip it to the time
that i put it into the soil
so let's go ahead and cut this one at
the 45 degree angle
and this one we dipped in the clonex so
we're gonna label it
clonex okay we know which one that
is okay i've selected another good one
here it's from the lower portion of the
plant
it has enough space to bury underneath
the soil
so we're gonna go ahead and cut this one
off and dip it in our aloe vera
you can see the 45 degree angle that
i've cut onto
this stem see it's open-faced
that's the angle we're looking for here
i'm gonna scrape this one again so let
me just show you that you're just gonna
gently scrape the outside layer
and what that's going to do is that's
going to promote more rooting sites
but you don't want to go too deep again
it's just that outer layer it's like
you're
peeling a vegetable or something peeling
a carrot
okay let me put my hole
into the soil take
my clone with no treatment on there and
drop it right on in
give a little bit of uh give it a hug
because we love our clones clones are
good to us so let's be good to them
and this one we're gonna just write
nothing because we've done nothing to it
okay so the last step for these are to
get the humidity dome on
and generate a little bit of humidity
all right we're about ready to finish
these off
we've got our three clones the aloe vera
the clonex
and the nothing we've got that
in our tray we got our tray
on our heat mat move that back there
we've got our humidity dome and a little
trick i like to do to kind of get the
humidity going
is take your ph water ph
spray the inside of your dome just give
it a little bit of
a little bit of life a little bit of
something to drip
a little spray a little spray on the
bottom of the tray too
that's always nice spray the leaves
because this is how they're going to get
water real gently
there's no roots for them to feed water
so they gotta feed
foliar give them a little spray
all right it looks good to go let me put
on the lid
put my tray on like that i'm gonna close
the vent holes on the top
and we're good we're gonna let it sit
and clones are gonna grow
we're going to finish up here by taking
three more clones off the lower portion
of this plant
and these are going to the aeroponic
cloner machine
which is my personal preference and i
also tend to take them a little bit
shorter
that way the stems don't sit down into
the water so
this one we've got a short one here that
i'll use this one
oh geez it's only about three inches
tall we've got another one over here
it's about seven inches tall but this
one i'm going to take in the middle
now you typically want to take it at
like a nodal space right in the crux
there
supposed to be more growth hormones but
you know what i'm going to slice this
one in the middle
just to show you that it can be done and
then beyond that we've got this one back
here
which is well it's a normal size so
we'll take that one
okay let's take our middle cut our
middle cut again even though it's in the
middle we're going to do it at a 45
degree angle
see if i can move this out of the way
here and then get you a good example of
the cut
oh okay we got the cut
and oh shoot see i messed that up i
scraped too hard
that one's trash okay we're gonna have
to go for another one
but we'll get this middle one so let's
do that
okay so here's my arrow cloner machine
with the three empty holes we're about
to fill with the clones that we just
took
let's lift the hood real quick though
and as you can see
under here there is a mister a bunch of
misters actually that
spray all of the cut of the clones
and from there it forms roots we just
take our plugs
that we just took we drop them in there
here's our short one drop that in there
and our cut from the middle
so there you have it we don't need a
humidity dome we're seven days
into the cloning project and i've
removed my humidity dome
and this applies to any time if you come
back and you see that your leaves are
dry
give them a little spray because until
they have roots
this is how they're going to get water
and feed all right
so all of them have pressure in the
leaves
so i can tell that something is going on
you can't see the roots so you don't
know
but the aloe vera the clonex and the one
that we did nothing to
they all look the same they all look
good the clones in the soil were looking
good
but we don't really know if they have
roots yet with the arrow cloner we'll be
able to tell
so let's take a look at our cuttings we
have the cut that we took from the
middle of the branch we put
nothing on it i don't see
any roots yet okay we also have
the medium-sized cut that we dipped in
the aloe
yeah okay a couple little roots on there
it's gonna have more days in the aero
cloner i'd say at least in
the yeah more time and then we have our
shortest cut with the clonex that
definitely has roots on it
so as far as the arrow cloner race goes
clonex wins there you have it
thank you for tuning in to my rough
guide on taking clones
this is chad westport and please join me
again next time