[Music]
hello fellow growers this is chad
westport and today
we're going to pop some seeds or get
some beans soaked
or as the scientist guys would say we're
going to germinate some seeds
i'm here to show you probably the most
common ways that people are going to
germinate their seeds
today we are going to do some rockwool
cubes
we are going to do direct so into some
soil
we are going to do the paper towel
method and the paper towel method can be
done a couple ways
you could put it between two paper
plates or you could put it in some
ziploc bags
so we'll do both of those uh over here
we've got
just some jars we're gonna fill those
with our ph
water uh ph it to 6.5
that might not be important to everybody
to me it is so
ph 6.5 water to pop my seeds and over
here i got a variety of seeds
for genetics the new ones i have right
now i've got an afghani times the dutch
treat
i've got the afghani back cross those
are the new ones those are the ones i
expect a really high germination rate
from
i'm also testing some of my older gear
i've got a harlequin time
secret sauce and secret sauce isn't
really a strain that's just my secret
sauce
i've got a northern lights number five
chimes
go time which was from jinx proof
genetics
i've also got a jax cleaner too which
was from tga genetics
times that to my secret sauce then i got
a really big bag here
of okay uh secret sauce times the agent
jack
that's the one i've got a whole bunch of
uh the agent jack
is a f1 cross of tga's agent orange and
jax cleaner too
so i want to see what germination rate i
get from those
first i'm going to show you the water
soaking method before we do that though
i want to stress the importance of
accurate labeling
i've got all of my little containers
labeled a b
c d through f i've got them all written
down here corresponding what the strains
are
the year that they were made that way i
know
what is what later and that is so
important when you're testing because
you don't want to get these things
confused
uh but hey the simple method of cracking
them
in water the soaking method you're just
going to take your container
i'm going to fill it with a little bit
of ph water
you don't need it super deep you know
i'm filling this maybe halfway and
that's fine
just going to do that you're gonna take
your seeds
gonna grab a pinch here and i'm just
gonna drop them in
one two three four five
six seven and as you see
right now they are floating around
they're in the center and we'll see if
they sink and open so let's go ahead and
do that to all of the other seeds
and there you go everything is soaking
now and we're just going to let that
overnight to see if they keep
floating or if they sink and when they
sink hopefully they open up and they
sprout a tail
that's how you germinate seeds just in
water the soak method
now i'm going to show you the rockwool
method before i do that though i just
want to show you something simple
again i've gone ahead and i've labeled
everything
everything needs to be labeled and i've
poked my own holes
through the rock wool pretty simple two
holes
each side gives me two tests on the
beans in
the rock wool so i've got my ph water
it's going to give them a nice soak
you don't want to get them too soaked
you still want there to be some air in
there yes
this is nice you could kind of squeeze
it you get a feel for how saturated they
are
that way
yeah perfect perfect happy combination
so again yeah i'm just going to take my
seeds i'm going to start plugging my way
in there
and i want to say before we put the
seeds in here the seeds have a side with
a dimple it's usually the fatter bottom
part
and then the side where it kind of comes
to the point that's usually the skinnier
part
now when you're putting them into the
rock wool or soil
just like this you want to put them with
the skinny part down
so dimple up that is going to help it
come up and grow out of the medium
so i'm just going to tuck it right down
in there and i'm actually going to give
it just a gentle
little tap down into the rock wool
with my skewer
and now repeat
now i'm only shoving them down maybe an
eighth of an inch
not deep at all
and there you go that is how to put
seeds into rockwool for germination
now let's do directly into the soil
i've got it uh split up and marked out
i've got it labeled up here
as far as what we're doing again you
want to make sure you keep track of what
is where
so you know what kind of results you're
getting okay i'm just going to
gently water this a little bit with my
ph
it's ph to 6.5 water again i don't want
to soak it because
the seeds gonna need some oxygen
but i want it wet enough to uh crack
that hole
okay so that's probably good and i'm
gonna do two seeds
per quadrant here so i'm just gonna poke
a little hole
poke a little hole
and that is quadrant f okay
make sure i get the right ones in there
and again when you put the seed directly
into the soil
you want that side with the dimple you
want that side
facing up so the sharp pointy side you
want
down into the soil general rule of thumb
is you're going to plant the seed twice
of its width
so if you have a seed that's basically a
16 inch wide
you're going to bury an eighth of an
inch deep so
not very deep especially for the
cannabis seeds
put it in there like so take this one
put it in there like so i'm just gonna
tamp it in oops
that one flipped around on me again i
want to make sure i get it the right way
down
a little bugger
okay then i'm just going to kind of
gently give it a little hug with the
soil
i'm not going to bury it deep again but
i do want contact with the soil and a
little something over it
okay so that's that side and i'm
basically just going to repeat
and there you go that is popping seeds
in
soil the paper plate method
all you're basically doing is putting
the seeds in the paper towel and then
covering it up with the paper plate to
create sort of a
humidity dome if you will i've already
got these already laid out and as you
can see they're labeled
you can see the seeds on the back and
let me show you how to do this basically
you just want to take your paper towel
your ph water get it soaked
ring it out a little bit unfold it onto
your plate
this is always the hard part getting it
separated
okay there we go separated there
you take your seeds you put them in
there and they don't need to face any
special direction
because you're just going to fold this
over
kind of tuck them in get them nice make
sure they have contact
i'm gonna fold it over again stay nice
and wet
boom take this
put it over there
there you go you got the paper plate
method for popping seats
we'll finish up here with the paper
towel method which again is very similar
to the
paper plate method you're essentially
getting your paper towel
you're putting a little bit of that ph
water on it
let it soak in okay
now the hard part is separating your
paper towel when it's wet
oh i got it okay
then roll that there
okay so i've got that done i'm gonna
take my seeds and again they don't need
to go in
any specific direction some people will
actually take the ziploc
bags and hang them upside down because
the root will grow down they are
in touch with gravity gravitropism i
believe it is
some fancy word but yeah the roots will
want to grow down but
if you lay horizontally not a big deal
for this portion
so i take my wet paper towel it's got
the seeds in there
they got a nice little hug so there's
contact there
take that slide that into my
zip lock bag try to keep everything nice
and separated
and i don't actually seal it but i do
kind of keep it closed
because as you can see on the one i did
earlier there's a little bit of moisture
and condensation building up around it
and that will keep them kind of moist my
room temperature right now is about 70
degrees
i do not need to use a heat mat if you
do use a heat mat if it was the winter i
would
if you use a heat mat don't put these
directly on the heat mat
because it's going to dry out the paper
towel it's going to be a little bit too
hot for that fresh seed
so just raise it or elevate it a little
bit off of the heat mat
and i always recommend that even if
you're doing clones so that's just good
practice
you want to keep these in a dark area
lights not necessarily going to hurt the
seed but light and water that can lead
to algae
the molds that can hurt the fresh seed
so
yeah just keep them somewhere relatively
dark relatively warm
we'll leave it like that and we'll check
in with them soon
okay here we are 24 hours later i'm
looking at all of the seeds and all of
the seeds
have sunk to the bottom of the jars so
that's a good sign
hopefully next thing is they will be
opening up for us as you can see
the three seeds here in the water have
cracked they've opened up and the tail
is starting to come out
these are ready to be placed into the
soil
all right so i'm going to go ahead and
put one of these seeds into the soil for
you
and i have tweezers to do that you want
to be gentle you don't have to use
tweezers but
i like to use them especially when
getting them out of the water just makes
it easier for me
so i'm just going to reach into here
get my seed and again you want to be
careful you don't want to
pinch it on the white part the white
part is sensitive
this is the tail the tap root and you
want to put that
down into the soil and another thing i
like to do when starting a seed in soil
is here's the top of my pot i have it
kind of carved out here
i'm going to put the seed down here in
the bottom i'm not going to bury it
too deep i'm actually only going to bury
it maybe an eighth of an inch
but what this allows the seed to do is
it allows it to get leggy and spread
up and then you can backfill giving it
more support because sometimes seeds
they stretch up this is a way to give
them support in the pot
so i have it i'm gonna put it here
again i'm gonna get the point down
let's put a little soil over it and
there you go it's in
the soil looking here
at the seeds that we put in the paper
towels two of these three have already
opened up their tails are coming out
and i'm going to take them out of the
paper towel so that the
roots don't grow into it and get damaged
when you transfer
i'm going to take them out right now and
i'm going to put them into my soil
and then i'm going to tuck it back in
and let that other seed stay in here and
pop for another day
we're five days into it now after we put
the seeds into either our soil our
rockwool
our water or our paper towels and now
we're just going to take a look and see
what we
have after five days you should your
seed should have
cracked and opened a tail you hope to
see that within 24 to 48 hours
sometimes it could go as long as seven
days maybe even as long as 10
but really after that point there might
not be too much vigor in the plant so
get a new seed get something that's
going to crack get something that's
going to grow pretty fast
so let's take a look at these paper
towels in the ziploc bag which is
typically my preferred method
and you'll notice here as i flip this
over
there's condensation which helped keep
the moisture in here the whole time i
never had to add any water to it
i just kept it in the warm place so
paper towel method in the ziploc bag
let's open it up and see what we get
here we have our results from the paper
towel in the plastic bag
uh a this is an old strain
not good results o for five um
b was three for three that was a new
strain i already put that into the soil
i took those out after 48 hours i just
kind of let these go to see what would
happen and to kind of give you an
example of why you don't do this because
it grows through the paper towel
but see this is an old strain i have
about six years old
it is three of three those cracked d
is another old strain that uh this one
got a nice
nice big root on it uh these two didn't
crack though
uh e another old strain no action there
f this is a new strain that i have and
this is three for three
and again guys i should have taken this
out uh 48 hours into it because they
have grown through the paper towel
and you want to be gentle on these roots
but i will show you later how to easily
get around this issue so there we have
it pretty good results let's go and
check the paper towel
in the plate method oh no
checking everything 24 hours into it and
my paper plate is dry
needs more water gotta do that now
so learning from that mistake quickly i
replaced
the paper plate on the bottom with
something that's not going to absorb
the water because again this absorb the
water
the paper towels dried out that was no
good you need them
wet to pop your seeds so i put them in
this
i've got them wet let's open it up and
let's see what we got
here are the results of our paper towel
in the plate method
nothing going on with this old strain
this new strain we got a nice tail here
one out of three uh here's the old
strain i have it got a tail got a tail
so two out of three there
um two out of three here this one's
getting a longer tail you can see that
there
uh that one didn't crack um nothing
going on with these
and then this one which is a newer one
three out of three but i wanted to show
you here
why it's important that you take uh
these out
after they sprout a little tail you know
right now you can still you can still
manage these you could grab them
you could take them you could put them
into your soil you could do whatever
i'm just going to shake those off right
now put those there
and this is why you want to take them
out because this
has actually grown through the paper
towel
so you know you don't want to damage the
roots when you're putting them in in
this case what i would do is i would
just kind of split
the paper towel here
and i have my access to it but again
you want to do as little touching and
damage to these as possible
and there you have it those are the
results from the plate with the paper
towels
let's see how it stacks up
now we'll look at our direct sows the
first direct so we have is our direcso
into soil
and i've got it all labeled here what
they are
gritted out easy to keep track of
again kind of seeing a common theme here
with results
a and e both older seeds
not having the best time with
germination but
my newer strains we've got the b
two for two right here and we got f2 for
two right here
so again the newer strains are coming in
at a hundred percent
and the other two older strains i have
here one for two
one for two so that's kind of holding
steady as well
that's the direct so into the soil
results
let's check out the direct so into
rockwool
and i'd just like to add that normally i
wouldn't put this many seeds in one
container
i only do one seed per one container but
this was a germination test this was
about seeing what popped up
this wasn't about growing these plants
any further
than this stage that they're getting to
so that's why i have so many
in one little space and the same holds
true for the rock wheel
you know one seed one space that's how i
rock it
now we get a chance to look at our rock
wool which is another method of direct
sowing into a medium
we just placed our seeds in there and
this isn't really a method that i
use i don't use rockwool frequently but
it is something that people
do so i thought i'd include it in my
germination tests
getting a little bit different results
with this one thing that is holding true
is my newer strains
excellent results they're both 100
percent you got two for two here
on what i labeled as the b strain and
then i also have two for two
here of the f strain uh all of the other
strains the older strains
they didn't have as good of results in
the rock wool as they did with some of
the other methods
one thing i do want to mention about
rockwool though is sometimes
you'll see the seeds in here at top it
may not
look like it popped but if you flip it
over
all of a sudden you see kind of like a
tap root
sitting in here so sometimes again
sometimes it looks like it didn't pop
because it's not growing up like this
but you flip it over and you see that
hey instead of growing up it just kind
of grew down
and you've got your root anyways so just
something to keep an eye on
with the rock wool and there you have it
after 48 hours i pulled a couple beans
that had already
cracked out of the water as well as the
paper towels
and i put them into soil because i just
wanted to make sure that they
were going to finish the job and so they
did again i have them marked here these
are the two new strains that i've been
doing
all three from the
uh water that cracked popped up
the two that i took out of the paper
towel earlier those have popped up as
well
and i even took some out of the water
for b
and they're coming up too i got one two
three four of those popping up
and again no way would i normally put
this many plants in one container
but this was about germination and i
just wanted to follow the job through
and make sure it completed its job of
popping up above ground
so there you have it guys i think my
results are in
a paper towel in a ziploc bag
followed by direct sew into soil
those were the two statistically most
effective methods
overall the new strains ones that i
would
expect to have germination rate they all
performed
equally the f was 100 the b
uh 14 of 16 i believe it was
and it had two problems with the
uh paper towel in the plate method so
overall great results on germination
from my newer strains the older strains
decent not so yeah whatever it is what
it is
but there you go guys that is kind of a
overall tutorial on how you can
germinate in a variety of different
methods so my name is chad westport
thank you for joining us i am from twin
peaks cannabis
and i hope to see you again on the
perfectly imperfect grow show
thank you
[Music]