and I think this would be a cool broad
point of view from all three of you guys
canopy management I see the cuting
behind Corey which you know are
obviously taken pretty well they're all
they're all about the same height you
can see the large canopy behind Anthony
and I imagine if that's a grow behind
Damon I imagine he's paid some attention
to canopy management as well but I feel
like there's no real no I feel like
there's no standard or like I feel like
it's like where art becomes more than it
becomes more of an art than a science
from grow room to grow room facility to
facility you know like and I feel like
it's a very underd discussed topic but I
feel like it's such an important one to
maybe maximize yield or maximize the
happiness of the plant maximize air flow
just try to maximize all the things and
I feel like in the ABC book of
growing there's just not many references
I want to get that narrative going and
see like people's point of
view Cory you want to go first I can go
first if not yeah go ahead brother I'll
take a little bit of a break
here yeah I
think it's something that's
uh I would say there's like not a a
one-size fits-all for anyone right so
the only way that it can be like sort of
standardized in the future is
by in my opinion like teaching Growers
how to discern like if you
can do a certain style of training in
your facility or not like for example if
you don't
have um the systems to handle like a
massive amount of flower weight in your
room it might be unwise to go like with
a super thick sea of green like you see
behind me or
whereas uh you
know there's plenty of benefits to just
going uh with a clone that you you don't
mess with at all uh you don't prune it
and it's just
apical um it's definitely a little bit
easier in those cases when you're not
doing as much plant training to just
maintain the environment a little bit
more so I feel like just Growers just
need to learn how to discern like okay
can can I do this uh even and if so like
push your you know push your crop to the
limits of your growth space but I think
that it's it's hard to standardize like
there's a right now a wave out west for
sure of a lot of guys uh touting a lot
of the benefits of not topping and I
think that there's really there's
benefits to both people are like I've
done a million studies side by side and
I just you know people are convinced of
one way or the other but I think it's
not necessarily a matter of which way is
better it's always going to be your grow
space is limited so there's going to be
a best way for your space but it's just
about Discerning that I think and
figuring that out for me and for this
space we had great HVAC and just our
systems could handle a super thick
canopy which is why we pushed it uh we
didn't do like a whole lot of like
topping and stuff but essentially it's
like a one top and veg let them run
through the end of uh stretch and during
those first three weeks of stretch we
are you know doing some LST under the
the trellis and bending and whatnot but
it's very minimal on like plant pruning
but I definitely think that to speak to
your yield Point uh this is something
that is huge for maximizing your crop
but it's it's you don't want to like
always go with this approach because it
can certainly be too much if your
systems can't handle it but that's my
long-winded
answer I'm glad someone else has a
long-winded answer on this thing other
than me um yeah so I mean there's like
yeah there's a lot of parameters for
this one you can feel free to cut me off
whenever you want because I'm gonna for
sure um so it depends number one like
yeah your space or or also the way I
also kind of take a look at that is like
what are your goals particularly you
know are you in a commercial grow you
know are you hanging out and just doing
stuff in a couple of tents there's a
totally different strategies you know
before I was just I wasn't topping
pretty much anything in my tents I was
just you know filling pots side by side
and just trying to get as much kind of
plant material there was the same thing
when I was you know testing out Auto
flowers you know you just kind of put
them in drop them and just kind of see
you know what different types of
cannabis plants do for you
so um that's a huge thing you know if
you're in the commercial space a few
parameters for you in your commercial
space is definitely your canopy so um
you want to make sure that all of your
trellis squares are have something in
them you know you don't want any empty
space in there you want that maximized
for sure empty spaces is a wasted
opportunity financially for the business
so you want to make sure that those are
full you then also have like other
parameters in your space and this also
will apply at home but it's like what
system do you have at home are you
growing in rockwool are you doing a
living soil system because the response
rate of your plants and your ability to
feed them is going to be totally
different so you can be pretty
aggressive in the hydroponic setting
whereas if you're going over in living
soil probably want to chill out a little
bit understand your liquid feed system
if that's what also you're doing in a
robust living soil system and try and
and manage that when you're pinching
your plant you have to you know also
think about that you know um are you
going to need an increased calcium so
that you're you know helping your shoot
tips actually grow while you're you know
doing that or you just pinching your
plant lacking in calcium and then not
getting the response that you want so
it's also having that nutritional
understanding of what you're doing with
it and then like if you're in the
greenhouse um you have different seasons
so you have a different light level that
is going to affect the growth rate of
your plants so if you're indoors you're
maximizing ppfd all the time you can
just [ __ ] slam it when you're in the
greenhouse you know even if you do have
supplemental lighting it's still not
going to be the same so for us when I
was working in the greenhouse we had
distinct times when we would reduce the
amount ount of shoots on their plants
and you know increase the amount of
shoots on their plant in the winter time
uh we would try and have more shoots
that are out there because we weren't
getting as much development if we had
less and then in the summertime I mean
the plants were just [ __ ] rocking and
rolling so we would reduce the number of
shoots because the plant was you know
just developing all this biomass where
we didn't need to have as many shoots
that were in there those plants C were
doing really well so you know for me
currently right now what I'm trying to
understand is you know how many shoots
am I going for because I do have some
math in my head so a quick calculation
is I pinch to uh six uh stems so I'll or
yeah I'll go and count six pinch that on
the top and then in a week to 10 days
after that I'm going to pinch those six
and then I'm going to have
12 and then a week after that I'm going
to go and pinch those 12 and I'll have
24 at the end of flower
so that way then I can calculate stem
density on my plant and then try and
deliver the right amount of nutrition
equally to all of those plants that's
the one of the worst things that you can
do for canopy management is make that
uneven so if you have a different amount
of stems per different plant that is
going to have a different nutrition
requirement so you want to make sure
that if you have those targets you have
those goals that it's one consistent
Target that you're doing or if you are
going to do you know two different
strategies in a room put that one
strategy in a place where you're a g to
remember it don't want to lose track of
it but make sure that they're all
together because that canopy size is
going to be different than the other one
for example I'm doing a six shoot
strategy and a fores shoot strategy
right now because I don't know what the
[ __ ] is this new cultivar that I'm
growing I'm going to try both so I put
my ones that I pinched you know they
reached a 6inch stage I'm pinching that
at four I'm going to let those fly in
obey and then everything else I pinched
to six and we'll kind of figure it out
from there but all those are grouped
together so that I can make sure that
that canopy is you know managed I know
one of the other ways people do a canopy
management is you know taking a
measurement so uh Mac 1 for example that
cut that I was growing uh we would go by
Heights we didn't really give a [ __ ]
about stems we would go by Heights
strict Heights 11 in 22 in and then
another one 34 and it was just that is
what we did um so there's definitely
more than one way to fry a fish um and
so just understand what you're doing I
would you know again at the commercial
space one last kind of piece of advice
is I would be really careful about you
know stretching out your stems and doing
any LST training things in there because
at the end of it you got to harvest
those [ __ ] things and if you're like
pulling your plant out and it's a little
bit crooked and it's getting caught in
the
because your worker isn't really doing
you know paying attention to the plant
that could potentially cause you a
little bit of trouble so make sure that
you kind of you know be a little bit
strict about it if you are at that
commercial space because it might be
nice that you do end up getting that bud
but you might lose it when people are
handling it unfortunately I've seen that
a few too many times uh across this
country in Canada here uh maybe it's a
Canadian thing but uh yeah we've kind of
avoided trying to do some of those
things in there because when you just
pull it through the chalis net people
get you know in a a mindset and they're
just trying to get those plants out of
there so yeah I think uh I think that
should addend my rant at this point in
time I think I covered enough in there
yeah I love it I feel like it's such a
complex
subject and yet it never gets discussed
enough to me you know I love it I
[ __ ] love it there's so many yeah
it's the real art to me I love it and
depends on your cultivars [ __ ] you know
if you got some of those column columnar
ones that are just growing like this
instead of like that you're take that
differently that's what I love about it
too you know like it's just it is such a
wide open thing you can take so many
different ways at it and to get that
same height it's hilarious the different
things you can
do what about like negative differential
does anybody do negative differential to
control the height of their
plants put the temperature warmer at
nighttime than the day Time by two
degrees you control the stretch of your
plants that's also a real brilliant way
to do canopy management if you have a
real stretchy ass plant uh I've been
able to keep there's one in particular
it was like a super thin leaf and she
would do about a three to four x stretch
uh we're talking like we'd get to about
nine foot plants you'd go in there and
deaf those [ __ ] things and try to
keep them down but they just kept on
moving so yeah negative differential was
also another thing that I would use as
far as uh environment management was
concerned because I know that was
mentioned by my esteemed colleague above
me here it was a brilliant [ __ ] for
sure that's another thing you can do to
keep your plans you know a little bit
down yeah that's
cool I do one followup too I feel like
one major Nuance to me you guys didn't
cover you guys covered so much canopy
depth indoors and maybe even versus
Outdoors even though like kind of well
known that the sun penetrates all the
way through I feel like the the carpet
of canopies always an interesting muat
to me like some grows maybe it should
only be 8 in some grows maybe it should
be 3 feet and like sky the limit kind of
quite literally for sun grown I'm
curious what you guys think of like
canopy depth like how thick is the
blanket of
flour like you're talking vertical
flowering canopy yep
uh yeah again uh I feel like you can
almost safely answer any question by
saying it's Nuance but like it just
depends on your environment to me like
it depends on your setup like for me if
if everything's cool I'm shooting for a
three or 4 foot freaking canopy and like
a six or seven foot plant and then
calling it there it's a tall plant but
it's a lot of flowering canopy as
well um that's just my preference and
like my target even like in my own grow
space is like roughly 3 feet of
flowering canopy but it takes a solid
light with you know Quality Parts to be
able to throw the light deep in there or
you know that paired with your
defoliation strategy also plays a role
but what would you say
Corey so I mean God it's like as big as
we can get them in in commercial space
you know like really just in like how
effective those buds actually are down
there uh yeah the there was that
Greenhouse picture that you showed
earlier there like that was it's a
really good thing where you can see like
how much we actually leave on that plant
which is like almost all of the [ __ ]
thing um versus like indoor where yeah
you're trying to like figure that part
out
essentially what I have kind of come to
the conclusion of though is if you are
you know number one if you're taking
those big leaves off you're definitely
really upsetting your photosynthetic
rate like it's just all over the [ __ ]
place because those leaves are solar
panels they're taking that goodness from
the Sun and creating your goodness for
your plant so it's really important to
like keep some of those but at the same
time you got to manage what's going on I
was really
surprised the amount of leaves on the
plant that they were leaving for sure
but like it was growing consistent Bud
definitely was not know the best of
quality it's you know definitely more
generic and that sort of says value weed
but the plant was consistent in that way
we didn't see a lot of interruptions you
know we were growing seven eight strains
of room and all of them were like pretty
consistent you know obviously like
there's some pretty basic morphological
changes that'll be there but for the
most part we were able to have a good
you know yeah 3 feet minimum um canopy
that was going down um ah I've briefly
talked to euben Zing at University of G
on S that [ __ ] plant gave me [ __ ]
powdery mildew and [ __ ] thrips and my
grow [ __ ] that guy who gave me that
PL nasty plant it was ended up being
really bad my my apologies wasn't
you sorry go ahead about gu oh no no no
you're good um that that's to the spider
mates that's like I used the other hand
but that's like a salute to iway way
that's one of the most brilliant
dissident artists of like all time and I
had a I was randomly roaming around in
Portugal and his um I've been trying to
see his art installation for like a
decade now and I was just walking down
the road and I saw that and I said you
got to be [ __ ] joking me he's here so
I just walked right in and saw it yeah
so yeah shout out iway way that dude is
a yeah awesome awesome dude
anyway I love this this is good you're
pulling up some uh I almost feel like
I'm I need to get like hot wings in the
hot sauce here for like the indepth [ __ ]
that you're coming pull that's like
that's a golden oldie right there that's
like almost four years ago that's
awesome Glow's for
Kobe you're ridiculous all right G
question go
ahead well uh it kind of it Falls in
line with the canopy depth question um
again I I shoot for a generic 3 feet
because I feel like I can achieve that
but you know to really dial it in you
been brought up a great point and this
is his recommendation alone but I'm sure
there's like a range like this that each
grower can find in their
facility uh but he's basically saying
you know if you peek out at 12200 ppfd
try to go no lower than 300 ppfd to like
en ensure a better product quality or
whatever I'm like okay that's a good
idea so def foliate up to a certain ppfd
level maybe not 300 but like I think
that that that would be an interesting
thing to dial like find the efficiency
of like where where is the flow like you
know starting to to get hard or you know
obviously some strains it's just
freaking rock hard the whole way down
but for some strains it certainly plays
a huge role like and things can get real
ly down there if you don't have those
ppfd targets or just like a height
Target I think is a more basic approach
you's way is definitely more dialed in
but I think that yeah that's got to VAR
per cultivar probably right yeah for
cultivar and I think also like again
like having that like same amount of
shoots that you're going for is really
key to that because then you'll find
consistency all the way through I do
like to shoot math for sure yeah like
you pinch one of your shoots one too
many or two too many or if like you just
have an imbalanced shoot in there that
whole thing is going to be different and
I've seen that that was you know that's
a really great way to troubleshoot your
workers you just go around your plan and
if you see like one branch just [ __ ]
monster vegging out from the other ones
well you notice that one definitely got
missed the pitch like you five of six
are flat you got this one just [ __ ]
given her for life so yeah it's it's
really important you could see those
that nutrient distribution if you do you
know feel free like I really encourage
people to try that out like if you do
have access to a few different plants
like or sorry I should say just an
amount of plants you know like do some
of those things like pinch plants at
different things like see what it does
like understand what that plants do and
it man it'll Advance you so quickly like
that was again like one of the really
good things about working on a place
with that many units I was able to do so
many [ __ ] experiments in the last
three years like even just outside of
the zamir Puna stuff and [ __ ] like I
learned so much stuff about the
morphology and the physiology of the
plan and reactions you know and it's
just yeah it's it's advaned so quickly
in my brain it's awesome
toxins phyto hormones Tony knows all
about phyto
hormones a couple things know about
all that's why I like hanging around you
smart young guys
I don't know I don't do any sort of
canopy management and I I have but the
reason why I don't is because I don't
feel like I'm getting a true expression
of that
particular plant a manipulating it like
when you do the low stress training and
all of that so I like to just saying
you're saying seed plants or even clone
plants as well I not working I haven't
worked with clones for quite some time
but even with clones I just found it
busy work right I'd rather just let it
do its
thing Comm well like for you have to you
have to because it all comes down to
square footage right and like so and and
efficiency
so I agree with what you guys are saying
but for me I just I want to see the true
expression and I don't want to get
manipulate get the true expression if
you don't do a hard top like if you do
low stress training and just you still
have your branches and you haven't done
like a destructive topping as I would
call what we do at the commercial space
like it it's still you're not really
like you're not inducing any like
pressure down into the roots to force a
reaction to get some nutrients out like
you're not I think you're still getting
the true expression even I'm not buying
a pH pen I not dry trimming my plants
and I am not training a canopy get off
my lawn I love that perspective Damon I
knew there like three very interesting
points of views I think that's cool like
and even a clone plant if you do get a
clone you'll just let it run
yeah
cool I'm like on the complete other side
man I see a clone I'm like [ __ ] top
it I want to take a cut right off the
top of it once it gets moving I'm like
first top is best cut give me I had a I
had a homie who sent me a video like I
didn't really used to think like this at
all like at least six or but like I had
a homie who works in a micro space like
micro cultivation space so he's got like
2500 square feet 3,000 somewhere in
there and he like as soon as he
transplants his clones he tops that
[ __ ] he just removes the AP
pickle right away it doesn't matter
going yeah it's really like before the
root like when he's like rooting his
plugs he's topping them or as soon as
he's transplanting them after after Ro
okay that's still pretty wild still yeah
no I was like I've ever goofball
experimented out that with that myself
that's pretty wild I had to get him to
like send the video because I was like
okay you're not even doing this like at
home you're doing it in a [ __ ]
commercial space like so that means you
had to have hit targets or else your ass
would have been fired by now so there
there has to be something something's
going on yeah so I got in you know I did
that I got some R&amp;D stuff like a couple
weeks ago and I [ __ ] said [ __ ] it all
right on transplant I'm topping let's
see what happens you know it is a
cookies variety so it is going to
stretch like an [ __ ] I'm certain of
that so I was like well this if I'm
going to top one that early this is
going to be the one so I put on my big
boy pants and decided to completely go
left field and just yeah because I man
that is man if I the people who brought
me up in the game would hear me doing
that I apologize guys but I'm just I'm
doing it in the name of science promise