[Music]
ah
yes
when you wake up
and you feel like you need a little
upper
or when you're down and out
and you need to get a little higher
if you feel like you need a blessing now
and you feel a little high today
welcome to the church
welcome to cali eye episode 57 i'm your
host chen zonico and this week our guest
is carter reeves the innovative
singer-songwriter of the band surfer
girl
he recently released his first single
two a collab with hip abduction off his
upcoming album sunrise due to be
released in september
reeves songs embrace the feel-good
aspects of surf reggae culture and at
the same time can leave you thinking on
a deeper level while as catchy melodies
linger in your head
his first self-titled ep surfer girl on
ineffable records written during the
pandemic shows his depth of talent and
may end up becoming anthemic of the
period with songs such as hero joyride
and bag of bones
carter saw his first success with the
band air right after high school and we
talk about those early beginnings in new
england as well as his move to the west
coast he tells of getting signed to
ineffable records and collaborations
with other artists on the label
including collie buds on roots rhythm
2021 with the song family
reeves also talks about his musical
influences and the decision to put his
solo material on hold while moving
forward with surfer girl
this is a very cool episode stay tuned
all right
cali high is blessed to be here with
carter reeves of surfer girl
and uh we're so stoked carter how are
you buddy dude i'm doing great thanks
for having me i appreciate it thanks for
coming down
so why don't you tell our listeners a
little bit about it yourself oh where to
begin i don't know man i
grew up in new england
i grew up listening to really great
music massachusetts yeah yeah i grew up
outside of boston about 20 minutes west
so suburban boy through and through
um
but i always grew up i i grew up
spending my summers uh with my parents
up in maine and so that's kind of where
i first got connected to that that beach
lifestyle and just kind of you know
kicked back on the beach and kind of
went oh my goodness
how could i do this all day every day
yeah and so uh
you know that's kind of synonymous with
the music absolutely and the surfing and
you know this kind of like easy breezy
feel good stuff you know yeah i never
grew up listening to to anything too
hardcore i definitely went through my
kind of emo phase for a little bit but
it was always something feel good yeah
so i think being from new england like
definitely helped to kind of set me on
this path of making the music that i'm
making now but yeah well it's very cool
i'm glad you're doing it yeah um
so when did you start playing singing
and writing tunes
it's always been a weird little bit of a
rollercoaster of a journey because i
never was classically trained on
anything i never actually really
properly took lessons still to this day
for anything tried and failed a few
times but uh
i don't know i always grew up just
making mouth noises just
being annoying and
bob-a-boo-ying around the house and just
singing and yeah finally my mom was you
know she pulled me aside and she was
just like yo
i love you but you're very annoying
you need to transfer this into some sort
of something
so she signed me up for chorus if i like
you know just like my middle school
chorus
which i hated
so much
because it was just it was too bland and
all is
you're learning all the the keys and the
tenors and the sopranos again it was too
rigid for me but um that was about the
first kind of step seriously into music
was i think sixth grade
yeah sweet so
sixth grade and you were taking coral
yeah and again you know it's just too
rigid for me and and but but it it
definitely got my ears going and my you
know my voice going and that's kind of
where i grew my singing voice
um and i had played a little bit of
piano in the past but again never really
took anything too seriously it wasn't
until
freshman year of high school
my best friends put together a
four-piece rock band literally in in my
friend's garage
we listened to the red hot chili peppers
religiously dude we wanted to be we
wanted to be them so badly all you had
to do was get four socks yeah right yeah
four socks strip down and you're good to
go
but it was crazy yeah i mean so we just
for a bunch of ragtag freshman
sophomores in in high school we took it
damn seriously yeah you know we would
practice for like five hours a day after
school every single day and who's garage
uh david von marring shout out to david
and shout out to david's mom and more
importantly because she would just let
us rock yeah
my mom had to put up with that too oh
yeah you know how it goes it's just
yeah it's relentless thankfully we
didn't suck that much so like at least
it was palatable to hear but like oh my
gosh that's cool but uh that was what
started the whole thing and and and that
band
that rock band in high school you know
it was the first time i had ever taken
music seriously
writing a bunch of music and writing
lyrics and and trying yeah that's good
and i had a lot of fun doing it and and
that that band was actually the start
of
well because it was a four piece band
and then
two of us kind of split off you know
once once to make air yeah yeah so david
von marring was the drummer of our band
and he was always he always had ideas he
was always spinning he was like you know
hey play this on the guitar hey write
the music like this or like hey let's
try this and try all these ideas and i
was like
dude we just thought you were the
drummer but here he is like with all
these genius ideas and he's kind of
starting to come out of his skin a
little bit yeah and uh
you know the band didn't end up seeing
eye to eye especially because kind of
college was coming up around the corner
we were ready to just go all in on this
band yeah and you know
that's that's not everybody's path in
life so
david and i split off and we did our own
thing and that's where air came from so
wow that's cool that's cool it was a
natural kind of progression
yeah who are your musical influences
besides the chili peppers
yeah well i hate these guys with all my
heart this is the worst band i've ever
heard
um
i was figuring you uh had some old
school influences oh dude i um
i mean admittedly you know i'll be
honest you know i grew up with music in
the house so yeah you know i was always
familiar with the beatles always
familiar with the stones and the beach
boys and
everybody but
it wasn't it it's not until you as an
adult or you as a listener you decide
i'm going to go back and i'm going to
listen to that stuff
so it wasn't until maybe five or six
years ago that i actually went from like
50s
all the way up to like you know the 80s
and just like listen to every album of
of all the greats everybody knows the
names right but like do you ever
actually sit down and listen to the
catalog and so finally i did um
but influences i mean it's got to be
got to be the beatles got to be the
beach boys
i love
this new funky group out of houston
called krong bin
bin yeah it means airplane in thai yeah
exactly yeah yeah they're super rat
which you know we can't get enough of
today obviously but they're super rad
and they kind of like you you know
i started to get into kind of this the
intersection of like psychedelia retro
vibes but also just kind of like you
know groovy
groovy like surf rock and so like that
kind of whole
world really kind of stuck out to me
um
and moving to california yeah yeah
driving driving on pca she just
what better music than than that kind of
feel good feel good stuff but um
i mean kid cudi shaped me jack johnson
shaped me sublime of course shaped to me
of course um
slightly stupid big time
i was a dirty heads fan when i was 12.
so like you know
these are the guys that that
shaped you know my sound now and and my
style now i'd say i've just spent maybe
the past 10 years honing it you know
yeah guitar influence
mark spear lead of uh lead lead
guitarist of krong bin he's uh
he just has a conversation
like they don't really have a lead
vocalist right you know now they're kind
of trying to do vocals but they don't
have a lead vocalist his guitar is the
lead vocal right
you just hear it you hear this
conversation you hear these melodies and
yeah [ __ ] i'm nowhere near being able to
play like that but
that that showed me a whole new style
and also opened me up into like
vietnamese rock uh
60s arabian funk like all this crazy
music that i never thought i'd listen to
i'll have to play you my old band i hope
dude
thai background singers
we're not here you're talking about them
that was sorry but
him and then of course him from a lead
standpoint and then i would say you know
the beatles just continually blow my
mind with their chord progressions yeah
their chord changes oh my god how do you
get from here to there and how do you do
it so smoothly so i'll sit down i'll try
and study those you know they've
been a huge influence so yeah beetles
are amazing it's a little hard to fit in
all those
c major seven to a dominant fifth with a
minor nine thought that it's a little
hard to fit that into like uh a reggae
groove you know yeah sometimes a sweet
chord right yeah a little too over
complicated but you know the beatles
chord changes were
non-top incomparable and same with with
beach boys yeah i mean brian wilson he
used to study you know bach and he would
study mozart yeah and that's how he
would make his chord progressions and
she's like
damn dude that's far out that's cool so
is surfer girl kind of a concept
yeah and who are they i mean you got a
band right yeah yeah um
you know so first and foremost you know
the name
certainly comes from my love for the
beach boys yeah uh surfer girl is
one of my favorite songs by them i mean
yeah you could go for days on all the
songs loved by them but that one you
know that one stuck out to me when i was
young and that one has continually like
stood up to the test of time for me
um
moved to l.a
fell in love with a long time friend of
mine who's from l.a
we've been dating now for you know three
years and she's kind of my surfer girl
as well how cool and so between the
beach boys between the song and then
between the fact that i think
well i see it in two ways i see
obviously surfer girl
is just such a beautiful concept you
know everybody loves this free-spirited
badass woman who just is out there
walking on water i mean that's an idol
to little girls it's an idol to
guys in the lineup surfing alongside her
she's just you know an idol and yeah
that to me is just always had this
really golden sunny beautiful
feeling around you know just
that person and so i thought it'd be
really cool to kind of like nod and
shout out
all of those folks and and those women
but then also at the same time
you know i feel like 2022 is a fun time
and it's an interesting time in a place
where i can be a male front man of a
band and
put together a band called surfer girl
and
may confuse a few people they may be
expecting some hot blonde to come out on
stage and they get me instead but you
know like
i think it's a fun time you know people
i think are shedding labels a little bit
and having a good time and just it's
about the vibe so yeah
yeah yeah it's very cool thanks um
was that first surfer girl ep written
during the pandemic yeah yeah um
yeah it was a crossroads of a time it
was definitely an interesting period for
the world and for everybody but
definitely for me personally
um
air had split up you know five years
prior um the duo that that kind of got
my foot in the door musically
i was struggling to do solo music for a
long time um
because each song sounded different from
the last yeah which i've kind of prided
myself man nothing long right right no
and i was priding myself in that and to
me i was kind of going through different
styles to see what stuck with the
audience but what what felt authentic to
me
um
so you know i think it was hard to grasp
onto for a lot of fans but but long
story short you know i kind of got to a
point where
financially i was looking at myself and
i said oh [ __ ] maybe it's time to
do what mom always says and get a real
job and throw in the towel and not to
say i get pressure from my mother she's
very supportive but you know yeah yeah
yeah well yeah moms are like that yeah
of course you know just my best interest
yeah exactly looking at looking at the
track record shout out what's mom's name
victoria victoria she's wonderful all
but looking at the track record and
saying you know it's been five years
trying to do my own thing
you know
i got to get something stable yeah or at
least get something that's got some hope
and and some kick behind it well surfer
girl seems to be very promising though
it's feeling good yeah i mean so
the world stopped yeah i went back to
the east coast to uh lay low with the
family for a little bit which i'm very
grateful to have been able to do
um was surfing every day through march
april may you know it's snowing in maine
there you are yeah in the water and
you know i i had been brainstorming with
some friends about you know kind of
dude you always made this feel good
reggae kind of beachy you know modern
modern kind of beach pop feel good stuff
maybe it's time you you you try and do
that because the carter reef stuff i
think i was trying to be something and
then it was just like i like the carter
reef stuff thank you yeah me too a lot
of it is is really strong but uh
well so
you know
pandemic hit was ready to throw in the
towel or potentially and and finally you
know my
my buddy and i were just brainstorming
on this it's like well why don't you put
together a band why don't you make that
music that always spoke to you in the
first place so i just started writing
songs making demos producing them you
know on my laptop with my guitar and my
bass and my
in the new england basement up in maine
and
had five great songs that i freaking
love and they're all hit dude thank you
sent them off to ineffable records
radio silence for six months really
screw you guys no i'm kidding i'm
kidding but it was radio sound radio
it's quite some time that's a little
disconcerting well it's just like oh god
i have this really nice body of work
what do i do with it yeah um and somehow
i got a call in august
from from adam gross shout out to adam
brother
and he just called me and he's like dude
i don't know how this just came across
my desk but i just heard the ep it's
amazing we want to support it we want to
put it out
let's go right and that was the start
that's very cool yeah yeah it's nice to
have a team behind you you know yeah i
like ineffable records they have great
artists cool and i love how diverse the
roster is i love how they're branching
out like genre wise but also just like
yeah they're they're doing it right yeah
for sure yeah he's a young guy and i
it's it's really
adam and thomas man both young dudes and
both just crushing it yeah
so
speaking of that ep let's talk about
hero a bit
let's um come out swinging and you know
this this this is a song that then
endeared my son to you because he has
some political ideas about who wasn't
cool a few years ago yeah yes
um are we still looking for a hero
i think so yeah uh definitely i mean in
the context of you know
hero is not a sugar-coated song by any
means
i
wrote that the president don't know [ __ ]
right and i said that loud and i said it
proud and i still stand by it i stand by
that too i think
in time the funny thing was and and so
like on youtube i'll get so many
comments and it was written in what year
it was 2017 right right yeah so it was
definitely a a for me it was a [ __ ]
trump anthem yeah i was pretty pissed
off and fed up and to me i
i
wholeheartedly believe that both sides
of the coin are
pretty bad yeah real bad you know yeah
we're still in a bunch of hot water
there oh tim who knows if we're ever
going to get out of to me it's it's
personal freedoms it's supporting people
and it's and it's also equitable support
for people who
if for
years generations our country was built
on supporting some and not others can we
just even the playing field that's
really what i want to do yeah and and
that's kind of the message of the song
was just like yo this
i think it was a pointed [ __ ] trump
anthem when it came out but it's cool
because it has lived on and and kind of
grew a new meaning to me which is
you know
everybody was
joe biden was not my top choice he was
not in my top 15 of trump that's why
maybe he's not my hero but he's not the
hero no no not at all he is not and so
it's funny because you make a strong
statement like kind of like the
president don't know [ __ ] [ __ ] trump
kind of thing and now everybody comes
how's your buddy biden doing yo this was
not my guy to begin with right but what
i will say is i'd rather have someone
at least seems like fighting for the
right direction of humanity and the
country and climate change
uh then not but with all that said
um the the message of the songs kind of
still still stands true yeah and when i
perform it live you know i kind of i
kind of tweak the lyrics a little bit
from uh
our president don't know [ __ ] to a
president can't do [ __ ] and like a
president won't do [ __ ] or or a
president don't know [ __ ] like it to me
it is more about
you can't rely on one human
yeah to
solve all the world's problems
and treat everybody fairly and and
and the system that we have the system
is broken let's open our minds you know
the system we do have is not
built in a way that's going to help
everybody and listen to everybody's
needs and so to me this kind of
overarching thing of like a president
can't be the one
to help you
you know it starts from within you got
to help yourself you got to help your
community you got to start small like
you were saying you know vote small you
know try and get someone you like in
build a strong community grow some
[ __ ] food grow some weed have a good
time and connect on that level and i
think that's where it's going to start
from so to me the message has more
become
don't just cast a vote and rely on this
person to fix everything it really does
start from within and it does start from
connecting you know on on the ground
level that's cool bro so that's where
it's at still looking for a hero for
sure absolutely yeah
definitely
as i listen to your music i can't help
but
think
what is your creative process because
you know as a songwriter
you look at other people's songs and i
really admire your songwriting process
so what is your
creative process
yeah um
i've been producing music for a long
time but i never felt confident that the
music i was producing was good enough or
you know up to snuff
until that ep and i kind of just like
said effort let's take this leap of
faith you know we got the label behind
us
and
that was the first
full body of work that i had kind of
produced
myself um
so the process now is you know just kind
of sit down with a blank
slate be it on a computer in in logic
pro being my my blank slate
yeah or just sit down with a guitar
outside somewhere or sit down with a pad
of paper um
i don't have one specific way in which
it starts but once it's sparked
i chase it down um well
i like
each your songs have like a chorus
a bridge yeah and versus you know what i
mean and they're they're it's and each
one of them seems to have a hook yeah
thank you you know what i mean
the formula isn't uh reinventing the
wheel by any means well
like you were saying i mean
they're
i believe these are pop songs you know i
think they're really catchy they're
pretty traditional song structures you
know i'm not doing anything wild i'm not
reinvented they're genuine they're not
like yeah no i appreciate that because
it contrived you can still do an a b a b
kind of song and and and have it be good
oh yeah you know and and have it be
catchy and not too bubblegum or not too
to this or to that so i'm kind of happy
with the process i'm kind of happy i
think you know eventually i would love
to kind of
i'm having a lot more fun with just like
instrumental breaks yeah yeah yeah let
the people breathe i don't need to be
singing from minute one i love those and
surf guitar yeah
interludes exactly so i've been having a
lot more fun and letting the soul speak
a little more and just kind of
going off of feel more so than going off
of like what i think is an impactful
arrangement you know
just have a good time
i know this question probably should
have been asked earlier but how old were
you when you started air
yeah um so like i was saying that you
know it came out of a four-piece band
right was freshman sophomore junior year
of high school
yeah we actually
i think it was right before my 17th
birthday
when we first put music out as air and
you you guys had some success with them
yeah i mean i wouldn't be here now if it
weren't for that hands down yeah um
creatively but also you know being able
to stay in music full-time um
we were young
it was senior year of high school and
this was like the golden age of youtube
and facebook and everything and and the
music was just blowing up yeah and i
remember one day going into the
principal's office and requesting the
principal for a weekend off or the
friday going into a weekend off because
we had just gotten booked at a frat in
at university of south carolina
[Music]
yep well so we going for community party
yeah and
and it was so funny because he gave it
he gave you the day off well yeah yeah
and he was the type of guy who was like
god i don't like this letting my
students take a day off to go
probably do a whole bunch of
debaucherous [ __ ]
with a bunch of frat bros in the south
sounds
like a mess but he was also the guy who
was all about experience and learning
from right going out and doing it that's
cool so he was just like yeah
yeah and he was he was he let us go yeah
and that was the beginning of the end
you know we just
from there on out it was just
graduated high school we're on the road
that june
[Music]
uh
except my mind and my calendar
[Music]
i know i've said this more than once
but it's time for my goddamn shoes
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
i'll still be getting stolen kicking
back on the low
[Music]
why didn't anybody tell me
that we're about to act down
we bout to burn it to the third degree
and you better not pass
[Music]
we'll never
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
i'll still be getting started kicking
back on the logo
[Music]
[Applause]
we'll
[Music]
oh
i'll still be getting stolen kicking
back on the logo
[Music]
i was going to ask you about the
transition between air and surfer girl
but i think we kind of went over that a
little bit so let me ask the next
question
joyride kind of deals with reality and
yet has a little bit of an escapist vibe
can you talk about joy or haida
yeah i mean i'm trying to think you know
that the whole ep was written
at the same time so you know the themes
are somewhat similar throughout but it
definitely
was this you know
i had never felt more alive at the time
because i was getting to be in the water
every day which you know even in
california can be a little rare but
every day in the water for like five
hours a day and just never felt more and
and creatively connected with the music
and
i would come out of the water and have a
new song idea in my head and just
i never felt
more
you know at peace but it was in this
juxtaposition of
i was also at a crossroads with myself
not knowing professionally where i
wanted to go
you know not exactly knowing what it was
that was
making me happy at the time and this was
like the whole world had shut down and
gone to [ __ ] it was a dark
time but yet i was able to take a lot of
right
moments of peace through it all and so i
almost kind of felt guilty about that
but then at the same time i'm like yo
you should just get whatever piece you
can get and so
joyride always felt to me as like this
song where it was like
you know
you're young you're lost you're kind of
looking around but like you know you're
still the sun's still shining on your
back even if it's like you know yeah
even if it's a dark time and you know
you know
i'm still driving the car you know to
and from the beach i still got the
spliff in my mouth you know you
kind of given a little perspective that
you know while you may be all up in your
head or or times may be a little tough
you know there are those little wins
throughout that can kind of keep you
pushing and keep you moving yeah it's a
great song when i listen to it it
reminds me of when i was young at the
beach yeah it's we and that feeling you
get of freedom and it's beautiful day
and it's like
yeah forget it but there's like this
almost there's this aggression behind it
too which is like let's [ __ ] hustle
and like it's time to work but at the
same time
you know be grateful for what you got
it's yeah i like doing that a little bit
a little bright with the dark
happy with the sad yeah you'll always
find kind of those bittersweet vibes in
my music for sure yeah and if we're not
going to the studio we're heading south
to mexico yeah oh my god
where do you like to surf around here by
the way
i'm lazy
so
well i moved to california and had never
surfed a point break ever
i had never well i went to sunset for my
first time which is sun slow yeah it's
well it's it's slow it's beautiful it's
just long peeling waves
granted it is crowded and it's kind of
dirty but you know what i i just i go to
sunset really all the time because if
it's hitting like three to four feet
yeah
longest ride i've ever ridden and
because i grew up on beach breaks how
about malibu i like malibu first point's
a lot of fun it's a really friendly
crowd
you used to not be so friendly yeah
i mean topanga i've gotten
pushed out the water a couple times but
um
you know i think i'm i can hold my own
now yeah
for a while there you know i just wasn't
conscious
of anybody right yeah
but now i know i know what the hell i'm
doing i'm a solid surfer and so it's
like you know yep stay out of
everybody's way know the etiquette have
a good time
yeah sounds beautiful catch me at sunset
i'll be there yeah a couple times a week
so you have
solo material under carter reeves yeah
super bloom is probably my favorite
thank you kind of whimsical
psychedelic tan
let's talk about that in a minute yeah
well
and i love the video by the way thank
you yeah
that was all shot in maine um
so that that's a crazy culmination
because
for a while there i was trying to trick
myself and tell myself i'm going to
be in the band and put out surfer girl
music but at the same time i'm still
going to be putting out solo carter
reeves music and we're going to do both
at the same time and everyone's going to
be so blown away by how cool that is
that is putting out secret side projects
and all this [ __ ] yeah yeah that's
exhausting you can't be you can't be two
artists dividing yourself up too much
and so when i was writing writing the ep
the the surfer girl ep that was also
when super bloom i wrote super bloom and
it was also when i wrote um another song
called let it slide and a song called
tell me laurel which are all the kind of
newer carter reef singles and grip um
yeah
that's an older one but but yeah you
know same same style and so
um super bloom's my favorite yeah like i
was telling you i was getting like heavy
into kind of like groove bass music drum
drum you know just one the drum and the
bass lock in
all is well in the world and you know
that kind of surf tones and psychedelia
and all this stuff so it's funny because
i put out super bloom tell me laurel and
and let it slide under carter reeves
they didn't get much traction but
listening back to them i go these would
be some pretty rad surfer girl songs
yeah especially super bloom yeah right
if it would fit right in i think it
would fit right in and so you know
sometimes i look back and say hey you
know maybe i should have just held on to
that for what i knew was
was the project with the hope and the
excitement behind it but so you're going
to put carter reeves on hold for him a
little bit yeah yeah yeah i think i was
i was having a bit of an identity crisis
you know i didn't know
i didn't know what i was doing and and
and it and it was it didn't seem to be
working well creating is what you were
doing yeah yeah well that's thank god
you know i always look at that i go yeah
once you create something unless you
destroy it you can't uncreate it that
right there is a win already so
so
family off cali roots rhythm 2021 yeah
kind of like relates to that whole album
yeah right and yeah
what an amazing opportunity to to
collaborate with freaking collie buds it
was uh how did you get a hold of colin
and how did that happen that was a wild
couple weeks because i got a call from
from adam
saying cauli listen to the project he's
a fan he wants to invite you to be on
the the cauli
the the 2021 rhythm and like
you know immediately and oh it's
produced by johnny cosmic by the way and
cauli and so immediately i was just like
okay whoa that's a big deal but on top
of that the fact that collie even took
the time to listen and gets down with
the project and likes it i was just like
you know i grew up i grew up listening
to cauli as well you know he didn't have
as strong an impact as you know some of
those other guys but i was a big fan
yeah um i like comment buds he's rad
yeah well and so and colin's very nice
guy he's a [ __ ] sweetheart man he's
great but it it so it was crazy because
it went from
hey you want to hop on this rhythm and i
was yeah sure and i actually had a
really hard time writing to it at first
because i think i wanted to do something
so crazy and then i kind of just let
let the heart take over a little bit and
that's where we ended up i really loved
the song and i sent it to adam and he
goes dude this is super unique nobody
else is really sounding like this one on
it and um collie heard it and he called
me up and he was like this is really
dope man this is one of my favorites
thank you
um
and then you know two weeks later i got
a call from my booking agent saying what
do you think about doing uh three weeks
with cali buds on tour this summer i
said
okay great and do it can i play his song
too like the song we did together yeah
of course it was just like oh my gosh so
it went it
that was kind of the first
seal of approval
you know and and
that one felt really good that was that
was a
yeah that's really cool that was a good
one that's really cool
i just he sent over the instrumental for
2022 which obviously i can't share
but i
i'm not invited to be on for 2022 but i
listen to the beat and i go oh [ __ ]
people are gonna like this one
he's got a good one coming up for 22.
cool that's brad you know that kind of
reminded me of mike loves 2020 the 2021
and that was the first one they did yeah
yeah exactly yeah yeah yeah mike mike's
kelly i like my club um you have a new
single out with the hip abduction called
two yeah and how did this collab come
about this one was fun uh
this one's got kind of a cool story i um
you know i was writing the album and and
you know producing it all out as demos
kind of over a year and some change in
it
a lot of them had empty verses you know
just like empty second verses empty
first verses you know in hopes that
maybe a feature would come yeah and this
one just sat empty for a long time so i
started writing up some verses and
saying you know i'm happy to fill it out
you know but i still think we can find
someone that will put a weird and cool
spin on it because it's definitely
got a hip-hop vibe to it definitely in
the beat and so
um the label put me in touch with with
david knew from from the hip abduction
and he's the one that did the verses
yeah yeah and he they put me in touch
just hey this is a guy in the scene he
kind of is doing this like indie funk
folk
connor reggae thing like he was on the
fringe the same way i think the surfer
girl project is is kind of on the fringe
a little bit
and uh
we just kind of like we just started
texting back and forth kind of hit it
off a little bit i didn't ask him to get
on any music you know and it just so
happened that he was going to be in
asheville north carolina
on a camping trip
uh the same time that i
the band was opening for the elevators
so he in nashville yeah yeah and at the
salvage station in nashville and i'm
gonna call you out david how dare you
call me an hour before the show asking
for guest list tickets you're an artist
you know how this works you gotta give
me at least five days in advance no but
i gave him [ __ ] for that too when he did
it um so i was like yeah i'll see what i
can do if i can squeeze you in i guess
you know doors are in an hour
and uh we get him to the show and and
he's there and
he catches the whole set he's just like
you know watches the whole set just
having a good time and then we play i i
played too because i was just
freestyling a second verse or just kind
of going off of versus the second time
and after the show he goes what's that
last song on the set i said that one's
two you know just enough for two you
know i'm just just finishing it now
this one sounds like it might not be so
yeah that's a van nuys
and i was like yeah that sounds you know
enough for two still work shopping and
still want to work on the production and
there's an empty verse and he was just
like that's the hit that's a hit that
was my favorite one out of the whole set
i go thanks dude you you want to get on
it and he's just like yeah you mind if i
do some production on it too it's like
of course i mean if you've ever listened
to hip abduction you know david produces
all if not
cool tunes yeah he's a great producer
and so
you know i sent it to him pretty much
just like copied and pasted that first
verse area in the second verse and he
stripped it back he added like you know
some sub bass to it he added a new
little guitar line on top yeah the bass
is it's funky and he sent it back with
these breezy kind of reverb very indeed
out vocals and i go
i'm kind of bringing this hip hop
sing wrap aggression thing going on and
a and a high hook and then comes to his
verse and it kind of strips back and
he's just breezy on it and i was like i
wanted something weird i wanted
something different not just like a rap
verse or
you know just kind of a boring verse and
david came through and yeah the hip
abduction hit it with a oh it's a great
song
yeah yeah thanks i dig it
took a note from the grateful dead on
that little melody it's kind of a weird
little
yeah
it's like a
disconsolating yeah
yeah um
yeah mixolydian you got it
yeah i'm thinking maybe we get to play a
song with card let's do it i'm down so
right after and and speaking of it
enough for two uh i want to thank
ellie cannabis for
giving us enough for two yeah
and then and then something and then and
some other twos yeah maybe
other collabs in the works
yeah i mean so the album's done yeah the
album comes out
at the end of september so early
september wow i just and i haven't heard
any of these songs except for two right
it's the only that's the first single
off the album uh i can't wait
yeah i'm stoked so the next the next
single that comes out in about two weeks
it's called sunrise which is also the
name of the album um which is
you heard it here folks first yes indeed
you did
uh that one's featuring the elevators so
we got jackson from the elevators a
fellow new england guy on there
uh god he just
graced it with his smooth smooth voice
this one's a cool one it's kind of got
like a jack johnson vibe it's a lot more
acoustic it's a lot more textural and
and organic
um
got got got swayze on the album i'm
working with little stranger on a record
uh
how cool man i got a good friend of mine
abby the nomad who's an incredible
rapper out of houston
and then
we got marcia from the skins i'm not i
don't know if you're familiar with the
skins but they're really killer
yeah yeah i mean they've had yeah
they've they've been rocking
keeping up with you guys
i do remember this again
on my phone she's very forgiving i'm
sure it's okay
um
but and she and i you know
we had been we met
eight years ago and we actually lived
together in brooklyn for a hot minute
and uh
she had just been a friend for a while
and we lost touch for a good bit and
then
you know when i when we kind of made the
dabble back into the the the modern
reggae space you know she was the first
person i hit up just being like yo
tell me about it
uh oh my eyes are watering
okay that uh it's that la cannabisco
seeing things
um well
you know marcia she's incredible and and
his skins are incredible and and
you know i was kind of like yo dude i'm
working on this project i'm trying to
come back what do you think and
she's like i really dig it i think the
world has missed you this space has
missed you and and i was like you want
to get on a song she was like yeah of
course and so she's she's the homie and
she doesn't really do many features so
i'm obviously honored that she would
that is really cool i can't wait to for
the record to come out and when does it
get released
september
9th or 10th it's whatever the weekend
right after labor day is um
would have been nice to have it pop out
in the summer but you know
i think it's got a good fall vibe but
it's also
all
all of the music was
run through the filter of johnny cosmic
wow so i produced everything but then i
took it up to johnny and you know he
knows how to take something that sounds
pretty good
too
incredible so the new brian you know
dude for real i mean like without
johnny's touch on this album it would
have been it would have been solid yeah
but he takes it to the next level and so
yeah we complement each other really
well that is really cool lucky got to
work with johnny for sure
so i've got a few uh
quick questions rapid fire yeah most
memorable gig
red rocks opening up for dirty heads and
pepper as air
um cold cold summer day
pouring rain it might have even hailed
pouring rain up in the in the colorado
mountains
we were not looking forward to going out
on stage in the cold rain
the fans were not happy
they just were ready to see some music
we step out on stage
turns to a drizzle
stops
sun comes out oh my god shining
beautiful warm evening from there on out
we brought the sunshine it was crazy
it was crazy how cool very symbolic it
was nice
favorite hip-hop artist
oh that's tough i mean i would say cuddy
just kid cudi had just such a strong
impact on me with his like melodic
singing
wrapping so it's got to be cutty
favorite reggae artist
uh i know it's hard to say favorite
right yeah
i don't know i mean honestly everything
that was coming out of studio one you
know
coxswain's studio one from from cox and
don you know yeah the early
early 60s into the early 70s i think you
know freddie mckay heptones
uh
just
willie williams like all
kind of that really old rootsy stuff is
definitely some of my favorite
off top
it's hard to pin one guy down yeah yeah
you know or gal down okay favorite old
school artist we kind of went through
that yeah uh beatles speech boys okay
uh the list favorite very long favorite
ineffable artist other than yourself
yeah uh
oh and i and i don't wanna draw
that's uh that's a good one i
i gotta say i'm really jacked up on the
hip abduction right now i know that
sounds
that's cool i'm calling out friends but
it's either the hip abduction or the
elevators yeah i think the elevators
are just such a rock solid band
touring with them they are tight they
are down to a t yet they give each other
enough freedom to have a good time
always on stage and you're going on tour
with them right uh we did last fall oh
you did hopefully that's not the last
one though i know it won't be but uh the
elevators are just tight denim he's the
future i'm really digging his hybrid pop
hip hop punk sound he's he's killing it
and then the hip abduction that's just
the type of music i listen to that's
cool though i gave you three i'm trying
to be yeah let's go diplomatically
yeah exactly i didn't want i knew that
question was going to like maybe cause
somebody to get master
oh no no no favorite cannabis strains
um
i haven't gotten my hands on jack
herrera in a long time
and that i grew up
my older brother's
friend's
older brother
always had some good good good [ __ ] and
so yeah i was like in high school
smoking jack and yeah it's just a lucky
guy
favorite foods
favorite foods um
big into kind of
you know
a middle eastern kind of just chicken
rice
throw some lamb in there
kebabs any of that that's cool donor
anything bubba ganesh yeah oh my god
uh favorite new england bud
favorite new england bud
damn i'm not sure i'm too familiar with
new england-centric strains do you have
any names or i don't but you know i
interviewed um
roots
from
he had a
podcast he stopped because he had a baby
he was from maine
so uh ideal gig
ideal gig um
even though the redrock one sounded
pretty good pretty good um i would say
the bill to me would be
in no particular order
denim
i want coffee there she's incredible
uh i don't know if you know tess elated
he's also unineffable yeah he's he's uh
just a killer kind of like pop
rap dancehall artist from jamaica
throw him in there throw me in there
and uh
and there we go get the dirty heads on
there yeah you know they have such a rad
fan base yeah and they have such a cool
sound yeah
yeah coffee's great too
upcoming gigs upcoming gigs we got two
shows in northern northern california
uh in june
we've got june 15th in
felton california so the santa cruz
people should should come up into the
mountains for that
and then uh oh yes
hello
felt music hall
the 15th of june
uh opening up for the hip abduction
doing direct support which is gonna be
great and then we the next night are
shipping up to san francisco we're going
to be in berkeley at the cornerstone
and uh that's on the 16th at the
cornerstone yeah how cool that's a
really rad venue
um
and then like i was telling you chanzo
we're thinking try and do some sort of
release party once the album's out
um and then of course going out for two
weeks this summer with bali who and
shwayze which is gonna be really rad
so
going on the road this summer for two
weeks with swayze and ballyhoo and it's
gonna be a really great time we're doing
the midwest and in fact we're locking in
logistics now and it's looking
unfortunately like the whole band can't
come this summer which is terrifying
uh-oh but if you need a keyboard player
thank you but i have i think a really
interesting hack
i have a friend who's gonna rent me his
camper van
like a pro like a dodge pro mouse or
with a bed in the back
i'm just gonna do the whole thing solo
we're gonna have drums come out for sure
yeah and then we're gonna do solo just
guitar drums get some bass going and
practice out right now yeah
exactly here exactly so it's going to be
a fun tour it's going to be a little bit
of a fun setup too you're going to be
playing any of the new songs definitely
yeah yeah how cool yeah
um
where can our audience find you on
social media yeah social media of course
instagram being at surfer girl music
which is kind of the same handle for
twitter and
facebook and uh on top of that we've got
a discord server which is uh i'm pretty
new to discord but it's a really cool
chat room and way to connect directly
with fans a little different than
facebook and all the other stuff so it's
called crane road surf club which is
kind of
the home venue of surfer girl it doesn't
exist it's all an imaginary concept but
surfer girl headlining crane road surf
club um
but then finally you know
surfergirlmusic.com and
all that good stuff cool easy spotify
apple music youtube
if you're there we're there this is that
easy okay so um
before we wrap up would you like to
shout out to anybody
yes i would i would love to shout out to
my wonderful team because this is the
first time i've had a team in a really
long time and it's
true what they say you cannot do this
[ __ ] alone
um so the team
brock laurel adam at an effort ball
thomas of course patrick at mint talent
group incredible booking agent got my
man aj uh who's just in incredible just
smart people it's just [ __ ] cool to
have an awesome team that is cool bro um
and then of course like the fans like
it's been crazy to see this project get
so much traction so quickly um i think
it's people from from air who are
circling back and saying hey welcome
back
but we're making a lot of new fans and
i love this
scene of music because the fans are so
loyal and so loving and just give and
give and give and and
i'm here to give and give and give too
so we'll both be giving back and forth
and and it's just been
it's been cool it's been overwhelming
love so obviously the fans of course
because we're just getting started
there's gonna be a long long time coming
so yeah well
shout out to mr botsani
thanks a lot indeed and uh la cannabisco
come on oh yeah cannabis we're gonna
hook it up right here uh
so i want to thank you for coming down
today it's been a pleasure and if you
you know when that release party you
know happens you'll twist my arm i'll be
there we'll get callie hi there easy all
right thanks bro thank you chanzo all
righty so
callie hi out
[Music]
shut the door
except for you
[Music]
if
for your sunshine
[Music]
waiting for someone
no
[Music]
enough for you
you