[Music]
so here's a camp this question that I've
been pondering for a little
while at what point at what percentage
do the tpin become possibly I I don't
even know if it's possible but like
damaging you know to our lungs and stuff
you know where we keep searching for
these really high tpine profiles go
smoke some well there's got to be some
kind of number on like exposure to
like that's why I feel like rosin is
so like I I bet 10 years from now
they're going to be a lot of lungs that
even though you think it's healthier
you're you're you're getting that much
high dose of specific uh kind of
cleaning style turpion in your
lungs yeah I I was just thinking about
that the last couple months I was like
you know I remember growing some uh
oh what was it orange uh orange
something it was super [ __ ] T like
dreadfully turpy and whenever I smoked I
was like oh man my [ __ ] chest hurts
my lungs hurt like I don't know if it's
just that particular turine and
my my Constitution to it or what it is
but there's definitely a level tpine
toxicity would be a thing so yeah but I
I'm just curious like and if so like
it's it must be different for different
tpin so like
what T's good for every person there's
no way like yeah I it would be different
like because like how sensitive I am to
stuff like uh L right small amounts of
Lan will [ __ ] me up that's why I can't
smoke like lavender
strain every time I take a dab or
something like I have a dab rig my lungs
would [ __ ] feel like they're dead for
like a week and this Tony said it might
be the wax and the lipids and all that
you know what I mean something different
I listen to people dab all the time
their cough is different than somebody
that smokes weed sound off uh my style
grow my Instagram is right there Philo
Phil yeah like the the mac and stuff and
stuff with Mac in it
I I mean it looks like a beautiful plant
but I can't smoke it it tastes like
cilantro
it it gives it makes my eyes hurt
immediately after smoking it I mentioned
that to somebody who gave me some a
while back and also some cultivars
immediately when I smoke them make my
eye pain so much worse it increase
glaucoma pressure this F and the other
and some some of them it's just like
it's gone as soon as you get near it
like so there's they're not all the same
for me that's in my experience at least
not all the
same I can to get my excessive tpine
causes excessive
lipid perox oxidation production and
subsequent
apop so that could lead to
death well I mean I know I know with
tpin there there is a level but I'm like
I know cannabis tpin aren't any
different I know be able to grow it to a
level that's toxic or right even like
even I don't know if we can even press
it in to that because of how low the
level is on the amount that we're
getting like if lemoning on a plant's
not going to be at 4% by itself usually
it's going to be like 2% or less so
concentrate that into a uh like a wax or
something like you can do the math if
you if your weed was 20% and now you're
at 90 right you concentrated at five
times so 2 * 5 now you're up to 10% is
that level of uh that tpine toxic to the
human
that'd be like the maximum level we're
going to be able to get that to as a
singular tpine but then there's is the
mixture of those tpping worse than a
singular level like if I had all of them
at 10 is that just as bad as one of them
is
10 I mean I feel like this is a valid
question like taking a a hit off of a um
like a vape cartridge I can tell when
they've got fake [ __ ] turps in them
and [ __ ] like it it the way it sticks in
my mouth like we don't do that dude like
and it's not because they're growing
fire weed because they'd be selling it
in there dude instead of pressing it
completely and there ain't no weed in
the shop like it never it's never live
[ __ ] it's always something that it's
either an isolate that's had that added
to it man there's I don't care if the
carts are live rosin or or what they are
but anytime I take a a hit of those dabs
or or a cart or something like that I
get what I call the whooping cough cough
you know it's like it there's nothing
but with flow and stuff like the expect
expector expect however you say that
like you actually feel like you're
coughing something up you know but with
the dabs it's like this hollow
like and then when you try and breathe
again it makes you cough it's like Feels
Like It Coats my lungs with something
that's Dam near like coating lipids and
fats I I worked in a Candle factory
right and you could only work so many
hours because the amount of exposure
you'd have the fat and lipids in the air
they you couldn't do overtime after a
certain amount of time they would
literally have to have another person
for the next shift because of those
exposures of of fats and lipids like you
could stop breathing this [ __ ] now when
you're making regular bubble hash yeah
are you washing those fats and lipids
off
well sometimes depend usually not like
that's where like when people show their
their uh Tricom heads like real close up
like Jen's G or uh jendo like yeah jend
do um Jen um she also do static cleaning
but she showed water hash before too if
you do a high grade you're trying to
collect that head without disturbing it
that's why you don't put a lot of ice in
there that's why you want your water
cold as possible that's why like our our
levels of how we did it changed we used
to just beat the [ __ ] out of weed do it
for too long but you can take that and
that's where that that head with a lot
of fats and lipids actually is
beneficial because it doesn't fall apart
and allow those oils to not quite
emulsify but become part of suspension
in the water where theyd go through your
net like the screens aren't small enough
to catch like liquid oil so theny to
catch so then if you're
making straight water hash and you're
still retaining those fats and lipids
M when you when you press that you're
supposed to be getting rid of the fats
and lipids and just left with tpin and
how how are you getting rid of the fats
and lipids pressing it you're
emulsifying it
together with heat and pressure okay
okay at least that's my view like
those they they get they're small
they're going to pass through like if
you're using a 25 micron they're passing
through that right but some of it
actually based on how greasy it is can
like reabsorb back in the flow that's
why doing flow sucks and they went to
doing like cash but even with some of
that just quickly keep an eye for uh the
backstage I got it carry on why who'd
you invite would like um this all
just so certain bats and lipids would
definitely be more runny at different
temperatures yeah it's just like if
you've got Mantika or if you've got lard
or butter like they're all fats but they
all act differently there's like fat in
an animal also there's a type of fat
that melts and renders real easy and a
type of fat that will stay hard and
doesn't want to melt down is readly each
one of those acts different in
suspension even though water and oil
don't mix
the fact that you can break it up enough
to just end up in the water floating
around is why it'll pass through and you
don't catch a lot of your [ __ ] you're
trying to catch heads that are
undisturbed hot bacon grease will leak
through a SI cold bacon grease will stop
in it that's another thing to think
about and that's where the cold thing is
if you can keep that head from snapping
so breaking off and then shattering and
that's like where they ask about weed
that presses like all that's dependent
on I believe the fats and lipids that
are encasing it are they thick enough to
keep that from being disturbed during
the process okay so another question all
right now when we're smoking pause
shedar pause
shedar does hash make you cough also
hash makes me cough a little bit more
than
flow well yeah it's but
it's it it burns more smoke I would
believe whoops there we go there he is
hey G hey how are you hi
everyone thanks thanks for the impromptu
all right the impromptu jump on let me
give everyone context ghee co-founder Po
and Barkley I've known him since uh I I
love when we first crossed P I think it
was like uh 2016 is or something at uh
at what was it in San
Bernardino
UMO and uh so the topic is something you
and I were talking about in what you got
are you showing
something F you got you got the wrong
guy wrong
guy so so the the topic is is you and I
in Vegas were talking about uh like tpin
and like being kind of cleaning agents
and and the effect on lungs and so can
you kind of give your thoughts on
on rosin and lungs yeah AB absolutely so
because you've changed your perspective
over time right uh yes well look this is
the beauty of an emerging industry we
continue to learn we continue to dig
into the science and you know at Po and
Barkley and papa select our hash brand
we would say Best in Class which meant
you know the the more you know the
better it gets or like if I know better
I do better so we all have to stay open
in our industry for science to come down
and for facts to come out right because
this is not while we may have been in
the industry like myself for 25 years
been using canvas for a long time it's
only now that we're really getting the
scientific tools and Analysis that we
need to understand what's happening
right but when we think about uh tpin
okay naturally occurring tpin 3 4% in
the flow same thing in the concentrates
tpin are volatile organic compounds
right they are in themselves yes my
issue is one getting away from plant
medicine I'm going to tell you guys
right now I just recently sold Po and
Barkley and cannabis has been good to me
I am on a mission to crush distillate
everybody here seems old enough to
remember when the clear came out and we
were all like oh the clear we all wanted
diamonds we all wanted strong THC that
is drug and prohibition culture I'm sure
none of us are drinking moonshine right
now right reality is the gift of
legalization is abundance and to just
have tasty delicious things if you need
more use more but stronger is not the
answer that being said you have these
vape pen companies out here now using uh
voc's or tpin to one make their formula
thinner so that it can work in
cartridges and also amplify the taste
well that may present a problem I want
to level set smoking and all the
carcinogens associated with that are not
on the same level as vaping so we are
kind of like digging into the minutia if
you will but when you start to put eight
plus % tpin in a vape cart we do have to
ask the question is that presenting
extra
carcinogens into the lungs right isn't
it better to just have a better saucing
program or better yet work with your
Chinese or domestic manufacturer to find
an apparatus that will burn your viscous
oil and then I'll go on top of that I
started you know so when we met actually
in 2016 I was just finishing up and
still have a company in Colorado that
was a vape company and like everybody
else coming out of prohibition I wanted
to race to the bottom over refine
cannabis and you met me right when I was
meeting my partner it was actually late
2015 at one of these old school High
Times events with my partner Adam as we
were getting ready to start popping
barkle which is when luckily I was
pulled back into reality of plant
medicine first and foremost right and
solventless and clean clean cannabis
right all that said this notion that
Vape carts have to be the way forward no
now that we have puffo devices and all
these electronic vaping devices
shouldn't we just be understanding that
a nice concentrate and some aroma
therapy is the way to go you don't need
to put any more tpin in a good
solventless concentrate good for that
matter so this over tping of carts it
does worth saying are tpin volatile
organic compounds which they are facts
could they get to a level in Vape carts
where they become detrimental to our
health and the the answer is absolutely
yes for those of you I don't know if you
guys are going to MJ unpacked in a few
weeks here uh in St Louis I'll be
talking about what's on your shelf with
Alec Dixon and a couple of other
retailers talking about some of the
pesticide scares some of the scares that
we've had here in the
industry and tpin may come up right
because we need to as an industry kind
of self-regulate because if something
goes wrong we're we're on the wrong side
of this already right so we need really
have our p's and q's up and people throw
around Turin and RP stuff and add turps
willy-nilly forgetting that these are
carcinogens and they are found in very
small quantities in the plants and if we
one never mind unnatural tpin you can
get way out of pocket with that and even
if they're naturally derived cannabis
tpin putting too much in could present a
problem so that's just my general take
on turps I'm trying to St facts somebody
has different facts I'd love to hear
them because I'm always trying to get
educated no I agree with everything you
were saying um absolutely
is gabage but but I feel the problem a
lot with that like he brought up using
puffco and such great idea but it's hard
for us on the smaller side of this to be
able to fight big tobacco who's actually
the ones
pushing the the pin they're the ones
that want you to rely on something that
can sell you in a package repeatedly
with their label on it and replace the
product that you're not going to want to
use anymore which is going to be their
tobacco soon as Canabis becomes federal
legal everywhere you're going to be able
to pick up weed easier than tobacco and
you will switch over and they'll want
you to because of the price difference
in what they can charge you they can
charge you double triple for cannabis
what they can for tobacco they're
they'll take that away for a moment and
then that'll become a novelty where they
can re reintroduce it and say it to you
on a smaller scale but at a more
increased price they want to Corner
multiple markets with this thing and
they're hooking you right now with the
flavorings are added Kevin talked about
that where they're like adding fruity
flavors and such they they brought the
Menthol flavored part of cigarette into
the pin and it's a way for you to easily
get hooked to a product because it
tastes just like the one they're
replacing it with yeah absolutely and
look so I I would remind everyone and as
you guys are you know hipping people to
cannabis and cannabis becoming more
legal we are born of counterculture and
we need to stay counterculture one of
the terms I used the other day in
Chicago is this no notion of compromise
to legitimize we don't need them to
legitimize us we do not need to look
like Pharma tobacco or alcohol that's
why I'm not big on the Beverages and
yeah vape pens were about E6 and they
were supposed to reduce nicotine and now
I have a teenager that [ __ ] uses more
nicotine than I do when when I used to
smoke cigarettes I almost wish she
smoked cigarettes at this point given
the addiction to nicotine right so to
your point we are being gamed as we
always have been one of the cool things
that Alec Dixon bought up about this is
as we talk about dirty things in
cannabis and all this testing popping
what we're realizing is they tried to
game Us by saying oh we need to test
cannabis to this level and what we're
finding out especially with the value
added products like you know gummies and
chocolates and all these other things
that are coming out is that it's the
rest of the supply chain that's super
dirty and keeps popping and testing we
have an opportunity here to really
continue our Green Revolution and Show
an example of what clean products can be
right and not fall into the traps of
tobacco trying to be it make it
convenient for us to your point like
with Menthol and the flavorings I don't
even I am so against flavors in cannabis
all the way down to Gummies at Papa
select we were blessed to create a gummy
where the only thing that flavored and
colored it was the tpin that's a strain
specific gummy does it take TLC to keep
those volatile uh TLC meaning tender
loving care to keep the vo's in the hash
so that it stays there and is potent
enough to flavor a gummy yeah you got to
want to do that but if I wanted a
strawberry gummy I would go to the mall
having a strawberry gummy or anything
that's not cannabis flavored in the
dispensary it's like why I could get a
flavored EIG anywhere I could get
flavored gummies anywhere I go to a
dispensary I want to taste all the
different strains I want to smoke all
the different strains that's what we
should be advocating for but yet when we
go into our retail outlets now they're
looking more and more like a CVS right
distillate fueled [ __ ] which is just
like Marinol and satx we had Marinol and
satex we had distillate products before
during prohibition now is the time to
say it's abundant and when it comes to
this notion of puup go and whatnot I I'm
I I want yall to just Vision in the
future to your point when cannabis is
easier to grow than tobacco much cheaper
there's a version of this where we are
not dabbing and holding it and coughing
but we're putting grams of of of rosin
on hot plates and letting it just aroma
therapy just breathe in delicious chirps
old yeah old that's the gift that we
should be for not this [ __ ] where
they're trying to keep putting taxes on
it because they're like oh well you only
need a few milligrams no I need
thousands of milligrams in the air all
in my face right it's a commodity and
should be based on how much it costs to
actually grow farmers are out here dying
because there's too much weed in
California and Oregon and Washington and
Colorado all our mature States one way
to solve that is to stop holding on
roaches stop trying to do Dives stop
trying to hold in the weed and just let
it out let it truly be free and in the
air right that's I think changing some
habits and some cultural things to
embrace this gift of abundance is what's
needed and not just just quickly show G
the rotten live rosin as a there we
go people it's it's the like the right
on demand is more of what they love if
they were never shown Parts people would
love oldw World hash just as much it's a
more it's a quality product that you
can't hide you can hide everything in a
cart
yeah well that's the reason it's in a
cart too yeah exactly 100% live Ros and
carts you know I mean those of you who
are familiar with some manufacturing
processes if you sauce which takes time
right there's no real way to that I know
of to quickly sauce and kind of separate
out uh your fats right to make it a
little bit less viscous to work in the
cart that's a Time factor and a lot of
people want to cut corners on that time
so they'll add tpin or sometimes they'll
add MCT and in the worst cases they'll
add PG or some [ __ ] like that right but
if you take enough time you can sauce it
out to have the viscosity secondly yes
you have to get a quality glass cart
that has gigantic holes so that it can
absorb a thicker material but lastly
carts are like the beer can of cannabis
it will only ever taste so good the fact
is you have an oil product that's going
to be wehe multiple times most carts are
in a clear glass cartridge therefore
exposed to UV light so that product is
completely degrading from the minute
it's it is a convenience factor so it's
hard to talk quality and convenience
cards have a high convenience factor
which by definition means their quality
is always going to be impacted right
look do I use carts of course I will
keep a cart especially nowadays where
people are all Draconian I have to have
one tap to my leg or something when I go
to the concert you know what I mean
because they're like frisking You Down
nowadays looking for lighters and
everything Amusement Parts too I used to
go to Great Adventure full of weed and
now they're not wait they don't call it
great adventure here they call it Six
Flags um you know they pat you down now
looking for all your weed and [ __ ] and
I'm like so you got to get the Vape
carts all hidden and whatnot so Vape
carts do have their place a place yeah
but it's not really in the quality
sector and so I know a lot of Vape C
Vape manufacturers kind of like Bud
Light bestselling beer want to flex at
all these events because they got the
money because they're selling a lot of
product but I'm quick to tell you're
just like Bud Light I'm glad that you're
making money I'm glad that you have nice
market share but you will never be
quality period the end and like he says
like doing all of it right in a cart
that gets spurned over and over and over
that's like taking all your weed and
rolling it in one giant joint and you
smoke it all the time like that till
it's at the end the first hit was fire
but that last hit tasted like a [ __ ]
just dude it was booty
hole um now you were talking about carts
with the tur and added tpes do you think
flour will ever cuz everyone's searching
for a higher T percentage on their flour
nowadays as well because it carries over
to their hash and so on and so forth you
think we'll ever see that that negative
level of Tarpin and
flour you know it it's a great question
I think that more tpin and flour will
affect smok ability right I do think
that those folks who grow for hash are
growing for tarpine content because it's
getting lost in the processing right so
if you're growing for hash yeah I think
you want to try to get as much breed for
tpin as much but if you're growing for
smoke ability which interestingly enough
I don't know how many people are focused
on that these days um you might not want
to have so much tpin because it's going
to be harsh one point you're going to
smoke flour in a way that is not about
getting high but about how smooth it is
and how tasty it is and taste is how
much is the turine content but too much
turpine content tickles it back your
throat and it's kind of harsh too little
turkey content it's not wow in the mouth
so it's that balance right um same thing
with potency right right now everybody's
trying to be north of 30% THC and it's
like really I was just walking with my
wife the other day I was like one day
we're going to go and there's GNA be all
different ratios of THC and CBD it won't
be about potency it'll be about taste
turpine content and quality of smoke and
rooll right now we're all from I I
understand what happened to the pandemic
but these dog walkers and most pre-roll
sucking through a tiny little hole if
you would ask me if you ask me now when
cannabis is legal I'm going to roll
fatties the only pre-roll should be
minimum half inch in size to let more
air in so that it's a fun smoke just
like a cigarillo or whatnot right it's
like a cigar smaller than cigarettes
it's ridiculous it's so small you heat
up that cherry on it and it kills all
the flavor of the joint you want a small
and now you can do a larger grind
that'll hold itself instead of a tighter
smaller grind that's just pack the same
reason why they got big cigars and
they're better than a tiny little
[ __ ] pack of swisser sweets and [ __ ]
like those things taste terrible the
other day sh me for having a cannabis
cigar talking about well you know not
all of us can afford a $50 canar and I
was like look I'm sorry that I'm in the
future but can it shouldn't be more
expensive it's artificially expensive
we're out here overgrown right another
way to start educating consumers is roll
a lot of weed stop being scared of weed
Farmers want to sell more weed and
remember that double-edged sword when
people talk about
distillate that disempowers the farmer
and we can never let that happen because
the minute we're growing for biomass or
growing for that kind of extraction the
farmer's job doesn't matter solventless
if you're doing
rosin the farmer matters because if they
don't grow a clean product that's turpy
with big ass tricomes you can't get a
good extraction if the farmer doesn't
cure their flour and dry it correctly it
won't smoke well right so if we honor
our farms in the product they're
creating we'll get great product and one
way for them not to be backed up is for
us to change our practices around using
it truly truly start to use cannabis and
understand that this is an abundant
god-given plan and we held it back
artificially and now that it's Unleashed
let's let it in but many of our
practices stemming from compliance
unfortunately are still out of scarcity
and drug culture tiny little joints you
know what I mean five little milligrams
or vape carts and all these ways to
maximize our milligrams when we should
it's not the milligrams will come just
like alcohol is all standardized you're
gonna get drunk but on your way you're
gonna find the things that taste good
you know you're going to look for brands
that do it right that meet your values
we're not even having those
conversations in cannabis most people
not Mo I don't think anybody on this
call but the majority of money made in
cannabis now is being spent with bad who
give a [ __ ] about us don't care about
the farmers and are just creating
products to give you THC as if you're a
drug addict and like there's still a lot
of work to be done advocacy wise and I'm
on fire about it as you can
tell just Qui just quickly G you you had
a hard stop at 12 oh yeah thanks for so
one I I I appreciate it raise your hand
if you'd like to see can I give you a
homework assignment yeah absolutely can
can you think of some people you'd like
to chop it up with and a topic you'd
want to talk about we'll go live on
YouTube oh absolutely yeah I who who
would like to watch that show of
hands oh what you got this is your
chance to raise your hand loud and
proud there we go well it was nice to me
the call I I really appreciate it I do
have to bounce um yeah I'll I'll I'll
send you some topics and some folks that
we could put together I love talking
about this you guys you know I I think
the the the the weirdness here is we
have this kind of legalization we have
all this misinformation they're still
trying to hold us back and so we can't
give up the we cannot give up the mantle
of advocacy there is a version of this
industry that is different than tobacco
alcohol and we need to demand it we need
to demand the abundance and the gifts
that this plant wants to give us and not
allow folks to force us back into this
Pharma Paradigm right it's a real
threat before you po out hey thank you
thank you for popping in and uh you can
pop in anytime you want just know you
thanks I appreciate you care byebye see
again all right the original answer
about it I guess that's three at least
three now that are for exactly what we
said there there's a point of no return
where we're we're trying to get to
because it looks shiny and [ __ ] but once
you get there it's it's shiny Edge to it
that's probably going to cut us we don't
cheddar I think that was directed at you
when you're listening to your Sublime on
your porch and drinking your white claw
maybe switch it up to some red wine no I
guess my my my original question has
been answered
[Music]