[Music]
okay guys we are three days after you
last saw it in the previous video
i'm starting to notice that the leaves
are changing a little bit of color and
they're starting to droop a little bit
usually to me that means the clone is
ready for soil so let's check out the
roots on this bad boy
oh yeah
i would say that's ready for the soil
there we go guys that is the roots
that is the roots we got off of this
massive
freaking cloning attempt so now we're
just gonna put it in soil we're gonna
see if it lives
check out those roots
[Music]
all right guys we are 24 hours after
taking it from the aero cloner and
putting it into the pot and these things
look pretty limp there's not much water
pressure this is actually what i was
expecting when i took it as a clone but
hey it did good in the aero cloner uh
right now i've just been misting it with
some water kind of foliar feed it a
little bit if i can and we're going to
leave it in here and see what happens do
you think it's going to bounce back
put your comments in the comment section
holy cow y'all it's five days since i
took this thing out of the cloner
it was looking a little limp these
things were
down and droopy but look at that they're
up they're turgid there's water pressure
they're growing
so uh
i don't think i'm the first but
when's the last time you saw somebody
take a two foot clone
boom
breaking science
or whatever
now the only thing really left to do is
take this
and take the bottom half
and flower them and we'll see how we get
it
we're back we've got our top we've got
our bottom and we're about ready to put
these into flour
and for anybody that was curious the
amount of time this took is not very
much uh less than 30 days so it took 27
days actually on the 26th i made the cut
on the 8th i had my first roots which
you saw in part 1.
that was a 12 day difference
six days after that on the 14th i
transplanted it into the soil with that
big root mass which you see in this
video
and nine days after that on the 23rd
i'm putting them into flour
so in a month's time i really created
two plants out of one because of this
twin peaks two plant topping system
this bottom part you know it really
filled out it really filled in it became
a nice bush with a lot of top colas
these middles have filled in so oh
there's to be a lot of bud produced on
this plant
and it's a long way from that scraggly
looking plant in the beginning
less than 30 days ago
and we got our top you know it's it's
got nice water pressure in it now it's
looking good it's getting new growth and
really i'd probably let it go another
week but i'm putting it in the flour now
because hey rotation is rotation guys
um
we are 10 days into flower now and in
case i haven't said it yet i'm going to
declare this one a successful clone i
mean look at them we've got them
starting to form buds both the top both
the bottom we're getting nice bud
formation
so
yes this successfully has been a clone
and i am definitely gonna say that's the
largest clone i've ever taken i mean who
knew
but
like somebody i think mentioned in
comments this is good to know in case
you happen to snap a plant in half
all is not lost you know now that hey
you might just be able to clone that
thing i mean we took this thing we
chopped this plant in half
we stuck this part in the arrow cloner
we got some decent roots on it we put it
into the soil we let it veg for a week
it's been a flower for 10 days and
ladies and gentlemen it is getting buds
on it so yes that is a successful clone
and
you know another thing i want to say too
is all these buds here all these top
shoots
that you see
if these were all the way under here
there's no way they would get the same
amount of light and there's no way it
would produce the same amount of yield
that it's going to produce like it is
here
so
by chopping this plant in half did i
actually just increase my yield
it'll be interesting to know i'm curious
to find out and let me know in the
comments
what you think is going to produce the
heftier buds is it going to be the top
or is it going to be the bottom with
presumably the thicker
fuller root system
we'll find out but i'll keep you guys
updated so no worries there
another possible advantage to this is
this really helped keep my plant count
down you know i only was growing one
plant so i saved time i saved materials
i had one plant until i saw the pre
flowers and i realized it was a female
and then i turned it into two
that could be helpful for somebody that
is trying to keep their plant count down
because you only have to grow certain
amount of plants and then if you like
them they're females you turn them into
two give it 30 days as i did and voila
you have two nicely growing plants to
flower out
so
some potential advantages to doing this
twin peaks two plant topping system
but it's not you know i'm not going to
say this is a commercially viable
technique this is something that you
could do at home you can have fun with
it who knows you might be able to
increase your yields keep your plant
count lower but it's something to have
fun with
and you gotta have some fun while you're
growing that's part of why we do this
[Music]
you