[Music]
hey everybody chad westport here today
we're going to have fun with a few what
if our first what if is what if
what if i topped the plant right here
discarding all of that above
and only keeping that below
do you think it would live
it's an awful lot to take off
but sometimes you have no choice so what
do you do
let's find out another fun thing that
we're gonna do with this
since we're gonna top it down here and
we've got all of that above
do you think if i put that in the arrow
cloner it will clone
i don't think so
but let's find out anyways okay so as
you can see i've got it all lined up to
be cut and i'm just going to pan up and
down so you can see once again the
ridiculousness of this cloning attempt
so let's pan up and check her out
and as you can see she's too tall to
flower out i kind of let her go this
long because i wanted to pre-sex her i
have determined that she is a she
through the pre flowers
i know that if i cut it back and play
around with it if it lives i'll get a
nice bush anyhow so
let's play
here we go
pick sticker out i'm gonna cut her at my
angle here right above the two branches
that i want to be the top
and
one two three
clone
oh it's so thick i can't even cut this
[ __ ]
oh my goodness
oh yeah all right
so right now this is a scraggly looking
plant i'm gonna train it i'm gonna clean
it up a little bit you'll see what it
looks like later but let's go check out
our monster clone
guys you can see the absolute absurdity
of this size of clone as i said earlier
there's a dozen good clones on there if
you really wanted to take a clone
they're in there not the one piece
but i've got it in the arrow cloner and
we're gonna find out if it works just
because go ahead and place your bets in
the comment we'll find out what happens
all right so you can see what i've done
with this plant is i've taken those
stems that were going up and i've bent
them down
that's going to serve a couple purposes
one
is these inner node spaces here here
here here all of these
the branches are going to grow up
that's going to fill this area in and
make it fairly bushy
the other thing i've done here is i've
used my binder
clips take them down
now because of phototropism
these are actually going to start to
curl back up
at the point that they're bound so this
is no longer going to stick down here
that's actually going to come back up
it's going to look for the light and
follow the light same with this one it's
going to curl back up
and it's going to be a nice bushy plant
and kind of stay within the confines of
the structure given by the plot or pot
we're about an hour into this monster
sitting in the clone machine and as you
can see i took some of the families off
that's just going to give it more of a
fighting chance too many leaves it's
going to transpire too much and there's
not enough water in the system so i'm
actually have expected the least to go
limp by now it's been you know like i
said it's been over an hour since i
cloned it uh they're still pretty turgid
there's enough water in the system we'll
see if it stays out holy crap guys it's
24 hours later and this thing is not
only still alive
it's looking more turgid and more water
pressure in there than when i cut it off
the plant
can this thing really be a true clone
we'll find out
so we're getting close to two weeks into
this after i've chopped the top off and
bent all of these all the way down
as you can see what i bent down is
starting to curl back up this was
way down there but again phototropism is
going to want to grow towards the light
they're all about the same height so i'm
controlling the apical dominance and all
the auxins and where all the priority is
going essentially
we've got these middle nodes that are
now starting to
put off their branches so these are
going to come
fill up the middle these will continue
to grow up around the side and hey at
the end of the day we're gonna have a
monster bush
oh my goodness you guys we are over a
week into this thing being chopped off
crudely by the scissors and stuffed in
this aeroponics machine
not only is it still alive
and not limp
all of the leaves are looking good
they're solid and
get this
this thing's starting to get roots
check it out
look at that guys
at that right there
that is just crazy do you guys think i'm
gonna be able to get enough roots
for this whole thing
to finish flowering
we'll have to see but i'm going to put
it back in the arrow cloner for now
[Music]
you