[Applause]
[Music]
hi everybody chad westport here we are
back for week four of the garden update
now i've already had kind of a peek
inside but i want to let you guys know
that the light has not moved since last
week so that's a good way to judge the
growth over this last week let's go in
and take a look
[Music]
again these are being grown under the
spider farmer s e 5000 light that you
see right there let's take a look at the
plants and see what they've done since
the last week oh we should probably look
at them last week
and now here they are this week
that one's touching the light look at
that
big growth on these ladies
okay so again week four and you might
notice that we're down to six plants uh
everything is showing their sex
uh the two
goji og times local skunks both turned
out to be male
so those are gone
and earlier the two burgers and beers
turned out to be male so those are gone
so what we've got left right now are the
roadkill skunk time space cheese by mr
toad we've got the purple pineapple from
the ranch and we've got kool-aid man
from bee leaf cannabis
uh let's go in and take a closer look at
each of the plants so this girl just
exploded up uh this is in the
appalachian supply soil this is the fat
leafed kool-aid man and uh yeah she's
looking green she's looking great
no complaints here
moving on we've got the thinly version
of the kool-aid man back here from bee
leaf cannabis and this one is in the
sohom living soil and it's got kind of a
cool fasciation going i'll show you that
real quick you can see the stem right
there how it's extra thick then it just
kind of comes up and it oh it does its
own little split right there oh get that
out of the way so it decided to split
it's going into two more
and uh this will be exciting to see how
this one grows out so yeah and and i've
noticed too on the sohum you know again
it's got a lot of good food in it
but i am getting a little bit of tip
burns uh but overall the growth is you
know growth is good just a little bit of
tip burn on this one next up is the
roadkill skunk time space cheese this is
the taller thinly fino that i got from
mr toad and it is actually starting to
bud up pretty darn early and this is in
the sohom living soil let's go in a
closer look yeah that's starting to put
on some nice buds nice and early
starting out good got a lot of tops on
it and you know again this too a little
bit of tip burn a little bit of tip burn
it's in the soham living soil and as you
can see from the growth plenty of juice
all right moving on from the thin one
to the short wide leaf roadkill skunk
time space cheese from mr toad that i've
shown him and asked about he said this
is an outlier so again i'm pretty
excited to have an ancestor genetic
popping up in my tent from that roadkill
skunk space cheese combo let's go in for
a close look and see how big those leafs
are man damn big leaf right there it's a
three-inch sticker guys
so yeah i'm really excited to see what
this one's gonna do for me and so this
is sitting in the kiss organics biochar
soil and if you guys watch the first
update i don't think there's any doubt
that this is the mvp comeback of the
tent so far so yeah looking good doing
good stoke to see what comes of it
moving on and right here we've got the
purple pineapple from the ranch and this
too is in the kiss organics biochar soil
uh everything's looking good and green
and lush on this plant starting to throw
out its pistols i can't wait to see how
it finishes up
let's go over to it's sister all right
over to the sister right here and the
sister is sitting in the sohom living
soil and again nice short profile
starting to throw pistols uh very
similar to the growth of the kiss
organics but this one is in the sohum
living soil a little more profile of
this one as it goes down i might need to
do a little defoliation down there but
overall she's looking good nice short
stout stocky plant all right so let's
recap you know i keep saying week four
but really it's garden update number
four
uh it's in the third week of it being in
these seven gallon containers
and it is the second beginning of the
second week of flowering so that's kind
of the time schedule it's good to know
so we can see when and if these run out
of juice
but also to let you guys kind of know
what stage of flowering they're in and
you know what kind of results to expect
i may have gotten these a little bit
larger but ladies and gentlemen i am
going back to the netherlands in may uh
i had to flip these now so i can cut
them before i leave had to be done so
let's recap everybody in the back here
we've got our kiss organic soil our kiss
organics biochar soil
we've got
sohum living soil sohum living soil
we've got the soham living soil on the
back there and our appalachian supply
super soil
in the front things are looking good i'm
very happy water only experiment going
great
keep it locked here to find out the
results a new update in seven days
chad.westport on instagram check out the
website chadwestport.com and keep it
locked here on the youtube channel
chadwestport so in the meantime growers
party on
[Music]
[Applause]
you