hey there okay field notes Afghan land
race this variety is called Chim tall
Tim tall and very impressed with this
one this is definitely a keeper so we
grew a few uh Finos of this uh we've
already harvested a few but this one is
probably the favorite of the whole mix
and maybe we'll just take a little
cruise around so you can see this whole
plant
and all of it splendor
yeah very traditional Afghan and then
we're finally
uh getting some colder nights so we're
starting to get a little bit of that
um you can see like on this Leaf some of
that black purple
action going that's uh
common with uh afghans
but still
we haven't had a lot of cold nights so
um if it got colder at night this whole
plant would start turning black which is
really striking and beautiful but right
now uh
this plant and by the way this one's I
think we're going to harvest it today
field note
oh the smell on this is like um
it's like mango chutney like a spiced
mango really beautiful
stunning delicious but deep it's got
like a deep
earthy ancient thing going along with
the fruit so anyway uh chimp tall
absolutely love it oh by the way while
we're in the neighborhood if you guys
just want to see
a big honking plant here's like a South
African variety
and by the way this thing it's even root
bound we haven't been had a chance to
fill in all the dirt so next year we're
going to grow these again and they'll
probably be twice as big so anyway if
you got
if you want to grow County Fair size
ridiculously large plants uh some of
these South African varieties are just
insanely vigorous but we'll get to those
later anyway we're focusing on you right
now Jim tall killer plant
all right