all right these are going to be compost
jlf and bokashi videos first up I'll
show you my new compost bins new meaning
they've been scraped out all the old
compost is put over here this is all new
composting that's going it's been going
on since about November I have a little
visual for you this is old compost
that's done it's loaded with red
wigglers and it looks really pretty
beautiful dark just great looking
compost you'll like to see it I'm going
to show you my jlf both these are 2
years old full of vegetables cannabis
defoliation M grass leaves imo3 bokashi
all kinds of inputs I might want to put
in there loaded with stuff and I'll show
you how much jlf I use when I water my
plants and then in the back back I've
got a trash can full I got two trash can
fulls actually but one's back there it's
bokashi that's been fermenting for four
months four months I've never Bashi that
long so we'll see what it looks like
okay first up is all the new compost
right here
you look in the light you can probably
see the bugs flying all around it little
fungus knat looking things flies soon
there will be lots of black soldierly
larvae and they will start to devour all
this but this is new compost that I've
started these bins in about November
this little visual here shows you how
many 5 gallon buckets it takes to make
one bucket of compost 8 to 10 I'd say
about 10 usually it's kind of a lot of
it's a lot of material to make a little
bit of comp so remember that but if you
but if you have a 5G bucket full of
compost that is very valuable to a to a
organic grower but you can see lots of
fruits flowers you can see where I've
put my Bashi down it helps with smells
I'm going to put more Bashi down on here
taco shells eggs spent mushroom bags
root balls just tons of stuff whatever
came from our table goes right into here
all right here is the compost that is
ready and and it is gorgeous stuff's
probably 9 to 10 months old or so it's
been breaking down for a long time
there's red wiggler right
there little cold but just look how dark
it is how grainy it is it's light and
fluffy it's been decomposed by red
wigglers and black soldier fly
larvae again you can see the red
wigglers right there they're all all
down in there
more they actually come when it's colder
red wigglers like it when it's colder
the black soldier flies like it when
it's like it when it's
hotter you can see them all in
there but that is what I use to make a
good im4 with right
there all right let's look at the jlf
all right here comes the jlf this is the
jlf that I use to water all of my indoor
plants
I don't switch up my jlf I've used it
from the very beginning of growing
indoors back around October so I'll take
this long stick right here just Mash a
hole right in the middle and then take
my cup and dip it out of that little
well um check it all the black soldier
flies along this lid they want to get in
so
bad but this this one I have not messed
with at all totally full it froze and
blew the lid off spewed out a little bit
but it's 2 years old just sitting there
you can see lots of vegetables corn in
there but now to a 5 gallon
bucket this is what I use to feed my
plants there one
quart two quarts that'll that'll measure
out at 6.2 on the ph and perfect for my
plans Bashi next all right next up is
the bokashi that has been fermenting for
4 months I have a bigger trash can full
haven't looked at either one of them
haven't used it at all I've never
fermented for 4 months it was simply an
experiment that I started this back in
just the end of October so I've got
November December January February it
just too cold during those months to
dump it out but we going to open it up
see what it looks like definitely got a
strong ferment smell let's see I've got
another bag down there I got to open
up just want yall see what it looks like
too
ooh it's pretty hold on look at that
guys ain't nothing wrong with that at
all all right I'm going to get it out
and get a better shot for you here we go
oh well heck look at
that all right I'm going to open it up
more all right here we go a little
better
shot so often when you boi you might see
stuff like this there's some mold on the
top right there that means some air got
in there that's all
that nice white bacteria nothing wrong
with that and there's nothing wrong with
that little bit of mold right there but
what I'm going to do is I'm going to use
the top layers right here for the
compost scrape off the top where
probably the air came in contact with it
and it just creates a little bit of mold
little bit of
bacteria whatever it might be but it's
got a good strong ferment smell I don't
think there's anything wrong with it I'm
going to get it out here I'm going to
dry it on those tables but I'm going to
mix this
Bashi with some of this nice Acorn
imo3 and I'm going to use this on the
compost here we go all right I'm going
to dump the Bashi
Out start
drying
smells nice smells like vinegary bread
man smells
good
yeah it smells really
good I just need to get it out I'll keep
I'll keep raking it for a couple days
it's going to be nice and warm will dry
out well fan on it out all righty
there's the bokashi all laid out
hopefully it'll dry the next five or 6
days out here I'll probably put a fan on
it and keep it in the Sun so I've got
the beautiful Bashi wet Bashi and acorn
imo3 I just set in that bucket it take
off but I also have my bokashi bag
that's loaded with lactic acid
bacteria tons of wheat brand rice these
are my jlf or sorry JMS
buckets we going to wash that out in
there a little bit they're starting to
get a few bubbles I showed these the
other day just yesterday actually
yesterday
afternoon must be like a little jump
little micro jump you can see the
bubbles
forming nice all right now to the
compost right bringing the IMO 3 and wet
bokashi back to the
[Music]
compost we're going to just give it a
little
covering you can test your Bashi put it
on some organic
matter 3 days two days in the heat it
should be all all high feet
out like that right
there Bashi helps a ton with the
smell keeps the pests away a little bit
but definitely helps with the smell
helps break down all the organic matter
all the labs that are on all the rice
holes and
stuff nice and Powerful I'm going to put
a little on
this compost and that will take off
it'll all Hy out in a few days it'll be
beautiful all
right