hey another uh field notes from our
African sativas everything's getting
charging and lots of flowers going on
but this one is one of my favorites it's
just so elegant and African and long
leaves uh so this is a Congo Congolese
uh Point Noir which I'm guessing means
Black Point uh so this is one of the
Congolese we're growing we're also
growing a Congolese red stem but this
one and the seeds were really tough to
germinate so I only have one female
going uh right now we had two other
males that we said bye to but anyway
very cool structure these long elegant
leaves and when it the Wind Blows the
whole plant just really dances and it's
just a gorgeous so such a unique
beautiful plant
and it it actually kind of
Whispers as it's blowing in the leaves
it makes this cool little Whispering
noise so anyway uh but this probably has
uh it's October 23rd today I would say
this has three to four weeks to go so
we're looking
um probably Thanksgiving oh there's a
I've got a lot of ladybugs right now
helping us beat back the aphid so uh I
don't every once while I'll see an aphid
but the ladybugs are really keeping them
in check and super stoked that we have
native uh predatory insects taking
protecting our plants very cool anyway
this is congo.nar or Black Point
yay