[Music]
you want to go inside yeah we're going
to do a tour so why don't we start up
here and then you can get to the pwn
story all right well we're on the
Connecticut Rhode Island
border and we are on 30 Acres of
Woodland so kill it we have Japanese
invasive Japanese Japanese Beatles that
Gemma is going to take care in charge of
she's the Grim
Reaper um so this is the house that is
here it's from
1802 uh the original house this are
perennial flower gardens going on around
here so did you put all these in
recently no these were here but uh the
issue was that um so we got this two and
a half years ago the issue was that the
person we got it from was very old and
was all by herself and hadn't been able
to take care of anything for about 20
years so we had um just an insane amount
of invasives that we've been clearing
out uh such as multifloral Rose and
Oriental
Bittersweet and other things that are
just nasty and
overwhelm stuff
um Y and uh and so we've just been
trying to fight that back um which we
have pretty much succeeded around here
and have discovered stuff like uh if you
give this a smell it's like a mint it's
a lemon balm so Min family yeah I love
it home randomly we discovered it
um this is nice it's just Elderberry so
we'll make jams out of
it um and I think you can make like a
like isn't there a yeast that grows on
the outside of these and then you can
make like a you can jar it up and then
it ferments and uh creates a sparkling
that I do not know but I will look it up
uh um but uh you know the Box Hedges
were here but anyway this whole thing
was just a crazy mess and it's actually
been very cool to watch it from um kind
of April May onwards because you know it
all dies back uh it's very little Woody
stuff that stays up and uh and it's just
kind of like big mud patches coming
through the spring and we have a couple
of these sort of GI giant hostas which
are are pretty cool um but this is
something that we're going to tackle
this is burning bush which is just
everywhere and grows everywhere it has a
berri is it invasive or it's invasive
it's beautiful um but it's invasive and
uh you know we want to have it for um
for privacy from the from the very
well-traveled dirt road out there uh
invas uh invasive means that what is
invasive oh this plant here this is a
burning bush it turns a fiery red in the
fall but so our current thinking is that
we're going to replace these with
something called mock orange yeah um
that is a dragonfly probably yeah that's
definitely uh we have a couple of
different cool species of
dragonflies
um and and uh but anyway it's a lovely
little
spot uh this grape here
uh there's a concord grape oh nice uh
yeah so these guys are coming in are you
excited and I am excited did you eat
them last year or no yeah they're
totally tasty but we're going to bring
it down and probably train we started
training it along that um the wall chain
link oh the chain link yeah
uh that is a big butterfly it's probably
a butterfly moths usually I think come
out more in the late Twilight
hours um but uh we have a lot so we have
a lot we we do have a bunch of concord
grapes and then we just have a lot of
wild grapes so it's kind of figuring out
between the two because the wild grapes
are just like a big seed
pack mildly tasty but it's a lot of
seeds to spit out yeah yeah yeah um I I
you know what I can uh give you I have a
whole bunch of koho grapes growing uhhuh
and uh they're super tasty and each one
has I think like one seed in it uh
that's good uh it's yeah it's going to
get various cultivars because wherever
there's well we're just their they're
babies so wherever we
see wherever we see you know wild grapes
growing and stuff it's like okay we know
grapes grow here doesn't mean every
cultiv our will grow here here but we
know it's grape friendly and we can
bring in some cultivars and uh and sort
of pick and choose I'll show you a giant
grape vine
Gemma
um you know so this is this is all uh a
burning bush um and it pops up
everywhere but this keeps um you know
the erosion control so it's like before
we move moving it it's like what would
we put in it yeah let me show you the
bathtub and then I can tell you you had
a question about the
pond it wasn't a funny story uh or the
funny thing was the
bathtub so if you see that what's all
this uh lavender oh cool um and then
this was this was going to be some look
these all right ready wait that's so
scary you got it hurry up ah wait
there's two I know they were making love
so this was going to be
cilantro okay they don't bite they don't
bite Gemma so this was going to be
cilantro and we put the you know stuff
in and instead we're getting a melon or
a squash um but anyway if you look at
this railing here so this house was
1802 they didn't have Plumbing in
1802 so this little thing right here is
the B that looks like a pretty awesome
bathtub that was the bathtub have you
done it I haven't about two year two
summers ago there was a big drought and
uh the Water had stopped running through
and we wanted to scrub it clean but we
didn't get around to do do it uh I think
they kind of made it so it would do it
but yeah we need to hop in that so
anyway so this part of the pond they dug
out and the stream that comes in is on
the right hand side
there poison nope I got rid of it for
you Uncle Michael with his bare hands
removed all the poison ivy lots of
poison on your a uh what do you call it
when you no longer get imunity an
immunity to it so we have this little
pump that draws from the pond and Waters
everything up there nice uh and then
these guys here are the wild grapes that
are
everywhere
um and then by uh so this was a a Wild
Grape Vine
see very big wa doesn't come down yet
though um and I'm starting to punch into
here because we want to reclaim this if
you just see how dense it
is
um
Tomatoes oh I want some Tomatoes okay
follow
them so these Tomatoes were from the
compost bin uh we opened up the bin and
there there are a bunch of tomatoes
growing and I figured instead of just
tossing them we'll see what happens
right here and there's just probably
store bought tomatoes and they're
growing what's
this uh I do not know what that is um
but they're growing and then I was
wondering if it was like some GMO tomato
that only fruits once uh but there's
it's coming out and I don't really care
if the animals get to it so if we get to
it first get to it if not but this is
kind of what this is what that flower
garden looked
like uh just binds over everything binds
over stuff I mean it's you know this is
grape uh but then if you start putting
your hands in it gets very pricker and
um uh with the multifloral
rose
uh here we've put in so this spot here
was a big jungle like that we cleared it
out and we
have put in some little baby cherry
trees cherry tree cherry
tree so for context the ultimate goal is
a an orchard
for seasonal fruits for white mustache
yogurt correct uh but and this is more
this area is just more kind of you get
get the vibe that like oh there's fruit
growing because we want to do everything
further where everything's in the woods
but we have cherry tree cherry tree
cherry tree this is a black cherry that
was originally there and I want to see
if once we have cherries around it if
that will actually fruit black cherry
over
there
HT that's okay that's just a actually
that's a wing of
something um
we have a plum over
there uh sorry that one right there that
one that's uh um fenced in is a plum
yeah and then all of this is just native
Blackberry yeah I'd cut it all down
actually so this all has popped up since
the
springtime and I figure you know see how
they taste I have a couple of thornless
blackberry uh that I've planted here
they taste fine they're just a pain in
the butt to try to if if you were like
I'm going to harvest all of this for Jam
it's a little bit of a pain uh and it
just grows dense and you can look at how
kind of prickly it is but the
blackberries taste you know decent um
and the issue that's where you get your
child labor you got two kids you got
nieces and nephew the one of the issues
is that it's a Bramble and it will just
kind of it just pops up everywhere so
it's trying to how do you kind of
contain it in one area which is just
sort of keep on chopping where it's
sprouting out um and uh we have a lot of
this High Bush
blueberry uh so the season has come and
gone but it has little
tiny uh blueberries that were
tasty uh so that's high Bush blueberry
High Bush blueberry
um and so we've
[Music]
planted these have big bulbous
blueberries uh so in two years that'll
grow
up
um and uh that's a pear tree pear tree
uh right here yeah two pairs Paar and
Paar um and then down here is
so the this is
Pimon is this a yur uh a yurt style tent
that I got for Father's Day if you want
to do a sleepover in the tent yeah J
let's go check out the tent you want to
go check out the tent uh let me show you
this so these are all going to go in the
ground and the
fall um it it is
apricot uh Persian malberry which is
different than our North American
malberry and then in here uh H's dad
brought these from California yeah uh
and it's a kind of a hearty pomegranate
from Iran so he so can handle the winter
so don't tell anybody but he smuggled it
in from
Iran like did not declare it in his
Customs forms grew them in
uh Orange County
California and then he brought them over
here uh like six weeks ago yeah they
totally died off uh from them com back
to life though and uh we're bringing
that uh you can kill that kill it that
little inchworm yeah that is going to
eat um and know no that's a spider oh no
wait no that's a
cricket Sor uh so we have pomegranate
fig that he's brought
in um here we have Persian malberry
which is the malberry that sorry this
one is Persian malberry uh and this one
this one here this one um and then the
Hardy almond sweet are these guys over
here the little little ones uh yeah our
Hardy
almond um and what's going to happen in
the fall is we're going to take out a
bunch of trees on this side yeah and
create space for these to kind of go up
uh here the the I see yeah I see the uh
the underbrush uh yeah so I've started
clearing out the multiflor rose because
you can't cut down the tree like the
rose goes like way up high into the
trees so before cutting down the trees
kind of get out all the stuff that you
would have to it it's like this right
here you go in there yes you can take a
look got to take off your shoes
though uh there's blow up mattresses
that are not currently blown up so
Michael of all these safe places you
could have put those cannabis
plants that's where it was they were in
that Fen in area no no no they were they
were next to it with like I'm going to
come and open up the fencing and put
them in there what
that
is so Gemma here is from the Mean
Streets of Los Angeles and just getting
her country legs
on Gemma is spooked by
every everything every
bug look that spider is going to eat all
the that's a good guy right that little
spider we like our spiders so you want
to look in there you can take off just
step in take off your
shoes whether you want to come out here
and do a sleepover although it's
supposed to rain for the next three days
it's too hot well during the day it's
hot you you don't yeah you at nighttime
you do you go to the fire pit you make a
fire you eat s'mores and sound fun you
come back out here there fireflies
everywhere which is pretty cool to see
it's like a fireworks display and then
you cozy up in
bedor fireflies fireflies I want to see
those things well then you got to come
spend the
night okay let's go if I'm not doing it
alone no you're not going to do it
alone okay let's
[Music]
go yeah I have to hack through through
here uh so like this area tons of grape
and uh so I want to clear it out and
then put grape cultivars in and do it
like proper kind of um you should run
naked through the
vines see what Happ the amount of well
one we're in tick country right yes I
was joking and then two it's all thorns
I don't want to go in there you're not
going in there
uh but it's kind of like
uh oh yeah and then the Japanese
Barberry we have a ton of that and that
is like Ground Zero for ticks because
it's a prickly bushy plant and ticks go
from the deer to little rodents like
mice yeah and then the mice hide in the
Japanese Barberry cuz it's like safe
from predators there and then the tick
climb up and wait for the deer to come
by oh no wait for people that come
by
uh J no we're going tour and then
we'll I'll show you a little bit of the
woods okay now we're going in the shade
okay so we cut down a bunch of trees
here and we'll kind of clear out the
ground because we'll line some uh some
tree crops up on that side so a few more
of these trees are coming
down um but I'm waiting for the foliage
to to leave
us
um but in the
[Music]
meantime
uh we planted be root
raspberry that are coming in
and what's funny with the be root
raspberry if you
come so they're coming in and with the
mulch for each one we have we have our
garden garden vegetables like almost
each that happens in my yard all the
time like there's
one here's one but all of this stuff is
invasive this is the multifloral Rose so
we got to come through and uh I have
something to yank this stuff out it just
takes forever or bring in little push
tiller to kind of go around because I
want to kind of be beat out the root
system what's our uh so we have perm
strategy up here
uh we'll do something um J go stand in
the shade right there you'll be much
cooler we're going to go in the woods
it's going to be much easier for you uh
no they're not I built I did some Trails
uh you some of these are getting nice
and big these are raspberry too that's
raspberry raspberry there's about 20 of
them on that side and that
side
um and
uh little mushrooms those are
mushrooms what are the weird uh uh worms
called the invasive ones uh I forget
they're real name but it's like a
jumping worm so they're like twice as
thick and about twice as long as your
regular earthworms and when you touch
them like a regular earthor be like o
get away from me and these ones like
spring up and like land some places I
haven't seen as many this year as I saw
last year yeah last year I feel like
they like owned right
but uh High Bush blueberry and then so
I've been doing Trails through here yeah
um and
uh we'll we'll do a lot of under
story uh stuff here in the woods um but
one of the things that's pretty
interesting I find interesting is and
I'll show it to you when we get there is
we have a lot of what's called Hillside
blueberry which um will start to fruit
if you give it a little bit of sun not
so much sun I think the canopy is too
thick so we'll take out some trees and
get some sun down onto
it um all the stone walls here
are back in the 19th century through the
early 20th century it was livestock farm
so these were the holding pens for them
Michael alpaca would be very happy in
here yes well this is the first one I'm
going to work on and turn it into like
basically uh it'll be
like eventually we'll do like a dining
room here so it's like you come up and
you have your you're eating in the woods
and yeah and stuff um but
basically kind of thoughtfully plant
around
it both kind
of Woodland ornamentals and food
crop whatever grows in the
shade such as your what was your shade
tobacco yes the Connecticut shade
tobacco right I think would enjoy being
grown in Connecticut in the shade in the
shade and we have plenty of shade
partial sun look at that
so anyway this what we're walking on all
was like that right there uh and so I've
made uh started started doing a trail
system through here you should do a tree
house for the girls we want to do a tree
house and zipline yeah zipline from cuz
we have a couple of really nice rockout
croppings that are up on a hill all the
way down to drop into the
pond right for bath time right uh
exactly
um
swings we can do some
swings uh the tent actually is going to
go way back here we need to build a
platform for it the the one that was
just in the one that Gemma was just
in there's so much time
sh uh
um I suggested
Sneakers but
um there are lots of little micro
climates here so this was a oak
Hickory
uh Woods uh and this is technically an
oak Hickory Savanah
um which I think is a funny name because
when I think of Savannah I think of
giant African PLS or
something but the
um we're walking up through the middle
of the
property
and this watch where you're even though
it's cleared you still got to watch
where you're Uncle Michael's wearing on
his
feet but anyway so this stuff that you
see here this is Hillside
blueberry and you'll see like I mean
it's kind of late but you'll see a
couple of little
blueberries but um supposedly if and we
have a ton of it uh and supposedly if
you get at least a little bit of some on
it they start to fruit and um and it's
kind of do it in uh is it like oak trees
kind of go Bonkers with their acorns
every two or three years to overwhelm
the wild life kind of just defeat with
numbers so uh maybe we'll make a
hillside blueberry jam
so main Orchard is generally going to be
where we're going to walk down to it
it's going to be down
there
what it's it's so it's this bark see on
the ground there Gemma see how there's
that Brown Strip there was probably a
log there that I moved when I was making
this
path okay well you know what we'll get
some some uh alcohol to dry it out CS
right that's that's it's probably from
the ocean you don't put alcohol yeah yes
you do
Gemma that's exactly what we did with
valentina's ears when she was
complaining that her ears hurt it dries
out the water that's in your
ear alcohol so was a rubbing alcohol not
a drinking alcohol uh so this is the
blueberry the hillside
blueberry so this stuff's getting
light yeah like there are some patches I
mean obviously there's just so much
there's a tree blight on uh beach trees
um not all of these are beach but
there's a bunch of blight in the
Northeast that's like you see so much
dead stuff uh and so it's just kind of
over the years thin out all the stuff
that's dead take out some of the bigger
trees let some of the small ER ones grow
up it'll start bringing some light down
um onto the ground here
uh but the trail system was sort of to
help me see what's back
here and to walk around in
it but Gemma here's some good spots for
a zip
line yeah look at that
oh and bunge
jumping we don't quite have bungee
jumping but
uh but we do have some perches that you
could do some zip lines
on here we'll go over to that one over
there uh so your cousins like to climb
on these
rocks yeah
I uh cleaned off this
one from all the prickers and stuff that
were on
it so that uh so that it was safe for a
six-year-old and a
four-year-old and they like to climb on
this one this big one right over here
this one yeah I took off um there's
there was just like a bunch of
Fallen branches is that you could slide
on there's um Green Brier which is a
pricky type of thing native but got rid
of it uh and then uh I brought them out
here and they spent a good two hours
climbing over this one grab grab the
tree okay ready
Gemma just got to scramble up ready give
me your hand hand so so step up to here
step up to here no or you can find a
different way you can go you can go this
way then follow me right
here
okay step
over now step up there right there right
no no no no right there
yep you got it good
job my God Gemma
what do you think of a if you had a zip
line from here would this work Gemma
down we should build stairs I feel
like we'll make a for the city girls
right have a little escalator solar
powered escalator for just bring you up
but if we did a zip line down that
way um build like a tree house we could
do a tree house if you come and help
build it we can do all sorts of stuff we
want to do some platform if you want to
do a play in the woods make a little
stage out here you guys what would
happen if it stopped in the middle if
zip line oh the zip line well well uh
you kind of have to move yourself along
or jump down jump
down over there is a big stand of
mountain laurel uh which is pretty when
it
blooms my ear touches it it hurts I know
so we're going to get you some stuff at
CVS to help
okay I know it might be some wax as well
no it it's probably water uh from the
ocean uh so we'll go down this way and
then I'll show you where we're going to
do the the orchard okay so follow Uncle
Mikey Gemma I'm in flipflops so then
ultimately a house you'd want to put
where somewhere up over in that
direction and how much further back does
the property go we're kind of dead
center of it so probably like like four
or five acres in that direction and four
or five acres in the other
direction um
so 8 800 yards thousand yards I don't
know
um uh okay and then it's maybe another
four 300 yards that way to the end of
the
property after the mountain laurel is um
is uh the St wall and then on the other
side of the property uh Federal fish and
wildlife bought that because they're
doing a study on flora and fauna in
coastal regions I feel you should be
like a huge trampoline here so if you
fall you
just what if you jump off the rock down
to a trampoline no no
okay don't you think that's a good
idea well you could do a net like a
circus net right
yeah come this way I'll hold your hand
as you step down
yeah or
trampol step step
step
[Music]
acorns oh J we could whistle into the
acorns
what's
that where are you looking it just it
just flew away see like
green uh yeah I don't know but is no
Gemma
no it's not a te
why not
dir okay let's go follow me this way and
then up here
[Music]
okay go to Uncle
Mikey
Marco Polo
Marco that's how we find each other in
here we also have little walkie-talkies
which are fun to
use okay Uncle Michael's going to show
you how he whistles with
this do you have a good cap
yeah haven't done this in
years
close we'll have to prac get back all
right Jim you're going to master that's
I used to do that when I was your age
that's probably one of the last times I
did it so if you look here there's a
stone wall that shoots down that way
comes across here and then on that side
and so this is
the first area of future Orchard so this
area right here this area here okay um
and uh you know it's going to be it's a
woodland Orchard it's not going to be
kind of like like we have a big open
field and start planting trees but we'll
take down a ton of this leave some of
the existing trees and then also you
know we're in Connecticut in the woods
we have lots of lots of rocks so sort of
plant your stuff all through here um
where it can but maybe the Rocks provide
nice minerals mineral
treats uh but it'll be um
uh a lot of peach probably and a lot of
Quints uh is probably the the two main
things and uh then I've also
[Music]
um uh uh some guy that I follow on
social
media uh sent me a bunch of pmen seeds
yeah that I've started and they're like
this big uh right now and and uh then
I've also started from last year's um
peach jam batch it was these Jersey
peaches that's a feather that's a
feather these Jersey peaches and I've
started those and that type of thing is
uh there's this guy Mark Shepard who
talks about the stun method which is
sheer total utter neglect and so I'm
growing those and I will just stick them
in the wood somewhere give them kind of
a happy home and just like see if see if
they grow
um and how they do but I'll let I'll do
that when they're like two years old
give them a Fighting Chance uh but this
will be cultivated here um our big issue
is figuring out how to get uh some
larger machines in here because that
pond has a brook that runs across the
front of the property and you can't and
we only have a foot path to get over the
brook um so we have to either build a
bridge or well didn't I send you those
like pontoon Bridge uh well we had this
one guy come and uh he's like I could
clear this in a week um he's like the is
because we would keep all the the uh
chipped trees and stuff um and just use
the wood
the we would just use the the wood
clippings um and uh but his machine
which is one of those giant things that
like comes down the tree and just like
grinds it down like cuts it like flesh
with the Earth is I think he said it was
tons so we are going to petition the
fish and wildli if we can get a access
from their side and coming through the
back
um so is there a road uh there's a
little Access Road uh but we would then
have to kind of cut down
down 25 yards of trees like this um on
the fish and wildlife property on the
fish and wildlife side to come on in or
like 20 yards
uh
archaeological Discovery
e what is that glasses little daddy long
bottles and
stuff okay follow Uncle Mikey what is
that so this is our archaeological
Discovery from Whenever However many
years
ago uh
and then these things are
interesting um we have them kind of all
over the property and one of my
neighbors gave me a book on oh my God
what is that it's a big Beetle that's a
big Beetle that's a big
guy uh a one pound Beetle joh um a
neighbor gave me a book on um indigenous
ceremonial uh kind of rock formations
yeah um and not saying it is but we have
a bunch of it when very well could be um
from hundreds of years ago
Jem you want to see where the chickens
are going to
go some nice size animal see the some
poop some animal poop
Gemma slow Gemma what do you do in Los
Angeles when you see bugs or are there
no bugs in Los Angeles not really any
bugs
yeah you like rly
py what are
rly I like ladybugs you like
ladybugs and rly pulley I remember when
you were three or four Carina likes
snails when you were three or four your
dad got a bunch of ladybugs and you were
the official ladybug
keeper so this was probably built when
this early 20th century like 1920s
1930s
um hold that
open and it's probably a little spot as
you're letting your cow and sheep grze
and you just need a little hangout
spot um have you pull like a light from
this well you have the candle thing
above you oh wait wait how old is that
probably 100 years maybe 90 years the
fireplace works
great um was it somebody's house no it
was just kind of uh a spot to hang out
as your cows were busy eating and your
sheep were busy eating
uh you could make yourself a cup of tea
or a coffee or a stew or a
stew that was that was the original one
yeah these are the original ones that
was like 100 years old yeah Jemma should
we make some tea no we'll clean we'll
clean them out one of these days you
shouldn't throw it away huh you
shouldn't throw throw oh we're not
throwing to throw it away we're going to
P it we're going to clean off these
tables and and make it a nice little
spot to hang out
in
overlooking yeah so this
uh this right here was just a mess of
invasive stuff so I cleaned it out and
there's clover growing in it that fenced
in area saffron uh how's the saffron
doing it comes out in the fall um so
actually we need to give it a good
weeding uh and give it space to come
out um
so where those
little which one's the saffron you can't
see it it dies back and then it emerges
in the fall but basically where you see
the pink uh little staks uh that's the
row there are three or four rows and
we're just doing a test to see how it
grows um and if it grows well we'll
plant more
saffron you got to scratch yeah and down
here Gemma is where the chicken coup
will go right down here right down in
there follow him cleaning out
space so I have chicken coupe with
little chickens and you'll be eating the
chicken eggs when you visit next year
and the chicken shortly after that
uh no we're going to have you should let
CH EG chick huh you should let the
chickens get first well we're going to
probably get little chicks
how do chicken eggs give birth well the
eggs hatch and turn into chickens and
then they give birth to uh you get your
rooster and then
um so more Blueberry Blueberry Blueberry
over
there
uh and then there's all that
side uh like that way yeah on the other
side of that stone wall which I haven't
even barely even touched this year Jemma
you survived a walk in the woods you did
a great
job you want to go inside and take down
a grow
tent no I want to go inside the house
yeah inside the house that's where we're
going
uh here
smell this one Crush that and smell it
what is it it's a
mint can I eat it if you
want and then this one is a different
type of mint oh and this
one smell this
one yep that one's from there yeah this
is more like a spearmint yeah one's a
spearmint one's a this one smells so
good and then one right I don't know
which one I forget which one is which
that one's a good one too that one's
like a spearm this last one
yeah so it's also like sure those roots
don't start we're also G to like you
know it's like plant rhubarb in places
and echon in places so there's a lot of
foraging opportunity like you might not
need it every season or every year but
you know where you can go find it when
you need it right
all right so burms and uh water what's
your vision for water uh when it rain
water is bring up here to holding tanks
and then feed it that way as well as no
no I'm saying when it rains to try to oh
uh okay so we have mad flooding uh
issues here I've witnessed it and uh uh
which is either the soil is so compacted
or the Bedrock is only like an a limited
amount of space
underneath uh but we will do um that
side is worse because there's a giant
rock face over there and it just comes
down and we're going to do um uh bur and
swes over there uh but then kind of just
an initial one just and then as we start
kneading water kind of Branch Branch
things out um
water comes down here not as bad but
this could end up being some sort of
like holding
Pond um but I would like to see if I
could do um
uh grapes uh they're not mutually
exclusive um smells
good we do a rice Patty
but yeah it comes down yeah were you
yeah you were here when this was just
all mud oh yeah uh and um this well also
when the water was just like going right
over the uh yeah this this spring like
in March like the average March rain
around here is 3 in and we had something
like 14 in so the water was all up in
here right um I remember it's coming
down that way and then the pond itself
is
overflowing
uh so basically this is what you would
need to get heavy equipment over yeah
but it but it goes down this way PR yeah
it goes down this way so I think if we
did do some sort of what like pontoon
Bridge it would be down over there right
um and then that's a matter of talking
with
uh with folk about doing you don't think
you could get just like a regular Kabota
tractor over this I can do like a small
little excavator so I'm going to get a
little small excavator but like a like
the kaboto we had growing up like you
could get one of those over this yeah
okay uh but I'm talking back where we
want to do the orchard where it's just
like if you had like a big excavator
yeah a catle yeah like one it's not wide
enough to come over but can't you like
put fish in here there are fish in here
and turt
what there's Turtles there's Turtles
last year I saw a big giant turtle
they're Ducks we had a family of geese
this spring which is really cute with
little baby
goslings um there still fish in here the
the ducks live somewhere right in here
occasionally see them pop out well
they're not in the Stream they're over
here if you come in the pond if you come
to the pond side and then you might see
our we have a great blue heron that
hangs out
here it's a bird about yay tall uh huh
he's about your
height um have
you no it doesn't let you get
close uh but here
[Music]
come yeah I basically if you either
stare at the water here or go to that
little bridge over there you'll see some
fish poking around every so
often this was a
find oh those are peppers oh those are
the peppers uh those are the um these
are the ones that James is growing right
the banana peppers uh and then this is a
hearty banana oh really yeah yeah so I
found I found this uh uh this spring and
this area floods in the found it where
like you bought it yeah at a local it
wasn't just wildly growing I was at a
um uh I was at a native Nur or I was at
a nursery not a native nursery and I saw
it it's from Japan and I was like that
looks like a banana so it's a hearty
banana if we're in zone six rapidly
turning into zone seven and if you were
in zone8 you would actually get little
bananas on it um unless you put it in a
greenhouse right but I have it in the
ground and basically each uh fall you
cut it down to about here and let it
just go uh goes dormant in the winter
and then pops back up so I put in two
one here one there
um and then this is funny so this
Tomatoes yeah yep so this was a willow
that probably fell 30 years ago or so
and when I was clearing out this area I
chopped a bunch of branches from it that
were coming off here
and this Willow is still
growing like there's some root somewhere
with some little vein that comes through
but this is the
willow um which is kind of
neat you don't go in that side you go in
over there that got sealed off God
there's so many of these
uh the spotted Lantern fly it hasn't
made it up here yet but uh I've been
following it's in like Fairfield County
down towards New York yeah um and uh at
Ned's house in Brooklyn last summer you
saw they were all over the place really
oh yeah in New York City um so they're
slowly making their Way North
these guys are funky they're cool it's a
dragon Lily um but it has its like
little
thing
there oh this is so I have a couple of
these at uh at
home this was the false
Indigo if you want these pods like you
take them off in um in uh like the
fall but it's a very pretty uh
ornamental so I mean what I was thinking
is like if you
had a dump truck of spent
barley I mean theoretically they we
could like just let it go back that way
well one of the things I was thinking so
the big issue for having a vents here is
limited parking right and so we have 3
acres over here right so
um what I was thinking of
doing is
uh just
like taking out the wall grading it down
and then um
oh
Jesus and then there's a there's a
stream back there but basically having
this area here where when you need it
you could park 30 or 40 cars um and
uh
um basically handle but what I'm saying
is if if oh and so then you could also
just dump your your stuff there uh
the I think uh there's a there's a
Spirits company and a beer company that
would both kind of said yeah we want a
whaler Brewing keeps calling me asking
they're like do you want to come Friday
with a dump truck uh so I like I would
do it it's just I just don't feel like
having a giant pile here where I'm like
with a little tiny wheelar
but you could leave it there's rush I
don't want to have a big pile of I mean
it starts
to I mean you can turn it so it's not
doesn't get
stinky uh but it's like this is the
front of a beautiful house um we put in
some blueberry and blackberry here some
sage and they're just letting like this
here was basically look like that
there um
um which some of that is little native
flowers other of it is uh the multiflor
rose so this is the multiflor Rose
hanging over does it have Vine I mean uh
prickers yeah yeah it's a pain in the
ass to deal with how you doing how are
you doing well thank you how you doing
um but
uh yeah so anyway what I'd love I mean
I'd love to do it if it could just be a
little bit further but if I had like
there's four of us ready to move it
around the property it's like dump it
here and we can just well that's why I
was thinking if the truck backed up here
put it and just dumped it in there yeah
you can leave it over the winter and
just let it do its thing yeah yeah and
that's one load and then you can see
yeah are there any issues could I take
another load right but it's like there's
no downside to having
yeah back back one load of of
stuff decomposing yeah back where I said
we're going to put the chickens is also
where we want to do the
composting um so that's also where it be
awesome where it's like yeah I can get
just a big truck to drive over there and
dump it out
but
our next event is the summer sweets
party nice
so all right
[Music]