[Music]
hey everybody chad westport here and i'm
sitting in my new spider farmer sc 5000
tent and i'm considering going organic
now i got a few hang-ups i got a few
problems a couple things in my mind i
just can't quite overcome so convince me
i'm wrong
but anyways it's a 4x4 tent ideally it
would be a three by three uh fabric
raised bed in here that i would use but
there's just a few things that you know
like i said i can't get my head around i
have a veg area and this will be a
flower area so if i'm running living
soil beds in here
how do i take it from my bed
and then put it into here
beware going from a non-living soil into
the living soil just for flowering don't
you think how do you transfer the two
you can't get the roots out i also don't
really like the idea of bugs whether
they're beneficial or not
not really trying to you know replicate
the wild kingdom
in my tent
but it's on my journey of exploring
going organic in here
who should i talk to who do you want to
see me bring on the show to try and
convince me i need to go with some
uh
living soil in here versus my normal
pots which i can move around easier
which i could fit more of which i could
transfer in and out easily
yeah
so i'm not sold but help me be sold who
should i talk to please leave that in
the comment section
and like the sign says
come at me hippies
this is chad westport you find me at
chadwestport.com
also instagram
chad.westport but thanks for tuning in i
hope you participate in this because hey
you might get me going organic hippers
party on
[Music]
you