so come on in we're going to welcome
sean and kevin from cutting edge
solutions
good to see you as always
dude here we're going to be hanging out
on friday
you're probably one of the first people
i met so if you guys want to kind of
take that we're going to see you guys
that are that are yours to
navigate
it's going to
yeah grab a mic cool i think you're uh
right there right that's yeah that's
what we decided and it seems like good
for video purposes
yeah
and we're just kind of shooting the
breeze about what's going on and you
know telling the story of mj biz khan
that it's been going on for 10 years now
yep this is the 10th year anniversary
here we are doing it again it's my first
mj biz too wow really no isn't that
crazy that is a little crazy so
surprising i was always doing other
events well we were just talking about
that in a little live segment that we
just did where you know even when this
thing has gotten as big as it was in
2019 the last time they did it there's
still a ton of people in this industry
that are big players that still haven't
made it and there is this thing that
where you know it's it's so new for this
industry that's been you know
traditionally in the shadows
you know to do an expo like this it's
still something that people are still
just kind of testing the waters out and
putting their feet in and seeing if you
know what they think about it so welcome
man i'm glad you finally made it dude
sure oh yeah it's awesome and yeah it's
it's interesting walking around seeing
all these different companies that i've
never seen before and this is like las
vegas itself is a place where
everyone comes out of the woodworks and
it's it's cool to see new innovations
new products and you know the same old
faces too of course i agree i feel like
every time i come here and i get away
from whatever it is what we're doing at
the booth and whatever you know walking
around i every year i get reminded that
there's never a point in this industry
where you feel like you're comfortably
at a place of knowing everything or
calling yourself a master grower there's
always some new stuff coming out that's
about to blow my mind and it's
unfortunate that when you're here for
work purposes we don't always get to
dive into the actual trade show and get
enough time to walk around and see all
the booths that the actual attendees do
well it's really cool there's so many
experts in each little niche but it's so
hard to be a true industry-wide expert
these days with such a diverse
flow of products and techniques and all
of this stuff
it's really hard to have a great
comprehensive grasp on the entire scope
of the industry so you're seeing people
really hone in and specialize i'm the
lighting guy i am the ventilation guy i
am the extract guy and
really
being focused and if you pay attention
to those experts you can kind of get a
little bit of a balance and that's what
we're trying to do here you know we're
so entrenched in the cultivation side
being with royal gold you guys being
with cutting edge
i think it's really important that we
kind of keep our
eyes on the prize but keep up with
what's going on in the industry because
in cultivation it's advising all the
other portions like are you cultivating
for chirping profile are you cultivating
for thc content are you cultivating hemp
cbd like there's so many different
things like kevin you're in tennessee so
you see a lot of a different side of the
industry than we see in the west coast
tell us a little bit about what's going
on in cultivation world in tennessee oh
yeah um well tuning back to kind of the
uh
the uh everybody getting in on their
niche and finding their specialty and
and going 100 into that that's where you
see the most successful companies the
ones that are
you know playing to what they know
consulting with their existing base
finding new customers and and going that
route and some of the companies that try
to do it all are the ones that don't
survive so
you see a lot of that and it's nice to
uh you know play on each other's brands
and build a community verse you know try
to try to create a one-man show
cultivation uh side of the eastern and
central u.s
unfortunately tennessee is not blowing
up on the indoor and uh and craft
cannabis scene um
hemp industry hemp industries blowing up
we've got i think
3 200 cultivation license out there
unlimited plant count
um you know that's a crazy wild world
with uh a lot of fluctuations in in uh
you know price per pound and biomass and
everything so a lot of people are
scaling back or or uh
or you know toning it down to be
um
more in a safe zone rather than you know
doing 60 acres and having to supply a
30-man labor crew and everything a lot
of people are
are toning it back and going more green
greenhouse and
and craft style cultivation
in the central united states right now
we're seeing
our biggest growth in in areas like
missouri and illinois and florida and
then
obviously michigan and up into the
northeast but it's nice to see
some of these new markets go live in the
central u.s like illinois per se where
they have home cultivation they have
commercial cultivation
and then they uh you know the culture is
really starting to evolve there
um and it's it's kind of um on the home
cultivation side
it takes me back to michigan 10 12 years
ago yeah it's in its infancy there yes
yes so we're seeing a lot of energy
a lot of positive community growth and
uh and just a lot of uh really good
things coming out of the out of the
midwest and the central us in those
markets missouri is one
just like that where they have a really
healthy
home cultivation model for caregivers
and stuff so
the retail market's healthy
the
culture and the community of the home
growers is healthy and then you also
have the the big corporations and
commercial facilities coming in to do
large-scale production so
we're really excited to see see this
cultivating in the midwest and then even
down into the southeast now with with
virginia uh so yeah virginia so big yeah
i love that there is some
preservation of the medical small
homegrown
cultivation style in these new emerging
markets and that's something
we've seen in a lot of markets that's
kind of scary and really inhibits growth
is when the people at home aren't
allowed to grow and there's very strict
large-scale regulation and all these
hurdles and barriers to entering you
know in florida you have to have had a
greenhouse license an existing
greenhouse business for the 80s since
yes
40 years 30 40 years to actually get one
of the commercials don't have homegrown
so you know which is you know
i think that that's one of the most
negative things that an emerging
market can do is limit in that way you
gotta let people come in fresh the
people that have been adversely affected
by
uneven law enforcement i think is huge
too like there's no way that somebody
that was busted for growing cannabis in
the 90s can effectively participate in
florida because there's no way they
could have owned a business while they
were serving time for having
an ounce of pot so
it's really these barriers to entry to
the people that built the industry and
fought for it for so long it really kind
of bothers me and you see places like
illinois where you're allowed to do it
on a small scale and you see people
excited about it missouri too like you
were saying that speaks to us as
cultivators people who got into it with
three plants or two lights and
built our knowledge base from this like
little
germ of an idea of having to hide in a
closet
yeah i love that the you know the aspect
of actually you know the home grows
getting put into the laws as these
states come online
you know the medicinal aspect of
consuming the plant is obviously it's a
huge factor
you know the part of growing the plant
the connection with actually growing
plants is something that you know
there's so many people that would never
really take that on as a hobby and
there's something so healing and
therapeutic and medicinal about getting
into the cultivation of a plant and and
developing your relationship as a human
to a plant or to your garden i think
there's there's such a fine balance
there now as these states come online
and actually you know push forward on
the home grow i think that that is such
a crucial thing for our society to get
back into nature in that regard
absolutely so
sean you've been with
cutting edge solutions for a good long
while now but you've been in the
industry for longer
and across a kind of interesting expanse
of different occupations and niches in
their career yeah kind of floated around
what are you seeing now
and like in your involvement in
cutting-edge solutions through these
home grows like
give us a little bit of your perspective
on the industry yeah so like
eight eight to ten years ago i was
wrapping up in the northwest so oregon
and washington and it was right around
the time when they were becoming legal
medical programs were rolling out and i
watched just like you guys were talking
about the rise and fall of washington
right that was one of the biggest most
emerging markets especially for home
growers and all of a sudden licenses
came out and homegrown got cancelled and
it destroyed a lot of not just the
cultivators but our industry as a whole
grow shops closed
every single like half of them closed up
in the seattle region
and that really destroyed the
the whole premise of
why we wanted cannabis to be legal in
the first place we just wanted to not be
messed with by the government right and
now it's become regulated not really
legal in that sense
but you know as the industry is evolving
do you think we'd be talking about legal
cannabis in missouri five years ago so
it's it's really cool to see that
happening but there's there's some good
things happening there's some bad things
happening and it's kind of all across
the board
but
the west coast the saturation is there
for sure you know farmers are kind of
hurting out there and i think the the
national model is is adding to that you
know pounds from oklahoma are going to
new york city all the time
and that takes away from the california
growers that have been doing it for 30
40 years on heritage farms i mean for
what it's worth the same thing's
happening all across the world now and
that's something that i feel like you
know it's going to lean heavily on you
know federal legislation changing you
know at some point i feel like
the natural you know the ability to
create a cheaper
well-crafted you know pound of cannabis
in california or oregon or washington in
these drier climates
you know that might change landscape
scape especially when you're talking
about possibly shipping out you know
overseas
for sure yeah we were just talking i was
talking with jose our sales rep who
deals a lot with mexico and colombia for
us and a company in colombia just signed
a 60 million dollar contract for
exporting flour to the u.s
and they can produce flour for pennies
on the gram
totally it's insane and so you see these
federal
kind of
hurdles slowing everything down and
really a big problem to me is that the
federal government's failure to act and
kind of support the greater national
distribution model
is dismantling
the existing industry in california and
oregon and places that have been doing
it so
by dragging their feet they're creating
an environment where
all these legacy growers are going to be
underwater by the time
we open up to a
an export model within the united states
being able to throw
a semi-load of cannabis from different
growers
in california out to new york out to
michigan out to these emerging markets
and if we can get some traction
get a lot of the people who are active
in the community in the legislation
writing these state legislations
and then pushing it up the next level to
their senators and pushing for the
federal we might be able to get over
this hurdle and preserve some of this
long time legacy farming and influence
of the people from the 60s 70s and 80s
that built this industry that allowed us
to be where we are today we wouldn't be
here talking about this in las vegas
at a public convention center if it
wasn't for those people that risked
everything
in all out
domestic warfare to produce cannabis for
all of us to consume so
hats off to all you legacy growers and
farmers yeah i mean the emerald triangle
as a brand
is
in demand worldwide so if we had the
ability to market that internationally
it would you know
set northern california for a market
that's sustainable for decades if not
you know a century
yeah and everyone in california was so
excited about it we're the napa we're up
in humble we're in the emerald triangle
we're going to be the napa of cannabis
we're going to everybody wants this
but they can't get it yeah and that's
that's kind of our focal point of moving
into markets like columbia right now
they are building their legislation on
export right now they are exporting to
germany and the uk and these markets
that only allow import into pharmacies
and stuff so
it's unique seeing that happen in other
parts of the world and and you know we
want to be a part of that
wow yeah and not being as familiar with
the international as you guys are i know
you were just down in colombia you just
did the big expo down in mexico yeah in
mexico tell us more about that because
if the u.s could get off its ass and get
some legislation and we could be
exporting to spain and all these other
places with our california cannabis i
think it would be a different world
totally and and what's really cool about
columbia and mexico especially the trade
shows we went to
it looks like
northern california 15 years ago
everybody wants knowledge they're hungry
for knowledge and they want to do things
the right way because those two
countries specifically don't trust gmos
they don't trust monsanto they've banned
uh roundup they've banned gmos and
that's the same model they're using for
cannabis they want to do it the right
way
but the people are are super excited and
the legislature is a little different
than than it is here colombia is pretty
much export only at this point which is
an interesting business model but they
they only export to canada and germany
which you wouldn't think are the main
places but germany has different
pharmacies where they can basically make
their own concoctions there so whatever
they bring in for material they can then
make a cannabis pill or make gummies in
germany but even germany their cannabis
legislation isn't isn't there either so
it's like everyone's kind of chasing the
tale of the next thing to happen and
we're doing the same thing in the states
too but it is cool to see people
passionate and hungry for knowledge in
these countries
for sure yeah i'm interested to see the
global cannabis coalition and i don't
know if i just coined something that
doesn't exist yet
but that's what we need to see is you
know lawmakers from every country from
every state especially that's legal
medical or recreational coming together
to share a voice
on a world scale to talk about how to
get past
the past 100 years of
demonization of one of the most
effective healing plants on the planet
true that
yeah
i wish that we had
50 states that were actually united and
we could actually work together
to make something like that happen but
we're so segregated as a country it
makes it difficult to see
how that's actually going to work out
you know the progress has been slow
we've been saying that i'm sure there's
people in the 60s that never thought
that they would be here today to see
this you know where it's at
you know it's a it is slow but like you
know i think it was our second or third
episode of royal grand radio
where we had a guest on that was born
and raised in virginia
and i think we made a comment that
virginia would probably be the last
state of the 50 to go legal and boy do i
feel like a dumb ass because i'm pretty
sure i'm the one that said that
yeah here we are like mississippi's on
the very dragon absolutely is another
that would who would have ever imagined
no absolutely
you know when you think about these you
know deeply entrenched you know original
colonies with virginia you know
there's some old boys mentality there
and it's nice to see
that emerging into change but we just
gotta
get the neighbors down in north carolina
and over in tennessee and kind of
get them to see the benefits that it
brings to the community
yeah i mean through the 90s uh
eastern or western carolina eastern
kentucky and and eastern tennessee were
you know their own sort of emerald
triangle in the appalachians so it would
be nice to uh to get to play at some
point yeah let's like get the hills of
kentucky into producing cannabis again
because that's you know been a hotbed of
homes
moonshiners and cannabis growers it goes
hand in hand
you know those the government hill
people yeah be a good special on the
discovery channel yeah yeah right
exactly it'll be on one day
i assure you i'd be feel more fascinated
to see how the hemp verse cannabis plays
out in places like that because i know
there are places humble being one of
them where they put the kibosh down on
any kind of hemp growing because the
cannabis market itself is so
strong
and you know there's a lot of fear of
their you know contamination which is
yeah
in in our market um
you know nobody nobody's growing seeded
him uh everybody's growing seedless
female
either
you know feminized genetics i think some
of the strongest feminized genetics out
there are in the hemp industry i've
grown four years consecutively with no
hermaphrodites or males and uh
and like
you know that is that is super
impressive so
um you know these two markets you know
that's going at a scale thing and then
and then you know our our side of the
industry is more more of a fine-tuned
craft thing but you know we're making
great strides with the capability to do
acres and acres of feminized seed and
auto flower stuff and just get the data
and research and and fine-tune
consistency and genetics so
so yeah i mean i'm excited about the
fiber market but um but you know if that
was ever to explode uh we would we would
need uh decoration facilities within 20
miles of each fiber farm to make it you
know logistically or or production
abilities make sense so
so i i don't foresee that until there's
a big movement of you know subsidies or
programs to encourage um decortication
and processing facilities for fiber
i think that's still a ways away but
that is truly exciting as well and i
think it'll have to be you know regions
go after that and other regions go after
female flowers or or you know like
oregon cbd is light years above people
in genetics they've created genetics
that uh will not will not pollinate
and oh wow you know even if there's a
seeded out farm you know that they are
making strides into you know where open
pollination is not even a threat so it's
sterile females essentially essentially
yes wow that's very cool
and i like what you said about you know
different markets and different regions
are going to emerge at different rates
and you see like
illinois again and they're starting to
see some traction on decor
decorification and actually processing
the fiber you got the guys at heartland
hemp and klr genetics and
they're really doing a good job of
actually trying to vertically integrate
and it's a slow process but you see them
cultivating large-scale
smokable hemp smokeable cbd flour
essentially
and also going for larger scale fiber
production and i think you're going to
see that sort of model emerging where
they're going to privatize and
vertically integrate for their own
you know processing of fiber in-house so
they can farm on site process on-site
and move directly ideally to an on-site
or neighboring fiber processing or
textile
facility to actually produce wares from
the fibers but you're right it's got to
be so local to make it cost effective
this is a hemp shirt i wouldn't wear
hemp stuff every day you know i want to
wear cannabis clothes you know well they
actually are making really fine hemp
clothing yeah we were talking about that
in the past episode where for years we
all wanted to wear it then you put it on
you're like jesus that looks like a
goofball you know but that's a really
nice finely designed shirt yeah this
patagonia like they're they're killing
it with they got a hemp khakis and hemp
uh nice shirts and stuff see that part
of the industry i feel like is so wide
open i mean there's so much room for
this plant to seriously take over the
planet on such a positive level when
you're dealing with plastics and fuels
and stuff like that i mean there's so
much potential for this thing to just
completely explode but again like you
were saying sean these are global
companies patagonia that's a global
company they're not reliant on us and
so you know tying back to that like are
you seeing the same vigor
down in mexico and colombia for the hemp
industry for sure
down in colombia
the focus has been more on the thc
just for right now they can only really
export extracts so everyone's pushing
for terps and pushing to extract and
then export that but they're importing
him from canada in colombia to make
clothing
so it's very funny when you look at it
like that yeah like you were just
talking about localization you'll see
that happen more but
part of the the qualm or the
the stopping point is always legislature
you know so
if those things can change like on a
local region in the southeast we'll be
making milling and creating textiles
all in the same place that we're growing
but i think globally that will start to
change too
a lot of their you know the the sparkle
in their eye lights up when with the
hemp side of things when you get into uh
bioremediation of soil
so
sucking up toxins uh of over overused
and and over uh
produce farmland and and
and you know just the
the uh
areas of our past that we've uh polluted
some of our farmland areas of the
country so you see a lot of interest in
that down there and
and yeah it's exciting you know a
tropical climate and a south american
climate would be perfect for fiber
production and stuff as well and about
40 percent of the land in mexico is
completely contaminated from herbicide
pesticide and fertilizer use or overuse
so they can't even really grow corn in
the places they were 10 20 years ago
because the land is so fallow
but
to pull up the contaminants starting a
hemp program to bioremediate that soil
you can get 20 to 30 percent of that
land back and then be able to use it for
agriculture again that's huge yeah
it's such an effective bioaccumulator
and you can get rid of a lot of the
the tissue that holds all of those
toxins and still use the fiber and still
use some of that plant in an effective
way
remediate the land grow something of
value
and actually move
forward in you know a conscious way to
improve the land again i think that's
insane and fantastic and we've got to
spread the word about this sort of thing
yeah and like all of us standing in this
room that's
kind of where we started with the
industry you know maybe we started
growing weed because we like to smoke
weed but at the same time there's always
that connection between the earth and
the plant and yourself
we we didn't start growing weed to make
money maybe but you know that was just
an added bonus it was a quick second
yeah for sure for sure but the whole the
whole point of having ranchers up and
humble and being out in the woods and
living in a tent and being connected
with the plant was because that was the
experience we wanted we didn't want to
just rip up the land plant in the ground
and then
maybe not grow there again two years
later because it's destroyed you know
yeah it wasn't out of convenience or
wanting to live in a lap of luxury like
you said
you're living in tents on the side of
mountains
far from
actual goods
water sources you're pulling from
springs and having to check your water
lines every day and like really living
in the land off the land in the middle
of nowhere so many of these people built
from the ground up with empty 40 acre
parcels with just an old logging road
and we had to learn how to cut wood and
build water boxes and you know trap you
know pests and rodents i mean you have
to learn everything from from the ground
up to be able to pull this off
successfully and it wasn't living in the
lap of luxury like we weren't all
cannibis ballers kicking our feet up on
the side of the hot tub watching the
plants grow that's not at all what it
looks like definitely not definitely not
yeah quite the opposite yeah you know
sustain sustainability and the focus
on getting there is you know what drives
a lot of us uh royal gold with the
sustainable media and then hydroponic
cultivation i think that is one fuel
that's always going to continue to burn
in this industry and and keep the fire
going because uh you know it gives us
all purpose to continue to better
ourselves so 100 and like what cutting
edge is doing to innovate more organic
liquid fertilizers for hydroponic
applications and you know using
sustainable mediums like cocoa to kind
of create a balance of
this is a soil type cultivation process
but it's all hydroponic we're doing all
we can to minimize our water consumption
to minimize
water contamination nutrient runoff
nutrient outflow we want the plant to
consume everything we're putting into it
and not be wasting any of these
resources so
yeah and we you know we've been
preaching foliar applications of organic
additives for
20 years now and it's
finally catching on finally the people
are starting to understand that plant
takes 80 to 200 times as much nutrition
through the stomata and you know that
keeps your reservoir clean
the plants getting available nutrients
you can add organics in you know
you know every day we're making waves
and it's nice to see some of these
techniques catching on in commercial
application scenes man i feel like we
could go on all day
um we've got another little while here
we've got some other guests about to
join us we got the thc girls the high
country girls from
florida yeah come and join us here next
we'll have to get you guys back on and
have more conversation you know at a
different time maybe in the studio where
we can dig deeper into some of these for
sure we'll get a uncle john to come out
too and we can all
tell the stories that sounds great
appreciate it so much yeah hey thank you
guys yeah this is a pleasure thank you
always good to just hang out with my
boys you know no doubt i'll be seeing
you guys all week for sure we'll have a
great time
[Music]