cheers everybody today we're talking
about something we all got to do several
times a day and that's cleaning our
Banger after a
dad and usually these
Q-tips things
uh Hey swabs things of that nature they
all work really great the the biggest
downfall that I found is when it comes
to the necks and you're trying to Shell
Q-tips up there and they break off in
there it's terrible things so uh dab
spongee shout out dab sponge they came
up with an
ingenious
flexible
NE so you're able to just get it right
down
there
boom and it's nice and flexible just
right in
there all deep black yeah they've got
the dab spun mini to be able to get down
into the control towers and and slurpers
and and the
other devices now what's really cool is
the original dab or I guess the dab
sponge
2.0 fits those buckets so you just grab
your
bucket and uh fit just right in there
goad dunk it
boom it's right in
there boom boom
boom they even have this nice cool
little carrying
case I haven't seted it up yet but made
out of silicone traveling be able to get
your marbles in there all that good
stuff as you can tell that was super
easy super fast uh doesn't get much
better than that honestly I'm glad
somebody came out with one of these
things because they are Lifesaver
especially when when it comes to
slurpers and troll Towers things of that
nature um these necks are a [ __ ] so oh
yeah
cheers