okay so see this thing
and all the way down there that's the
root oh look a little mushrooms growing
in
between the little fingers uh
i would not eat that one yeah but
what i want you to do because we don't
know if it's poisonous or not
look there is it just what is that a
wasp
that's a y it's fine it's a it's a
friendly one it's eating probably little
bugs that we don't like okay anyway can
you
come here aphids no uh yes
probably hopefully can you try to grab
this
and pull it out why because we're gonna
we're
it's ready to take out yep pull
good job oh my god all right let me get
a
a gemma shot all right what do you think
so we're
so these we grew for their seeds
okay there's but we can eat
that now right
and then okay
so so now we can plant more stuff in
there okay
are you super excited
not so excited all right can you can you
put it over
on the on the grass over there okay
watch out for
oh thank you perfect yep
all right thank you
yes you can definitely pick one who's my
assistant gardener
are you gonna pop are you gonna get the
seeds out of this you know what i'm
gonna do i'm gonna give those to other
people
can i pick a few you can pick a few and
why are your hands all green
from the thing that i made at camp okay
i'm gonna pick the big ones okay
so basically they'll dry out and then
we'll send them to people
can i get a bunch uh you can get a bunch
just don't drop them
and are you super excited to eat the
daikon
yes are you like i can't even wait
i need to eat it right now you can't
wait