i'd try to put him on your citizen's
rest
you did i tried to
it didn't work it didn't work
what it did let me know for sure there
comes
[Laughter]
oh man i had a wood splitter stolen out
here about a couple weeks ago give me
your id i'm gonna put you under citizen
seriously and i looked around and all
them looked at each other like
and then my buddy pulls up and and i go
down to this window and i'm all dude
their cops get everything [ __ ] burn
it whatever you got to do blah blah blah
and then the guy that guys the guy was
almost fighting with his name was
balzano um agent baldwin later on i
found out yeah
and he just comes at me he's all i'm
tired of [ __ ] with you and pulls a
gun out and his little necklace [ __ ]
thing and
he starts walking towards me and i'm
like [ __ ] [ __ ] and so
his gun out so i hit his arm up and i
just take off running through the woods
and i'm running through the woods and i
got this doberman and i'm running
through and my doorman's right next to
me just hopping over stumps and and i'm
like oh [ __ ]
[ __ ] we run and i got like i got my
wife and my newborn baby and then in the
house we just built like about a mile
away so i'm running through the woods
all the way to the house i'm gonna get
up get up and get her in the car and
with the baby and i'll drive out the
back way go get out of here and then i
then i'm like oh
god we're getting raided [ __ ] and so i
start walking down through the woods i
go underneath the gate and and i can
hear i'm talking at the gate and and
about the time i get there i get like
almost to the grow because i got 15
trimmers in there i'm like we got to get
those guys out of there you know this
cops are coming in i'm just trying to
and i'm trying to get there and then
also here's the trimmers coming through
the woods like running i'm like
oh they're like oh brian brian showed up
and said
said
that we're getting raided to [ __ ] run
down the creek i'm gonna keep running
down the creek i'm uh brian brian's the
one that pulled up in the car so he's
the one when i did this he ran
he got out of there
wow so so they tried to bang on the
window and got him to like take the key
out and then he got out and he pushed
the door into him and he took off
running too and so he's running so i get
back to the grow and i'm like oh [ __ ]
didn't take a while so i don't know why
i did it but i'm like i went up to dry
room and started snapping lines down and
carrying bundles of weed and trying to
stash it and and i do this for a while
and i'm like [ __ ] i'm looking around for
a lighter because i'm like man i'm
getting some gas and lighter i'm just
gonna burn them you know just get rid of
this thing and i can't find a lighter oh
no
[Laughter]
and then pretty soon i could hear the
cars coming down the driveway a little
popping sound of the tires
so i start walking up the hill
and end up just like i could see them
coming in they start clearing buildings
with all these like people with flak
jackets and i'm like oh my god my
world's just
come to an ending it's like [ __ ] the
darkest like oh
it's crumbling so bad
is gonna be so bad this is such a big
operation at that time 250 lights
[ __ ] um this is the house with the
with the fake flowers yeah yeah fake
lovers
yeah so so i'm like man this is not
not gonna be good and so i go up i walk
by my neighbor's property he's got
indoor these generators go and i can
there's i can hear vehicles just coming
in too i'm like um turn you off okay you
probably don't need to be on right now
oh no
oh
and then i walked to the road and i get
a ride down in the back of this truck
and
and uh
and then i ended up going back up there
that night because i had a bunch of
money stashed
in my house
and get up there and there's still like
news crews now there's like the news
trucks and stuff that's when i knew i
was in trouble i'm like
oh [ __ ] you got four news different
crews like at the road front thing i'm
like
oh this is a big deal
it was a big deal i remember being
with a group of our friends in willow
creek
and hearing it on the news and all of us
were like
we just went from one to two lights and
we were all like dude we're [ __ ]
doing it and then we read about you and
we were like
wow
guys we're not doing it yeah we're not
as big as we thought we were
i remember reading about it in high
times i was in michigan still never been
to humboldt and
you know reading about that and taking
so much inspiration i was like wow
that's what i want to do and our group
of friends that we're growing you know
like a couple dozen plants and tomato
patches and stuff
we're like wow we can let's do it we're
getting lights and
you know i've done a light here and a
light there and
some outdoor and we took inspiration
from that and
i think i'm just one of many voices that
can say
thank you because
you fought that battle and took that
fall and we all learned from it and we
all
took it up a notch yeah
yeah well i didn't take the fall i
decided to run
instead because i was like i went and
got
i went and got this lawyer and
you're not supposed to say name so i'll
say it but um he was a very famous pot
attorney and i went and see him in san
francisco and
and i'm like
here's what we got
dude you just got indicted for uh
you look at 20 years like you're young
you got a family um
maybe you should go become a canadian
get the [ __ ] out of here this is
federal now and and they don't play
there you're you're gonna do some
serious time and it's it's [ __ ] you
you don't want to do this and i'm like
all right so i'm like so i went on the
run
and uh
uh you know
you know going down to the spy store in
san francisco got all the books on how
to change your identity
yeah yeah
and i'm like so
so i became uh josh abrams
i had this guy used to sell we too and
and reno and
and gave him like 10 grand him all dude
we kind of same hide same build whatever
and and well
you know let me borrow your identity so
so we go to the dmv in nevada
and
they they
they uh
they do the thing where you go up with
all your information they get your
license you get do it this and then they
go like go to window nine to take your
picture or whatever and so we
went in there and checked it out for a
day or two and just trying to see what
the routine was and i'm all right dude
you go up do all the stuff with them
and i'll be sitting right here and when
they tell you go to window nine i'll
grab the paperwork and go to window nine
and take the picture yeah and so
i go to window nine get the picture i
get this now i got a driver's license
and then i went to the post office and
and i ended up getting a passport and so
i'm set and then i'm like i got a wife
now and i got my daughter
so i find this other
lady that has a kid the same age and so
now i got passport ids my wife and the
kid the kids got a passport too
now my wife's sarah
and so we're like all right we're on the
front now we got ids i'm [ __ ]
learning [ __ ] and and so i buy a motor
home and i'll start we start traveling
and and so we end up
traveling all over like the kind of uh
kind of north northwest you know oregon
washington utah and and then i'm like
well should we try canada like that's
what he said and so so we don't have
nothing on it so i'm like [ __ ] go in
the canadian border and pull up
and
like hey
you know
and he's oh when she just pull right
over there and you guys go on inside i'm
like
go inside they search the motorhome
and then we give them our stuff and
what we didn't think about was that
you know josh abrams isn't sarah's
husband and it's not the baby's dad and
that's a little bit of a red flag i
guess
no no
like
am i
taking somebody else's kid up to canada
and they want to talk to the dad
which is a divorced husband of the girl
that we got the id from like
oh [ __ ] oh
damn this is where the cookie crumb is
yeah i'm just sitting there sweating
bullets and then josh abrams never told
me that he got arrested at a concert
selling weed and so they're like what
about this blah blah blah rest you have
and they want me to describe it to them
and i'm like
i don't know
i'm trying to make [ __ ] up i'm trying to
i'm trying to lead them into telling me
and it's not going good you know and
they're just like we're not comfortable
with this and i'm over there pacing
sweating like
is this how it's going to go down at the
border right here and finally they're
like
josh come here
go over there and they're like and they
got the the the entry forms and they
have the stamp it's like a red [ __ ]
thing in itself
and it's rejected they're all you're
ejected
from canada you can go get the motorhome
go right around the building it'll turn
around and take you to the u.s customs
and then i'm like oh great i'm like i
feel like i've
i really skated this one and
and so i have to go and get the
motorhome i'm like oh
and i pull up on my oh [ __ ] u.s customs
that's even worse oh no
you got a double guy
and they're like why did they reject you
why'd they do it
oh no [ __ ] but they made it through that
one and
you know what i think i might just stay
in the u.s
it seems wise at this point
[Laughter]
so i'm with santa rosa
wow and i shaved my i shaved my head
bulb
and i grow a goatee
i look kind of like a little white
racist [ __ ] you know
[Laughter]
you know you know and it just looked
totally different and i
go and i start doing stuff in santa rosa
i'm on the run and i'm like man i need
to get deep in this medical marijuana
thing and get this stuff legal you know
and so i just become like this huge
advocate and start supporting all these
like
like venues that are like going after
legalization and stuff as josh abrams
that's josh abrams and uh i started
dispensary in berkeley called berkeley
medical herbs on university avenue i
started one of the first dispensaries in
santa rosa called anko
and and and i'm just building grow rooms
as fast as i can it's like i've got it
down i could literally couldn't be like
oh okay you got you know whatever you
got a garage or you got this like three
bedroom house and i like i got this
downloader like like i could go to the
store and get almost everything i need
to complete it all in one thing like
system now i could build a grow room
literally like two days and have it up
and running
i go grocery store and home depot and
[ __ ] have that thing going in two
days
and so i just like grow rooms for
everybody and i'll be like hey just give
me like 15 20 i'll build it yeah
and so i started making money just
getting little percentages off the
grounds i built and then i started the
dispensaries and
everything was good for a while um
you know lake county and built another
big indoor because
dennis perron at the time was like
like oh man we can't get enough weed to
support all this stuff
i know what to do about that
i did like 150 lighter in lake county i
found this nice property and and and
then but the things got hot i had a
property in lake county where i had the
150 lighter and then i had another
on the lake in clear lake i had a
house on the lake with a boat dock and
jet ski ducks and the the house was all
the way down the creek right next to the
dam and so i was like i don't want to
drive where i get pulled over and so i
take jet skis all the way and i dock
right below the property on the creek
and i go up over the hill and then go
check on the patch and then the garden
and then the grow and stuff and then
then i go back over and i had like alarm
system there because i was like with the
security store in garberfield and i had
that thing where i had a pager on it had
all the little stuff sensors everywhere
so it'd page me and i could get to a
camera and see what's at the gate
because i never want to get caught like
there you know so i had all this like
like redundancy
and it had a repeater had to go up to
the hill and then back down to the grill
and
and then i'd go back get on jet ski go
back home
i did that for like a year and a half it
was super fun
and then
things got hot jet skiing to work never
a bad day
then i then i um i went to nevada city
because i was feeling like [ __ ] was just
you know you just feel it's closing in
i just like man i don't feel good like
we just gotta do a new start somewhere
in nevada city and and then
a couple months later uh dea
rated rated me
[Music]
you