so i buy this property in potter valley
oh this is going to be a doozy guess
and and i got this great deal on it and
then it's like [ __ ] and it's surrounded
by national forest it's 40 acres
and three gates to get in it's like this
is called oak gap road it's like when
you go over the hill and you just start
heading towards the lake pillsbury it's
like right there you go up damn
man it's got this little cabin on it
it's like half built pretty pretty
pretty close but not not like finished
out
and it's got these green houses up above
and then it's all national forest i'm
like oh my god we can grow so much weed
in that natural forest
and so
so we get going i get a generator
startup get all the plants [ __ ] going
it's winter time like you know it's like
february and we're just like getting
everything i'm just cloning like crazy
and and we're up in the in the in the
up in the national forest we got
four-wheeler up there digging holes and
little benches and just up there in the
rain and [ __ ]
like carrying soil up with the
four-wheeler and carrying out to all
these little patches
and and this one day
i got my my fiance or maybe she was my
wife at the time and she was
transplanting down the greenhouses and
and me and my partner and his brother
were up there
digging holes and and
and we're [ __ ] it's getting hungry
it's like one o'clock been raining all
day we're just soaking wet and picks and
shovels it's just like oh we get on the
four-wheeler we start heading down the
hill
and we get down to the flat where the
greenhouses are in the tractor that i
gotta borrow from my dad
and all sudden his freaking sheriff and
flak jacket and camos jumps out behind
the the tractor he's afraid [ __ ]
like i was like whoa am i in the formula
i'm like whoa
and my first like and his brother starts
to jump off and and my part's like go go
go and i'm like it's like hit like
the guy's got his gun right here my
partner hits the arm up and then the cop
grabs on to the back of the four-wheeler
and i'm just start hitting gears you
know i'm dragging this this sheriff yeah
and when we start going and i don't know
what's going on i'm just going and we go
and and apparently
he went for held on for a while and he
let go and he just starts sliding on his
belly and he starts flopping over
and then there's all these sheriffs and
stuff over here and they got a canine
unit and i could see them coming at us
and and they're running towards us and
and i guess canine unit that
that sheriff just was flopping and then
the k9 guy just grabbed hold of him and
just started shaking him and
and we went down a little dip and and
i'm like getting ready to jump and i
jumped off i wouldn't didn't realize how
fast we were going so i jumped off and
was like
just start eating [ __ ] because i can't
run that fast and so we flop we run up
the hill and i'm like oh my god what the
[ __ ] there's shares here we're getting
raided and and and i'm like oh my god my
[ __ ] wife's on the greenhouse and so
i started turning around like no dude
come on they're just going to arrest you
you're not going to be able to help her
go get her bailed out and i'm like all
right so i keep hyping up the hill call
my mom my mom meets me at the little
bridge down there by the way when you go
over the hill a little bridge there and
my mom picks us up and
my mom calls bails her out
luckily my wife didn't have to like
dress out got her build out right away
right and then then i went turn myself
in
and uh wow and then what i learned was
i bought the property from the biggest
meth
cooker in freaking mendocino county oh
no his name was john loudermilk and they
called it the louder powder
and they had been after this guy for
[ __ ] decades this guy was like the
king and he like had people hired in the
sheriff's department they would tell him
when they're gonna rate him and he'd
like clean it up you're like [ __ ] you
you know
eventually and then it's gonna get dark
for a second just
you can cut this if you want it
so john laudermonk just was was i
i wish i knew it before about the
property i probably wouldn't bought it
yeah
um but
they were after him so hard and they
just could never get him
and uh
and so they they framed him
they they got this glassware from humble
evidence room and brought it up and they
framed him and busted him
and
at some point at the same property
during that same time
uh he had a party and this girl
like
that
fell down the stairs and died and they
were having a bear all raging and
partying and stuff and he ended up
burying this girl on the property no no
and then later on
went and
told them like hey this was an accident
and told him where she was whatever but
now
so they got him like tampering with dead
body or whatever like
and
and uh but they also framed him and then
he caught them framing him
and so now he's in court on both these
things
and and they they they're like
the judge is like you guys youtube go
figure this out this kid's not going to
trial this is terrible like you got a
sheriff framing this drug dealer you got
a drug dealer that buried a body and
i'm like reading all this [ __ ] i'm like
that's the property we [ __ ] decided
to buy
wow
so
so anyways
wow
right we had
3 300 plants i got busted for and and uh
ended up going from from over 300 back
that was 94. that's a lot of plans for
94. it was a lot of fun
and the only reason that we kind of got
a good deal is they were on a probation
search when they actually came to the
property they were looking for him they
didn't realize the property sold so they
cut all the locks without a warrant and
so they kind of had if we went all the
way to trial
it would have been like we might have
won yeah
and so they offered a good deal but they
also got to put my wife in prison if
like we didn't take it so i i took the
deal and i did like seven months in
in uh in
mendocino county jail which was on low
gap so i kind of i went from oak gap to
low gap oh man
that's a quick slide it's it's crazy to
me how many stories we hear in the
cannabis industry about
people who are you know just growing
cannabis getting rung up for the
previous tenants of properties
who are doing much much darker things
who managed to skate through it with
little or no consequence and yet then
the cannabis growers were the people who
got wrung up i i had a similar
experience
in humboldt after uh you know
somebody was doing the wrong thing on
the property and you know the cops come
two years late
and catch somebody growing weed it's
it's crazy
but so this is 94 and personally i'm a
little younger so i was really just
starting to get heavily into cannabis at
this time and in the midwest and 3 300
plants to me looking back it's like wow
we had like seven
and we thought we were a big deal in
michigan you know growing it in the corn
fields yeah 20 plants
and
so that's an amazing start and you come
out after seven months
in mendo county i had a lot of time to
plan my next indoor you know
i was like man you know what i'm going
underground yeah so i like lit in there
with that little short pencil [ __ ]
like drawing out my plants that there's
a underground indoor that i'm going to
build i'm like and i'm like yeah i'm
like man i'm kind of blown out in mindo
now they're like know me you know right
yeah i'm so i'm going back to humboldt
um so
so um what was the scale of that bust in
mendocino at that time as far as history
goes was it considered it was the big
one it was a big one but i was young
there i was like a kid like 21 years i
moved here in 94. that's why i'm asking
you know
so they kind of
it was one they were like they kind of
were culpable in the mid the probation
search and then other well like here's
this kid like doing this like at that
time they're like look at me like what's
this kid doing this
yeah and so it's kind of like i think
they put a little mercy on me you know
like oh you know this like
let's just get this
guy out of here let's teach him a little
lesson he'll figure it out he's
definitely not doing this again
[Music]
you