hey good how are you doing
come on in that's right
it's always it's always a holiday in
maine
right vacation land
oh would you like to introduce yourself
in the shower sure thing my name is tom
falbe this is casco bay cannabis company
i'm the owner of the company and this
owner of this fine fine building here
we just opened the beginning of april
and
we carry
mafka certified clean cannabis that is
grown by casco bay we're looking to
carry some additional people who will
also be cultivating with that standard
i'm a big fan of
elaine ingham's composting style and and
all that the living soil um growing
method so that's how we grow and then
we've got some edibles and
now some
live resin and
some live resin carts and some
cartridges
and we're just tucked away here in the
middle of a
a small neighborhood in south portland
you know about
four to six thousand people around here
and we're just looking to serve serve
the medical community as as best we can
i've been involved with the medical
program since 2010
[Music]
i got started when i had lyme disease
and i was i was using medical marijuana
for that and
and then just wanted to help other
people as as best i could because
it was it was an amazing experience for
me and and i've seen it make an amazing
difference for so many people and in
different
conditions you know people walking with
a cane to walking without a cane
people with ms
yeah so all those things
so and and i and just love
i just love growing weed it's just
you can't beat it
you can't you can't beat it and the
microbial scientific stuff
um that's always discussed on on future
canvas project i love i tune in every
week i'm on every thursday to listen
to leighton and everyone else talk so
so welcome yeah
so um how was the process of getting
open here
it was
it was a long
it was a long road 2020 was when i
started uh may of 2020
um you know i was i was looking around
being like gosh should i do it should i
not i don't know because this was a
commercial kitchen at the time
and
it would have been
easy to just leave it as a commercial
kitchen and rent it out
but you know new england is
in my opinion i grew up in new hampshire
and um you know new england is famous
for being progressive but then
once the floodgates of progressivism
open
they put the brakes on and that kind of
was what i expected to happen so i was
like man if i'm going to do it i better
apply now so i filled out
you know the initial application with
the town planner and then you have to
work with the town planner
and
fill out
you know several hundred pages of of
site plans and
all that kind of thing
and then you go before the town and and
they
decide whether or not they're going to
give you the thumbs up
and
then once they give you the thumbs up
which happened to for me in december
2020 then you've got six months to start
and you've got a complete 25
of
any changes within six months and so
what counted as 25 for me was paving and
it was the middle of winter and so i
couldn't get paving done and so it went
down to the wire i got the paving done
in april 2021
and then you know we're in the middle of
covid so
then you know my carpenter's coming in
to do work in here and he couldn't get
supplies and getting windows like a
skylight and that kind of thing put in
you know took until august
and then getting security put in
security is all backed up they're
getting all their stuff from china and
then everybody and their mom is starting
on adult use grow and so they're have
huge projects and so i was kind of
back seated for a while and that got put
in in
december
and
then that um delayed for two months
because i had the wrong recorder and i
had to get that from china and that took
two months to get here so then
we're in february 2022
and then i go before the town again
because i
i initially applied as
i initially applied
as one company and i thought i could
just easily change it and they're like
no no you have to get a new license so i
had to get a new license go before the
town that happened in march and then i
opened this month in april just in time
for 4 20.
i'm sorry so that was it yeah sounds
like a grueling process but i'm glad you
made it here and i imagine it might be
even less grueling than some states you
know so it doesn't sound easy but yeah
glad you made it i think i think in
maine at least
the small guy has a shot yeah you know
and and i think that that's why you see
such a thriving community of caregivers
in the state and you see such
active legislative participation from
caregivers because they have a shot
and they have a voice whereas i think in
other states at least my impression is
that there's
there's not even a chance
yeah yeah i agree
slight chance of anything
on the way
rolling the dice yeah exactly
okay um what products are have the most
movement or if there's anything that
you're just stoked to share you want to
show us a couple of the flowers that you
think are the best or whatever products
in general are moving whether it be
vapes or
rosin or edibles or the
shiatsu kush
has been moving and uh
that's a that's a good one um for pain
you know and
the what else has been moving um
the great gushers has been moving pretty
well too
awesome
right here yeah great pressures
and mostly flower you guys see the most
traction here yeah mostly flat yeah
mostly flour some edible some edibles
are starting to move as people you know
it was funny because i
again i'm waiting on the town to get a
sign put up on the side of the building
and so i put out a green cross flag and
people didn't really come in then i got
a sandwich with with like a sandwich
board with you know casco bay cannas
company written on it and people have
started coming in so now you know it's
getting a little bit of traction
um
but um there's
some people in the neighborhood are
starting to come in looking for
you know to get
edibles and those caramels are starting
to go pretty well because they're
they're based with fico
and so those are cruising along
um
here's a little
some shiatsu for you
yeah that's great
is most of this in-house or do you have
some trusted caregivers that you also
work with or
yeah we've got some we've got we're
adding more caregivers you know just
getting going so right now this is
mostly in-house but adding more
caregivers as we go you know
um that's the goal is just to have
you know local caregivers that can be
featured in here and and kind of spread
the love of of like a a small
a small um
operation and a small grower you know
just a craft grower who's
you know more tuned into
quality than quantity
so
[Music]
yeah we have you know we've got medical
cards that you can get on demand now so
anyone can come in that doesn't have a
medical card and they can
call this number right here
and say urgent
they can text urgent casco bay cannabis
company with a picture of their id and a
selfie
and they can
get a medical card within 10 minutes
so awesome
so i have a question from mr guerrero
uh what is your favorite daytime snack
not necessarily an edible but whether it
be a chip or a cookie or anything like
that what's your go-to daytime snack my
favorite daytime snack
i would
i say blue corn chips and hummus
yeah
blue corn chips i'm i'm a big
connoisseur of you know and by like all
the different kinds of health food
stores and that teacher whatever that
place in mexico is i can't even
pronounce it but
it's chitolan or something like that um
yeah those are those are my favorites
i'm sure awesome yeah the second part of
that question is do you foresee in 2023
an absolute explosion of the cannabis
industry tied into the snack industry
whereas you know doritos and nestle are
going to start getting involved with the
cannabis industry or even the smaller
you know let's say craft
uh snackers
that would be fantastic i would love
that you know like some some i mean
there's there's like i've got ice cream
coming in here you know the the you know
the you look around it's like the more
you look around there's more more and
more
products coming to market it's just
figuring out how to do it you know yeah
you know i think
doritos or you know i mean you see
chocolate bars and all those kind of
things but snackies would be phenomenal
yeah you know and the hummus i would
love to have it in hummus yeah that'd be
awesome
the reason i ask is i think mr guerrero
he's forecasting that that's going to be
the next explosion of the industry
so
i'd like to share that info
that would be awesome
and um
you had touched briefly on it in the
beginning but do you have anything else
that you want to tell the people
in the future cannabis project about
yourself or how they can find you or
follow you or
yeah sure um
at casco bay cannabis company on
instagram we're located at 575 westbrook
street in south portland right in the
middle of
red bank and old english village right
across from the new development there
um come on by we'd love to serve you if
you're a medical patient
awesome
all right this is live from maine
signing out back to you future cannabis
project