[Music]
foreign
oh wow we're live wow we're at the sesh
we had 420 last week and we're super
excited I think we're smoking some
golden coast today thank you anyone
who's watching or watching in the future
thank you to Golden Coast for for giving
us all of these flavors on the table
um and I think that just to frustrate
Peter we're starting with some form cut
Girl Scout cookies and then we're gonna
move into some really interesting stuff
but the Girl Scout cookies and I think
we can go around because we all smelled
it smelled really awesome but then here
there's some more land racy stuff and
it's just going to be a great sesh
so what did uh Zach I know you had some
really cool smell notes on the Girl
Scout on the Forum cut yes it was
um the aroma I got was this gray
um nutty coffee
Vibe and very sweet the cookies uh stood
out is just a it has such a foundation
as a as a like a tone I can't wait to to
smoke it I can't wait to see if it
translates I mean I bet it I bet it will
it's uh very impressive in how uh Rich
even for the amount in the bag it was
very like just invasive you know so I
love I love the terp that just gets
right in there and it's undeniably a
forum cut it's like it's so cookies I
love it it's like nutty and yeasty and
sweet and like vanilla it's just great
but also like mothbally it's real it is
really complex I'm stoked to try it but
you all were smelling stuff before
um we got here did anything else stand
out yeah oh
sorry the Lemon Cherry gelato that one
was so amazing it had like a very nice
vanilla kind of frosting smell so it was
really sweet and it really stood out to
me if you guys haven't smelled it then
definitely take a whiff right it's super
nice like delicate almost yeasty sort of
smell to it but I think this is a great
mix of stuff we have in front of us here
I think gold coaster next is a great job
presenting
um what he's known for what he's
passionate for with his land race
crosses present in the Colombian Haze
and the Albert Walker crosses we have
and some of the more new uh hyper stuff
you could call it like the Lemon Cherry
gelatos
um and everything else we have so let's
get into it I think we're rolling up
right now Otis what are we rolling up
form cut we're rolling up the Girl Scout
cookies Forum cut and then I think yeah
Jazz if you want to pick another one to
go in on yeah definitely
um you know we also have we have the
garlic skunk strain here this is the one
Pito is getting ripped on on 420 and
this is actually something unique
because we have the dry suit version and
rosin version of this as well
um that's something yeah we do so we
have three different variants of the
same strain and that's something unique
you very rarely get to see that so we'll
definitely get a chance to compare that
on the show today
um
yeah right now we're talking about the
garlic skunk so we have this in flower
form as well as rosin and dry sift form
so yeah right and it's it's very rare
that you get uh different forms of the
same cannabis flower so we're definitely
excited to tuck into that on the show
today and uh do a deeper dive on that so
we'll roll some of that up we uh
maybe we'll put some of the wax into the
joints and uh yeah the dry sift
definitely will put a garlic skunk
Square joint yeah a donut hell yeah yeah
um I mean this is such an amazing
selection I guess Jazz are you more
familiar with with golden ghost work and
sort of which one of these are
meaningful parts of a stable and as sort
of genetic Library
um just a little bit so I'm aware he's
very passionate him and Peter connect a
lot on the the land race side of things
and specifically uh just all across if
you look on what we have present here it
is mostly South American land race
crosses such as the Colombian hazes and
other variants of sort
um but it is cool because he does have
some Modern stuff too like uh as
mentioned before the Lemon Cherry gelato
the garlic skunk uh the manic kalio we
have a bunch of new stuff and we're
gonna tuck into it all but uh really
what I'm most excited for is there's a
Colombian Haze a somewhere here that
that smells ridiculous so definitely
want to tuck into that and see what the
experience will be like and um
Dave really has a wealth of knowledge
yet when I've seen him and Peter connect
um on YouTube it feels like there's a
really strong understanding of just what
makes quality and I kind of love to see
that there's someone who's like a
purveyor of
things like these equatorial hazes and
is also like yeah the form cut is good
enough that it makes the cut you know
like it there sort of isn't
any sort of biases it really is just
about quality exactly and I tend to find
that those
people of that mindset are the best
Growers yeah yeah
um I think everything we've examined
here so far uh whether it be old school
genetics or more new uh was all given
the same amount of love and care and you
can definitely tell them the end product
as you can tell by our reactions when
we're just going around right now
um so we'll definitely share this with
you and what we're thinking too
um but right now Gabe what do you think
about that joint man
first in hell is really nice it
definitely reminds me of cookies it has
that kind of gingerbready thing
you know the first hit the Cherry's
always a little hot yeah
but I'll have something to say about it
in a second but enjoyable smoke I mean I
certainly
um
I certainly think the dry pole was
really really flavorful
um there's just like a cookies is just
good comfortable neutral smoking weed
you know you want like when you have an
ounce of cookies you don't resent it by
the smalls at the bottom like you sort
of are just down to keep enjoying it
right
um
you know another thing's gonna be a
little more a little more difficult and
a little more challenging whereas I
would describe cookies as like the most
unchallenging
smoke and definitely a stable in
anyone's in anyone's uh stable it's
definitely a strain stable and
everyone's trying to collaborate at this
point in time
or some variant of it
Otis I just want to say I love your
Organics alive hat man oh yeah shout out
to Organics alive friend of the show
shout out Eric for sure Eric no no
nutrient company or I guess beneficial
company pulls up to events and really
supports the community in SoCal like
Organics alive shout out Organics alive
shout out to Aaron shout out bioag up
north shout out all the homies shout out
everyone man yeah we love the animals
shout out everyone we got to see a free
seat day too
it was great to get to talk to Trevor
last week these sessions have just
become such a
such a cool meeting place for so many
people and that hash I mean I'm still I
still think that that hash from um
uplift uplifted Minds is so good some of
the best material I've ever seen and
they were out there on 422 at
um king of ZL it's
it's just awesome seeing Community come
together oh what do you think of that uh
kooky it's nice
the flavor profile is still developing
it's very enjoyable it's smooth
it's very kooky
and so Jazz did you want to get into the
hazes next or the kushes because I know
that the Albert Walker's in there too
and you mentioned it
yeah
oh yeah busy hands I was really
intrigued by that Albert Walker dogoji I
was told that Albert Walker is not a
Skywalker but rather something a little
bit older so just something I've never
seen before I was really curious about
it well I guess in the chat can you as
if the Albert Walker
is a part of the dog walker because I
feel like the dog walkers are really
popular one and I'm pretty sure that
it's just like chem X Albert Walker and
so it's really cool I mean I think
getting to try like known parentage like
I've never tried the Eddie lepo Jade
that's in so many things like getting
the opportunity to try these you know
meaningful parents is always really cool
to get to understand sort of the history
of popular Turf profiles
oh it's kind of lemony cheesy it's not
really a kush yeah it's it's very
interesting as a nose super fruity on
that one bro the nose on that is super
super nice did you guys get that kind of
like
the Albert Walker yeah
[Music]
no shade no like totally great all this
product is amazing all this stuff is
amazing but we were all interested we
were all interested in the difference
between the Tupperware versus the bag it
seems that the bag based on structure
quality nose
um seems like it's indoor work and then
there's there's this these Tupperware
that seems like it's depths and I'm not
throwing like depths are cool I don't
have any problems yeah some good weeds
also yeah outdoor full set and I guess I
don't think we've and I don't know if
we've had this conversation yet but I
mean mixed light makes for some of the
best hash on Earth I guess it does is
some of the best flower to depending on
strands it's all about genetics as well
and it Calio number six this one is one
of the most stinky ones I've smelled so
far that one smells great this isn't
Calio this is manic all right
but I think manic may be Peter and if I
don't know if there's something to pull
up or if it's seeds you sell but it
seems like manic is a running theme
around these jars so maybe that's like a
common parent yeah yeah um the Irene is
another one where like I've rarely seen
the Iran on its own but it's just in so
much definitely definitely
I'll roll that one up
yeah manic manic kalio number six that
one smells great there is there's a
there's an orange
we're gonna have to roll the lemon
charge gelato eventually we just have to
I think Louisville runs our life up at
the end definitely definitely I like
what we're doing right now where we're
switching it in with the land race and
then one of the newest trains and then
switching it back so yeah yeah it'll be
a good one
and so Peter is that say that again
[Music]
Peter was fresh press right that that
the Tupperware is mixed light and the
Tupperware is stuff that he grew at home
okay and I just texted him asking uh how
he grew it
nice I mean again and thank you so much
to Golden Coast for this um spread also
shout out to homie Kebab Senpai if you
use his discount you can get 15 off on
brothers broadleafs do not forget
uh if you use the homie Kebab senpai's
discount code uh on Brothers broadleaf's
website you can get 15 off it's the
discount
carrying that stuff
nice blunt you can buy
and is what is the is the code Kebab
Senpai just so that everyone knows what
is the code the code is just kebabs all
caps
a b o b s
k a of course but you know there's two
ways to spell kebabs so just just making
sure they know so for blunts
so we're putting Haze in blunts this is
the one that I'm about to uh
Chinese food is that that's not what
it's called is it no this one almost has
like I think that's what the noise is
reminiscent of some kind of Mandarin
vibes
based on that nose c-a-l-i-o
manic kalio number six number six it
smells good there's a nug in here to
smell yes
chocolatey
yeah it's like a um it's like a Walker's
chocolate orange like the like English
ones thank you thank you
what am I experiencing I'm experiencing
a Walker's chocolate orange yeah
chocolate orange exactly I was gonna say
the Tootsie Pop the orange you're like
biting it into the whole thing you're
not even you're just like
broken glass into the terpiness of
orange and chocolate yeah and it's like
it's like a chalky chocolate there's
another nugget right here to put in
there yeah chalk is for sure like chalky
is is a terp profile that will come out
wafers
like who
who this came from over here pink Z pink
Z yeah
it's unraveling that Durbin poison notes
how's it feeling so the good homie it's
really nice weed I mean I enjoy I really
enjoy it
I really do like it this is pretty
let me think okay definitely like I
smell that definitely that orangey
tangerine like creamsicle type for sure
this one also has kind of like that
light glaze the sweetness
I do like stuff like this
I really hope I can taste this that
would be a nice thing to do
let's do it
I always liked it
number six
right now
is that him no this is tobacco the
flavor really developed in this one I
like this is three five is what I'm
calling I needed to get halfway through
this before I could like uh
get that classic cookie flavor that's
what we were just saying is that the
mintiness really just came out and it's
so Jazz was just pointing out how smooth
it was yeah um yeah great job Dave so
far you're one for one on on the Triple
A is for sure and it's it's spooky with
the good cookie flavor and not the
doodoo musty flavor yep it's like that
that well well point of like gas that's
just well-rounded and not too obscure
but not too much either it's super well
balanced
I agree on that extremely smooth
likes
I like his I smoke them in the morning
and they'll get me lit I like the hazes
I've tried I like I think I've Haze
you know the best Haze I saw was pipco
screen Haze but I really don't know how
many of those like true 110 plus day
aquaponics grown in Miami type you know
like that really is it's something I'd
love to see more of
smoke some Haze rosin that's like some
real Haze or Haze like uh
uh yeah for sure like uh lower than my
Lifesaver like a dry Siff would be cool
I bet there's like some old heads who
have some stories about like Haze finger
hash or something bouncing it on screens
I mean it's like you have to be in a
very cold environment pretty much oh
yeah have you done dry stuff no I'm not
I just seen the internet you know and
um of course like the traditional way
that people make it which is pretty cool
like with these like endless amounts of
filtered
um screens and and like you know these
are people in Morocco or people making
this in Afghanistan or something like
that which is like super cool
um and like all the different varieties
and stuff that's super I mean every
Micron is different you know in the and
the way of course also again how it's
how it's constantly processed in like
certain seasons and stuff like that's so
cool to me you know it's like a very
ritualized event you know which I I like
a lot about a lot of weed stuff you know
it's the ritual the history well it's
also how things were originally sort of
like preserved and how Terps were
actually shared across the world was in
hash you know like how it can be
preserved yeah
um so I think we should on that note
definitely in the next joint oh you know
we should we should smoke what Peter
smoked on 420 next
and some of the rosin in it as well
we have rosin dry sift and flower of the
same form and from the same person as
well if you like check it out yes I was
very impressed I was very impressed by
the dry sift
um it looks really nice it's sticky uh
it it just you can the like when you're
breathing it in the the way that it
invades and fills the sinus and
everything is like do you want to hold
them up super
has it just it is full it is like a jazz
cam the Jazz cam is that what this cam
is right here
it's currently aimed at use look at this
I mean it's pretty it's pretty I mean
it's
green but I mean like dry stuff is dry
sift you know it's like you're removing
certain size heads and it's doesn't mean
just because it's green doesn't mean
it's bad it's not tricep or is that I
thought it was oh all right I guess well
I guess I wasn't assuming it was bubble
hash no I mean it I mean it kind of is
it depends on it's basically dried this
is cured already I should I'm pretty
sure it's cured
um you know usually dry sift has to be I
mean it it but it's um you know it's
like I don't know if this is from his
trim bin or whatever but but I I hope
he's it is from his trim bin
very clean trim bin very nicely done
very clean but I'm I'm excited about
that it has such a I mean uh Streisand
yeah it's very very rich
um kind of has some like gassy notes to
it
um
yeah it's it's herbal
can I check it out for you yeah
it's got some like uh Sweet Lemon notes
to it I mean there's it's I was
impressed I was like into it have you
ever played around with any skunk
genetics do they wash uh yes they do
um
I haven't personally Percy washed but
I've heard good numbers about some of
their genetics I'm trying to think what
would be the greatest that I've seen by
them
oh I was just talking about like skunk
one type cultivars but also yeah yeah oh
I think I think you're saying like skunk
house genetics
yeah yeah no they're I know they're
they're worth watching they have great
genetics for washing
um but uh I don't know I actually I
haven't I haven't watched any song
genetics but I'd be down I'd be down
bring me bring them to me bring me your
fresh frozen yeah and we will do first
for the science for the community
I think it's only right that we put the
lemon charge a lot on the blind yeah
that's cool are we are we is the
hospital gonna be the blood no no no the
hash oil has to be in a junk we have to
taste the colors
I agree all right
okay it's like now you're getting picky
yeah no um sorry I love blunts they're
uh they're guilty pleasure I really
can't beat them man okay well Lemon
Cherry and a blunt is it's like the 20th
century
God
it's Timeless a blunt is times but Lemon
Cherry in the blunt I would say that's a
rather new trend
that's not on the paper I don't know
anybody nobody nobody you can smoke
Lemon Cherry gelato in a blunt in any
state
this is an interesting one to go around
the table is lemon tree a lot gelato
runs answer your say what you were gonna
say and then answer the question but is
Lemon Cherry gelato runs it's a question
aren't opposed to the room well first I
was going to say well putting the Lemon
Cherry gelato in a blunt it kind of
tastes takes away from that flavor of it
and that's why it goes great in the
paper or a cone or you know in a bong
hit like a solid rip because you can
really get that Rush of that flavors and
like I don't know it just lights off the
terpenes and in a magical way 100 agree
with that statement however this is
superior tobacco this is a Brother's
broadleaf
well the pink Z really came out so I I
have faith in it just because the pink Z
I can really taste the flavor of that so
that was really nice you can really
still taste the fruitiness of it so I'll
give it to you
um he said he had it was a pink Z that
that was in the last bone Daniel was a
was a was it Pinky
was the pink the pink zebra yes shout
out to don't don't panic
it's hard we smoked on 420 it was good
yes we did we smoked the fruit zoops as
well but I guess and I'm curious what do
people think about because I agree that
it's super flavorful to me it is very
similar to runs but there's something
it's obviously a different Fino but is
it the same
thing or is it or is it just a gelato
Fino like people say is it a 33 bag seed
I think it's very close to the cake
because a lot of times you get
I think
I think it's closer to cake just because
you get that um that like that sweetness
and then also you get that like that
dark purplish normally with those like
orangish hairs so you get that nice
little combo which you really see in a
lot of the cake mixtures so I definitely
really like the gelatos more than the
runs personally
I think it's runs I think it tastes like
runs it tastes like a floral like fruit
punch yogurt uh or like some kind of
yeah funky funky old milk Vibe with and
yeah you know and I think that that's
pretty consistent amongst all all of
them I've tasted and I know a lot of
people rename everything this and by so
I've but I've you know it's been around
it's been around but I'm I'm gonna be
very straightforward I'm not a runs fan
really not
um certain gelatos I do enjoy a lot
um 41 you know that's great you know
everyone's a classic always so good in a
blunt oh so good in a blunt but I think
one of the stories about Lemon Cherry
gelato the one that is other than it
being runs is that it was a connected
bloody one bag 41 bags seed yep and like
who knows they're so similar and so
closely related regardless but it's a
fun one yeah it is the mythology of runs
versus so right now we're rolling up the
uh
the manic kalio number six which tastes
like Japanese food which is interesting
because you know tastes like Chinese
food
food yeah this one's Japanese food soy
sauce this one this one tastes like
seaweed salad
Umami yes Umami yeah
yeah which is present in a lot of stuff
yeah I love that I love that's one of my
favorite
um
finding like that kind of like kimchi
note that's in food too or in weed too
is super delicious well and I also feel
like because like it you you are more
attuned to seeing it in things that
people described in more purely desserty
tones I forget what it was that we were
looking at recently and I was thinking
of it as just like a straight dessert
profile and then you very astutely
called out that there were some of those
yeah
[Music]
something I think it might have been a
skittles cross which you know you don't
normally think about that being in
Skittles But Mommy it's there
it's good the flavor is translating
there's not like Tootsie Roll Tootsie
Pop that you were talking about
um there's like a
kind of like a condensed milk thing but
then also kind of like a seaweed salad
like like
like good seaweed solid with like sesame
oil maybe it's a sesame oil thing I'm
tasting more than seaweed but the
condensed milk is that Umami yeah
but you crushed that to script like that
oh yeah hell yeah taste that you're
gonna you're gonna get that condensed
milk for sure it's good it's more sesame
oil than seaweed solid I didn't realize
that one was manic this one number six
yeah oh here you go well because because
said condensed milk to me it totally
just tastes like a less sweet Thai iced
tea yeah like a less overtly sugary yeah
that's awesome Max I kind of like this
one
yeah I like that I would sit on that
joint and smoke this one is crazy
it's the um the lemon the manic
manicolio number six
so this one has a spectacular look super
tracked out a lot of pistols on it
because the perps because the color has
the smell to it like we said
um we're gonna put this one in the blend
just roll it all up laughing gas
this is the Cali the minute call 2012
thin mints
oh that is sound you're next that one
smells crazy that's like it definitely
has like a mint back undertone yeah
the cookies are unbelievable Peter it's
hard to say or are you not a fan
Peter do you want to ask Dave what 2012
is
yeah I know he told me before hold on
one second I like that one
I think I might have to take this one
home with me man at Calio number six
it's got orange flavor which I like it
really does though yeah
Chinese foods over here and then
Japanese food is right here
where's the Chinese food one wow
and then this one also yeah that's a
very Chinese
wow there's a non-chinese food number
three that's that's crazy
um yes I'm gonna I'll do it
yes
I can't wait uh now we were talking just
briefly to mentioned what what kind of
Japanese food are we talking about I
mean it can be very that's a very
complex thing
wow
yeah actually uh no it's definitely on
that weird not weird but tahini it's got
this kind of Rich Sesame Vibe for sure
so yeah it's very accurate yeah
and it's cure it's cured you know
you can taste the curedness right now
around the LCD right it has like yeah
this is the Chinese food man having I
really thought Otis's note of condensed
milk was spot on do you get any of that
condensed milk Thai tea there's no weed
in it though yeah no we did it
oh this Chinese food it has again with
the sour Dairy note smells like the same
[__]
sour Dairy note with like the acidic
very acidic uh whereas you taste the
Tangerine in this you know but it's also
very acidic which I think is the
relationship with also the the like
ponzu or something like something that
has like a a sharp
Citrus but not sweet citrus
Lemon Cherry
yeah okay I'm gonna be honest too it has
like a vomit vibe
sort of vibes from it sort of like that
you know like that piffy hazy almost
like like youth throw up sort of sort of
nose to it like you know like when
someone pukes in front of you and like
you're holding up the Earth to not puke
in there it's like you're a real homie
this is a turn around this is a term
description we keep it real over here
yeah they can't all be winners greasy
guitar frequently talks about like baby
as a terp that's in the July in the 33
heavy that's hilarious
um
jelly beans that taste like gross stuff
right I mean it's a terp it's available
yeah I mean I think some like Grease
Monkey I always talk about is being like
one of the nastiest
um terpenes that I've tasted
um where it has that acidic
it's like this Curry poo Vibe Curry poo
Vibe I really like
oh yeah that's number six I'm about to
roll the number three I love curry I
this is not a bad thing the simulator
it's nasty it kind of intense
you know gets really into this so so
like uh just so this one's way sticky
yeah this one the number three is way
stickier than the number six the number
six was uh uh maybe just more far along
in the dryer or something
butyric acid is what contributes to that
butyric acid butyric acid is what is and
it's very common in a lot of the gelato
progenie
and amazing
yeah but then there's that orange thing
too that's like yeah there's nothing
yeah there's definitely a really orange
back like back end yeah yeah
it's like spelled like it's like uh like
a South American land race it's like
c-a-l-i-o but
I think it's just Cali Dash oh
sure sure we don't need to exoticize it
it's just California
tally oh the Cali ounce the Cali oh
yeah it's a English land race geez
English Lauren Rays grown in Scotland's
foggy Hills
[Laughter]
cavios like the OG California Orange
train well I think Calia was the common
parent of like Tangy and then everything
that comes out like I think it's it's
with us still yeah
California
calios and Cali orange Matthew seen this
one oh you seen this one
I'm like like I like smelling I like
smelling hay this Haze but I don't want
to smoke it what is it phase phase um
it's just called the haze it's called
It's called The Colombian slash Haze a
the A1 the A1 is pretty amazing see
that's what I would throw in the blunt
Jazz that's what I would but
Shout Out Below for the sponsorship we
have multiple blunts cave that's not a
worry Italian cheese on that one
these tupperwares are very cool I like
this this is a great method of getting
people work
nice
parmesan turps which also has parmesan
has a that that butic acid yeah it is
yeah
exactly yeah love that the more you know
um I'm curious about whatever 2012 is
and then I guess Peter a question for
you which of these genetics have been
like most popular in seed on the site
this week oh nice
well that's awesome
and our name is the crosses or offered
in seed
[Music]
of fruity
I like this
we should definitely smoke one of the
ones that is available in seed
s
shout out curved paper you can buy them
on dogga dog Garden
do you actually oh yeah
you can you can buy almost amazing
things there I would have said it best
you can buy anything you can imagine on
daggeracademy.com and and Dagger Gardens
dagger Garden dagger garden and you can
read all the flower reviews your little
heart could ever desire on
um on dagger academy one of the best
sites to learn and interact with the
with a very friendly Community
it's more articulate over there
and there's no Instagram word limit
either so
shout out my English class teacher I did
you write
two page limit
your elements don't have the windmill
they're not real china pack and then I
think we just got an incredible and
incredible piece of knowledge that if
your element pack doesn't have a
windmill you probably should go and buy
some curved papers off dog a dog Garden
because you have fake element papers so
put it up to the camera again
foreign
smoke real papers people oh yeah
don't smoke that Kaka
I'm trying to get all the OCB stuff yeah
OCB classic old school we aren't smoking
that dog [__] over here
we're smoking that Albert walker dog
uh the papers or certain papers on my
bed
wow nice it's a nice tip in there
yeah Scooby Snacks
Scooby's not Cannon Scooby smack Cannon
no-till Tropicana which cut yo what cut
is this
job yeah chop yeah yeah yeah yeah this
Lemon Cherry gelato
um
is uh is it Terps the power it's it's
pretty good it's it's I would say out of
the three things we've tried so far it's
euphoric flights
shout out shout out Saint small batch
man
yeah dream guest shoe to the womb that
is citrusy as usual on the drop
was the flower purple
do you have do you have the flower here
no
herb script from up North the butter was
super purple yeah
okay can I see that I want to see that
Nook it's okay oh this is a good Lemon
Cherry oh it's actually a very well done
Fino of it the strain that I would say I
see the most of
unfortunately unfortunately and you know
it makes it so when you do get a good
batch it did makes for a pleasant
surprise
yeah it's good candy
yeah
[Music]
give me all the leaves
yeah it smells amazing Peter are there
tobacco seeds on the website
if people want to grow their own leaf I
kind of like yeah
how long do you think it takes to grow I
mean you have to grow a big enough tree
to get the leaves
a couple months that's it it's big it's
big right that's sick
yeah
wow yeah yeah
and then you've have you ever done that
have you anyone cured it you cured it
no no but it's it was like that's cool I
was like I knew I knew you know what it
gets passed it's gonna take the same
time that's what's the review
let me see here I've been waiting I've
been waiting
yeah
it's delicious
definitely still wish it was in a joint
for sure both knows noses small garden
or that one's from PDX I think that
one's actually that one's from
uh PDX present okay oh so and who sent
this down and that's uh
you can look up on Instagram two terpy
oh yeah this is good Instagram dog
let's hold on to that for just a second
more my friend
that is love lace Gardens that's who's
actually from Lovelace Gardens Lovelace
Gardens in uh in Portland Oregon
land yeah South Portland like right
around Eugene Portland Oregon right
around that area yeah yeah
yeah
oh man
this is delicious
this is very nice yeah you know the
Lemon Cherry has made has made one round
around what does everyone think this is
great this is probably one of the better
um I've smoked it's sweeter
um much more developed it's got like a I
feel like I just yeah I guess mids
there's i've smoked only mids and this
is above it
but this is delicious good job not being
meds uh what was the name of the guy who
grew it
what's the name of the homie golden
golden coaster mix is not mids yeah
Coast is not mids no it's delicious I
agree all the weed all the way that we
smoked tonight it's been delicious
everyone that's smoking mids thinking
it's gas
change your life yeah run through life
runs your life home
only interesting one tonight it's been
that many cardio speaking of which I
actually I saw a young lb in real life
last week Chinese food yes this is the
Lemon Cherry gelato yes
Daniel it gives me like an orange
chicken vibe
yeah yeah yeah literally gives me like
an orange chickens like slash sesame
chicken Vibe like that like burnt no way
okay like that burnt yeah I smelled it I
smelled it I was like yeah it's good
I personally loved it it was just as
smooth and that full body body taste
um you could taste it definitely through
like I was saying earlier I definitely
still wish it was in a joint but all the
flavors still came through and I it was
it was definitely one of my favorites
out of all of them
we also got Otis over there on the
rolling station shout out to The Rolling
Master [__] no dude Jazz that was a
great role
Jazz with the rolled blunt too dude you
in the background Matthew in the
background
good roller it's always about how it's
rolled
the delivery a joke is best you have to
have the right delivery right a bunch
you could have the punch line you can
have good material but you have to have
the delivery so
let's see this rolling Tech we got some
cool rolling Tech over there I'm gonna
do a little stuffer another stuffer
oh he does the cone Tech
he's a conehead conehead conehead
conehead we are from France this Lemon
Cherry is blowing
I got like some honey notes in there
oh how sweet it was I was gonna say like
it definitely seemed like it was it was
taken full term for sure like with the
notes I'm getting it's very different
from some lemon Church letters I can't
tell how much of this from the blunt but
it is like a good bounce like you said
like that honey note with the slight
nuttiness of source you get from the
Gelato and then just that General floral
sweetness as well without like that
sickly sweetness you know that sometimes
you get from some variants of Lemon
Cherry gelato so but it also doesn't
have the peppery note that happens when
you take it too long like decidedly so I
think there's it's pretty dialed it's
done very very well yeah he runs his
life up that's for sure
it's safe to say we here at FCP believe
Lemon Cherry gelato and runs are the
same thing
what's next all right we got to do this
are we gonna do the walk the the dog
walker Albert dog walker
I like that that had also some very
cakey Vibe
um I like the way it looks it has a
great structure and big fat nug both of
them big old nugs
um
a lot of trichomes on the leaves on the
Sugar Leaf that was left there which I
also have to say I like your trimming
style that's always a you know
indication of of uh headiness I think
you know
it's the presentation
perhaps and I think that it is you know
a lot of
when I get stuff directly from Growers a
lot of the times they give it to me on
trim and they're like this is how I'd
want it
like you do that yourself
it's a little annoying but I get it I
just finger tripping man but for the
preservation of the I do think it
preserves the trichomes I think there's
something to be said about
whatever that is and it's like so so
like everyone has a different visual
appearance preference right some prefer
some sugar leaves some prefer a lot of
sugar leaves some prefer none some
prefer
some people like the
the
some people like the holes in their buds
from the machines
yeah yeah
I think I think we all agree here like a
more delicate thoughtful trim is better
than a little shave an LA pack shave and
trim for the win or rubs your life then
sending your pack to the barber yeah
yeah literally the washing machine
you ever guys ever run one of those
machines you guys have any experience
with tumblers those are lit dude
no trim machines oh no I haven't dude
trim machines are ridiculous man
how they're not covering the [__] yeah
it's you gotta you gotta have this the
way they've met I don't know what
originally was for like shucking peanuts
or something automative you know it's so
I feel like it's definitely something
that's taken from the AG world like and
thrown into the Cannabis world and how
they how they decided to just like
tumble trim this stuff thinking it would
work I feel like they never tried it and
then seeing people do it like wet no
like oh you're supposed to do it wet
like there's all this myth like how it's
done the best and it's like it's all bad
it's a fundamental misunderstanding it's
like the fruit isn't the plant matter
it's the resin yeah like it's a CL the
principles might work from an
agricultural perspective yeah
Chads that don't know what they're doing
we Boomerang to the Lemon Cherry
this tastes
similar to the number six with that
Sesame note but there's something
different about this that I haven't
discovered
it's almost less uh
the number three is almost like less
condensed milky more like sesame oil
Chinese foodie but it has the it has the
elements of like
um elements of orange essence of orange
but definitely like a like you just hit
some sesame oil for sure like at the
Korean barbecue you know what I'm saying
the little dunk dabs right off the
Hibachi yeah exactly bro
Hibachi dabs like a hot knife with my my
spatula my hot spatula
when I make hash I wear a chef's hat
yeah exactly
that's number three AKA Chinese food
this one is peppery but also has less
more floral yeah it's more floral it's
interesting less condensed milk number
three oh sorry my bad I forgot it wasn't
a blunt
excuse me
by the way Otis you you bought this
thank you bro I appreciate it Pearls by
Og oh yeah that one was I had to wrestle
with that one but I got it rocking watch
out for the hand rolls coming soon super
small batch
that's genius that's genius
the hand rolls
yeah exactly the hand rolls
screenshot
they're gonna lock me in a basement
until we have a thousand donuts oh man
I'm down with that I would love to do
that where's my where's the basement at
it
at Peter's house
Peter's got a baby you get occasional
piano performances like like we got on
420 which was amazing yeah the best part
of 420
we try to hide our weed but then we
realize she's married to you so it's
probably ours I still hit my weed I hit
my Rigs and my weed
is it extremely is it extremely
literally extremely grade a performance
oh it was awesome my mother watched it
[Laughter]
my mother my mother
FCP is for the children
yeah we need a theme song Eventually
yeah
Laker that's a really nice name for
rapper just Laker
I guess it's a real guy
right did you get the peppery floral
yeah uh it definitely did it
there's some pepperinis for sure oh yeah
that's your speed that's your speed
number three okay oh it's definitely
louder than the other you get the salt
and pepper like pork Labs salt pepper
Vibe like out of the out of the little
package that you get the restaurant yeah
it's mixed they're mixed together and
it's yeah it's like preservative it's
preservative yeah
and it's citrus
yeah no like citrus peels
like no sweetness at all just like like
a bitter peel live yeah citric acid like
and it's in its finest form exactly
that's like you're taking the words out
of my mouth dude these are exactly what
I would call it what are your thoughts
on the number two it's less Orange
very sticky chocolate Vibe almost has
like cushy kind of stuff going on
number two this is really nice to get to
smoke two fianos side by side to just
see how the variation between the
genetics right as we've had guests speak
about it before something that truly is
uh so wide in terms of the variables
you're playing with and the traits that
that can run down and and so to find
Keepers is you know people really do
underestimate how hard it is and we get
to participate somewhat through these
these small little different variances
of females would get and and it really
is hard to find a keeper or just truly
pick one that you think everyone would
enjoy uh and so I think through this
we've also developed a lot of respect
for The Growers and breeders who are
able to do these in and pick winning
crosses and bring them to Market
wow this um
laughing gas might be my favorite nose
we've had yeah so so the laughing gas
was honestly I thought like all
sweetness without that gelato knows did
you smoke at all no we have not yet
actually but when we're passing it
around originally this was and I believe
this is one of the newer genetics as
well so uh this looks to be indoor run
smells amazing uh what do you guys think
about this laughing gas that one smells
awesome
you see this super D fire
super deep fire Albert walker dog
I think I smelled this do I got that dog
in it
it's not that dog in it okay shot that
dog walker
like mosquito spray
oh like citronella
all right that's a good one
which one was that oh The Laughing Gas
yeah
right the laughing gas is the one
we got a Lysol flavor right here it's
like Lemon Pledge but more pledge
Albert walker dog oh yes
it reminds me of some weird Batman [__]
that one's crazy it's like a Batman
straight laughing gas I don't know why
Heath Ledger I see Heath Ledger
sweet smoking is trying to you know his
impersonation of the Joker
with the laughing and did we smoke the
garlic skunk no we didn't we have not
yet I like Stone green with garlic
there's a guy aggressive whichever you
want all three stop looking at that
cannoli yeah should we do a garlic
cannoli
that sounds pretty fun to me I don't
think there's any way we can say garlic
Stone cannoli
ation
what's up
I don't know if there's enough of this
Peter you smoked all the garlic
no one likes that yeah
[Laughter]
it smells good I love this nice as you
should what was your favorite Peter what
would you like out of all this
yeah
now the garlic scum's good and then I
had the uh
no we're about to roll it in a household
yeah I'd love to take a dab of that yeah
we should take some dabs right now hold
on let's sacrifice the mics for some
jobs
yeah yeah yeah okay
[Music]
I wonder what's up with this hash Peter
you know anything about this rosin is it
what what's the micron
is this indoor outdoor full spec
forgot who washed it mystery wash sauce
wash
[Music]
ing just speaking to friends of the show
The Mission Hill melts Lobster Farm is
amazing
honey bananas the Mission Hill melts
Lobster Family Farms
is Sensational oh that's some of the
best stuff which was that the honey
banana chili burger yeah
always I'm a but I like those banana
Turfs
was uh your your [__] is fired X
yeah oh yeah yeah he's also rotten
skateboards yes sir adron skateboard
smoking on some of that right now got
some of the honey bananas still in look
at this chamber nice
that amount like I had like
that's a crazy compartment secret
compartment I didn't know there's a
secret compartment compartment for all
you stashers
if you want all your rosin to go really
dry crazy to say but I accidentally
forgot that there was rosin on here and
I flew home to uh South Carolina last
week with rosin in my dab eggs so I
definitely could have taken a rip in the
smoking section of the airplane
[Music]
I knew it was in there on the way home
so I was like man I could just go out in
California and do like the cigarette
smoking area and take a dab X rib for a
pre-flight so funny so dank when I was
in Ohio there was they would have these
like enclosed almost like phone booths
so you'd have to go
it sends us a picture from inside one of
those with a dab X they would have
joined there will be there will be
something very cool coming your way yeah
flaming poop on their doorstep
[Laughter]
just kidding just one of the many
services offered by dog a dog guard
to take care of them
and Shout out our old guest Jeremy who
came on a few weeks ago his book we have
with us
um
every time we come I read a new page and
I'm captivated by the [__] that is going
on
thank you
there's gonna be a mini doink I'm gonna
put the hash in the next opened it today
and he was like he got set up he was
dating a girl who had mental problems
and she set him up at a McDonald's and
then the cosplayed up
yeah
yes in the book
that was chapter 13 tune into chapter 14
tidbits um next week guys we'll
definitely uh
audiobooks by Jazz just another service
offered by dog Gordon
um
[Music]
[Laughter]
I want that I want that
can we get Zach would sing a good night
lullaby
do you work the video that I got Golden
Coast on was also had JJ from Top Dog
and it was the school Lake East West
Coast thing but I feel like I didn't get
the strongest sense of what Golden Coast
likes to smoke
that one's the number three Chinese food
oh again yeah
oh yeah but Peter what does Golden Coast
when you've spoken with him like what is
his favorite stuff to smoke out of all
of this
our way to his personal preferences lie
[Music]
Stephanie
stuff sick I like Ty
there's a Thai velvet Buzz saw thing
that I like to smoke in the morning the
Velvet Buzz saw is insane dude it's
crazy
and it's it's delicious it is so
elongated and
um like it is a very unique blood
structure but the high itself is just
something that is so great
that's some sticky dry stuff I have some
dry sift that I've been saving from
various harvests in my freezer like
probably like a pound and a half of dry
sift from like Harvest when I was
working at a bigger like facility and
it's a lot of GMO but it's some of it is
some of it is really carefully sifted
and it's all just like melty like this
it's all dabble varying grades of you
know debris behind three stars yeah I
got some three stars got some two and a
half stars
with a half star fam that's what
hashiness is it's some of these
combusted you know materials that makes
up like what it is you know exactly and
like you can refine it too that's why I
have it in my freezer still I've got
these big ass I have a whole shelf in
the freezer just all filled with dry
stuff jars like from like the last few
years
and I think when we're fine dry sips can
be some of the most Pleasant smoke I
mean like the was it resin Ranch that we
tried that yeah he has uh he has some
great dress very good
medium like
like that's hot that's a hot dab 500. I
like 500.
let's open this glass it was a glass by
the real Dillinger the real Dylan it's a
little thumb print thumby tube with some
yeah a little bit of a little re-wag on
the bottom glass collectors this is some
heady [__] there heady glass yeah real
heavy Karen yeah
yeah wait what's what's the pendy today
oh today I'm rocking a rice made this
pendy he is uh he blows glass out a
piece of my dose C in uh Newport Beach
go sure to check them out at rice made
this on Instagram Bryce made this color
killer work very cool very cool uh fume
work very chill there like that I have
uh I have six of these same pennies so I
am a Savage collector of his work
sweet thank you here we go go in dogs
where's this cap there we go
that's a nice sized dab
great oh nice beautiful oh if anyone has
ever been doing the smoking Olympics OG
is the ringer he that's a small dab
oh it's good
[Laughter]
do you remember him oh yeah
the cough cam the cough cam now the
shots Tony toast too much for taking one
gram dab so we were trying to film the
show that was amazing the clouds we saw
lily look like a volcano had been
erupted at the tables behind the FCP
Studio set
I have no memory of this
uh no but the man who was coughing was
taking one gram dabs that was the reason
yeah
yeah those guys are ill yeah he was sick
he was sick
he's coughing up his dad Teddy Karen
could I get in the line notes that are
on Kevin GMO without the like garlic
full body dark notes I think you'll like
it
yes
shout out shout out John Doe the homie
for hitting me with the ninja dab on
420.
you've been here then like what we're
dabbing on like I usually have the booty
slurper the [__] whatever the hell
yeah no I'm not even using the Toro I'm
uh I'm using the the bootleg slippery
that's a real Toro right there the G
West yeah g West they're actually great
yeah it's us yeah no no no hate
and shout out to what is Forrest Gump SD
Den quartz yeah in course 619 holding it
down
yeah big four
um
I think for one of our sesh regulars I'm
interested in talking to him about it
but he was involved in something that
won Kush stock in some capacity so
congratulations yeah shout out to four
uh you know we like to think of him as
the residential resin expert here at the
sessions um oh yeah one of one of one of
always
um
yeah right uh but certainly the
Ambassador with the most
yeah
we miss you bro
we're eating cookies that that taste
like tri-tip for you
true exactly
um
rolling up I forget oh yeah yeah
yeah yeah
and where's the rosary
did it yeah like you rolled it up yeah
I'm gonna sprinkle of dry sifted it's
gonna be dank and and Otis did you take
a dab with a honey bananas Wilson or
these no I smoked this dude it was
really good there was effervescent notes
similar to GMO and chem
um you know I think that probably comes
from the garlic part of the lineage
um and then some lemon from the skunk
um it was like you know GMO without the
full body and like uh like a lemony chem
without like some of the more like
bitter cam notes which is really
enjoyable
hmm
big fan of chem can never go wrong I'm a
huge fan of chem
and those notes that I call bitter I
like
I have a I have a chem I-95 Pax and I
did a chemi 95 Durban that is like it's
like more more funky skunky bitter than
like GMO even like we called it we were
like joking we were like we should just
like call this like new GMO but it's bad
it's uh
it deserves it's it's better than that
not better than GMO but it deserves its
own life
and I think that the breeder behind that
is having a moving sale so if anyone's
interested in covert genetics
unfortunately I don't think on dog a dog
Garden but available on Instagram
um his stuff rocks Cuts or just seeds
how about Cuts I know I feel you
've taken orphans
Gabe
that was awesome isn't that good to the
Future
yeah but I'm just weak you know those
are some clouds of respect
dude there's something about that nail
that nail is powerful man
Char and so I'll give you a few seconds
lemony yeah
it was lemonade
lemonade
lemony with like an earthy undertone
that's exactly what I love
sure
[Music]
thank you very garlicky
she's right um Peter I understand if you
were smoking on that all 420. that was a
long day
I uh I started early and uh
Two Joints at once
I like to
did anyone smoke like a ridiculously
large joint for 420 here's something
that was like cartoonishly
funny like comedically ended up you got
ninja dad that's that's never fun but
also kind of like a point six to seven
dab 0.67 he was a massive block but some
awesome fresh press not fresh press but
some rainbow belts that was fresh press
and then what did I get ninja with
something good bhf BHO
Delta eight a diamond
CBD isolate from the internet yeah it
might have been the dark
um mega dark Z it was it was the Mega
dark D from Mega dark Z from super dope
and that was really nice actually
amazing you were mad that was actually
uh the surprise dab of 420 along with
the pie dough from uh JD's perfume and
the mega dark is the super zope right so
that is the zope variate and the
um the blue is their Z
and uh the red is their rs11. drive safe
how's it going bye
[__]
yeah shout out Golden Coast this has
been yes great smoke thank you so much
for the flavor flight I think we truly
enjoyed this and we're we're all looking
forward for this Albert dog is getting
wrote up right now yes Albert dog I
extremely want to try yeah we could do
it amazing
we can do it we should have everyone
rolling joints yeah I mean I could roll
a joint I could packing cones how many
people cannot roll how many people could
roll here I can roll I mean not like I
can't roll like you but you know this
guy can roll yeah how do you pack a film
[Music]
no but there's but really it is a
properly rolled joint
elevates the smoking experience so much
and I uh you just crush it every time
and I think you want to talk about sort
of the dimensions that you go for the oh
yeah I mean um
for me I think
um rather than rolling like a long
skinny joint with the same amount of
weed you can roll a shorter fatter joint
where there's more surface area that's
being vaporized and smoked throughout
the whole joint for the front of the
joint is going to be smoked back of its
vaporized from the hot air and Hot Smoke
um uniform Dimensions I mean you can
roll cones and stuff but you know
whatever's easiest for you I like the
uniformity it burns uniform
um you don't want it to be too tight you
want to be able to draw I like to use a
couple crutches
right
you know everyone rolls their own way
you're not like uh you don't have glass
tips you do any of those I have glass
tips but I just I don't like having to
like wash them and [__] like I'd rather
just like I can make something that
feels as sturdy out as a glass tip out
of like four crutches but then again
people claim that the crutches have a
flavor to them
that's real for me I just like I'll roll
like a fat joint with no no tip at all
and just get everybody's mouth covered
in Scooby Snacks
like glass tips
like glass tips I want to make some as
soon as I'm blowing more glass
oh yeah it'll be sick and the use of
capillary tubing to make tips got really
big through Gordo scientific rib tips
also everyone check out if you have
Instagram Otis King glass wow
what is King glass
um some really cool pieces we use them
on the show all the time oh yeah we can
all verify they're amazing they smoke
you should definitely check them out
maybe soon to be available on uh this
piece isn't by you but it's by your
Mentor right do you want to talk about
this well
I don't know if he wants to hey if he
wants me to tell very much about that
but
he's a legendary guy in the color game
and
he did a line of bongs secretly once and
this is one of them
but shout out to you if you're watching
you know who you are
it's awesome yeah
that is definition of petty that's so
bad we'll rip it yeah we'll remove it
yeah
I'm gonna see what what's up with that
functional glass
this it's the blower bro
this is garlic skunk X garlic skunk
excited about this Peter tell us about
the playlist selection tonight yeah
what tell us about the more diverse
playlist tonight you kept it
[Music]
having stuff no I mean it's like I have
no time to do that so one of these weeks
I want to DJ yeah I'll probably up in
here
DJs finals everything from some of the
finest DJs oh yeah hot stepper the goats
yeah go check out their mobile DJ sound
system uh check out their Instagram to
see where it's at hot step of Supply Co
shout out to the big homie right here
Tetris I will say that the first smoke
of the day event and the bright The
Vibes that you brought that was one of
the coolest things this year such a cool
way to kick off the air yeah
um that was really amazing actually I
didn't go to that one I was literally I
think I was literally out of the state
but the Vibes were so apparently bombed
that I could feel it through Instagram
so they're radiating vibes
and notice you you barred this joint and
um
once again we just want to emphasize
it's very rare that you get the
opportunity to try uh different versions
of the same strain and so thank you once
again Golden Coast genetics for
providing this opportunity with the
garlic skunk and I'm pretty sure this
torch is super loud right now but we
love hot dabs so I'm not complaining
the
the gunk is I just described as like
super GMO super gym White Rhino laughing
gas
is that a white rhinocross the laughing
gas is the White Rhino Manic the black
oh
right should we smoke the uh The
Laughing Gas we should maybe roll up the
Laughing ass first and then the next one
go
laughing gas smells this is like ZaZa
is there somebody selling laughing gas
at this event I think we should get
somebody doing that potion man maybe two
for five
[__] the authority
we missed you appreciated with the ice
cold fatties you have to climb over the
chair ice cold fatties
foreign
yeah shout out to fish custom Nature's
Mafia
I should be sure I got custied at the
fish before five
I got that'd be sick inside us yeah
three for 20 man jeez
I think Super G mode would be the best
way to describe this but once again with
all the flavors we've been able to try
today just very well done super mature
grown smoke
and I think the dry sift actually has
like I had a really unique component to
the similar almost to like
did I say a full metal hassle of sorts
in terms of like the the upliftedness
I'm feeling in the in the smoothness
and Slow Burn of the studio as well
that nail reps
that's a clouder
that's for taking rippers
oh nice tank delicious
dude lime lime Aid limeade super
delicious
this is delicious
everybody
Gold Coast might need a part two there's
so much weight on this table we still
have not even tried
before he gets too like
okay
yeah that's the lemon tree
super sweet yeah it's good right super
GMO with the GMO
yeah I think it's more effervescent it's
like uh in the rosin you're getting more
of like the like lemony skunky like
lemony with like almost like a a light
Kim sort of back into it like I love the
camera bear GMO case at the end of that
right now like you said it's it's those
lights almost effervescent is the best
way to describe it yeah it sort of
Glides over yeah like champagne bubbles
exactly right like pleating yeah
what am I smoking right now this is
laughing gas oh [__] we're gonna smoke
some laughing gas
it's very Zaza it smells super Zaza
it's interesting to smoke the hash and
then I like smoking hash and flour from
the same plant yeah or same like mother
plant grow I'm aiming to do that with my
[__]
full spectrum and then you have the the
rosin like I can't wait for that too
that's gonna be okay yeah we've been
calling it Freshies
Freshies it's great
that was perfect temp by the way too it
had like a I had like a key lime pie
Vibe ooh I like that I really like that
I like that
tea limes
I went to San Diego today hell yeah oh
[__] hell yeah shout out San Diego shout
out to
homeless melts also holding down and
Shout Out Dragon's Den in Mission Beach
one of the coolest smoke shops we've
ever been shout out to Brad shout out to
Denise it was a party yeah live glass
blowing there oh that's cool that's
awesome they just have a little setup at
the front of the store and some of the
coolest pieces they had some stuff
whatever you want oh yeah Steel
it was literally a replica of this piece
right here uh running at a very very
affordable price
hell yeah
huh
run this system he's from San Diego
shout out to uh Holy Rollers San Diego
shout out cold room Cuts shout out uh
New Moon novelty shout out all them boys
holding it down
putting in great work
shout out strictly lit San Diego
you guys know about strictly lit that
guy's killing it
yeah he's strictly lit in San Diego this
guy's killing me yeah
so
we got we didn't sponsor [__] yet we'll
be sponsoring it soon
we'll figure it we'll figure it out I'm
normally wearing my fresh pressure he's
usually I'll see it yeah coming out with
new colors soon covered in Jim's way
yeah
fresh press affordable for all yes I
love my hoodie
Karen Terps
sweaty ass Karen Terps
bloody butthole crackers
savory
what's up with this where's this going
like that Peter
it's the honesty it's the honesty
no way
yo what does the chat think about
Wu-Tang ugh yeah if someone in the chat
is a proponent of Wu-Tang
we'd love to meet you yeah
I get it it's a ritual it's cool it's
the humiliation it's amazing yeah
behind the camera right now
Peter's taking a big ass dad a producer
our producer we need a Peter cam where's
the Pete cam
what do you think Peter
low temp dab [__] smoking of the garlic
skunk
garlic skunk is a real big winner
yeah garlic sucks dank real big winner
I'm already where I need to be
like oh yeah could be could be yeah
everything's live man
endless noise
endless noise heady heady coffee heady
records
yeah it's a Vibe it's a Vibe it's a
lifestyle pull up on Tuesdays lifestyle
all right
come on pause
what are you twisting up right now I
don't know I forgot the Laughing ass
crossed to the uh wait just laughing us
the left why do I know
put that in there we put the garlic uh
yeah
double garlic oh [__] super garlic I I
need to take a break for I'm where I
need to be oh yeah
smoking
a great point
I was just gonna say that yeah we should
make this a two-part or yeah
we might have to make the full lineup a
two-part everyone's already too high
we still have a [__] little [__] we
probably did like five yeah like four or
five yeah
[Music]
Lemon Cherry gelato I think was still
one of my favorites
what was your guys's favorite strength
you guys tried the cookies I'm smoking
on cooking you smoking on mild whoa I
like that yeah
the Garlic's gone
that [__] was hitting
humongously
I'm gonna be cliche but I I think for me
it was a Lemon Cherry gelato that one
kind of took me by surprise and uh
so far at least it was it was the one I
enjoyed the most out of all these
but I'm also partial because I like
blunts so
we'll leave that be I think the garlic
skunk was also phenomenal too so that
would be my flower take I'm a a big GMO
fan
I like the Calio manic Calio the two or
the three uh I like the six the six
words so you were saying the six was the
one with more citrus chips or less
Citrus terms six was more like condensed
milk like uh like more like more intense
lactic vomity condensed milk like the
sort of like rotten milk sort of smoke
the six first yeah then the number three
was more citrusy more floral it's not
necessarily more citrusy
that boat destroy
Ed
nice I think after we light this it
might be time for us to wrap it up
everyone's getting so high Gold Coast
did a great job shout out Golden Coast
this is I mean
good chronic for every palette there was
something here and and the one that
really hit mine was as good a
representation of that strain as I've
seen in a long time yeah same I think
everyone really uh hopped on the
yeah
you know I think everyone really hopped
on a flavor flight today and was able to
find something they really enjoyed and
uh thank you Gold Coast Again The
Chronic was bubonic yeah
it's flowing easy today
let's do it let's do it but thank you so
much everyone for watching this thank
you everyone for tuning in I hope you
guys have a great rest of your night
tune in next Tuesdays we'll see you guys
soon have a great week
[Music]
we did it