[Music]
foreign
I guess we're we're sitting in the
aftermath of masonic's free seed day the
third annual it was a lot of fun shout
out Masonic for bringing the community
together and then shout out FCP for
giving us a place to be the next day the
first ever Sunday sesh right now Grove
bags is in the building which is super
exciting we have Trevor Sun ground mids
here and I don't know I couldn't be
happier to be spending my Sunday this
way shout out mace really really
appreciate the space and the reason to
come down here to La it's always great
to see everybody and yeah just thank you
Peter for also holding it down this
space uh endless noise is awesome so
yeah did you contribute to the bags or
dick free to see day yeah I I've dropped
the uh
Gary Payton tkm10
um you got a Gary Payton bag uh it's a
Gary Payton had that he wasn't taking
yeah yeah but it's uh
it's some nice Gary Payton you know
gassy squat Ganny type Style with that
tkm 10 hitting it so yeah
I'm painting personally I think it's
[Music]
again it's just like neutral smoke and
weed it just has good
yeah easy flavor to enjoy throughout the
whole joint yeah sweet enough
it's definitely as a smoke you know
flower it's good uh I had some friends
who washed some and it wasn't wasn't
producing yields on the wash but it
definitely it's a nice smoker so and the
color all that you know it's it's a
Cookie's cross it's
checks and boxes
and uh so for those who aren't aware of
what free seed days it's basically an
event thrown by Edgar AKA Masonic smoker
at his store on Fairfax
um it was from 10 to 3 yesterday but the
line started on Wednesday and the event
was on a Saturday and basically you can
pull up in a bunch of uh
people will chip in their seeds and what
they want to give out in terms of gear
and you can come and collect the bag and
Trevor is one of those people who had a
table there and was giving out gear as
well and did you see anything super
interesting there in terms of gear stuff
because I saw stuff coming in from Ukiah
stuff coming in from other states and
some CBDs some Autos so just wanted to
see if anything caught your interest uh
uh yeah there it was
this time it was interesting to see uh
some of the people who showed up
um like there was some old school cats
who are like you know La Legends to a
certain extent at this point DNA was
there Crockett was there and it was cool
to see those guys at seed day because
I've been to every free seed day since
the first one when Masonic first did it
and um
you know this time it was
it's been super efficient in the past
where it was like you know the bags were
pre-made people stood in line they came
in they got their bags they were able to
get some shirts and different stuff but
like it was quick fast this time people
got to come in there was tables out they
got to select different stuff that they
wanted to select they got to add and
kind of build your own bag and like that
was super cool and um yeah it was it was
legit in terms of seeing how many people
were there you know there was Bloom
there was big names people Oni was there
what he was handing out absolutely
incredible if you got one of those Oni
packs like that's special and yeah just
I bumped into people who had gotten my
stuff at previous free seed days and
talked about the different gear that
they had and like you know I made all
these Pina hash plant crosses with my
buddy uh landhammer farms and those
crosses have made some great
concentrates and some great flowers and
people have those Pina hash plants seeds
and they can go and make their own and
breed with that and make their own
little thing and I think that you know
that's something that's really awesome
about free seed day is that people are
getting like they're not just getting
random ass packs like you're actually
getting breeding gear you're getting
stuff that you could start a company
with if you wanted to well and so we got
something different last year not the
Pina gear put some Sky cuddler from you
um I think it just happened to be in the
pre-made bag that we got and it was one
of our favorite things that we
ran and so that was I guess what you
were giving out last year this year was
the The Pina
um I know sorry yeah the TKA Dem 10
sorry what's what are you working on
like in the near future and sort of or
in looking towards next year I think
next year people are either going to get
gold star crosses from um I got some
seeds Kevin Jody hooked me up with some
gold star F5s and uh I got really I'll
be honest somewhat depressing
germination rates on them I got like
eight out of 72 seeds but out of those
eight I'm gonna keep them all keep all
the males and uh we'll do as much of an
increase as we can with those and then
otherwise I'm uh also selecting males
from an afro Pips Malawi gold and so
expect Malawi crosses next year
last time we linked up a couple months
ago
um I had some of your Malawi chem and
some of the Malawi Wilson and those two
were some of my favorite smokes of the
last few months
um I mean they're just phenomenal any
time of the day smoke absolutely fire
thanks man that yeah I um one of those
Malawi crosses I'm growing out some more
I've got a bunch of the Malawi chem
started I'm actually kicking myself
because I had a bunch
it's old seed stock it wasn't
particularly good looking seed stock
there was like a lot of white seeds and
so when I just popped my seeds this year
I put a bunch of like three four you
know seeds in a Cell every one of them
popped and so I'm like you know yeah
yeah like and there's just there's
two to three times more than I expected
to grow and so I I've got a bunch of
seedlings that I'm gonna try to bring
down yeah that is awesome man so yes we
may do a little thing in the coming you
know next month or something I'll come
down have little starts and some watches
for people and just hand those out yeah
really cool oh my god dude so that's
yeah the Malawi chem and uh probably
just some pure Malawi from the Bodhi
increase of African seed cows Malawi so
very cool yeah very nice yeah and I've
been able to smoke some of your guys's
Sky cuddler and absolutely on point oh
thank you dude crushed it with that we
appreciate you man we can't wait to grow
more sky cuddler nice that's like the
sky cuddler from
the man sungrown mids himself man that
is one of our favorites from our garden
yeah and
we'd be remiss to not shout out Mean
Gene Mean Gene the originator of the sky
cuddler uh Bollywood bam who did the pop
um he was there at uh possible and he he
popped like a thousand beans and he
kicked us uh land Hammer all of the
males and all uh not all but like four
or five select females and that's where
that uh F4 increase was made was off of
those and Shout out the work he's doing
in uh Santa Cruz County to help bring
Justice to the situation going on with
Farmers out there yeah yeah definitely
April 27th he's got a hearing so if
you're in Santa Cruz anywhere in
Northern California honestly if you can
try and get to Bam's hearing because the
more people that show out the better for
him and for everyone he he's gonna come
on with the lawyer he's working with to
start talking because because he's uh
he he's gonna Apprentice with that
lawyer
which is amazing like I didn't know you
can get a law degree without going to
law school
and he's like a civil rights like
defense lawyer nice yeah yeah and so
that's that's an important case and he
also he's already gotten big wins in
terms of getting his uh his seized uh
possessions back and so that's good to
hear yeah that's good to hear
we're hoping for some more wins on the
horizon yeah yeah so that's um
that was that Sky cuddler uh Cross or
increase and those there's there's a
whole bunch of them there was like
there's the sky cuddler f4s that got
made there was also the um
uh some no magic that you guys got oh
yeah we're excited about those
some some no magic I believe you said
that was Masonic yeah that's from our
good friend Masonic we
are so [ __ ] excited to grow that [ __ ]
we um you know
we love everything we've ever grown from
Masonic in our last Garden we had is
Chiclets and his banana God Z3 both of
those [ __ ] fire
absolutely fire
banana God Z3 was the one yeah that
banana God Z3 is really good we got a
bunch of uh a bunch of clones going from
that one I think that's the out of out
of the out of the garden our favorites
were probably banana God Z3 Chiclets and
Sky color Kush which were all things I
think we got it free seed Day last year
yeah it all comes full circle last year
you said something that really struck me
and I wonder if you'd elaborate on it
you just sort of spoke about how you
viewed partially what Masonic was
building but also sort of what was
happening in like Urban centers and how
they've become equally sort of centers
of influence around stuff genetic stuff
um as much as what's going on on the
hill and so I was curious
yeah if you have thoughts on that I
definitely think that what mace is built
there at his shop is a a cultural Hub
where people can come you know every
weekend he's open if you've got an
opportunity and you're in the LA area
just to experience it you should come
down even if you're not a grower or a
breeder it's definitely worth coming and
experiencing what he's building there
and the thing is is that
you know there's been epicenters for
years in terms of like
up north up in the hills in Mendo and
humble like as when I was a kid a lot of
us started out we'd go up there and we'd
trim and so we'd trim we'd get seeds
we'd bring them back to wherever we were
and then we'd start growing out those
seeds and that kind of like got us on
our foundation and leveled us up in a
certain way and that's not accessible
it's particularly not accessible anymore
because the whole trim scenes like gone
and dead like that's not really probably
one of the last contemporary kids to
like get in on a big grow and become the
grower there from trimming in the last
like four years like that's not a thing
anymore yeah yeah like that is it's
strange that it happened to me that's
like when I ran my first big spot like
that was by proxy of literally just
getting a trim job there you work your
way up they eventually need they
eventually need somebody to cover and
then boom you're [ __ ] running a 50
lighter all of a sudden now you've only
grown in your backyard and in a garage
before like yeah and honestly it doesn't
happen anymore as much trimming's a
great way to learn learn about the plant
because you really get to learn the
structure and details of individual
plants and the variations and
differences and the better you get at
trimming the more you get to like
understand the plant on a morphological
sort of basis and so that Lake those
first early years that was that was our
a lot of people's introduction and
access to good genetics the clubs came
along eventually the Bay Area clubs were
you know an epicenter La absolutely
popped off but again
that whole dynamic and everything about
that has changed there's not really so
much of a community there's not so much
of a trading underground thing unless
you're on the internet
and the internet's cool but it's
amorphous and what mace has done is he's
given a brick and mortar location for
this type of thing to get together and
giving people in urban centers like La
who had no access and no no way going up
into the [ __ ] Hills of Mendo and
Humboldt or wherever they now can just
go down to Fairfax of all places and get
in on that and experience it in a way
that you know gives them access to this
community to these genetics these
resources but also
you know I've met so many people there
from who have just become regulars at
the shop and learned so much and leveled
their games up like I got flower at uh
this year and I've seen these people's
flower for the last three years and it's
gotten consistently better and better
and better and so that's something that
you know we've got a new
a new sort of cultural Hub and a new way
for the culture to expand and articulate
and express itself that I think is
beautiful
I really think that is the the best way
to describe what my songs on Fairfax
really isn't all about even from a
Southern California perspective there
really was no place before that you
could connect at least the city of 10
million people and most people tend to
stay in their little neighborhood or
city and so I kind of gave people down
here as well a place to connect with
others and and build camaraderie and
just grow on that aspect like can't they
do on the hill where people are more so
a tight-knit community and I feel like
La is venturing towards that and
masonics is definitely the focal point
of where all that is originating from
exactly anyone who shows interests and
you never know who you're gonna see
there and on top of that it doesn't
matter if you're affiliated with
cannabis or not he's happy to answer any
questions about what it is I've seen
people walk in with no idea what's going
on and he'll just sit them down and
educate them and
to people's coming in what's a masonic
smoker
that [ __ ] is so funny or some people
will walk out like after having taken a
giant dab maybe never having taken a dab
in their life but just our cannabis
enthusiasts that happened to stumble in
because they think it's a shirt store or
something or just are curious yeah you
know the vibe is cool and the locals
there like mace gets a lot of love and
the people who are kind of like have
it's Masonic no context you know they
just walk in they've got no idea and
they see these shirts they see a bunch
of people around the table and it's a
it's a retail experience they've never
seen right and they're like what what's
this about and you know there's a
possibility for a lot of culture clash
and uh like potentially like bad
outcomes I've never seen it yeah I've
never seen it mace handles it and like
interacts with people who don't have any
idea about what's going on in a way that
just like brings them into the set in
the community and like you know people
right there in that shop shopping center
like went from being like what the [ __ ]
is this to like what's up what would
show with this yeah and I think that all
stems from how open mace isn't
approachable as well like we said anyone
can walk into the shop and you'll still
be the first person to greet them ask
them how their day is ask them what's up
and tell them all about the store and
what he's about and I really think
that's something that stands for stands
for more than that so that's something
to stay for yeah yeah no it's it's legit
like I said if you anybody who hasn't
been there go it's legit
and uh shout out to free C day man
unbeatable experience
you brought here uh so I'm the worst at
this kind of stuff like I I should have
yeah let's just do that that works too
so the sky cuddler Kush f4s uh gonna go
back through with these guys yeah here
we go so got a fat sack of those
um
let's we got the biscotti Sky cuddler
Kush we've got the no magic Sky cuddler
Kush and the gushers Sky cuddler Kush
just to go through a range of sky
cuddlers for you guys and um then this
is I'm excited about these there's the
chemd tkm10 so this is what if you got
free seeds same males here as in the
Gary Payton
um Diesel tkm10 nice
Josh d tkm10
and Lem OG tkm I'm excited about that
one yeah so like all gas there that's so
fire yeah that is gonna be fun that is
gonna be good hunting
oh yeah exactly
but yeah and I mean
what was really there was a lot of stuff
at free seed day this time
um
you know uh I know uh Hydro uh high
definition yeah he um what's up dog he
dropped the uh uh just a Mystery Pack
where he mixed everything I uh I grabbed
that Mystery Pack of Wilson dude so that
mystery Pack's got some incredible [ __ ]
in there there you got banana God you
got all kinds of different things that
are in there so it's
it's a random pack with all his
different things where it's just seeds
that got mixed together where he's like
he can't say what it is but he knows
that it's from his list of females that
he made with it and uh I smoke some of
that Wilson F3 crosses
um yeah the final test the strawberry
footer crosses were amazing yeah so
those I'd look out for
um
yeah and like I mean all sorts of people
exotic mic sent in seeds Bloom like I
said sentence seeds some I-95 crosses
um yeah so there's gonna be some [ __ ] in
there and like you guys said
oh no shots of flying line research
those are some highly experimental ones
that are
could like you said someone could find a
business on those yeah
yeah we should shout out land Hammer a
little yeah
lanhammer farms uh
he uh he's the homie he grew a bunch of
Oni seeds this year and um in those Oni
seeds there was the zahidi lime the
um uh chemt Hayes and uh
so dude won first place like his flower
or whatever uh got washed to uh make the
first place entry at the emerald cup a
few years back
hands down we all agree this is Far and
Away better than the emerald Cup winner
and yeah thank you bro so
also uplifted meds Johnny check him out
uplifted meds we don't mind switching
the camera he's showing off the jar he
definitely has been making some killer
killer [ __ ] milk
[Music]
like it's just it's it's phenomenal and
the uh the chemt Hayes is got some
really limey Haze Terps that like super
potent will last and last and last for
hours and the um
the sour Haze you were saying was your
favorite it was my favorite it just is
so different I think we had an
experience with some people yesterday
where I took a dab of it and then they
walked in the room and they were like
why does the room smell so good you know
it's like it's one of those
yeah
Aroma of
them and it does that one really does oh
this is the sherb Nana from chirp Stars
what did you think of this
it's sweet it's tasty
oh it's cool yeah yeah
um and then
did you see any hash yesterday that you
thought was particularly good like
elsewhere outside of yeah the land
Hammer stuff I mean so before hash I saw
some flowers that were phenomenal there
was some midnight mass flowers that I
saw that were just beautiful
um uh of course Oni had some great some
great flowers there were some piff and
um yeah then
um I stuck with people's uh IG handles
but uh got hash homie he's always got
the fire Pedro I have some as full metal
here yeah shout out to Pedro yeah yeah
he came on he was one of the first
people that are we did
um well we smoked a lot of this
yesterday it was good but yeah and
remember he opened a jar and we were
like you know we weren't even in the
circle where he was at we were standing
off to the side and we just both looked
up and we're like
damn what's that and like when you're
standing outside
five to ten feet away from somebody not
even like in the circle where he's
handing to show people and you're you're
smelling the Terps across the world
you're like yeah that's what you want
when the sun it kind of warmed right up
and the wind oh yeah that's when you
know it just hit us
delicious dude
um zahidi lime is such a delicious Cross
of a lime flavor and a skittles flavor
the Tahiti lime is super super like
it's like really round Citrus it's hard
to put like a pinpoint on exactly what
it is it's lime but it has like slight
bitter notes of like kumquat almost and
like loquat and then you know of course
the Z is delicious brings grapefruit
notes candy notes it's very very very
euphoric off the bat delicious Sun grown
resin
um
yeah that's
what more can I say
give Peter the seeds that you added ego
Clash right the the pineapple butt melon
yeah yeah
um so yeah I mean that's one that
everyone can look forward to soon um
what's good with that
I mean just so the pineapple butt
melon's interesting if you grow it for
flour and you have the flowers it's
going to be really
Donnie Berger GMO forward really like
you smell it and you're like this is a
GMO cross
if you take it and wash it
the GMO and the Donnie Burger all moves
to the back and all you get on the the
resin is pineapple forward and you're
like damn this is super pineapple but
then on that back end you'll taste that
Donnie Burger sort of funk the butt and
uh yeah so the the pineapple butt melon
is just gnarly as can be on the garlic
funky terp and the flower
sweet and pineappley as can be on the on
the concentrate that's awesome yeah yeah
and great like you know everybody we've
handed it out to has gotten great
germination rates super vigorous and the
uh everybody who's tried the
concentrates has been like yeah this is
the shit's fire
and that again shout out land Hammer
land Hammer grew all those popped them
straight from seed in uh July like
direct so and uh grew out a bunch of the
Donnie Burger a bunch of the uh Oreos
and other peanut crosses
that's awesome
um yeah the pineapple Terps are really
interesting and cool I I like that one
yeah no they're they're unique it's nice
when that stuff kind of comes through in
the uh in the concentrate and you really
really get like
true to form where you're like yeah this
is pineapple and that's the type that
you don't really see but I've seen it's
making a Resurgence at least uh I was at
a funeral hunt last week where uh
pineapple and terpinoline and Jack
flavors were the the highlighting
yeah I gotta rung out after about eight
or nine of those duties but it's just
something that you're right it when you
can forward the taste all the way
through it is something that's very
present and very uh
straightforward those uh those Terps on
that Lifesaver are really unique you
know I mean like head entrancing almost
yeah and it's just it's like we were
saying like you just don't get that in
most concentrate because you know the
yields aren't there necessarily but like
uh it's not production it's not
production hash it's a flavor hunting
hash yeah also it's head stash yeah no
and it's it's worth it on that level
like if you get to experience it it's
it's unlike whatever you're gonna try
it was
it was 14 grams total six pounds 14
grams total from six pounds of fresh
Frozen
yeah yeah no and so
you know at those fashion projects
it's legit to see that Simon
um and to be able to experience it
because it's like it's a one and done
and that's something that's really
unique
[ __ ] that dude it's a it's
good
thank you man
fire it's uh it's really fun resin to be
able to smoke
that [ __ ] zahidi lime got me so high
it is strong
for anyone who doubts the power of candy
and fruit Terps
uh do not doubt any longer get your
hands on some zahidi lime
yeah definitely and be on the lookout
for uplifted meds he uh he washed all
that great washing
um I I know he's at a couple events
coming up he's going to be up in Oregon
uh in the coming weeks
um I think he's in Sac this weekend but
um uplifted meds is definitely somebody
if you're into uh Festival where if
you're into uh
good rosin he's your he's your plug
dude's got it all he makes really cool
outfits hats all that stuff him and his
uh girlfriend and um they make great
melt
on the note of interesting hash that I
did see yesterday shout out to some dude
named compost Malone I don't know your
real name but I know your Instagram tag
that scoring was really really
spectacular and um a unique kind of sour
Citrus Tangy Turf that I hadn't smelled
in a while
um shout out to you I appreciate it
yeah and the um also
uh Tapatio melts yeah
um you know it's it's cool that we see
homies from out of state and out of
California come to pre-seed day and rep
it really is an event that brings people
in from all over and you really get to
see and share memories and hash and
smoke with some people
some people good people
yeah
homie's doing work uh
the Tapatio melts is like dope branding
and also just really really high quality
material that's getting produced like
you said out of state so that's dope and
it's amazing to see that you know the
hashtag isn't really being gay kept and
people are doing incredible work
everywhere because there is really good
material everywhere
um and hash really allows a lot of
sunburn material to shine I think in a
cool way
it's awesome
I should probably bounce out at this
point Sun ground resin legit we uh yeah
we can wrap it there
[Music]
hey thank you everyone good to hang out
with you guys uh yeah
[Music]