[Music]
foreign
we have another session everybody showed
up early oh we're live we're doing this
hi everyone
um yeah no we have a great sesh today we
have some cookies we have some
sovereignties we have some really good
hats so let's talk sovereignty with our
uh sovereignty glass expert
thank you for bringing the really sweet
glass through of course of course
um I got a mini three Dome here so it's
a 44 to 50 to 44. uh and then I got the
44. it's a downgrade stem they're both
partials
um and then I got the cold work fa
I could take a rip out of right now
because I already have a bowl pack so if
somebody wants to hold this for a second
yeah yeah let's get it and talk
so I think that this uh this downgrade
stem what's good this downgrade stem 44
it's a ghost over ghost accent it's like
you said it's a partial accident you got
a nice booty color right there some some
Bridge color some some nice ice pinch
color
ripping the full accent Bowl
yeah he's got a nice Sovereign scene
lighter with some sandblasting nice
etching on on the sides
oh yeah fatty bowls and they're
relatively local right the pricing on
the song local sorry oh local yeah no
they're out of uh Riverside I believe is
where they blow all the glass hell yeah
yeah but they've started super small and
became really big there's a really cult
following for them people prefer to rip
those bongs over anything else well I've
always heard that for function so yeah
they're not necessarily per se for like
the looks of it yeah like the looks are
just a give or take it depends on if you
like the glass or not but they're about
the scientific function of the perks and
how they actually work not just like how
it looks you know
but I always feel like my issue has just
been that like sometimes they're too
much of a rocket launcher for me oh 100
well that's why that's why there's so
many different perks because they all
have a different effect and there's
going to be one that's going to be good
for you you know hell yeah so it I
personally like the 44s because they rip
super fat and then some people like
these the um
it's I think mini three to dome the
domes are really smooth because you get
that extra percolation of the smoke
and it also keeps it really clean like
you see how up here there's not much
dirty water compared to down here
so it's super fire
it's super expensive is that that is the
function of the middle zone is to have
like a wider perk I guess yeah kind of
there's a there's different sets so
there's like even tree cyclers that it's
a full it's it's the same width it's a
44 the whole way up but it has three
perks so it's just more diffusion you
know yeah yeah hell yeah
yeah all perked up
so do you want
anything yeah no so I'm hash right we do
a lot of solventless extracts we're from
the San Fernando Valley this is our
brand right here oh yeah we got tons of
Terps for you guys if you want to dab up
on some stuff we got some new strains
would love for you guys to try it out is
that flower that you grew as well yeah
older older batch but yeah about your
medium and how you like to grow the
medium how we like to grow
so we we grow we started growing mostly
out of rockwool and I like I like saying
like talking to people about it because
I feel like a lot of people are like oh
I only like living soil I like you can
get a very clean turkey exactly and you
can drive the plant harder and you can
do a lot and the resin production
creates exactly so when you're washing
control over that and you're getting a
more full expression exactly that Medium
which is cool same thing with so then
another thing that people don't like
with me saying is that we use salts and
everyone says that you lack Terps when
you use salts but I honestly don't see a
lack of anything well and you're mostly
if I remember the genetics I've seen
correctly running with stuff that was
bred under Hydro conditions oh yeah in a
lot of places and so it's also like a
lot of genetics were steered towards
thriving with those oh yeah 100 percent
exactly it's the high yielding High
resinous strains you know the really
good bag appeal dense buds like and so
what are some of the Staples in your
garden sorry what are some of the
Staples in your garden some of the
Staples uh we're trying to get the cut
back it was our big staple but Peyton's
pie is Gary Payton times Georgia pie
it's a Fino that we hunted from uh a raw
genetics pack uh raw genetics has some
really good stable genetics he's working
with some
not necessarily he's one of those
breeders that's not working with stuff
that he's created himself but it's super
stable high quality strains that are
from really good breeders and well-known
people so shout out shout out genetics
amazing video Peter I don't know if you
even watched it but with Chad
um yeah he was really good on that yeah
I think you should because he does a lot
of really cool stuff with the Georgia
pie right Georgia pie uh he's doing a
lot of like blue slushy crosses like
really cool Z crosses
unique Stuff strawberry Terps we we did
a big veto HUD we did a big feta Hut on
strawberry milk we did the paints pie we
did
a handful of things honestly it was uh
the guala one of our strains it's
Scotty's cake it's animal mints times
biscotti times gelato 33 so that's a
seed pack from him as well that we Fino
hunted but we've we got a lot of fire
out of there and some of them are
Staples in our garden now and it's
really cool well and I just appreciate
that you're a hashmaker running stuff
indoor and hunting from seed because so
many people I know will only take in
verified dumpers you know where that cut
is and sometimes
she
tell you
sometimes you have to take those losses
to understand because
you could be missing out on really good
Terps that aren't yielding very high you
know like
there's so many Terps but I mean think
about poochie's papaya if someone
skipped over that just because it was a
two percenter we wouldn't have some
crazy candy artificial Terps in the game
I actually didn't know papaya was I
would have assumed papaya was like a six
percent horrible yeah papaya is horrible
papaya Cake's like three percent like
it's it's not good no yeah
but it's worth it for the flavor you
know so damn straight people try to push
it onto the market and that's why you
don't see much of it or you see the
crosses like the GMO crosses like we
have garlic cookies papaya honey banana
papaya anything vigorous right to help
kind of fill out that chirp and it's
like how they're doing all the Z crosses
it's because it's such a weak strain
that everyone's like I love the terp and
they want to bring that serp out but
bring the Vigor of other strains into it
which and Shout Out people like clutcher
who are kind of exactly actually doing
it right yeah things like that and
someone else that I feel like I want to
shout out is deep east he's oh yeah he
gets deep into it he's he's not like oh
here's my f1s I'm across it with this
and here's my strain he goes deep into
the genetics deep like
I have mad respect for him well in his
on his first smoke of the day
um I feel like he really talked about a
lot of stuff I hear on FCP about you
know the real breeding work is in those
f2s those f3s exactly it's the stuff
that you're unlocking later down the
line that nobody would really see you
know and it makes it harder for people
to replicate your work because instead
of them being able to just take that
strain and cross it with the same strain
it's a different
further Express genetic of it you know
so it that's that's why I have a lot of
respect for him he takes a lot of time
and so what he does he's not just as
forced as a pollen chucker just someone
that's like oh these are two strings I
think would do very well together you
know he puts a lot of thought and time
into it
and then creates with the pollen chokers
are trying to catch up you know like I
think a lot of what Dio has done
people are pulling chucking their way
into right now with the really fruity
sherbs 100 minty lavendery yeah the tea
kind of Tasties yeah exactly crazy his
work is awesome do you have any of his
stuff in the garden we used to we lost a
lot of it though we had all the original
Z cuts that basically created RS 11 and
all the RS phenos we had just got the
permanent marker and we lost it right
before we could even grow it it was I
was so sad
is that like like a three a light type
situation permanent marker because it's
a Cushman
insane like
bummer on strains like that like light
like you could say like a plant weight
but it all comes down to the grower and
the environment you know because it
plays a huge role you could have a
strain that you're gonna think is going
to stack and be six feet tall and
[ __ ] full of nugs and the person
doesn't know what they're doing and they
don't know how to drive the plant they
don't know how to catch a swell and then
you're just full of a room of popcorn
nugs you know so
I think that yes it's a strain that has
the potential to do it but you need to
drive it correctly and that goes back to
not just the medium but the people
behind like you know the care that is
placed in the method and your system
that's exactly that's why I'm kind of
like the people that say oh you're not
doing living soil or you're not using uh
you're using salts I'm just like
it doesn't necessarily matter of the
medium or the nutrients you're using
it's how you use it it's
interesting in the case of of like
making hash because that somehow I feel
you're able to get a more pure
expression the herb right because the
herb is even to some extent like in the
way of the resin whereas and that's what
yeah that's why I respect people who
also grow their flour and wash it
because you get the and start to finish
kind of idea of the process and I feel
like as a hashmaker you need that to
really get the full idea of what you're
doing like you're not really
doing things to your full potential
without understanding that start to
finish and so is all of your stuff
single Source or do you take in
materials a lot of our stuff is single
Source
um a couple like whenever we're testing
out new strains that we really want to
run
whenever we're testing out new strains
that we really want to run we kind of
source from some people if we need to
but we keep a lot of our stuff in-house
we have a handful of really good
cultivators that I I trust with my life
they they just love they have the
passion for growing it's not because
they see it as a cash crop it's because
they they have that love for it you know
it is really awesome and so do you have
any requirements of what you'll wash I
mean do you need are there certain
requirements that you you know if
something is good if something's gonna
hit less than one percent will you touch
it I just washed something from a buddy
of mine that I was testing out straw AC
and I got .3 to rosin so and I paid for
it I paid four racks for it bro so it's
like you win and you lose sometimes and
that's part of the game so that's what
where those people fizzle out you burn
out when you don't have that real
passion for it but if you really love it
and like I'm crazy about hash bro so
that's not gonna get in my way I'm Gonna
Keep [ __ ] going and I'm gonna find
what's gonna help me out and what's
gonna do good for me you know
yeah
and keep in mind that point three
percent wasn't even [ __ ] I would smoke
it was so bad it was just all it was all
just stocks and bad stuff yeah bag did
most of the come out of it I pulled it
well I pull all my stuff 90 through 159
and I keep all the other stuff as well
but um even just the 90 head zoos it
wasn't heads it was all stocks and when
and when I pressed it it was just like
didn't have much Terps it was that
greeny kind of like nastiness you know
what what stuff that uh maybe doesn't
have high numbers in terms of how well
it washes but that you still run because
it's amazing hmm
that's a good question I've ran into
very few of them to be honest I feel
like
um
one of the strains that I really enjoy
that doesn't produce enough for us to
make sense to be putting it into
production per se is uh the uh
uh Double Cup it's our red pop times
runs that one's around like 3.4 percent
to sift
2.9 terazen a little under that and
it doesn't make much sense to put it
onto Market because you're sitting on so
much valuable product but the terp is
really pronounced that I I like it a lot
it's like one of those
strawberry Terps that it's like an
artificial cough syrup terp that's why
we call it Double Cup but and it's a
strawberry Turf yeah it's a red pop red
pop times runs so it's straw red pop is
strawberries and cream times uh times
strawberry I think
so it's it's super super strawberry here
hold on just quickly so you you uh
say that again it's yeah it produced
amazing consistency man like I just
rolled up some 305 Hayes from Miami
straight up and come on man like I
couldn't ask for anything better to
preserve that um
the flour mill does a lot of Justice in
terms of preserving the trichomes I feel
like you know one of these cookies
they're called so that's yeah so those
cookies while we roll up some other
stuff and thank you I mean thank you for
sharing so much about your brand of
course no worries I'm here I'm here to
spread the information it's a joke so
this is something that I'm up to with a
couple homies
um we are bringing this to the rec
Market it's a infused cookie mix okay I
don't really want to talk about it I
just want you guys to eat them no I
would love for you I'd love for you to
talk about it check these things out
they're [ __ ] fire but I can vouch
them
no no no no no I didn't you could have
told me they weren't infused and I
wouldn't even know so that's what we're
super stoked on we came up with the
recipe and we use a nano THC yeah
um that really provides no cannabis
taste and also when you're baking it in
the kitchen smell it's a quick onset to
the nanotech yeah we're really excited
about it I know some people are starting
to actually
make smokable versions of it which is
really interesting I think it's best
suited for topicals and edibles but yeah
it hits way faster past the pith to mace
pass the pith to mace Max what do you
think of the cookies
that's a 305 Hayes Miami Heat's right
there
for all you kids out there this cookie
is amazing delicious yeah it really is
honestly
I can't really taste hash in it are you
technically one of the owners Gabe of
this Cookie Company I am an investor
owner CEO what are you so me and two
other partners one of which Otis OG is
my oxygen is not here today the other
partner Ben is in the kitchen making
cookies and shout out to Ben for making
these delicious cookies today yeah shout
out to Ben and for putting them
Ben's in the kitchen cooking up
um and he developed this recipe which
I'm so happy that I didn't have to do
because it would not be nearly this good
oh 100 so so do you know if he's
infusing the butter or no where it's
actually we're making the cookie mix the
dry mix and so it is a nano THC
alongside a neutral carrier it it looks
very similar so it's like it's like a
crystalline it's like Crystal that it's
okay and so we're having to then just
homogenize it into the mix okay very
cool um which is harder easier said than
done 100 we're getting into Edibles and
doing mass production we just finished a
200 000 piece order it's [ __ ]
congratulations thank you I appreciate
it but it's it's it's a pain in the ass
so are you doing we're doing gummies and
are you using your your rosin we weren't
for this order it was just some
distillate order but down the line we
want to get a line together of rosin
edibles but
I feel like you have to approach the
market in a certain way because I was
talking to I'm not sure if you know but
Dank Tank yeah yeah the homie yeah
absolutely he's he's real he's a homie
but he sees things very far in the
future and we were chatting with him
about it and
he just feels that either the demand is
going to be so much that you can't keep
up with it that there's not enough rosin
to really
eat it you know but that's the whole
idea right yeah this was always like you
don't want that
I have to say I respectfully uh hold a
different position because yeah but you
don't want to be well the
industrialization of something creates
this thing called the standing reserve
and that standing Reserve effect almost
limits the quality of like the
production so it's always going to be
like the mythical one percent of hash
right but then we got to have to feed
the masses so I think he's understanding
what is like yeah it's like that right
there you know it's something convenient
sorry to strip you of whatever you're
saying and just spend you on a different
topic But but so
I don't know if you guys follow Bloom
Seed Co
so Harry Palms I I appreciate I
appreciate him so much he's he's like
way further in the game than anybody I
feel so him and his group they're
starting to discover my partner could
talk way more about this because he's
very very like
the the triploids
no have you no have you seen about uh
triploids no tell me tell us
so it's basically normal clones and
normal cuts of weed it's a they have two
chromosomes so triploid it has three
chromosomes and what it does is it
affects the genetic like stability in a
sense of it that it won't be able to get
pollinated wait can we step back a
little bit where are these things are
they their nature or they exist it's
existed in nature it's been a thing
since the 90s people have been growing
crops of triploids before it just hasn't
been uh look looked into
[Music]
exactly yeah there's skunk there's
triploid skunk that people were growing
in the 90s
that's a force a forced mutation or how
does that work it's a natural mutation
that that occurs and people people have
noticed what it does they've been
starting to study it more and more and
then what is Harry doing with that so
what they've noticed is that you're able
to control THC percentage and trichome
growth so they're saying that you could
get a 300 Micron trichome imagine
dabbing just one [ __ ] trichome
is
feels like a would be the resin would be
too heavy I remember I mean so that's
what that's their further thought of it
but so the whole idea of what they're
doing right now with it is so that they
can do 100 Acre crops of high yielding
High strains and it not get [ __ ] by
the hemp Fields next door that are gonna
seed it with the pollen and the reason
being it's not because they want to [ __ ]
on the market of hash it's that they
want to stop ethanol extraction to where
there's so much outdoor rosin produced
that you could be using rosin instead of
distillate and he just posted uh not him
but his partner 707 uh I forgot his
Instagram
he just posted uh he's seating 100 acres
of crops Auto flowers that are gonna
high yielding hash strain autoflowers
that are gonna be cut down I forgot when
but in a couple months and he's like
waiting wait until you see a hundred or
a 50 gallon barrel full of rosin well
culture forward exactly in a lot of ways
it also is going to set a standard that
the people are going to have to
increasingly so like they're saying in
the comments people are like why are you
gonna do this you're going to mess with
the traditional hash Market or all the
artists in hash I think that's an
approach that is realistic it's undoable
and that's but it's not what they're
trying to take down they don't want to
be anywhere near like The Artisan hash
or any quality kind of hash thank you
they're just trying to get Mass outdoor
rosins to production to where the cost
is low enough so that you can cut out
ethanol extraction and this yeah then
you're having a more pure expression of
the terpene and of the exactly that is
they're also in my mind the one concern
I'd have with that is not so much about
what it would do for production but more
what it would do to Terps because there
are just things that don't don't and
they're Terps that I like that don't
dump and that's the smoke and flour over
dho so are you are you uh are you cons
like do you care what Terps you're
getting in your Edibles yeah no exactly
no yes okay and there we go yeah hell
yeah so that's exactly so they don't
give a [ __ ] about that you know like so
so going so good and that's what them uh
where he's going uh distillate for
example people started Ryan uh um
distill an entire plants like we're
talking about stock and everything the
whole league yeah the whole plant and uh
like he said when you're doing Edibles
you're not really focusing on the Terps
like at all mass production also you
could do so much with it you know
elixirs all this other new [ __ ] that is
gonna come out everything that came out
showing distillment it's gonna be uh
it's gonna be like uh you're gonna
replace it with rosin people are gonna
go buying the rosin decarb pills on the
shelves now there's gonna be rosin
lotion rosin lip balm everything and
none of this has to have high amounts of
turps no 100 I think that I was not
thinking about it right I assumed that
it was all getting smoked no 100 million
and so that's what I'm saying is
everyone thought that that's what
they're going for but they're saying we
don't want any part of that market we're
trying to attack this Market the cool
side of it is that with the triploids
and the auto flowering that they're
messing around with you'll be able to
chop down your harvest in 60 days
it'd be a high yielding High strain and
on top of that you can manipulate the
THC percentage and trichome size
so it's like there's so many benefits to
it Peter what are they oh oh sorry what
are they saying in the comments I feel
like the comments will have thoughts
about this we're just recording oh okay
well in theory you all would have had
feelings about that
um
but no it's super interesting and I
think that
you know it seems very novel right now
but I think a lot of the crops hearing
stuff that's happening right now you
know pushing the plants like you were
talking about
25 years ago that was it just opens a
lot of opportunity because think about
the chances that people are going to get
because their crops aren't going to get
pollinated you can grow anywhere now you
could grow literally anywhere and What
markets are they mainly looking at
it
you know just up north like literally
just big farms was like the Oklahoma
type World anything like just what are
the what are the benefits of these
triplets you're talking about so it
stops uh cross pollination you can't get
the plants can't get can't get
pollinated and they're saying that it
can mean you're able to manipulate the
Vigor of the plant THC percentage and
trichome growth and so I guess I
understand why they would be sterile
sorry like the sterility makes sense to
me with the three
chromosomes but I guess I don't
understand sorry I'm paused let me grab
my friend because he he'll help shmom
come talk I'm talking about triploids
come come inform the people
I appreciate it
he's the he's the big brain yeah he's
good I mean I appreciate though that you
you guys well because we're really
passionate about it
so wait I have I have a question for you
yeah hello I fundamentally understand
why triploids would be sterile I don't
understand how you can then steer the
resin production
um so basically the idea is
it came from an Instagram post from uh
707 gross
707 underscore grows
um
and he's affiliated with Bloom Seed Co I
think
uh so he predicted that the future is
basically going to be
distill it free because
triploids that produce like six percent
uh resin Autoflower triploids
um are going to become the next thing so
people are planting like hundreds of
Acres of this and basically they're
unhindered by uh CBD Farms so if there's
a farmer that has male CBD plants right
next door it has no effect on it because
they're sterile
um
and that means that there's going to be
a lot of
not clean but there's going to be a lot
of really cheap outdoor rosin uh from
these autoflowers because they're going
to be dumping six percent in 60 days and
that's where we started was we were
talking about sort of what it would do
to the market but I guess what we're
curious about is sort of the mechanics
of I guess it is just that you have
Elite genetics that are now autos and
sterile right and so they will dump
there's nothing about the that steers
them towards dumping or am I
misunderstanding no so what steers them
towards dumping is simply the genetics
yes they're going to be elite genetics
yeah
um
Bloom seed co-feminized triploids are in
the works and will be available soon
triploids are plant varieties that have
three sets of chromosomes experiencing
hybrid Vigor heterosis it makes
everything bigger bigger plants larger
larger trichome heads increased terpene
and THC content and are sterile this
allows Farmers to the ability to plant
triploid seeds next door to an
industrial hemp farm with Acres of males
and not be affected as they do not
accept pollen
if you could plant Acres of hash dumpers
that aren't affected by Rogue pollen and
produce kilos of of rosin cheaper than
disti what would be the benefit of
traditional ethanol distillation
I think the rosin is going to replace
the disti market in the next few years
especially when Bloom seed coat times
automatic genetics collabs are done and
farmers are pulling seven percent crops
in 60 days it's going to be game over
for Dusty
genetics
it's it's
the technology to back it up
it makes sense
no 100 and the other thing too is how
they're in introducing the autoflowers
into it because on this other post he's
talking about him
uh seeding the 100 acres and he says
that he's gonna be hard he's gonna
harvest the field and have it replanted
by August 1st
and we had the homie last week and a
couple weeks ago on Jeremy Nori who in
addition to doing the secret cup
historically
now does the Autoflower yeah and so he's
seeing the evolution of early BHO and
his vision now of what's coming next in
the market are 100 and so I think it's
interesting that this sesh where you'd
expect people to not be super into Autos
it's coming up well because all those
used to be so frowned upon like it was
just something that people to throw on
their porch would be growing you know
but now it's being utilized as
how quick they can flower that it's like
people are like this is going to cut
down on production time how can we use
it you know
so and I feel like that's kind of what
the industry is stepping into is
everyone taking a step back and looking
at what have we missed and how can we
benefit from these things you know
there's a lot of little nuances that can
help a lot around the community I feel
do you have like another example
uh honestly no that's the best to put
you on the spot no no I know it'll come
come to mind I feel throughout the night
well you said that there would be
applications for like Edibles you know
more broadly whatever the other
placements
now I understand what you're saying Okay
um think about the people that are
coming into the market that are older
than us like the new the
the stigma of being a stoner is kind of
going away people are educating
themselves on what they can benefit from
the product
there's there's oil oil-based there's
topicals there's
several things my grandma [ __ ] smokes
a vape pen before a night for her
glaucoma in her eyes so
mine are too strong for her
yeah patches a lot of uh there's a lot
there's a lot of menstrual stuff coming
out for like women and there's really
big things that people are looking into
so so on another note to the lady I met
so your question cannabis anal butt Lube
yeah there's [ __ ] lube and [ __ ] Bro
there's there's support a small business
yeah but to bring up uh I feel like a
thing
another topic like you're saying that
has been on my mind is
but everyone everyone talks about it but
how THC percentage doesn't matter
I understand that everyone understands
that but what I feel like we need to
start looking more into is how the
terpenes affect us because that's the
biggest
thing that affects you I feel like think
about how lavender makes you sleepy
peppercorn makes you awake like the
certain terpenes gives you certain
effects is live exactly and I feel like
that's that's very I feel like that's
very overlooked
no it is and I mean I think that yeah
the term education is
you know there's some Australian
supplications
no but there's more there's more there's
missing out there's a lot that you're
missing out on it's the same thing as
all the [ __ ] someone trying to
explain how a strain will affect uh
affect you like oh it's a cerebral
effect like the [ __ ] does that mean bro
how do how is it gonna get me high
what's the high like not like how's your
spiritual [ __ ] being like you know
what I'm saying
I feel like there's things that we can
look into with the Terps that you can
actually put a pinpoint expression of
what it's going to give and also what's
like beyond the Terps like the
flavonoids flavonoids there you go
exactly cannabis you know all of these I
forgot who we were talking we were
talking with four and uh here right here
so I was at Green Street this was about
two months ago and we had a new string
called spoiled fruit it's not new but uh
what I did was uh
I opened this up we were like about
eight people there was there was no
flowing air it was it was all still we
smelled it we smelled one thing and then
I got a like the fan hit me I smelled
the same exact jar it smelled different
and I looked a little bit weird I looked
off because I was like dude this doesn't
smell like anything that you guys are
talking about and the thing is it's like
20 30 people against me with just one
person and I'm like no all you
[ __ ] are wrong and so what I
did was I went under the uh the AC vent
I I opened it again and I called
everybody back to under the vent and I'm
like smell it now and they're like holy
[ __ ] it's crazy over there where there's
no air it smells like strawberries in
front of the fan it smells like GMO so
you know sometimes like yeah maybe a
little knucklehead but I had to do that
just to prove my friends that you know
what I was talking about I was trying to
get my point across
I mean you go pass it around but once
again it's uh it smells it smells more
like strawberry and then you put it in
the fan it smells like GMO can I see
that stuff
oh absolutely they're volatile I mean
you're experiencing it firsthand because
you're fresh pressing stuff
what you're seeing in the jar no and I
mean honestly though some of those
terpenes that are volatile at room
temperature the most caustic like when
I've taken dabs fresh off the breasts is
when I'm the most blown out Gabe off the
top of my head when Pele polar brought a
flavonoids versus terpenoids I could
just think of blue cheese you know blue
cheese smells a little disgusting to me
but you dig into it it's all sweet and
creamy because so the breakdown the
oxygen exposure smell versus taste
creates a chemical reaction and that's
the whole thing with hash is like the
uniqueness is that it's stable and
preserved but it can still be like
transformed subtly over time because of
different and that's like if you go to a
moist environment you go to a dry you go
to a beach it's gonna you know cannabis
why did we say give parmesan cheese
some one of those lactose it's not urea
right
now it's like a bacteria
oh it's the um I forget what it is
butyric acid is what gives parmesan
cheese its smell
let's get technical cannabinoid
compounds in hash let alone weed so as
it oxidizes it's going through those
phases
yeah and that happens with tea and
what's rain and other things
2009 [ __ ] CBN thcv all those
different compounds they are expressed
and that's what oxidational special like
Temple balls five years old Temple balls
exactly one thing I learned was like you
can wash the hash it's very durable so
like you can get boiling water and hit
some old hash or whatever and let it dry
in the Sun and then you've got these
unique trips and break into you know
it's like a like a crust that preserves
the inner hash so yeah are these your
terms yeah yeah these are our church
how does that smoke bro it's really
smooth I mean the high doesn't last me
too long but it is smooth as well that's
because it's the tier two oh definitely
I'm just listening let's talk about that
is that how are you doing is it first
wash versus second watch like what are
the coolers to me I have a bit of I
don't hate calling stuff Tech because
it's the same thing back to how I was
saying about the I like hash makers that
grow their own stuff as well because
there's no Tech in half in making hash
you can make cash that's gonna be super
super harsh because there's a lot of
plant matter in it but if it's Fire
Starting material it's going to taste
fire and look fire so when they say Tech
I think they're just saying uh their
processed terminology their process you
know the process is basically
um
we depending on weight of the wash and
what the strain is because certain
strains wash way quicker than others
depending on the nug structure
um
we do our second to third wash and
separate our 90 through 159 for our
premium tier one what we packaged we put
our side label on top label and then our
tier two we just put a top label on and
that's basically our 73 through 189 new
of the
later washes and the lower and the upper
heads of the first through third wash
mixed into it word if that makes sense
it does yeah so yeah so we and that's
also what goes into our pens is the tier
2 rosin
which I'm I'm not afraid to say it
because it's [ __ ] fire absolutely
sort of to the conversation we were
having earlier because you're doing a
broader range of heads there's going to
be a broader range of experiences
exactly and more spectrum of terpenes
and flavonoids to be able to taste
that's where it comes into players why I
don't I I believe in the not the 90 and
upper heads are the most ripe the most
developed trichome heads but I don't
believe in doing 90 through 103 or 93
120 I want to get as close to where
there's like 91.89 or some [ __ ] like
that 93 189 93 159 if I can get as
little plant matter through I'll get to
the biggest screen I can because those
bigger heads have such Rich sugar like
church especially especially if the
genetic like I know it's gonna Contour
but like a Tangy like where even the
leaf has like a suite you know so that
when you get those filtered you're not
getting like an unwanted taste you're
getting that slight other resin from
there you're getting the pure expression
of what the plant wants to give you you
know
Oliver I'm gonna be opening up one of
your jars of garlic juice
um I thought yeah uh check this out I
thought it didn't smell like garlic
juice I do smell hints of garlic but I
want your guys's opinion let me know
yeah I want everybody's opinion stuff
stuff so this is my buddy out in uh
Kentucky his uh Mr Auto grow he works
closely with Bloom Seed Co he does a lot
of personal Fino hunts for them uh he
sent me this cut a few months ago this
and some grape guava the grape guava
didn't do too well but we're gonna try
and get the garlic juice back because
this one's a [ __ ] funny because I
have a homie who gets like six percent
off the grape guava which speaks to
different pianos no 100 well no it's not
necessarily I just I'm picky when it
comes to that those guava crosses
because I've done so many of them that I
just I don't like when it's heavy on the
strawberry guava you know because I'm
tired of that guava terp
I
we and the thing that sucks is we had a
really killer Fino we had a strawberry
bubbles it was Mimosa times strawberry
guava and we had a killer Fino of it
that it was straight Mimosa candy and a
little guava on the back end but it only
yielded like 0.5 percent to rosin but it
was the best flower I've ever had this
is a gassy garlic juice oh yeah correct
right it's not like a common garlic
juice right well garlic juice can go
super it's like a it's like just beef
it's not funky papaya it's the gassy
papaya it's like yes sir it is Galaxy
they're super sweet thank you they're
super cute there's the artificial papaya
there's uh funky papaya and gassy papaya
you know
congratulations thank you I appreciate
that but from what you smelled in the
past
you've been here many times so
yeah super gassy right it threw me off
it smells great but it threw me off
that's the beautiful thing about FCP the
super buff we could always come smell
try
yeah it's very push forward glue but
like the back end has this nice floral
like sweet expression of the colors
floral that's one of them
wow I like it it kind of just stains
your whole like esophagus with sweet
tier one other two too tier one baby
which you know I've been around a lot of
you I'd say I don't sell jars I sell
hash like you can miss me with the side
wrap what's that is
it doesn't have packaging and stuff
because we uh we're gonna be packaging
it this week it's all new stuff but that
would normally come with a side wrap and
everything this is the or I gave it to
him do you have the spoiled fruit jar
that has the side wrap and everything
for
it that's just like a super super Trump
cherry
yeah
crazy uh do you have the super Booth jar
with the full wrap and everything
who is that from
gold oh nice oh yeah
and what is the cross what is the cross
on the supervision the super Booth is
Tropicana cookies sometimes black cherry
punch nice yeah
and then the spoiled fruit is doci dose
times chopped Cherry word yeah
and so it seems like
it's like and so trop seems like it's a
staple in your garden here check it out
serious oh my God perfect
smell some of that that's the tier one
super uh spoiled fruit
spoiled fruit and that's the tier one
which one that yeah I don't know what
that is that's the super Booth the one
that I gave you oh nice yeah it's great
here yeah pass that around this is the
tier one spoiled fruit
spoiled fruit is
Dosey dose times trap Cherry yeah it's
super unique because that was the strain
that Ford was talking about with the
airflow and how it changed so it's super
gmoe funky dosido smelling that
sometimes and then on the back end you
get the strawberry like really sweet
candy smell
now you got to get the hash right with
the hash right right for you know what
I'm saying gotta get the hash right with
the hash sure
yeah we got second place at cush stock
could have got first but hey dude and
then we got uh we got first place for
our Edibles though yeah thank you
sorry yeah
which is the right amount yeah nine nine
I'm nine in and I am faded I didn't
think I already get me that high
honestly even like even I did eat it a
lot but like before I thought 40. no no
no no that's too much that's too much I
brought those I brought those for
everyone because yeah yeah
um
but yeah take one there they are
medicated four milligram Nano that's
cookie that's uh cocoa and salts
okay
that was our first run in Coco no so the
the spoiled fruit was
rockwool and then the super Booth was
Coco
so the and the cocoa but you just still
ran the same salt formula yeah same salt
formula and everything nice and then
we're gonna
reintroduce so like I was saying that
was our first run we didn't get crazy
crazy numbers because we weren't
expecting it we only got I think four
and a half percent on the super Booth we
were expecting 5.6 because that's what
we normally get
um but we had no foliaries we didn't
have any beneficials nothing in the room
so honestly we crushed it because we got
2.27 a light with nothing just literally
just feeding it nutrients and that's it
so I'm excited for the next few runs
because I feel like we're gonna get some
really good numbers out of it the next
room that we have coming in uh
it's got a while it's like 60 days it's
gonna be jealous bananas and oil tanker
yeah jealous bananas jealousy times
banana cream cake and then uh oil tanker
is motor breath times trophy wife
so yeah actually I have some motor just
straight motor breath right here too
this is a personal friends friends and
family batch here one tier one we're
gonna only be releasing I think six jars
of it six yeah super limited three times
two the motorbike that's heavy it is
heavy
and this is just that straight motorbike
half gram dab you think I'm uh
I was gonna try to I would say like
someone here
yeah yeah we'll stay warm you can
probably squeeze
yeah you got to take some gloves you
gotta get the full expression of the
Terps
superbooth
you could you could glob all of them if
you want what everyone stood out the
most to you
which about a set up Gabriel with the
nice fat glob of some hash right which
one did you I don't think I've tasted
your house will this be your first time
taking a glob on FCP no I've taken
gloves and not of this hash what was uh
your favorite so far that you've smelled
after this it honestly might have been
the rotten fruit I'm forgetting the
spoiled fruit yeah no that one sticks
around with people it's it's one of
those ones that just sticks in your head
you know yeah like for me one of those
strains is like mac like caps cut Mac
that smell stays in my head like no
matter what
so it's one of those strains I feel you
know yeah you're more than welcome to
take a dab of whatever word hell yeah
so ask Eric what he
[Music]
what's wrong Eric how'd you do it tell
us about it on the farm and a little bit
at home too and a couple other spots
yeah
in beds and pots in the ground we had
some in the ground we had some in pots
30 gals uh four by fours
um and uh yeah some little yeah
everything all between
um
how do you deal with those what's your
IPM for that which one the caterpillars
um you know what slugs I I don't they
weren't bad enough I didn't really have
a problem with those in my place
um and then caterpillars we did the uh
track of gamma wasp
oh we did the uh trike again predatory
wasp yeah track a gamma wasp they're
yeah so it's a predatory insect so no
no sprays yeah you could just let them
go in the greenhouse and or out in the
field and they'll take care of them not
super dope yeah what what do you grow
like like on the hunt because you also
grow hemp but
uh we had some Gary Payton some soap
some cush mints some
um
um sour AJ's Sour Diesel AJ's cut we had
some
um
what was ice cream man was the other one
ice cream man Jazz what was this
um
it's a Peter term for sure
20 firing up there for hello
that one's tasty
I'm gonna take a dab of some hash I do
not know the name of this brand I'm
finally taking it it's called keeping it
Coastal it smells amazing that's all I
have to say
and this is soil grown right now yeah
oh you can go you can go
all of maximum I guess we'll take a dab
together yep
let it go down that's a very heady house
too lots of heady hash today
you guys like that guy I just got the
dab rig
what's the what's the quartz on the end
of it SD dank quartz
and a Bowman rig
[Music]
oh there's definitely water in the rig
those let's just wait for the
temperature to go down we're not trying
to kill Gabriel either
Gabriel how hot do you like your dabs
game so sorry just back to this 800 game
uh about keeping it Coastal they're a
small boutique farmer located on the
regional coast of Sonoma County if you
want to learn more about them there's a
full review on their flower on
daggaacademy.com
Academy you know me I be high but it is
what it is
all right
all right let's go it's ready
let's get a game
Cheers Cheers
put it lower on the dish
let's hear it spin that's actually a
pretty big dab right now
[Applause]
Peter you spoke too soon you jinxed it
oh [ __ ]
but that was clean ash good it smells
amazing
[Applause]
[Music]
you're next
strong fruits rotten fruits what was it
called spoiled fruits spoiled fruits
yeah
he's had more fruity on the um
I'm crying
that uh that had a lot more uh fruit on
the burn than it does in the jar you
could tell I'm crying that sulfur
volatizes really quick you lose all of
that garlic smell yeah and it turns out
to the fruit once you pass that yeah
once it's cured right now it's like
smoothed out and become a lot more uh
enjoyable yeah
that's one of the beauties of the Frozen
you get to capture all that expression
but then after the whip man the art of
the whip you gotta you gotta come on
that was a big dub that was proper good
off like point five yeah I'd say I'm not
supposed to take times that was the
largest and hottest dab I've ever seen
gave take
[Music]
five I think is my biggest biggest and I
was getting ninja dubbed
um
good [ __ ] and so what was your favorite
thing that you ran this year
or what do you get what are you running
this coming season uh this coming season
we got a whole bunch of
um gosh all the some mint stuff
um but for the as far as like seed pheno
popping I'm going for some kind of older
green gas crosses like some chem stuff
um and uh some OG crosses that are just
green to green and then uh some lemon a
lot of lemon crosses so I've been as I
travel around everywhere I go I've I've
been asking everybody for for what they
have in the lemon Realms so I've
collected a handful of lemon packs so
I've got you know like a dozen or more
people's lemon crosses
you know just a bunch of guys lemons
lemon lines it's gonna be fun so what
are you looking forward to the popping
the most out of those lemon packs
um I know flying lion research Sean he
he gave me a lemon hash plant on Lemon
hash plant
um whichever another one that I just saw
the other day that looks really fun to
go through
um who was oh I got a um Hawaiian Bud
lines uh from Hawaii it's uh they're
they're Citrus I mean like uh it has so
much Citrus in it so that's not truly
lemon but that's in the Citrus world
might get something that kind of leans
that way but had like all the Citrus
um and then uh what was the other one oh
um
you know uh Russell Char genetics just
gave me a couple of his uh lemon crosses
that he was doing because he had a lemon
hash plant too
um and then oh uh Jake from 808 genetics
he gave me a some lemon peels all right
he had a bunch of different lemon things
which is like a uh lemon macaroons to
lemon something so that that that should
be a fun fun one to go through so yeah
like I said there's just a bunch of
lemons in there that's great and Eric we
all got kind of hot and we glossed over
it but if you want to just introduce
yourself real quick to The Crowd Oh yeah
sorry the people who don't know you
foreign
yeah we uh we do all organic nutrient
line uh we've been have been able to
come out with a uh soluble organic
nutrient that'll you know totally uh run
through all your fertigation systems and
then um yeah we've got
supplements and everything you need the
whole whole organic fertilation it's
good stuff fertilizer line thank you
yeah we enjoyed we enjoyed I wish Otis
was here to talk about how we used it
yeah yeah
um we were really happy yeah thanks
that's you know going down the terp
profile and into that world you
definitely you know your inputs matter
you know and so if you want to get right
now we need to uh I want to send the
whole lineup to a grower who's gonna go
on YouTube and we can do like watch them
do a grow along with all your just
running your stuff definitely I'd love
to yeah let's do it that's what uh you
know it's all about getting it getting
the fertilizer in The Growers hands and
to get the content and I feel like
you're always doing sort of r d and
looking towards the future what are you
working on right now uh you know an
organic micro nutrients so we can get
into like a true organic hydroponic
system is going to be uh going to be
next and so an organic cream like you
could effectively drip food correct
effectively drip feed into cubes or into
into
um you know dwc or into
um you know hydrogen what's that
most likely
yeah
yeah the key is solubility and state
stability too so yeah we're working
through that and we're in a true organic
cow mag that's soluble as well that
could be passed through so those are a
couple of things we're working on right
now is there any Community against
calling uh liquids like organic or
anything like that
um any Community against calling liquids
organic yeah even though they're organic
like fertilizers and all that whether
it's like
accepted just yeah
like um
you know yeah you have liquid Organics I
mean our fpf is 100 organic non-GMO
organically stabilized basically food
grade you know so that's our um our
fermented grains and that has fulvic
acid amino acids enzymes that's awesome
um and the key right there is the aminos
and the fulvic acid because I'm a huge
fan of uh anything that's easier to keep
the grow clean you know instead of using
soil all the time absolutely yeah no
this uh you know the what the fpf
supplies is powerful lots of energy for
the plant from the fermented grain
for sure
Bank
how do you feel about uh veganic growing
Style
[Music]
what's this tier two yeah yeah
it's probably got some limit on it too
I'll do that [ __ ] that I was talking
about it's totally awesome he said this
is life damn yes super smooth for me I
couldn't tell well they do some indoor I
couldn't tell you specifically but I
think they mostly lights up
keeping it Coastal very talented
[Music]
very good
uh one of like the true best examples of
terroir as I mentioned before they grow
literally on the coast right above the
water
this is someone else's jar I feel but
yeah that is the brand here it's good
oh it's your boys
oh yeah absolutely
I'll be honest
Kevin it's cooler than yourself
that is not cooler than this one
I think it's pretty goddamn cool I think
it's on the same level but I just saying
how cool do you think this is
you see he said it's cool it's not that
cool it's cool
that's a good tool it's a handy it's a
you know multi-tool
well you'd have to you know use it to
know it's totally of how good it is you
know so let's wrap it up well everybody
Organics alive hash right some cookies I
think it could be worse I I think it was
a great great evening thank you everyone
for tuning in we hope you have a great
rest here Tuesday we're going to enjoy
this sesh y'all have a good one thank
you
[Music]
thank you