hi everybody chad westport here i'm here
with 71dpo
and we just want to give you a quick
little update about the show he's been
doing lately so tell us where we're at
tp hey what's going on everybody i
really appreciate everybody's
involvement thus far in the show
really enjoyed it
i've been just taking a little bit of
time off i got to get some things
situated in my life just renewed my
lease i was planning on moving that
didn't happen so
just once i get things a little bit more
settled down i'll get the show going
back up i do have somebody coming on the
25th and uh that's mrs vicious
you can find her on instagram
she's a beautiful person in the movement
of psychedelics and
she does a lot of
reintegration and she's very involved in
um
the walls and stuff like that so i can't
wait for her to be able to
talk about the movement she's involved
with like decriminalized nature and
stuff like that so
yeah excited
very cool man i i've been excited by the
shows that you've done and it sounds
like you're going to keep continuing
where you've left off and again i kind
of want to just take a moment to pause
and say
big ups to you because you're following
the advice that you give sometimes we
need to put you know extra things on
pause
and get a bearing doesn't mean you're
done so yeah absolutely
i want to be able to put my time and
energy into this show
and give it the respect it deserves and
uh i owe myself the respect i deserve to
get myself uh back in tip top right so
100 100 i don't think anybody's gonna
argue with that uh but in the meantime i
do just want to leave this info up
because it can and may help a lot of
people maybe the people
watching or someone they know but
suicide prevention hotline everybody 24
hours a day 365. uh you can reach that
1-800-273-8255
and also nami.org which is the national
alliance of mental illness
lots of great resources there so please
do check that out
and uh like the flyer says keep calm and
i'll be back soon returning june 25th
and hey everybody while we're here i
want to give you an update on the shows
that i'm going to be doing oh for the
last little over a year i've been doing
the perfectly imperfect grow show where
we take you inside the home gardens of
our peers our community and that's been
really fun it's been really rewarding
and i'm stoked to see it catching on
with a lot of other shows so that's kind
of taken care of now and i always want
to be doing something a little bit
different so i will be back every
saturday with a new show called the
friendly cannabis show starts june 18th
we're gonna start it off with marge from
the bite me podcast and manny from bud
and lather we're going to be talking
about alternative uses for junk that we
throw away when we trim our plants or
even the buds so many uses for this
plant it's exciting so we're going to
cover that and then after that
i've got some exciting guests lined up
for everybody some people you don't
always hear from a lot of times but
people who you know and love so i'm
excited for the future please keep it
locked here on the future cannabis
project in fcpo2
good times ahead everybody party on
thanks for the update dp we look forward
to seeing you then brother much love
everybody
peace