uh
[Music]
hello everybody and welcome again to
amazing conversation we are here at the
dank hour and we are discussing
finishing the perfect cannabis plant and
why your flushing debate don't mean [ __ ]
there are many different ways to have a
great flower at the end of
your cannabis growth now i mean
we spend a lot of time developing our
plants putting them through veg and
flowering all of this effort so how do i
go about getting the best possible
outcome a lot of conversation happens
from flushing and we thought we'd have a
great discussion today and talk about
exactly that here on the dank hour now
don't forget to sign up for our
newsletter click like follow subscribe
do whatever it is you got to do to
spread the word and share everything
getting on in the industry now without
any further ado let's jump into the show
with our experts and see what's going on
when it comes to finishing the perfect
cannabis plant
[Music]
awesome actually we're at 501
um i'm going to give it like another
minute and to let the other people get
it i've brought up leah as well she is a
a
really amazing uh knowledge when it
comes to
humic and fulvic because we're talking
about finishing off a little bit earlier
jamison when we were talking about kind
of planning what we were going to
discuss for the day so i thought i
brought leah in to help with that
discussion as well so she's here as
support too
happy to be here guys
very cool welcome leah
nice to see you
alia good to see you
hey corey hey manny hey leah
all right how are we doing over there
are we connected and recording there
my excellent mate cory we are recording
on the green room and we are also
recording on garage band so we have a
double
safety we're ready to go brother
on gara okay cool well that's excellent
very very exciting guys
well welcome everyone to the dank hour
where today we just where we bring
experts together discuss very exciting
and interesting aspects of cannabis
horticulture and processing of cannabis
it's it's a really always just a fun
time talking about dank
dank subjects and amazing
cannabis horticulture from really
profound experts i've had the fortunate
ability to uh spend and share a time and
room and conversation with these people
and they are the dankest minds i know in
cannabis and i'm excited to share them
all with you as well
so welcome to the dank hour today we got
a big bag of crap we're going to unload
and i'm excited for it as you can see
it's see it's a very fun title finishing
perfect cannabis and why your flesh
debate don't mean [ __ ] all right i i
really i i'm not a huge fan of flushing
i think a it's it's a misinterpreted
word um oftentimes uh people
misinterpret it with leaching so just
out of um ease and
communication and understanding we're
gonna we're gonna go by like the jorge
cervantes kind of the the classical tech
textbooks on cannabis that's and and
horticulture that lean towards leaching
is adding a surplus of water to your
medium to remove
excess nutrients or imbalances to rinse
your medium of
certain improp problems or issues this
is leaking
flushing is commonly dictated as at the
end of flower when you feed nothing but
water to starve the nutrients to starve
the plant and cause
chlorosis in which that the plant uses
the leaf to fuel everything else but
we're going to get into that very fun
subject and everything about it so we're
going to lean away from uh flushing and
lean into all of these amazing experts
on
[Laughter]
thank you
and we're gonna lean to all these
amazing experts on what exactly we do to
to to get the perfect flower at the end
you know we we all have our own little
tricks of the trade uh we all have our
own we've read a lot of science paper
we've done a lot of research and we all
have little things that we do so i screw
flushing let's finish the perfect
cannabis plant and see what each one of
these amazing experts are doing on that
subject so first off to start off we are
going to say thank you over to resonate
radio they are our conglomerate best
pals over at the green room they are
recording and being an excellent group
and as we know cannabis grows as a
community and together we grow um so
it's amazing to have uh cory and the
resident radio over there
projecting our show to get a little bit
more out into the open so i'm really
excited and thank you again cory i
appreciate that but i'm just going to
give it forward to our amazing
moderators if you could all just kind of
follow ptr and introduce yourself all
the way down for everybody speaking so
as you may or may not know those that
are new to joining us
this is an hour-long recorded discussion
following that we do open up a garden
party room
that is the show after the show where we
get all these experts together and
invite everybody up up on stage and just
have a great conversation about
horticulture usually try and keep it
kind of dictated towards um what we were
talking about during the room but often
we we
get to go down a few rabbit holes it's a
casual conversation that isn't recorded
you can also see our shows
you can also see our ourselves if you
click on me and check out my youtube we
have our first episode up already on our
youtube channel and we have many more
coming to go unfortunately i was
unavailable last week and we had and
we've had to slow down a little bit on
production because i had a baby
um she is a mezzakin is a beautiful
young little lady i am super excited to
have her with us so it was a little bit
hectic but thank you guys so much for
taking the reins and jumping in and
doing the show without me i appreciate
each and every one of you so let's get
started chaz if you could introduce
yourself and
the group of amazing moderators that we
have as well
hello my name is chaz
i have been
cultivating cannabis for over 20 years
in the legacy and recreational markets
started off in washington moved down to
humboldt for about 10 years and then uh
more recently moved
to vancouver british columbia um
i've had
a wide range of cultivation experience
from
outdoor full-term to
greenhouse and mixed light inside of a
greenhouse light depth
and indoors and
my preferred method of cultivation is in
living soil beds um with a blue map
system for my watering
that's me
hey everyone my name is jameson welborn
i'm the co-founder and general manager
of a fully licensed nursery here in
canada by the name of big league
genetics
we specialize in
unique terpene profiles and high
cannabinoid ratios
and we specifically deal with licensed
cultivators in the canadian market
i've been touching the plant since 2007
[Music]
and yeah i'm really happy to be here and
happy to learn with everyone
[Music]
my name is corey i'm the principal
managing partner of resonate cannabis
incorporated we do large-scale
cultivation
consultations uh this calendar year
we've been in canada america colombia
and now portugal
and i'm just really excited to
be on this panel and share the space
with all you
lovely human beings it's just really
nice to have some time
outside of the madness to just you know
give back and talk about some of these
very very interesting topics and today
i can't wait
[Laughter]
hi everyone i'm anita um i
am
not a professional
but i do like to uh grow um my
medical plant um however i come from the
retail consumer side
and
um
have a lot of insight with regards to
what's going on in the canadian specific
industry except um well oh look i'm
finding out that
um in the north american market as well
a lot of these um
trends that i'm i'm seeing so um yeah
i'm i'm i'm on the consumer side and uh
yeah
media and things like
[Music]
go ahead manny you're up
hello
i'm manny i have a yet to be licensed
hello what was that that was weird i
have a yet to be licensed facility in
southern ontario
um
breeder grower
lover of the plant and that's me
i know you're quite busy with your kids
josh are you available
i am hey everyone i'm josh i've
been in the campus industry for quite
some time i
worked in research and development for
three and a half years
um currently
working to help somebody empower growers
get to the
to a micro license to get into the
system and
very happy to be here thanks
and leah go ahead and introduce yourself
as well
hello i'm leah i am a co-founder of a
humec and felvik
company called quad neutral products and
we are purveyors of high quality and
active humic and phobics
that are used as adjuncts to existing
nutrient programs to improve performance
and nutrient uptake
awesome well we have quite an amazing
group of people and i'm really excited
to talk about this talented conversation
i just wanted to have a community throw
out there i i i also gotta say hi i'm
london from ucategrow
i'm an educator
and i teach people how to grow cannabis
i have an online free course that you're
welcome to check if you click on my
profile check it out there we also do
lots of social media stuff and this and
that so if you like what you see here or
you like what's going on don't forget to
follow or like any of our moderators or
all of our moderators please do um that
as that is how we derive everything
forward
as well as don't forget to check out
their other socials or check out
everything else and check the free
course and all that business i wanted to
show you this really cool photo i have
of the beautiful man next to me chas
he has this epic outdoor plant that he's
just trellised down here i just want to
show you the steer size of this single
plant in this photo chaz is not a small
person but he looks dwarfed in this
photo
now while i segue just with just enough
time there rj are you available to
introduce yourself we're just finishing
off introductions now
awesome hey everyone i'm rj ellis i am
an extraction refinement
specialist for uh canada's leading third
party extraction company just a little
late getting off work hope everyone is
good
and uh super excited for this
conversation about flushing it's a long
one or a long time coming and uh it's in
depth so
stoked uh stoked to be on the panel
started this conversation
and uh thanks for everyone for showing
up
awesome and i am excited that you were
able to make it that everybody has been
here today because it's been an exciting
week and i am excited to spend some time
with some adults and have adult adult
style conversations that aren't
regarding
small children and what color their poop
is today so a very exciting and
wonderful stuff going on here let's talk
about flushing our plants uh and not
necessarily flushing i really want to
focus on and
alleviate this how we're going to finish
our plants and how each one of us
interactively look at it we're all in
different systems and we use a lot of
different mediums and grey methods and
really depending on this could dictate
how you personally finish your plant so
let's talk about the last three weeks of
flowering what's actually going on there
and what we what we do ourselves to
create the best and opportune best
opportunity situation for our cannabis
flower to produce the highest
cannabinoids the highest terpene profile
everything that we feel is makes best
and i think there is other than the fact
that there's little there's definitely
some science out there that we we should
all have a read and have a look at but
there is
a certain thing to be said to each and
every individual cannabis is about
growing and enjoying growing the plant
and being part of the community of
growing the plant it is not
if it brings you joy to do something
go ahead you know if it makes you happy
go ahead and do it the world is your
oyster go ahead and experiment these are
our opinions on how we do things and our
methodologies uh and we are all very
open-minded individuals we certainly
critically have no others
i look forward to hearing everybody's
responses and how they go about here so
i am going to jump around a little bit
i'm not going to go straight to manny as
he would probably
expect i'm going to start with
a really kind of
open-ended question towards josh like
when it comes to finnish cannabis
what do you think really defines great
cannabis like what what what is
perfectly
finished cannabis to you
maybe i uh you know what josh this kid
i'm gonna i threw it really
are you available
yeah no i just had to kind of pull away
for from the other room there um but
yeah so
great uh cannabis to me
uh would be you know something that
like generally for myself anyway i've
cured things for a minimum of two weeks
depending on the cultivar sometimes
uh much much longer um
but yeah so i mean when you're you know
having that kind of a a
product
you know it's been hang dried it's been
hand trimmed
uh when you smoke it it's you know
it's very smooth um you know
generally white ash is a good thing
although it's
not always indicative of a quality
product
but uh yeah generally speaking you're
gonna have you know a
very nice
pure like a consistent color dash at the
very least um and not consistently black
um which anyone here can attest will
taste horrible um but yeah and then
depending on you know the quality of our
inequality and you know the thc level of
that strain and the terpene level that
strain you'll get you know a really nice
grease ring
on like a joint for example but um again
that
isn't always necessarily you know a
marker of quality of how to do quality
you know joints that didn't get that
grease ring but you know those were you
know the you know the levels of your
team had been lower but you know the
terpenes were still there you still got
an amazing effect from it
but those are all just little things
that i kind of
look for in a clean product
awesome so we know we all know we're
looking for this beautiful nice clean
smoked smoking product and we see the
whiter ash
oil ring
or for very very sticky residents
products these are things that we look
for for a great finished product so jazz
what do you do on the tail and the
flower for your plants i mean you're
doing a lot of extraction specifically
solvent less extraction um does that
have any
variance in how you finish your plants
or what exactly is your methodology
about that
i mean i grew in beds
you know inside right now so
i can't really
flush my beds in a
in a
in a way
so
i
never flush essentially i just lay off
putting
any inputs any top dressings or anything
onto my soil
um
like half of the half of the
plant's life usually like four
weeks
at week four or five i'll stop putting
anything on my soil so that
what is there can get broken down but
the biggest thing that i've noticed in
growing
organically is that
you can
screw up your
your beds and your
finished product by over applying
too much compost
[Music]
worm castings or whatever
you will get a black ash from doing that
your plant will
uh cannabis is a bioaccumulator so
uh
it will just pick up everything out of
your soil
um
good and bad and sometimes it doesn't
need all of those extra inputs um
so my whole approach to
to it all is just keeping it as simple
as possible
and
not adding anything basically
past the halfway point of the plant's
life
awesome and you're you're in you're in
large
bed style organic right
yeah uh in
in four by four beds
um
you know so all i do is just top dress
and that that is it
um and i do some supplemental feedings
when the plants show
that they're starting to
maybe need some more food
but i just try to keep it as simple as
possible and
you know if you get out of the way with
cannabis and just sort of get the
environmentals right you don't need to
at least the way that i grow you don't
need to add a lot more to it um you know
i have all my nutrients pre-mixed in my
soil so
um
you know that that's where
it gets all the goods from
um
and
yeah i mean i
i
i just try to
get out the way and let the and create
is least stressful an environment um for
my plants and if you're not giving your
plants enough food
they'll show it
they're all there also will show in
different ways if you're giving your
plants too much food
i think people oftentimes with cannabis
uh
have uh
an approach of being a [ __ ]
where they think just putting more on
your plants and more on your um you know
more water and more
more nutrients that you're going to get
a better product when
truly you don't need that as much like
even the recommended dosages on
fertilizers or you know if you are going
to use a fertilizer um
start off at half
of what the recommended dosages and see
what happens
you know one could be huge cost savings
and two
um
you know you could be way you could be
wasting your time and money down the
drain with uh uh
with
over applying fertilizers and that's one
just thing that i see overall and that
will end up if you over fertilize your
plants that's where you get the
black ash from and there's no way of
flushing that out
of your plants like it's in your leaves
in the in the plant
material
doing solvent extraction i get a little
bit of a
uh
you know
we don't see that
as much in our end product because all
we're doing is
extracting the the glandular heads
and not don't have anything to do with
the leaf so
um
but
your plant will be much happier if you
don't try to force feed it and shove
everything down
it's just finding that happy balance and
once you do it enough you start to see
little nuances
oh it's a very organic methodology about
it now i'm going to kind of jump over
and just because i really i think this
is an excellent point of movement here
to really highlight the differences of
opinions on experts because chaz and
manny are probably two of the
i'm going to say the most experienced
here
um
and and they have very different
opinions on so i'm going to ask manny
how do you finish the tail end of your
plant or we're going to see here because
i don't really know um that the last
three to four weeks of your plants
flower cycle how do you like to finish
your plants because i know you're a big
advocate against the flushing debate
but i would love to know a little bit
more detail on your your thought process
and methodology about it
thanks london
so
kind of
start from the beginning
there's a misconception with
flushing and what it actually does and
you did cover the terminology and and
how people have got it wrong
but i think that
there's a little more to it that people
don't understand and that is i think a
lot of people have been taught
that the last week or the last two weeks
that you feed your flower nothing but
straight water
that miraculously everything that's
accumulated over its uh flowering cycle
and life cycle
that um
anything bad or bad tasting is somehow
miraculously going to be washed away
and you know that's
not true at all science shows us that
it's not true and if you understand the
biology of the plant you'll understand
that as has been said by a few people
that it is a bio accumulator
that being said
i do think that you're
we're on to a good point from what jazz
stated about people over feeding their
plants and that is that
there are different levels for different
strains that will take different amounts
of
feed opposed to others
that feed needs to be tailored off at
some point in that cycle
because that flower's not going to need
that high of concentration when the
flower first starts out
you know once you flip and and you start
to see bud sites if you're into let's
say week four
that uh feed regiment what i do is i
start tapering it off so i will run my
feed regiment to a maximum
as what the plant will take that will go
anywhere from 15 to 1800 ppm
but then i also
will use teas
in order to raise my ppm
at the same time uh for the longest
period that i'm going to be at the peak
to around 2800 to 3200 ppm
by using the tees now this doesn't
affect or adversely affect the flower in
any way
and helps build a very good strong bud
and strong structure
i will
then start to taper off so that by the
time i'm on my last week of
feed i'm down to 100 150 ppm
and um you know i'll uh i'll finish my
flower that way i don't use any type of
finishing agent
i don't i don't believe in him
i don't
i don't see any any need
to feed straight water
if you've
[Music]
fed your plant your plants properly and
have it here to a schedule where you you
take them to the max and then you know
slowly reduce it back down to as low as
possible so that's how i finish it's
kind of similar to chas in many ways and
we do agree on on many many things
but
you know that's that's always been
my go-to and i'm done speaking
it's awesome i think there's a really
interesting aspect and
point that i'm really seeing here is
that nitrogen toxicity in the fiery
stage mid
early
and the later in the flowering stage the
worst is the worst the plant will suffer
in in this in this
bad flavor or issues um in the plant so
avoiding this high nitrogen toxicity um
it is is probably people were over
compensating um by trying to flush it
out by trying to do a derivative now
when you have something like an
ammonical
ammonium based nitrogen like nitrogen
sulfate um the plant takes these in as a
salt a lot harder it's actually forced
fed uh ammonium sulfate if i could
i know i'm correct is the plant takes it
in through the water no matter what and
that's how you get these really high
nitrogen base burning and that's when
you get this terrible flavor so i wonder
if this kind of common over time and
misconception was a way to counteract
this balance here and that's why this
whole flushing concept came out jameson
i would love to hear a little bit about
how you think about i mean your flowers
are
fantastic if you all have a chance to go
check out damien's instagram plate have
a click on there because it is quite
impressive um there are some beautiful
flowers to check out what do you use or
do at the end or in general
what's your kind of mentality
and theorem when it comes to finishing
the finest flower that you can
so
my school of thought you know i follow
in the footsteps of guys who you know
know more than me and you know that you
know chaz has been cultivating in
organics long long before i had him so
you know i i align completely with
everything he says um
you know at the end of my
cycle i'll top dress with like
leonardite or like a fulvic acid
and i'll water that in
um to like help chelate
some
potential heavy metals out of my plants
and i've had
uh
like i'm not testing so i i can't really
i'm not testing a control so i couldn't
really say it's making a difference
there but what i can say is like
um as far as like my curing goes and my
white ash like i'm able to achieve
a white ash faster
uh when i use a fulvic
at the end of my flower versus
uh
like
not using that same problem
so i mean i think that
you know very similar to what chad said
in the very same vein i mean i remember
when i started growing i was you know
full advanced nutrients i was running
the full program with the boosters and
you know my
you know my thoughts were you know the
more money i could put into my reservoir
the more money i was going to get out of
that room and you know it took me many
years to kind of figure
out that wasn't true and you know i
flushed then and
you know like i you know i didn't really
have controls back in the day but i can
tell you that i was feeding so heavy
that you know i i did have nitrogen
toxicity and
it probably was a bit necessary but
um you know
it's
it's a bit of you know how i look at
this is a bit of different strokes for
different folks but like i completely
you know i have a tremendous amount of
respect for manny and i know you know
how much time he's put into this craft
and
so you know i i i believe he's got a lot
of great points there too but as a as a
living soil grower like you know just
top dressing some some amendments
that'll help
you know
bring things out of the plant is about
all that i do
towards the end of my cycle
i think there's a huge variation between
when you look at kind of when growing in
like a four by four bed and then when
you're going in a three gallon pot um
and that that what how you want to
finish that plant especially when you're
doing
these type of systems i mean i'd love to
jump over and and
have a talk
with anita about how she finishes how
she likes to finish off her plant and
kind of
her opinions on what consumers find
to be a high quality
flower and what their opinions are on
kind of is this a is this white ash
thing uh a little bit more of a
of a head of a classical grower type of
stuff or is it something you hear on the
streets on a regular basis i'd love to
hear it
for sure um thanks for
watching
um i um personally i'm actually similar
with like in the way that i do
like organic like gardening and so i
don't brush at all um i just
mix the soil at the beginning i'm using
organic
as much as i can like my own compost and
i have a
worm uh farm that
i started yeah i gotta work from my
backyard um and
it's uh
it's
really for me it's just a lot easier
so you know and i noticed that some
sides you know get a little bit
um
they start getting a little bit more
like you know meeting more nutrients or
whatnot and then i'll i'll uh add
amendment as i go during flower but um
yeah usually i just kind of let it go
and and just keep an eye on it the first
year i i drew though um
and it all
happened and like
heartbreaking but huge lessons that were
learned that year um but yeah for under
the consumer side yeah white ash that
kind of idea definitely you know
thinking that i hear um from people that
are teasing um consumers that have been
part of the
community for some time um so yeah they
look for the white ash and
the rings
um
on the joints or whatnot but i think
that
most consumers that especially new ones
or ones that
don't
even know there are different screens
really like
they
think beyond it but those kind of type
of people i think they do appreciate it
like a good finish because they don't
understand what it is that they're
appreciating um they like the smoothness
of it and it's not hard or
um those kind of things those are the
descriptors that they would use um from
like
somebody that's
a layman i guess um but yeah definitely
it does matter um
i've
seen products out there that doesn't
burn very well it looks nice looks great
uh it doesn't burn well uh it looks
kind of nasty when it's burning and um
it doesn't taste good
so it goes from something that could
have been potentially beautiful um
because you know the trichomes are all
there and everything but
for some reason it wasn't finished
properly or it was
too late or and you know it oxidizes in
the jar or it's been sitting there for a
while that's a huge problem in our
industry right now um the amount of time
that
product is getting
so you can have a perfect finish um have
it in a perfect type of a container so
to protect the integrity of the bud um
and then it sits there
for a while and it continues to oxidize
in the jar um so your perfect bud now is
not so perfect and so there's a lot of
challenges there um i don't have any
answers for those um other than you know
we need to start speaking cannabis um as
a fair triple product instead of a dance
product like how we are um i have been
this week i've been going around um
trying to find an old product for the
companies i work with
um and buying them um because
i don't i don't want stuff out there um
that
you know a year old that that's saying
to me but there's no there's no
you know anyway that's another topic all
together but um for finishing yeah it
does matter to people but some people
know why it matters some people just
like the final product it's like you
know fine wine or whatnot you can have a
cheap bottle of wine that tastes great
and everything like that um you have an
expensive one that doesn't
doesn't actually taste that great and
but they don't really know what's going
on or why um but yeah i think that it
sells faster you get a better um return
customer when there's a good thing
and that
you turn customers on a regular basis
what you want you don't want somebody
just try at once you're like well that
was fun
anyway
awesome that was an amazing way to
respond that question i really
appreciate that anita i wanted to before
we get too far away from where because
we were talking about leonardi and and
humic there for a little bit
and i know at the end of flower
and in a lot of systems a lot of the
nutrients that are there and available
aren't chelated and they're not quite as
as bioavailable to the plant at all
points in time so i'd love to give the
opportunity over to leah to talk a
little bit about what like humic and
phobic can do at the end of flower like
jameson was speaking about using um to
to what what exactly it would do there
in the process or how how it might help
the plant at the end of the flowering
cycle
thanks london
um
well i think understanding what huma can
falvik are and i appreciate that jamison
noted that he was using letter diet
because there's different sources that
you can extract humic and fulvic acids
from
these are natural organic acids that can
be
extracted naturally from these highly
decomposed layers of earth
and the sort of the far-reaching
decomposed layered before it turns into
a hardened coal like what you would burn
is leonardite and date is very soft and
crumbly and you can extract uh humic and
fulvic acids which are organic compounds
out of that decomposing matter
the benefits of human can fulvic really
well let's first start with fulvic acid
is actually a part of the humic acid
molecule when it's extracted differently
using a different extracting method it
can be extracted extracted separately um
humic acid typically is going to be
negatively charged much like your
growing medium and if you're in
a hydroponic system
whether or not you're using soil inert
media or living soil the concept is
still the same
if your root zone is going to be
negative is typically negatively charged
and it draws in positively charged ions
or your nutrients
fulvic acid on the other hand is
positively charged but interestingly
it's high in oxygen so it actually
chelates nutrients extremely well and
because it's such a small molecule it
can actually trans transfer through
cell walls so that means that it can
actually drive up with that nutrient as
a transporter basically it's like wheels
on your on your nutrients and there's
lots of nutrients that are immobile
meaning the plant can't move them around
once it's taken them off they kind of
get stuck in the plant that's where
sometimes you find nutrient deficiencies
in your fan leaves but your new growth
looks great or your new growth is
looking deficient but your fan leaves
look great well it's usually indicative
of a certain type of nutrient immobile
nutrients that are
becoming deficient
so fulvic acid in particular is a really
interesting component to nutrient
programs
for the main reason that it is oxygen
rich it does chelate to lots of
different types of nutrients both
positively and negatively charged
and and it helps to mobilize those
nutrients throughout the plant so from
the soil for whatever your nutrient
programming is whether you're using
compost teas if you're using synthetics
and salts or you're using a combination
which a lot of growers are getting into
more hybrid type situations
folic acid in particular will actually
help the plant mitigate deficiencies and
help mobilize those nutrients to where
the plant needs them but also making
them more bioavailable in the soil
fulvic acid really should be
complemented with a humic acid because
humic acid being a negative charge holds
on and attracts to those nutrients for
when the plant is ready to take them in
it also holds onto water so if you're
dealing with drought conditions or maybe
your temperature goes off or your ph
goes off they can all sort of mitigate
some of those concerns and those
stressors so really it's almost like a
buffer program for your nutrient program
it doesn't replace your nutrients but it
really helps the nutrients that you're
putting into your system become more
readily available be retained better
within the media so that you're not
losing it to leachage or in certain
outdoor situations to gas off if you're
in an
outdoor environment you know nitrogen
tends to be a lot more volatile
so the combination of the two is
i think something you start to see if
you see nutrient products that say
organic acids in it generally they're
using
some form of a humic or a fulvic acid um
and there's an array of different
quality of humic and fulvic acids also
so understanding a little bit more on
that side is i think
important to this part of the
conversation with in terms of nutrient
availability if that was sort of
addresses your question london
yeah i mean we're kind of like it really
points in the direction that it's going
to create that chelation and it's going
to allow those those nutrients that
would be harder for the roots to access
and bring up into the system um a lot
easier um
and therefore kind of maximizing your
dollar at the end because we're talking
about even every time we talk about
adding something in a nutrient a product
anything to our soils this is money that
we're using at that point in time right
like we're using this uh and these em
admins cost money we might be able to
anita it's a fantastic example if you
guys go check out her space she's she's
just vermiculture so she's supposed to
fly in and got her own nitrogen source
and a lot of her nutrients from that
plant um so there are amazing ways but
that costs time and effort so you gotta
understand where these are and something
like a humic and a volvo product like
this can really help
especially the flower get the best and
the max out of uh your system at the
very end and kind of utilize as many
nutrients that wouldn't usually be
available and that's kind of what you've
seen kind of in the outcome jamison
right after using products like uh with
that base
yeah i've seen nothing but positive
results
[Music]
in london if i could add uh quickly just
in relation to the conversation about
you know the topic today about flushing
and just you know water finishing or
whatnot
um
when you use a human canophulvic in your
program interestingly when when you're
having this debate about whether you
flush with water or
how you taper things off um we've also
seen that even if you do do stress tests
with just feeding water that there's
enough nutrients within that media that
it helps the plant taper off in that
finishing stage so you're not
necessarily having to starve your plant
which some people are of that camp
others are more
in the mind of to taper it off and
that's fine you don't necessarily need
to be adding additional nutrients when
you're finishing a plant but the plant
won't be starved per se because those
nutrients are still available within the
media so you're kind of depleting it
not necessarily because you're just not
adding any more to
your program but it those nutrients are
still there it's just whether or not the
plant can access it so
i think jameson you might be finding
that as well is when you use the humic
and the phobics at the very end and the
tail end of that flower stage there's
still enough nutrients within the media
that the plants getting essentially what
it needs and not starving it not
stressing it but you're still getting
that finishing benefit
yeah i mean
my media is
it it's an it's a no-till dead so it
stays the way it is and and continues on
but i i have a question as you know i
was kind of taught that falvik was sort
of down
plant
towards the soil and humic was more
soil
towards the plant and so you wanted to
use a fulvic at the end and not a human
here am i am i not properly educated on
that would you advise using both
um in concert or how would you do that
definitely in concert
the interesting thing about fulvic acid
is it it like i said it binds to the
nutrients so whether you're using it
systemically so we have we have growers
that use uh the fulvic acid strictly
with their compost teas so that they can
make the nutrients within those teas
more mobile and more bioavailable
it's excellent as a foliar as well
because by nature fulvic acid has some
trace to it it's minute but there are
some additives that you can add to it
it's also excellent when you combine it
if you're doing any kind of an organic
ipm it works like a wedding agent and it
helps those additives better permeate
into the canopy and help assimilate into
the plant a lot better so when we
recommend using humic and fulvic humic
for sure in the ground at the root zone
it's the root zone activator it helps to
support that
root development it helps to feed the
biome so if you're using with your
living soil it becomes a carbon nutrient
source for your biome which helps
those populations flourish which is
obviously going to better empower that
nutrient cycling that naturally happens
between root zone and biome
but fulvic can be used 100
in systemically in ground and furrow you
can put it in the ground you can put it
in your nutrient system if you're
running an irrigation or fertigation
system and it can also be used as part
of any kind of an ipm or foliar program
top to bottom
[Music]
so while we have a quick pause here i'm
going to jump in hey everybody welcome
to
the dank hour get growing together where
we talk about uh where we get the
dankest minds and cannabis that i know
together to talk cannabis horticulture
we are having an amazing discussion
right now about finishing the perfect
cannabis plant and i'm not gonna lie to
you all i've done a little bit of a
clickbait here because you know what i
really hate this term flushing and i
hate this ongoing debate that's going on
about how we need to remove this or put
that in now we're talking about
utilizing and maximizing the potential
of our plant at the end part of the
cycle and what each individual does to
create the best outcome that they have
that we've had we've talked with various
experts about their methodologies and
thought processes on how to really
accelerate and create that balance as
best as possible now we were talking a
little bit about no-till
jameson and using humic and phobic
and i wanted to bounce over to mania a
little bit now we
he mentioned this starvation this this
plant um starvation and you mentioned it
before now when we're talking about
flushing often what is what it's talking
about is actually people leech their
plant at the end of flower where they
add so much
water to the medium that is at least a
minimum of threefold of the volume of
the media of the medium
to rinse the plant of nutrients what
would this do to the end of flower i
mean theoretically
you know you see people say oh this is a
good thing the starvation of the plant
causes chlorosis which causes the
breakdown of nitrogen in the leaves
which creates a better tasting plant is
often what is spat out in some
word-shaped format like i am dictating
at this point in time to you manny what
are your like
is that what happens like is that a good
thing does that have any benefit to the
actual flower of the plant what's your
thoughts
the flower of the plant by that point
has our is already been
structured it's already been nurtured
there there's nothing that you're going
to do
that's going to take that away from the
flower i mean we keep saying the flower
is a bioaccumulator as a bio accumulator
you know everything that it's pulled
into
into itself it's not going to release
because you're running straight water
through it no matter how much you're
stressing it or starving it
whatever's there is there it's the
leaves that are gonna that are going to
um
give up before
uh any of that would even go anywhere
near the flower right
[Music]
yeah sorry i left my mic on there
exactly like you the plant is going to
eat up the nutrition and its leaves to
protect the most important part of its
vital system what's the most important
part what's the plant always trying to
do it's trying to reproduce right manny
so these are the buds the calyx that's
not gonna pull nutrients from that spot
that would be ridiculous that's right
that is that is this the sex of the
plant and it is going to do everything
in its power to sustain
that sexual uh part of itself for
reproduction because that's you know
that's its life that's what it wants to
do so by you know running straight water
for even three weeks it's not going to
do anything to the bud whatsoever it's
it's it's unfortunately uh you know
some people like to say bro science i
mean i'm just going to say it's an old
wives tale you know that
people started telling each other that
that would was working but you know as
we've
learned more about the plant and learn
more about the biology of it we can now
see that that type of thinking isn't
correct at all and it's you know it's a
point of argument for a lot of people
that swear by it but
i can provide all kinds of documented
scientific evidence which shows
that it's absolutely useless even the
the definition of the plant as a
bioaccumulator spells it out for you
that no
flushing isn't going to do anything for
it um unfortunately
you know
i'm not saying those people are doing
anything wrong to their plants because
really they're not but the thought
process that they're using isn't correct
[Music]
i think you touched on like a really
awesome point josh go ahead there before
you speak but just beforehand i just
want to touch on that that really
important point that you dictated there
is that we are all growing and there are
all things even when you have huge or
vast amounts of experience that it's
it's it's important to have that open
mind to other ideas and manny just said
it so well there's nothing wrong with
doing that if that's what you want to do
but i'm going to do it this way right
and this is why and i think that's
really important that's why i love this
panel of experts i'm just going to give
you guys all an awesome shout out chad
jameson and manny joshua and corey
because you guys do that you guys have
this awesome conversation but show that
there's a reason for it and that this is
our thought process but this is why you
could or someone otherwise so really
thank you so much for having that open
point of protection josh i appreciate
you holding on for me for a moment going
not a problem at all i just wanted to
also add there i think uh you know
potential reason this
you know issue had come up like i
remember when i was a young grower i
you know being the skeptic decided you
know i'm gonna test this
you know flushing or not flushing
because back then i i flushed my plants
um
but back then you know like it didn't
dawn on me that i should be feeding the
plant based on its stage of growth so i
was just like well i'm just gonna keep
beating it in week seven and eight and
nine the same way i have you know in
four five and six
um so at that point you you know i was
giving the file way too much nutrients
for what it needed and that's why it
accumulated so much and had such a
terrible finish as opposed to the
product that i had flushed
now
you know after having learned more about
the plant and you know learning how the
growth stages work and what the plant is
requiring in those stages um
you know i have
i mean the the ptr that i put on there
was from a sample
that i'd take we'd taken samples that we
eight nine and ten
um
the the plant just to see which you know
week was best for that particular
cultivar um but that said and this is
from the week 8 at the week 8 it was
still getting
almost it's
like almost it's full nutrients uh week
nine had gotten dropped down to a much
lower rate and we kind of was still at
that much lower rate
um
but i mean you know four i mean this
isn't perfectly white but for you know a
week eight was
you know still having quite a decent
amount of nutrients um i think it's
important to note that like the dry and
the cure also really have an impact on
the final product um
you can still like the flavor in this
you can tell that there was you know
that little extra nutrients
comparatively to the the week nine and
week ten samples and the terpene
profiles are also different
um so yeah i just wanted to kind of add
that you know
sometimes people might be thinking that
this you know the alternative to
flushing is giving a full feed which you
know that's not entirely the case you
know you got to feed it based on the
stage of growth that it's in
and thank you
[Music]
i said yeah and what you're feeding
really matters i think like
it when you're looking in our beautiful
organic bands like jameson and chad's
are working in the plant has this
ability to pull
what is necessary when it needs it and
and able to
figure out everything else otherwise
right uh that makes it really quite a
bit cory are you available would you
like to chat a little bit i know you
were on a phone call a little bit
earlier um are you available now
nope okay
well that's fine we will continue
forward anyway so we were talking um
about flushing and finishing our
cannabis plants we'll talk a little bit
about my
thought process on it because i
something
the other people in this room is i kind
of do
i'm kind of closer to what manny does as
in i do organic and hydroponic kind of
together and then i use ammonium-based
nitrogen as well as
organic
nitrogens and teas and stuff like that
to really boost
the plant up as much as possible
so no that wasn't uh no you're good um
i'm just
doing my little ones crying so i got a
little bit sidetracked there and
distracted my apologies guys so i'm just
kind of running through what i do um so
i'm doing i do as three gallon pots and
my idealism is that i can create as much
life
into these pots as possible and the
plants going to take what it needs but
also has everything that it has in it
now i've tried
different cover crops to do
and allow for higher
doses of nitrogen such as clover i find
you get a lot larger of a blood bud um
at the finish
um where if you use things like acilium
which are little flowers they can create
a smaller bud because they're sucking a
little bit more nitrogen out but when it
comes to the last part of the end of my
cycle is i tapered down my nutrient
system a lot i'm probably running close
to what manny runs maybe a little bit
higher at about 200 ppm but i'm also in
a drain to waste hydroponic system so
every time i i water i water with about
10 runoff and check my ppm and that's a
great dictation i think it's important
to know that there are even some
um
strains and and phenotypes that really
if you over feed it can be way more
detrimental than if you under feed and
some plants just love to eat you can
just give them as much nutrients as
possible and really push them up to you
know 30 to 2800 ppm at their highest in
mid to mid flower like you can really
push them up high
and that's great but trying to
maintain when you have a plant that
can't take those high ppms and trying to
push it up all the time isn't
necessarily the best way to go sometimes
reducing them can be and then it's a
cost point right if you're putting
depending on the amount of nutrients
that you're putting into your system is
coming out so that's why when i do a lot
of like gallon pot work where you have
uh drainage it's okay to check your ppms
on the way out and see kind of what
they're sitting at i always have 10
runoff i know that's a little bit
backwards because i'm doing hydroponics
and organics but i find this way i can
really tally and find out how much is in
and being rinsed out of the stem holiday
plant is taken up it's really really
helpful and that's the big learning
curve i think that
organics is so challenging for a lot of
people is because you have to plan and
work ahead um yeah i mean jamison your
bed is like immediately ready to go
right after right after your flowering
cycle is done so you can pop right on
top of it maybe amend a little bit what
do you do
in the transition period from the end of
flower to the last one to uh to running
your next round in the same bed
what's your flip what's your transition
there
[Music]
i'm still learning soil biology so what
i'll do is i'll go to a l labs here in
canada i'll get a soil test and then i'm
lucky to have friends like you know
jazz or like lately i've been working
with joshua stevensland who's you know
analyzed soil tests for me since back in
the day um and then sort of work with
him to
figure out the right strategy for an
amendment the top amendment and then
water in and just roll like you know you
can clamp in and then sort of send your
test off and amend it after so
um
you know you don't need a lot to get
those starts going so yeah i mean i'm
still learning i'm you know only on my
third
you know third year of doing this so
it's uh you know the living soil is just
a wormhole that you you know continue to
go down
[Music]
what about yourself chaz what are you
what are you doing in between
[Music]
uh i do something similar as jameson
does uh
you know depends on
you know sometimes i'll skip a a cycle
um you know if it's just my homegrown to
get it tested but i try to get it tested
so i'm not
um
adding more of something that doesn't
need to be in my soil
because it's really about keeping
each element
uh
you know your
micro and macro nutrients
in the proper ratios within your soil
for your plant to uptake them correctly
so
if
you just keep on blindly amending over
time
you don't know what the plant is
utilizing and where your bed stands and
you can
run into issues that then might require
a lot more
fertilizer to bring up the ratios into
the correct level than you would have if
you um
if you would have just you know as you
went
check your soil
through laboratory testing and keep it
within those
the sort of
ranges and if you are getting your soil
tested um you'll get a lot of different
opinions on
you know who's got good lab testing my
advice on it is uh just stick with the
same one that you're going with and um
and go from there
because you'll
each each lab is calibrated differently
and if you go from one to another
uh
you won't be able to
interpolate understand your data um
over time because it will be skewed
so just stick with one lab so you get
the big screenshot of what their
testing is like and uh and you can
adjust accordingly
and i'm done
[Music]
that sounds like exactly what i like to
point out at all times that is always
about creating community a bit around
you i mean if you're going to choose a
soil
company that's going to test your soil
out on the regular basis stick with them
and go through them we're all developing
businesses thing happen just because
there's one error one time doesn't mean
you should bounce around immediately
don't get me wrong there are crappy
businesses out there so definitely make
the right decision that depends on you
but i i think where it's about community
giving maybe a smaller guy a chance once
in a while is very important in this
space um i mean you guys all let me
bring you here to this wacky weird
tuesdays and we all have a lot of fun so
it's actually we're at the top of the
hour so what we usually like to do is is
end our recorded session at about this
time and then bounce over over to the
garden party room to have a conversation
however i do like to allow
any of the moderators that have any
closing
statements that they wanted to say
before we go over to the garden party
room i hope you all come and join us
that's the show after the show where
everybody comes up on stage and we have
a great conversation about cannabis and
become a community you can talk about
anything you want up there just be
polite and join the conversation
appropriately uh but anyways do any of
the moderators if you want to flash mic
and let me know if there's any closing
statements you would like to bring up
otherwise we will shut down the room and
pop over to garden party and and
continue this delightful conversation on
cannabis horticulture
nope well think thank you each and every
one of you i appreciate you we are here
every tuesday at five o'clock pacific
standard time to six o'clock pacific
standard time uh every single tuesday on
the dank hour club so click the little
greenhouse click the follow click the
like check it out join us over on the in
the dank hour club uh garden park
cannabis garden party which is open
going to open just shortly we also do
another show on saturdays with rj where
we talk about uh post harvest uh
processing um consumer packaged goods
and what happens to canada's plans when
we make extractions and the process the
answer of the thought process because
that is an amazing in-depth area
afghanistan that we don't get a lot of
options to talk to and that rj down
there is our resident expert and we have
some other amazing people coming on we
have our some guests coming in as guest
speakers as well so we're going to keep
it quiet but stay tuned stay excited and
stay entertained and educated thank you
all for being part of the dank hour i
appreciate each and every one of you and
come over to the garden party i'll see
you there guys thanks again ciao
[Music]
so
no no no no
[Music]
hello
god
[Applause]
me
[Music]
you