[Music]
welcome the blue stream aquaculture this
is our cape cod facility
built in the 1860s
as a trout hatchery
uh it's where we me and my family call
home and we call the home of fish brew
this is where fish brew started
our first three products bold flow and
epic flow are derived from this farm
as you can see
this is an old style flow-through
farm
with some updates with solar our solar
canopies do two things for us they
provide us with energy these panels
actually store the energy in batteries
so at night time we're we're on battery
power uh the these solar panels operate
and run about 85 percent of our energy
use that we need year round
they were installed five years ago
as you can see some of these some parts
of this hatchery are are
older than others this part of the
hatchery was actually originally used as
a tannery in the 1700s
the old stone race old stone wall
around it this this tank this pond here
houses our rainbow trout
and as we walk through the hatchery
we'll see more updates these raceways
here were reinstalled about four years
ago we tore out the old wooden raceways
but we kept the sand bottom
raceways
as you can see
our wells
putting water into the raceways
artesian wells
about 40 35 to 40 feet deep
here's a tank full of rainbow trout
these were fish from two years ago spawn
it's the sand bottoms of these raceways
and the beautiful water that we get from
an under underground sand river that
runs through the bottom underneath the
property that gives us the great quality
of water to start with for raising fish
it also is with the sand bottoms gives
us all the ecology over 160 years that's
been developed that's part really
important to part of our fish group
this race right here travels
all the way down it's about 400 feet
long there's fish in different sections
all the way down depending on years size
and species
over this way we have two undeveloped
raceways that we're in the process of
redeveloping
installing these panels over here these
concrete panels that we poured
that will give us a little more capacity
in the farm
this farm is primarily used for fish
leave here to get stocked
around the state
now we've moved to another part of the
hatchery this part of the hatchery also
older part of the hatchery with with
sand bottom raceways people often ask
how do we move the fish around the farm
and this is the way we move them we have
a stainless steel tank we also use this
for hauling the fish when we deliver
them to people's ponds for stocking
it's battery operated aerator on the
back of the tractor we fill it with
water
add the fish and move it around pull up
alongside the tank pull the valve and
dump the fish in
uh we're moved this time of year is what
during the summer is primarily we're
doing is grading and moving fish getting
ready for fall
uh this tank here is one of our older
raceways uh it's wood lined with a sand
bottom
these fish here are brood stock rainbow
trout
we have about 350 fish in there
we'll start spawning rainbow trout about
mid
august to the end of august
over here is our
hatch house this is where we hatch and
spawn is where we take the eggs
by hand stripping we bring them into
that building and we have incubators in
there where we spawn the fish right now
there's nothing in there because
spawning season is still a month and a
half away
uh this is our experimental greenhouse
um where we do a lot of different
experiments with our fish brew products
we started testing the fish food
products about six years ago
before we at least four years before we
brought them to market
and we'll take a walk inside there but
you can see here some of our outdoor
gardens that have also had been treated
with fish brew
our blueberries which i've seen fish
brew bold and hydrolysate as you can see
they're very large
and this year uh we have
quite a bit of fruit developing on the
on our blueberries
and only being the first week of july
and we'll take a quick walk through our
greenhouse this is our greenhouse where
we do a bunch of different
types of experiments this is a
hydroponic nft where we do testing with
hydrolysate and fish brew epic
same here this is a floating raft
culture
we're doing different stress tests with
plants right now
we have some soil beds that we've
developed
making living soil from our products
we have
tomatoes uh aloe plants
uh in here
we have a variety of plants
these plants here are all on our rise
and thrive products
we're doing a trial in here right now
for growth
stress
and as we move through there's more
tanks in here that have fish
you see these are small rainbow trout
we try to utilize all the farm
um
here's my prized zucchini plant this
year this plant was completely grown on
bold
blue bulb products
no other fertilizers used
as you can see it's a
very healthy plant large
leaves are much larger than my hand
[Music]
we have some dry product that we're
starting to develop
of fish brew
[Music]
it's a very light
product has a very nice um a lot of
properties of npk also has a very nice
for making a compost tea
there's some small brewers that we do
testing with
we'll come around this side of the farm
as we exit the greenhouse
we come out to another system this is
where we collect a lot of our waste for
the fish brew there's a series of tanks
here
it's a flow through
with recirculating components
we have a drum filter where we take off
the waste
water then passes through a biological
filter
water comes in from our pond
um in the front of the hot in the front
of the farm
passes through here the water that is
being introduced by the pond overflows
into another series of raceways on the
back side of the farm but these tanks
here housed
rainbow trout brook trout and brown
trout
all the tanks are covered for netting to
keep the birds away
as we move down here this is a second
system
same thing we have a container where we
harvest the waste
that later becomes our fish brew
this is another drum fill filler there
that's taking the waste off
very slow moving filter constantly
sucking off the waste
putting it into this tank here
which is a thousand gallon holding tank
that we aerate
it's the beginning of this brew
from handle from here this tank it's
transferred into our barn where we have
different brewing rooms
now we're going to enter into one of our
brewing rooms these are located in our
barn on site
these brewing these brewing containers
are both 250
gallons
so we always have on storage at least
500 gallons of the bold product
and then we do all of our bottling and
labeling in this room
we also have our storage for hydrolysate
that we bring from our other farm ryzen
thrive which is our newest one of our
newest products that's a combination of
cape cod farm in new hampshire farm
giving us different bacteria fungal and
protozoa protozoa from the bold product
so we're trying to utilize both farms
and there's the third brewer that has
the rise and thrive
that's a quick overview of our farms um
i want to give you guys a quick we tried
to do it on a podcast we were unable
unsuccessful to keep a
feed going but that gives you a general
overview of what our farm on cape cod
looks like uh we'll be hopefully soon
bringing you
some views of our other farms if you
have any questions please
contact us and follow us on fishbrew.com