[Music]
foreign
today we're sitting here in our 3000
square foot Greenhouse where we do all
of our research with our different
products today I wanted to talk about
bold flow which is one of our products
made here on Cape Cod at our trout
hatchery the trout here are raised for
stocking ponds and with those fish we
extract the waste with a special
filtration system that we've designed
and that waste is our bold World
products this product is full of
beneficial fungi
bacteria protozoa amoebas and some
nematodes and also full diatom which is
a plankton that produces oxygen which is
a key point for our product the diatoms
not only produce oxygen in the water but
also produce oxygen at the root of the
plants they also are great uh
structures for bacteria and fungal to
grow on attached to it also Aggregates
your soil
when the diatoms keep reproducing in the
bottle over as much as two years which
keeps the bottle oxygenated which keeps
the product in the bottle uh aerobic
instead of anaerobic which is key to
this product
this product is concentrated
we recommend for just
watering for container gardening
for raised beds for straight in the soil
gardening whether it's vegetables house
plants or cannabis we recommend 15
milliliters which is
as simple as three capfuls of this
product to one gallon of water this is a
two gallon watering so we would add six
capsules to this watering can and then
water your plants that at a normal
watering rate until you see your soil
gets damp
um
and you have adequate watering do that
once a week with this product regardless
of the age of the plant this product is
also unique from our other products and
that we like to use this product from
seed all the way to harvest and I've
done it with multiple different plants
including this cannabis plant which is
seeded in directly in soil fed bold flow
on day number seven from seating and has
only been on bulb 12 up until today
which is uh the first day of September
and as you see it's in its budding stage
blooming stage so this product can be
used through all stages vegetation and
Bud and Bloom of of all the plants that
we tried it on at this point another
example is this pepper plant this pepper
plant has been getting harvested since
May 15th it's now September 1 and as you
can see it's still loaded with peppers
this is a lunch box or mini pepper plant
and as you can see there's plenty of
fruit still being produced even new buds
here at the top one once again this
plant gets watered once a week with bold
flow at the given rate on the back of
the bottle which is 15 milliliters per
gallon of water
house plants that can be used on house
plants I like to use it during
transplant of house plants so as I'm
going to transplant
this aloe plant and I'm going to break
away you can see the root development on
that plant
pretty extensive root development aloe
plants tend to like to be crowded a
little bit so as this plant gets broken
off
to be separated out to be transplanted
we would do really simple
droot wrench of this product
using the Bold flow so it'd be as simple
as
getting the plant wet you could leave it
in there for five to ten minutes pull it
out transplant into your potting soil
water once a week with the Bold flow in
your and within months your product your
aloe plant will look like this one here
this is a rosemary plant that was also
started from seed that was started from
seed about 28 days ago
also only use bold flow on that from
seed to the stage as you can see the
rosemary plant is thriving
another thing I like to use the bolt
pull for different than some of our
other products is I like to use it for
cloning
cuttings this is a tomato plant this
once again is as simple as
using 100 mils of this product
so that's 30
100 mils of that product
we'll let that sit in this water
out of the direct sunlight preferably
keeping the water temperature cooler
sometimes we'll put a small aerator in
there to keep it aerated this tomato
plant will start to root and be ready to
transplant in 10 to 11 days from today
so what we'll do is we'll place this
plant off to the side and we'll come
back in about 10 days and we'll we'll
see how it's developing we're just using
the Bold flow as a as a cloner
this is another thing we've used it on
this is a ginger plant where we soak the
ginger root in bold flow at a rate of
100 mils a bowl flow to 100 mils of
water we actually did several bulbs this
is just one example of one so this plant
was done about 32 days ago
you can once again see the root
development what I'll actually do is
I'll break this away a little bit
so you can actually see the ginger
so this is the ginger plant this is the
ginger root that was soaked in bold flow
placed in soil
and then later has been watered once a
week with the Bold flow products
and as you see it's it's a really green
bright green getting plenty of nutrients
easy uptake of any other nutrients you
may or may not want to use full flow is
also a product that you can use with
other nutrient products we've tested it
with several other nutrient products and
had good results
um this is a soil conditioner or a plant
probiotic which means it's adding your
living organisms to your soil
um this product and you can go on to our
website
fishbrew.com and you can see uh
different testing results we have with
different products including bold flow
including any testing that we've done
heavy metal testing biological testing
as well as any NPK or testing of that
nature of these of each one of our
products this product here has had great
results with living soil products in
that it's high in bacteria Italian
fungal Italian beneficial protozoa
amoebas as I mentioned diatoms which is
really the key this product gives your
products your plants a nice silica boost
when needed
um
it also it also works very well with
other women products other living soils
that we've tried it on in the past and
and we're still continuing to work on uh
to see how it develops
I liked myself and I'm a little a little
biased and this is one of my favorite
products because I can use it from seed
to start and I don't have to worry about
burning the plants this product is
is a biology product it has plenty of as
I mentioned beneficial bacterium fungi
so you don't have to worry about
nitrogen overload you don't have to
worry about burning the plants if you
get it on the leaves of your plants use
it as a folio spray on your plants it's
not going to burn your plants uh your
plants are going to boiler spray we have
done some work with that we have used it
on a few of our products we're still
doing trials on it the results will be
coming out soon this product has also
been used on Turf it works great on
wands we've had several clients use it
on their wands here on Cape Cod and
they've had very good results especially
this year during a drought it's actually
helped retain water some of them are
claiming it's helped retain water in
their lawns so this product can be used
for like I said for many many different
types of plants can also be be used on
blueberry shrubs it can be used on
rhododendrons we've used it on
hydrangeas there's just a fig trees we
have a fig tree here on the farm that
last year produced over 160 figs this
year we use it on paw paws and and we
saw our pawpaw right now our pawpaw girl
has uh roughly 142 Papas which is kind
of unique here in New England on Cape
Cod but the plants are doing really well
on it
this product here you can use weekly is
what we recommend when you're starting
out as your plant gets developed or it's
a house plant that you know is going to
have many years you can extend it and go
every other week on The Bold 12 products
if there's any questions like I said you
can go to our website where you can find
our contact information