hello again everyone and welcome this is
Ken with peace of mind
farming today we're finishing up the
moon Mountain Kush across to Black a and
headband it's very typical structure of
an indicia about 3 feet in height
uniform spacing and well-worked line an
easy grow for beginners with minimal low
stress training needed in veg
a week or so into flower I did a heavy
defoliation and trim I find this to be
the best time to get your sea of green
or your scrog set
up the turpine profile of the cured
flour is matured into a soapy fuy flowy
with a sour Pine earthy finish these
flavors are very reminiscent of the gold
stand M Hashi Shu PR
911 a brilliant and complex heavy smoke
for my tast and
experiences this Freeborn selections
cultivar is very heavy relaxing and
sedative High IID suggest this is a
bedtime or an early evening smoke as a
patient I find this heavy OG leaning
cultivar helpful for insomnia pain Le
spasm and inflammation among others this
cul toar by Freeborn selections is good
medicine five out of five for flavor and
effects thank you to the Future cannbis
project and Mean Gene from mandino
Freeborn
selections this is a cultivar you want
it would make a great medicinal
concentrate a taste the market has been
looking for or you may be able to find
it at d.
Garden if you see it on a dispensary
shelf get it before it's gone it won't
last and for those who've yet to
experience old school flavors this is
one for
you go to do. Garden to check out more
freeorn selections cultivars like
subscribe