hey another African sativa field notes
here this is Gambia so we'll need to
we'll pull up a map and show you where
Gambia is so uh but it's October 23rd
and this one is actually very close to
being finished uh this has more of the
traditional African sativa really sort
of fluffy little Spears going on but the
hairs are all starting to Brown up quite
a bit
um we only grew one of these plants this
year we had they were tougher to
germinate
we do have seeds though to back it up
and uh
this one just kind of has a
sort of
funner kind of smell
um
slightly like uh
old school bubble gum like Bazooka
bubble gums or that spice bubble gum
smell
and kind of like uh
Fabrics off of her like the old pink
fabric softener from like the 70s and
80s there was Liquid I don't like that
substance in a bottle but when it's
coming from a cannabis plant
smells interesting so anyway Gambia very
very cool and we'll be harvesting this
uh before Halloween so right now it's
October 23rd but cool Plant very
primitive primal almost bush bush plant
okay