[Music]
[Applause]
so this is the gemma cert or gamma cert
depending on where you're from
it's a
near-infrared spectrometer that gives
you cannabinoid content readouts as well
as
active water content and it's uh powered
by android so we got this android phone
right here
we are gonna fire up the app and see
what it's like
so i've got some weed here this is just
something from a friend
unnamed farmer unnamed genetic untested
previously but we're gonna test it and
we're going to see what kind of
cannabinoid content we can get
first though i am going to take a bong
rip out of my sovereignty
so what you do is you place this nug
on a magnet with a needle
and that needle holds it in place for
the spectrometer
and then the device does analysis just
on the whole nug i think you can also
use ground flower too but primarily i've
just been testing it out like this so
far
so now i'm going to open the sample
container
so the next step is actually
you take this
and you
pop the sample
in there
and then
you close it
like this
and then on the phone you hit
analyze
all right i've inserted my flower sample
and then it runs analysis
so this is really interesting the
analysis just finished and it gave me a
notice that said
low water activity which makes sense
because it's some pretty dry bud
we're gonna hit
okay
click on our results
okay so it says we have to remove our
sample
some good bud
it's definitely some good bud
all right
now let's check on our results
nice
okay so our total thc for this one was
thirteen point two percent
total cbd was point two percent
total cbg was two percent and our active
water content was under point five five
um
i think gem assert uh is really cool for
doing the active water content that's
really important for uh you know testing
your crop to make sure that you either
don't have molds or you know testing
your dry or other things like that your
cure
but
yeah cool device
um and you know like i said
13 thc on some
beautiful
beautiful dank bud
it's definitely not some swag guys this
is some good butt
so what i find most interesting about
this device and uh i'm about to go in
for another bomber up here
but what i find most interesting about
this device is that it uh offers a
possibly more accurate way to test your
cannabinoids than to go to a lab that
you know in theory is inflating results
to match market trends or hype versus
giving an accurate readout um i think at
first i was
and you know i'm not an expert so who
knows but
at first i was
astounded by how low some of the
thc readouts were
but you know my critical thinking side
of my brain
um
you know
basically led me to believe that
this could be giving
more accurate results and the test
results that we're used to in the high
20s and
30s could be a
fabrication
of what the actual content is i could be
wrong but i've always had a sneaking
suspicion that some of those results are
fabricated especially on the metric
recreational california market
i feel like you know a lot of consumers
are
misled and led to believe that high thc
equals you know good effects or high thc
equals
quality um or just you know
among other you know deceptive practices
that high thc is what you want to be
looking for over any other factors such
as you know
the harvest date or the actual aroma the
terpenes
um you know the
quality of the bud when you look at it
things like that that matter more than
thc percentage
however we do think this is a really
cool device
and we're looking forward to doing more
work with it in the future testing
metric strains doing
comparisons
uh
yeah should be good but shout out to
everybody for watching leave a comment
uh about what you'd like to see us do
with the gem assert and also you know
make sure you subscribe to future
cannabis project and future cannabis
project o2 as well as budgasm and og's
myoxygen on instagram
thanks guys talk to you soon
almost forgot to
take my bong hit before we sign off here
peace out everybody
[Music]