[Music]
foreign
this is the distribution
uh location and then also you're doing
the r d here and the uh
cross them grow them test them keep the
moms throw away everything that doesn't
make the cut
and then you want to walk down the line
here so like lemon chemicalio is
genetics I brought in
then you got laughing gas what's their
genetics we're using to breed with
chauffeur Skywalker Fire OG GDP
Long Valley Royal Kush crossed with
right Rhino manic crosses I've done
uh
white lemon 91 chem cross with thin
mints
um horchata grape grass crosswood banana
Bubba
so there's lots of stuff rents super
runts
Lemon Cherry gelatos rs11s here's some
more of the moms so what we do is when
the moms get about this height yeah I
have them clone them as soon as they we
throw them away
that way I'm not setting myself up for a
lot of problems with big moms
uh so as soon as the next one Roots
you'll throw yeah we'll throw these moms
away and start our moms over yeah so
every and typically how many clones do
you root out just to make sure you have
redundancy
well two two because we're pretty
consistent so we take two of each once
one Roots we replace it that's kind of
what those are your Replacements those
are also The Replacements and our system
is is when there's a hole punched in the
tag that means they're cloned up there
sorry when there's oh when you punch
them yeah so that's our way to keep
track of what's been cloned and what's
going to be exchanged out
and the plastic over the lights is
because
plants have a hard time handling the
amount of light these put out what these
are Nano locks yeah
and if you don't clone under these
lights and you clone under fluorescence
you get really bad Lumen shock
so we went through some Lumen chalk so I
diffuse the lights with plastic now that
they're coming back we'll get rid of the
plastic and start cloning under the LEDs
only not the fluorescence and so kind of
you were saying before like the goal is
for you to you know do breeding and
selection and find some cool unique
stuff that no one else has and then so
that way they're not all selling the
same stuff they have their own unique
stuff
and so yes these are the latest crosses
Germany
biscotti sherberts and rents and Lemon
Cherry gelatos and rs11s and laughing
gas and sour monkeys and punk rock rent
crosses all kinds of stuff
these are all feminized
kind of LA's finest stuff
and then we'll germ here plug them and
then they'll come you can follow me over
here they'll come into this our flower
room
this is where we do the flowering yeah
which I can see this is the r d flower
room because you guys have the like once
you select stuff once we select stuff
the campus in Desert Valley Hot Springs
and it's the same lights the same same
lights yeah
yeah we only have to run four lights and
we're learning to do a whole tray it's
plenty
and so when are you next gonna uh put
stuff in here so their next session is
we'll clean this all out we're gonna
plug those little suckers in six inch
cubes and start rocking them
and then we'll run all these four tenths
full to find the winners out of there
and you have to do the hard job of
smoking at all oh yeah it's all
downstairs the last Harvest we haven't
even got through that yet that's what
some of these are the kind of pots I
like uh
especially outdoors in La where
everything Peaks
yes
plants are getting big so we threw them
in there but normally I like to use a
rock wolf because it's pretty quick and
I can flush them really good yeah
yeah and then is there kind of a balance
between like 2 you know you have some
stuff that's pretty hypey but then also
some of your stuff which is you know I
view it like
the top pop 40 song meets like the 70s
like obscure well what you may like and
what I may like it doesn't necessarily
means it applies so Joe and Derek have
an idea of their clientele so they gear
they help me gear my breeding towards
their Club what they think their
clientele is going to want yeah
very cool I mean we got old stuff from
Colombians the jalalabads there's a lot
of stuff in here yes some of the older
stuff
um we have the jalalabad star
I just crossed it to Lemon Cherry gelato
so we have a couple of those seed
increase of that for uh xc2
and manic calios or stuff we did that's
downstairs to see if we like them
and again these get trimmed down a lot
because they grow so fast and we're not
trying to make a bunch of clones we only
send a couple clones down there and then
they mom them out yeah
yeah what else do we have
manic Kelly
yeah
is the stuff you brought for me up here
can we walk through that up here do we
have to go that's right here
so you got that's sweet
and some garlic kief smell the kief even
is pretty crazy
and this is from one of the lines this
is the Garlic skunk that one of the
Mills guy did a b Mills from Humboldt
washed it
and was like freaking say like dude this
is some of the skunkiest stuff I've ever
tried it's super good I want to bring
you something I was like killer
and this is some of the dry Siff garlic
skunk that I made
yeah
pretty Reiki huh
so then you got some Albert walker dog
Albert Walker
and I put the labels on the bottom so
sometimes if you put them on the lids
you get the lids confused yeah so I go
with
super deep fire
Colombian Haze
two of the different females
[Applause]
and then you got these
all right so let's I love the uh
the uh I stoled it from a 50s
like total it's like the early James
Bond like if you're reading the James
Bond books like or Hardy Boys or
something these are like they're not
Party Boys edgy adult comics in the 50s
yeah because everyone has to do with
chicks that are hot right I just love
the artwork like the pinup style artwork
this is the fun zone is I
don't know this is the super D CrossFit
Albert walker dog
super D these two crossed
uh this so This cross with that yep yep
okay and then this Fino Hunter
you know Hunter is the Albert Walker
James Bond heads to the Casbah right yep
that's the Albert Walker across with the
super d
okay and then you got the tiger eye
which is a scene increase of the Albert
Walker OG dog
down in that angle
yeah and then you got the Albert Walker
across that Albert walker dog which is
this one
and Albert Hitman is just a seed
increase of the Albert Walker
so that's great awesome
I think
very cool
yeah and some of these are pretty
pretty impressive little nuggets
yeah that's awesome
stinky
and this one was the Albert walker dog
so that would probably be your next
question I have no idea what dog these
are seeds from Canada Cabana from about
2010. yeah so
[Applause]
probably pretty controversial this just
reminds me of a 100 NL
it's a complete NL structure
trimmed and untrimmed
yeah
this one was one of the different
females a little more leavey but it's a
little more
kind of odds out
that smells awesome
a bit structure everything to me was
just screaming NL and it kind of makes
sense because it's from Pacific
Northwest right so it's very possible
and then what was this one this was the
uh Albert walker dog
oh gee
Albert walker dog Albert walker dog OG
and then do we have a we had a straight
Albert Walker right that's that one that
was the one I think is screaming in now
really mm-hmm
like maybe a NL four-ish three maybe
not too short but kind of short
it's got the hybrid texture the same
leave texture Brax Jai is a little
golden kinda
just I'm not ever familiar with an NL it
smelled like that but although I haven't
tried all the NLS either
and then how would you describe kind of
Colombians in general
um like from the how they grow in bud
structure and
we'll get to those right now so let's
look at these real quick super D fire
this is what made the garlic skunk some
of the parents and this is probably my
desert island weed any of the garlic
sunk or this stuff especially if you
squeeze one of the nugs yeah
oily super strong
just skunk
gas and some other kind of greatness
so I had a couple phinos out of the haze
one's a little more
foxtaily smells a lot more like Cali
Mist kind of sour acrity and then this
one's a little more dense with the
redder hairs probably a punto Rojo
possibly
and this has a little more of the
frankincense clove type of Honey Thing
if you really squeeze one you can really
get it
and that's most likely is what
made the original Haze before it goes to
Amsterdam
especially these little guys
yeah
and it's pretty Cali Misty sour kiwi
tropical acrid
yeah no I definitely have the tropical
and unsurprising it's got some good kick
to it
it does work for being wet from 1977 45
something year old seeds
you're covered because you like to do
dabs and then there's a little Keith and
you can do bong tokes joints whatever
it is huh
so yeah that's your power pack setup
I love it do we have the uh did the
canisters come in or not yet
for the Kona Gold yeah I haven't ordered
them yet okay okay still in limbo I have
the Kona Gold at home but
all this is better
it's a lot like Mexican so I'm a little
worried with when people grow the seeds
they're going to be like oh
but on the same hand that's what it was
yeah I can't make it better than it was
but like compared to this
this is like wow smell wise all that
stuff right
but yeah I made a whole lot of seeds uh
I got a lot of them
so these are kind of odd because you
kind of get a Jackie train wrecky
Southeast Asian sharp sour
I notice a lot of the Southeast Asian
strains have that kind of sharp sour
thing astringent
real astringent
and same with this guy too that's the
other thing when you trim all the purple
leaves off that's what you end up with
green nuggets
so it's probably more of a lumen shock
or stress than genetic purple
this stuff though just so
sticky greasy oily
just like a chem structured nug
maybe not D but 91 and four
and the smell is incredible and those
suckers is this the same stuff that's
Albert Pier
it's Unique and different
we were talking about Albert Walker the
other week right
I don't know much about it that's not my
story to discuss all I know is
dirty 40 year old strain from Pacific
Northwest clone only they think it's an
Afghan skunk or something of that nature
but right there's fairy tales everywhere
who knows
all right well I'm excited
plus looks is one thing now you gotta
test drive them right
that's like hot looking chicks you're
all stoked you finally got the hot
chicken you get her home and she's just
like a boring piece of wet
Wonder Bread or something in bed
so my goal is super modern polar Stars
they got to be freaking bad yeah super
good looking and wild in bed that's the
whole package so that's my my breeding
goals
if it's good no flavor no punch it's got
to go if it's strong with no flavor It's
gotta go
I made some other [ __ ] I think it's
downstairs it smells 100 like Chinese
food oh you mentioned it yeah let me see
if I can find that stuff
I don't like it but it's such a unique
smell I like it
so this is when
of the pollen donors
that's biscotti sherbert
to say that again this is wet I reversed
a biscotti sherbet for a pollen donor so
this is the h15 is biscotti sherbert
give it a whiff
yep
so that's kind of why I went for that
this is
semantic Irene
oh that's not a good one
super Frosty super gnarly
kind of like a GMO real Frosty
indica-ish kinda
I like this one I've got some roadkill
to it
skunk
that's the white lemon 91 camel cross
with thin mints
firecracker burnt rubber
candy gas
yeah there's a there's a lot of stuff in
here let's just find some good one
there they grow bags
what's up Manny this is Peter Peter
I think that's maybe a wrench or
something
yeah
yes this is a garlic skunk
and so this is all this stuff you guys
are hunting through right now yeah
that's where you just pulled this is my
favorite plant right now that's my
garlic skunk
yep
it's like one of the closest to skunk
that has garlic in it
so this is that yeah
right I uh
these are the parents went and made this
all right so this this is the same as
the uh yeah so the Keef is actually that
yeah the super deep fire is the parents
that made that
yeah it's the same thing without the
garlic the super deep fired
and then which one's the Chinese uh I'm
looking for that still
for bugs
it's the mom plan or the Clones I said
I'm on the black table Roger
one of these is the Chinese
foreign
cabbage grease The Wonton Wrapper but
when you smoke it it's kind of orangey
sour it's actually super good when you
smoke it
yeah it's I smell I've never smelled in
the weed world before ever
yeah of course
I think we got some Ziplocs right here
[Applause]
and so this the one that one smells uh
manic patio three
and I also made some of these
Albert Walker garlic skunk seeds and
those are going to be epic
and there's also there's a Sharpie zip
locks we got plenty of stuff to
throw your goods in why not as I brought
uh I've been talking to these guys I was
like we need to make a uh
like whenever you're at an event and
someone gives you a nug just like
would be cool if they made these but
they had little dividers so if someone
gave you a nug you could slide that one
in there and then you could keep your
little nug separated
something like this like white that you
put red on
laughing gas I like this one got a lot
of sourdie to it
that's awesome
can I try that yeah
get your bag and throw LG on there
I mean your zip lock right there
not bad for an old and out of touch dude
huh
I mean
it's uh hindu's making funnies that's
all right sarcasm I laugh uh
it's funny to see oh Jesus what's uh
what's happening
is this laughing ass yeah
it's a little one but that's that 2012
white lemon 91 thin mint you got to try
that one that's the one that gunpowder
skunky candy stuff
so 2012 was a strain I made in 2012 and
it was the White Cross My Lemon crossed
with 91 chem
and that's what I called 2012 because it
was 2012 and everybody thought the world
was going to end so I figured oh I get
to play off that
so this was 2012 what
2012 cross Thin Mints
good
manic kalio number four
so that's Mana Calio number two I number
two
so
when you are selecting through these
what did you like about them too
it's not as it doesn't have that
obnoxious smell and if you tip some of
the buds there's res in all over your
hands this caked with resin and it's got
a nice clean little orange smell to it
[Applause]
trying to find this um so this is all
from the last round yeah okay
how many different lines do you hunt uh
I think we had 32
yeah smell that one
minute I mean Anna Kyrene number four
smell that sucker
super FR like your hands are just caked
with powder resins all over the place
some form the original Girl Scout
cookies that's
all smaller nuggets and was this from a
clone yeah
it's really good
and so what would you do as something
like this in terms of the market like
would you cross it with yeah I hit it
with the biscotti sherbet and the Lemon
Cherry gelato
and those where we're gonna grow next
and that's some of the seeds that are
like this is a laughing gas White Rhino
manic that I made the round before oh
wow
we all do most everything is pretty
Frosty
now this is
what was it laughing gas
cross with white wino manic
manic
the manic clone
manika some crazy clone that's similar
to OG and chem but it pre-dates them and
some punk rockers in Santa Barbara had
it and I only know of Oregon kid had it
and loved it and Fletcher had it a long
time ago and did some breeding with it
but not many other people have this
thing
yeah that's
very tropical
actually
and so what are you most excited uh
in terms of expectations of all those
seeds all those in that tray I'm very
excited about if you had to pick one
that you're most one of your children
that you're most excited about about the
potential
or most intrigued about it look it's
tough because what I like and what I'm
making for them in the market are two
different things so
oh that's that biscotti Sherbert it's
pretty it's got some zap to it
I think that might be trying to find a
Lemon Cherry gelato have you smelled
that one yet
nope
it's number 275 laughing gas
oh and it gets tough babysitting all
these strains man I'm like a teacher
with 80 kids in the class
I gotta remember all their names what
they eat all this stuff and then does
stuff get kept for long term
like if you guys you know thinking if
you're you're drawing for the commercial
Market it's like rotations but then
maybe sometimes coming back to stuff and
well that's what all those moms are but
at some point you'd have like 800 moms
because you keep
so then work like so if this one is
better then we have to get rid of that
one because this one's better and if
whoever's like like you like a king of
the hill whoever can stay at the top of
the hill and push the other guy out then
that person's out and we move on but it
but it could just be
like I really want the next thing well
the only benefit to that was it's all in
seed form so we could always try to pull
it back because everything is backed up
in seed form yeah so everything
be in seed form
I mean everything we see except for a
couple is all from seed right except for
some of the Clones that I wanted to do
the pollinations with
so this is not a good example of
laughing gas but that's the laughing gas
we have some more somewhere but I this
is one of my favorite I mean Lemon
Cherry gelato I'm sorry
and if you give it a good squeeze
I mean it's got to be it's good because
everybody's using it right now right and
everybody's trying to tease it because
so many people have it that's because
it's just good
so what's something that you
that you would love to introduce to the
commercial Market
that uh
the lemon irrelevant of warm white
people currently like what I'm hoping is
the Lemon Cherry gelato on the
Colombians might make something special
because of the flavor profiles and we
have something really old that's Pierre
sativa with something that's extremely
modern pure Indica usually when you do
the Indica to sativa you get really good
hybrid crosses
so I'm pretty anxious about that I
didn't bring any but the jalalabad star
is amazingly crazy
good loud weed so I did next time I'd
love to
I did a cross of the Lemon Cherry so is
this like the same Irene that's in the
Irene Colombian uh
uh from kagu yeah okay
because it's it's clone only and I think
he got it from
we got it from Radio Ridge and I'm
pretty sure they're pretty reputable
so I kind of like these
like
all around this is really good weed
there's something for everyone
the garlic skunk I really like
so this is the number three the number
four
some manic yeah
all right
if I have some work to do
we have more downstairs but here's some
of the previous rounds
of all the seeds we've made
oh cool
and there there's a lot
and then I got about the same amount
downstairs in one of those rooms
so example that's how I do the crosses
RS 11 h15 we put them in little jars
with the tags
sorry Where was the rs11
and so here you have this is my system I
Mark the branches that I pollinate yeah
top is the plant that I pollinate bottom
is the pollen Donaire yeah that gets
clipped on the plant yeah Branch gets
harder and then those are the seeds from
we Harvest that branch and then pull out
the seeds and put them back in their jar
so we know
what's going on
example this one has a lot more
yeah some pollen takes a little more
some plants are a little more fertile
than others
so that's laughing gas cross with lemon
Cherry gelato
and then the branches
yeah what I do is I get the hole punch
and cut a thing and then attach it to
the branch oh God I gotta get it so when
I look in there I know where the branch
is
and then I have a map so if any plants
are next to it and I see seeds in there
I know what pollen it was because that
tag is next to that plant yeah
so we don't have any problems with
cross-pollination or nothing
yeah so you just get a
r d all day yeah just keep knocking them
out right use my knowledge and their
knowledge collect those genetics cross
them and see what we get
[Music]