ah
yes
when you wake up
and you feel like you need a little
upper
or when you're down and out
and you need to get a little higher
if you feel like you need a blessing
and you feel a little high today
welcome to the church
welcome to cali high episode 37 i'm your
host chen zoniko this week cali high
revisits episode 37 with rocky dewoony
in our collaboration with the future
cannabis project de winnie's latest
album voices of boon bon has been
nominated for a 2022 grammy in the
category of best global music album and
this is duluni's second grammy
nomination dewoony is a ghanaian singer
and songwriter and while his roots are
in the african styles of high life and
afrobeat dewooney often plays reggae as
well and his 2015 album branches of the
same tree was nominated for best reggae
album
his videos are cinematic masterpieces
and we feature two in this episode we
talk about his music growing up in ghana
the first time he ever heard of bob
marley song his muses for certain tunes
his videos and the state of cannabis in
africa
tune in for an amazing groundbreaking
episode for the cali high backyard
series
good morning
cali high is blessed to be here today
with rocky dewooney ghanaian reggae
artist and grammy-nominated songwriter
for the 2015 album branches of the same
tree rocky welcome thank you very much
uh it is an honor to be here and join
you
in this beautiful nice cool place it's a
beautiful day and thank you for coming
down to the backyard
so
why don't you tell our listeners a
little bit about where you grew up i
grew up in ghana uh ghana is situated in
the west coast of africa you know a
country of you know a little over 30
million people
ghana was also the first
african country to be independent so
ghana has always been
you know at the forefront of many
amazing innovations and advancement on
the continent and people we like to call
it the gateway to africa and i was born
on a military barracks at the time so my
father
was part of the ghanaian army and at the
same time too he came from a traditional
royal family so i had a you know a
combination of tradition and at the same
time too
[Music]
yes so i grew up you know in an
environment of tradition which i was
getting from
that my my home and then also because my
father was in the military discipline
you know and then at the same time to it
was really at a time when the ghanaian
military was in political power so i
also grew up in an environment that was
politically charged
and all of those elements became
you know a way of seeding who i became
you know and i became you know somebody
who loved music somebody who loved
politics somebody who loved uh engaging
the world and at the same time somebody
who
is proud of the cultural uh
background and foundations that i grew
up from
and
was that
near akra
um i actually uh which is the capital
right
the capital of ghana is accra
uh and then
where i grew up is tema tema is actually
part of accra
so it looked like the malibu of
from the map i was looking at yeah yeah
yeah you know tema was like a place you
know the tema has the port
uh but the parks was a little far from
where the port was and um
first they call it the first infantry
brigade you know so
it was you know it was a very strategic
uh military base for the ghanaian
military you know and you know growing
up there was
you know i it was kind of a very
sheltered environment
but at the same time too
it was a place that i felt uh provided
me the opportunity to
you know grow
uh and be able to
you know learn certain things that have
become very uh key to who i become like
you know you know it's the sense of
discipline the sense of you know
constantly wanting to strive and achieve
and and then also a drive you know that
became a key part of really my musical
journey you know starting from ghana and
building my base in ghana and then you
know expanding my musical reach to
beyond the confines of ghana
and speaking of your musical background
who are your earliest musical influences
well you know their thing was that they
were there was the traditional music so
everybody that grows up in ghana or any
part of africa you are first exposed to
your cultural music because you know our
traditions and culture are very very
deep and we all come from deep tribes
so
my tribal music was something that i was
exposed to earlier on but then at the
same time too i was just exposed to the
music of other tribes you know living in
a tema was an area that was um the
traditional area of grass you know uh
the tribe there it was called the ghans
so gun music was very prominent you
heard it around and then at the same
time two other traditional ghanaian
musical forms were there so those were
the initial found musical foundation and
then there was also high life music
which was kind of ghana's version of the
pop music you know so
my initial heroes were the high life you
know heroes of you know those days you
know so african brothers
uh was one of the first bands that
i kind of gravitated towards and african
brothers their high life variants too
was the foundation
of that style that became popular all
over uh west africa and also was the
musical form that eventually evolved
into afrobeat and all these other styles
that most people right now are hearing
and are used to you know so from then
onwards then i became exposed to uh
reggae music
[Music]
yeah i was just gonna ask you
can you tell us when you first heard
reggae and bob marley so yes um well
what happened was that you know to give
more of a a broader background was that
reggae music
you know ghana has an ancestral
connection to jamaica right and uh also
because of ghana's pan-african history
uh our first president uh kwame nkrumah
was very he he studied here in the
united states so he came back to ghana
uh ghana became the first african
country to be independent so his whole
idea immediately
was connecting ghana to the diaspora
the first president of ghana uh
kwame nkrumah
he was actually named the african of the
millennium
um he
led ghana to
its independence ghana being the first
country in africa to be independent in
one year
1957. oh wow yeah
and when he became president his initial
idea was connecting africa to the
diaspora because he lived in america he
was influenced by
you know the
you know their pan-africanist movement
that was going on here w.e.b
so he wanted to create a model african
country
a lot of jamaicans came from that
geographic area because obviously in
those days we didn't have those you know
it wasn't you know
ordered into different countries that
was a colonial thing that was created
but most jamaicans came from tribes that
were situated in that area
so
ethiopia
it was mostly west africa yeah west
africa yeah and so there was that i felt
that it was like that connection that
uh innate understanding the dna of the
music yeah yeah also could be
comprehended there you know so reggae
kind of took root there
and also the messages that reggae was
you know kind of projecting were about
elevation of african ideals african
culture uh you know uh blackness
empowerment of africa and i think that
because the ghanaian military seen
themselves too as
liberators of the continent
the music took roots there oh wow yeah
so
you know in the barracks you heard a lot
of reggae music you know yeah yeah peter
tosh burning spear you know those early
uh forefathers from the sound were very
very popular there
so obviously bob marley was a very
you know
undeniable presence
and
for me
i was not fully you know i was into
other music i was not kind of aware of
bob marley i had heard the mu i've heard
of his name and all of that but i was
not really a big reggae fan at that time
what changed it was that there was a
military band that used to
do
cover songs
you know so
i was kind of i had kind of
figured out that music was something
that i wanted to do
so i gravitated towards anywhere that i
could find music being played or
anything
so
i i ended up starting to spend time in
the rehearsal space of the military band
so when the album uprising came out
above mali's album they were rehearsing
the album
to
to uh to play them
and the song that i remember i went
there and then they were trying to learn
coming in from the cold
so
from the cold
you know yeah and i remember i was just
like wow that's a really cool song i
wonder who sang it
you know because it had not heard i had
not heard the song but i heard the band
rehearsing it so you know the guy you
know they will start you know and then
the bass line and then how the song
started you know just like this is
brilliant yeah yeah you know so
afterwards i was like wow that's bob
marley you know and so that led me into
you know the music
and
not long afterwards
you know bob passed on yeah you know and
um 81 81 yeah so
it was like something that
you know really resonated with me and i
was an artist trying to also find my
voice
and coming from the military barracks
and believing and also using my music as
a means to project
social issues political issues and also
empowering
uh you know my people and also using
that as a cultural conversation with the
world reggae made sense as kind of a
music that i gravitated and obviously
bob marley's voice but in addition to
artists like fella cutie right who were
also very popular at that time and so
the soldiers had kind of a love-hate
relationship with felicity's music
because he sang against
the nigerian army
but the ghanaian army loved him
you know and so you hear songs like
zombie
nigerian army it was against nigerian
army but a ghanaian army was like we're
not nigerian yeah i was wondering who
that was about yeah you know so so like
water
get mean gets no enemies yeah water gets
real that's pretty awesome yeah but
there was also you know like a
derogatory term that people used to call
the soldiers where zombie you know you
know yeah you know you just hated that
name you know interesting you know so so
those styles you know so fella and bob
marley i'll say where the popular ones
that inspired me
well i can see both of their influences
in your music yes yes yes you know but
underneath it was like also the
traditional music the cultural music and
the high life music of ghana
and was reggae always legal to play in
ghana oh yeah yeah yeah reagan music was
okay very popular because i know that
like lucky debate in south africa had to
wait until like it became legal i think
at some point well south africa still
was under
and all of um
so a lot of things that kind of really
ignited the consciousness of the people
was you know not not uh was prohibited
because yeah yeah they they were
fighting against not only
uh physically restricting the people's
progress but also fighting the people's
mindset yeah and reggae kind of ignited
and opened the mindset of people yeah
they were afraid of that
[Music]
all righty then
so
did you know a group named osabisa
oh yes
you know osibisa was like uh
traditional heroes of ghana yeah yeah
you know because they were the
traditional heroes of africa because
they
were actually
the first african band to take african
music
and
kind of
bring it into the mainstream
of uh
you know
global music yeah you know so they and
they were from ghana
you know so the group started from ghana
and then eventually um a lot of the
members became
some of my mentors yeah you know so
you know teddy jose
and mark tonto
uh became very close friends who
supported me actually in the early parts
of my music yeah and uh they are
you know they took
high life music
and also integrated it with western
sounds
and created
a fun
i mean they were amazing live you know
they brought like also the cultural
aspect of ghanaian music too and
presented it in a way that
could uh be comprehended by audiences
beyond africa you know so uh is a very
you know they're they're they're heroes
of god music yeah now
didn't one of their members
move to venice lofty assisi a mao didn't
did he do you know that guy
no okay
all right never mind moving on yeah
um so when did you actually start
playing music and writing songs
writing started way earlier you know
because i remember being
a little kid from around the age of five
years you know i recognized that ability
yeah and so i started making up
songs
you know i will hear something and i'll
make it up and
i will
you know hear melodies now gravitate
towards the melody and start really
analyzing them so when it comes to when
people ask me about songwriting i say
it came it was there i thought that it
was always part of me like i was born
with that already in me right and then
at five i started recognizing it yeah
and then five yeah around the age of
five and then by seven years i was
making up my own songs but there were
never
things that i realized that you know i
was gonna
do it professionally yeah yeah but i was
i was making them up
and
professionally
i'll say
by the time i got to
um
let me see
12 years that is when i sat for my
common insurance exam to secondary
school in ghana as by time i was i got
to secondary school i was already
singing stuff that
are where original stuff but i was doing
it without telling people that i was the
one that composed them so what i would
do is that i usually will i was kind of
the noisiest kid
around you know hold little parties you
know people will be playing on this and
then i'll sing and i'll sing popular
songs and stuff and add it to it so i
you know i always created that
environment wherever i was and then that
was kind of part of nurturing my
songwriting yeah but
when i got to i remember when i got to
secondary school which is probably the
college equivalent here
that was when i started
seriously putting structure
to
[Music]
and so
then you were writing in second year
yeah yes in secondary school but what
the way the writing was was because
you know because we never had it was
hard to have access to guitars and
instruments because those were expensive
yeah so your father would never any like
you want to be a musician no no no no
you go to school yeah so that was kind
of how things were so
musicians were seen as oh those people
you know they just follow women and
smoke a lot and drink a lot and they
like wayward people and all of you know
that was kind of like prevailing mindset
you know so
life of a musician exactly so being a
musician was not something that you know
you go out and say that's a career
choice
you know it's a partner you got to
believe in it and you got to make
everybody accept it absolutely so
the kind of
style of music was what i figured i hear
you call beatbox
so we started by
you create the song
and also i could hear the instruments in
my head
so then i had a few friends
who were also taken by what i would do
so i will have one on the baseline
one play the drum
and then we will just make up the songs
like that yeah yeah yeah so that was
kind of how we started creating
structure to what was in our mind
starting right started writing songs
because we didn't have instruments yeah
yeah so my first even albums
that eventually i did that was kind of
the style
that i eventually evolved into my first
demo you know i remember when i was
doing the demo a friend had
two
tape recorders
you know and then another friend had
like a nice
cassette right she bouncing back and
forth yeah yeah so i went to her and i
was just like you know that's your
cassette and she's like no no don't talk
about that mike i said i'm not giving it
to you i'm like i'm trying to do a demo
so i can go and get a producer for my
music you know so you know if you give
it to me i will you know
pay you back i don't think i ever paid
back but
the the the first demo was putting the
tape in there
you know recording uh you know recording
having somebody sing and then me
and singing it directly into the tape
with somebody i mean and then afterwards
we played that to another cassette
and then we added stuff so that was kind
of how we we did it and then created you
know the first demo for people to hear
that oh wow you know this is a song okay
this is how the bass goes and all of
that i think what it did for me too was
that it
allowed me to be able to be a uh
develop
production instincts
that whenever i wrote songs i could
easily go into a studio and then say
okay this is how the bass go this is how
the drum goes this is how that goes
created that instinct you know for me to
be able to be a good arranger and also a
good producer yeah yeah yeah
well your albums now sound
very well produced i must say and all
the uh the musicians are great thank you
[Applause]
boom
boom boom
me
ah
[Music]
temple all night long
so
[Music]
up
everybody open your eyes
[Music]
vibrations
go
[Music]
mama shake it to your body
me
up
[Music]
africa
up
[Music]
african thriller
yes
from your grammy-nominated 2015 album
branches of the same tree yeah
is like an anthemic dancehall too right
yes and the video is is a visual
experience and cinematic experience like
so many of your other videos yes can we
talk about making that video and your
videos in general i mean wow yeah
you know when i came to spend time in
america you know lived here
and started seeing i mean
everybody's impressed with what
artists like michael jackson did with
videos
you know videos became a means by which
you could tell a new story beyond what
the music is
you know so you use that to expand on
the concept of what exactly the art the
music
is
so
personally too i kind of gravitated
towards that idea that you know whenever
you were doing a music uh a music video
the song was the starting point yeah and
if you have a great director too who has
a great vision they could also help to
really push oh you know so
for african thriller you know a very
close friend of mine uh uh you know
glenn wilson uh he also actually an
amazing photographer so he's done a lot
of my
in the photography
he's also um directed at previous uh
video that was called african reggae
fever
that was also kind of very well shot it
was shot like in venice and all of that
i saw that you're walking down the
street yeah walking down the street yeah
he's playing the guitar this girl's
playing the guitar exactly and then
people doing loops and all of that yeah
beautiful and well well welcomed nice
you know and he he was
you know his like his
visual that he was very specific because
he was a photographer too he knew how
you know how to frame things and also
get deeper into the texture of the
images yeah well that's a great video i
gotta say and you know it was made in
2015 yeah and then
after i saw the video i had to go back
and check to see when black panther was
made because it it
okay it's maybe some
you know reoccurring
cos african costumes yeah yeah yeah and
some of the women yeah however yeah you
know you just
probably i want to you know you know he
visually he visually too because the
song was called african thriller
you know so
because
african thriller you know we're thinking
okay michael jackson
uh we were thinking
manila you know that's boxing yeah um
you know inter so it was paying homage
to also
african create african and
african-american creatives who have
excelled from muhammad ali
to michael jackson and at the same time
to
uh africa where
uh the the big uh boxing match between
foreman and muhammad ali
zaire yeah you know with all you know
james brown was there so it was a
combination of music
and also boxing oh yeah and then at the
same time using that too to create a
conversation piece between the diaspora
and also the motherland yeah in a way
that is fun it's inclusive and using
dance as a metaphor that's beautiful of
boxing so you step in the ring but
you're not going there to go and fight
you're going there to showcase how you
know your day your moves yep you know so
philosophically there was a gr it was a
great concept and then we just knew that
you know with glenn you know he could
you know so he needed a space and i
remember we
we filmed it in uh in a boxing ring in
pokemon you know uh he brought spoda
yeah i mean you think it was filmed in
africa in africa you know and that's the
magic of uh you know film you know and
he brought and we got you know
amazing choreographers you know i mean
uh yeah uh the the lady who
choreographed um you know their uh their
the the the video right now yeah the
moves
choreographed for a lot of big stuff you
know
and uh so we we had some of the best
talent yeah you know and friends
you know it was it was a kind of a
family affair and uh obviously my
manager kerry sullivan was also very
involved in kind of really putting all
of that together and making it all
happen so it was a it was filled with
spirit yep it was filled with um a sense
of truth
uh it was also filmed with vision
pain homage at the same time to reaching
out into the future and i think that is
what and then the song itself too
kind of was that it was a combination of
african traditional music dance hall
um afrobeats
and uh you know and also paid homage to
like you know you don't you know as a
human living being you gotta move yeah
movement yeah it's life you know and
that is all depicted in that video it
kind of yeah
it has a little fellow cootie in that
song yes yes yes that's the afro beach
aspect of uh fella cootie and then
felakuti comes from high life and all of
that so yeah yeah as an african a lot of
times you know most people know that
will experience high life and all that
true afrobeat by our experience from
where the wealth same well springs that
fella yeah also my experience from no no
it's all it's all good yeah
reference points yes yes yes
[Music]
so um in your new video
beautiful people
uh which is on your latest album voices
of
boom boom boom boom boom boom
boom
boom boom yes yeah volume one yeah it's
dedicated to the people of ghana yes and
is that village where it was filmed
special to you
yes that's not pacoima yeah yeah yeah
that's very far from pokemon yeah uh
that is my ancestral village that is
where
my the village was founded by
my
great grand my grandfather
and it's one of the big thriving
villages and my family has been the
royal
family of that so
my
family has been the chiefs my father was
the chief and then now my older brother
uh is the chief there uh and the idea of
beautiful people too was to
you know to find the beauty in every day
yeah life and yeah yeah well it's
beautiful yeah everybody has beauty in
them and i feel that a lot of times we
try to look for the beauty outside and
also in terms of outward things that are
not
uh real you know so i felt that i didn't
needed to use that
uh video to show that everybody should
appreciate their origins
to appreciate where they come from
absolutely i appreciate the people who
make them who they are the community
that to some extent gave birth to who
they are yeah so the video i went back
to find a beauty
in the community divine find the beauty
in the everyday things that people were
doing the you know the the look of the
people the feeling of the place
yeah yeah
yeah people really feel and then the
song you know great spirit and in doing
so to inspire other people to go to your
origins you know honor where you come
from honor who you are because that is
who you are you know so it was it was a
song that
in telling my story i felt that it
allowed people to to tell their own
stories
well it's a great song great video too
thank you thank you
[Music]
i dedicate this song to you my beautiful
people
my beautiful people
come and sing along
[Music]
here i got a song for you my beautiful
people
my beautiful people
sing along
[Music]
there are many things we cannot hide
everything in life is a sacrifice but i
know it was worth
the price
for i did it for you
[Music]
here i come with a song
i dedicate this song to you my beautiful
people
[Music]
and you know i did it for you
and you know that music is a
language from everybody
[Music]
yet i did it for
oh beautiful people
come and sing along
[Music]
i dedicate this song for you oh
beautiful people
oh beautiful people
come and sing along
[Music]
you know that love is
yeah this song for you oh beautiful
people
oh beautiful people
[Music]
um
[Laughter]
2016 album beats is zion yeah
uh and he adds a little hip-hop to that
yes um i wonder what which language of
ghana is this and briefly
what is the meaning of this okay so
churchill beardemo is actually uh a
remake
of one of my favorite
funky high life so that's the
traditional high lifestyle high life
songs
and uh and that's a song too that
has become a standard not only
for high life lovers within ghana yeah
but also people who discovered high life
in all around the world you know
so
when i was working on beats of zion
um i had the opportunity of recording in
the village studios i was gifted time
there you know like oh come and record
in the village studios
whoa and then they're like wow and you
get to use fleetwood mac studio yeah i
was like no [__] all right
all right when do i come yeah when do i
come so i was like okay what's what
songs do i
and i was getting ready to start the
record yeah that time i was like what
songs should i do and by then i had been
adding chanche mba di mew to my sets
yeah yeah yeah by live sets
so you know to add a high life element
too to you know because from the after
root stuff that i play and then also the
reggae stuff you know i had like also
traditional high life stuff that i had
adapted
a much more
funky way you know so i was like okay
why not record this song which is a
traditional standard it's also high life
music and at the same time two hours
like high life music in ghana never got
opportunity of being recorded probably
in a studio like the village studios
which is one of the top studios in the
world oh yeah so
i was like let me do that so i went in
you know organized my band here and the
band 2
um
was from all around the world from
brazil from cuba from so
traditional high life music from ghana
now being played by a global cast
i could tell they
because you know i have another question
about the musicians on that song but
keep going yeah so so we went in there
and then recorded the song you know and
it just came out really beautifully oh
yeah and then afterwards i was like okay
the original
had uh you know original was traditional
right but then there's been remixed by
certain hip-hop artists
but i felt that okay if i am remaking it
then i have to work with you know some
of the cutting edge uh you know yeah
artists and and the language too was chi
which is the language of the ashanti
tribe ghana so that was the language of
the song and one of the top
uh rappers in chi was sakura yeah so i
called up sarkodie and said hey you know
i'm doing a remake of uh changing
vietnamese when all of that and i feel
that you know you should be on it and
it's like send it to me let me hear it
and he heard it's like wow this is this
sounds good like very well recorded and
like you know it's
you know really amazing you know so he
also added his
bit to it and uh it became it sounds
good yeah it became that beautiful
uh you know i feel that we really did a
great homage to that song yeah and uh
etched another high life masterpiece uh
re
refreshed it for a new audience yeah
well i i certainly like listening to it
that's for sure
um and then my question was where did
the horn section come from
oh the whole section yeah that whole
section so the whole section is uh it
seemed like it was almost afro cuban
yes because the trumpet trumpetized from
cuber right
uh the trombonist is from brazil
and then
and then the saxophonist is
african-american oh wow so
i had it was not a ghanaian yes this was
like the diasporian cats and different
dimensions of the diaspora that played
the horn so yeah so you know they like
sinking deep into the song there's so
many different elements that kind of
gave it such you know deep spirituals
and cultural significance because it was
a a song that was its inception was from
ghana but then that remake
also took into consideration all the
diaspora sounds and stuff and bringing
it back and bringing it right back yeah
yeah that is amazing
um how many albums have you released so
far rocky um
eight albums seven albums and then an ep
so the ep voice of boom ball was the ep
that uh just
uh was released actually that i've been
working on that has beautiful people in
it yeah yeah and there's your volume two
coming up come on volume two
it's gonna come up it's not necessarily
gonna follow yeah yeah um it's probably
the next one will probably be an album
okay cool yeah
um
you also work for humanitarian and
environmental organizations
which ones and what do you do
well you know from
uh
shall i say
growing up yeah
you
and also growing up in um talking about
my military growing up in the military
barracks that was politicized
we were constantly exposed to
issues that required attention
because the ghanaian military
was in power then so they were dealing
with national issues
so wherever i walked you know like you
know wherever i found a bunch of
soldiers gathered and you know after
work and they were chatting the
conversations were always about
development
they were about
how to make the country better
so those conversations
i was privy to all of that yeah yeah so
at an early
age
i was
figuring trying to figure out how i
could also make a difference
and at the same time to most of the
ghanaian soldiers to where
part of the u.n peacekeeping force
because
when i was a little kid there was the
arab israeli uh peace uh issue that was
going on in the middle east so six day
war um was that after that maybe yeah i
think more i don't know what i got yom
kippur one yeah but most of the soldiers
were kind of stabilizing phones that was
sent to
egypt
part of the u.n force to go there and
you know be in between yeah yeah all the
all the feuding countries you know to
try and maintain stability there so
so whenever they came
you know they were talking about all
these divisions and how
you know
they could they could be so there was
like
i was
sponging all of this the united
nations um
local politics
you know trying to make a change
um at the same time too
they
the influences that all these soldiers
who were exposed to that part of the
world were bringing right back home they
were not bringing it to ghana they were
bringing it right into the confines of
the military barracks so we lived in a
very tight place so it started
building
that
need in me to be a voice
for social transformation yeah uh to be
to utilize whatever
uh gifts that i felt god had given me
to
to to help society in advance and also
to speak truth to power and at the same
time to use it as a means to
empower people
but i also felt that
it's one thing writing about it it's
ranting talking about it it's one thing
sitting on the stage and writing lyrics
about it
you can only make some of those changes
to
if you're able to translate what you're
saying
into reality by being on the ground
action
so we're back with rocky dewooney yes
thanks for uh putting up with our
technical difficulties here
um
so
how is akra the capital of ghana i mean
what is it like and
how is the government nowadays you know
there
accra right now you know just like every
team in
urban capital
you know it's
it's a lot of traffic
um you know
a lot of congestion yep
and um you know dealing with issues too
of you know trying to
maintain when
you know people are moving from
different areas of the country
into every day
coming in coming in you know so
you know when it has to do with you know
issues of housing um
food
you know
all of those problems are
going on you know but you know
underneath all of that too you know
people are going about their lives like
everywhere you know but
since the crisis the global crisis
happened
what
it has done is that it literally killed
a lot of the night life
which ghana was has been struggling in a
way to kind of bring that back so it
really
killed that and then now
people are just trying to
you know get their lives back get back
to normal yeah get back to um you know a
semblance of normality yeah right now
you know like the rest of the world like
the rest of the world yeah yes
um
and i hate to ask about another city but
you wrote about nairobi oh yeah you love
nairobi and i just wanted to ask you
what do you love about nairobi that's in
kenya right yeah you know actually that
song was um
was a metaphor
so
what happened was that kenya had a big
political issue i mean the issue is you
know is steeped in the history of kenya
which i'm not gonna go deeply into
but
there are
two big political factions that have
been
kind of
fighting for power a long time and then
there's been one
faction that has been in power
for that length so
and all these factions too
revolve around tribes
so one faction is two tribes another
faction is one major tribe with other
minor tribes around it so it's not only
political but it's also steeped in
cultural and identity and all of that
so
um everybody will remember that kenya
had elections
and that election was contested
and then there was like a big huge
problem where
people started fighting the country
nearly fell apart and then the u.n kofi
annan and everybody went in there so it
was between kenyatta and also raila
odinga
so when
that period went through and they kind
of got to a point of understanding an
agreement and they were just about to do
another elections after a few years of
stabilizing the situation
um you know in which the international
court of justice were all involved in
and kenyatta was actually at first uh he
was going to be charged in the
you know with crimes against his people
and all of that but eventually all of
that was resolved and he decided to do
an election
so
i was invited to kenya at that time
as
part of a peace initiative
with the red cross of
to come and
you know work
uh with musicians and all of that as
part of the peace building and also
trying to
you know
create a peaceful foundation for that
election that was just about to happen
so i traveled in
i you know with the red cross you know
we went into areas like kibera
meeting you know to meetings with
various musicians various groups
um you know
promoting peace promoting inter tribal
you know connection and then also an
ideal of
a united kenya
an ideal of a united people
and
whilst i was going through all of this
i felt that there was such a deep rift
between the people that was not
political
it was cultural and tribal yeah to a
point that
ghanas was not even
you know ghana's division when it comes
to the tribes and culture was not even
that deep but kenyans was deep
so i was like what
can i as a musician and as somebody
who's here as part of you know getting a
snapshot into this issue what can i do
to help the healing process
so i was like wow you know it has to be
a song
but i didn't want a song to that was
like
obvious like hey you know you guys come
together
yeah so it's like what does all kenyans
like
what do they all agree on that we're not
gonna fight about
and you know people and i thought that
wow you know nairobi actually everybody
was proud of their capital yeah you know
every kenyan do you know regardless of
whether the person was lu
kalenjin
or you know any other tribe you know
they were they were proud of uh nairobi
you know like yeah you know you know
nairobi no everybody was like nairobi is
like one of the most beautiful you know
capitals in africa and all of that there
was a certain pride to it so i was like
okay
maybe what i needed to do was uh write a
song about something that
unites everybody and they use that as a
premise
to speak about harmony
and unity yeah well then so it's a great
song yeah so the song nairobi was kind
of
birthed out of that intention and
connected yeah
i just had to wonder you know
um because you did keep the the politics
out of that um
you know
here we are at kelly high and so i feel
i have to ask you is is herb legal in
ghana
herb is not legal in ghana and many
african countries um
you know
have
you know because african countries uh
inherited
a lot of their constitution
and a lot of their judiciary judiciary
from
the colonial colonial uh entities powers
that were there
you know so herb was also something that
you know all around you know urban hemp
were banned in most of those places and
that
was also replicated in these places
right right and to some extent it also
wrapped around in
people thinking that
herb causes craziness
you know it was like everybody said that
most of the mad people in the street
they will always say oh dear oh we
smokes you know so there's kind of a
false narrative that i think has kind of
its roots from here that was also
perpetrated all over there so it was
something that was seen as the yeah
serious type and stigma it was something
that was seen as
deviant you know and also
that it was
also people it it causes illness it was
terrible for the community and the
society so
you know
everybody was
against it and but the musicians it was
popular within the musicians and the
creative community that's why everybody
was like oh you want to be a musician
you know those people they just smoke
wee and all of that kind of stuff nobody
wanted their daughters to marry a
musician because they're like they're
not stable people
so
so most african countries were very
adamant and then it got also one way or
they got wrapped into
the religious establishment
so they
the religious establishment also
constantly is preaching against oh yeah
you know people who were
yeah yeah they want to see that people
who
you know anytime they're talking about
people who didn't make it in life they
like you know they ended up being a we
smoker they ended up being this drinking
and smoking weed it was seen as
people who never were able to make it
into
uh you know the society
um and fell off it was always blamed on
that so that stigma has survived
up till now although
when you look critically there's a lot
of people
who are beyond that stigma artists and
even people in
you know government places and
all attitudes will change right yeah
yeah you know but now it's changing yeah
it's changing because
other parts of the world are doing so so
yeah exactly and then most of these
economies too are seeing
the numbers from
other economies that are
you know but the political will is still
lacking from most of the leaders because
they feel that
if you legalize it first of all you're
going to lose your base because it's
aggressive
so you're going to lose that so most of
them are walking
you know kind of a fine line between it
but there some countries that are
are decriminalizing
the farming right of it
but they are not legalizing yeah the use
of it you know and then recently in
ghana too
it's uh it's amazing that i'm doing this
interview right now because
just about a week ago
uh the
the ghanaian government also
uh came out and said that they are just
on the verge
of uh
allowing
the farming
of hemp hemp
yeah 0.3
thc um you know and
we feel that it is a you know it's a a
major step because obviously if
they feel a certain concern
about
you know legalizing it and then all of a
sudden everybody's walking around the
streets
you know
uh smoking which was actually
you know to even diverge to a funny
situation was that
the first time it was announced that
the government was thinking about doing
that the following day social media
everybody was people were putting things
off lighting
on there and all of that i was just like
hey guys a little bit too soon yeah a
little bit too soon because that's not
what these guys are talking about and
you're actually
kind of exposing the greatest fear
you know of everybody walking around and
lighting it up you know and smoking in
the streets and all that just
relax and allow them the space to be
able to you know move this along you
know their own pace of some kind yeah
yeah you know but but you know it's
something that
it is
you know i think it's ridiculous
that
most of these countries are not seeing
it as a means by which they could deal
with their debt issues
they could oh yeah restart benefits yeah
economy money one thing and at the same
time to the health benefits of it
exactly cbd
you know the the the the nutrition from
the seeds
you know the fiber from hemp and all of
that you know these are all things that
can be transformative for economies you
know so i make my my clothes out of all
the stems and seeds from my previous um
seasons oh wow
it would be nice right yeah yeah
yeah but that's that's you know hemp
material and hemp fiber and hemp you
know it's it's it's it's incredible you
know so i feel that
i feel that you know if that is what
we're comfortable with
you know it also has transformative
benefits and we should take a step yeah
and then eventually you know all the
others you know will come along yeah
okay
um are we still rolling here on both of
these guys maybe can you check him out
real
quick it's been six minutes it's got
that red butt okay and check over there
please i'm sorry
i don't know about that one but this is
gone that's going and this is going to
okay
all right
okay how many more questions uh a few
more questions and then maybe just for
insurance we'll go back and do one or
two more i'm sorry man all right so
um
all right here we go uh
you have an amazing band are you are
they always the same people or
we talked about that a little bit yes
you know the thing is that it's very
hard these days to keep a standing band
yeah yeah unless
uh the
economics of the
you know the industry right does not
allow
most of the time especially when you
leave you're operating from major cities
yeah let's say i'm operating from los
angeles or i'm operating from accra
ghana yeah yeah uh
you know to hold together a band you
need console and you also need to be
touring yeah you also needs to be
touring you know and then the touring
dates too you know so
you maintain
a group of people that you work with
that are your band by the same time too
most of them
also work with other yeah yeah other
bands great musicians great musicians
yeah you know great musicians you know
to work with musicians on that level
um it's um you know they're also equally
uh you know
in demand in everywhere and you have to
come to terms with that you know but i
have you know i have a solid band yeah
here in the united states and then also
a solid band in ghana that's to work
with yeah and so plans for touring now
that things are opening up
yes yes uh we're hoping so but you know
the thing is that things are opening up
but they're not the touring world has
not it's not necessarily like in america
looks like things are open up much more
faster
than in europe yeah there's really not
much going on in europe i mean basically
our you know touring and booking
agencies over there have said that
literally just forget the year
you know because nothing is really going
to happen and then from the news too we
are seeing that europe is even getting
you know things i've been shutting down
more
yeah
you know
instead of yeah instead of opening up
you know so
so for me
i am seeing that
music and artistry and
all that we do
um
you know has to evolve you know there is
a saying
that
uh it's actually
uh in a chanting tree proverb that say
when
uh the hunter learns to shoot
without missing the birds will have to
learn to fly without perching
[Laughter]
that means that whenever you're giving
any
situation you have to make the
adjustment yeah yeah and elevate above
it
so i think that
musicians have to now start being
innovative yeah in terms of where they
are
and where they're situated and where is
their
natural
places to be able to project globally to
and there's a lot of tools right now to
help
that but it has not become
the norm but
with what is going on
we have to
work very fast to really
um
you know put a platform out there yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and it also
makes some money exactly exactly you
know virtual and interactive at the same
time you know and i feel that that is
where
uh people have to
push themselves too so that regardless
of whatever it is you're not limited by
geography because it's becoming very
hard to
navigate across
borders and geography because people are
becoming more divided around the world
as we've seen
nations are looking more inwards
you know everybody you know even
political stability
is uh becoming a big question around the
world yeah so all of these things impact
the ability of musicians to travel and
be able to showcase their artistry so we
are the mercy of all these elements and
i think that we also need to
now start seeing things that the
innovation doesn't necessarily come from
other people doing it we need to
innovate how we still are going to reach
the people yeah
[Music]
um
how many albums do you have
i have seven albums and then one ep yeah
um
and then the new one get a new one the
voice of bomb is the current uh ep
that's out right now
and
branches of the same tree was nominated
for a grammy for
reggae album of the year yes really
that's one year yeah yeah
yeah it was like um
i think i'm either the first or the
second african
to be nominated in that category yeah
and then also the first of my country
uh to be nominated for a grammy yeah so
so that nomination for me
was um you know i mean people like to
use the word historic
uh for it but i
also saw it as a combination of you know
when you're evolving a new sound was
that the afro-root sound finally
was able to grab the ears of people as
to
what um
innovation that
that sound had brought to contemporary
reggae music at the same time too
brought to contemporary high life and
afrobeat music because what i did was
fuse
these two sounds in a way that could be
accessible
and also
could speak in a way that everybody from
every culture could access it
and i think that the
grammy nomination was
an eventual validation of this sound
that
i have constantly championed
and um it is um you know now every you
know all the ghanaian
uh you know artists everybody's striving
to win a grammy so i'm just like good i
you know i lighted a big fire yeah out
there so you say it's a big inspiration
sorry you didn't win that one it's all
good in that one it was a morgan
heritage yeah morgan heritage yeah
that year yeah yeah
well that's interesting
um
and congratulations for being the first
ghanaian to be nominated for a grammy
bro thank you very much and may you get
it grammy thank you for your next album
thank you thank you
so
cali high has been blessed to be here
with rocky dewooney today rocky thanks
for coming down and we really appreciate
interviewing you here
and uh you know forever and ever you
will always be the king of wakanda in in
my eyes oh thank you very much and also
you know the thing is that california is
california is also
a home for me you know apart from being
in ghana i've spent a lot of time here
you know so
you know i feel also like a native of
california you know as they say you know
you sometimes you recognize that you
don't belong to one place you belong to
many places
and uh this place for me too is a place
that i'm proud to call home too yeah
yeah so maybe we can get some gigs
around here before the rest of the world
opens up and then yes yes we'll be
partying exactly exactly all right thank
you so much for having me it's been a
pleasure yeah god bless you all right
all right
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
[Applause]
video
[Music]
[Applause]
video
[Music]
ah
foreign
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
way
ah
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
[Music]
okay
[Applause]
oh
[Music]
[Applause]
so
[Music]
[Applause]
you