okay
what's up it's a windy day here let me
show you what's going on
[Music]
just cleaned out the room today
um these are in flour I don't know what
I'm gonna do with them yet but I got the
Moonshine Haze F2 uh my version from
Montrose and I got a couple plants out
there that I want to pollinate so I'm
not quite sure these are the Moonshine
Haze this is the Moonshine hey it's just
two different
two different seeds so this is Tap Root
and then um of course I gotta clean out
the room
so
um yeah I just taken everything out
it's gonna flower everything and uh
[Music]
this is across
it came from this
this is re-veging because I have it
under my 315 so this is a male re-veging
his brother sister so this is the sister
this is the brother
and that's the dad to this
[Music]
so this is brother sister
from that Dad
[Music]
windy day here in Colorado
oh
a bunch of stuff seated up and I'm
already getting seeds that are done so
these are the ones that usually fall out
so just figured I'd do a live let you
guys see what's going on here I got a
plant from dankovic this is the Blue
Dream baox times Odo 2 and this one is
generating seeds
it's a really cool looking plant
um
so it's got this CBD
in it
um
anyways there's some there's some seeds
in here that are already ready to go
so I'm gonna take this one and defoliate
oh I so many I can't count I mean I can
just show you what kind of strains do I
have but
um
Wonder fuel times Kim so wonderful is
chem 4 OG times Wonder fuel from Green
Source Gardens that one's seated up I
got blue dream times b-o-x
Oto two that one's seated up all these
are all seated up
um
Funk punch
that one's from rain strap area 420 this
one's all seated up
they're all sticky too nice and sticky
icky everything's everything out here is
all seated up so all that stuff seated
up yeah I got white widow moonshine
haste as well
it's somewhere around here
yeah this is another moonshine hey so
I've got three of the Moonshine hazes so
this is the Moonshine Haze and this
one's all
um seated up
Sunset sherbet cross this one's coming
out great the males and the females and
I'm so glad I ran this one it's like
it's it's got a really really cool
profile on it
um
but yeah a lot of these plants are
seated up
and then this is a male that just
is doing phenomenal
I'm really really happy with this bud
structure here this flower structure on
this male here
so yeah things are going good
tropical Blues Peter from future
cannabis project gave this to me
it's doing really well still have that
sherbet on my fingers though so I can't
really smell anything else
but yeah
things are going well
oh yeah for sure
[Music]
can you be careful please
those are glass
yeah I'm making seeds so
I got
I got a a bunch of uh hey mister that's
not being careful hold on a second
oh I got a phone call gotta go