what's up friends my name is julie
some of you may know me as green scotus
on
instagram or up in chat
um i'm a cannabis grower
i love growing organically i'm also a
colorado cultivator caregiver
which means that i grow cannabis
medicine for my patients
i'm also one of the founding trustee
members
of luna gardens foundation and what we
like to do is help educate the community
about cannabis medicine
and how it helps people heal from
various ailments and diseases
and which types of cannabinoids and
terpenes they should be going after when
choosing medication
depending on their ailment and disease i
just like to help
share research and information to help
people understand
cannabis medicine and plant medicine in
general it's my way of advocating for
the cannabis
plant um so one of the things that we do
as a cultivator caregiver is we make
medicine
oils for our patients this one in
particular
is a thc stream we go after terpenes and
cannabinoids
we got a couple different one-to-one
strains of oils that have like
an uh equal amount of cbd and thc
but um i just got some seeds so we're
looking at getting into growing more cbd
rich
strains uh cbg rich strains
and looking for ones with a really high
loud terpene profile
because uh terpenes cannabinoids they're
actually found in
all sorts of plants and food and uh one
thing that i love about growing
organically
is mainly um the microbials that were
pulling up out of the soil into the
plant
and consuming it ourselves it's very
important to eat healthy
foods grown organically with microbials
and i believe a lot of reasons why most
people get
really bad ailments and diseases is
because their diets are not
high in rich microbial grown food
or even medicine it's what got me to
change my mind about
growing cannabis organically and when i
first learned how to grow it was with
bottled nutrients
then when i started getting to the
medicinal sides of things i realized
that wasn't the way to go i started
growing organically
my weed was tasting amazing my products
are great
so i continued on with that and i feel
like it's really important to grow
cannabis and food organically because
it's
all medicine doesn't matter which plant
you're getting your medicine from
so anyways um i wanted to share a video
with you guys i mainly learned so much
this past
year about growing organically first um
first person who brought living soil to
my attention was
brian years ago at the denver endo expo
he did a talk about living soil and i
was really into it
and a lot of my friends that i was
growing with weren't
so at the time i was the only one but
throughout the years and through fcp and
through
meeting all the friends that i did i
found out there's so many people out
there just like me who love growing
cannabis
and food organically and i've learned so
many
different ways of doing it some people
are using um
microbial teas to inoculate some people
are doing
top dressing to inoculate there's also
the korean natural farming side of
things that i learned a jadam way of
doing things
and i've taken a few courses
over this past year just learning how to
grow
cannabis in general and i've learned so
much um i apply it
all in the garden which might be a
little bit too much but
i swear one of these days i'm gonna find
that right basic easy formula that just
works out great
so i wanted to share my outdoors garden
because if it wasn't for
future cannabis project and everyone
who's came on the show i wouldn't have
been able to learn all the things i was
able to learn how to do
so i want to give a quick shout out
thank you so much peter
leighton and especially brian thank you
very much
for all your guests everyone you've had
on your show thank you for
sharing all the education for free to
teach people
how to grow their own medicine whether
it's cannabis
or hemp or even tomatoes and cucumbers
or peaches you know just plants
plants are medicine we all have a
receptor system
and each different plant terpene
cannabinoid
can attach to different receptors in our
systems
and help us heal so let's get into it
first i'll introduce you to the ladies
uh these first four plants that you see
right here here's one
behind her is another over here
that big one over there and this one
right here
fcp had a guy masonic seeds on
and he was given out free seeds which i
was so thankful to get thank you
they are los angeles pier kush
cross with panama red cross with wilson
and that's what these four lovely ladies
are right here
they also had um mr toad on
this really tall plant back here is um
haze for days it's really skinny because
when i first
moved to the plant back here these ones
have already been growing back here for
a couple of months
and i figured it would catch up and it
did this
these plants were started in january the
seed
haze for days that was started in may
i put that seed in the ground in the
beginning of
june and it's just as tall as the rest
it just
needs some more sunlight i bet if it got
plenty of sunlight it would have grown a
lot bigger than it is right now
but just to give you an idea let's come
inside
i'm about five three five feet tall
three inches
and these plants are clearly taller than
me
see this i mean
i can't even touch the top
that's how tall these plants are this is
my third year growing outdoors
so plants in here are doing absolutely
amazing
and i've learned so much more this past
year about growing organically
than i have before so of course this
season is going to be my best one
let's see back here you guys remember
having um
a [ __ ] sorry i just saw a um
a grasshopper jumping on my plant and i
had to take it off
anyways these two back here you guys
know miles
he's the guy that creates we should
taste good gear
t-shirts he also does fermented plant
extracts i've been using his
pumpkin ferment if you've seen any of my
videos on instagram
he also uh does seeds too this one
is wolf glue cbd wolf
i think it's crossed with gorilla glue
but i'm not going to say that for a fact
this is going to be my season's one to
one strain
equal amounts of cbd to thc
one thing i had learned last season was
about chopping
my cbd plants down a little bit early
because i do want to keep that volume
equal so that way there's not too much
thc
dominance i do have to harvest this
a little bit early than i would like to
um
but not too much i just learned that
from doing it last year so this year i
want to make sure i get it right
um so that's this one
wolf glue this one also back here is a
wolf glue they're pretty freaking huge i
put them up in nuts
and it's not gonna if i'm gonna have to
net them up some more
like i said way way way tall
right here i have my favorite
bubblicious
this one's a great one for oils i got
these from nirvana seeds
i believe they're out in holland um
this has always been my one when i mean
i've gone with these guys and i kept
getting their seeds for so many years
and i've never
had issues other than you know just
making sure to harvest it early so you
can
um have a good product that has very
equal amounts of cbd and thc
if you wait too long to harvest then the
thc amount might go up a little bit more
but not by much
but like i said i'm trying to go for
that one to one this
is the same one it got shaded out okay
so here's the thing
when i first started this um
little grow bed i walk in it so down
here on
that's the soil and i as you could tell
i got steps
i walk in the bed there was plenty of
room when i first started it with just
six plants and i thought
well there's so much space maybe i could
put some more plants back here so i put
in the two bubblicious
and then i put in the one haze for days
and
there's definitely not enough room for
these plants i mean this bubblicious
hardly sees any sun
this haze for days hardly sees any sun
um so what happens with the rain
when it comes down is it goes into
the gutter back here and drops down into
a trash can and i collect all the rain
water and a lot of times i'll water with
that rain water that's been collected
um i also like um i like the jadom
liquid fertilizers i did make a cannabis
jadam liquid fertilizer
back in march we had some
pretty heavy snow and
i put a bunch of old cannabis plants
that i had to
get rid of they turned out to be males
chop them all up put them in a big
bucket
actually a big root barrel filled it
with some of the snow water and just let
it sit in there
for six months and sometimes i'll put
i'll put a little bit of that juice into
my big reservoir
um also right now since they are still
in the veg
phase when i'm down here watering on the
ground i'll also spray the leaves
to get the food on the leaves as well
and try to come out here early early in
the morning before it gets too hot
because
in here it does get really really really
hot and that's probably why these plants
are so huge right now
i also have a whole lineup of things
that i like to um foliar with
one of them is k f maintenance spray
that's one of my favorite things to
foliar with
i also like to do
some sort of like plant ferment
with um things like
aloe or silica
um i have a whole list i do like to
foliar with em em5 i got it from build a
soil
i get a lot of my stuff from build a
um what else
uh fuller a foliar spray with um
sulfur as well tomorrow i'm about to do
that before there's very
some of them got you know like little
bug bites on them
it's just nature it happens
i still love um i love being out here
and i love growing outdoors
one thing that i absolutely love making
is just home-grown medicine for
everybody
and i love making it organically i love
the sun the natural sunshine
i love coming out here this is my chill
zone
where i want to smoke some weed or relax
or just listen to the birds it's one of
my favorite places to be
um so that's all for now i got work to
do i'm gonna let you guys go i'm sure
you got things you want to do today too
so i want to let you get back at it
if you have any questions about how to
make anything
feel free to reach out to me a lot of
the k
f formulations and some of the jadam
i have made myself and i share that on
my instagram
so if you guys want to check it out go
for it
i learned it all for free basically
so it's one thing i really like being
able to do is being a thrifty farmer
and saving some money so that way i
could grow
naturally if you have any questions
hit me up reach out my email is
greensgoddess420
at gmail.com hit me up on instagram i
mean
i'm always um not always on there but
you know if you leave a message i'll get
back to you and i have time
because i'm usually in here
so anyways i also wanted to give
one quick shout out to my husband
anthony because if it wasn't for you i
wouldn't be able to do all these things
that i'm able to do today
so thank you very much hola that's my
daughter
come in and say hi
say hi ang i swear she's taller than me
bye you guys have a good one
hold up uh i was just doing some editing
on the video and a whole bunch of stuff
got cut out
including the most important part of the
whole video what's in my soil
here's a little view of what we got
going on down here
a lot of chopping drop i got some um
redwood bark mulch which worked out
really nicely to keep the weeds away
um let's see uh this is my second year
going in this bed i basically do like
accouts mix
coots mixes one-third peat one-third
aeration like pumice or rice hulls
and one-third compost and half of that
could be worm castings and the other
half could be like
regular compost that and
that's your basic coots mix and then you
have some amendments added into it
like um gypsum glacial rock dust and
azomite i use
both basalt crab meal oyster shell
mean meal kelp meal yep
that's in there i don't know google
coots mix that's what i have in my soil
so i made that a long time ago i didn't
use this bed last year and in fact last
year
there were so many fires ashes all over
and i bet a lot of those ashes fell into
this bed
from a lot of the fires that happened
last summer and this year what i did was
i
grabbed some more a little bit more peat
and a lot of compost and i tilled that
into what i already had in the ground
and i let that sit for about a month
then i came in and i made another big
ass batch of coots mix
about i did like 100 gallons
and i um put that in here
um along with the plants i like to
top dress at least once a month i use uh
this little mix it's a recipe from gold
dust farms
it's got like your basic top dressing
amendments
uh products from like down to earth
stuff like that
you know like oyster shell kelp alfalfa
um gypsum things like that i couldn't
name it all off the top of my head
but i put it all in a mix and that's
what i put
um you know probably about like a cup of
that per
plant do that once a month i do bokashi
once a month i love bokashi it works out
really well
um other than that chop and drop i mean
if you have uh
leaves you've got a defender pull down
just let it fall to the ground and
naturally do its thing
so just wanted to share that with you
guys couldn't let you go without the
most important part what's in the soil
and this is straight in the ground so um
you know
there's nothing really they're not in
pots or anything like that
well hope you guys have a good day
spark one up for me peace out