summer solstice
happy summer solstice here's a
bedlin
there's uh some of the later here's one
of the earliest males to fly
and uh
the females are just starting to show
i left about seven or eight full size
about a third of the crop i just went
ahead and folded over
and then several others i chopped the
top off of
these are all uh strategies um to
experiment with dealing with the extreme
drought situation these have not
received any water here in utah
these uh not been
fed or watered they were direct seeded
on march 19th again here's a male coming
around
and i'm doing this as a demonstration
project to show people that dry farming
actually can occur wherever you are
we are in extraordinary drought
and again these have not been fed i'm
having some serious pest issues but
i'm going to have a really good medicine
crop for my daughter's mother who's
dealing with cancer
all natural with true terroir
you can see uh this is alkali dust from
a small rainstorm we just had
um
i know leighton likes to say that
um we don't get bacterial
or microbe distribution
anymore but um it's quite obvious that
we do get quite a bit of windstorm
activity that blows
surface soil particles
and
deposits them
you can see it in the snow on the
mountains it turns all dark because of
all these soil particles in the air but
anyhow um bugs i'm dealing with are the
pill bug
earwigs
grasshopper
and uh
spinosad is my number one go-to and veg
for these things but i also am doing
pyrethrin flower um tea
yeah that's a quick update for you all
on on the bed liam philbian
again the males are all i removed the
majority of them the last ones are
turning and the females are just showing
up
and it's solstice
appreciate y'all for
learning how to change the world with me
yeah i know these don't look awesome
these are uh this is worst case middle
of the [ __ ] desert we don't get rain
we don't we get extreme temperatures we
get these actually just had
five days of
30 mile an hour wind basically
i ripped out branches from my my front
yard trees and uh so these were furnace
blasted we were 97 degrees the first day
of it
so
take that all for what it is never been
fed never been watered
extreme desert blasting conditions
right
so i'm not claiming that these are
beautiful i'm not claiming this is
the end all here there's a
pest right there
i'm just showing you can do this just
put seeds in the ground and produce a
crop you don't need to be spending
a million dollars on a facility
pounds for pennies