[Music]
so this is greenhouse number two
running hundreds in here so little
smaller pots
um
I direct sewed these seeds so
kind of all over the place some of them
uh
didn't take and so I threw something
late
so those ones haven't been sexed yet but
uh yeah this is uh all the sweet and
sour series over here
so I'm working on this week
got some of the uh sprayed them
yesterday
these ones uh
didn't have any bugs on the plants but
uh got some of those light green aphids
coming in on the Clover so I chopped the
Clover
and composted that and then just did a
spray with some
Horticultural soap
thing looks happy
but yeah this is a lot of the kundo's V
over here
these are the uh
the sour lemon head this is a mango
I didn't release this one I didn't have
a lot of seeds of it but uh it's the
main go by sour lemon head
stoked for this run so I'm gonna finish
cloning this one this week and then
[Music]
hop over to uh
third greenhouse and start filling pots
so
by the end of this month I should have
all three greenhouses up and running
I was gonna do an outdoor plot
but I've got a lot of work to do out
there before I come
really get things going so
and uh yeah all this is recycled soil
chopped dress with a some of that uh
compost from the dairy farm
this little diatomaceous earth that I
sprinkled on before the nematodes to try
and get the fungus gnats under control
but
not really seeing many anymore
we need to have somewhat of an
infestation but uh
nothing too bad
some more sour lemon head crosses over
here
where is
yeah these are the S ones which I didn't
release
but uh
I don't really like it so far
basically got that same kind of diamond
diesel profile and
just uh
good structure
not too lanky not super branchy
super DP
so
yeah
and then uh yeah some more of the condos
V
but uh
there you have it Greenhouse number two
lights are coming on
and uh this will also be done sometime
in June so yeah a couple months behind
typically I'd have like an early spring
harvest in both houses but uh
I'm just stoked to be able to uh
get everything set up in these pots and
finally not have to be resetting
Greenhouse every time so
um
I think uh in the long run I'll make up
those couple months that I was down just
in
transition time
yeah God ever you got the last few
double Enders out everything's LED and
uh
irrigation set up finally
been hand watering my whole life so
It's Gonna Save Me probably a couple
days a week
and see what else we got going
set up
months