Greenhouse too for a couple weeks
behind
but I've got the legendary Oz from
Thomas
front here and then my OC Kush f2s I've
ran through them before
um
this round every plant gets 100 gallons
[Music]
the same as like next door I've got 200
gallon pots over there we're running two
plants
per pot so
let's top these again this morning kind
of plant them when they were lanky so
they're
starting to bounce back
these are cool this is one of my eight
is code selections I had outside
already flowering
so she's uh
like a mid July flower
pretty awesome
it's only one
number 10 out of you know four or five
selections flowering right now so I'm
gonna re-bedroom and maybe work with her
most of them are you know
fall fall Harvest so