what up hope everyone's having a good uh
Friday just figured I'd give a little
garden update uh
I'm gonna flip this next week
right around the 10th or so
so I gotta get in here
clean up the lowers take phones
[Music]
went back to one layer of trellis
uh I just did bamboo last time
so
just trying to figure out the best
system for these big pots
I think last time I ran three to four
plants this time we're doing two plants
just in a row
kind of imitating
outdoor production just giving them as
much root space as they want and we're
just feeding
plain water and the drip tape
I think it comes on two hours every two
days
it's moist so they practically grow
themselves
the system yeah
I wish I would have been here from the
get-go but you know sometimes you gotta
take the long route but uh
yeah
you know I threw some hay downs we got
grass growing which was no problem I
just trim that back and throw another
layer of the straw or local hay so it's
non-squay it's just from
from Friends faster but uh so you do get
weed seed but I'm not too worried about
it
um but yeah as you can see
just been uh the reason I threw the
trellis on was because
the plants were kind of getting big and
it's nice to uh just to train them down
you know so you have an even canopy
multiple tops everything got topped
twice and then it's just kind of been
you know bending
and uh keeping them somewhat even
especially these taller plants
it's a little smaller funeral hunt than
I would typically do
[Music]
only
20 plants probably
each run some of them have taken you
know going back through like my mango
tree the Jaffe
um usually what I like to do is I'll do
kind of like uh you know just to take a
peek and kind of see and then if it's
something that I really like then we'll
uh grow out a larger population
so like this you know I've got my mango
tree up here
in the front right and then our Jaffe
which is a seba by comertonic Z
I've got high alpines lemon cookie dough
and then his uh sour on his pineapple
sugar cookies just likes to grow some
some length to her and then uh over here
we've got Bubba G which is a CBG variety
from Swiss cannabino way
figured out what's going on with this
pot I think it's just you know getting a
little too uh over watered but I didn't
check it out I'm trying to figure it out
I'm gonna try and train that big old
Bush over and kind of fill in the Gap
and then we've got his uh
so this is uh I'm excited for this
greenhouse
I'm down
probably uh
beginning of October
[Music]
still got that men's monster tobacco
plant it's growing out harvested a
couple leaves right now she's just a
catch for uh
fungus gnats
there you have it I mean it's pretty uh
pretty simple system I we uh we did
Columns of biolive
and uh
so far so far that's all the
amendments we've added you know I'm just
grown in recycled soil that's probably a
couple years to five six years old
and uh
yeah they're loving loving life
um I think I've only foiler sprayed once
just uh a little bit of grasshopper
damage
um
and I you know I use uh
pretty minimal boiler sprays to try and
keep it the cheapest possible but we do
uh like stuff oil X which is just like a
mineral oil and then I like the
potassium fatty salts
relatively cheap just like Horticultural
soap and then
I like sulfur you know the micronized
sulfur usually will do that with maybe
once in veg
and then diatomaceous earth you know if
you had a couple uh
you can add a little bit of that to your
spray just to gives like a lightly
coating you know I don't like to do that
too close to a flowering so typically
I'll do one more spray and just kind of
rinse them off
after this maybe with a zero tall or
like a isopropyl alcohol just to kind of
clean them and do a light
pesticide spray
yeah here you have it