this is usually my seasonal storage
Greenhouse just got a bunch of pots and
irrigation lights
[ __ ] but uh
yeah this year I'm gonna be uh just
running
but I got 44 pots in here
probably just do a little Fino Hunts uh
some uh some stuff not really sure quite
yet but I do have you know like the
party lights
that uh that I can control the photo
period
um
got some soil in there I was playing
around with the recipe so
uh yeah
got uh another little grow room back
here this is just kind of my outdoor
breeding area
which is going crazy with the cover crop
um
I haven't really got this thing up and
running
to throw some tobacco seed in there
it's going a little crazy I just pull a
couple of those out and thin them out
um
but this is uh
got the pollen donor pots set up and
then the main beds
but yeah this greenhouse is kind of
seasonal don't really use use it a whole
lot unless I've got a lot going on but
since I've been busy filling pots and
whatnot
um it's kind of just been sitting
waiting for me to plant it
some of my Oz selections back here
a bunch of the uh CBG dominant f2s
um
some uh I've got a uh actually found a
CBG dominant Death Eater Kush
and a
Wizard of Oz CBG dominant believe it or
not so
um
to uh
take off
but uh yeah
it's uh you know starting off slow but
uh I feel like uh
this is what I had envisioned for the
farm you know five years ago so we're
you know just takes time
but uh yeah got everything set up here
for the drip lines
um
typically running you know four rows per
pot
and uh
filter we got eye mineral content in our
in our well water and then just a little
timer gotta get that set up
and uh yeah
this is little our little family farm
hope you guys enjoyed the update what's
been going on I've really been posting a
lot but uh yeah got some fresh cow
manure then I'm going to uh be
composting maybe doing some uh
some warm compost with trying to get
that rolling
it's all screened up it's a little fresh
though so
yeah hope everyone has a good day