check it out so I've seen uh the orchard
guys use these things for uh you know
tying up Vines and whatnot but uh
finally got one for the farm and it's
just a uh Auto taper like typically I've
used that green
metal twine
to save a lot of time
see here
hard to do with one hand but
just uh Staples and uh
plastic tape so
trying to get away from using a trellis
um it definitely serves a purpose and
it's you know quick and quick and dirty
but I don't know we'll see how uh I like
it
probably made a bunch of work for myself
but uh
be nice just working on the plants not
having to get tangled up especially
Harvest Time
so
yeah you haven't uh seen one of these
and still tying up your plants check
them out