what up I figured I'd do a garden update
this morning uh it's been a little while
as it usually is but uh kind of had a
rough start to the year finally got
everything switched over to the big pots
and had a pretty good cycle going and
then uh I decided to spray the uh
the Weeds on the side of my Greenhouse
with some 30 vinegar and uh the plants
did not like it overspray got caught in
the fans
and fried the plants so
as you do in farming how to make the
tough decision whether to uh
replant or try and nurse those along and
since they were already in like the
first week of flowering I just decided
to uh
coal everything and and restart so
fortunately I had a couple trays of some
plants
and uh planted those
and uh we are already flipped again so
set me back I don't know
too
it's a
sure it's not the first time
it's not the last time it's definitely
not the first time so but anyway we got
a
some Auto projects going in here I just
pollinated and see the Fallen sacks
um you can spray everything down here in
a few days and then these
Fino hunt so I definitely learned a lot
from the first run
I had kind of uh the plants over planted
overcrowded so now we're doing
like three plants
per pot in the 200s I've got some
singles
which are doing really good
and uh
yeah
stoked for this run I mean these big
pots have definitely been a learning
curve I'm used to 10 gallons
and plants just don't grow as quick and
don't get as big and so uh
yeah a few you know take your eyes off
them for a second they've gained a foot
so
lights are coming on
um
this is the first Greenhouse uh this
stuff will be ready
but uh got some adus code doing a big
Pinot hunts of Ada's code
also Oz
which is probably one of my favorite
crosses from the Oz series
and then
[Music]
uh got some uh stuff on that back row
but yeah here we have it
haven't even sprayed this crop once
haven't had any pest issues just watered
in some nematodes for the gnats
it's like all this Clover's starting to
die off
but
I guess technically this is like my
second cycle in this this greenhouse
even though I didn't finish the other
one but
yeah got uh gotta finish
bambooing everything trying to move away
from plastic trellising we'll see uh I'm
sure I just made myself
over
it's uh
yeah
yeah Greenhouse number one
it's all set
you can head over to Greenhouse number
two which I direct said
yeah these are
looking good
I figured I'd do a little Auto project
in here before everything gets going so
not getting the best light but
enough to play around with
yeah
so I'm definitely running less plants
but I think I'll be able to see
you know uh their true expression as far
as like
morphology and how they want to grow
naturally
see some of these are kind of lanky
but uh
yeah I'm just running three different
cultivars in here
three of my favorites and
[Music]
uh see uh see how everything does
up over the next train house