how's it going future cannabis project
Community Lobster fam Farms here today
I'd like to go through some of my most
recent techniques and methods to be
viroid safe while taking cuttings
so I like to start by bleaching any and
all tools I will be using to take
cuttings that includes the scissors the
bottom trays the top domes and even the
little plastic containers that I'm going
to be using to put the cubes in and the
rooting solution
and anything you use you want to bleach
thoroughly
we've had these scissors soaking in the
bleach for about 20 minutes
so I've got all my equipment and tools
bleached I've taken a shower and changed
my clothes so I can be as clean as I can
now it's time to set up for taking
cuttings
so I've got some rock wool cubes today
I'm going to be handling everything with
plants or with plant fluid with my left
hand which is going to be gloved at all
times with a different glove for each
plant
so I've got mine for for
rooting mixture water ready
and start soaking some cubes
while those are soaking
I'm going to place in each plastic cup
this isn't something I've ever done
before taking cuttings but thinking
about it long and hard it seems like
this is another way that the fluids can
pass through each other so if you're not
doing one genetic from one plant and a
whole tray this is my preferred
technique where I've bleach these little
cups
do probably
maybe nine per tray maybe only six or
eight but what I'm trying to accomplish
here is making it so that the root base
and the fluids passing through will
never touch each other and I'm going to
try to give them each enough space so
that the plants themselves don't touch
each other if they were from a different
mother plant
cubes are soaked up
with the glove hands
I'm gonna plop one in each
and then after we get those all set up
Next Step begins
so I'm making my labels for the plants
that I'm going to be taking cuttings
from and even this process I'm going to
hold them all with my left hand with a
fresh glove and use the marker with the
right hand just because these are going
to be jammed down in the soil I do not
know how long the fluid would just live
on a piece of plastic and fresh air but
one more thing to keep in mind
so I've got my area staged I've got all
my scissors bleached and cleaned I have
as many gloves as I can fit on my paw
comfortably I can usually fit about nine
or ten before I start losing dexterity
and circulation I have about 18
different plants to take cuttings from
today so two rounds of nine gloves will
do just fine
last thing I'm doing
is putting rooting solution in each of
their own individual cups for the 18
plants
I like to use plastic Dixies and bleach
them but sometimes these little wax
paper ones are good in a pinch they're
quick they're cheap and it doesn't
really like leave too much of the carbon
footprint so
I've got my rooting solution ready one
for each plant
so what I'm running through today I have
eight Harlem River hazes from pifcoast
genetics and I generally like the
morphology so far they got humongous
leaves some of them are narrow some of
them are a little broader but I like the
way they're drawn
next I have some sister nice
that is a Oregon Afghani crossed with a
G13 old school G13 these ones are from
Professor p and Relic seeds and I'm
really digging these ones they got the
super leathery looking leaves dark dark
green now this one right here has a
serious issue that doesn't seem to be
showing itself anywhere else in the
garden so it's got to be a mutation or
something genetic anyone out in the
community who can give me a little
Clarity on this it seems like it's
directly one half of this Leaf directly
these two halves of these Leaf blades I
don't want to go Bro Science and try to
diagnose it if anyone out there knows
better than me let me know
I have four of those then I have these
two that I'm very excited about these
are Oregon Afghani cross with uh the
cheese male the cheese back cross mail
that Professor P messes with these ones
again have super super dark green
leathery leaves squat growth and I'm
really really stoked to see what comes
out of these I only have a couple so
it's kind of a gamble but we'll see it's
always fun
speaking of gambles I have three of the
Holy Communion crossed to a Wilson by a
mortal Hatchery although I don't think
he would call himself a breeder but he
made some seeds they found their way
into my hand and they got wet the next
day so I have four of them this one I
don't think I'm going to take a cutting
off of I just don't like the growth of
it
just I just don't dig it so I got these
three that I'm going to take cuttings
off of this one's super super lanky
this one's got some broader darker
leaves
a little more closer structure but the
branches aren't going out so much this
one I kind of like so far I'm hoping
this one's a tasty female
that's what's on the table today
so I think I'm just gonna do six plants
per tray on this one I have this hand is
going to be my scissor hand every time
that's not going to touch a plant and
it's going to go from this scissor is
going to be put down I'm going to grab a
fresh one every time I'm going to try to
not get plant fluid on this hand
regardless even though ideally it's not
touching another plant each time I go
through a plant I rip off a pair of
gloves and then that is for the next
Plant I have the little cup of rooting
solution that will be just for this
plant
ready to rock and roll now as I've
already gone over in a previous short I
did I like to get at least two
cuttings when I'm first starting so that
I can flour one and keep one as a backup
so I'm going to try to get at least two
off of each plant this first one is the
Holy Communion crossed into the Wilson
and I'll tell you what that sucker looks
covered in grease already
whoa doggy
okay that's fun that's fun
and now this plan is going to rest on
the cup that's going into
this plant smells good man I love this
left
so we have two
of the Holy Communion Wilson number one
is ready to go this set of scissors
going down after I plug those this pair
of gloves coming off actually these
scissors aren't going down yet this is
something I wanted to touch on now I've
been being hyper cautious with this
round of seedlings I haven't even pruned
the cotyledons are like the little
jammies off yet so since I have a pair
of gloves and scissors that correlate
with this plant this is a perfect time
to get in there and prune
and typically I would have already
pruned all this stuff off but again just
trying to be
hyper cautious this round
against this viroid but this is a plant
shape that I much prefer
especially when doing a hunt
because that doesn't take up as much
room
it's not going to transpire as much
maintain it pretty much just get cuts
off of it
and another thing to consider that I
just thought of since I'm doing so many
less
plants than typical on a tray like this
the little micro climate in there is
going to be something to consider now
I'm going to take some bigger cuts to
try to fill that area out but whatever
your Technique is going to be if it gets
too dry in there obviously the Coatings
aren't going to be happy so if you're
ever going to do this few Cuts per tray
most people do 50 20 at least
you're gonna have to keep that in
consideration the microclimate is going
to be a little different so these are
soaked for a solid 10 seconds or so
I'm going to use the sand glove
I think that sucker right now
use this same glove
I don't see how this could be a male
this thing reeks
and so now those two plants are going to
take up that little area
these ones are going to get their own
area even though they're sisters
and pro they came from the same you know
flower
just in case
they're all going to get their own space
I haven't heard conclusively from anyone
yet if there is a 10 pass of the viroid
through seeds doesn't seem like it's
really proven yet so I'm going to assume
yes and that if I have 18 cuttings in
here most likely two of them are coming
equipped with the Violet so why not just
keep them all separate and keep them
safe
from there it's a good way to start
things at least
so this plant's prunes
his glove off
onto the next one wash rinse repeat
some final thoughts on hot plate and
prevention
when taken cutting so it's not just when
taking Coatings it's all throughout the
entire gardening process even late stage
transmission can lead to some funky
flowers so I've been trying to train
myself to be super diligent one thing I
like about the garden beds is that if
you do the same genetic ideally from the
same mother plant let's assume the
plants are clean to start then you can
only have to use one set of scissors per
day
on you know or one one pair of scissors
per bed which is ideal to me that like
I'm like not stripping gloves off all
the time and just being able to go at it
and not have to worry about all the
little hiccups in between that really
helps me a lot
um
some questions I have for the community
if anyone else knows like I'd love to
know some things how long does this how
long can the viroids survive on
fingertips like let's assume I had dirty
practices pinching some leaves off of
some Infected plants how long can it
live in that fluid on my fingertips
how long can it live on the plant fluid
on the scissors let's say I missed
something and shared scissors with a
plants that I shouldn't have but it was
like you know let's say in theory 10
days apart can that fluid still be
living on those scissors what's the
expiration date and how that can
correlate too it's like let's say I I
pruned an infected plant two days ago I
got plant fluid on my hand that was the
last thing I did now I'm going to a
clean Garden is like my watering
practices and me touching the bucket and
like my hand even touching the water
that's the mixture is that a possible
transmission I don't think so but like I
want these things to be clearly laid out
that's for sure one thing I would love
too is to see clear concise conclusive
evidence if the viroad is being passed
by pests or not I feel like then all of
these techniques are for not if it's
just going to be as simple as uh having
a bug come in bite won't plant and bite
another I've heard very conflicting
views on this subject I'd love to raise
the conversation more I'm not educated
enough and you know entomology or plant
biology to speculate but I'm assuming it
can you know but I want to know how long
can that plant fluid survive on a pests
you know anthers or you know wherever
this fluid is smothered in its face so
I'd love to keep this conversation going
I love to hear other people's approaches
and techniques if anyone sees any Folly
in my Approach I'd love to hear that as
well
and uh nothing but respect and most love
to the Cannabis community
peace out