[Music]
so
hey friends greens goddess here uh today
i'm going to put together another 3x6
foot fabric pop bed and i just wanted to
share with you guys how i'm doing it in
case if you wanted to start growing your
own cannabis medicine from home you
could go with pots or you could go with
a nice big fabric pot bed if you're
going to decide to go with a nice big
fabric pop bed let me show you how to
set it up so first of all
we got a nice
three by six foot fabric pop bed i got
this from buildasoil.com
um it's made by grassroots
the first thing that you want to do when
you're setting up a bed is to prepare
for what's going to go underneath
because you're probably going to
experience some water runoff so what i
built was
a bed frame and it looks like this it's
made by two by fours
it's uh 78 inches
in length and these ones are 35 inches
in width
and then i got this material
to help all of the rain water come down
to one area
when i go to set up my frame see it
looks like this on the floor
one thing that you want to keep in mind
on one end you're going to have a little
lip over the edge of this so that way
the water can go over the lip and it
could collect into a tray in case if you
water too much and then at the other end
i made one of these things it's just to
lift it up
um give it a few two inches on one end
so in case if the water comes down it'll
all go out the other end so
what i'm going to do is just lift this
end up
slide that underneath
then i'm going to go ahead
and take my huge fabric pop bed
and put it on top
i already built the whole thing together
see how nicely it fits on top of there
it's perfect
with these measurements you get like a
few extra inches on each side
so when you buy this fabric potbed
it comes with these pieces it comes with
these pieces
but what you want to do
it actually comes with these pieces for
your corners you're going to want to get
the upgrade
which gets you this piece if you don't
have it at your local lowe's or home
depot store
this piece you could put another pvc
pipe going up and that'll be your frame
that you would put your trellis on
so let me give you the measurements
because if you're to buy
the fabric pop bed three by six from
build a soil they don't come
with a one inch pvc pipe you got to go
to the store and get it yourself if
you're going to do that you want to take
cuttings and i have it all written down
right here
um for your 3x6 fabric pop bed you're
going to need 1 inch pvc pipe for your
legs you're gonna want four legs
uh cut at 17 inches
the length there's four sides
one two three four
those are going to be cut at 32 and a
half inches and then for your width
you're going to want two pieces at 31
inches so
in case if you're wanting to make your
own bed
that's how you cut your pvc pipe and it
all goes together like that see
now we're going to fill it let me show
you what i got
following leighton's advice about the
soil horizons first we're going to start
with rocks
then we're going to come in with some
sand that i collected from the beach
during my most recent trip to california
including crushed oyster shells
i got natural soil from my backyard
i even went out to the mountains and
connect collected some natural soil from
there
over here i have like these are sticks
old sticks from old harvest these are
leaves from my avocado tree when they
died off these are old avocado pieces
from old avocado tech
so
that's all going to go in your middle
layer
your very top layer is going to be your
coot's mix
i got another video how showing how to
put your coots mixed together you could
use anybody's mix that you want to use
you don't even have to make your own if
you don't want to if you want you could
buy somebody else's i'm just showing you
how i fill my beds
there's good snacks
smells very nice
right
let's get started
because i've been waiting all weekend to
fill this bed i just wanted to make sure
i had all of my material so that i could
show you guys how to do it
okay so the first thing i'm going to do
is i'm going to go ahead and lift up
this side and put that um
stand underneath it so that way we know
this side of the bed is going to lift up
in case if there's any extra water it's
all going to come out towards the front
of the room
think about when you're doing this where
you want to position your bed in the
room once you fill it there's like no
going back it's going to be full and
it's going to be really heavy
all right and i make sure that i got my
fabric pot in the center of my frame
perfect we're ready to rock and roll
first thing i want to do
is throw down some rocks and you go wild
crafting for rocks
what you want to look for is smaller
pieces like this
about an inch
these pieces are a bit too big but
that one's got a lot of beautiful
granite minerals in it
i only have about like a small handful
pieces this big the majority of my
pieces are small
like this
the first layer is going to be all of
your rocks
first
[Applause]
your first layer only needs to be a
couple of inches tall
maybe about three four inches tall not
too crazy
if you're looking at your fabric pot
beds
you'll see where there's a white
thing here helps keep in the moisture
and the water
underneath that at the very bottom
probably about three or four inches so
think about your rock layer being a
little bit less than that definitely not
going over
there we go
two bucketfuls is definitely not enough
rocks
[Music]
i'm gonna have to go out and get some
more rocks
you wanna make sure that your whole
entire bottom layer of your bed is
completely filled with one inch rocks
okay so
i had to go back and get more rocks
but here they are
see how it's like completely covering
the bottom
the next thing i'm going to add is some
sand
so your very very bottom layer
is going to be
rocks and sand
i like that that one has the oyster
shells in it i got this down
from my most recent trip back home to
santa cruz
so it means a lot to me i also found
like this floating driftwood it looks
like a rock but it's actually really
wood
and it was floating in the sea i thought
it was awesome it's probably going to be
filled with
all sorts of nutrients from the sea
and plus when you put wood in your beds
in the organic layer it provides a nice
food source for a fungi which you want a
lot of fungi in your soil when you're
going
canvas more sand along these edges
just to kind of get it nice and even
let me show you guys what i'm talking
about
let's see
so i'm just going to spread it out like
this
so now this layer
is rocks and sand
that's your bottom layer
see how i'm just kind of spreading it
out
to the corners
making sure that it covers depending on
where you live you'll be able to
wildcraft a lot of this stuff naturally
i live out here in colorado so
i got clay soil i don't got a sandy soil
so sands all at the bottom
make sure you spread it out nice
and then after you spread it out you get
it nice and wet with just a little bit
of water like the sprayer
i'm using um the shower setting on my
sprayer
just to get it a little bit wet
kind of helps compact everything down if
you just spray it very lightly when you
do each layer
that's good nothing too much
all right so your next layer is going to
be your organic material
now what i have is a bunch of um
i have a bunch of old pots i've been
doing living soil in the same pots for a
couple of years now so these pots have
seen a lot of runs they already have
worms they already have high voice
smiles and nematodes
um they're pretty much
mainly uh
possibly just worm castings at the
bottom of these pots since they're so
small like 10 gallons and i've been
reusing them so many times this is why i
decided to go with a larger bed because
if i'm going to be reusing my soil i
want to have a much bigger
area for everything to grow and move
around in versus having all these
individual little pots that i have to
keep picking up and moving this way
um you just grow the plant from the time
it's this big to the time it's ready to
harvest
no picking up and moving things from one
room to the other room
so let me bring in my pots and i'll go
over all that
this was old 10 gallon pot
reused many many times
it's had it's been amended it's got tons
of castings it's had cover crops it's
had mulch all over it
this is going to be my organic layer
these old pots
and i'm also gonna throw
some old branches from old harvest that
wood that we were talking about earlier
before the fungi
this is still soaking wet at the bottom
and
i haven't even watered it in a couple
days because there were no plants in it
but um
let me show you what my first one looks
like
you see how wet it is
but oh man if you smell this it smells
amazing
this
i've always used coot's mix you could
use whoever's mix that you want
you could go to the store and buy a mix
there's a few companies that sell good
mix all ready to go like build a soil
um
who else big farms oh i found a
a worm
big roots
do you see this guy
they need to wake up
so i got three of those that i'm going
to put at the bottom of here
and then we'll see how full it gets
okay now we're back
um
okay first of all let me show you guys
what i did i got my um three
old soil pots that have been retailed
recycled over and over and over again
that's gonna make up my organic layer
the three pots three 10 gallon pot so
that's 30 gallons total
um this is what it looks like it's
pretty wet pretty moist in here i got
like my worms
my beneficial bugs i already got my um
organic
microbials growing one more thing i
wanted
to let you guys know um the funny thing
is while i was spreading this out
i happened to come across the corner and
i told you guys about putting a lip here
so that way water could come out
and um what i did was i sliced my foot
going across the corner here and i had
to go to the hospital to get stitches
and i'm thinking
i could have gotten this bed done
hours ago but i had to put everything on
hold to go to the hospital and get
stitches and i'm sitting there thinking
you want to if i'm gonna make a video
showing everybody how to do this a
certain way
i mean at least let it be me who gets
the stitches so i could warn everybody
so it's not them i don't want you guys
copying what i do and getting hurt from
it so
let me show you what i should have done
this corner
i'm gonna get my favorite pair of
scissors
and i'm just going to cut a curve
save that piece throw it in the garbage
don't want to step on it
and now i have a rounded corner
no more slices on my ankle
no more visits to the doctor's office
please then i'm gonna get duct tape just
for added measure
almost happen again did you guys see
that jeez
okay i'm gonna pin this down and i'm
going to put duct tape all along the
edge here as long as it's sticking out
of the wood you're going to want to tape
it up
and i'm going to put it all along the
front edge too
two pieces just to be safe
doesn't have to be perfect it just has
to get the job done of not injuring
yourself
as you're trying to work
all right so now that i've shown that to
you guys
blood guts and tears is that what it
takes to put these beds together watch
out
actually i know a few friends who have
put in beds together several times
and uh they had a hell of a time doing
it i'm not saying that this is easy at
all it's not
so
with our organic layer we also want to
add
native soil ooh my piece of wood i'm
going to save this actually i just want
to put it on top like that native soil i
live out here in colorado we have mostly
clay soil
soil has sand silt and clay
this
is what your
bed needs for its organic material
having samsung play is extremely
important for redox potential
i'm not really going to get into it
because i don't know
everything about redox potential but
there are a million shows on
fcp that they talk about redox potential
mainly it's the um
cation exchange
right between positive and negative
cations
something happens with stem silt and
clay that helps
um
the redox potential and the cation
extends and it's extremely important
so i'm just spreading that out
i used a five gallon bucket
of native soil now
all right so
i had put in
a five gallon bucket of of native soil
from my backyard into here what i did
with it to make sure that i wasn't
getting any bugs
is i dug up a lot of my native soil and
i just let it sit out in the big
container so if there was any bugs in
there they could just crawl away
um now the next thing that i want to add
is a nice big scoop of soil i had gotten
from hiking in the mountains
this one was found near a tree with a
lot a lot of fungi growing from it
so that's going to be super awesome
another organic material i like to add
sticks from old harvests
i could have cut them up and shredded
them i probably should have
i don't really have a lot of time for
that right now
so the reason why i'm adding sticks is
because i want to add any kind of woody
material so any kind of woody material
that you can think of that's what fungi
loves to grow off
i'm just going to spread it around
even if you're outside building a soil
bed i did this outside too
i built my soil bed for my outdoors
tomatoes same way
i used a lot of outdoor wood that was
already lying down everywhere i used
some lawn clippings and i use organic
soil mix that with compost and what not
let's see i have another bag here
this one also has
the leaves from
my um
avocado tree that i have
um when you have dead dying leaves it
still has plenty of
nutrients
inside of it that can be taken up by
fungi bacteria microorganisms worms and
stuff like that they love this
um i have a lot of skins from old
avocados i'm sure if you've been
watching
you know all about the avocado
so nothing too perfect i'm just
spreading it out
and
uh
so i got some old bones i really wanted
to make
water soluble calcium and i just never
really got into collecting enough bones
to char them to do that
and these have been sitting out for a
long time i figured i'd just
put them in there any kind of organic
material
except for your avocado seeds otherwise
you'll end up growing a lot of avocado
trees like me
um
but these are old
old rotten avocados these could go right
in there the worms love it the worms
eat up the avocado they get together
they start rubbing on each other
and having what some would call
worm sex
put in the avocados take out the seeds
avocado tech is typically done on the
soil surface
but
i'm looking for organic material to put
in this layer so
let me show you what i got so far
so i just kind of spread out the sticks
old leaves
old food
nothing too crazy
now
now i am ready
for
my coupons
you could use anyone's mix that you want
to use
i like coot's mix i i made a big huge
like
60 gallons of it and worked out perfect
when you do it this way and you stick
your plants in you don't even have to
worry about feeding it anything your
first round
you just uh let nature take its course
i'm sure you guys don't want to see me
sit here shoveling all this in but i am
being very very careful because of the
stitches on my ankle right now
i'm trying to be uh clean just showing
you
how we're getting this done
i'm going to fill up this bed and show
you what it looks like when i'm finished
hey friends building your own soil
you can make your own mix it's coot's
mix
this part is going to be the total value
of how many gallons you're trying to
achieve
this is a percentage
this part is going to look at your total
cubic feet
and this is how many cups
per cubic feet
of your
total mix
so
uh where i live we don't really have
access to pumice or scoria so in the
place of that i use rice hulls
and i did get some pumice from bonsai
jack most of this will be rice hull so
i also got peat
i got a bio char i got that from build
the soil i was short so i had to get
some more from the grow store
i got worm castings compost
azomite oyster shell
crab meal malted barley
basalt
um gypsum
and we're getting it all put together
60 gallons
coots mix super soil
when you're all done mixing it you could
put it in a big root barrel
and this is what it should look like
super super blended you can't even tell
the difference of all the ingredients
that were put into here
it's a lot a lot of mixing
there we go
all right now that we got the bed filled
with our 60 gallons of coots mix
we're pretty much done with this part as
you can see i still got plenty of space
from where the top of the soil is to
where my bed is which is fun
because over the years as i'm digging
out a hole and planting in a new plant
it's going to continuously add more and
more as i top dress with like
mulch from the plants or when i top
dress with things like compost or
whatever it's going to keep adding more
and more layers so this doesn't have to
be completely full to the top right here
is good enough for now
um let me just show you
see cook's a lovely mix
all in there looking great
nice and smooth
uh what i like to add now
is some compost you can get any compost
that you like
uh i found a bag of
this compost
it works out just fine i don't have too
much left in this bag i'm going to use
what i have now
um i might end up going to the store to
get more
so i'll use what i have for now and
spread it out i don't need too much
it's just um
going to be available for the plants
when they come in here so that's not
going to be for a few days anyways
this is what i have left of fukashi i'm
also going to get more bokashi
i usually would get bokashi either from
growing organic
or from um bokashi earthworks
i'm just gonna sprinkle it like that for
now i'm going to go back and buy more
compost and more book kashi and you
really don't need to add too much
technically you don't need to add any at
all this is just my way of giving this
bed an extra boost for the plants
also
we have build the soils cover crop blend
i like this crop blend um not everybody
does a cover crop
but on a bed i definitely do not mind it
so i'm just going to sprinkle this cover
crop on top
like that i'm going to get everything
wet
i'm going to come back with
probably just a tad more compost than
bokashi not even too much let's see what
it looks like now see
and i kind of want to like
like that
sprinkle it around
get it going like this
when you put plants in here you really
don't need to add anything whatsoever
you could just water and go
um
let's see
yeah
looks like we're about done i'm just
gonna get my uh watering wand
i'm just gonna get my watering wand and
get this nice and wet
so when i put a bed together like this
[Music]
adding as much
amendments as i added with coot's mix
you might want to let it sit for a few
days to cook
basically what they mean by that is it
takes some time for all these amendments
to get together and
coagulate and all that stuff it could be
a little bit too hot right now to put
plants in so you just want to give it
some time to work itself
together
um it don't take too long
i know sub cool has a super soil recipe
that he recommends that it be cooked for
about 30 days
some people when you're looking at their
recipes that give you a recommendation
on how long to let it cook for they mean
how long to let it sit all collectively
together
anyone can make their own medicine
you can make it in your backyard
you can make it in your house
just keep in mind that if you make it in
your house
you're going to want a frame to put it
on and
you're going to want to tape up the
corners don't cut yourself like i did
um
i
have found it pretty easy
doing pots
growing with pots all my life to
understand how to water pots
by weighing it you cannot pick up a bed
and weigh it so
the only way to really tell if your bed
needs water
i usually look at the plants the plant
leaves it starts going down like okay it
needs a little water
sometimes i'll just stick my finger
right in there
if i stick my finger in there and it's
way too dry then i'm gonna water it
nothing too much i give a little bit of
water probably let it sit for about five
minutes come back and give it a little
bit more water because it just kind of
takes time for all the water to go down
so that's about it for now i'm gonna let
this sit for about a week or two and
give it some time to cook and uh then
i'll be ready to put my plants in
uh now make sure when you have your room
set up for your bed you're gonna want to
set your lights at like a veg cycle at
first while your plants are growing tall
until they get about i would say up to
here
and once they're about this tall then
you'll want to switch your light cycle
from
one of most people have it at 16
16 hours on or 18 hours on
no
i usually you do my light cycle and veg
it's like 20 hours of light four hours
of darkness
but uh and you don't have to do it that
way some people do it differently when
you're going to flower you've got to do
12 12 which means 12 hours of light 12
hours of darkness so you put your plants
in you let them grow until they're about
this tall and then you switch your light
cycle you do that just on the timer it's
so easy you don't have to pick up this
huge plant and then move it to another
room which is what i've been doing for
years so
this makes it a lot easier
i really like the bed it makes it makes
my life so much easier doing it this way
um i'm going to get some lights in here
to go over the bed um
you could also do autos autos are great
you don't got to worry about a photo
period with autos you got this huge bed
they got plenty of room for their roots
to spread if you get hooked up with a
really great
uh auto breeder then you'll have some
really amazing auto plants so we'll see
how that goes
um
let me show you guys
it's just nice and wet
i'm just letting the water uh take some
time to sink down so that's all just
wanted to show you guys that
um
oh yeah if you want to see my stitches
stick around i'll take you
into a different room not in this room
and open up my bandage and show you my
cool scars
take care everybody peace out
all right now that we're all cleaned up
um
if you guys are anything like me and you
don't like looking at
cuts scars anything inside the skin or
stitches
now is a really good time to click that
like button and go ahead and shut off
this video but if you're a weirdo who
likes to look at scars and stitches
i'm going to show you the cut that i got
earlier that got me going to the
hospital for stitches so let's take a
look
oh this is so gross i haven't even
opened it up yet so this is my first
time
oh
ew
you see that
safety first ladies and gentlemen
make sure that you're cutting those
corners and putting your duct tape on
them you do not want to slice your foot
off of the metal from that material
trying to put a bed together the things
that i do for fcp
never cease to amaze me i just wanted to
give you a little update on the bed so
far i did put some lights over it and
since
i only need a light on for the little
seedlings i decided to go with just my
315 lec for now
i'm giving it just a little bit of
microbial tea nothing too much i just
wanted to keep it a little moist
[Music]
as i go through harvest i'm gonna chop
up the stems and whatnot try to create a
nice mulch layer
some of the seedlings are starting to
grow
there are also some areas where i had
put the bokashi that had started to
create some fungi which is really nice
when i get more bokashi in i'm gonna
sprinkle it on top with a little bit of
compost and then i'm gonna put the mulch
layer over that and then we'll update
you guys when we're ready to transplant
some plants in here
hey everybody we're back it's been two
weeks since we've uh put this bed in and
so now we got a little bit of cover crop
growing
we've got a nice mycelium connection
already happening i went ahead and
transplanted a few plants
if you're lucky you live in a state like
colorado then everybody gets to at least
have six plants
uh or i've heard people out in canada at
least get to have four
however many plants you want to put in
your bed is totally up to you
more plants doesn't necessarily mean
more yields because you can train them
if you wanted to so anyways i'm just
showing this with the six plants in the
bed
so first what i want to do is
get a nice little shovel
to uh move it apart just a little bit
i kind of like saving the little woods
that i call it
but i'm made mainly uh just building a
small enough hole to put that in
try not to disturb it too much because
the uh mycelium in here is really
looking nice
um one thing i like to sprinkle down
this is azos
it's a beneficial bacteria
i sprinkle this in the bottom of the pot
one spoonful for a plant
take the tan glass
you take your pot you squeeze it at the
bottom
and it should pop out easily
i put um perlite at the bottom of all my
pots so when i put a transplant then
it's easy to loosen it up and get the
roots
right there to make contact with the
azos or any other beneficial bacteria
that you may find at your local store
push it all back into place make sure
that my plant is sticking straight up
and if i
move the lid ceiling
just to kind of give you an idea of how
it's all stuck together
i like to put it right back on top
just to kind of put nature back in place
right now dude
all right that's looking good
don't forget to put your tack to your
plank in case if you have a few
different strings in the same bed
i like to hook this somewhere where it's
not going to get wet when i water it
so now that that's all done some of my
last steps
are to top dress just a little bit with
some bokashi
just a little all over the bed because
this is definitely what helps get that
my ceiling going
differently
i also like to top dress with some
compost
this is a malibu's
um
uh biodynamic compost mixed with
fruits organic baked grounds compost
and the final thing that i like to do
with my new transplants and a nice new
bed
i don't need to um amend this i would
amend this if it was um used but since
this is my first round no i'm ending
just um composting compost tea
another thing that i love about having
these plants um in the beds is as i'm
giving a nice soil trench i can also
give it a foliar spray
that way this nice microbials and this
gene knot are not only are going in
their soil but they're also going on the
leaves
there's more than one way for our plants
to get taken through one way through
roots
and the other way is on the leaves
that's all
i would say i probably lightly mist this
like this every other day
just a little bit of water i don't give
it too much
i would say this is probably one gallon
we think about how much soil is in here
one gallon isn't a lot and i definitely
go really really slow with the water
just like this
while i was transplanting i noticed
this one was a little bit more moist
than this like this so i'm just going to
keep that in mind when i water
try to focus on this i get just a bit
more attention
that's it
i hope you guys enjoyed this video and i
hope it helps you learn how
one method anyways how you could grow
your own campus
good luck everybody take care
you