[Music]
welcome to nothing for sale the review
show by custies for custias
what's up guys i'm og is my oxygen this
is packs to the future off to the side
here and uh today we're here to review
some outdoor donnie burger before we get
into that i just want to talk a little
bit about myself i'm a grower i'm a
glass blower
[Music]
i also you know work in media worked on
documentaries worked on live visuals
and also
now i'm going to be working with peter
at future cannabis project to help
produce some content
and uh pax why don't you tell us a
little bit about yourself as well
so excited to be here i think i'm really
an enthusiast
learning about growing now but not as
accomplished as you are so many of the
amazing people on this channel started
out as a fan watching peter
watching everyone that he brought on
it's really marvelous content and we're
just super excited to be here
i do strain reviews and you know i'm
super excited to be here doing strange
reviews with you bro
appreciate it dog appreciate it yeah um
and you know big shout out to future
cannabis project and peter for having us
on and uh we're stoked for many more
reviews in the future
so particularly excited about this
donnie burger which is han solo burger
xgmo the han solo burger is gmo x lario
g
um gmo you know chem x cookies
so a ton of gmo chem terps i think in
this obviously
too it's the rubber glove squared and i
like to i like to describe the like
super like acrid like
uh almost kind of like some people might
call it a fuel ear chem terp i like to
call it that like rubber glove or latex
glove tip it's just like pungent and
like it hits your nose it's like it's
it's really acrid and i really enjoy
that and honestly associate that with a
lot of cannabis that gets me really
really stoned totally specifically the
gmos because you've got what like four
different instances of gmo showing up in
this like genetic a lot of cam
engineering yeah a lot of chemicals for
sure and it's what's really exciting is
this is an outdoor
grow and there's a lot of
buzz going on right now around the chart
that was developed by the emerald cup
indicating that you know you see
significantly higher terpene percentages
and outdoor flowers and like you were
saying this has that acrid tennis ball
but also really meaty like kind of bacon
grease
and also not dissimilar i mean i don't
know why it would be awesome if someone
could tell us in the comments where the
burger came from and han solo burger but
there's a meaty quality definitely it's
like when you're frying bacon and it
just fills the kitchen for hours and
fills your nose and you can't get rid of
the smell but
you know the way i described that some
might not think of as very pleasant but
with this
with this donnie burger it's quite
pleasant and i think there's a real
movement back towards chem terms there's
a lot of discussion around
candy and the candy way of being over
and people wanting to go back to gas and
ogs and i think for a lot of purists
that's chem 91 totally like okay so i
just cracked this right now we'll both
take a sniff a bit
this right now is just like it honestly
like it it honestly kind of smells like
oatmeal like a fresh thing of oats like
the funk of the grains and like the
and i know some people might think
that's a bland description but i think
it's a very like significantly funky
description like
like almost like
you know to get into the kind of wine
descriptors almost like uh like a barn
floor hay kinda there totally is a
grassy quality i also got a buttered
popcorn when i was smelling it last but
that chem dude that [ __ ] that glove
smell and here i'll hand off this nug
that i just cracked for you to smell and
invigorate your senses you're thinking
we don't know where this was grown but
it was clearly
grown under beautiful sunlight in
really rich healthy soil and the flower
indicates you know a very happy growing
environment really a lot of the textural
qualities
that you would see in outdoor
are mitigated by just how overwhelmingly
sticky this is to me i think that while
it's not incredibly frosty it has great
trichome definition and it was clearly
you know living in an environment where
it wanted to produce all of those
natural defenses definitely i think um
this one was possibly done in northern
california which as many people know is
one of the best um best tier wars in
california for growing outdoor cannabis
possibly mendocino possibly humboldt um
but
looking at this it's just it looks like
a really happy plant looks like it was a
very happy plant i mean just on the way
this is growing the you know the
[Music]
the little leaves and the calyxes are
pointing up like the whole thing was
praying its whole life so
it's definitely an indicator that
something's good and it's swollen and
greasy it's
all right guys we're going to roll this
one up now um
we've smoked this one already and it got
us incredibly high but ultimately the
best test is going to be smoking on
camera and describing the experience as
it happens
um but we we really enjoy this donnie
burger
it's
definitely a strong one um just similar
to the gmos and the chems
uh you know wait till i'm done clacking
this to describe it
there's a narcotic profile to the
terpenes i mean even when you're
smelling it in the room
there's something woozy and skunky yeah
it will absolutely do the trick
definitely
so we're gonna light this joint up here
once again this is the donnie burger
outdoor unknown grower given to us by
peter from future cannabis project shout
out to you peter
we're excited about these terps gmo
i think
and z are the two strains right now
where
i don't mind that someone is just
inbreeding it to itself totally
you can you know double up on some of
those amazing qualities of those strains
and take it in different directions i i
do think there's there's a distinct
meatiness to this that is interesting
yeah right off the bat the flavor is
really
chemi gmoe
uh definitely like
full bodied smoke
um you get some of that garlic you get
some of that fuel you get some of that
meatiness
let's take another puff
just off the aroma of the smoke i'm
getting that acrid raw garlic for sure
yeah definitely some garlic very like
you know when i say accurate i don't
mean
anything you know unpleasant but it's
you know if you've smoked a lot of gmo
or a lot of cam you know what i'm
talking about
and i think that unfortunately we were
born too late for it but
those skunk one terps and those true
really funky dead body road kill terps
yeah people the poopies some people call
it yeah
not necessarily a negative thing no
people breed stuff for those poopings we
were highlighting this earlier and i'm
feeling it again it's a very smooth
smoke the ash isn't as clean as some
indoor and that is to be expected i
think
but
now going into our third joint of this
neither of us have coughed yeah and it's
very pleasant interpret on my
respiratory system i enjoy it yeah it's
a really good joint the inhale has all
that funk and that chem and the fuel and
then the exhale is pleasantly sweet
almost like they may have like finished
with a molasses or something like that
um i know personally in my garden in the
past we finished with a molasses type
product or a sugar type product just to
sweeten it up
but you know there's all kinds of ways
to do that including just letting the
genetics rock
um you saying that
i do get
a distinctly
molassesy
flavor yeah on the back end i wonder
what that is it's almost like
gingerbread really delicious totally
overall this is a very pleasant smoke
the joints burning great
the you know there's apparent resin
at the top some people call that the
resin ring
um
yeah overall really pleasant and the
stone you know i've smoked this is my
third one now
the high on it is really really good at
first it's kind of clear-headed as you
start to feel it build behind your eyes
but then it becomes like a really
powerful you know full mind and body
stone
and while the bag appeal is not the same
as some of the indoor production work
that is definitely more popular than
this i i would say that this smokes
significantly
better yeah you're not going to find
something as good as you know this
outdoor donnie burger at a dispensary
that's for sure
and now that we're a couple minutes into
this joint
the effects are pretty consistent to
when we smoked it last
it's pressure behind my eyes for sure
it's it's a classic
more indica type high it's super
pleasant and something
but it isn't a straight thc blast which
is what gets me
excited about trying outdoor
um i think so many of the strains that
are being bred for the metric market and
percentages
are really
unfocused and just
a neurological blast and it's just
not as pleasant as something like this
that does feel
very harmonious and it makes sense that
nature constructed both definitely
i feel like with these organic terroir
based outdoor terps you know
you're getting a euphoric pleasant
in pretty you know individualized to the
strain experience that's based on how it
was grown and you know what kind of you
know inputs and genetics and stuff too
but really
when you get those uh
i i guess the simplest way to put it is
this weed makes you feel really good um
the living soil outdoor type weed just
it's euphoric on another level and you
can't compare that to dispensary hydro
weed which you know
to a lot of people would just make you
feel kind of panicky whereas this stuff
really makes you feel enlightened or
just
great to be honest
yeah it does feel like
slide it or not
i've heard people
describe
thc as like being the engine of a plane
and the terpenes as being the rudders
and when things are
you know out of balance the plane
crashes right
um so it's
a joy to smoke something that's sort of
harmonious yeah definitely
yeah
i mean this is just absolutely
incredible if you can get your hands on
some of this donnie burger if you you
know are in the know then get yourself
some
and you know big shout out to future
cannabis project everybody drop a
subscribe and a like
comment what you liked about the video
um and if there's anything else you want
to see us review if there's anything
else i think
we're definitely trying to get into
landry stuff we're super excited about
outdoor but we also love
good good pipe weed and you know are
just excited to share it all with you
through that guys appreciate it
[Music]