so i feel like this is a
a good time to highlight some of the
irrigation system going on too
yes dude so that was another part i want
to get to so we did this all in-house
this is all our design
um everything is
and we'll walk up there and i'll show
you too but we have there's there's
over 100 year old hand-dug ditches that
bring the water from the river across
the property
everything was set up to be flood
irrigated so there's these little
sort of outlets where the water you just
put a tarp down and it just flows
and that's how these fields were were
done and since mostly for cattle and for
grass
or hay you know that'll work but
what the problem has been is that these
things are over 100 years old and hand
dug they leak like crazy
so water being such a precious resource
out here
you got to have it you got to be able to
protect it and contain it and bring it
where you want it to be and not waste it
along the way
so we're the only farm on this
river system right here that have piped
our ditches
and so that way we've removed that
leakage and everything else and so what
we put is a bulge pond i'll show you
guys up here in a minute
that brings our water from through the
pipe ditches not wasting a drop
puts it in the bulge pond and then our
irrigation system
comes out from the bottom of it with a
main line heading to two brewer tanks
and then we put in main underground main
line and then headers that go up into
each one of these
and i can literally flip a switch and
water the whole garden at once
amazing so amazing and jeremy
how much of what you guys do at cannabis
conservancy focuses on the
water conservation it's a big part of
what we do water energy
waste it's a metric to help help the
farmer reduce it not only
recognize it but also reduce it we're
also here casey is one of our flagships
on
earth we're cannabis conservancy is part
of that too so not only regenerative but
sustainable farming and that's
that's really really our focus is to
helping the farmer
recognize their practices and seeing
where they can better save
water save you know reduction reduce
waste etc
so you're kind of like handing the
farmer a magnifying glass and saying hey
take a closer look at this component
let's take a look at this component
let's take a look at this component and
elevate it all
absolutely absolutely i like i like the
analogy there
awesome what a great concept to improve
the growth of medicine that's improving
the lives of so many people
this is another farm favorite this is
the funfetti cake you made that one
casey yeah this one is
farm fetty cake crasher by cookies and
cream
the trichome stacking on that is
ridiculous stacked
great nose too doughy sweet is that the
cookies and cream coming out of it i
think so
it's really
yeah the way it knocks out like that
yeah this one definitely
a lot of people a lot of people in the
dispensaries been like yes bring more
funfetti
this one was just recently planted um
each one of these houses now is going to
get
uh is in the process of getting sort of
a depth makeover
um where will force flower on these
houses in
third week of july 20th around the 20th
a problem that we've had at this
particular site it's a really
interesting microclimate
so we're at the bottom of a hill there
right on this flat
right on the river and at the bottom of
the hill on the other side so we have
this natural cold sink
and the last three years we've been
hammered by cold weather in fact on
october 25th
of 2020 it was 16 degrees in the garden
oh my goodness which is like colder than
anywhere else in the valley
in the greater valley i mean this was
this was insanely cold
and we had a tremendous amount of loss
so we feel if like if we can
depth these out being that we have the
infrastructure let's get in
before the frost even has a chance to
mess us up
yeah head start man jump that what three
to four weeks on the natural flowering
exactly
okay i really like that you can kind of
see in the
you know fresh planting a little bit
more of the layers yeah
so we've got the wood chips we've got
our compost
we've added some earthworm castings on
top but
underneath is just the native soil and
we
we're saying it's just a native soil but
it's so much more given the years
yep of sheet mulching and like bringing
it back so it's
this is the essence of regenerative
agriculture you take semi
dead soil from years and years of solar
abuse and whatnot and
overgrazing over you know over ag
practices that didn't necessarily
jive with with a a regenerative
format you know that of just heavy
watering this particular
piece of property was one of the
original homesteads in this little
applegate valley
and it hadn't been farmed in 50 years
when we got it there was just a
tremendous amount of grass
kind of overgrown and maybe even a
little bit of marshyness
from sort of the leaky ditches and
everything else and
we just sort of set to work on it laying
down mulch
and and getting it better and then every
year
we get more productivity out of the
plants and out of the garden
[Music]
you