back out in the woods there are a ton of
mushrooms all over this fallen tree
let's see got some down
here little oyster mushroom type of
thing I'm not a myologist I don't know
y'all can always help me out we got some
of these big Brack
mushrooms we
got this here it's not turkey tail
something else but there's it's loaded
on the bottom end of the tree with
them it's
covered more of them as I grow out the
side we got some big bracks on
top anyway I'm going to grab some of
these
mushrooms and just see what eventually
I'll do with
them all right nice little spot that I
found a lot of good sponge wood you can
already see how this has just totally
turned to beautiful what I call native
soil I'll come back and get every bit of
this this whole log is sponge
wood look at
that starts getting hard there boom get
soft right here on the end all this on
the end be great look at that big let's
pull this chunk off see what we look
like that guys that's all sponge wood is
is super duper soft look at the
beautiful mycelium
growing come
on come
on and that's why stump wood is
fantabulous sponge wood all that good
stuff go out and Hunt guys get it look
at the size of this tree guys that goes
for a long ways splits at the top
there's tons of good stuff on a good old
dead log like this that's a big one
first of all that means I'll be coming
back out here for years to
come oh here we go I want to show you
this this is what's great about stumps
this is a crease of it all right here
what I would call native soil but this
stuff is simply dark humic
soil look at that y'all I could take
that home and I could grow cannabis in
it and me I grow anything in that right
there but that's so full of humic acids
that kind of stuff will adust just pH
naturally you can make add the native
soil to your imo3 to make a native soil
im4 like I've shown but I will come back
and I'm just going to scoop stuff like
that out from the cracks it's perfectly
broken down
wood
gorgeous beautiful large
stump but up top is what I'm looking at
watch
that that'll break up real fast whenever
I make IMO 3 with it that is sponge wood
it's sponge because it'll soak up as
much water as a sponge whe this stuff is
nice and dry this is a type of material
that I could take back and make bokashi
with it you can Bashi any dry organic
matter so good
stuff all right so this is one thing we
talked about on Friday Night Live with
Mi beneficials and at rubber ducky
isopods when the leaves are down there's
nothing in your
way spot mushrooms a long ways away you
see them over
there lots of them let's go see what
they look
like o these are pretty white ones real
pretty just totally undisturbed I don't
know the names of it just a basic Brack
mushroom
yeah real nice again I can take these
home shred them you could ferment these
um I've never done a fermented extract
with these this type of mushroom but I
plan on trying it with a lot of
different mushrooms lyen funy these got
really big here oh wow look guys look at
those big
ones look is my hand some fatties
there real pretty all right right found
some big fatties I going to cut one off
to show you how big they are they're
angled
[Music]
down pretty nice size right
there four holdes on the bottom no gills
you can see it's already breaking down
this stuff would again just that would
make really good soil it'll break down
it's beautiful dark soil this kind of
stuff I'm looking for sponge wood again
this might be the softest sponge wood I
have found see how thick it is let's see
how far deep it goes into
it oh my well it's completely sponge
wood one hard little core in there I can
feel but that is
all
beautiful
yep you take that back and you shred it
add some acorns to it let it sit you'll
have great soil in just a few weeks
stuff you can use in your soil anyway
this right here would just turn into
just soil
quick kinds of cool stuff in there good
log and this is called a honey hole the
tree is actually leaned over a little
bit so everything falls off right here
you can see how a big massive chunk it's
falling off it's all sponge wood but
this would be what I would get in this
pile this is where the tree fell down
but all of this is just the broken down
log would you look at that soil this is
native soil right here I could take this
back I could grow in it I've done it
before this is Mother Nature's im4 right
native soil tons of microbiology in
there again we imitate what Mother
Nature makes so when I take it into
Gasoline Alley I'm imitating nature
nature does IM o4s imo3 you just got to
go find it this is Nature's
im4 another massive massive tree that I
can get right into the middle
of scoop out everything all the bark
it's falling down on the ground that's
all good stuff to
shred oh yeah come on now look at
that shred that up you can make bokashi
like I said shred it up using an
imo3 use it in im4 shred it up and put
it in your garden break it with a hammer
spread it out on your no tills fungi
loves wood this stuff is eaten up with
it see what's underneath the
leaves that's that's Mother Nature's im4
right look at that how dark that soil
is
excellent all right little tree with
turkey tail old turkey tails on
them we get a shot how close we can get
you can see they're kind of
fuzzy the base there got the turkey tail
fan and then on the back Spore
holes these are quite old but I'm going
to gather them all up
some big
chunks come back to this
log summertime fall
time hit
again this log has puff balls all over
it
all those
spes show you
place they really released a lot of
spores look at
that all over the
place all right here's a good example of
sponge
wood you see it it's just so soft but if
you get a little
squeeze it just beat tons of moisture in
it so that's the example of a sponge
wood o hi
Hy
yeah there pretty
girls see it
dripping there you go that that's
perfect this is right by the river too
getting close to my house again all
right those are some fun videos hunting
some turkey tails checking out Mother
Nature's im4
im3 I'm going enjoy this view for one
moment 2004 is tomorrow I pray the best
for all of you guys do not underestimate
yourselves and do not overestimate your
problems there's greatness within you
you can do it all right let's do this