hey how's it going hope you guys are
having a good weekend
um I'm just hanging out here with a nice
big bag of freshly uh dried and cured
Thai
flour cannabis flour so this is our
favorite Thai strain and some other
people I have uh
uh reported they they also appreciated
the Thai strain when we use it in our
tincture so I've got very good news
we're just today I'm going to start
making a new batch of our high potency
sativa tincture and it's a thousand
milligrams of THC so
very very potent and you get a lot of
bang for your buck uh so a thousand
milligrams and instead of eating gummies
and all these other Edibles and such
like that
um we feel at least that this is a
really good value too just keeping it
really simple and in olive oil and then
with tinctures you're allowed to go up
to a thousand milligrams per bottle so
it really is an efficient way and an
incredibly healthy way to consume your
cannabis and your high potency THC but
don't just think this is a wellness
product that's not recreational this
especially this um Thai strain most
people myself included uh feel that it
is has an extremely cartoony clown-like
silly effect so and you actually when
you're walking you actually for some
reason it kind of makes you bounce so
you have to actually concentrate on not
skipping when you walk so if if that
sounds fun
get ready and look out for our new tie
strain so I also want to show you just
the quality of what goes into our
tinctures so right here you have it
and what this is this is just pure
trophy flowers so these could all get
trimmed up if we wanted to do trimmed
flour sometime but uh we actually right
now our Niche is
um is doing uh tincture the olive oil
tinctures and we feel that that's the
healthiest and best value way to consume
your cannabis so that's that's what
we're doing but anyway these are just
some of the flowers
that are going to go into this tincture
that I'm about to make actually just in
a few minutes I'm going to start making
it so here's the flowers
very killer and then
um this is an example this steel drum
this is actually empty now but this is
where our olive oil comes from so this
is comes from an artisan olive oil
manufacturer or Creator or farmer in
Paso Robles California and he actually
grows award-winning olive oil super high
vibin and then he's such an incredible
nerd and purist about his olive oil that
he actually
designed these custom stainless steel
drums to store the olive oil to make
sure it has as little oxidation as
possible so he does these aren't even
stored in plastic uh so it's his own
stainless steel drums and then he gives
me the polyphenol counts and everything
I mean this is top-notch high-end
Artisan olive oil so and then all we do
is we take
these flowers and we soak them in olive
oil not in the drum we put it in a big
Kettle type situation uh but it's all
food equipment and we just let the
Cannabis soak in olive oil and what
happens is the olive oil is the solvent
and it actually just naturally absorbs
all the cannabinoids every little bit
that's in the trichomes in the plant
matter just naturally absorbs directly
into the olive oil so we don't use any
chemicals we don't use any solvents
alcohols nothing it's just
olive oil
and pure whole flower cannabis
and that's it and that's all you need
and people have been doing that since
Biblical times and before and it works
beautifully so
anyway that's how Jade nectar is made
we'll show you more information later on
but uh just because we have this
beautiful bag of Thai
flowers right here just wanted to show
them to you it was a great time and also
let you know
that our tie strain is going to be
featured in our next batch of sativa and
then after we do the tie
we're probably going to do an African
selection which we've got some
mind-blowing African uh varieties uh
land race varieties this year too so
we're gonna have some really good
sativas as well as our indicas that are
going to be all Afghan and Iranian uh
indicos as well so anyway lots of good
stuff but just know
that's this is how we make uh Jade
nectar so uh
who knows maybe someday we'll do a trim
flour uh because this it's Primo anyway
you guys have a good one bye