hey how's it going uh today is October
12th it's starting to finally feel like
it's Autumn and wanted to show you we've
uh shown some videos before on our
layered harvesting technique that I know
a lot of other people use but wanted to
show you how we do it and the benefits
of doing a layered Harvest so first of
all oh and by the way this is a Thai
plant that we've been running for a
number of years this is our absolute
favorite plant for um doing uh sativa
tinctures has a really nice cartoony
effect so if you like the silly cartoony
giggly effect this plant will take you
there so anyway it's it's a favorite
anyway so this plant
uh so the layered harvesting system is
when you have outdoor plants that are
like Yay big but it doesn't matter what
size but the basic concept is this plant
used to be about this big and so the top
outer colas
uh would uh get ready and ripen first so
we just take those top colas off
and the plant take it down about two
feet
and then the other colas the inside
flowers will then uh get more sunlight
and they'll mature and then get nice and
big and fat and then you take those and
you just keep doing that until you've
got nothing left on the plant so this
actually
today we're going to be taking the third
Harvest off this particular plant and
just I'm going to cut this and bring it
to the camera to see
but let me know if it when it goes in
focus
um
so basically right here this bud
you know a few weeks ago was just tiny
little larfy popcorn that had nothing
but now that it's been exposed to the
sunlight and allowed to develop
it's now this really beautiful
dense Cola like you could actually trim
this up as a flower
um so anyway so that's kind of how this
works then we're going to take this
whole plant down to nothing but I'll
show you another plant so here's another
Thai plant
same situation and just yeah just look
at the Crystal on there
so
and the concept being that if uh
if we were to harvested the entire plant
all at once
uh and taking the whole plant out of
here all of this would have been very
small little popcorn almost unusable
buds but by letting the these uh small
inner
buds now have their time in the Sun and
their time to shine they've totally
delivered
and so now just this one branch here
got some these are like top colas at
this point where a few weeks ago they
were just like larfy popcorn that you'd
almost throw away so anyway you can get
sort of triple or quadruple the yield of
really killer
flour if uh if you're interested in
doing just sort of this layered Harvest
so um today we're going to be taking all
these plants down to just a stock so
we're actually starting to close out our
garden at least stuff that's ready but
like this this is a Nigerian plant that
we're growing for the fun of it
this thing's not even gonna be this is
going to be more like
Christmas
yeah
but uh anyway
all right so that's the layered Harvest
concept we're gonna get on with our
harvesting so hope you have a wonderful
day
hey just wanted to show one more example
of this tie
these buds if we would have harvested
the entire plant all at once these would
have been tiny little larfy nothing buds
but now
hope you can see that I don't know this
camera doesn't always focus on the right
thing maybe it's focus on my nose hairs
instead of the plant
but yeah these are
just kill or like trophy buds
that uh
yeah just giving that inner popcorn buds
a few weeks to mature just get amazing
amazing amazing so anyway
I'm impressed so hope that helps some
folks
enjoy