howdy happy Friday so it's October 14th
Friday and just wanted to uh demonstrate
by the way it's about 9 00 a.m but just
wanted to show uh sort of the uh The
Perils of uh growing in uh Coastal
climate uh we're in the Santa Cruz
mountains we're usually fairly high
above the Marine layer uh but when we
really get socked in with fog this is
the kind of experience we get and fog
and high humidity at night and cannabis
is not always a good match we grow uh
most of our genetics are land race
um
and or just hybrids of just uh land race
to land race and such like for instance
this is a lamb Zam we're calling it but
this is Jamaican Lamb's bread crossed to
zamal but the point being is
even though we didn't get rain I don't
know I'm gonna shake this plant here and
we'll see if you can see all the water
on it from the fog all night
I don't know or if you come this way
gonna show you uh
this is uh our last Syrian plant but I
think you can see here too all the fall
I'm gonna shake it
but anyway so uh when we start getting
that consistent Marine layer coming in
um yeah it can the buds will sit wet so
this is a testament to how mold
resistant these plants are because we
still don't have any mold but you know
if this goes on for weeks and weeks and
weeks it can be a challenge so uh that's
why each environment is a little bit
different and then you just kind of have
to select genetics that fit your
environment and all the different
elements and variables of your
environment
um again so far no mold but I just
wanted to demonstrate because some folks
don't know anything about fog and
cannabis we're in Santa Cruz mountains
which is a beautiful thing but sometimes
we can get that Marine layer just while
we're here
fun to show you another plant
this one actually is surprisingly uh
just in the last few days I need to uh
it's getting a little yellow so I'm
gonna feed it just a little bit to kick
it through but this is a um
uh Santa Cruz Haze this is actually
original Haze right here so um and it
seems to be pretty darn happy about
things so uh but it probably won't be
ready till Thanksgiving or later anyway
you guys have a wonderful Friday
bye