this week's subject that we're going to
chat about um is sort of there was there
was a there was a guy okay so at the
time there was a guy there was a guy
that uh that ended up giving Neville uh
four different
lines okay and those things ended up
permeating a bunch of Neville's hybrids
and crosses and things like that right
and they they're pretty important even
today so we thought we'd talk about it
right and so today's edition in our
reoccurring series on cannabis history
is going to be about uh Jim Ortega and
the strains that he gave Neville and
sort of what happened with those yeah
okay um so when in the mid 80s when
Neville started his Seed Company um he
garnered a bunch of interest from
Americans right um which is how he ended
up trading with a bunch of them and sort
of like filling out his diversity of his
seed stock from people okay
and one of the people that was
interested in what he was doing was this
guy I don't believe this is his real
name but you know uh we they called him
Jim Ortega okay yeah and he gave Neville
um the maple leaf Indica the garlic
Bud um the Kush
four and the Hawaiian the there was
something called Hawaiian IND
those four things right um and so I
guess we'll start with uh we'll start
with the things that and so here's the
gig right um here's the
gig the history of this so as far as I'm
aware okay um we'll call him Jim Jim is
alive right um but Jim is alive and he
has periodically although fairly rarely
popped up on the interwebs and added
some depth to things but he has not uh
really laid out a ton of History um this
was somebody asked what year is this I
would say this is in the in the mid 80s
mid mid to late 80s okay I would just
based on how Neville operated I would
imagine that he probably got this stuff
from mortega probably around 86 because
he was he was good on it he was
definitely moving his process along like
if he got something within the next one
or two years it would be introduced to
his program it would end up in the
catalog there wasn't a big gap and 86 is
the year with it still has all the [ __ ]
[ __ ] has the stuff from [ __ ] Dave
Watson it has all that too so most of
what we know about these lines comes
from Neville working them into releases
that he made okay and then much much
later than that
uh on the Mr Nice forum and say like the
200920 era Neville popped up on the
Forum and started chatting for a couple
of years yeah uh and that is where the
vast ma the vast majority of what we
know okay about this comes from that
right and so this is an interesting
thing because like when you talk about
Cana history there are probably people
that are still alive out there that know
far more than we do about the origins of
these things where they came from what
they were mixed with all this different
stuff but that has not been you know
made public right no so we don't know
those things so what we know is
basically from Neville getting them what
he saw in the seed lines and deciding
and what he decided to say about them
and his educated
guesses and you know one of the things
that is so cool about these specific
lines is that because they were so
prolific in their time and across the
Dutch Market not only do we have things
that he said but in the case of things
like garlic Bud that became we can say
that but um in the case of things like
garlic bud and what they become you have
this huge range of people that had grown
them over many many years who have their
own anecdotes you know all of those
lines barring a few were sold you know
just saying that like whether or not Jim
made them all whether or not he was the
middleman and he acquired them from
different friends and pass them
along their origin story starts with him
giving them to Neville well maybe we
should start there because one of the
few anecdotes we have of a previous time
was Neville's rundown in that 90 catalog
when he said oh the Afghan mix came from
the collection of someone named Maple
Leaf Wilson
and who that is who that may be we don't
know but that seems like it is the only
singular piece of that story that
precedes him actually looking through
the lines and that story may or may not
be what Jim Ortega told Neville and
that's and that's very true because
these seeds come from America Neville's
not from America he's from Europe right
and it appears that you know he mailed
him to him right
so um we will start I get I'm going to
start backwards right and we'll start
with the the two we'll start with the
two that I feel like have I don't want
to say the least impact but got used the
least right okay um yeah so Neville had
this Hawaiian
indicia
okay we don't know all its permutations
of what happened with it okay but it
appears that Neville took this line and
he crossed it to nl1 okay which was what
he kind of did to most things back then
nl1 was sort of like the only like in
seed form pure kush variety that he you
know pure Indica variety that he had um
so he crossed Hawaiian Inda to nl1 and
then he released it as Hawaiian indicia
by nl1 yeah and there's picks of it in
his seed bank um later on um it got
released under Sensei although they
dropped the byy nl1 and just sold it as
Maple Leaf or they sold it as Hawaiian
Inda yeah without without any of the
qualifiers that it had been Blended
right right and there are some pictures
in Neville's old cataloges and different
things like that of this strain okay
yeah um you know it's it's possible that
it ended up in some of s sees later
works and some certain later hybrids um
but it sort of appears a little bit as
sort of like a
singular yeah right we don't know for
sure that it permeated through other
work no right um and
so that was one of them yeah another one
that he gave was this thing called Kush
for okay which we didn't know very much
about at all until Neville started
posting in
200920 okay um and what that stuff seems
to be is according to Neville it was
kind of a cushy line and he um crossed
it to what he considered his other Kush
line that he had which was nl2 and he
released something the last two or three
years of his seed bank um called Kush by
kush yeah okay it would it would also
seem there was actually a section of
that as well because when you saw I
guess what we're supposed to believe is
the final iteration of his work that was
available the Orga one two and three
lines that um gosh kit from Legends was
the one selling early 2000s yeah one you
know they were all you know NL early
hybrids with the oran stuff but one of
them was I think it was the two was it
the one that I [ __ ] had but I'm using
my I have I have screenshots of of the
makeup of all those of all those ones
from later on but they're on my phone
and I'm using my phone right now to chat
with everyone so I can't look but um but
you can go look in Neville's old
cataloges probably about 89 90ish right
and you'll see something called Kush by
kush yeah which later he clarified was
kush for by nl2 right right and um you
know and he believes you can take this
for what you will he believes that the
what we consider Kush in in our OG Kush
TK all that different stuff he felt that
stuff looked so similar to it it was
probably descended from it I mean he
went so far as to say that he believed
that OG Kush was just
nl2 which is interesting
because we have a more common like
metric for what nl2 looked like through
Oasis then original packs of nl2 and
when you compare them it's so night and
day what came out of Oasis never looked
like OG um and it makes me wonder what
we hadn't seen of nl2 that made him so
convinced that OG that he saw in his
later years oh this is just [ __ ] I me
he might have he might have picked he
might have picked a
particularly cushy in his mind look
to cross to the Kush um I have a I have
a screenshot from from uh from Mr Nice
where he literally says he believes that
hybrid is the foundation of today's Kush
lines whether or not that's true I can't
say I I I never bought those lines from
him I don't have any personal experience
so but that's what he said okay yeah I
could you know I tried desperately to
get those [ __ ] Ortega 2 f2s that
[ __ ] G slot [ __ ] uh may just
made I got the [ __ ] I got the Ortega
to hybrid up that was how I made purity
ring all this but like I couldn't get
any of those f2s up and I knew they were
like 22 years old when I tried to pop
them but like I I took my best stab at
trying to see what the [ __ ] was there in
a in a lost era just failed we don't we
don't really know those were a seed line
that was available for probably three
four years right right and um you know
he made some comments about what the you
know he clarified what was in it years
later and he made some comments about
what he thought about it but that's not
really um that's really all we know
about it right okay um and I will say
that we should probably take a moment
because I feel like most people's idea
of kush for now is a plant that looks
very very similar to Bubba Kush and has
been shared with VAR people I know CSI
has it I know bod has it I know they
both made hybrids with it but in
that is that what kush for was
originally we don't know is that
something that someone was like hey this
is this is kush for you know this this
is it and it it's hard to say so even
metrics we should have today how
reliable they are we we can't say I mean
there's also a thing too for a few years
I haven't seen it much lately but there
was percolating around collector circles
about seven or eight years ago there was
a kush for clone that that's what I'm
talking about yeah that was that was
reputed to be um you know from that or
whatever um but it's very you know it's
just it's just soaked in mystery from so
long ago right and you know out of all
the things that Jim did say when he came
back if anyone needs to find things that
Jim said or post he posted as dog
on a number of forums um but out of all
the things that he did say and some of
them
were a little much I mean uh he never
verified that that cut that goes around
and it no no he did not he he did never
came up he did pop up on on the forums
over there and um he did clarify what he
sent Neville and they did do some back
and fourths and stuff and so it seems
like it happened right the next two
things that I'm going to talk about or
we're going to talk about are things
that are sort of the meat and potatoes
of what Ortega gave Neville in the sense
that they got much more widely used and
they're much more familiar to people and
so I think I'll leave the big one for
last but the third thing that he gave um
was garli garlic Bud yep and Neville had
a whole bunch of thoughts about garlic
Bud yeah right Neville called garlic Bud
a pre- Sam
skunk yeah which probably irritates the
piss out of Sam if he's listening um but
uh sorry uncle those those guys are
those guys are the those guys are uh the
original weed beef right so not to tap
into that I wasn't there I I was a child
or whatever but um as well but when it
comes down to it um what we do know is
that is that Neville sold garlic Bud as
a line okay for um for very um you know
he sold it in his in his seed bank
company okay and um he put pictures of
it and he said it was a very high
yielding you know donkey dick as as you
like to as people like to say sometimes
uh donkey dick style buds okay and he
viewed it as a skunk Arc Type yeah would
you say interesting what's interesting
especially with the garlic is because we
don't have an exact distinction about
how Neville received all of the seeds
that we're talking about there is a
chance that what we call Garlic bud and
what we call you know Maple Leaf in
reference to you know the Afghan in the
Afghan s might have actually just been
the same group of seats yeah we don't we
we we we know what we know what they
told us okay and so um so garlic Bud was
widely sold by Neville okay it was very
popular because you can go back and look
at the catalog and they just have this
picture of this plant with this mon
monster colos monster side branching
resinous very very pretty all that type
of stuff it was very popular okay he
crossed it um into all kinds of things
um because it had that as he likes to
call it uh donkey dick style buds right
certain
Gena and so and so we'll we'll jump
ahead briefly okay okay so when Neville
got bust when Neville got busted and he
ended up having to
sell up having to sell his company
to um to the dronkers right and sell his
seed stock to sensey all right sensey
did not want to just make it seem like
their company was a um direct Port from
Neville would you say that's fair any
yeah no it's absolutely accurate but I
mean it
was um so what they did okay is they
changed the name of garlic Bud to Shiva
Shanti yep okay named after Ben's
daughter right yeah and Shiva Shanti was
sold a lot longer than garlic Bud was
right the interesting thing about that
and this is a whole story in itself is
that since he was lazy enough they uh
they didn't change the picture they
didn't change the advertisement like the
they did change the they did change the
advertisement but they mostly the same
verbiage in language yeah it's very
direct they took a few sentences out
right and they changed some names okay
so garlic bud is Shiva Shanti so it's a
direct it's a it's a direct Port right
it is although I'm not exactly sure and
I don't know if it's ever been clarified
by anyone close but there is a Shiva
Shanti one and two um yes there was a
more Afghan version of Shiva Shanti that
came out later right I wonder how each
one of those was made like was one you
know f2s of a different mom than
whatever however the sad thing about the
dronkers is that they're both still
alive right and they're a they they
could be an immense Fountain of
Knowledge and historical information and
they basically decided to say ceny is
the exact same it's always been all the
parents are are the exact same they've
always been all the lines are the exact
same they've always been by from Sensei
we're the ogs right which is not
particularly help like so not
helpful so garlic Bud Shiva Shanti right
because of the length of time that it
was sold as seed
stock ended up probably in a lot more
weed than most people think it ended up
in all kinds of hybrids it ended up in
all kinds of stuff from you know Neville
gave a bunch of the stock from from
shant from to Shanti right um so Jim
Ortega giving the garlic line to there
was a version of Black Domina that had
garlic in it um yeah there was a there
was a lot of uh there was a lot of
things that permeated from that right
sure and it's still sold today okay um
but what most people don't know is that
when they bought the company most of the
things that they sold at Sensei were
large amounts of Neville's seed
stock right that he had already made and
they didn't actually make anything new
for the first three or four years that
they bought the company right they just
sold stock that he they had already
purchased right so probably the last two
two two three years I can't remember if
it was 88 or ' 89 that he came out with
it but the last two or three three years
you could buy garlic Bud from the seed
bank and then proba and then probably
from like 90 to 95 you could BR 91 to 95
you could Bry Shiva Shanti that was
probably the same damn seed stock
probably you know direct from from
Neville okay and so that that bud from
Jim Ortega made a huge impact because
tons of people bought Shiva I mean
there's rumors that like for instance
the Ohio dumpster
is a is a is a Shiva Shanti feno um it's
probably in a lot more things than we
think probably yeah in all
H you know probably honestly it's
probably in a lot more things than we
than than we think and so um and so you
know the um I'm ignoring tons of
comments guys because I'm trying to stay
focused on what we're chatting you know
so uh I'll get distracted and I'm trying
to get like a I'm trying to get a uh a
consistent thing out here right so um
maybe we'll get back to them maybe we
won't okay so anyway garlic Bud Shiva
Shanti pretty impactful sold for a long
period of time um you know and the the
interesting thing about garlic bud is
that it doesn't see it seems like it was
always a seed line right yeah which
meant which was important because it
meant that it wasn't dependent on one
clone Staying Alive in order to make the
breeding right anytime you have a line
that relies on a single clone mother
father or whatever to make a breeding
it's delicate because that thing has to
stay alive anything that you get that's
an actual line it's a little easier to
keep it going because even if you lose
some of it if you have a bunch of seed
you can pop it and find stuff you want
and just make more of them yeah right
because you have a whole line okay um
and so
so I would say that the first two things
we mentioned um the the least you know
the least impact just in terms of how
often they were used garlic was used in
all kinds of stuff and Shiva Shanti was
used in all kinds of stuff so that was a
pretty huge impact and then the thing
that the thing that Jim Ortega gave to
Neville that probably had the most
impact was what crybaby already
mentioned uh this thing called Maple
Leaf
Indica okay um he gave Maple Leaf Indica
to Neville right and Neville popped it
sounds like he got a whole bunch of
seeds yeah because not only did Neville
pop the seeds and find various phenos
that became famous and ended up in all
kinds of different things but he had so
much seed he decided to sell that
Original Seed and he called it what did
he call it original Afghan mix or
something original Afghan mix 50 packs
yeah and he would sell literally he
would sell breeders packs in the 89 and
catalog of stuff that he got that was
just the same seeds that he pulled all
of his famous fenos out of right um and
and all that right and
uh um and so the reason why Maple Leaf
became so impactful okay is because he
had um this feno of maple leaf that he
called Afghan
te right that's right and he crossed
this to skunk and that became the basis
of Super Skunk right which is obviously
one of the most longtime extremely
famous lines that has ever existed right
it was also his best-selling line by
Miles he sold so much of that [ __ ]
line it it would probably be shocking to
think about you know that kind of speed
movement the [ __ ] he said he analyzed
his own sales and he analyzed um
sensey's sales and um you know it was
the bestselling line yeah right so he
basically took some stuff from Jim
Ortega and he crossed it to some stuff
from Sam and he ended up with this you
know he called it he put the skunk
because Sam had intentionally been
breeding the skunk out of
skunk he felt that by throwing this
skunk line back on the AF the Afghan he
brought out the original
skunk and I will go back a second
because you know one of the similarities
in all of this and one of the shared
like little commentaries is one of the
reasons that it seems although not
confirmed that garlic and maple might
actually be the same seedline not just
two different things is because that
commentary about being a skunk archetype
um was used about Afghan in particular
as well he said that you know what was
it like oh it was like you know the
archetype of Sam skunk
so oh yeah Afghan is the Bas of allies
but um yeah so before any further so
anyway this one's gonna take up a chunk
of time for a second because it goes
into all kinds of things
so Neville made some interesting
observations right about how he thought
he understood the maple leaf line okay
but it kept throwing um different fenos
that would throw him off right so he
said when he first started popping Maple
Leaf he got these like very big bud
style chunky like bubblegum smelling uh
Afghan fenos right yeah and he thought
oh this this is kind of cool I
understand what's up and then he said
that he started popping some stuff and
he started getting these very hash plant
very frosty very dark hashy type plants
that he called Ortega right and then he
popped more and he found these sister
plants that he ended up calling Afghan
te and Afghan s right and he thought
these were more like skunk Arch types
right yeah bigger buds longer running
buds they were all in the same they were
all in the same line okay yeah um but he
found when he bred with them that they
tended to breed true to type yeah even
though all those types were within the
line itself you know he felt like the
bubblegum big bud ones tended to breed
more B big bud Bubblegum style plants
the hashy Ortega ones tended to breed
more hashy dark thick Afghan plants
right the Afghan s and Afghan T were two
of his favorite he used them in all
kinds of hybrids and he ended up making
a ton of stuff of which only a tiny
percentage got released yeah right and
so you know and there's a lot of stories
like he mentioned um you know uh Maple
Leaf uh Maple Leaf Wilson um there's a
lot of rumors about where this stuff
came from yeah you know uh that we could
talk about a little bit but the bottom
line is that they came from Jim Ortega
y Jim and Neville both agree that that's
where they came from right Y and Jim has
never
seen um worth it to him right for lack
of a better way to put it to come out
and lay out whether or not these things
he made whether these things he
collected who he got them from what
their parentage or lineage might be um
so all we have is Neville's
observations sure and
the way I is that Jim was a big
collector and had his people and the
things that he did make were things like
uh the queso Negra and stuff the cheese
Mexican or [ __ ] whatever it was but
you know early stuff and I think that
Neville's own words kind of you know
have that same implication you know
these things came from the collection of
someone else and this is someone who
isn't who you know we know that I got
them from
so but regardless of how they occurred
or anything else it just doesn't seem
like he has interest and what Jim has
seemed to be very interested one second
hi
Dwight oh I've been completely ignoring
uh the commentary because I haven't
wanted to throw off
anyone um but well done the only person
whose comments the only person whose
comments I've been putting on this
screen where Dwight's comments as you
were talking so anyway I'm not gonna I'm
not gonna out Dwight but um but if if
nine I DJ is Dwight um then he is one of
Neville very very old friends um and he
was around in the 80s and he was present
for a lot of this history that we're
speaking of um and he's also just a
really nice cool person so uh I feel
very happy that uh that he's in here um
and I like him quite a bit and uh I
really appre he's taken I've spent hours
chatting with him on various things uh
he's a straight OG uh he knows a lot of
the old history and um yeah so anyway
the reason I've been ignoring all the
comments is because it's it's gone off
into like Todd in NL land and I didn't
really want to get um uh completely
Sidra absolutely
sidetracked but I will say that Neville
loved the maple leaf okay and I feel
it's important I'll mention a few things
all right everybody got everybody got
obviously famous um you know from the
nl5 but when Neville made his first um
nl5 Haze crosses but when Neville
crossed the haze his two favorite
indicas at the moment were were the a
were the Afghan T and the NL and the nl5
feno that he had and so he made Haze by
Afghan te as well right
um I don't think he ever released it you
know but he had it and he called it I
even think he called it silver haze
right he did he called it silver ha
which is really confusing because then
later on uh released
the ceny released a silver haze that was
silver Pearl by Haze so it was very it
was very uh it was very different um but
Neville made a ton like a literal ton of
hybrids he had
I want to say three to five fenos of
maple leaf Indica pure Maple Leaf Indica
that he gave specific names to Afghan T
was one Afghan s was another he had one
that he called Ortega 15 okay um these
got used a lot um these got passed
around um the Ortega stuff went over to
Canada uh some of those seeds and and
they were released uh Louie Legends
indicia was based upon Neville's uh
Maple Leaf work um obviously the super
skunk has has been probably one of the
most things that was bred in by tons of
people into tons of work and Shanti
still uses a a Neville Super Skunk male
to this day so the the Afghan te uh
exists in a lot of different lines and
then I should say it's just it was
basically just like one of the biggest
Staples and whether it got name changed
or whether it got bred into different
things it became one of the big
backbones yeah canis I I mean kandle
kandle loved nordal too and that's the T
and the S smashed up with skunk one and
like those things hit there I I don't I
don't know if they thrived there but
they certainly [ __ ] hit there was
things that Neville made that he didn't
release that batches of seeds got out to
other folks in Canada and elsewhere and
then they ended up making lines and
releasing lines of things that Neville
had bothered to release right and so
there was um you know there was all
kinds of stuff going on so if you're
looking at impact um as crybaby
mentioned 10 minutes ago or something
like that Neville when Neville analyzed
sales both at his company and at Sensei
Super Skunk was probably the bestselling
line of the 90s yeah right so it it just
got blended into eenth million things
which meant that the maple leaf that Jim
Ortega had given to Neville ended up in
just all kinds of stuff renamed or
elsewise right yeah absolutely and still
percolates to this day right
so going back all right and this is
something that that Shanti just revealed
not that long ago in an interview with
his son but super skunk was something
that was bred by Neville but that Sensei
ended up trademarking the name okay so
when I went over to Amsterdam after
Neville had left Sensei uh and and was
working with
Greenhouse he would sell this stuff
called Ultra Ultra skunk yep that was
that was basically Super Skunk but it
couldn't have the name all right and
then later on Neville gave a super skunk
breeding mail to Shanti okay at Mr Nice
and Shanti couldn't call it super skunk
but if you look at his breeding and if
you see an Afghan skunk
male that's the super skunk male yeah
right so it literally is getting back to
the to the maple leaf maple leaf is
literally in in it's in so many things
yeah it's unbelievable one of the final
things one of the final things I should
say about Maple Leaf is that what's
interesting about Maple Leaf is that
when Neville when the company went from
Neville's own company to being owned by
the dronkers in sensei okay Maple Leaf
fell off the menu for about seven to
eight years I
think okay and then in the in the very
late 90s I don't know we were trying to
we were trying to figure out exactly
what year but we're just going to say
the very late 90s okay yeah sensey
re-released Maple Leaf Indica as a line
that they still sell right crybaby and I
were trying to figure out exactly we
don't know because ceni doesn't tell you
but Neville made a lot of hybrids that
were basically 75% Maple 25% skunk one
you know he took a lot of the fenos that
he liked like Afghan s Afghan te Ortega
15 so and so mash them together use
skunk as a pollen donor um for some of
those ones and so it's entirely possible
although we're not sure that the um that
ceny revive the maple leaf indicial line
yeah from those
mostly Maple Leaf but slightly skunk
hybrids that Neville seems most likely
it it's what seems most likely we don't
know for sure but we do know for sure
that after seven or eight years of being
off the menu it rep popped up on the
menu and most of the maple leaf
including the stuff that crybaby and I
and our friend rings and stuff like that
has been percolating around is from that
late is is from that late 90s very early
2000s Sensei releases yeah you know um
and uh you know know and you know so it
it exists it percolates around out there
um that plant those that seed line that
that Jim Ortega gave to Neville Neville
loved and he crossed it with basically
everything good that he had he released
some lines officially under his own
brand Sensei released some other stuff
it was mixed into all kinds of stuff
there was a version of black domino that
had the garlic bud in there uh there was
a version of black domino that had the
Afghan s in there I believe
um right there was a lot of there was a
lot of different things um released you
know uh Shanti because Shanti bought a
chunk of Neville's collection both uh I
believe clones and seeds um there's
probably a lot of that percolating
around through shanti's work because it
seems like that super skunk male is one
of the cornerstones of his breeding yeah
which means that it exists in all kinds
of forms throughout different uh
different things right and so it's sort
of one of the big it became one of the
big backbones of cannabis because
Neville liked it so much crossed it with
so many different things and then it
popped up and percolated in different
companies in Canada different companies
in Switzerland different Holland
companies and it just I think it's
impact you know um despite being like
here's the funny thing right is that Jim
Ortega has decided not to tell us very
much more than we already know about
this line right but the reality is is
that Neville liked it enough and other
people have liked it enough to keep
working with it like to me that's the
greatest compliment you can give
cannabis is when people like it enough
to work with it and then over years
people still want it to keep finding it
to keep working with it because they
like it so much well think about this
way one of I I mean what would
conventionally be seen you know in a
commer sense as one of Neville's
greatest rivals in the early era when
they had the opportunity to get that
number three Orga seed line they made a
whole [ __ ] deal out of it Hank made
it the biggest [ __ ] deal when Dutch
Passion released that Ortega number
three and it was in these special boxes
and it was a [ __ ] Legacy pack and
that was someone who did actually have
weed that was unique from neb earlier
cuz he was the big hash Smuggler way
back and all that [ __ ] like he had Dutch
[ __ ] that wasn't Sam that wasn't Nev and
even when a decade later he had the
opportunity to pounce on that he was
like this [ __ ] I'm gonna I'm [ __ ] I'm
getting this [ __ ] I'm releasing it and
and that's and that's a great example
when when the impact of your work
actually makes your [ __ ] competition
consider that they need a pie pie of
that too they need to do something with
that too so the cool part is that a seed
deal that Neville made in the late in
the mid to late 80s okay still
dramatically impacts the Cannabis scene
today yeah absolutely it does you know
um you know and and uh a lot of you know
a lot of the
uh you know honestly to to switch back
too like when gab I don't know if gab's
still in here but when Gabby and I were
doing a bunch of that super dog work
right that had super skunk from Neville
in it yeah you know so it like it I mean
whether or not people get credited or
not um you know Jim giving that to Jim
giving that to Neville and then Neville
popularizing it uh we keep using it you
know so people were using it in the 80s
people were using it in the 90s Gabby
and I were using it in our own way in
California it gets used used and used
and used you know all these different
things and it just has ended up being a
combination of um you know a jeel um you
know there's all kinds of different
things that it keeps popping up in it
really
is um one of the biggest backbones in
cannabis well you know and this kind of
goes back to you know where we started
hours ago you know what does it mean to
cannabis if you started with what's
essentially very close to primordial
material in the Cannabis world you know
did your work with it and managed to
reface the whole [ __ ] game the whole
industry the nature of what people
wanted for an indefinite future is I
mean how how can you breed any further
than that really the funny part about
this is you know we were trying to uh we
were trying to uh keep these shows to
two hours or something I
thought I thought that when we when we
started this this chat about uh uh this
week's history lesson that we would be
able to bring it in a little shorter
than that but it just goes to show um
how wide ranging uh that trade or that
that deal that Neville made with with
Jim did and how um you know and how
impactful it was and how impactful it
continues to be um you know and so I
think like a lot of the original Afghan
a you know Afghan mix parents are dead
but it's children and grandchildren and
stuff like that uh like really really
continue to impact sure and you know we
can't do genetic testing and stuff like
that right now but um you know it it's
in so many different things because it
tasted good and it smelled good good and
it made nice bud structure and all that
and if you look at it that Afghan skunk
if you look if you go on Mr Nice you
know seed bank or something and you look
for things that a Afghan skunk that
breeding mail that Neville gave him is
one of the four or five backbone
breeding males that is still in all of
his stuff yeah and it's been used and
used and used over and over and over
again it has used to
death yeah because it's just good it's
just good and it's been used by
different companies in different ways
and different companies have taken
different permutations of some of these
things and gone in their own directions
with it uh I mean I I wish today I could
still get Louie you know Legends
ultimate indicia it would be it would be
pretty neat you know and uh and those
guys in Canada and Blockhead and some of
that different stuff that they were
making with it and that was just random
seeds that they got right so um Black
Domina uh was out of seeds that I
personally
bought um that was the coolest thing
that I found you know and um you know
speaking of speaking of Gabby uh Gabby's
buddy gave us a Black Domina that I was
tasted like pepper and I wish I still
had it was phenomenal Yeah you mentioned
that to me before yeah it was really
good man I I still regret losing that
one um but it it it was really I mean so
I think what happened is is that's a
story for a different time because we
can get on we can get on tangents we'll
save that one but in in in closing on
this week's history a mysterious guy
from America that chose the moniker Jim
Ortega did some trades with Neville gave
Neville a bunch of stuff the stuff ended
up being fire he ended up using it in
all kinds of different things and it
keeps taking on a life of its own and
popping up in different breeders work
still today rundown was immaculate
you know
[Music]