hey a few more African sativa field
notes it's very exciting to see that
these Africans are finally going off and
getting close to finishing so this I'd
have to say
as a plant now I haven't sampled any of
these the final like effects of the
dried flowers because we haven't Harvest
them but this is from Kenya and we grew
a bunch of Kenyan lambre seeds this year
in fact we've got one
two three four five so we have five
female Kenyans and they all are fairly
uniform in this just really nice
sort of globular structure just covered
in sphere so it's actually a very um
efficient design for yield so this could
actually be sort of a productiony type
plant
um
weird
wow uh so
kind of what hit was
almost a little vulgar kind of a almost
body odor
smell but you know like a pheromone
musky primal
sort of body odor funk that's a little
intoxicating
uh let me see
wow but also herbs Savory herbs
with some body odor funk I know that
sounds disgusting but it's actually kind
of intoxicating here's another Canyon
you know that kind of that has that same
little bit of funk going on
just kind of a body odor thing
and then um
yeah they they all to tell you the truth
these are kind of somewhat uh
uniform these are probably the most
uniform plants all five of these phenos
really are very
clear
close see
this is the most done one I'd say this
one's ready to be harvested could be
even harvested right now
but may let it go I don't see a speck of
mold on any of these as these are
African sativas which tend to not have
mold issues
um
but yeah are you able to get Crystal on
there no I'm getting maybe the ladybugs
oh okay maybe
there's one I'm gonna just kind of hang
out and see yeah
anyway hope that helped
and uh
anyway that that is the Kenyan it's
beautiful beautiful beautiful gorgeous
plant again these are field notes for
our own record but we're sharing them
with you so you can if you're excited or
interested
here you go we're sharing it with you
anyway Kenya very cool Plant love it