hey we're back this is the plant that I
uh showed you all the other day that I
was doing the regrow on and you can see
how once we've got some good growth we
could cut back on all that extra
material but there was a lot of
questions about the process and so I
wanted to show you a couple plants that
I did at the same time so you can kind
of see the difference in pace
so uh and and it's it's important so
that you understand about patience right
so this plant has uh Mexican gentic and
TI genetics in so it has
equatorial and I didn't breathe this
this is from uh Charles Scott's work but
the equatorial genetics affect the pace
of flowering how it shifts into
flowering how it shifts back out of
flowering and so if you take a look and
what I call it I call it determinant
meaning that once these hormones have
kicked in to drive the reproductive
process they want to stay in motion and
the more the northern latitude or
Southern latitude depending on what side
of the Equator you're on
the further you're away from the equator
the more determinant the plan is so this
particular one is kind of plastic
because of that equitorial nature or you
know 15
latitude but we come over here and you
can see this kill aash plant that I
created now this one is a cherry pie and
I used a a gny Afghani as the pollinator
for it right and now this is just
beginning to pop out and this plant was
so nice this is I just was on first
smoke of the day and this is the plant
that uh Alex and Lena washed so I could
bring it down and this stuff was just
foul I mean just screaming so I really
wanted to come back but you can see the
the how slow it is where this one's
already fully developed and going this
one's just initiating and you can start
to see here if I pull it in where the
bracks are kind of open back up and you
can see the color change it just says
hey we're starting to return to
juvenility we're starting to move
forward and then we go over to this one
that's kind of between both and this is
a Skittle that I used uh
F3 red Leb Puck mail on and out of the
there out of the total sift all these
three plants they came out of about 300
so six tables of
50 and this was by far the the best of
the red Le pucks into the skittle and
this was just phenomenal hash plan I'm
glad I get to capture it and this one as
well but you can see the difference in
that that shift where this is really
beginning to start to open up and once I
start to get some true development I'll
be able to carve away some of this plant
material this one is just beginning and
you can see some signs here where you
can see the color change but a lot of it
is for me with the with the root it's to
cut back the root ball a little bit and
then put it into a smaller pot so I'm
not having to constantly up poot what I
want is I want a wet dry cycle so just
like when your crop stering in a cube
smaller Cube cubes give you better
control same thing with this is that I
want this to be able to go through a wet
dry cycle so I initiate root stimulation
and then what I do is I take the plants
and if you can see how it's grown you
can see there was another side here what
I do is I create this this this V and it
lets me chop half the plant off for the
smoke test and then the other half I let
hang on to regrow so I have material it
it it likes you know moderate nitrogen
nothing excessive it likes sunlight
really so if you could put it outside
and then bring it in at night and
stimulate with some extra light so that
you uh keep the flower response down and
just be patient but you can see the huge
difference in speed where this
plant is fully vegetative and and in the
mood to grow this one is just starting
to break free and this one's in the
process in between both but the point is
that you know in a perfect world we hold
clones but I would have had a pull I
would have had to pull 300 plugs and I
would have had hold 300 plugs for month
and a half minimum right so I mean I
don't even want to track them when
they're flowering I don't want to deal
with it in the tray so say just say you
know full two months so 300 plants for
two months while we're flowering 300
plants it's just a pain in the neck and
so I used to do it when I had the
facility to hold the material but now
that everything's so highly regulated
you don't get to play some of these
games with your own
projects and so I went back to just
doing vegetative work where I allow the
plants that are outliers I make the
selections and I do the smoke test and
this one looks like holy hell right now
but my God this thing was a screamer man
what a stunner like the aroma was
fantastic mouth was powdered sugar
orange
spritzer and early finish just gorgeous
morphology so I had to keep it it was by
far the best one of that whole that
whole hunt and just by being patient
here we go and you can see it but that's
what you want that's typically what you
end up getting and that's a transition
and so just learn that you're just got
to take your time and be patient and
allow it to happen the longest it's ever
taken is probably I want to say over 5
months on a variety that was so
determinant that it literally stayed
almost in stasis for two and a half
months where it didn't even change it
just was like frozen but we just decided
let's see what
happens and lo and behold over the
course of the next 3 months it emerged
and we were able to pull a copy and we
had a really valuable plant that we
would lost otherwise so a lot of it is
just take your time and and make sure
that you don't start chopping out too
much material because you don't have
enough enough Leaf material here to
really Drive root health so once we
start to have enough
material then we're able to have a
healthy bottom end healthy top end now
we go into into vegetative and now we
have the plant so have a great day