hey there hey we're out at our uh land
race Botanical Garden again doing field
notes for this very cool Afghan plant
and this particular variety is called
Kush [ __ ] cushcock and uh this is an
incredibly unique terpene profile I'm
just gonna open it up
and smell and uh
what's so interesting about this one is
it smells like Mesquite smoke at least
that's what I'm picking up it already
smells like smoke but really good
Mesquite smoke kind of with a scedery
almost bug spray kind of smell but it's
really intoxicating and Incredibly
unique so I'm very excited about this
plant and today is October 18th by the
way it's really hot so sorry if I'm
oozing sweat it's incredibly hot today
surprisingly and uh but we're gonna
Harvest this today so just want to
document it we'll cruise around
maybe this might be a good bud
come in on
um reality is could probably go
three four five days longer but uh
they're really really thick dense Buds
and uh we're getting a lot of wet nights
so I'm really a little concerned and I
can only make it out here
every few days if I lived here full time
anyway I'd be able to stay on it a
little more but uh right now they're
close enough to harvest and don't want
to see them start uh imploding or
getting a mold so I think we're going to
take it today but bottom line it's
really really really cool Plant very
excited about it
kushcock
yet another
each Afghan I'm trying to think which
ones are my favorites but to tell you
each one is incredibly cool in its own
right and they all have unique terpenes
and this is yet another one but that
mesky smoke
is probably yeah none of them none of
the other ones smell like this so that's
something really unique about this place
oh and then one other thing wanted to
show
here's another kushcock that we already
started harvesting so and here you'll
see that uh starting to purple up a
little bit it's getting a little darker
at night so this plant if it were colder
at night we'd probably get a lot more of
the purple and black but uh
uh yeah it's been warmer than usual so
everything's kind of green still anyway
great plant
that's it