[Music]
all right today we are going to activate
some EM1 we have our old activated EM1
container all right so we're going to
take our
molasses of course you want to get uh
good molasses you don't want something
that that you wouldn't want to consume
yourself you don't want to put that into
the plant so we're going to use
5% nice thick good stuff this is a food
for the uh effective
microorganisms to consume while they're
multiplying that's uh quote unquote
activation we're taking what's in here
and making a lot more so
uh it looks about 5% you can be a lot
more um scientific and actually measure
it if you'd
like all right and for the
water we have this beautiful water tank
right behind us but before we get that
in there we're going to take the EM1 go
ahead and mix it in there with
that about five 5% so about 10% of the
total volume go ahead and get the water
there's some uh goldfish down in here as
well I think we just scared them off but
we'll get the
water diversity is
amazing so we'll have all the amazing
microbes that the the Goldfish are
producing in there to help activate the
is so uh once again you can go to
panic.com and they have a wide
assortment of of wonderful things for
the garden so go check them out and uh
this is going to be good after about 7
days you want to keep it in kind of a
warm dark place um and it'll speed up
the the activation rate if it's really
warm it might go a little bit before
then uh but yeah we'll check back in in
about seven days and we'll show you the
activated D1 cheers have a good day
so now it's been about a week week and a
half uh we have activated EM1 ready for
our
disposal over here and now I just throw
it on basically
everything that I'm trying to inoculate
[Music]
take
let's do something there