[Music]
hello everybody
this is chad westport and i just wanted
to pop in here and show you a really
quick grow hack
when you don't have trellis to kind of
spread out your plant
or the branches the grow hack i'm
showing you today is
binder clips so this plant is getting
ready for flower and as you can see
i've done a pretty good job of spreading
out my main terminals to produce more
colas than if i just let this grow in
the traditional christmas tree shape
and kind of how i helped spread that out
is through the use of these twist ties
and my grow hack of binder clips
generally speaking after about a week or
two of being held in the new position by
the twist ties and the binder clips
the branches will take that form or keep
that shape when you remove them
so this skunk number one plant is going
to have the twist ties removed before i
put it into flour
on this temple runts plant i've already
removed the twist ties
and as you can see here and here it held
its shape from when it was bound
and tied down which allowed these to
grow up around it
and these to fill out in the middle so
more colas here
because of the way i used my binder
clips and spread this temple runts out
as you can see
there's now plenty of tops on the plant
and it's all because of this training so
real quick
let me recreate the binder clips on this
plant
whatever size of pot you're using they
have a binder clip for you
they've got large they've got medium and
they've got small
i'm using the plastic pots this also
works on fabric pots it cinches it grips
so
let me just show you real quick what i
did here to train this plant out
i just took my medium clip put it right
there on the edge of my planter
nice and sturdy grab my twist tie put it
in
twist it out bring it up grab my branch
and hold it down and if you want
you can progressively kind of tighten
this and bring your branch lower
maybe you don't want to do it all at
once you're not trying to snap the
branch off
so you can kind of slowly progressively
just keep bringing it down
and laying your plant out and the end
result of that training
is a lot more terminal shoots and i'm in
a tight space so the more i have the
better
and i've achieved this through my binder
clip grow hack so
fellas ladies please let us know in the
comment section what you're doing to
help spread and train your plants
when you don't have a trellis be
interested to hear what you're doing
my name is chad westport i'm with twin
peaks cannabis you can find
me chad.westport on instagram thank you
for watching
i hope you learned something and again
share with us your tips in the comment
section
so party on
[Music]
you