[Music]
[Applause]
what's up everybody this is otis aka og
is my oxygen yo it's pax of the future
here
and we are coming at you with another
nothing for sale strain review today
specifically talking about magic meadow
farms gelato 33.
we're super excited about this one we
were gifted at the emerald cup a few
weekends ago
it smells really incredible we've had
the chance to smoke it a few times now
we we believe that this is outdoor og
here will tell you a little bit more
about the really interesting grow
conditions that led to this product but
this is some serious serious gelato so
we were told by the growers at magic
meadow farms that
this was grown from the ashes of the
northern california wildfires
from a very fertile land uh in theory
probably
uh ripe with nutrients so they were able
to turn a very tragic thing into a very
beneficial and positive thing for their
farm and rise up from the ashes with
this crop and other crops and end up
actually competing in the emerald cup
with this
and one thing that magic meadow
emphasized during our conversations was
the importance of land restoration
really their focus is around growing
phenomenal product
as well as contributing to the soil
health and and the regenerative
practices in their area i think that we
are always really excited when
sort of the product that we consume can
align to our larger values and this
certainly meets that criteria totally
yeah we we feel really good supporting
grassroots organic farmers
ultimately
that's where people can
build community and educate other
growers and everybody can support each
other speaking of northern california i
think that gelato in a lot of ways is a
pretty classic northern california
strain this is the 33 fina which is one
of the the more common i know that
people are really excited about all of
them now the 41 and the 45 are really
popular but also at this point people
are excited about the jello the guava
and and so it's nice to have someone
bringing it back to what i sort of
considered to be the classic the 33 it's
it's earthy and sweet and i think best
described uh like you said earlier as
being very reminiscent of sure but
there's a cooling quality to it that's
really pleasant um and i'm sort of
excited to spark this up and see see how
the 33 flavor translates with magic
meadow totally yeah like i said and like
pax said the uh oh thank you pax he just
passed me this
doink that we just rolled up right here
so like pax and i were saying the sunset
sherbet flavor is really pronounced in
this cut of gelato 33.
ultimately it's a very very
sweet earthy
delicious
smoke and in both a vaporizer or a
uh
joint like this doink that we rolled up
right here it absolutely
shines the couple times we smoke this it
actually reminds me of jealousy which is
a strain that people are really excited
about right now which is just
background putting the gelato on to the
sunset sherbet but i do think as as
we've gone ahead and smelled and hit dry
puffs of this joint to this point that
the sherb is really coming out and i'm
stoked to spark
it yeah i'm super stoked as well this
joint looks really good it's a fatty for
sure and uh
really excited for those uh delicious
kind of sweet earthy
um almost like
kind of like fermented fruity but still
like very delicious like jam-like
flavors to come through from that
sherbet so we are going to be smoking
this today in both a
vaporizer
and
a joint
it tastes really good in both of them
the effects come through strongly in
both of them uh overall it's a very
stony smoke
this is a fatty
hell yeah
smoking great already
i can already smell that gelato
sweetness coming off the joint totally
yeah like i said
there's a lot of sherb in it but you do
get those desserty flavors as well that
are very reminiscent of gelato
i haven't even hit it yet but i can tell
there's a creaminess to the smoke
definitely and in this kind of joint i
mean it's just absolutely like
such a flavor rush on your palate to
smoke
i'm gonna even out our burn here on the
joint real quick
gotta waste something to taste some
exactly
as many know you got to waste it to
taste it whether you're smoking dabs or
lighting up the end of that joint
we're definitely getting
closer to a nice even burn
so i'm about to pass this joint to pax
but i want one more hit first
or maybe two
that's looking real nice
yeah it's delicious here take this man
thank you brother i'm really excited to
hit this and hold this up beautifully
it's smoking good
there is more of an earthiness in this
outdoor expression of um gelato 33 than
a lot of the indoor expressions that
i've had the pleasure of trying and i
think that this highlights how
epigenetic factors can really contribute
to to the flavor and the potency of of
flour this this does have
more of a toasty almost kind of toasted
rice thing going on in addition to that
super sweet creamy it's almost like a
toasted rice milk tea if you've ever had
that from a boba spot which is delicious
do you get that toasted rice milk tea is
a great comparison
just feeling that on my palate
is making me actually want to drink one
right now
we might have to get one of those later
today yeah this is definitely a good um
yeah good representation that flavor it
it feels terpy on my throat that's one
thing that i enjoy with a lot of the
outdoor varieties that we've been trying
you do get that
it almost feels like the monoterp thing
when you hit some truly fresh press
right off the right off the press
where it's
i don't want to say caustic but it's
it's a volatile thing that you feel in
your throat yeah um
it's enjoyable i don't mean to make it
sound negative at all no it's a great
feeling it definitely tickles your
palate and tickles your taste buds
tickles your nasal cavities
it's from the terps
so now we're about to do the smell test
pax has got the jar right now and he's
going to give you his thoughts
it definitely does smell like a sherby
gelato um there is that that cooling
thing going on
but to me
it kind of smells like a bread and
butter pickle yeah i think that's the
note i'm getting most i'm excited to get
a sniff but when i smelled it before the
video it definitely was reminiscent of
those flavors
let me bust this open
all right guys crack in the jar
i get the sweetness from the bread and
butter pickle
i get candy sweetness funny enough
almost similar to like a lifesaver maybe
like a red or a
pineapple lifesaver i definitely feel
that that that is very much there
and definitely the earthiness and
definitely the fruitiness from the
sherbet
sunset sherbet i believe
overall it smells great
so i filled the davinci iqc with
some of this gelato 33 from magic meadow
farms
i
rock it at the top temperature for the
max vapor
basically i'm going to let it heat up
and then we'll hit it and we will tell
you our impression based on the vapor
all right now we are up to temp on this
thing so let's uh take a hit
it's pretty good it's really good
actually
the flavor from the sherbet is so good
in the vaporizer because you're just
getting those uh resin glands vaporized
on the flower
versus burning all the material
classic just vaporizer stuff
i'm excited to hit it it's good though
the um
the lifesaver sherby flavor really comes
through
in the vaporizer and it does in the
joint too but i think it's definitely
more prominent in the vaporizer
yeah it actually this vapes incredibly
well um yeah that would be my preferred
medium for creating this and i think
that for outdoor
it we should definitely start using the
vaporizer every time because totally
as well as a lot of the really sherb
heavy like rs 11 strands that people
love
and when you can get this from the earth
and the sunlight you might as well
definitely that's a real treat yeah it's
actually
it's very very enjoyable
wow i would recommend vaping this all
day long yeah definitely recommend
vaping this it's really good
as you can see there's like
definitely like some vapor from it
that is one of the better vaping
buds i've ever encountered absolutely
i've been very pleasantly uh pleasantly
rewarded when i put this in the
vaporizer
i don't want to say surprise because i
know it's good bud
and am i
wild for feeling like it hit me much
more quickly out of the davinci i think
you're getting a much more pure
expression of those cannabinoids and
terpenes and flavonoids and the various
compounds that cause the entourage
effect
probably just straight to the dome from
the vaporizer compared to in the joint i
don't have any data or proof about that
but it just
smokes good i'm going to pass the drip
back to you and hold on to the vapor
for sure
yeah this joint's looking good smoking
good too nice white
ash
oh my goodness but we did probably put
around two grams in that joint yeah
probably about two grams and we probably
put around point one five grams yeah bit
little paper vaporizer and
to be totally honest i'm enjoying the
the vape significantly more the
vaporizer hits really nice with this
stuff i mean the
resin is expertly crafted that's for
sure and um
you know props to the farmers for doing
a great job seriously
wow this is uh
i want to show you guys if i can get
this to focus nicely
absolutely leaking resin
that's like a
at least a half inch resin ring
as with all of the outdoor um that we've
gotten um
as a part of this reviewing cycle
i i'm super impressed i know that um
magic meadow
farms is also running some really cool
like 11 week
really long flowering hazels we got a
chance to try some of those and they're
wonderful i'm curious around their sort
of whole stable
genetic stable i think i'd want to try
all of it after this i i definitely
think it's one of the few
times i've enjoyed vaping more than
smoking which is really interesting
because we know that magic meadow are
huge advocates of health
so
all in all an impressive product yeah
absolutely killer job on this um
i really enjoy this herb it's
really flavorful the effects are
really nice solid behind the eyes stone
i feel it you know my body as well
pretty prominently in my shoulders
ultimately just really great clean grown
gelato 33 grown regeneratively by magic
meadow farms
you know shout out to
shout out to magic meadow farms for
absolutely
doing a great job on this gelato 33.
thank you so much for checking this out
we had a lot of fun with this one where
we're looking forward to some super cool
upcoming
reviews um clearly you can hear that
both of us are pretty
stoned and yeah it's wonderful i
wish i had less to do this afternoon but
so it goes um we'll talk to you soon
thank you guys so much for watching make
sure that you subscribe to future
cannabis projects on youtube as well as
future cannabis project 02 we appreciate
you guys liking the video
just comment if you guys have anything
you want us to know or whatever you want
us to review next
but yeah we really appreciate you guys
thanks again
[Music]
foreign