all righty today I'm going to be making
im4 this is Acorn imo3 that just came
out of Gasoline
Alley get a chunk of it let's look at it
look at that nice
stuff that is Acorn
imo3 you can see all the IMO all over it
that Acorn imo3 was made with logs that
look like this right here mushrooms
growing out of them everywhere ground up
tons of logs like this added acorn meal
that I gathered around my house got them
all crushed up added some inputs and
things like that cook that in Gasoline
Alley so now I'll be taking this
imo3 and I'm going to be using some
native soil that I got I'll show you
where I got it and I'll be adding some
inputs and I'll show you here we
go all right and this is IMO 4 material
I'm getting some native soil oil out
from
underneath all of that right there get
all those
mushrooms but this will be native soil
I'll be using to advance my
imo3 to
im4 and I just went and got a bunch of
chicken manure today for5 so that's what
we're getting right there that's going
to be good
stuff all right so first I'm going to
mix this up basically equal
parts it's still under 5
gallon equal parts of native soil that I
got from Outback that you saw in those
videos and then about the same amount
Acorn IMO 3 I'll also be adding the
inputs and I'll show
you I just kind of mix it up
to something I think it looks like I can
grow
in I need that a little more soil
remember it's going to get
wet but if that right there was wet
would it be a good growing
medium man it's getting real close to
it might add a little more
soil all right so there's the first
batch kind know what it looks
like it's real good that looks like
something that I could grow in it's like
a good pretty much a good
soil so I'm going to make a little bit
more making it right here this little
tote it's Acorn
imo3 native
soil a little mix
and I want enough to feel this tote
right
here look at the contrasting
color that's what comes with native soil
native
creatures that's what makes it
good I never worry about creatures or
things I see out in the native soil I
just let them come along let them come
along and keep doing what they do all
right here's the mix we got a little jlf
in the bucket I'm going to make a mix
pour it all in and then if I need more
moisture I just going to add water look
at that that is hashw waterer Labs look
how got the purple Hue to it the
Cannabis we used or the Cannabis we
washed was very purple this is Alfalfa
and kelp
FP made by atona farmer gentics this is
some sea
water this is Oriental herbal nutrient
this is fish amino acid from Marco
growing all that going to get mixed up
there's the full wheelbarrow this is
going to get poured all over it and then
if I need more moisture I'll add water
but this everything has a little bit of
moisture in it right now that native
soil
does get this all in there start
mixing all righty mix it
up water kind of drains to the bottom a
little bit
a little more water in I might even add
some rice
holes break this up a little bit more
the native soil is a little more compact
not bad more compact than
compost I often use
compost for this method for my own
growing
but you can see how the dirt will kind
of Clump little bit of rice hole little
bit of uh oh wheat brand will help that
out a
lot all right going to add some rice
holes that will help break that soil up
a
bit and a bit of wheat
brand always
good now I'll definitely have to add
more moisture with all these dry
ingredients but this will just make it a
better growing medium just from
experience and it's it does have to be
moist cuz you have it has to get
inoculated
it's dry it just doesn't work well but
again not wet
moist everybody
moist
oh that's
perfect all right so the im4 has been
made now these are two different types
of im4 they're both made from Acorn imo3
this one was made from native soil this
one was made from compost this is
actually the bucket that I took to the
Mushroom Festival this year and it's
been what I've I'm growing in gasoline
Alle but let me show you it just comes
out in beautiful sections and brownies
cuz it's got high F all in
it really good stuff but see it just you
want to look like something you can grow
in a good soil that's what the im4 level
is for me anyway way it's something that
I use to grow in so I'm going to make a
few batches of im4 because you need im4
to advance theo5 and you need you need a
couple of IMO fours you need a couple of
IMO 5 so that's why I've made all that
Acorn imo3 I want to make a lot of IMO
fours so that I can make a couple more
IMO 5S all right I'm going to close this
up put in Gasoline Alley and show you
the conditions I use all righty here's
the cooking conditions inside Gasoline
Alley one space heater some guny sacks
that I'll put on top
I like to kind of poke some holes in it
like
this and those holes will start to see
high feet grow all in
them it'll
take four or five
days it's going to stay covered up that
right
there space heater kind of close don't
burn
nothing and that's it about 5 days I
have some good
im4