hello everyone and welcome once again to
royal grown radio thank you all for
tuning in and joining us today
we're really happy to be here
with a true old schooler ben up here in
humboldt and throughout california
cultivating cannabis
doing breeding
exploring the entire cannabis culture
since pre-215 through 215 and into the
modern day
we're here with mr d with happy dreams
genetics and happy dreams farms who's
been
really pushing the envelope on modern
day genetics helping bringing all the
land race and original strains up to the
modern day
threshold that people are seeing today
where they expect you know these super
frosty super standout strains
and
really interested to dig into the
history
the many lives the many pasts of mr d
and
kind of get a little feel for what
inspires him to bring that energy to
cannabis
my name is michael beck we've got rick
elliott hey what's up
and the infamous mr d
happy dreams yeah
so
we were just kind of meeting introducing
ourselves the fun thing about royal
grand radio is we don't always know our
guests sometimes we do but we really
like to dig into the past
we don't know each other we've talked on
the phone a little bit to kind of get a
little bit of a primer to come in
together
tell us all about how we ended up here
today what started you on the path
towards cannabis and humboldt and
how'd we get here
oh wow that's a that's a pretty big one
there but
for me i could say it's kind of like the
water you know like
i was raised in southern california
but it was around uh pools
and as the water dried up in the drought
long time ago the pools were empty and
we skateboarded in them and it's like
the early early years my friends were
actually
legitimately jay adams jim muir
dogtown tony alva and i still can't keep
in contact with several of them and
poor jay passed away legend z flex
anyway
so skateboarding skateboarding led to
surfing surfing led into radical
radical was we were doing radical things
um when all the
kind of jocks in school were
getting drunk
we were sneaking off behind the back and
finding our old my older brother's weed
stash and smoking weed
skating pools and trying to get air and
surfing led to snowboarding
um
probably is
way back
14 or something years old
you know some of those seeds i had
we put into the hills
you know and planted them and uh
yeah like we were talking about some
friend earlier
uh
you know those were funny plants you
know barely got buds dried up in the
oven
um and then later on it became like
surfing
surfing evolved around a lot of chill
time chill time was smoking weed so like
for me i grew up fortunately
where i had like this really good weed
all the time so i had
a lot of it became like the original og
as i got a little bit older
and uh with snowboarding
and i was uh friends with the guys that
had the original
og in san fernando valley and
our friend teddy as an example he used
to make these cookies and everyone say
oh you got to hello you got teddy's
cookies like don't even take more than a
quarter don't even take a quarter
this is long before the days of
pre-measured dosages measure doses so
then uh
anyway i had uh
skipped through some other things i had
a i was a surfboard i made skateboards
so i made surfboards it brought out the
weed brought out a lot of creative
things and i
threw
different medication medicines i've
taken no pharmaceutical medicines my
over 30 years now
um
but through natural medicines if i
started to see things quite a bit
different and i i had a brand called ig
ig was uh more like
dude i'm inhaling ganja i don't know
what you guys are doing but like this
weed i'm smoking it's making me super
creative
and i'm going to start a skateboard
company and i'm going to have a
surfboard come and make hollow
surfboards i'm going to make surfboards
out of plants
and i had all these different ideas and
then i opened a store when i was uh 20
years old
and i had my own store my own brand ig
boarding shop ig surfboards ig
skateboards ig snowboards 1685 a bunch
of different things and that all became
around like
you know the people would say hey what's
critter
he lives up here now too and uh my
friend chris and he would be like what's
critter always carrying that box out to
the car for at lunch time well that's
the bong you know the shop bong
one problem we have is we had drug tests
there you know and if you if you
showed up with no weed in your system
[ __ ] you were fired
that's fantastic so we had a pretty
lenient policy so i've been quite you
know liberal in my views and then uh
fast forward to later on in life is like
i had times where i got injured blew my
knee out you know like oh my surfing
career is
i'm gonna
grow some weed you know oh i tried that
indoor people are doing the indoor like
try that indoor and then it was like oh
yeah wow i'm pretty good at that and
then i was like when uh
one point in time i told my life i was
like i'm gonna move north and i'm just
going to find a place and
i want to live in the trees you know i
want to live with nature and i want to i
don't want to have generators i did live
in a property with generators for a year
maybe two seasons
but right after that i was like i gotta
get a property with really good
environmental
thoughts uh lock the gate live in the
trees
have my own spring
it was until later with compliance that
i put the well in because i had so much
water i didn't know what to do with it
all and the other time i have to put a
well in
but i live in the trees and lock the
gate and have a great life and not
you know deal with the whole society of
the internet and the computer and the
emails so it's kind of ironic it's come
all the way around now with legality and
compliance
so the first property i got was
basically with uh
under the 215 where i i read the law and
it said you couldn't cultivate unless
you were a
dispensary cultivating yourself so i had
a friends with some of the dispensary
so we actually went in escrow together
purchased the property and then so it
was basically their property and my
property and then i was the guy that
would provide the
cannabis for their thing and i basically
never got paid my whole time grew a
whole bunch of years never got paid
that was
so common we all just worked we just
grew it because we were growing you know
it was like growing
and it's because 215 was pretty much
like a donation you were growing for the
patients you know we had a lot of
patients
we and i started just putting in
greenhouses and greenhouse i was really
into the greenhouses i wanted to have
sun grown but with the controls of the
environment in the off seasons sure put
a little heat in the spring put a little
d hums in the fall
protect against those september rains
right so i did some full term
you know runs um but mostly
was into the greenhouse thing
and then as it went into like compliancy
and all that i was always breeding seeds
and
and uh doing the
different uh you know upgrades to try to
make everything have a single twisty
tire zip tire piece of plastic on my
entire property probably
40 acres of pristine
redwoods and trees and you know the
county kind of liked it in the beginning
and then after going along for a while
paying all the fees they were like no we
don't like that the road's not good
enough
yeah so
that was a tough one on that one
and then i got into growing in the
farmlands
uh more in the flat
uh like holmes flat
and i learned about dry farming and
i was doing kind of a modified dry
farming for a while
yeah that's a fascinating area i went
down there
a few years ago probably meeting some of
your neighbors i would imagine
and i learned a little bit about
you know the magic of that area and how
the the eel river kind of swiggles
through those those mountainsides
and and creates this this amazing
farming possibility that i really wasn't
very familiar with since then i've you
know later learned that there's some
vineyards doing that down south i think
paso robles area there's a few
um
you know the whole technique just
fascinated the hell out of me i really
couldn't believe it it looked so amazing
and it was so thriving not just cannabis
they had food everywhere and herbs and
butterflies and bees and the whole place
was just
it really was just as magical as it
could get
um
yeah so i've always been fascinated to
go down there and kind of learn more
about how the plants can sustain
themselves over the course of their
cycle
you know
with that concept
so yeah it's amazing yeah dry farming
quickly got on to dry farming but uh
talk about a lot of different things
today if we'd like to but uh yeah with
the dry farming it was it was pretty
neat with me because i was like okay i
had done some indoor but i originally
grew outdoor you know when i was a child
you know like trying you're just like
fun
couple plants
saw and i've always had gardens and
fruit trees and all this stuff so
then the indoor and then the indoor
you're like okay i i don't really feel
good
then the greenhouses became like okay
the greenhouses are cool and i was doing
greenhouses with lights and power
no generators but then i when i i bought
a property in holmes
uh
strictly because of that's the way the
ordinance was going and i thought okay
this would be great be on the fly so but
then there i was doing
light depth
with no lights so just timing it
effectively planning at the right time
and then no fans no power but i had
power so i was trying to do it more
sustainable and i planted in the ground
but at the time i didn't know
anything about dry farming and i
actually bought the property there not
even knowing about dry farming and
it was sunshine johnson who you know
told me yeah we're doing this dry
farming thing and
i thought you should try it and i was
like try really really not going to
water yeah dig down there there's some
moisture in the soil and i was like okay
and then
so i i did like
10 000 square feet was what the license
was going to be for and uh
i did 10 000 square feet of greenhouse
hoop you know depth like 20 by 100s and
then i did a separate area that was my r
d testing area and that was dry farmed
like completely and
the plants that i fussed with and
pruned and
i had the hoses there as an emergency
and i watered the holes in the beginning
and some of the neighbors had done that
too not everybody's pure in that area
sure but
you know it's moved closer towards it
now and uh
i had the hoses out and that's to lead
into that so anyway the dry farm plants
did better
they got better buds they got bigger
they were they're more dense even more
dense and the plants i had watered and
foliar sprayed and
fussed with and stuff picked leaves and
stuff and pruned them
those
didn't get as good it was like amazing
so then we're just like what the hell so
then i transitioned into more
uh getting closer i did a back feel i
moved triple r there and i grew like a
bigger area
and i had it like okay
we'll kind of try that and then uh
what came full circle was uh the
person i gave my first like seeds out to
was uh
uh out in shively
organic medicinals and they were more
the purists they were the
they had an organic food farm they still
do new moon organics so they farm all
kinds of fruits and vegetables and
squashes and figs and
nuts and they do rotation of crops
and then they were growing a smaller
plot of cannabis
versus i had a smaller property with a
big plot of cannabis
and i was really intrigued by how they
could
just leave the plants
natural and
their technique though was true dry
farming you know that's the whole story
we could go into itself but uh
so when i went back over to homes every
day i was like man i got even my hill
spotted well i got to get rid of this
hill spot the county's probably right
like we should just get out of the hills
we should be down on the fields and the
flats we should be in the perfect place
and then even my home place it doesn't
really work for me because it's it's a
pretty good place but it's like this
place in shively is like this like the
best place
and i pretty much decide i'll sell all
my stuff
and just sell i'm over it i'm over it
the prices were going down it was two
getting too complicated
and i sold everything and then
after i sold everything liquid
everything then
uh jane and organic medicinals said why
don't you come over and farm here
and i was like well what do you mean
like
so well you know you could get a license
and you could lease a place and
so i started uh
kind of just helping out and
had a bunch of
past due invoices to try to collect from
the first years of track and trace i was
100 in on the track and trace and
everything and it was like
25 hours a week and
no one was paying nobody was paying like
all the distributors were basically the
middlemen you know they were hustling
the hell out of us yeah yeah so i had
all these people weren't paying me and
and i decided to kind of take a break
and just like
and i ended up coming back then into
shively
and leasing a place out on their farm
and then i grow alongside them because
we have similar views and they have the
real pure views
don't get me wrong they're the purest of
the best of the dry farmers
and even over there in holmes it doesn't
compare homes has like seven feet of
topsoil larabee has about three shively
has like 30 feet of topsoil wow and
shively is such a diverse
like mini
uh biosphere almost where the
all the neighbors have kept really
strong to the organics over the years
and each other farm
you know the scentsy bolt down the
street humble flowers and a few others
that are there have kept strict on their
organic ccof
certification so we don't even have to
do pest control
nature takes its course like it's a kind
of a wait and see approach
yeah where in the past you'd see an
aphid and you'd be like oh my god aphids
now you like look at them and you're
like okay what are they doing and
they're like they're still there three
or four days like dude they're still
there and then on day six you're like
someone's coming in and eating them
millions of ladybugs and then they start
breeding and often you're like whoa i
have more ladybugs we've ever seen here
so it's really neat out there that's
really cool i didn't know that about the
top soil layering and
you know
these properties these places that we're
talking about are down along the eel
river
along the banks of the eo river that had
crazy historic flooding
for eons before but all the way up into
the 60s
um before they put the dam in
right you know like 53 and like 64 or 54
and 64.
64 was the big one it's no damn it's
what happens is the eel river it goes
out through ferndale
and a series of big wide bridges and
then it goes out into the alluvial fan
out in the ocean out there
and
there was a really big tides king tides
a really big swell so the surge of the
swell and then the moon cycle
was a full moon so as the storm hit real
big
and the water hit you know something
like 70 inches of rain over like a week
or something
and um
the water had nowhere to go because the
ti so it just filled up and then in that
eel river valley
and that's really the appellate as you
know you could have them organic minutes
dry farmed organic venisons
come back on and talk about the
forming an appellate there and that's
the appellate the eel river valley
uh basically from like high rock just
north of like the honeydew exit
founders grove
um
in through
uh up to like stafford so it would
include like
larabee
holmes
shively
pepperwood and stafford that's kind of
the flood plain
area and the river backed up there and
made then deposited all the forest
matter
so all that organic forest matter from
the logging and the building of the
freeways
washed the complete towns out but it
basically washed off the mountains and
then
the finer
forest matter settled into that
eel river valley there yeah and i've
read some history on it too that it had
snowed
really low leading into that so there
was a lot of snow on the mountains and
then that storm came through so it
melted all the snow
and logging was you know really ramping
up in that area then and so
lost a giant hillside or two
full of trees and stumps and oh
everywhere just giant hillsides down
into the river so like eons
worth of this ancient redwood fur forest
soil
just piled up and got deposited in that
area of the eel
that's really just super fascinating to
me
and
you know having not had any experience
personally with dry farming it's super
fascinating also i actually was speaking
with sunshine just the other day
on uh kmud
we had a really good conversation and
she was you know kind of shedding some
light on some of that stuff and talking
about water conservation and the
droughts and you know i was coming at it
from a very different perspective that's
another thing you and i were talking
about earlier
is
i've grown in a lot of different ways
but i've never done the dry farming but
i have indoor outdoor
you know all different styles of indoor
all different styles of outdoor
automated organic salts
hand water
to get a really huge
feel for everything and you know
a lot of those folks out there you guys
have been like
steadfast focused
on developing these techniques and
really improving this whole permaculture
thing and that really speaks to me
so much we've been touching a lot more
on regenerative farming and that sort of
stuff on the podcast
you know even though rick and i work for
royal gold and we sell soil and we
endorse however you want to grow grow in
your pots grow in small pots grow in big
pots you know bring the medicine to the
people
but i'm just super fascinated by this
dry farming concept yeah we both come
from a pretty long extensive background
in
you know caring for the earth trying to
trying to be the best humans we can be
and that definitely leads you know
pretty deeply into how our food is
produced and oh yeah and uh and how we
you know we use this land and live off
this land as as gently as we can
especially you know having kids
you know it's it's up to us to kind of
guide our little slice of the future
into the right path you know and a big
part of that is
to me is recognizing
the influencers the elders the people
that came before us and developed this
stuff and you know the culture that
created these concepts so
you know i think it's really awesome
that you came out of this surf skate
community we we've
focused a little bit on this community
and how integral it is to cannabis and
bringing cannabis to people and kind of
opening people's eyes
how did all of these
you know kind of convergent paths start
to focus your energy more on breeding
because
you know i know you're farming on all
sorts of different ways but really you
were saying earlier your focus is more
now on the breeding again
what what brought you back to that
passion
okay probably like
six or so years ago it got to the point
where it was like
as the 215 was growing the stores wanted
you to double up and double up and
double up and then as the
the engineers were sending you these
giant bills as you're going into the
the new 64 legalization you were like
okay double up double up and then you're
like okay sign on the dotted line you
know you're gonna have all this square
footage
um
so i had a pretty good
footprint that i had signed on under 64
you know under the new licensing
early out of the gate
and it became like okay
so the amount of time i was spending
cultivating
the amount of time i used to spend on
the breeding all of a sudden went into
this i was spending track and trace we
were in the early version of the track
and trace
where
you had these little tiny stickers that
would rip off the zeros and
a a
o and a zero is like the same and the
twos look like the fives
and you're like
oh my god i can't barely even see this
stuff and anyway so what happened is i
started to go like okay i cannot just
keep doing this whole like depth scene
pulling tarps we had like a strict
schedule
703 707
7-eleven you know four minutes apart
drive the motorcycle up the hill
ten minutes apart get that one every
night every night every night boom every
morning open them and then blowers on
them and the whole thing and
we produced some really quality weed and
it was you know i i got some
high recognitions from even like the
early just like sun growers guild as
farm of the year and highest terpenes
and
got like three out of five of the awards
the first year year and similar the
second year anyway
so i i started to go like i need to get
back to the breeding because like
i had been fortunate enough to back in
the day
uh have the connection on the original
ogs which then i was able to
have those get up here in the humboldt
and then those became
like the sfv and tkog basically got bred
together and became like the humble og
and then the lario g kind of popped out
of that
same time and then
so when i
uh started having some friends come up
you know that had distribution outlets
san francisco area they had the
my good friend was uh you know lived a
couple houses away from mario guzman so
mario was mr scherbinski you know so
scherbinski
was like hey i got these cuts you know
i'll get you the original cookies i have
sunset sherbert and then i got this new
one we're calling it gelato
gelato he's like which one do you think
you got
gelato 41 or whatever it was the one i
had and i was like the sixth farm or
something to that matter
that sherbinski and we were gonna be
called like the sherbet tribe and
have this medallions and all this funny
stuff that his manager was doing was a
good guy
jay lofty back in the day
and uh
so
anyway fast forward is i basically had
an agreement that i wouldn't breed with
any of those or do anything but i had
these
really good og seeds which eventually i
crossed
to into the gelatos and the sherbets and
the cookies and then also was like
accumulating other
gear from people that i knew or had and
so when track and trace came about i had
about a hundred and like 19 or 117
strains on the track and trace list
they're just like
what though and i was literally tracking
every one and i didn't fake it at all i
had like yeah i've got this one so i
started pheno hunting like major amounts
i would be like okay well i'm putting
500 plants and a 20 by 100
or even more sometimes and i'd be like
okay so that's all different seeds
that's going to be 500 of that cross 500
of that cross so i was doing like five
to six hundred
i started doing a couple like thousand
plant hunts and then people were like
what are you doing i said dude i'm
honestly
tired
of like having to grow the weed harvest
the weed and then just have it go into a
bag and put a sticker on it so it can go
into some metric system i'd rather just
work on the genetics
work on the strains
work on what really people are looking
at because no one was looking at
terpenes so much and i was seeing this
correlation between like certain
terpenes if they hit like point four
certain ones that hit point two
it'd be half of that two to one some of
them were four to one so like cbd thc i
was seeing correlations between
you know merisine
uh humelin you know different ones
linalool and you know sometimes my
pronunciation is different than certain
people on something
i get mixed up with violence
yeah anyway so uh i've seen these
correlations and i was trying to like
devol uh divest my brain or whatever the
word is into like understanding all
these so then all of a sudden i had like
so many and everyone's like how are you
doing that i said well i had a
background where i worked with numbers
shaping surfboards
so on a surfboard it's like a curve
that's an infinite amount of numbers
because you're only measuring every 12
or 24 inches down a 6 7 8 9 10 foot
board so on a curve you have infinite
numbers so i started equating all those
numbers of like the cannabis plant and
the piece of wood in the middle was like
the stalk
and that all those curves are all the
different terpenes so some people want a
narrow nose some people want a wide nose
and we want a middle one some people
want a narrow tail a wide tail some
people want a double wing swallow a pin
tail and all those are the different
terpenes and people like what are you
doing you're sacrificing so many pounds
of money and all that and i was all look
dude the money
is the money that i'm trying to figure
out what
all these terpenes are doing for
each person or different people and then
i realize like the whole plant you know
has a array of
terpenes versus
the bud on the north side of the plant
versus the south side of the plant the
east west the higher the lower salmon
fruit trees
so what's intrigued me with mixing the
farming with the cannabis is that all
those elements come into play and it
hasn't got that far down the road yet
with cannabis and it's just starting to
turn that way and it's real like really
exciting to me
yeah it's really exciting to watch the
crop science come out and
i'm fascinated by that analogy
that you had with the surfboards in my
mind i'm like picturing
three-dimensional curvature and like you
know moving the different
terpenes around to strike different
balances and achieve different healing
effects and also you know
different you know psychedelic and you
know different highs and flavors i'm a
flavor person too like
personally i think this
massive
selection for only 20 and higher up to
30 percent i think it's a disservice
to the entire lineage of the cannabis
plant because some of the most unique
strains most flavorful standout strains
are tested at 16 17
and they really
affect me just as potently but maybe not
as couchlock maybe the thc isn't quite
so high but all that entourage effect is
really important to me so i love that
analogy of how that all works i think
that's spectacular