hey there it is October 30th so it's
Sunday we're almost done with October
and all of our African uh sativas are
going real strong so looking good so
this is another field notes uh this
particular plant right here we've
planted two of these but this is a
Malawi uh but specifically uh mulanier
and I looked it up it's Mulan Hape but I
guess you pronounce it actually Mulan
yay so trying to get all the
pronunciations correct uh so anyway this
is a beautiful beautiful gorgeous land
race from Malawi and uh yeah all I can
say is absolutely gorgeous
gonna take a sniff
and a close-up of that bud hopefully
it's going in focus
and as you can see it's got sort of that
traditional African spear shape uh I'm
guessing it's gonna be about two weeks
so mid-november will probably be
harvesting these maybe as far as into
Thanksgiving we'll see how quickly this
finishes up uh the top Cola I would say
is about 12 feet tall
uh and then
um oh and the smell
wow
very bizarre
almost uh caramel
caramel and fruit
yeah a week ago this was all rotten
fruit but now it's developing like a
creamy caramel
nose which is very bizarre let me smell
this one to make sure
now this one's a little more spicy
maybe each one's different
no this one's got the caramel again so
anyway definitely a caramel fruit thing
going on
uh which is really actually unique for
African sativa so anyway
totally loving this plant as well so and
again we just want to honor all these
plants so these came directly from
Malawi from uh mulanier area and so
whoever if anyone because of the
internet if anyone sees this video who's
from that area just yeah
totally honored to grow this beautiful
plant and thank you for these cool
genetics love it thank you