[Music]
ah
yes
when you wake up
and you feel like you need a little
upper
or when you're down and out
and you need to get a little higher
if you feel like you need a blessing now
and you feel a little high today
welcome to the church
welcome to cali high episode 56 i'm your
host chanzo nico and this week our guest
is big arson also known as justin claus
a local hip hop artist from the 818
big arson has just released his fifth
album at the age of 23 called keep going
he gives cali high a candid look into
his creative process for this album
which is tied in with the inspiration
and support given by his uncles and dad
in pursuit of his goals
justin tells us how the theme of keep
going is derived from that inspiration
and support
stay tuned
you little [ __ ] you did it again
this little white boy's just a [ __ ]
song is is banging jay
you have talent boy
let that [ __ ] [ __ ] keep on coming out
of that whale well
it's getting better and better you're
[ __ ] brilliant keep going
i keep going
huh
[Music]
they grew up in hood it was catastrophes
okay cali high is blessed to be here
with big arson today one more time
also known as justin claus and justin we
go back a ways to trading mixtapes in
american literature in my classroom and
that was
our kind of
beginning right yep so the beginning of
the journey yeah and you have a new
album out
called keep going which is very cool
and so let's talk about it a little bit
first of all how you been
uh been pretty good uh it's been about
it's been about what a year since it's
about a year man or the since the last
interview but yeah yeah i've been good
just
been uh keep going i guess i've been
you know yeah still going
a lot of gigs absolutely yeah yeah over
that last year just trying to you know
keep it keep it going that's cool yeah
so your new album keep going
uh it's very cool uh i love the
voicemail from pops
which is the intro to the album yeah and
uh
so let's talk about the theme a little
bit what is the theme
um so the theme i guess where i can
start with that is uh
i'd say 20 20 20 um march 11th
uh that's when my uncle passed away um
and like a few months before he passed
away
which is actually
connected to the last song on the album
which is rash california
it was uh
well basically with that with that
there's a voicemail at the voice
recording at the end
which um a few months before my uncle
passed uh we were having like a
conversation right we would have like
lots of conversation you know so many
con conversations um back when i was
living
uh by myself i was actually the manager
of of an apartment building and stuff it
was pretty cool i was living there it
was 2019
but uh yeah we were just chilling we
would have like lots of conversations
about hip-hop about you know lot life
just so much conversations you know he
would just talk to me about uh
you know just a lot a lot of stuff you
know about his life and his journey
through his life kind of a mentor to you
yeah yeah and for some reason
um on that one on during that
conversation uh it was me and another
one of my friends him me him another one
of my friends there we would just kick
it you know just chill hang out and um
there for some reason i don't know i
just felt like i had to record that
conversation you know i'm saying it was
like yeah i don't know it's just like
something was like you should record
this you know so during uh you know i
was like i was i pressed record and then
he was just talking about how like his
journey because growing up my uncles
they taught me how to rap and we talked
about that on the last interview yeah
but uh yeah like he was just talking
about like you know like he because he's
really good him and my other uncle
ricardo um just we were just growing up
i would just freestyle with them we
would just hang out you know they would
just
just rap we would just rap and [ __ ] and
then um
during uh
yeah so during that conversation he was
just bringing up like because i think we
watched we listened to some of my tracks
and then he was just like we were
watching other videos online on youtube
and he was like you know then look
there's a lot of other local people
doing it too and you know you're doing
it basically and he was like back when i
was like 18
you know because i think i talked to him
about like oh why don't you rap too you
know i'm saying you're good as [ __ ] like
if if if he really wanted to he could
you know do something with it um but
then he was just saying like you know if
you listen to the the voicemail in the
the last the last part of the song uh
the last song on the album you could
hear how he's giving you encouragement
you know i've been like i've been uh
i've tried i've done it before here and
there and then he's like you know i was
at the studio
and with one of my friends it was like i
was about like 18
but basically he's like you know it's
cool you know but i don't see myself
going on that journey like exact quotes
from from from that part and he was like
you know i'm good at this [ __ ] but he
was like you know i don't see myself
going on that that journey but he's like
you're already there you know what all
those songs you got and everything and
then he was just like yeah you know it's
like something some i forgot exactly
like exactly what he says but he was
just like just just keep going just keep
going and then i had that voice voice
recording for about like a year about i
was just working on music
but then i it always it always popped up
in my head i was like keep going you
know that like it kind of kept stayed
with me that like that that message that
he left
and uh yeah just ever since i kept going
and then back to the voicemail actually
um when my dad i made a rock song it's
called toxic it was like i was like let
me remember that yeah let me explain i
was like let me experiment with rock
song and [ __ ] recorded it put it out and
then uh my dad my dad had heard it
and then he left me a voice uh voice
message a voicemail and on that message
he's like you know that shit's tight you
know i'm saying you got talent he's like
just just keep going at the end yeah and
then that was basically like
confirmation
confirmation for the album because i i
had a i had an album planned prior
before that
um which i didn't i didn't i had a few a
few songs worked on it and stuff but
then
i just i just basically stuck to that
and then as soon as as soon as i got
that voicemail it was based that
confirmation same same message you know
i was like keep going yep so then that's
when you know very cool yeah from there
determination don't stop yeah definitely
so what is the recipe to keep going i
mean i know you mentioned a recipe in
there right
um
let's see
i mean
i mean you know in life there's like ups
and downs and [ __ ] you know but
you just
gotta keep gotta keep going basically
because
you know it's like people could you know
sometimes people try to discourage you
and [ __ ] you know and then you got
people there's a lot of negativity you
get encouraged and then you get
discouraged and then it's like [ __ ] you
know like you know i'm not not not to be
cocky but i'm pretty good at it so it's
like you know i know myself that i'm
able to to keep going so it's like why
not yep basically so that's how i see
yeah keep the vision bro yeah so yeah i
just stick to it as much as i can no
reasoning
the song
yeah um is that autobiographical
again look at the streets again um
autobiographical like you mean as far as
it sounds like a
wild like
an episode of going out without too much
forethought that one was kind of like it
was kind of it was i wouldn't say
because it connected with the pet the
pandemic but it was basically like just
like i might basically basically you say
that was like going out again you know
yeah yeah it's like i might go out again
and then when i go out you know
you know i'm saying get lit this and
that you know etc you know you know what
i'm saying but yeah basically you could
say that too it was just you know yep
like that if i go out i'm gonna go out
again and then the streets you know it
could connect too to my music too
you know if
once i go out you know i'm saying i'm uh
yeah i'll go out get get these
experiences you know just living my life
and then just putting it on my music
basically so yeah
i guess you could say it's odd like how
you said autobiography
so how do you avoid the burnout factor
in in being a rapper and performing
these days
that's a good question um
burn out what do you mean by that i mean
well you know the road the road tends to
put a little pressure on you but it's
also encouraging right yeah um i i
started performing last year i'd say
it's been 20 yeah 2021 is when i
actually like just started performing
because i i had planned like for right
before uh covet hit the pandemic and
everything i was like damn i gotta start
touring but i think it gave me kind of
like uh i'd say a good enough amount of
time to actually like have songs like
where i have enough songs to perform
live right because i'd say back then it
was just so that i had yeah pandemic
kept you from burning out yeah so so
basically like right i just got uh i
found a connection with um
a guy a my friend friend of mine named
curfew and then he throws these shows
called no excuses shout out to no
excuses and curfew and a big big mic as
well you know um but yeah shout out to
you so i shout
yes sir yes sir so i got connected with
him through my friend george which you
met george as well oh yeah yeah and then
um we just pulled up one day
basically yeah like it was just to see
what's up and like same day i performed
like on some last minute [ __ ] but
yeah so i've been performing like i
think you can remember that like about a
year
and then um yeah i mean
i just we just we did a few shows like
we went to texas arizona and that's the
farthest i've been to so it was pretty
cool it's pretty fun you know like
getting out there and [ __ ] yeah yeah
instead of just staying in like one spot
the whole time but um i mean it was a
little tiresome you know because we [ __ ]
we drove to texas like first we drove to
arizona arizona was like six hours
and then um when we drove to texas that
[ __ ] was like about
like 16 hours something too long
yeah
so it was the drive was tiring but once
you're there it's like it's a it's like
a throw you know yeah just experiencing
new people oh yeah people showing you
love from different parts like seeing
like yeah where where you you know how
people from different uh parts of you
know the country react to like your
music and [ __ ] and you know we're barely
getting started so you know we gotta
gotta keep going yeah but um i mean it
does at times it could get tiresome but
you know it's encouraging
yeah it's encouraging so it's kind of
like yeah i never see it i never feel it
like that way it's just you know i'm on
for like the ride you know yeah
basically all right yeah no burnout
there's no burnout folks okay yeah no
but i mean
everyone there is you know i just get
the strength somehow you know so who
have you been listening to lately for
inspiration um
[ __ ]
i listen to so much music lately um
some good artists right now so many good
artists coming out
uh party next door one of my favorite
um artists
lot of great music you know i'm saying
he's one of my uh his inspirations
[Music]
just different i don't have like a
specific like well you know he asked his
questions like [ __ ] who did i listen i
could look through my phone but it's
just there's so many um
damn i don't i can't i can't answer that
right now i can't that's okay there's
too many like when you look back to some
of your your influences who were
kanye and yeah biggie smalls biggie uh
biggie m biggie eminem as far as like
lyricism
kanye as far as like his like
creativeness as far as like he could
just switch it up at any time you know
i'm saying yeah yeah so all of them uh
[ __ ] drake kendrick there's so many you
know what i'm saying and even just i
think we talked about this last time too
but as far as like anyone that's i just
i get inspiration from different things
but for sure like from hip hop yeah um
i'd say those are like top top ten top
five ice cube
so many
who's doing the beats on this album
um these are there's a few different
producers
um there's like certain certain websites
that you could buy uh buy the album yeah
get the beats from and stuff a few
different ones
um the only one that
that i worked on
and my uncle my uncle uh dj brawley as
we call him
raleigh uh braglio uh we worked on the
last one was jackson for my uncle and
that that track i had it for
i'd say about like a year a year about i
had it just sitting there sitting with
yeah just sitting there and then we
tweaked it a little bit at the at the
end like right before putting it out but
that one that's that's the one where we
had uh we worked on we worked on it yeah
you know well i like the choice of beats
yeah i appreciate it very cool there's a
few different producers one few
different
groovy piano
starts off in the low range of the piano
also the one 405 where you're singing is
very oh yeah i have 405 um on can't go
slow it seems like there's a few
meanings okay
um
well honestly
if i'm being honest like
when if when i first hear a beat that's
like what matters to me the most so that
b it's just like something about that
beat it's like
when it starts
so it's kind of when i first heard it it
was like
then how it starts off and it's like and
then it and then drops it just reminds
me of it kind of reminded me of like a
like a car taking off and getting ready
to take off you know yeah yeah so and
then and then i'd say uh the meaning as
well is it goes with the concept of the
album
most of the songs on there it just kind
of connected some some of them i meant
to meant to connect yeah and others that
kind of just you know connect with the
message of keep going but you know when
when you're when you're going on your
path you know you can't go slow and you
can't can't slow down yeah you know what
i'm saying so you just gotta just gotta
take take off fast yeah keep the pace
yeah you gotta you can't go slow you
know what i'm saying and your life is
kind of like a race
especially with this [ __ ] you feel me
so
um
my favorite song on the album is 405
because because of the chorus where
you're actually singing yeah um what
about more singing you ever thought
about who inspired you to do the singing
and are you going to do more
uh say inspir well obviously like i said
i'd say drake
drake is a big inspiration i'd say for a
lot of like a lot of artists of today
you know because he started not not that
he started that
right before him it was kanye and then
right after uh kanye started with the he
dropped the album called 808s and
heartbreaks and then he switched it up
because i remember when that album came
out
like uh my uncles my uncle my dad they
especially my dad he loves kanye you
know he's always like kanye's [ __ ]
and then uh with that album he switched
it up with like more scene scene rap
yeah yeah and that was like 2007 2008
and then you know they kind of weren't
like like [ __ ] with the album too
much you know because it's like
different from just just hip-hop hip-hop
yeah and then he and then he switched it
up with like uh singing a little bit you
know then right after him
you know drake kind of kept that going
with the singing and now nowadays if you
listen to like today's rap and [ __ ] it's
like so much singing rap you know yeah
which i i just started getting uh i've
been i've been [ __ ] around with it
well you have a voice bro i think yeah
yeah i appreciate it but that one um
yeah i'd say say drake kanye there's so
many like inspirations but growing up
too as well my dad has always bumped uh
not just hip-hop but r b
yeah yeah old old-school [ __ ] you know
like yep some so much [ __ ] but i've
always i've always loved uh like r b as
well but i'm just getting getting into
like you know getting comfortable with
the singing and stuff i'd say yeah very
cool
clowns
clowns you're saying what's like the
what's up with that
clones
that one i mean
you know what i'm saying i'm just
there's just so much there's so much
same clones nowadays you know i'm saying
trying to make the same [ __ ] yeah rap
about the same [ __ ] try to rap the same
cadence the same you know what i'm
saying and uh yeah yeah no i just yeah
like i just feel like i'm yeah you know
i feel like i'm different yeah you know
i'm different and that's like that's
that's how it should be for most people
you know get in your own lane basically
you know what you're saying there yeah
so
and at the time i don't know if you know
at the end of uh the end of it did you
hear that uh that voice recording it's
actually a youtube clip i found like
near the same time
yeah the
the same time it's actually uh
like near the same time i started
recording it i might have seen that
video that clip before or after but
funny enough it's actually t-pain on the
clip i don't know if you knew that no i
didn't but yeah it's like a clip where
uh
t-pain is like streaming live and then
he's just talking about new music and
shane he's like do you do he's like do
your own [ __ ] there's too many other
rappers sounding the same it's like
there's there's two artists with uh baby
in their name it's like do some
different music and i was like i gotta
use that you know what i'm saying and
then i put that at the end of it i was
like that's perfect yeah but yeah you
just gotta there's so many clowns you
feel me
yeah
what is the pain in
f what you saying that's what you're
saying
i mean like i said earlier basically uh
just too much
you know there's people that try to
discourage you or
you know just all those comments and
[ __ ] you know and like as you get older
as you become a man it's kind of like
like [ __ ] [ __ ] what you're saying you
know like yeah like i'm a grown-ass man
like you know what i'm saying like i i'm
i'm keeping it cool like you know what
i'm saying i'm not trying to be on a
gangster [ __ ] or this and that but at a
certain point it's like [ __ ] what you're
saying you know yeah like i don't give a
[ __ ] what you're saying i'm gonna keep
do i'm gonna keep doing me i'm gonna
keep going you know kind of fits into
the thing yeah so it's just like yeah
basically that's you know like i don't
give a [ __ ] i'm gonna keep i'm gonna
still be doing my [ __ ] you know
basically
a line from mission
mission yeah get help that's the mission
now it seems like a
song addresses addiction yeah
how do we find help
um
i mean there's different different ways
there's different different ways you
know i've had like fam my fam some
people in my family you know struggle
with addiction and stuff yeah there's
different ways there's a lot of people
there's some people that find uh
find find a way to beat addiction
through like going to god or you know
rehab there's like there's different
there's different things you know just
find help yeah there could be messages
yeah there could be more ways like you
know there could be more ways in america
you know but there's help out there you
know but it just just depends there's
like so many different ways but yeah
addiction is like a it's like a big big
thing for a lot of people you know even
myself like like i say on the song like
i i have not been immune to yeah
there's like people have a dif and it's
not just with drugs you know there's
different things but there's so much so
much addictions you know and it's just
like basically that that song is just
kind of me saying like you know we all
got our own addictions we all got like
our own convictions you know what i'm
saying but then the point of it the
mission is uh
get up you know like and then i say like
jesus jesus rose you know jesus rose
yeah you know
that like that's that's but he got back
up you feel me yeah and you know easter
is coming up
sunday tomorrow's easter yeah tomorrow
tomorrow's just easter yeah exactly
happy easter yeah happy priest and it's
just like that's the message you know
just just get back up even if you fall
just you know we all got our problems we
all got our struggles it's a great
message yeah
um
close
featuring josiah is a is a great vibe
yeah um
can we talk about the mindset here
okay um so that one
i actually wrote that one i'd say
i want to say like about a year ago it's
been a year or a little more and i
remember just hearing the beat i wrote
it wrote it up and then i was like i
heard her voice on there you know
because we worked on a few tracks yeah
um she actually just dropped her album
so shout out to her josiah 777. you
follow her on instagram as well
but um yeah she actually just dropped
her her album and i'm also on that a new
song uh the first song on the album
called year of the year year of the
tiger oh so cool yeah yeah
yeah you check that out but uh yeah with
that one as soon as i started writing
and i just heard her he like i said to
the beat the beat is what
it's where i kind of start off with the
pro the writing process and everything
and i just heard the beat and like you
know just kind of like i can't really
explain it with you without me like
singing it and [ __ ] but i understand
i just got maybe sometimes too it's like
maybe i mumble something and then i kind
of but it then it all connects with the
the words eventually but uh without the
blanks yeah with that one too
i don't know if i had the
the the idea for the i the album yet
like i was for sure gonna call it
keyboard it fits in the theme yeah but
it all just kind of yeah it all kind of
kind of keeps going and then um yeah i
just started right and started writing
it and then
i saved it and then we recorded it what
like about four or five months ago but
i've been having that ridden since like
a while
yeah but yeah that's the message just
you know i'm close like every time i i
come up with something like it could be
even uh it could feel like a little
discouraging or like give me anxiety
like because every time it feels like
i'm closer and it's like oh i'm supposed
to be happier and then it's like you
know i do feel happy like you know the
more [ __ ] i put out and the more people
show me love and [ __ ] but it's just like
you know yeah like you know i feel close
you know close every time you know yeah
yeah but uh that's that's the message of
that one i guess behind that one yeah
that's just funny it's a little
frustrating but it feels good and then
it's like start over and but you keep
going yeah yeah that's very cool bro um
we talked about this a little bit
earlier but you open and close with
words from pops
and then you close with words from the
uncle we already kind of talked about
that yeah but i want to just uh
you know i think that's a really
cool way to
show some respect you know
upcoming gigs
um i got a few i got a few planned um i
kind of took a little break like about
two months just to kind of finish
working on the album but yeah i
definitely got i always got my you know
my guy curfew he's always got shows yeah
like everywhere even like out of state
um but i got i got some stuff planned i
just got to tap in with him but uh yeah
it's always it's okay
let us know and we'll uh put it up yeah
definitely
appreciate it
and where can our audience find you on
social media um you can find me
basically every social media instagram
uh twitter
even tick tock i don't really be on it
that much but uh everything a big big
underscore arson our big arson yeah yeah
and then um
yeah every on music so uh musi uh apple
apple music we got spotify basically all
all
major like music streaming platforms
yeah yeah it's just big yeah capital b
capital big arson yeah are the i and the
g capital no uh yeah everything
everything's got broken capital in the
beginning
yeah own capital arson too yeah
everything everything
yeah okay
all right well thank you very much
justin for coming down big arson you got
to check out his new album keep going
it's amazing and uh
we're going to come to some gigs
yeah definitely check you out yeah it'll
be lit it gets pretty lit
appreciate the love and uh you know it's
just gonna
keep keep going from here you know
that's that's that's the goal just to
keep going all right appreciate you
check back in with you bro yeah
definitely appreciate you okay cali high
out
peace
[Music]
i know this might sound [ __ ] up but at
times try not to think about you
cause then i remember that i'm gonna
have to live without you yeah it's crazy
how they done it took your [ __ ] life
i remember days when we just used to
spitting rhymes no alcohol and i just
rather [ __ ] drown in it every time i
think about you dawg i cannot stomach
this
i was five years old remember you would
bring me chips
memories so vivid how can i mistake this
[ __ ] this ain't counterfeit
try to maintain but damn low key i'm out
of it you taught me how to spit you
taught me how to run you taught me how
to grind show this little rap of mine
imma let it shine
through these raps in these lyrics imma
let you shine cause you showed me i was
gifted and one of a kind also lifted
transcendent now it swings as we've been
given you was a blessing god had gifted
the life you live was like [ __ ] from a
movie scripting but i can't get to the
script that the [ __ ] you seen as a kid
was just way too twisted it threw a lot
a kid in and out of prison but still
through all that you made a change but
to the devil he was trying to keep you
chained but you kept pushing anyway made
it through the struggle made it through
the rain through the pain
even through the sadness always smile on
your face and when i think about you
take a smile off my face cause then i'm
sad cause i will never see you face to
face but then i hear a voice from god
saying you in a better place so then i
smile and at you in a safer place you
made it
[Music]
hey
he's
[Music]
okay whatever
just