so native soils and
potting soils are going to be very very
different just like
a mineral soil that's you know rock
based or
rock and mineral based is going to be a
lot different than
a peat based soil like something that's
organic rich right
you are not going to grow things down in
the sacramento delta that was a drained
organic soil the same as you are you
know
somewhere outside of that region because
the properties are so different
so understanding cec is really important
but with potting soil and horticultural
it's a little bit
different right because in in
when you're growing in the ground you're
you're relying on that soil to provide
nutrients for you
through its organic matter and through
the fertilizers you've added
and typically it's not as easy to just
add a little bit more do a little liquid
feed do a little top dress it is it
is in more of a horticultural style
system where you're
in pots or raised beds so
you can take advantage of that potting
soil and and do that
dole out a little bit at a time and like
you guys were saying
earlier you know looking at plants
seeing what they're doing where are they
yellowing how are they yellowing
what's happening and then looking at
your soil test and being like oh
well i'm seeing this yellowing because
i'm short in this or i've got
too much of that you can be much
much more i guess direct in in your
feeding in a potting soil and that's
that's why i was developed right because
you can get high yields and shorter
turnarounds because you're
not waiting for things to warm up the
same or you're not waiting for
other processes in like a mineral soil
that are going to be slower than
in a potting soil interesting so you're
able to kind of you know
directly target your nutrient
provision in a lower cec
soil that maybe you didn't have
wouldn't have the capability of in a
higher ce soil if there's all of it
stored
you don't have that same kind of micro
management ability of the specific
exactly nutrient management an
interesting point
you can still do that same sort of thing
in a high cac soil
it's just going to be a lot more
forgiving than in that low c
c one like you're gonna have to no
matter what
dole things out and sometimes that's not
the most appropriate or the easiest or
most economic way
to do it i mean depending on what you're
growing cannabis or
or any other thing like the height of
the plant and the
density of the planting causes
problems with with that in some cases
okay but we don't really have that issue
we've got
the space usually right
and um the like potting media was
created to be able to feed and drain and
you know the hydroponic and the you know
horticultural media was intended to
drain and not hold on to a lot of stuff
and then native mineral soils amended
and this like super soil concept that
people are talking about turning potty
media into super soil is like
um because like your native mineral soil
building that up into a nice
like high cec you know forgiving
buffered type of soil
that's kind of that the gift that keeps
on giving longer
cycle put your amendments in and and
let them break down over time with
microbial activity
so that's why we talk about blending the
agriculture and horticultural concept as
you're taking
something that's supposed to be you know
uh you know feed and drain and rinse out
quickly concept with a
soil building you know you know concept
and then you're mixing them together and
then we're like
you know trying to wrap our heads around
what that means now because like we
understand
potting media organic versus native
mineral
and then what about when we mix them and
people come into the lab and
we try to gauge like well how much
mineral soil is in this potting media
well and then they'll tell us a story
and we're like is it 80 20
is it 70 30 is it 50 50 is it you know
what is it
and they're like uh you know you have no
idea i dug a trench
right and then i put some of the
original soil in there
and then i added it to the full brim
with the no
you just don't it's a spectrum right so
like you know people think of soil as
like
potting media native and like we're like
no we're like a spectrum here in
humboldt and like you bought that
potting media
20 years ago or last year well and
exactly right
something that ties into what royal gold
does is we wonder
what media was that because if you're
using
a lot of the traditional soils or
traditional soil building materials
these are all cellulose based
products yeah right and so they're
breaking down quickly
into smaller and smaller pieces and
being digested by bacteria way more
effectively we're at royal gold we're
building out of
like high lignin organic matter right
exactly right so it's gonna
last in theory it's gonna last longer
and
build fungus more effectively so
not only are you asking when did you put
what in but what
was what you put in made of yeah
yeah i think the you know the chemistry
or the actual
you know structures of the
whatever matrix we're growing in is
super important right
um there's such different chemistry
going on with lignin versus cellulose
materials
absolutely totally there's such
different chemistry happening between
peat and cocoa there's such different
chemistry happening between like mineral
soils
and organic based potting medias or
whatever
like totally apples and oranges right
and like structure structure's another
one that really
it interests me that we take these
organic materials and we farm them and
we call them super soils and we're
building
structure and we're building all these
things that like native soil inherently
has
structure you know they've got root
systems and there are earthworms and
you know aeration and movement of
finer particles coming through and
there's all this stuff happening that
affects the way
water drains and how the structure you
know so
it's not just the chemical properties of
the soil that are so different between
native and potting it's also
the physical structure of like
we create all the structure by sticking
you know whatever we're gonna stick in
there to aerate it perlite or whatever
you know
lava pumice whatever yeah and in the
same way that
really nature's doing it where you look
at like
the successional level of plants that
are growing in an area and how that
affects the soil biology
and chemistry totally where you can have
basically identical soil makings
but then you have a historical
meadowland that's all
low successional plants and it's all you
know bacteria driven soil
lots of weeds things like that and then
it borders right into a forest land
that has all of these lignin rich old
growth
you know conifer contributing
to the soil structure and you look at
the biological diversity and
how this the nutrients move
in these i nearly identical like you
said
you can spit to a different soil
structure
where does that tie in as well
to modern soil building
uh i have i have something to say about
that so
it's first of all it's interesting that
like with agriculture we're always
destroying the soil structure by tilling
up the soil but we want to build soil
structure because it's really important
and then with potty media it's an
artificial structure
right so we're like fluffing it we're
creating a fluffness
which is in lieu of an actual texture of
a native mineral soil
over geologic time has created
actual structure right so
riddle me this in order to develop
structure
in a potting media you first have to
destroy the structure that you built
which is the fluff
which compacts it then you add the
biology
and then that ties the morsels together
which then creates structure
which then would be closer to a histosol
which is like you know more of your
potting media that's been farmed and
refarmed for 20
30 40 years now you're kind of making
your own
histosol structure full living soil
so super soils i don't think it's
something that is created today and put
in a bag and sold to people
um unless i might have a different
definition of super soil but i think of
it
as a developed over time whether it's
organic or not it still has
still has to take time it doesn't have
to take geologic time
because and that's the other thing this
is let's speed this up right we've got
composting and cover cropping and
all these things and it just empowers
people too to say you know how many
billions of years it takes to form one
inch of topsoil or whatever it's like
well i'm never gonna get that
sorry can i swear on this oh yeah i'm
never gonna create an inch of topsoil in
my entire
you know however many generations what's
the point right and so we're destroying
it at massive rates but we can create it
at massive rates too because it's called
human intervention
so if humans can intervene in a bad way
and destroy stuff
we could also intervene in a good way
and build stuff
so let's do that that's
amazing and it's part of the whole home
composting movement
absolutely you really see us starting to
recognize
as a human culture that we can build
life or we can destroy life with a lot
of our choices
and the same comes to the world of
cannabis where we're looking to build
life
and in the world of soil building where
we're looking to build life and
we're trying to create a format when
we formulated these soils and started
looking at
the science behind what we put in there
was working and
you know discovering why some of it
worked we didn't maybe
know all of it when we built these soils
but
wow all of these things contribute to
building a structure long term
yeah and in a world where we are losing
top soil to erosion
faster than it's being created and
there's you know actually
soil endangerment and soil biology
endangerment going on
all over the planet this is another way
that i feel like cannabis
tying to hemp and moving into big ag is
going to hopefully benefit the world
yeah with potting media it's not it's
it's
it's always traditionally been meant to
just feed
the plant it was never intended to be
like a
living thing so when people started
digging their trenches like
you just changed a lot of
how things work right because now you
have this exactly pretty inert
medium i mean like it's it was organic
but it's not
really doing much it's just providing
space
for roots holding a little bit of water
holding a little bit of nutrient like
it's a planting media
exactly not soil soilless media
but its properties give
plants that jump start that they need
and so even though it's definitely not a
traditional bag ag
sort of thing the kind of idea of having
those
trenches makes a lot of sense right
you've got this
potting media that stuff can get growing
quick but it's also coming in contact
with the native soil which means that
it's coming in contact with all of that
biology it's all moving in and out and
transferring nutrients from
the organic matter that'll actually
break down in the soil right because
whether it's grass or tree cover doesn't
matter that organic matter
is turning over every year and feeding
the microbes feeding the plants
so having that potting media in contact
with the native soil
allows it to kind of be that gateway
and allow that transfer between the two