[Music]
[Applause]
hey everybody chad westport here and i'm
here with a little update to my water
only experiment going on right now
between the soho and living soil and the
kiss organic soil
well i put out a couple videos going
over those soils and appalachian supply
reached out to me and said man
you've got to try our water only soil
so here we are i've got a couple bags of
the appalachian supply water only soil
we're gonna add these into the mix and i
got one more suspenseful reveal
always loving to you know keep things
interesting around here but now
we for now we've got a three-way mix
going on so
i'm gonna make a video and do a little
bit more detailed explanation of this on
my own channel chadwestport on youtube
but stay tuned to here fcpo2 you'll get
some grow updates on the water only
experiment
all right catch you guys later party on
[Applause]
[Music]
you