hey there hey it's Sunday October I
don't even know what day it is what is
it 23rd 23rd
um we're gonna do some field notes we're
now moving into our sativas so we're not
just doing Afghan anymore and this one
right here is actually Purple Haze uh so
um not we have a bunch of military jets
flying over our property right now so
sorry about the
sounds like we're in a war zone but
um anyway ignore them
uh this is uh
Purple Haze though
um very cool Plant incredibly chunky
buds we grew a few of them so I'll show
you this one first
um not quite sure about the purple I'm
not seeing any purple at all but
absolutely beautiful chunky buds so I'd
say they're just a few days away from
being ready to harvest
um the smell
it's just complex
sort of
different fruits and kind of rotten
fruits and melons and slightly rotten
melons
so just a really complex melange of
different fruits and rotting fruit
with a little bit of spice
yeah
very bizarre very interesting I'm very
excited about this so this is uh the
Purple Haze which I believe the story on
this is It's originated out of Santa
Cruz so it's actually this is almost
like a land race a Santa Cruz land race
so um kind of cool oh and then let's
look at the other one
uh
so here's another Purple Haze so yeah it
seems to be right on schedule
this one yeah it's about ready as well
and then the feeding requirements on
this was yeah I probably could uh
handled a little more nitrogen next year
we're going to have bigger root space
area
um but you know I never want to risk
over feeding
um so anyway it looks looks just about
right but very nice and then we have a
third one
uh
anyway it's all the way up there in the
corner do you see that so it's on
schedule as well and it's dark well
let's just go up there
because this one actually I think this
one's the furthest along so let's take a
look at this
starting to get some brown hairs
and just yeah
let me see what the smell
yeah this has more melon like a musk
melon
uh situation going on but yeah anyway
Purple Haze very cool it's basically
like a Santa Cruz land race so I'm
excited to grow it and
there it is and I think we're gonna
Harvest probably this week
anyway bye