we're going to do some strain
history yeah every week right we're g to
pick different cuts different strains
different lines and we're going to chat
about rather than like I've done it in
the past but sort of like by breeders
and a much deeper wider thing we're
gonna take them in little segments
little little little chunks little
chunks right and um you
know crybaby and I went back and forth
on like where to start okay and so
um I guess the best way to say it is
this okay is that I want to tell you all
that cannabis history is hard for a few
reasons one is because we were one is
because we were illegal for a long time
and so things were in the shadows for a
bit okay two is that memories are
imperfect and people often
disagree okay and so all these stories
that we're going to tell and all these
things that we're going to say over the
coming months about these various
strains and different things are the
information as best we know it to the
best of our knowledge okay to the best
of our knowledge they're all and and
it's so it's an organic living thing
right a a living document if you will
that is very open to people coming out
and changing it or adding Nuance to it
or people coming out of the shadows and
adding CL verification to things we
didn't know about or whatever you know
and so what we decided to do is um you
know we're going to talk a lot about
like old Holland and Neville and you
know and and various different seed
stuff because that's sort of like the
basis for all of it but yeah crybaby
thought that we should talk about um
something uh at least first that
originated with me I agree there's not
that many things so I'm going to tell
you
I'm gonna tell you the story of the meno
Tada okay um as best I know it even
right and then I'm want to tell you a
little bit about what what it's done um
different people that have gotten it
various Pathways it's taken all that
different types of stuff right
so the story starts with um I was fresh
in meno I hadn't been here very long it
was late 90s okay and I had a buddy
who was a glass blower all right and
glass blowing was and its infancy enough
that we were just starting to learn that
when you fume gold and silver and heavy
metals onto molten glass it could kind
of be unhealthy for you right and so my
friend lived in Willet and he he his
first his first grow his first um glass
blowing shop literally had a cheap box
fan stop stuck in the
window okay that was that was his uh
ventilation Tech all right so we found
this old man all right who was a HVAC
professional okay his whole life was
about
airflow you know venting uh tubes you
know uh hoods all that different types
of stuff and he was old and sick so we
hired him hey can you come into this
garage this shop and can you build us a
ventilation system that will keep my
friend
safe right he was old and poor and so he
agreed okay so he comes in we paid him
we paid him a chunk of money uh well you
know he was it when I moved here uh
Mendo was not very economically po it
was it was it was in a depression for
lack of a better way to put it there was
a lot of rural poverty and stuff like
that around here right sure so and
everyone was affected by it and so he
was building this thing you know um
various duct work and and hoods and all
that different types of stuff and in the
process of talking to him I discovered
that he had cancer okay so that affected
me pretty greatly because at the time my
ex uh she we that's part of the reason
why we moved to Mendo is that she was
undergoing
chemotherapy Mena uh California had just
passed 215 about a year and some change
before right
and um it was the first place in America
that you could have cannabis for certain
ailments and not just be seen as like a
a total uh a a total criminal right so I
felt bad for dude and I was doing
relatively well for myself at the time
and I was young so I ended up giving him
like a quarter pound of weed and a chunk
of hash to help with his nausea with
chemo okay and he didn't have anything
to give me back he couldn't pay me or
anything like that so I didn't care I
just said here you can have it it's just
a bonus for helping us we're super
thankful right didn't think much of it a
few weeks later um when he's finishing
up the the ducting and and the putting
in of the the ventilation system or
whatever he comes back and he's got this
medicine medicine canister um that had a
couple seeds in it and he goes you know
I used to grow in the
70s um and he's like I've got some old
seeds in my closet here's a couple of
them and uh uh it's all I have for you
so I was super thankful for it whatever
I didn't expect much of it but I
um I uh I went home and I sprouted them
and whatever I got both of them popped
and I was growing them up and
um I got him about two feet tall
okay this this sounds kind of dumb but I
had a I was growing in bedrooms at the
time uh indoor at least and I had a
friend come in I was moving my veg and I
had a friend come in and help me set
stuff up and move stuff around so we
hung a few lights and we some tables and
we painted this room and da D anyway so
we do all that stuff we get it all built
we move the plants in there okay I come
in the next day and there's this big
plant that's dead on the floor right and
one of the one of the lights back then
the hoods were pretty heavy and they
were metal and they were kind of
sharpish one of the um he had missed a
stud on one of the hooks so one of the
hooks had come down and
swung and chopped off one of my two
menop plants at the
base all right Y and it was the I had a
male and a female and that was the male
so at the time I was super pumped that
um the the female didn't die right
and
uh so I take this female and I Bloom it
out with other stuff that I was growing
and it was unbelievably purple and it
smelled wild and it smelled okay it
smelled absolutely wild and I was like
oh my God right so I took this I got
some dried flour of it okay and I took
it to uh homie and I was like what is
this and he was like dude I didn't even
know I had this anymore I thought I gave
you something totally else okay this and
he told me the
only the only uh the only story I have
to it is he said this is the only purple
weed I ever grew and I grew this in the
summer of 1977 in Koval which is a very
remote town in medino County all right
and at the time this is 1998 is or
whatever so I was
22 and the seeds were a
21 they were about a year younger than
me you know well lucked out and I lucked
out really it was pure luck okay um I
never really got very much more
information from him and sadly he died
of cancer um within three or four months
of that time right um so he was passed
and
so uh you know and basically he lived
like people don't know this about meno
but like meno has a lot of Hills right
and he lived on the northeast
side of a mountain in a cabin okay and
if you live on the northeast side you
don't really get and you're in the woods
you don't really get a lot of sun right
right so he basically had his little
seeds stored in a cold
Closet in his little house forever okay
and you know be that as it may so that's
the story that I have behind
it okay um now funnily enough strangely
enough so we're growing this stuff out
and
it's vibrantly purple looks like nothing
else on the looks like nothing else on
the market smells incredible the only
weakness to it was that
it flowered really fast but it was kind
of light in the
bag you know like it like the first
month you're growing it you were like oh
my God this is going to be the biggest
yielding thing in my
garden and then the second month other
things catch up to it and it ends up not
being all that great a yield and it's
pretty lower on the level of
THC okay but that actually is one of the
components that makes me think that his
story is true okay because when most
stuff in the late 70s and early 80s
was high single digits to low teens THC
yeah that was actually really normal
yeah for that era that was kind of like
you know I mean 14 15 16% was like crazy
rare
potent okay you know and and I'll I'll
tell some cool stories about it or
whatever
so uh like you know how sometimes on the
base of stems right you'll get like a CX
that forms yeah right sometimes with the
Mendo P that KX would be so dark purple
okay I don't know if you can see my
fingers that you could take that KX and
go like this and there would be like a
purple stain on your finger to the point
[ __ ] stain on your hands to the point
where we used to joke that um we could
make ink out of it or something he could
right and so I kept it around okay and
um four or five years later three years
later four well probably more like four
or five the purple craze
hit where Urkel and you know things that
became known as as purple Urkel
Granddaddy Purple uh Grape Ape Platinum
all these different things started
booming Mendo was part of that it wasn't
as potent as the other things so it
didn't catch on quite as much and it
didn't spread as far okay um but what it
turns
out in a nutshell is that and I also
think this sort of ties into the fact
that it's probably really old right is
that it's that one plant that I had its
genetic diversity is really
wide yeah like really wide okay I know
we've seen the on tons of them tons of
so if you grow out and I've seen we've
done this in a number of times if you
grow out like a few hundred
s1s okay you will get tall plants short
plants you'll get plants that are all
green you'll get plants that all the
leaves are green and all the and all the
weed is purple you'll get you'll get
weed that's lavender you'll get weed
that's pitch black you'll get weed
that's
burgundy probably 10% of them smell
skunky probably another 10% maybe 5% 5
to 10 smell
cushy the vast majority probably 60 70%
have some kind of like incense floral
nog Champa type hashish or that I can't
this is where he's laughing at me
because my the the greatest weakness I
have in canana is describing Aroma
accurately right and I'm you're fine
you're fine chatting with Mr I'm just
telling you my
caveman
sense of what it was okay and
then around that time uh so that was
that was late 90s and then a few years
later I met this dude named Jason
King okay and um I met him at um at
Eddie Lep's Farm in Lake County which is
a whole different story or or whatever
and Jason was trying to go around the
triangle and photograph and make blurbs
about a bunch of the old school heirloom
weed okay that was around then and him
and I became pretty good friends then
all right and I helped him um uh go
around mesino and go around all these
places which at the time was like very
underground and very suspicious of
Outsiders right um and get sort of an
inn okay on all that different and with
different people that would never have
let him in the door sure so if you go
into the uh into the canab
Bible um the second one at least uh all
those pictures of the Mendo
P are from my garden
Tada right and that kind of made it a
bit more
famous obviously
um because it was it was it was raided
in there and uh you know and you know so
that kind of boosted it a little bit and
then there's another part of it where
uh my buddy
CSI
okay got a hold of uh this weird
smelling burgundy
weed with some seeds in it
and he was blown away by its Aroma it
didn't smell like anything else he'd
ever smelled it was like reddish looking
and wild okay so he hunts it
down all right and he actually found
people that were friends of
mine okay because that's where it had
come from it was like he had to like hop
from this person to this person to this
person to this person but he ended up
kind of getting closer to me right and
he he got close enough to me
that those people told him the real
story right that I told just now
combined with like who I got it the old
man the cancer The Swinging down of the
you know and so what's funny is that at
that
point various people were lying to him
okay and telling him that they had bred
it and giving him a bunch of Guff right
so he ends up meeting me and I claim it
and I didn't realize at the time that it
was anything or that he had had three or
four other people that had claimed it
and so he asks me to tell what I knew
about it right so I start chatting about
it and I start telling him the story and
then I like sheepishly admit that we had
this error with this old ass super sharp
hydrarm hood that dude missed the stud
in my bedroom ceiling and the thing
swung down and killed it and
apparently that part of the T tale had
been told to him by his
friend and no one else had brought up
that little
tidbit right so he was like holy crap
this is the person that popped
it right because I had these weird
little
details that nobody else had speaking of
speaking of weird details um someone
asked has there ever been an essential
oil analysis from real Afghan or nepes
hash um not to the best of my knowledge
however I mean I'm sure lots of
Europeans could pull it off and I would
always be interested to see what some of
these old hashy you know insensi plans
like the menop show up on like a full
panel yeah compared to something like
actual traditional hash on a full panel
so so
I point to add to that in fact so when I
was going when I was going out to
Amsterdam quite a bit okay
um for a bit all I did was go to stores
and buy essentially what we would call
Today wck weed
wed but eventually I made friends and I
started getting weed and hash that was
too good to make it into the
shops better than W weed better than W
weed right and so a lot of people this
is you know in Amsterdam it's mostly a
hash culture and a lot of people don't
know this but a lot of a lot of The
Growers I think Yos Samy and stuff has
talked about it a lot of The Growers um
that were growing uh weed for like the
the coffee shops and stuff like that
were actually growing it for money and
they would take that money and they
would try to buy the best traditional
hash they could get their hands on which
was rare hard to find and the top
qualities literally never made it into
the shops because it was swooped up by
all the collectors before there so I met
this dude they call him the nose he's
still alive he's over there his name is
Steve he worked he grew for Neville
right and Steve had this collection of
different kinds of
hashish okay and apparently everyone's
favorite hash that they could get I mean
they had stuff they had Lebanese they
had Moroccan they had this they had that
but apparently the best hash their
favorite
was um this nepes Temple balls
okay and they said the best hash that
was from Nepal was these nepes Temple
balls but it was westerners or Europeans
in this sense right Europeans going over
there and helping the farmers with
cleanliness and Purity and some of the
processes to keep it a little nicer for
export to the Dutch Market interesting
okay so that was sort of like like
nepales strains grown by nepes farmers
in their taah or whatever you know in
the high elevations and all this
different stuff or whatnot but then when
it comes to extracting and processing it
the Euros just added a little bit of
like
cleanliness to the processing and stuff
so I smoke this nepes Temple balls
okay and it is the only thing that I
have ever smoked all right that tasted
like the Mendo PE
yeah and I'm not saying that Mendo has
some unique flavor or anything like that
but what I am saying is that maybe for
whatever
reason meno p might be one of the only
things that
survived West with that flavor
profile and it's interesting
because it's not like it was absent
something that you and I have like
talked about and I've shown you before
is like if you I've gone through every
issue of High Times up until I guess
2005 or six and then like basically the
same with every other counterculture
magazine for cannabis you can find lots
of early stories of very very like bold
genetic purples in your region but
there's a timeline Gap you like I showed
you that picture that's like you know
that little kind of squat but like
hybrid Leaf looking purple thing in
Mendo in 81 I showed you the purple
skunk and all of that stuff from like
the like mid Sam days those photos and
stuff but like it's just all of those
thing things seem to just kind of
like go off the timeline at the same
time and as soon as you see like 85 86
and all of like articles and magazines
and stuff are mostly dominated by what's
happening with like the booming Dutch
Seed Market um it's like a lot of that
stuff was lost up until basically the
pre days of the purple craze
and it's strange obviously it wasn't all
lost and people had their own projects
and stuff but
like it's interesting how it came back
with like a Vengeance because it almost
seemed like at another point it was like
wow like even that old article on
Dolores is like wow look at this deep
purple alien weed [ __ ] right like I
think I didn't I didn't realize it when
I was young and going over there and
buying a bunch of seed from Amsterdam
how temporary availability is and how
things can you know and so it's like we
don't have a a huge plethora of things
you know from back in the day we have a
few things that have survived here and
there right and so you know um I so
that's kind of like that's kind of the
meno PE story and and like the Mendo PE
story like starts with me in the sense
that like I I cracked the seeds but it
also starts with this old man okay and
it also ties to you know late 70s 77
that's when he was talking about it that
is when with the hippie hashish trail
and stuff like that um a lot of early
Afghans and a lot of early hybrids from
that region started making their way to
California and Oregon sure in the mid to
late 70s that's when the sort of the
first wave because the first wave of
cannabis in America was pretty much
seeds from imported weed Mexico Panama
Colombia Jamaica Thailand perhaps you
know these different things and the
Afghans and the Afghan hybrids and stuff
those got made into hash so there
weren't free seeds with your purchase
right right and so and so the people on
the hippie hashish Trail they started
giving Afghans and Afghan hybrids to
people up and down the West Coast that
they were friends with you know
everything from like that's where the NL
thing started especially in Mendo and
humble where there's like very old you
know weed growing and stuff like that
people started getting a hold of that
kind of thing and you know and so you
know what's what's ended up happening
is that it turns out over time I I I
would say probably that like menop is a
premier breeding plant okay CSI used to
joke with me that like we could do a
giveaway of a bunch of
s1's and have people pick their
favorites and then have them post it and
there would be such variation in what
people picked right because there was
such a w there's a lot of s1's where
it's kind of like it's it's a lot more
narrow
right Mendo is one of the rare ones
where there's literally like dozens of
different ways you could go with
it okay yeah and you know it probably if
it was 20 or 25% THC it would probably
be like one of the most legendary
strains out there but it's like a
lighter High um but it has incredible
TPS incredible colors it's got a lot of
variation in it and it's it's really
neat um I mean I just Gabby uh you know
I think I told the story before but like
that's actually like one of the things
that cemented Gabby and I's friendship
was me and my my friend Shawn who sadly
passed uh gave him a joint of
menop and he hit me up and was like what
in the [ __ ] is that you know because it
was just so it was so different from
everything else that was out there um
and so like a lot of old plants um you
know I think its best attribute is the
ability that it's sort of like a time
capsule and that you can breed with it
and you're going back in time to an
earlier time long before all the
sameness came in long before all the
inbreeding and stuff with all the famous
cultivars that have happened in the last
15 or 20 years it's just from an earlier
time you know and it's really valuable
as as far as that goes and so um one of
the reasons why we decided to start with
the with the meno PE story is because
it's partially my story and it requires
less interpretation now a disclaimer
when it comes to all these stories you
can choose to believe as much or as
little of it as possible right um
because they are just stories it'll be
fun and um you know but uh oral
histories and stuff like that and
stories are are neat right and so we're
going to do basically every show we're
going to be picking strains clones lines
every time there's going to be a
reoccurring segment on strain history
yeah right and it can even get updated
if there's somebody that all you can
take audience suggestions you can also
take audience suggestions and even more
so than that if there happens to be an
audience member that we're talking about
some strain that they have a personal
friend or a connection to and they want
that person to like clarify or add you
know some some depth or some flavor to
the conversation about things that they
know it's more than welcome all this
stuff isn't meant to be definitive it's
meant to be to get information out there
for for younger people to educate some
people and to start a conversation about
the history of some of this stuff it
it's each person's truth as best they
remember it and the caveat here would be
as as calmly as you stated someone else
can come on and tell their truth from
their perspective that people uh are
nice to each other and don't start
slinging mud at each other well the
slinging mud thing which sometimes
happens this the slinging mud thing I
think boils down to two basic factors
when it comes to Kaa because we all came
out of the Shadows um being an OG if you
will okay A lot of times is tied into
did you happen to be lucky enough to
have some history with a famous strain
before it got famous sure we want to
hear your story oh you were involved you
were talking about this or that and so a
lot of times when it comes to history
okay history is always history is
history but then there's a bunch of
people that are like well how can I make
this history make me money or build my
rep or work for me right now right and
so capitalize on someone else's story a
lot of history is like I'm gonna do this
tale that paints me in a really good
light you
know and um you know and so one of the
interesting things about menop is that
it's such a unique smell and Aroma that
almost everything we found so far um
that smells like it or comes like it
ends up being descended from it and I'm
not going to like really dive into all
that uh about where it went and the
various things there's a lot of info we
could get into in the future um you know
and it's not really necessar it's not
like even mine really it's like this old
man gave it to me because I gave him an
act of
right and he gave it to me and I popped
it and it just it was just sitting in
his closet and uh you know so there's
there's that