we're going to segue into our uh into
our recurring um strain
history um but we're gonna I'm going to
do a couple of notes first right about
it and one of the notes is going to be
is that as I said before the whole point
of talking about this strain history
isn't to come out with some like
definitive I'm right you're wrong
anything like that it's basically to
educate people on like what we know and
okay which just happened
um we want it to be an ongoing
conversation so if people are listening
to this and they end up hearing
something that they feel is incorrect or
they have Nuance that they would like to
add or they have tidbits that that they
might want to add right or they want to
correct things right that's not like us
being um you know we welcome that
absolutely we welcome the conversation
we welcome the you know people adding
pieces to the tapestry
right we doe of
credibility you say completely [ __ ]
wild I might be so some of so so some of
the stuff that we talked about on a
previous show um for instance to bring
up Gabby again he wanted to clarify and
he wanted to chat we've been meaning on
having to have him on to talk about
certain things
anyway and so like that part of the
ongoing conversation will happen well
he'll get his chance to clarify right
something else that happened that cool
that was really cool is last week when I
was discussing or we were discussing
sort of like what we knew about Jim
Ortega and the maple leaf right I
mentioned that while Jim Ortega was
still alive uh he was quite private and
he has chosen to rarely or for the most
part never but maybe a little rarely
speak publicly in depth about some of
the history of that kind of stuff right
and it does appear that he made friends
in the era he came back as dogist with a
handful of people that we share as
mutual friends and you know
acquaintances of our own and one of them
did reach out to us so cool is that
everybody probably knows who bod is
right when it relates to cannabis seeds
and and all that well uh bod and us are
friends right and so he reached out to
me because uh he listened to the show
and he was like hey man you know he's
done some work with the Kush for okay
and he's actually communicated with um
with Jim Ortega about details um
relating to the Kush for okay and so
this is lovely uh in a couple of ways
one it's because it it comes from uh one
of the um one of the really cool
breeders in our community
uh well you know what and I and I don't
mean to just like always black raincloud
[ __ ] but like more than
that very very few people besides bod
are looked at in such a way where
basically everyone thinks you have
nothing to gain by misleading anyone
that's antithetical to your personality
and who you are so if you have something
to say or something to add that at the
very least you're telling the truth
you're telling your truth what you were
told sure so with that being said we
told our truth or what we knew about the
maple about the Maple and about the Kush
for and the things that Jim Ortega gave
to Neville in a previous episode yep uh
bod reached out with some correspondents
from Jim that enlightened a little bit
about one of the lines we were talking
about which was the Kush for so before
we get into this week's um chat about
strain history I wanted to add to last
week's and say that Jim Ortega had
written bod and he told him that the
Kush four
seeds he they got in the early 1980s I
believe it was
1982 okay in New Mexico I don't have all
the notes in front of me so I don't know
which college it was oh yeah go ahead
but there was some but that's kind of
not relevant but in New Mexico in 1982
there was some Afghan exchange
students okay that came out to study at
this particular college and through
knowing him or his friends or some you
know Mutual circles or what have you
they got a hold of seeds from
Afghanistan from these Afghan students
of out of which the Kush for came and
what Jim Ortega said is that obviously
1982 was um pretty early in the game for
a lot of indicas throughout America he
said that those indicia lines that they
grew for a lot of consumers on both the
east and west coast
were very unique and very different than
what they were used to getting and they
worked with it a whole bunch right so
when I spoke last week about the Kush 4
I mentioned that we barely know anything
about it apparently it came to them from
uh exchange students from Afghan an in
the early 1980s in New
Mexico and it got passed along to Jim
Ortega and friends down there and they
ended up growing it and you know it
ended up getting blended into the USA
Market that way so something that's
interesting about the story and I that's
a cool story I love hearing about people
from unexpecting or unassuming places
being responsible for things I mean how
is it any more exciting than that right
random New Mexico Afghan exchange
students um but you know something that
really kind
of got with me about this story is that
it doesn't further explain what made it
to
Neville I would assume that the seeds
were reproduced whatever the push for
was and that became the seed stock
however the Clone that went around
because Jim didn't come back around
until about 15 years
ago that would have and I'm only using
knowledge that we have heard as a
community we know that Jim went away for
whatever reason that's a thing that
happened what is that seed stock that
survived that he popped and that clone
that goes or reproduce seed stock over
years from someone else and it doesn't
really put us any closer to certain
concrete answers because there is a
clone now that's from a seed line from
1982 when was that clone popped is that
clone in fact a product of pure genetics
or is it something and I don't think it
really matters to an extent but it's a
good example of we can know what we know
we can have more clarity added even from
the original source and still not be
100% clo like 100% spot-on and closer to
any definitive answers and I think
that's isn't that kind of part of what
makes cannabis magic it's all kind of
like I mean it's
cool so what what's neat about it is
that our little uh chat on YouTube Led
to uh more information getting shared
that was at one point private um and you
know it doesn't add a ton of depth to
the story but it does add some cool like
now we know where it came from now we
know how they acquired the seeds we know
what year they acquired the seeds we
know what state they were in at the time
all these different things now this
could also lead to you know um you know
uh this could also lead to more
information later on so I would I would
love to hear about it I mean so every
time we do this
segment it is a conver hopefully okay
not always but sometimes it might be a
conversation starter yeah where it
brings people out of the woodwork some
people might be like oh you were wrong
you were incorrect I would love to add
to the T AP of the story and correct it
or change it or add Nuance to it on a
future show like we're doing right now I
was born in the 80s you think I saw the
original kush for tell me [ __ ] more
like it's that's that's just the way it
goes and like you know and there's like
little nebulous things that you can
think and like it's one that I told you
and if this generates some sort of
someone coming to be like you don't know
what the [ __ ] you're talking about kid
by all means I love that [ __ ] I mean
no com getting Jim would be cool Jim
would be super cool um but you know
there's a lot of
oldtimers who are you know very
important to the scene um that don't
want to be public or choose to be
private and they might have private
connections and they might say things to
friends or what have you um but you know
uh there's a lot there there was a lot
of decades where keeping your head down
and staying invisible was the most
critical component to staying free
should we do should we do like a fund to
see how much money we have to fo over to
get Uncle Dave to come on God talk to us
about some [ __ ] I mean so anyway I got
at least one [ __ ] skunk one vintage
[ __ ] kilo cost on this interview so
if you're listening I'm here for it
buddy so we're gonna start this week's
we're gonna start this week's segment of
strain history on something that most
people have obviously probably heard of
or had some familiarity with uh we're
going to tell you what we know and we're
going to tell you a bit about like what
we think it affected and all that and um
this week it is white widow or on a
larger level the white
family
okay
so I think the basic story yeah is is
this right there is that white widow was
released as a seedline in
1995 by Shanti under the greenhouse
seeds label okay
okay and it won awards it was extremely
Frosty it won cannabis cups it quickly
became um one of the one of the big
strains of the next 10 years right um it
really changed the game in a lot of ways
and if you're someone like me from
California or Chicago or what have you
um you know you got that you got the
story that it was you know Shanti Baba
made it it was
from Holland right and it was dropped
under greenhouse seeds and that was the
that was the line that sprung into a
number of different like the white
family if you will Indian Brazilian
Indian was collected by him Brazilian
was some [ __ ] line called like the
kahba or some [ __ ] yeah that was his
story that was his story so then I go to
Amsterdam okay different story and it
turns out that um and it turns out that
most of the guys in Amsterdam would tell
you that there was this there was this
gentleman named igmar right and he was
cracking open a block of
hash and at least one maybe several
seeds fell out of it yeah
okay maybe we should clarify who he is
to like yeah go for it oh um he was a
big player in the early coffee shop
owner of an early coffee shop and seed
bank and
the as far as allegations go long before
it was called White Widow it was called
aram's Wonder you know based on the
little neighborhood outside of you know
I guess inside I'm sorry I don't know
that that City that well but like
General Amsterdam Metro greater area and
that's where it was being passed around
it was apparently being passed around as
a clone since maybe as early as 198 n
from what I've heard and that you know
if if someone who's actually Dutch wants
to be like again you don't know what the
[ __ ] you're talk by all means but that's
that's what I've
heard when
and what was his shop called when his
seat back that I forget but apparently
you go you could go in there and you
could buy I'm not gonna anyway you that
that was the tale okay and he got
basically this very pure very frosty
afghan that came out of it and
apparently he even sold clones of it out
of his coffee shop to certain people at
times what I heard
right um and you know so there's these
different origin stories right I was
around for neither of them so I can't I
can't add I can't add verification to
either one but what's
indisputable okay is that in the mid99s
Shanti released a seed line that was
called White
Widow okay and it took the Cannabis
World by
storm very quickly after he released it
it was white labeled by various other
seed companies in Amsterdam right
um and then the other thing that we
should mention too is
that the first cannabis cups and like
and the High Time stuff in the late 80s
a
a lot of the awards and a lot of the
pictures and stuff like that were pretty
ugly right the weed look ugly like the
um it just didn't it just wasn't very it
just wasn't very good by the mid 90s
when the white family sort of Hit the
market High Times had shifted and it had
a whole like Cannabis Cup special
edition right and the center of these
high times at that time would be very
glossy very high quality professional
photos of of pages of all the winners
yeah and I would say that was true 995
96 97 98 and so for people like
me okay um you know like you would get
high times and you would look through
this stuff and you would see which one's
one and you would see these high quality
photos and you would see all this
different stuff and you would drool and
want to get um and and want to get that
stuff right yeah so so the white family
really changed the
market okay it Spa after White Widow
came out there was a strain uh we spoke
about it before it went from Peacemaker
to great white shark to shark shock
which was White Widow by Skunk one um
there was another strain called White
Rhino uh which was White Widow by a
different Afghan I believe I think that
he revealed in that last interview that
is indeed afan Maybe but didn't he
reveal that it is Afghan te in White
Widow as
well wiow I can't recall but there was I
would say the great white shark White
Widow and white rhino were sort of like
the three-headed Hydra of the white
strains through Greenhouse they all won
a bunch of awards um for the time they
were super photogenic they were Frosty
um they ended up getting crossed to a
bunch of things Simon from Syria seeds
took took the White Widow and crossed it
to his AK-47 line and he called it sh
and he called it white russian because
obviously the AK-47 is a play on a a a
Russian uh you know a Russian assault
rifle and that became one of like the
five or six strains that Simon sold for
decades the the you know the uh the the
white russian um and all that and I
would say that between 95 and the early
2000s
the white family became one of the
dominant
strains in
cannabis yeah absolutely I mean I feel
like if you got into weed and from like
maybe like 96 to like 2000 and like you
know 1998 1999 is when my little
juvenile shitthead mind started being
like Oh look weed this is a [ __ ] that my
mom and my sister smoke like I
uh like I saw those pictures like in the
you know 99 2000 High Times of like
white russian just like the two page
like ads where Sirius had like boom boom
boom Bud shot lined up next to each
other paradise had them too and they all
look so fire and I was like I have never
seen weed in the [ __ ] in the wooden
box hiding in the [ __ ] random drawer
that [ __ ] looked like that like
that's that's it this is it and and part
of it is that since High Times went from
like these like if you look at like the
the 89 and 90 High Times Cannabis Cup
photos or whatever they're pretty awful
photography I'm not a photographer
that's more crybaby's world but like
they're dark they're not very attractive
looking um they're small photos and by
the time the white family dropped like I
said before like the center of these
High Times would be multi-page big
glossy see different kinds of paper very
well lit much much much nicer nug picks
and those something something I want to
grab before it gets away from me because
there's so few so so randomly questions
I can just answer so accurately uh
someone said Sharon White Widow was
apparently popped from sensey White
Label stock in the early 2000s that's
correct it was popped by um Lone Star of
Texas resin company and uh it was real
[ __ ] lug but apparently real [ __ ]
strong I've seen the pictures of it um
one of those one of those dudes still
has it that was a buddy of his maybe
it's composer it's it's one of those
dudes they still have it no there
there's people out there that
legendarily finicky and a pain in the
ass to grow and and then the question
about a Aloha so that was Judge arizo
who's unfortunately not with us anymore
um neither is Lone Star from Texas resid
company unfortunately um but
so there's a cut and he had that it was
called like sweet thing and it was like
cherry and it came from a club in the
Netherlands called Aloha
Amsterdam um it wasn't really a seed
bank but they sold seeds and they had a
special White Widow cut that was indeed
a hybrid he went back years later
because it was so [ __ ] good and he
loved it so much and got more seeds and
that's where the FG of the Aloha Widow
from him came from as well see look look
I'm actually [ __ ] useful today there
you go well no so and you know I mean
the hard part is is that running or now
I see it cool if you talk if you talk to
people strong thing if you if you talk
to people in in Holland there are any
number of people that will stand by the
ingar story 100% oh absolutely shy Shany
has said that he developed it and it's
from him and that's incorrect right like
I said I wasn't there I'm so I'm we're
just telling you the two competing Tales
of how it came to be I'm just saying
that that second story could come with
like might be a lie but it might come
with like a free of the Dutch mob with a
gun to the side of your head as as AR
says this is our [ __ ] can say
definitively right is that it wasn't
until Shanty released his seed line in
the mid90s that it became world renown
and there was seeds available to
purchase if you just came into Holland
to grab seats right if the ingar story
is true it was basically a local
phenomenon right and that you could only
get the Clones if you knew him or you
you knew his coffee shop or or what have
you but when Shanti dropped it with
Greenhouse the next three or four years
I would say 95 96 97 98 is whatever
those years were dominated by various
White Widow hybrids or white widow
itself winning a bunch of Cups placing a
bunch getting a bunch of Fame they
become some same with some of the
biggest stories in cannabis uh Shanti
still sells a version of it he calls it
black Widow because when he released it
under Greenhouse um arjan uh trademarked
the White Widow name so he owns the
White Widow name right and um so you can
still go to Mr Nice and get a version
called Black Widow from him sure right
um you selling a version too and you
know what I've never seen them run back
to back by the same grower at the same
time so inam Mar's version is called
Master Widow and he's worked on it
progressively it's actually one of the
few parents that we know from anything
we know about uh what Luke's done at
Paradise seeds um so I I mean if it's
that coveted in that program must
something good must have come out of it
right however I haven't ever seen them
compared and I would have loved to see
that Ingam Mar's first seed iteration
first the first Greenhouse iteration
that would be that would really be
telling you know there's no doubt
there's no doubt that Shanti through
Greenhouse popularized it and made it in
the weed Community a household name sure
like that's and what's interesting is um
something that I'd heard and it was a
story that went around and it might not
be true but something I'd heard over the
years was there was
a former either
Dutch living but German born hash
Smuggler someone who was doing what like
Hank you know was doing early like
moving [ __ ] moving [ __ ] bricks
like getting it by by the way Bulldog
guy all some of those guys a variety of
them super legit they weren't just
random [ __ ] weed shop owners like you
see today these were dudes that [ __ ]
smuggled hash and [ __ ] really tried
to break down the laws where they were
[ __ ] or living and definitely those
dudes still deserve respect but
like basically what I was saying was
there's a story about one of the dudes
like that who ended up being an editor
of a very early counterculture magazine
over there having brought back random
[ __ ] seeds and even maybe some plants
from
Brazil and those would have but those
would have entered um the Netherlands so
so so much earlier than Shany got there
because he wasn't from there I don't
know people you know he's like Nev neev
was from Australia guess guess where Sal
he was from as well like most most
cannabis stories begin with a certain
amount of division and mystery because
they come out of the Shadows so to speak
um and so but what's indisputable is
that after Shanti released it under the
greenhouse label as white widow it
dominated for probably a good 8 to 10
years it got crossed into all kinds of
things it was one of those white Frosty
you know potent Afghans right and so
people crossed it there was a really
there was some really famous like Cuts
going around in the early 2000s around
here of blue widow right because they
took blueberry and white widow and they
smashed them together and it was much
tastier than white widow was and it was
much more potent than the blueberry was
um and obviously like the white family
got crossed into all kinds of things
hold on before you go any further just
because I brought it up earlier someone
said motor breath is like white rhino
but less body and obviously motor
breaths [ __ ] you know got that kind
of [ __ ] petro camoo and remember when
we're talking about the clarity of
Afghan te you know yeah and that's
what's and that's always been
interesting to me is that if indeed need
white
rhino is Afghan te White
Widow that would be an example of one of
the rare combinations where Afghan tea
turns real nasty because it's
interesting to think of that as like
some skunk archetype and the father you
know the you know part of the like
greater scheme of the nastiness of Super
Skunk right that's how people imagine it
and whatever that dials into whether
that's this or that
but that same parent produces nothing
but sweet plants when you have the most
broad like squat versions of like Afghan
Haze which should theoretically also be
made with Afghan tea unless all of it's
in incorrect
um those are all sweet plants like
syrupy sweet like the way that the
dronkers described [ __ ] Maple Leaf
Indica seedline when it came out like
sweet or limey or [ __ ] whatever like
and that's interesting
because White Widow would be the kind of
parent or have the genetic capability to
make yeah Afghan te represent a skunk
instead
of skunk petrochemical I've heard people
say White Rhino [ __ ] horrible
airplane glue odors came out of it that
[ __ ] doesn't come out of Medicine Man
and no I've never seen it and like it's
white wi is an interesting breeding
plant I think that's what I'm getting at
something about it is unique enough that
it does drag out interesting things from
other hybrids that otherwise don't exist
in those hybrids it became one of the
modern building blocks of cannabis
because it became super popular through
winning all these Awards and High Times
it had some amazing pictures that drove
a lot of drooling because back then I
can tell you as a young seed buyer it
was very difficult to get a a hold of
things right these were all regular seed
lines at the time because the feminized
breeding thing had definitely not taken
off so when you bought them you got
males and you could use pollen to cross
on to other things it became so popular
that most of the other seed banks bit it
bought seeds of it made their own
versions of it people started offering
all kinds of hybrids of it it started
getting mixed into all kinds of things
right and it sort of became I would say
probably from I don't know 1995 to the
early 2000s it was one of the dominant
most popular strains in cannabis
and it's probably in a lot more things
than its name gets credit for oh
I'm just because the combination of
green houses popularity at the time how
many awards it won how many glossy Expos
and people getting like me being young
getting all excited going over to
Holland and buying that kind of stuff um
it really made a Major Impact right um
and whether it was bred entirely by
Shanti whether it was an accidental bags
not even bag seed hash block find from
block I love has whether it's some
hybrid of that and it's like Shanti took
the Clone and crossed it to Brazilian C
and worked it some before he you know
some did something to make it a seed
line right right whether or not he
created it from himself um and and
that's kind of like what we want to do
is rather than being like these people
are right these people are wrong I think
these are two slightly intertwined
stories that multiple people you talk to
believe
strongly
yeah right yeah um yeah seeds in a hash
block that literally I think that's
literally like a a seed fell out of uh
you know and in Holland back then most
Amsterdam was hash culture they really
weren't into they really weren't into
flower that much it was it was in the
80s especially most of those guys were
very hashish based right um and I I
don't I can't verify it or anything like
that but I will tell you that there are
multiple old connected people in
Amsterdam that believe that
story completely yeah not a doubt in
their mind like they don't they don't
even tell it like it's a supposition
they tell it like it's just like a
statement of fact yeah you know I always
I always think of homeboy's little
expose on Shanti where he was like I'm
the [ __ ] king of Amsterdam who do you
think you are but what's what was always
screwy to me about that is like other
than the obvious like straw man and
personal attacks and [ __ ] everything
else seemed very reasonable
like yeah yeah and this was the dude
that hired you that's that's so Ju Just
so people know probably does know some
[ __ ] [ __ ] that's all I'm saying if you
take the if you take the Shanti version
right obviously Greenhouse owns all
those names okay but Mr Nice sells I
believe White Rhino he calls it medicine
man today yeah he sells White Widow as
Black Widow and he sells great white
shark as shark shock yeah and I believe
Simon from Sirus still sells White
Russian yeah no he does I think it's one
of his I think it's one of
his I think it's still like you know
Simon only has six or seven strains he
sells he made a
new but it's just made of old things and
that I just mean white russian is one of
those half a dozen things that has been
on his menu since the
90s you know old boy call Miss fell
apart and
like I I hate to break it but no one
really wants like strawberry or kill or
like white Russi and they want the old
[ __ ] and like here's the thing even if
you lost the moms and you don't want to
own up to it because it came from a
result of a really bad experience
totally understandable your personal
business is your personal business but
if you have something that like people
have an allegiance to something that can
like you know keep your Legend alive I
would do absolutely everything in my
[ __ ] power to give someone the truest
version of what they wanted and what
they remembered especially if I was
playing with enough money that that
wouldn't be a problem it's at some point
it's about like it's strange to see
people who have been around for a long
time trying to burn their legacy to
squeeze a couple [ __ ] extra bucks out
of it at the end like you can you can do
whatever you want with your life fam but
like I I would I would hate this see
that like I hate to see Vernard selling
like random cheap CBD it's like you're a
[ __ ] Legend you personally I would
say that my favorite version of white
widow was The Peacemaker great white
shark uh shark shock uh line um there
was some some of the most potent weed
i've smoked from uh from over there was
uh was was that it's incredibly potent
I've talked about it a bunch and then I
would say like the best outcross I've
ever smoked I Mo I mentioned it before
was blue
widow which combined somehow the turps
of the blueberry line it was really
flavorful right but it was extremely
Frosty and potent and so it sort of took
qualities that each line had and merged
them with qualities that each line
didn't have like white widow was kind of
bland but it was very potent blueberry
was kind of had had some turpy elements
but wasn't particularly potent and so I
there was uh when I was going to those
like Harvest festivals and stuff like
that in the canab Bible era um blue
widow was a pretty popular one and there
was some fenos of it that were just
absolutely lovely oh yeah there was some
great blue widow out there even even for
a long time like yeah it was it was it
was a really it was I haven't seen it in
a really really long time um but it was
delicious and it was very potent and I
kind of thought that like it was an
improvement upon both lines oh I agree
the out the the outcross itself right
correct um and so you know if anybody's
listening you know uh if anybody has any
any um any key points or anything like
that or anyone has any like bits of
information about anything we talked
about on this little bit of strain
history by all means reach out to me or
crybaby absolutely and you know on a on
a future show or something like that
before we do that week's strain history
we might amend or add to or add some
Nuance to stuff we've said before you
know and all that type of stuff and so
we're going to keep doing this um you
know some of the strain histories it's a
littleit difficult because some of them
it's like we could talk for one or two
minutes about what we know and then you
hit brick wall right we sort of started
with the maple leaf and the white white
lines we sort of started it off on stuff
that we thought we could chat about for
like a good 30 plus minutes because
there was a lot of depth to them and
there was like versions of the story and
they had a big impact right there's no
way I'm not
shocking yeah you know and yeah so I
mean I'm just I was just telling you
we'll
just basically like those two stories
those two sto reach out like and give us
the info I was just telling you this is
ingmar's version of the tale this is
shant this is shanti's version of the
tale and whoever believes what it's upon
them and the the truth could be one or
the other the truth could be a blend
yeah you know it's hard to say you know
we're at the two hour mark you think
we've talked enough about Widow
speculation and we are at the twoh hour
mark so we're going to keep doing this
uh same channel same timing we're going
to we're going to add various things to
it and stuff like that I hope that you
guys all like it um you know uh
and uh that's kind of like yeah we're
going to try to keep it to two hours and
we've gone over so um I would like to
thank Peter again and I would like to
thank his homie who stepped in uh when
Peter was unable I could get on to be
the man behind the scenes and all that
and we will be here next week and the
only closing thing I would say is that
thank you for listening um we love the
conversation today and an open
invitation to reach out with stories
Tales bits and information we're all
just trying to sort of like orally
document our Shady history yeah what
what I what I posted earlier so people
who are watching on Instagram I can't
put their comments up on screen so I
need to copy paste them from Instagram
so I thought I'd add someone's two cents
on that story from Instagram as an
example of someone just asked we're
gonna yeah we're gonna get an email but
we are slacking on that just what what I
was gonna do is give you guys uh both
access
to I think it was it this one questions
at so I can create like a group login
and just anybody log in and that would
be lovely you can reach out to us on
that that he just posted you can reach
out to me on IG under Nao dog or crybaby
Organics on IG
[Music]
he