you know last week um we did a strain
history thing on uh on on the white
family White Widow White Russian white
uh you know great white shark all that
kind of stuff White Rhino and you know I
I've mentioned before
that one of the things we wanted this to
do was rather than be some sort of like
definitive layout of what happened that
we would tell things as best we knew
them okay and that we welcomed people
that were in in the know or had
information or what have you uh to come
out and to um you know message us or
talk to us or what have you about all
that that added more information we
didn't know and some Nuance right and
so after we did that uh that happened in
Spades uh because because Shanti Baba
reached out uh with a bunch of claric
with a bunch of clarification on our
white right uh show so I thought it
would be I thought it would be cool to
uh read and comment a little bit back
and forth on some of the things he said
so we could add his take uh you know to
it give our own opinion whatnot then
we'll dive into this week's strain
history and then we'll dive into sort of
like the the core of this week's show I
guess right so I'll start out I'm going
to look down because I have to read read
this um and this is actually pretty
interesting because it goes into uh uh
it goes into um some of the shadiness
that goes on in in our world right and
so he wrote and said um arjan or
Greenhouse seedco never trademark
adjectives like white widow or right
White Rhino Etc as it is not allowed to
own the name it is only they only put
the reg the regulation symbol to let
people think this I Chang the names of
the strains to do the correct thing when
leaving a company so as to make clear
the distinction and no people would know
when they were buying things from me and
when they were buying things from the
previous uh you know previous regime
so what's interesting about that is that
when I read that I was super amused okay
because obviously when you see a
trademark symbol next to a name okay you
assume something right you you know yeah
and and sometimes assumptions makes you
a a-hole right because yeah how you and
so Argent did this thing apparently
which was very clever and that he
figured if he put a trademark symbol on
it he wouldn't get caught and everyone
would assume that he had done
it seems reasonable so that that's
that's that's pretty clever I always
thought because when you would buy those
packs after Shanti left um they would
all have the trademark symbol and then
he changed all the names yeah you know
and so you think okay well he obviously
had to change the names because there
was trademark
involved right right and apparently uh
that was totally
untrue and it was just a thing by
Greenhouse to make people assume that
that was
true yeah and it probably is also for
the best because when someone leaves a
company and when they're going to you
know go off and do their own thing I
mean seed reproductions have to occur
you know existing stock doesn't last
forever so there likely is you know a
distinct difference even even if it
takes a year or two to occur between the
same line even if it had the same
progator sold by two different companies
because your seed stock will run up and
you will have to make new and you will
not have the exact parents especially
you know if you let somewhere you know
not on the best terms not every as a
buddy [ __ ] splitting up everything on
the way out like there will be a
distinct difference so even Beyond you
know the trademark it was probably in
the best interest you know for people to
be able to decide what version they
liked so I'm going so Peter put
something up a little bit I'm going to
read it actually because I have it in
front of me because I think shanti's um
shanti's words deserve he's he's a
really an OG in the scene and has done a
lot of work and contributed a lot of
lines to the so I think it's probably
cool to just like say his own words
about the subject and then uh we'll chat
on in a minute uh he said I also made
the seed versions of all that you
discussed as ingamar story of finding a
seed in a piece of hash does not allow
for breeding unless it was chemically
induced but really if you follow things
a bit further like breeds called
critical mass or super silver haze or
the CBD strains you will clearly see I
went on with seed breeding and
Innovation While most others went for
sales of fem seed I'm not making an
opinion just stating facts since this
Widow seed came out in 1995 if you look
prior to them where there was no seed
for Widow nowhere it was just a plant
and a cutting story so while I do not
really care anymore about what stories
are popularized I find it amazing that
people still have their theories when
all seed companies who copied my seed
version use my words that were written
up by me in the greenhouse seed Cod days
no one really uses anything from arjin
or imar when it boils down to
descriptions so I hope that clears up
some of the EXP some of some of the
thoughts and some of the stories from
the early 99s be well all the best
Shanti Baba
so uh a couple things I'll say about
that and then I'll turn it over to
Crybaby for one I should not that it
matters but I should put my finger on
the scale and say that I tend to believe
Shanti Baba okay um we were just trying
to offer up the two stories that existed
right I'm sure if you're Shanti and you
and you created it and you popularized
it and all that it was probably a little
bit of a bummer to hear a a version you
know that in included someone else um
but I will say I do believe him and for
all intents and purposes he is
absolutely correct in that the larger
weed scene had never heard of white
widow right he is the person that
released the seeds and the early hybrids
of it and so every single person that
bought those got Shanti Baba's work
right no that's 100% accurate right I
mean that's really what happen so you
know um and you know so everyone's
getting Shanti Baba's work whether it
was at Greenhouse Seed Co or later on at
Mr Nice or what have you um it was
Shanti making the seeds it was Shanti
selling the seeds um you know whether or
not you know this clone story or
whatever is true or not it was very
localized to Amsterdam's Holland right
and Shanti Baba releasing the white
family under the greenhouse label in the
mid 90s is absolutely what put it on the
map right sure yeah um so we don't you
know I mean I I just wanted to throw
that out there where you know we we're
trying to be objective and offer things
that we know right um and you know so
that's that's we've had two things now
with our stories the first was bod bod
giving us some information that Jim
Ortega had given him about the Kush 4
which was lovely addition to that and
now we have Shanti coming in and talking
about the white family and adding some
trademarks and some extra like you know
Nuance to it and stuff which I think is
also super
cool and there's also something to be
discussed about there is a difference
especially in the canas community
between you know what we could called
like true origin the very very first
iteration and you know projection of
something onto the community and then we
can say you know when was you know
Community spread and popularization
occurring you know as as much as I hate
to say it you know sour is a great
example of that there are people who had
that those plants that plant Etc very
early however when you look at the
broadscale popularization of that plant
when the masses got it what they might
know of it might be a little bit
different for people
so there is something to be said about
whether or not the origin of a story
relates exactly to how everyone knows
the end point result and regardless of
how white widow might have got there the
point is and very true that if you were
into white widow if you bought seeds if
you grew plants if you grew hybrids you
did grow shanti's version and barring as
far as you know people with a you know
expansive reach and reputation barring
Luke from Paradise I don't know anybody
at all who has a prolific breeding
program and you know cites White Widow
as being critical to the greater part of
their world and what they've developed
besides him you know and and it it's
that's I'm not saying that one's better
I've never seen them run side by side
I've never seen any of that
however how it got there how people know
it definitely is mostly single source
and the handful of people otherwise you
know what they have to say is equally as
valuable however on a broad scale White
Widow you are talking about Greenhouse
or Mr Nice Seed origin plant and
everybody everybody that bought White
Widow and crossed because it was a
regular seed line obviously and and uh
back then everyone that bought it and
crossed it to things and made hybrids of
it of their own and everything else um
you were buying the you know what Shanti
had created uh for sale right so um we
don't need to we don't need to Deep dive
too much more into that except for I
would like to say that uh we view the
strain history portion right as a
continuing conversation Absolut okay and
so it's lovely that he was a list
listening and B was willing to add his
thoughts and critiques right and so you
are
like yeah willing to engage and be
polite and nice about it and stuff so if
we're talking about something and you
have an area of knowledge about that and
you're like oh that was wrong or that
that was this or that was kind of right
but there's this context to it by all
means reach out please and it'll
probably end up you know like on the
continuing conversation like we did now
absolutely the next Dutch mob joke I
make might be about you come on
[Music]