well happy father's day
this is the belgian
sean
this is the earliest one and here's
something to start to come we're gonna
go ahead and sample a couple of
different early and late
see i went through and
chopped a bunch of these down
here's the crazy i want to show you
though
it rained yesterday after we had crazy
crazy so we went up to 97 from
80s and now we're at um
we'll be at 75 again today but we had
strong winds
for several days ripping branches out of
trees and stuff and kicking up alkali
dust from the west desert and such
and then we had about a minute of rain
and that's with this alcohol so i'm
going to give these guys a rinse not a
watering but i want to get that alkali
dust off of them
again happy father's day no show today
but uh
check me on my own channel if you
haven't subscribed yet alex hardy
here on the youtube
and we'll catch you next week there
and i'll drop another reminder here
peace out