going to be a
interesting conversation tonight we're
going to talk about the phylosphere
and we'll probably get a little bit into
the rise of here rhizosphere
and we'll probably talk a little bit
about the regen conference this weekend
uh because that's where i am heading in
the morning so
uh definitely be talking about some of
the things going on uh this weekend
depending on how the show goes
hello nick
hey jason good evening
next week we're going to do because
you're not going to be here nick
i do have a a different guest coming
next week a gentleman by the name of
jesse and he's going to come and we're
going to talk about
hvac and
humidifying and dehumidifying and
why do humidifiers may not necessarily
be the right choice
especially if you're running ac because
they can be somewhat the same thing
interesting if i could join that one
actually i like the conversation around
environmental controls because
it seems like in most cases the physical
constraint that
large-scale operations run into is
their total dehumidification capacity so
yeah
yeah absolutely absolutely
too many things going on this week and
uh again getting ready for the regen
conference so i spent uh i spent an hour
going through seeds earlier
trying to pick packs of seeds to bring
with me to trade
uh
this weekend
and uh because there is a seed swap on
sunday
so
looking forward to that as well um
be good to trade some genetics and
see what uh what else is out there i've
got a lot of genetics
just going through stuff was kind of
crazy
trying to figure out you know what i
want to keep and
what i
may or may not actually get to
it's only so much room in the tent um
you know i think at my best run
let me let me go ahead and pull this up
i don't see any activity on
the fcp uh on the youtube side so let me
go ahead and pull this up but i uh
i was counting uh
you know how many cultivars i was
running a year and i think my
one of my better years
i think the most i did was uh let's see
[Music]
21 different cultivars from 15 breeders
and
that was uh that was even a little bit
of a stretch so you know
plants
a year
um
at most i possibly could get away with
and
if you have 200 packs of seeds that's
eight years right there and that's just
you know if i ran one seed from every
one of those packs
you get to work that out for you for a
long period of time
i might just have to uh you know at some
point in time i've always had this uh
idea of just you know paying somebody to
borrow their facility for for a round
and
run as many of those seeds as possible
to see what to see what came out
although you know with all the
metric stuff it's kind of hard to see i
don't think anybody would actually let
me into the facility with all those
genetics because they have to be tagged
you know
they have to be entered into the system
before you can actually have them in the
facility legally
depending on the state yeah
correctability yeah exactly like you
said depending on the state in certain
states the traceability is
taken pretty seriously and in other
states uh that's true
maybe one of the newer states coming
online might be able to get away with it
under the radar
sneak them all in there
all right nothing from uh
either one of them
um so i'm gonna assume that the youtube
feed is a no-go for tonight which is uh
definitely cuts into some of our crowd
um and uh so i apologize there uh for
that and uh we'll we'll go ahead and
we'll uh you know we'll have our
conversation about uh
rhizosphere and phylosphere and this is
recorded here on clubhouse so
it is possible that uh they might be
able to do something with it and throw
it through the youtube
magic later on make it available
so uh rhizosphere and phylosphere so
let's go ahead and kick off with a
little introduction
you know the phylosphere is a term used
in microbiology to refer to the total
above ground surface of a plant
when viewed as a habitat for
microorganisms
the phylosphere can be further
subdivided into the colosphere which is
the stems
the phylloplane
the leaves
the anthosphere
the flowers
and the carbosphere which is the fruits
which is usually our favorite part of it
the below-grain microbial habitats
the thin volume soil surrounding the
roots of the subterranean stem surface
are referred to as the rhizosphere
and the llamosphere
most plants host diverse communities of
microorganisms including bacteria fungi
archaea and protists some are beneficial
to the plant
others
function as plant pathogens and may be
dangerous to the host or kill it
and
you know i think it's an interesting
topic to talk about the phylosphere
we've talked about
foliar
and we get into lots of conversations
around uh soil conditioning
and uh you know the soil health and the
soil food web
is a constant conversation but we don't
really talk about the phylosphere all
that much
leaf surface or the phylosphere harbors
a microbiome comprising diverse
communities of bacteria archaea and
fungi and algae and viruses um you know
i know
again we we talk a lot about the fungal
bodies and and you know the
the need to put um
good
things in your foliar sprays but you
know one of the things that i didn't
learn until recently was that you could
actually spray
predator nematodes
on as a foliar as well
and uh predator nematodes can actually
be
very productive in the phylosphere
in addition these environmental elements
affect plant physiology such as
photosynthesis respiration water uptake
etc and indirectly influence the
microbiome composition water and wind
also cause temporal variations to the
phylosphere microbiome
again getting back into talking about
insects and pests uh rain
uh
you know will knock a lot of pests off
of
a plant depending on the type of pest it
is um i know you know thrips are clumsy
they don't necessarily hang on really
well and uh blasting plants with water
is a great knock back technique you know
it's not gonna solve your problems but
it's a good way to kind of break down
some of those populations and
then coming in with uh you know some of
the predators and some of the sprays and
some of the other things that you you
could apply to help with uh
taking care of that issue
nixer
how are you doing tonight hey i'm doing
pretty well i'm doing well i just uh
kind of missed the usual introduction i
thought we were to get the welcome
welcome welcome and the whole uh
introductory spiel but we launched right
into it which i'm happy to do as well
yeah you know and you're right and i was
thinking about that part way through the
uh
as i was getting into the conversation
in the file sphere and obviously this
youtube thing is completely throwing my
game off tonight so
welcome welcome welcome to hoteb's grow
and tell and i appreciate you for
reminding me nick that i do need to
welcome people to the show uh even if we
are not being recorded in simulcast on
youtube tonight which we normally are
through the future cannabis project we
are still on the future cannabis project
channel here on clubhouse and i guess
all of you
get an exclusive grow intel tonight so i
appreciate
ron and mikel and laurie and big and
kiara and artemis and caleb and taylor
as well as drew and dr chris
and jacob and justin who just joined us
for joining us here on clubhouse because
everybody else is going to miss out
hopefully those who are normally on the
youtube feed and do
use clubhouse remember to come join us
here in the clubhouse room tonight thank
you for joining us naved appreciate you
coming caleb i see you're new to
clubhouse as well welcome to clubhouse
and make sure that if you haven't
already that you click on the little
green house at the top
join the future cannabis project make
sure you follow myself and nick as well
as the other folks here in the room it's
a great way to build your follower
list and find some of the other great
contact content that is on clubhouse
so uh drew for instance is commonly in
the wednesday k f club
so you constantly see him uh taking part
in those fantastic fermentation
conversations that we tend to have on
wednesdays appreciate you for being here
tonight and of course dr christ dr
christ who is our man in the future
coming to us from al taro in new zealand
uh always happy to talk about hemp and
farming and growing
uh so
this uh week unfortunately we do not
seem to have our normal youtube feed as
i mentioned but we are recorded here on
clubhouse so if you do miss any of the
conversation and want to replay it later
please feel free to go back and uh
replay the show and
with that
um i want to remind everybody that this
is our thursday cultivation club we are
here every thursday at 9 00 pm eastern 6
p.m pacific time
to here to talk about the plant that we
love
uh ways to grow ways to care for it
ways to grow it occasionally ways to
consume it and you utilize it
although we tend to focus mostly on the
cultivation of the plants as well as the
different aspects of
chemistry
biochem and biology that are going on
within the plant and also around the
plant so thank you all for joining us
this week i do appreciate you being here
and for joining us every week actually
for all those who've joined us before
this is episode 28.
uh i believe and actually let me bring
up my list so that i get my numbers
right since i did not uh create my
script tonight uh we are on episode 27
excuse me and uh we are talking about
the phylosphere and the rhizosphere
tonight primarily that we're going to
focus on the phylosphere because as i
mentioned in the intro i don't think it
gets quite as much attention
uh as uh the rhizosphere we spent a lot
of time talking about the rhizosphere uh
things like the rhizophagic cycle and um
you know ways to uh
to help get uh improved soil biology and
fungal balances and things like that but
we don't really talk about the
phylosphere too much and i think that
was a a great idea to have that as a
topic tonight nick hosting me with me
tonight as always is my good friend nick
uh almost always because he's actually
not gonna be with us next week is my
good friend nick from the rooted leaf
how you doing tonight nick is that
better
it is it is it's much better i'm doing
great
about it
as you mentioned uh the phylosphere it's
kind of intriguing to me uh for a number
of reasons first and foremost because
um studying the phylosphere kind of
represents the latest and greatest in
like botanical understandings like when
you know people are studying plants and
they say well how do plants grow
one of the things that's kind of a hot
topic right now is looking in great
detail
at the phylosphere and examining some of
the microbial interactions and some of
the relationships
that happened up there so i thought it
would be interesting to kind of reflect
on a couple of points about the
phylosphere
uh and then make some references back to
the rhizosphere because there's some
sort of metaphorical stuff to understand
so i feel like a lot of the
people that are here right now listening
may already kind of intuitively
understand what happens in the
phylosphere but it's still nevertheless
uh going to be good for us to create
some of this connective tissue uh and
then also um you know there's actual
hard uh connections between the
rhizosphere and the phylosphere one of
the examples would be
uh mycorrhizal fungi
that funnel water you know to plants you
know when it goes up through their roots
and enters the leaf surface
a lot of times the microbial
relationships and populations in the
phylosphere can actually be dictated and
influenced uh is perhaps another more
adequate word it can be influenced by
um what's going on underground and and
the reverse is true as well that the
microbes and fungi in the phylosphere
um can kind of
you know create substances and modify
sugars produced by plants and then uh
release that you know back through
the phloem tissue out of the roots again
and during the night time the
the rhizosphere
organisms and inhabitants will sort of
you know feed on that so it's uh it's
kind of interesting because nothing's
really known in great detail except for
the one thing we do know for sure is
that we don't know anything for sure
it's like there's a lot of information
thornton is kind of a very hot topic so
yeah yeah looking forward to it
awesome awesome awesome i did just hear
back from london and um unfortunately he
had uh he had some personal stuff and is
just not available to do the feed
tonight so maybe peter will pop in and
we can get him on but unfortunately
london is not available tonight but
everything's okay so uh he's all good
but uh just not available to help us
with the youtube tonight so um yeah
let's go ahead and uh get back into it
you know i did talk about a couple of
points around the phylosphere uh to kick
it off right so you know talking about
the fact that it does harbor its own
microbiome uh which to me is is also
you know it's obvious when we talk about
we often compare the rhizosphere
uh to the stomach uh in humans right
there is a whole set of biology and
bacteria in your gut biome that is
responsible for helping you actually
digest the food
and and allowing you to get at those
elements and nutrients and
but similarly we also have our own kind
of phylosphere in our skin surface on
our skin surface is actually our largest
organ
in the human body is the skin
and the skin is responsible for
you know all sorts of activity
both inhaling and exhaling
uh different types of chemicals and
signals and all sorts of different
things that happen in our skin surface
and there is a whole biome
and set of bacteria and things that run
around on our skin surfaces that also
help keep us healthy
and in some cases aren't necessarily
great for us as well
so it's similar and and should be of no
surprise that it's similar with plants
and plants have this whole
microbiome going on
that
is on the leaf surface not necessarily
all about what's going on under the
ground and it's not all
necessarily just about the stomata
either i think that's another thing that
we tend to focus on not so much about
all of those
different micro organisms so
you know the interactions between plants
and their associated microorganisms and
many of these microbiomes can play a
pivotal role in the host plant health as
i mentioned function and evolution
interactions between the host plant and
phylosphere bacteria have to have the
potential to drive various aspects of
the host plant physiology
however as of 2020
knowledge of these bacterial
associations in the phylosphere remain
relatively modest and there is a need to
advance fundamental knowledge of the
phylosphere biome dynamics again just
like you were saying nick not only are
we
kind of uh
just learning about what happens with
the phloem
and the movement of these things there's
also a lack of knowledge about how
this interaction works in the file
sphere
yeah yeah and to kind of piggyback off
that too it's interesting because in the
phylosphere at least
the changes that happen across the leaf
surface are a lot more dramatic and
they're a lot more intense it's a lot
more severe
in certain cases and microbes are
subject to a much higher degree of
oxidative stress particularly in
presence of the light so in a lot of
ways you know if you think about the
soil it's kind of like if you're a
microbe and you're a fungi that's kind
of the place to be because at least down
there there's resources and there's
shade and you can better resist
desiccation up on a leaf surface
and you have to deal with uh the harsh
conditions that are present on the leaf
surface which is you know dealing with
the air so it's high in oxygen it's you
know depending on the humidity you're
going to get desiccated pretty quick
there's intense and direct sunlight in
most cases so it's a lot more harsh of
an environment and to boot there's no
carbon substrate you're dealing with the
air so
very very limited resources overall very
limited water nutrients very high
probability of desiccation and oxidative
stress
so in a lot of ways the phylosphere is
like the ultimate conditioner for
microbes that can survive
pretty stressful environments and you
know if you zoom in under a microscope
you can kind of see like
these these microbes they're buttered up
right next to plant cells you know
they're kind of sharing the same space
they're occupying the same
more or less like square centimeter um
in fact i think if you took like one
square centimeter of any leaf surface
you know if it's really healthy you're
gonna have hundreds of thousands
potentially even millions of different
bacillus species and then you may you
may have tens of thousands if not
hundreds of thousands of beneficial
fungi um hopefully hopefully they're
beneficial um but the other reason the
phylosphere is kind of interesting
besides that is uh you know you look at
the overall surface area of just like
hey i wonder how much surface area is
occupied by all of the leaves on this
planet it's kind of like a you know
crazy hypothetical question but think
about it there's a very large surface
area that makes up this space we're
calling the phylosphere so the right
microbes if they get into the space they
occupy this massive surface area across
the whole planet they can kind of
eventually
start to you know
form their own specialized functions
over time
and this is something that's
i think going to start to be more and
more evidenced
that there are distinct microbes that
exist just in the phylosphere
then there's overlapping microbes that
exist kind of both in the phylosphere
and the rhizosphere
and then all you know also uh there's
microbes that exist just in the
rhizosphere and have not yet been found
in the phylosphere so it's interesting
to see this dynamic at play and like i
said part of it is just the intense
environment and the conditions that are
present
i also think the phylosphere gets a
pretty bad rap overall because most of
the studies that have been done on polar
surfaces have been from the context of
dealing with pathogenic fungi which is
kind of casting
the delicate and nuanced
nature of the phylosphere in a weird
light when you're only studying it
because there's a disease present and
there's imbalance presence so when
people kind of go in and start learning
about the phytosphere one of the most
immediate things is like oh you want to
keep that as a sterile environment you
want to kill everything on it you wanted
to be perfectly clean and you wanted to
be spotless and you know at the end of
the day
powdery mildew
yeah yeah yeah so you know like you have
an imbalance in something that's
happening and that you know may lead to
an over correction and i think that in a
really healthy
environment your phylosphere is going to
be strong just like your rhizospheres
that's going to be able to um out
compete any of the pathogens that are
trying to get in so yeah
yeah um yeah the um
yeah the the the phylosphere micro
uh microbes
uh from different plants uh from what i
was reading
um is uh you know they're somewhat
similar um in uh at the high levels of
the taxa but at lower levels
there's uh different signific there's
some significant differences between the
plants so
you know as you were saying the
environment has a big effect on it
so whatever the you know the micro
biome of the environment is
has a big impact on the types of
microbes that exist in that environment
overall and at a higher level and at a
you know macro level when you look at
you know the the groupings and stuff a
lot of it's the same even between
different plants because they're just
all over the environment
and um but when you get down to the you
know to the individual leaf surfaces
onto each of these individual plants
that's where you start to see some of
the specialization and as you were
saying in certain cases where they've
created an interaction or there's
certain cases where the plant is
producing uh compounds that tend to push
those bacterial things away
like in cannabis you know terpenes are
one of those things that are used
to help protect the plant that it
releases in
in a way to help drive things away from
it that are are bad for it so uh it's
it's interesting that uh as you were
saying that the you know the environment
does have an
effect on it and and but you do have
these different
micro interactions not just what's in
the larger
uh macro environment and um
you know the types of communities the
balance of those communities is also
different depending on the types of
regions you're in
and
so you will have a larger
you know a larger makeup of
fungal bacterial
in a jungle in tropical regions and a
lot less in a temperate region
or you're going to have less diversity
in a temperate region and more diversity
in a jungle region
because you have more diverse plant
species and animal species you probably
also by association gonna have a
more you know diverse fungal community
and bacterial community within those
leaf surfaces
yeah yeah and everything you've said
there over the past couple of minutes
actually interestingly enough applies to
tea pretty well because there is a style
of tea called pure that is aged and
fermented with
microbes and if you look in the
literature you can see uh you know
several studies have been done to
identify what is the microbiome and you
know what species of microbes and fungi
are present and everything you just said
right down to talking about you know
jungle like regions that have you know
even if there's changes in humidity
changes in altitude things like this um
the degree of oxidation of
the tea leaf obviously plays a big role
in and there's two distinct styles of
processing poor but you know without
getting too far into it the premise is
overall that
you know microbes and fungi these are
organisms that are highly active in leaf
surfaces and you know if you look
specifically at
puerto it's basically just tea that's
been harvested you know uh dried in the
sun and then processed uh you know
further dehydrated sometimes it's
pressed into a cake otherwise it's you
know kept loose but the idea is that
these microbes will continue to age on
the leaf surface for uh decades and the
longer that you let them age
the more potent the flavor of the tea
becomes and so it's like it's almost
like the plants are producing certain
metabolites that are going to get
unlocked over very long periods of time
and certainly gore is one of those
uh luxuries that you know if you can
afford something that's 30 or 40 years
old
it's going to be you know one heck of an
experience um but it's interesting you
know to to also think that for cannabis
plants there are perhaps microbes and
fungi that um you know participate in
very complex
uh interactions on the leaf surface to
maybe deter pests you know to keep
disease pressures at bay and ultimately
maybe in some more realistic or
practical environments
uh
deal with light intensity or to deal
with dehydration you know things of that
nature biotic and abiotic stress i think
is a is a big factor at least for you
know commercial cannabis producers and
um you know that being said if you're
also growing uh medicinally you know
having that uh population of microbes
and fungi
in check also i think improves the
sort of nutritional value of your plants
overall if you do things like juice you
know with the leaves and also the
therapeutic qualities of the flowers
because you get those broader spectrum
metabolites produced by the cannabis
plants you know particularly because
they had these interactions with the
microbes and fungi you know i think a
lot of times it's easier you know easy
to forget that when plants produce
secondary metabolites it's in response
to something and sometimes that response
can be
mediated by a relationship that's
present on a leaf surface or within the
roots in the rhizosphere so yeah these
things ultimately come together to kind
of create the
you know broad spectrum flavor profiles
that we all know and love cannabis to
produce
yeah and uh like even interestingly
enough those microorganisms themselves
have to even adjust their own um biology
to their metabolic you know they have to
adjust their metabolic uh rates and
stuff to be able to survive
in many cases in some of these
environments because they can be harsh
uh for for bacterial bodies um
and so they they need to uh even adjust
themselves so that they can survive be
more five uh finely tuned to survive on
that specific surface and i imagine it's
the same case with especially something
like cannabis that kicks out so many
uh different types of uh terpenes and
uh esters and and all sorts of uh
different types of chemicals
yeah and you know it's interesting that
you know um a lot of like the active
pesticide ingredients are actually uh in
some cases derivatives of
um microbes that might actually be
present on the leaf surface like there's
a bacillus subtilis qst 713 strain that
i think is called cease is the
commercialized name
um
and then there's also other products
that feature enzymes
uh you know they're derived from the
exact same species
so it's very interesting you know
because you can take that approach which
has shown efficacy you know it's it's uh
it's good to take a biological route
like that but it also kind of raises the
question of
you know well i wonder if we can do
something to set up the chemical
um
you know equilibrium in the phylosphere
such that these microbes
uh have access to resources that they
need to you know have healthy amounts of
populations and prevent these infections
from happening so that we have you know
we're not so reliant on taking reactive
approaches but rather we can take
preventative approaches through good
cultivation
sops you know having this understanding
of taking care of the soil and taking
care of the roots i think you know the
more growers focus on that the better
they become at growing healthier plants
and so it also kind of stands to reason
that if you understand
the complex dynamic of what's happening
in the leaf surface and you strive to
improve the quality of the air and
improve the quality of the environment
in that leaf surface
for your plants i think you're also
going to see
similar results as far as being able to
improve the quality
of the flower that you're growing the
extract that you're making and the
overall health of your plants
absolutely absolutely
it's uh it's really
it's interesting to think about
um
making applications to support the
protobacteria the bacteria diets the
actinobacteria
uh all the different types of species or
at least supporting the types of ones
that are going to be the most helpful
and productive
you know some of those bacillus species
are definitely known
to be helpful in both the rhizosphere as
well as the phylosphere
you know we we talk a lot about lab
lactic acid bacteria is a very very good
uh foliar as well it's it's uh fantastic
many many old school growers have been
known to
dump milk on their plants to help
fight
powdery mildew
and that's because the lactic acid
bacteria in the milk
is helping uh counteract some of the
powdery mildew and helping
create a better core
microbiome for the for the plant
yeah yeah and a lot of times for plants
the um
[Music]
the ability to resist
disease pressures like pathogens is
actually something that's mediated by
other microbes other microbes like
lactobacillus acidophilus which i think
is the
lab culture that you're talking about
those will produce compounds that will
destroy the cell walls of pathogens and
they uh interestingly enough don't do
that in all cases but when
certain species like pseudomonas for
example that genus of microbes can be
plant pathogenic and so
often times if you have the correct
species profile you've got good
diversity of bacillus species they can
actually
uh help sort of prevent that pseudomonas
from can you know infecting the plants
and producing harmful substances
that's the part that's a little bit
unknown and you know again this is a
very complex
thing to try to monitor because
you know
it's so it requires such delicate
instrumentation just to be able to
observe even for very very small periods
of time
what's going on and what exactly
is allowing certain microbes to
mediate the interaction that other
microbes have with plants and if they
don't get along well with the plant then
they basically can get their cytoplasm
blown out um you know this is kind of
more specifically how
uh some of these compounds work is they
they do things like they denature the
cell wall so they allow for the leakage
of the internal guts of you know the the
microbes to come out and then
subsequently get oxidized and all the
dna gets destroyed so it's a very
effective way
um of of killing something else um and
then on the flip side too there's
something uh along the lines of they
produce like sugars these
exopolysaccharides that
sort of uh make little biofilms very
microscopic biofilms and these biofilms
will actually prevent they're like a
little protective layer uh
that prevents other microbes from coming
in and physically attaching to the plant
cells so you can have
a disease pressure present in the
environment
but that disease pressure is going to be
unable to actually interact with the
plant and infect it and get inside
because this biofilm formed by the
protective beneficial microbe in the
phytosphere uh
you know it did its job and it prevented
the bad guys from coming in and stealing
all the resources and robbing the bank
basically
yeah uh bio film is um
is a really interesting topic in itself
hey peter how you doing tonight
oh good i had no idea we wanted to go
live tonight
yeah yeah i i apologize i was not good
at advertising this week but we are
going to try to stay consistent and show
up every thursday so
all right well i'll uh
i'll grab this after and we'll put it up
on youtube but uh carry on yeah i
appreciate that and i apologize for my
lack of pre-notification to keep
everybody in line that's my job i'm a
project manager i should know better
and um so anyway
thank you and and uh again uh you know i
hope uh everything is uh sending
positive vibe london's way i i uh
and uh he's our usual co-pilot for the
evening as well i'm sure you're in the
middle of dinner uh probably with your
in-laws or you're in the middle of
cooking something no i'm cooking uh yeah
fantastic fantastic well thank you for
being here and since we are uh past the
half hour mark we'll go ahead and
re-light the room and then we'll talk
we'll get back to that conversation
about biofilm i was just about to to
mention um so this is hot herbs grow and
tell we are here every thursday night
every thursday night whether i notify
people or not
at 9 00 pm eastern 6 p.m pacific
uh
we are uh available and usually uh
recorded in simulcast on youtube on the
future cannabis project fcpo2 channel
and as peter said later on folks will be
able to go ahead and re-listen to this
through youtube or as you know you can
also re-listen to it here in uh
clubhouse if you feel it necessary to
check back in on some of the things that
we covered already tonight
and as i said the folks in the room
tonight you get the exclusive live
version everybody else it's just a
replay for tonight
uh if you haven't already make sure you
click on the little greenhouse and join
the future cannabis project and uh hit
the you know hit the little bell so that
every time there's something going on
you'll be notified
so uh back to it so as i was about to
say biofilm is is actually a topic in
itself and it's actually something
lighten talks about so i'm not sure if
he's actually done a future cannabis
project on it already peter
but biofilm is definitely a topic i know
light likes to talk about and it's um
you know biofilm is a very natural
occurring thing i think people
think about it uh in a negative way
because it does uh it's the slimy stuff
a lot of the time right
but biofilm is actually one of the
reasons why
natural child birth is actually better
than
caesarean because of the biofilm and all
of the other things that come out as
part of the natural childbirth and so a
lot of time we think about these slimy
biofilms and things like that as a bad
thing but in many cases they're a really
good and productive thing um you know in
vinegars a lot of vinegars if you have a
good vinegar that has a mother you'll
get a um slimy rubbery
kind of
biofilm buildup on top and that's that
mother and that's actually a living
biological soup
that is
part of the fermentation process and as
part of that living body
uh that's in there so if you ever get
like a bottle of dr bragg's
apple cider vinegar or something like
that you
let that puppy sit out you're going to
get that kind of biofilm starts to form
on it and that's the mother what they
call the mother and you'll see on the
label vinegar with mother and it means
that there is some of that in there to
help kind of form that really cool
bio
or biofilm
yeah that biofilm is interesting too
because you know like i mentioned
earlier if you just consider how harsh
the phylosphere is
as an environment it does a good job of
you know conditioning the microbes that
can resist major swings and fluctuations
uh in temperature and humidity and light
intensity um
so it kind of stands to reason that part
of you know the the evolutionary
advantage of
biofilms may actually be in creating a
more stable environment for the microbes
and certainly enough if you kind of look
more specifically at some of the
properties and some of the benefits that
these biofilms have they do help offset
some of the stressors of dehydration for
example or desiccation which is very
common in the leaf surface
whereas in the roots ideally you know
the microbes that are in the roots don't
have to deal with dehydration or
desiccation stress nearly as much
and then furthermore because it's also
a nutrient deplete environment you know
the phytosphere is not the soil there's
no minerals you know there's there's no
nutrients present the microbes have to
do with very very little and so part of
the benefit of these biofilms is that
they can act as many nutrient stores
uh for microbes and so they can you know
be accessed at later times to help pull
out certain resources while at the same
time they can kind of
you know act like sponges to soak up
extra water and help store that so as
the
environment around the microbes changes
very rapidly
they've got a little bit of a buffer
that they've built up to kind of help
you know deal with that um
like jason said that the topic of
biofilms is pretty complex it's one word
but it actually
uh refers to
you know probably a variety of different
actual distinct sugars uh you know in
perhaps the architecture of the way that
those sugars are linked together is also
something to consider just like if we're
talking about humic acids or fulvic
acids
the three-dimensional shape of a humic
versus the three-dimensional shape of a
fulvic almost defines the differences
between them even though they come from
the same parent material so in a similar
way i think there's
the structure of you know some of these
biofilms is something that
you know could be examined at great
length so this is definitely an
interesting topic we won't get too far
into it but the biofilms that are formed
on the phylosphere uh are definitely
formidable because they have to you know
regulate these massive swings and all
kinds of different environmental
parameters
oh caught me away from my mute button
[Laughter]
you know and and you know i was
as i was reading through some of the
stuff on this interestingly enough
um you know just similarly there is i
know we don't think about it but there
is also a phylosphere on
marine plants
they also have a phylosphere and they
also have the same
types of epiphytic bacteria that's found
in the marine environment and
exists on that surfaces and i imagine
they could not exist on those surfaces
without a biofilm that would allow them
to attach in those extreme environments
i mean talk about being in an extreme
environment
probably more moisture as you were
saying earlier they don't necessarily
have to worry as much about drying out
although the the effect of the salt
waters on their
uh bodies might be interesting but in
the uh in the marine environment they
have a ro they're thought to have a role
in the nitrogen cycle so
um you know without
uh
epiphytic bacteria
playing a role
you might not necessarily be getting as
much nitrogen in
marine plants
they're not able to pull that you know
atmospheric nitrogen out that our
land-based plants
love to utilize
yeah yeah the sea plants are are
interesting you know they uh do it's
interesting because i think there are
some
um you know there's some differences but
there's also some similarities in the
microbial populations that you can find
on
sea plants and versus land plants too
and in a lot of cases you know the seed
plants are producing
certain types of sugars that do a really
good job at
resisting dehydration stress in case you
know during high tide they get smashed
up on a rock and it starts to turn to
low tide and you know they don't get
pulled back in the water
um a lot of sea plants basically have to
deal with being totally dehydrated after
being completely submerged
you know for hours and hours and hours
on end and rapid changes in humidity and
salinity so
part of this complex soup of metabolites
that are being produced in the cell
walls of
uh
aquatic plants um you know there is
overlap with
the the microbial species you know and
in terms of some of the enzymes that are
being produced by these species of
microbes and with the land plants too uh
it's interesting if you look at some of
the epiphytes like the some of the
bacillus species
in the phylosphere of land plants you
see that they actually produce compounds
that help recycle
cell walls and so they have like
cellulase enzymes for instance to help
break down
old dead cell material just like in the
roots we know that there are some
beneficial microbes that
will help break down old dead root
material and convert it back into
soluble sugars and
feed younger plants and help them create
new root materials so this process of
recycling
uh is kind of interesting to point out
that the same thing also exists in the
phylosphere and there's uh interestingly
enough similar if not the same microbes
that participate in the same way it's
very fascinating
yeah it's really cool
i was i just kept
digging deeper deeper down different
uh rabbit holes while i was reading
reading through some of this because
again
most of my focus and a lot of the things
that i've read about
uh tend to focus on the soil the
rhizosphere
how do we get you know how do we improve
the fungal and the bacterial bodies and
how do those interactions work and all
those things again we
don't necessarily focus too much on the
types of bacterial and fungal
life that exists on the leaf surface and
so it's definitely something that's
important
bio biofilm is also
you know important again talking about
the rhizosphere biofilm is what helps
put together those fantastic uh you know
underground uh combinations of of
bacterial bodies and biofilm and things
that help create actual soil structure
so having having those um comp those
aggregates come together
is what helps create really really good
soil structure um it's one of the things
that as those uh you know get deeper and
deeper and deeper into the soil they
help with the channeling of water and
help you know reduce
runoff and flooding if you have really
really great deep aggregation of your
soil with all of these little tiny you
know when you if you pull up a plant and
you see all the roots are hanging down
and there's those little clumps and
balls of dirt well that's all because of
the biofilm and the bio slime there's
things going on there with the bacterial
life that's happening that's a sign of
really good healthy soil
yeah again so much is dependent on this
you know communication of information
between
the leaf surface of a plant and what's
going on directly underneath it because
a lot of times um
you know they have to inform each other
otherwise there's going to be a little
bit of a an imbalance in in the growth
overall so it sort of stands to reason
that a lot of times the microbes that
are going to be present in the roots are
also present
uh in the leaf surface
and i think you know maybe a more
uh sort of common example of something
like that would be
i think a few years ago maybe 10 or 15
or 20 years ago even by now
um
you know there were some studies done on
uh how trees in a you know deciduous
trees in a forest were connected through
mycorrhizal
relationships and they basically noticed
that if they applied something to the
leaf surface or if there was some kind
of stress
induced in the leaf surface of one of
the species that the message would
somehow get transferred down
to the mycorrhizae you know past i mean
this is like in the actual ground it's
you know outside of the plant at this
point and then that signal goes to a
different plant
and the plant itself is capable of
responding in its own leaf surface by
producing some volatile organic compound
or it has a change in the expression of
secondary metabolites you know now all
of a sudden this plant is producing
something to ward off the exact same
thing that this other plant is you know
being contaminated with or being
attacked by um
so you know it's very interesting to
watch how
the this signal is preserved across
uh you know a variety of very harsh
environments
uh in a variety of different kingdoms
you know it starts off with maybe a
microbe or a fungi in the leaf surface
you know gets mediated by the plant
presumably somehow
it interfaces with the plants phloem
gets loaded up inside of it takes a
little ride down through the phloem
tissue gets pushed out of the roots and
microbes and fungi there
um you know kind of
pick that signal up and and they can
make changes with other plants that
they're connected to so it's a very very
interesting concept yeah
so and you know to complement what we've
um you know
i know complementing the you know
rhizophagic cycle there's also a similar
cycle that goes on with
sienna bacteria
being able to
basically enter the plant through the
stomata
and colonize that intercellular space
forming
uh loops and uh inter
intracellular coils
um so again
this interaction with the bacteria
actually coming into the plant itself i
know
when i first started learning about
the soil food web it was you know the
bacteria they eat the soil and the
things in the soil the out to the
elements the raw elements and convert
them over to this
uh inter you know the into this uh form
that's readily uh acceptable to the
plant that the plant is available and
can absorb it
but it's not just that right it's
actually deeper where some of these
microorganisms and bacteria are actually
coming into the plants cellular walls as
part of this process and then being
expunged back out to restart the cycle
again and similarly there's some there's
a similar interaction going on in both
the rhizosphere and the phylosphere
yeah yeah and i'm glad you you know you
brought that cycle up because it's
something that um
uh you know sort of shows how plants can
mediate and condition
the interactions that they have with
microbes around them there are certain
examples where microbes effectively have
the ability to disarm
otherwise harmful and pathogenic fungi
and the you know the exact mechanisms of
this are not quite understood but this
pathogen is basically neutered for lack
of a better phrase uh and then the cell
walls of this microbe are oxidized by
the plant so it doesn't have a cell wall
and it's basically just um
you know it's like jason said it's
within the plant and
it's participating in functions like
nutrient acquisition
uh uptake you know increasing the
efficiency of nutrient uptake uh and
then through these cycles um you know
the cell walls do eventually
come back they're reformed
and then this microbe is kicked back out
into the soil and so you have the cycle
that's occurring a lot of these
you know maybe it's something that we
could have talked about in reference to
potassium but a lot of these
uh
you know particular um nuances they
happen very rapidly and they're actually
mediated by potassium
um signal flux you know potassium fluxes
that act as like signaling um cascades
basically and so you know you see a
massive
uh spike in the mobility and the
metabolism of potassium in conjunction
with all of this turnover that we're
describing here and i think part of the
ability of plants to do all the stuff
comes back to you know the fact that
microbes and fungi
are a lot smaller than plants plants are
very complex multicellular organisms
they're very very big and
you know innately inherently plants have
the ability to accumulate a large amount
of reactive oxygen species that's just
kind of the name of the game for them
because they photosynthesize so
when the conditions are right and
everything is dialed in for the plants
they are able to basically treat this
reactive oxygen species generation
capability like a weapon against
pathogens that come in and
you know in cases where the plants need
defense mechanisms they can generate
these reactive oxygen species like they
will produce
peroxides they will produce
singlet oxygen free radicals and they'll
basically drop nuclear bombs against the
microbes because again the plants have
way more stored energy potential than
microbes do so this is one of those very
interesting evolutionary mechanisms and
tactics that they've evolved over time
to
help
achieve something that until just
recently was actually very very elusive
and people
either thought it was impossible or
you know did not quite understand um
how this process worked but you know
we're starting to learn more and more
particularly probably over the past five
to ten years about some of these
processes where plants can kind of turn
on and off the ability of certain
microbes that would otherwise be you
know pathogenic and produce toxic
substances to the plant
still uh i'm still you know again
geeking out on uh the amount of uh
different interactions
that are going on within the plant
constantly
um and uh you know the the leaf surface
the stuff above the ground
is just that area where
um
it's the area we see so you would think
that we know more about it but we don't
yeah and just understanding some of the
structures you know just like when we're
talking about the roots on the
rhizosphere it's a lot easier for us to
like draw a picture of you know a
microbe growing on a root here because
you can lift the roots out and you can
actually see that when we're talking
about something like uh bacillus
methylotrophicus
that is growing on the outside of the
stomata pores it's a lot harder for us
to just be like hey look at this you
know there's your that's your you know
where your bacillus methylotrophic this
is growing but uh you know the point is
ultimately that the plants and the leaf
surfaces they're actually very very
advanced structures biological
structures that are uh home in some
cases
you know not only to diverse species of
microbes and fungi but also in
particular cases unique and distinct
species of microbes and fungi and one of
them would be i think
some of the species of
bacillus methylotrophicas that exist in
the leaf surface there are some that
exist in
the roots and so it's not like it's only
found in leaf surfaces but um the ones
that are found in leaf surfaces are
unique because they kind of populate
this area that's just outside of the
stomata and as jason mentioned you know
the only way in besides the cuticle
unless the plant is damaged mechanically
it is through the stomata and so as the
stomata open and close
to allow for water to come out and for
you know oxygen to come out some
microbes can
kind of try to sneak in and so this area
right outside the stomata is typically
populated by
microbes like this methylotrophicas and
they have a number of cool properties
one of them in particular for the
methylotrophic is is that it metabolizes
the waste stream
of the plants so everything that's being
dumped out of the stomata is basically
like
you know the junk or the garbage or the
byproducts the metabolites the the
plants don't find useful and it's
interesting how there's certain microbes
that will take that waste stream from
the plant
burn it as fuel and then generate
something useful for the plants like
this methylotrophicus that i keep
mentioning is one of my favorite
microbes it does produce
valuable growth compounds for the plants
growth hormones
um
it can feed nitrogen back to plants and
so can help you know with nitrogen use
efficiency for example and also with
nitrogen deficiencies it can kind of
help correct that by
you know better metabolizing some
nitrogen
so there's all kinds of benefits um
associated with as i mentioned earlier
looking at the phylosphere in greater
detail in understanding you know how do
we set this up to be the best
biological environment possible just
like we currently focus on the roots and
we notice hey if we set up the roots to
do really well with a healthy bacterial
population in a healthy fungal community
then the plant itself is much more
resistant to stress and disease and so
we we should kind of take the same
approach with the leaf surface to say
let's create this equilibrium where
in the phylosphere we always have
healthy biological activity happening
it's a little bit different than the
rhizosphere obviously it's
um you know you can't just spray massive
amounts of microbes on the leaf surface
it's a little bit more nuanced and a
little bit more delicate because it's
such an extreme harsh and unforgiving
environment overall but uh yeah i do
think there's a lot of like mysteries
and magic to be unlocked there in that
in that uh little known about section
awesome awesome stuff so uh we are at
just about at the one hour mark so go
ahead and reset the room thank you all
for joining this is hota herbs grow and
tell our weekly cannabis cultivation
club we are here every thursday night at
9 00 pm eastern 6 p.m pacific
and we are here to talk about
cannabis
uh the plant that we love and ways to
care for it ways to
enjoy it occasionally
but primarily uh talking about
how plants
grow so that we have a better
understanding of what's happening with
the plant
and that will allow us to
hopefully
create better
uh
healthier
versions of the plant in our own
environments whether that is commercial
or home
cultivation and
this
group hot herbs grow and tell was
originally a was originally really a
home cultivators
cannabis cultivation club uh most of the
folks that used to come to worcester and
meet on a monthly basis were primarily
home cultivators uh just getting
together sniffing each other's jars
smoking each other's weed uh and talking
about how we were growing it what we
were growing what breeders what you know
what types of inputs environments all
these different things and um
that's where the club was born from it
was born
out of the need
to converse with others
uh
having been
uh in the closet uh hiding
uh for so long
it's important that as legalization
continues as more people have access to
legally grow the cannabis plant
that we
spread
this knowledge openly and share this
knowledge
as much as possible so that others can
also be successful
a lot of this a lot of the time cannabis
cultivation
has been this mysterious art uh not
necessarily because the plant itself
is so incredibly difficult to grow
but because the
legality of it made
it
challenging
to share
uh fully um so we want to continue that
sharing and i encourage you all to share
uh this information not only what we're
talking about tonight
but you know with others
help others answer questions
help people
learn about the plants so that they also
can be successful in growing whatever
they're growing it doesn't necessarily
have to be cannabis
a lot of the things that we talk about
every week tend to be uh very general
especially when we're talking about
elements in the way that plants use them
we we definitely talk about plants and
their different groupings and their
different families
and and some of the differences between
those but
it's important that we do continue to
help
spread education
which is why i appreciate being
recorded in simulcast on the future
cannabis project fcpo2 channel so not
only should you join that subscribe to
the future cannabis project
and the fcp02 channel both
but you should also check out all the
other shows not just my show
and nick's uh fantastic uh information
every week but there's all sorts of
really wonderful people on there and uh
you should definitely go check out all
of the shows on the future cannabis
project peter also does a fantastic job
hosting some wonderful shows i don't
think i mentioned peter as a host all
that often because i always think of him
as more of a producer but he is also a
fantastic host and has some great shows
on the future cannabis project which is
his baby so i appreciate you peter for
being here and producing the show and
all the other great content you get out
there uh and also just give you the
quick plug there is also a uh
seed site so dagger gardens dag and duck
gardens uh definitely check it out
there's all sorts of fantastic seeds out
there
if you happen to be on future cannabis
project make sure you hit the like
buttons while you're out there
okay enough shameless plugs
uh i appreciate you too
[Laughter]
absolutely and and definitely i'll be
plugging you all weekend at the regen
conference although i'm sure a lot of
the folks there at the regen conference
also
uh know you
um and and so and appreciate the content
that you're putting out there i
also next week uh i think i'm gonna have
a
mutual friend uh somebody who i actually
just met uh jesse
uh who's doing a whole bunch of hvac
stuff
i met him at nikken this past weekend
and so we talked about him coming on and
talking about
some of the differences between
humidification and dehumidification and
uh some of the reasons why you
definitely you shouldn't necessarily be
doing both um i know he said that he's
been on your show so i'm looking forward
to that conversation coming up soon
very cool
yeah
and i will
get a poster posted on monday as soon as
i get back
from maine
yeah we actually both of us deduced that
you were probably driving up to the to
maine so we're like yeah he's probably
driving up to me so that's why there's
no show right right right no no i
actually i'm heading up in the morning
um because i did have to work today
and
needed to take care of some stuff and
it's easier to
be away from the plants for
two and a half days than it is to be
away from the plants for three and a
half days
uh on the watering cycle so i i can soak
the plants down in the morning and then
jump in the car and head up and uh
fortunately because of timing i'm gonna
get there probably about the time that
uh kevin jodry touches down at the
airport so i'm going to pick up kevin at
the airport in portland
uh on our way up to dresden maine
for the regen conference so i'll be with
uh dutch bloom and steve rasner our
friend potentponics
all weekend as well as chris trump and
many of the other characters
for the northeast that uh frequent the
show
looking forward to seeing blue as well
all right so let's get back to it uh
nick what else would you like to talk
about in the context of the phylosphere
tonight
well perhaps one interesting property to
point out would be that the phylosphere
when the biofilms are produced in the
phylosphere it can also help with water
retention and also the absorption of
certain types of foliar sprays you know
it's very common practice for instance
to use saponins or surfactants or
wetting agents when you're watering in
the soil and similarly when
certain compounds are being applied
typically it's pesticides and fungicides
but
also with nutrients
people also add surfactants
you know saponins maybe dry from yucca
or kelaha
we're using licorice root it works great
but the idea is ultimately that microbes
too kind of do the same thing but
they're kind of
inside of the plant they're in between
the cells they literally exist their
cells are buttered up directly against
the cell walls
of the plants they exist within the
plant and so these biofilms that they
produce
um can actually
in a lot of ways function to increase
the solubility of water in case there's
you know rainfall
in a natural environment or if the
humidity is higher during a part of the
day the biofilms themselves can trap
some of that moisture and prevent
desiccation later on in the day let's
say the sun comes out fully and all of a
sudden everything gets really dry and
dehydrates on the leaf surface
again the biofilms are really unique in
their ability um to kind of modulate a
very very otherwise unforgiving and
harsh environment for these microbes
that have kind of specialized in some
cases over a very very long period of
time
awesome awesome stuff
yeah and i i think um you see
a lot of um
a lot of the cases where
um
it's helpful to do that
i know
you know this is one of the reasons why
spraying compost teas
and
applications of uh you know korean
natural farming
tend to be very foliar based especially
in the in the vegetative cycle
where we're trying to get
as much good
biology as well as some of the minerals
nutrients
onto the plant surfaces
when we you know a lot of the the base
vegetative cycle feeding
tends to be
a
fpga which is a fermented plant juice
and that fermented plant juice is
probably going to have some of that
surfactant quality to it especially if
you use i use a fermented aloe myself
um
you have your
uh
your
ohn
which is an anti-pathogenic
so you're getting some of those healthy
ethnic anti-pathogenic in there you know
putting some lab in there liquid acid
bacteria
but you know we also tend to use
faa which is a fish amino acid
in uh the veg feeding so getting some
you know some nitrogen
and getting some fish amino acids uh as
well
uh onto
uh the leaf surface as part of that
foliar spray and
i think the other thing to remember with
foliars
is that
depending on what you're trying to do
sometimes it is helpful to go back in
there
and
especially if you're using some heavy
surfactants
to get in there and hit them again with
just some cleansing water
uh in between to help uh mitigate some
of that
extra buildup over time
yeah yeah and foliar surfaces are
naturally very complex
anyways you know there in a lot of ways
they are set up to accept and receive
signals that are being emitted from the
soil and you do find in certain cases if
you study soils that the microbes that
are in the soils do produce volatile
organic compounds that actually get
airborne lifted up and then once the
plants have their stomata open
that signal works its way up to the
canopy very very rapidly the exact
nature and mechanics of this um
you know are still kind of unclear but
what is known is that you can induce
some pretty powerful responses with
plants this way you can actually get
hormone-like effects generated as a
result of these vocs being produced
and emitted um
and naturally plants produce ethylene
which you know is gaseous so it kind of
stands to reason that there are
uh
you know interactions happening up from
the rhizosphere uh to the phylosphere
via the air whereas in the phylosphere
most of the messages that are being sent
back to the roots are being loaded up in
that phloem
um stream so it's something that's
inside of the plant it's you know been
solubilized and it kind of gets
transported down
whereas again the opposite is true with
the rhizosphere the phylosphere you can
get stuff that is released from the soil
and works its way up so that that part's
interesting too
i was reading a uh
an article earlier today and i was
trying to find it but um you know as you
were mentioning the volatile
releasing volatile compounds um a lot of
um
what they're
starting to understand more about and
i've heard uh paul van hortmann talk
about
terpenes being released from hemp plants
in the same way
is that these volatile compounds
in many cases actually affect the
environment
and as they are released into the air
they will
in many cases reflect light and so the
benefits from
trees and forests
and things like that is not just about
the carbon sink that they are
but it's also their
ability to release these volatile
compounds and terpenes
into the air which helps actually keep
the planet cooler um so
in many cases these volatile compounds
are are helping
with some of that cooling action
um and i've definitely heard
paul van horman talk about that a bunch
of times when he talks about
how hemp can help save the planet
in that the release of the terpenes and
these volatile compounds
up into the air are
very very important for helping with the
overall
health of the environment and keeping
temperatures cooler and helping with the
build up and creation of clouds and
moisture
yeah yeah that's something we had talked
about a few episodes back maybe in one
of the earlier episodes about how
terpenes are basically the ideas
terpenes are these you know classes of
compounds that mediate relationships
across entire kingdoms and in certain
cases like if you're walking through the
forest as the sun is rising
well the trees are aware of this and
they're going to start producing alpha
pinene and so this distinct odor of pine
you can actually see if you're standing
at the right angle when the sun is
coming up
uh
directly over the forest it's a little
bit more blue and this kind of like blue
haze is actually the
volatile turbines being emitted because
as jason mentioned
as the rays of the light you know as the
rays of the sunlight come in
part of that energy
is absorbed by the terpenes that are
being emitted by the
pine trees it's it's actually a literal
sunscreen that's being ejected out into
the atmosphere and so it does have this
effect of absorbing some of that excess
energy and creating a cooler
environment overall one that
you know soaks up some of that radiative
stress
that's outside of the frequency ranges
that the plants might want to keep
active for like chlorophyll for instance
you know maybe they need to get other
frequencies
out of the way first and then
chlorophyll is going to be more or less
you know it's going to have this paved
road to allow all the light energy to
come in and to hit on chlorophyll
without causing too much stress and too
much damage so yeah it's very
interesting
very very cool stuff and
um
most of those
items are are coming from the
phylosphere not from the rise of fear so
um the phylosphere again
uh having a tremendous impact on uh the
health of the plant but also the health
of our planet
so really interesting um
that uh
these uh how how important the
phylosphere is
uh and those interactions are for the
for all of these uh different uh
aspects uh again not something we
normally talk about or i personally
focus on all that much
i tend to again talk about what's going
on in the soil and how we prevent
flooding
and how we improve soil health and cut
down on our use and needs for uh for uh
for chemicals and things like that so
it's uh it's super interesting um
let's go ahead and move on
um and i did uh
for damore i will get you quickly a link
for the regen conference into the chat
shortly um but i i wanted to get um i
was looking to see if i could find that
uh
that article that um and i did so i'm
going to go ahead and get that pinned up
into
into the chat here
so it's cool
it's good stuff and it's cool because
the global temperatures would actually
be warmer if it wasn't for them
it's fitting that i was reading that
today when we were going to talk about
the phylosphere so
very very good
so rhizosphere obviously we've mentioned
it a couple times tonight and
you know we can't talk about the
phylosphere without also mentioning the
rhizosphere uh which is where we do
spend a lot of time chatting um i know i
do and
the rhizosphere is what's happening on
the soil and down
and primarily when we talk about the
rhizosphere what we're talking about is
the area that's between 1 and 10
millimeters
away from the root surface
so the rhizosphere isn't everything
underground
the rhizosphere is this zone
of interaction and activity
that's happening directly around the
roots themselves
the rhizosphere is
where the soil food web interactions
tend to happen the most
um although
al as we mentioned earlier during the
conversation there is plenty of
insects
uh as well as bacteria and fungi that do
travel uh between
those different zones you will find
similar bacteria and fungal life in
both the phylosphere and the rhizosphere
um different
bacterial and fungal life uh exists in
the back obviously in the rhizosphere
that cannot exist in the phylosphere
as nick mentioned earlier because it is
a darker moister place with a lot more
biofilm
than exists above
we talked a little bit about the
rhizophagic cycle
when we were talking about
the different types of interactions
between
bacteria becoming part of the plant
and that also is a really really
interesting
interaction to me that that was one of
the things i think that kind of captured
my fascination more
with learning about how
plants were actually
taking up nutrients right it's not just
about
them sucking up things in the water that
they pull into themselves so
really really um
it's
very
interesting that those interactions are
just starting to be discovered
but all those crazy interactions that
are happening in the soil
are
the primary place that the plant does
get most of its
nutrients and food
other than
the largest macronutrients
of uh oxygen and hydrogen which it's uh
getting in the form of carbon dioxide
as well as water um when it absorbs uh
moisture and vapor
where's the carbon at man you forgot the
carbon i forgot the carbon man the
carbon is part of that in the co2
uh is part of that interaction and the
water uh and the carbon is is is you're
getting the carbon out when you break
down
that hydrogen and oxygen did i get that
correct at least
well
yeah the the gist the premise yes yes
it's all about carbon you know
it's always about carbon it's always
carbon's the yeah carbons the uh the
number one
most important and in fact even water
metabolism revolves around to the
acquisition of carbon plants have
invented this process basically to
suck carbon out of the air and then over
the course of 100 million years they do
this thing called create soil and then
they give rise to
hundreds of thousands of different
potentially millions of different
species of microbes and fungi that are
found nowhere else except for within
soils so it's very very interesting to
see this process of carbon being
recycled over and over and over again
and it kind of makes sense that when
plants produce sugars and carbohydrates
throughout the day that they want to
funnel those down into the roots and
kind of like
store that carbon you know because if it
gets released back into the atmosphere
all of their hard work was basically
lost kind of a bummer if you're working
all day and and all that goes to waste
so
these microbes and fungi do a really
good job at participating in cycles
some cycles take longer than others some
are very very long like you know
decomposition cycles that create humic
substances in the soil those
cycles those processes take very very
long periods of time you know
potentially tens if not hundreds of
uh millions of years to you know get to
the spot where they're finally
at their terminal sort of metabolite
point um so there's you know this vested
interest that all of these
microorganisms and also plants
collectively have
to take carbon out of the air and bury
it in the ground uh as much as they
possibly can
um and all of them kind of help each
other out with this process overall if
the plants need some kind of mineral
nutrient
then the microbes and fungi are highly
specialized to be able to go and do that
for the plant
and uh on the flip side there is a
little bit of a cookie or a snack or a
cake as jason likes to say
in exchange
for cookies and cakes cookies and cakes
those sugars and starches the exodites
the cookies and cakes is dr elaine
um i i definitely gotta i gotta uh give
her credit for that but it is it's it's
cookies and cakes you're attracting the
plant is releasing the exodites the
sugars and starches that it uh
knows are going to bring in the bacteria
and fungi that are going to be important
to helping it
get at those nutrients and and elemental
minerals that it needs to survive
um which is also really fascinating i i
wonder
um if there is a
as we mentioned before you know the the
there's definitely some
compounds that the plant releases to
fight off
um you know predators or pests and
things like that i wonder if there's
those similar
cookies and cakes being released in the
phylosphere to attract the appropriate
uh bacteria and fungi that we're not
we're just not aware of
yeah yeah there's probably a very very
complex relationship too and then in
some cases there's
probably a concentration gradient like
the methylotrophicus
bacteria that are they they like to hang
out around the stomata because they take
the waste stream that comes out of the
stomata pores
and they treat that like a food source
and they pass stuff back to plants and
so i imagine there's
that that beneficial street is two-way
because the stomata themselves represent
one of the major entrance points for
pathogens to be able to get into the
plants and so
um you know whoever the guards are are
probably being paid pretty well to make
sure that the environment is kept clean
and all the bad guys get to
you know stay out
probably being fed carbon
that's right
um
so um as i mentioned as we as we talked
about earlier i think you know similarly
uh
biofilm is uh super important in the
rhizosphere as well uh it
you know as i mentioned when you pull
the plant up and and you see those roots
underneath and you see those little
clumps of soil and things sticking to
the roots
that is the biofilm and that is those
little interactive environments as i
mentioned that rhizosphere uh it's
almost like a mobile rhizosphere at that
point because you kind of took it with
you but
that um those clumps those aggregates in
the soil
is all part of um they they stick around
um after the
after they're no longer part of that
rhizosphere
um hopefully
the roots um you know have gone down
deep and the deeper those roots go
as they go on their
path down into the soil
they create more and more of these
aggregates they make these little
pockets
of
biofilm and bacteria
and root
and all of those other things as they
make their way down and that allows the
channeling of
water
nutrients and
bacteria
and fungi which are brought along with
the water deeper and deeper into
the soil as that process happens
they continue to start breaking down
the elements minerals nutrients and
things that are locked in those lower
layers of soil that plants may not
necessarily have had access to
so in many cases
some of the limitations that
plants will run into
is because they will there will be some
limitations to their ability to continue
to go down further
directly down into the soil into
expanding those
channels for water and nutrients and
expanding their
rhizosphere as they do that um and so
those
um in
in
malawi for instance there's a
technique called deep bed farming that's
being used and taught by
an organization uh called the tiene org
and um they've trained it's uh it's over
ten thousand farmers
in this um technique of regenerative
natural farming
where they
they have
suffered because of the environment and
because of the
western
farming practices that were
forced upon them in many cases
they basically have developed this super
hard pan
this surface of soil
that is extremely compacted about a foot
and a half down into the soil
and sometimes down as deep as
15 feet into the soil and so
they are able to
you know break up the top layer of soil
and get crops in but what happens is
that the crops aren't able to put their
roots down into the land
deep enough for them to be able to
create channels for water
as well as to be able to get at the
nutrients and minerals and things that
are actually lowered down in the soil
not in this depleted area that's above
the hard pan
and so they are
they basically have to get in there
uh and break up that hard pan
which will allow their future plantings
to be able to grow into that soil and by
doing that
they've
been able to farm without the need for
nutrients
or any industrial fertilizers
and it has allowed them to
completely
grow
amazing
forests of food
in some of these
really really tough areas where
they get
you know like three inches of rain in a
couple of hours
and then they'll go for periods of time
with almost no water and so uh
traditionally
because the
the hard pan underneath and because the
way they laid their rows
there was lots of flooding which would
destroy their fields and their crops or
cause
famine in many cases um
so that rises fear and being able to
create
a
ability for the roots to continue to
travel down
deeply into the soil to develop a bigger
and bigger
rhizosphere a bigger biome
create more of those aggregates and then
eventually leave all of that carbon
uh behind as well as those natural
aggregates and channels for water which
helps more moisture and water go down
into the soil as opposed to
runoff
running off your property and not uh
actually allowing your
your soil
to get properly saturated
yeah yeah and that's part of the dance
between microbes and uh fungi and
plants is that when the plants produce
certain compounds and release them from
the roots it's kind of it you know in
the best interest of the microbes and
fungi to find a way to pass that carbon
as an energy source around back and
forth and in other cases
uh
to create humic substances which
contribute to things like the fertility
of soils and
you know the longevity of
um
populations you know it doesn't matter
if it's plants or microbes or fungi any
time that you're building organic matter
into the soil you're going to increase
the likelihood of those populations
surviving
whatever kind of changes are going to be
present in that environment so
in a lot of ways as this bulk draw of
carbon is going from the air into the
soil the microbiome in the fungi are
acting on these
carbon substrates to help create in an
environment
that you know starts to take up a larger
larger surface area and oftentimes
initially this environment that i'm
talking about is actually just outside
the rhizosphere because if you think
about it when the roots themselves are
growing
the roots are um ultimately just sensing
their environment around them and
they're signals that are being fed back
to the roots as they're growing in real
time because if there's a signal that
comes back and says you know dead end
coming up here
uh there's a rock immediately ahead
there's no way the roots gonna grow
through that
you know
there's there's this feedback mechanism
and part of it is these microbes are
involved
in sending these signals back and so as
the roots are growing and the root hairs
there's like this little cap that's on
the outside and it keeps pushing through
the soil this cap on the outside of this
cap is a whole bunch of active microbes
and active fungi that are conditioning
the soil just ahead of where the roots
growing because they're trying their
best to make it
ascertainable for the roots they want
that the perfect environments that the
plant can grow there and it can uptake
the minerals and the water and so on and
so forth because if the plant is
able to do all of those things then it
can photosynthesize better which means
that it can produce more sugars and
feed the microbes and the fungi and
continue this whole process this very
dynamic process of
you know it's like in in a short time
span you have microbes and fungi
actively conditioning
soils to help roots grow in the process
of them actually growing and in some
cases when we're talking about
you know several inches to several feet
at a clip you know that's a lot of
movement that these microbes and fungi
make
but also it's true to say that
humic substances which take millions of
years to properly form are also being
sort of conditioned and brought into
existence by microbes and fungi the same
ones that also on shorter time
spans and scales of time will um you
know help microbes and
or i'm sorry we'll help plants grow
and access the minerals that they need
so this is a very very dynamic dance
that's happening back and forth
excuse me
um
yeah it's um
very very uh
deep
not to
use a pun um so
anyway uh it is 10 30.
uh we are
coming uh up on uh the final half hour
of the show this is hot herbs grow and
tell
we are here in our weekly cannabis
cultivation club coming to you every
thursday night at 9 00 pm
uh 9 p.m eastern 6 p.m pacific don't
want to get those backwards because then
i'll be up in midnight trying to do the
show
and uh it's hard enough as it is
uh some of these some days to do the
show at uh from 9 to 11.
but we are here every week on clubhouse
so if you enjoyed what you heard tonight
and you're not already a member please
click on the little green house and join
the future cannabis club project club as
well as give a follow to nick myself
peter as and anybody in the studio
audience tonight uh because they are
also
obviously some plant geeks if they could
see here and listen to us talk about the
rhizosphere in the phylosphere for
almost two hours
so i appreciate every one of you for
fellow plant geeks for joining us
as you most of you do every week
we are
recorded and simulcast on the future
cannabis project on youtube uh this week
it will be as i mentioned a recording
they're not going to get the live feed
we don't have the live interaction
distracting me on youtube this week as
well which is kind of nice
that i'm actually able to just focus
directly on the conversation with nick
and the topic
and not necessarily worrying about
moderating some of the uh chaos that
tends to go on on the youtube feed
uh in the background you never know
where that conversation is gonna go
uh off-screen off to the side uh away
from our main topic of the night
um so the you know i think we've uh
covered a lot of different aspects about
both of those different zones uh and the
importance of
thinking about the
bacterial
fungal
needs of those different zones
the different interactions that
are just
being uncovered in many cases in many in
many ways
you know again with the rhizosphere i
think you know tilling is another
uh thing that most
unfortunately most commercial growers
are not aware of how damaging
tilling is
to the rhizosphere
being able to support those healthy
biomes is super important and you know i
think tilling
when
people started tilling
um and in many in some cases if you're
doing low tilling um or really just
doing tilling to kind of break up the
soil
with a
more
modest or manual um you know more of a
manual plow
or a thing like that then it's probably
not as bad
you know it's it's just part of the
process of of in some cases
uh creating a proper environment for
your plants to be successful to get them
going
but when we use these mechanized tilling
methods that have these
mechanical metallic spinning discs
that cut deeply deeply into the soil and
spin and destroy everything they come
across what happens is it destroys that
biology it destroys that
rhizosphere that biome
kills the fungal bodies it kills the
arthropods and all of the fantastic
things that are living in that soil
along with a lot of that biology it
destroys those aggregates and breaks up
all of that fantastic biofilm that's
been created
and is really really a has a
tremendously negative impact
on um
on the soil
fertility
and the rhizosphere probably one of the
most damaging things that we actually do
as part of our normal
farming practices
again i think the initial idea around it
probably wasn't as bad
again just breaking up some of the soil
so that you can get planting in there
but
really tilling is just such a
destructive thing because it does
destroy
that rhizosphere as well as really just
expose
tremendous amounts of carbon to oxygen
which creates co2 and then you're just
sucking all of that wonderful beautiful
carbon
out of the soil
and letting it just go up into the air
yeah and interestingly enough it's
actually uh
being understood more and more nowadays
that the practice of heavy tilling which
most people would just you know consider
to be regular telling but this like
really really
heavy treatment of the soil does
actually release
stored carbon
back into the air and it does actually
create this transfer back i mean plants
spend a very very long time
and they put a lot of energy into
sucking carbon out of
the air so it's a little bit ironic how
between cycles of plants we decide to
come back through and say okay we're
gonna
reset all the work that was done um
and
you know in some cases like the
relationships
between plant fungi and microbes these
things are still being
uh studied you know to understand them
as they occur in these small segments of
these slices that were capable of
measuring like in a controlled
experiment for example this doesn't
really speak to
what happens when you don't touch
you know land for maybe 10 20 30 years
and that kind of research is of course
being done but it's very very
um you know few and far between you're
not likely to find something
as extensive and deep and historical as
that and when you do
uh you should you know definitely hold
on to it because it's
an example of something that
you know was in the making for 30 plus
years let's say um and and you really
get a chance to look at what
uh what happens when you don't disturb
something but you just nourish and allow
it to kind of grow and develop its own
complexity in its own maturity i mean
get to a spot where you get this broad
expression of microbes and a broad
expression of fungi and
uh you know in a lot of cases you know
the the uh
the depth and complexity of these
microbial populations is something that
should not be
underrated as far as the ability of some
of these microbes to produce beneficial
substances for humans too um you know
there's a very very
uh sort of famous and popular
compound um produced by fungi is a
specific species of fungus that was
found in only a single soil sample in
the world and has not been found ever
since and it has been you know a very
very helpful medicine it's been
something that has allowed for the
global eradication of certain parasitic
diseases in third world countries and
there's been over 40 billion doses of
this particular compound
administered globally so far so
uh
yeah it's very interesting you know we
got to do a good job of taking care of
the soil and the phylosphere and paying
attention to some of the very very
diverse species of microbes and fungi
that can grow and and really just
screening them and monitoring them for
metabolites that they might be able to
produce that are functional medicines
for humans or you know
biostimulants in agriculture for that
matter
michael welcome to the stage thank you
for joining us
i see you are a rej a sustainable
cannabis food and alpaca farmer how you
doing tonight
i'm doing good i'm trying to be
sustainable i should put up there uh
trying to close aren't we all right yeah
trying to close as many loops as i can
but so i'm a cannabis farmer as well and
i'm in uh
raised
beds living soil and just
going back to
what you were i believe you were saying
about the
damage of tilling you know i don't go
with a tiller but
are are you suggesting that if you could
just leave it all alone except for
digging the hole where you're going to
plant the plant that that is what would
be the best thing you could do
absolutely
those roots and existing structures
are
fantastic sources of
nutrients uh and minerals that have been
you know
sucked up into the plant and
though all those as i was mentioning
earlier all those fantastic uh channels
and aggregates have been created so
in many cases
uh using uh cover crop
as well to help protect the soil
structure in the wintertime and and the
off months in between your crops is also
super beneficial to to
and then basically just going in and
chopping and dropping that stuff and
if you happen to you know running your
alpaca over those fields after you've
done like a chop and drop on those cover
crops or just letting them go through
there and eat that
they're going to create you know they're
going to crush down some of that plant
material and and get and help enrich
your soil further
so yeah no absolutely i would highly
recommend just trapping the
chopping the stocks and leaving the
plants in and then just staggering your
your planting pattern uh in a way where
you plant in between
i have a friend i can't remember which
he
awesome stuff online they have these
huge
beds
and um instead of you know actually even
planting digging the holes he actually
has uh pots that have no bottom on them
so it is a fabric pot that doesn't have
a bottom and they basically just puts
them into a
open spot on the top of the bed and the
roots grow down into the bed
at the end when he harvests he actually
leaves that pot in place
chops the plant
and then moves over to the space next to
it and puts the next plant in
and does that rotation and then
when that second plant comes down that
first root ball plant is taken away
because a lot of that underlying root
base has then at that point been uh has
decayed and broken down and you know if
you're in a good living soil bed then
the worms and everything else are taking
care of all that stuff as well so
highly recommend you taking that
approach
yeah that's interesting we we're doing
that cloth pot tech for the first time
this year
we where we cut the bottoms off and
we dug them in a little bit but
you know we still have some to plant so
maybe we'll just try leaving them right
on on the top that's an interesting
thought
yeah and then just pop the next one
right next to it right like just go in
between
um
you know uh leave you know you'll
usually have space in between them and
and just plant between um and then that
plant will be able to take advantage of
a lot of that stuff that's left over
from that previous plant
yeah and it's a good idea to do like if
you're if you've got some compost teas
and you're brewing up some microbes in
that compost tea it's a good idea to
post harvest try to
uh introduce like a a strong maybe a
concentrated dose of that compost tea
that's very rich in microbes to the
plant that was harvested because those
microbes are typically going to produce
enzymes that will help hydrolyze the
cell walls
so as the cell walls get hydrolyzed and
broken down
they kind of get repurposed as building
blocks into sugars that
are solubilized and they they can you
know be used for a number of different
things including to feed the next
generation of
plants or even better to just keep the
carbon stored in the soil in a soluble
form and then just enhance the quality
of life for all the beneficial microbes
that uh that are in there
that's great my you know one question
i'd like to
ask
you know currently one of the things i'm
dealing with because i've
built all my soil you know from the
ground up and didn't buy bagged soil and
i
used
organic dairy manure from the local
dairies and stuff i now have this
quite large population of uh roly-polies
that
are
last year for the first time they were
actually up in my colas and i had to
pull my crop two weeks early you know
because they started
having parties up there and taking shits
and like causing issues so i'm just
trying to figure out
the best way to deal with these
once ocean dwelling creatures that
seem impossible to beat
yeah that's um those are uh those are
pests that actually have not had to deal
with yet
i've i've dealt with a lot of pests and
doors unfortunately
and um though that is not one of them i
know that i know that there is a jadam
approach
somewhere in the jadam approach to cover
that specific type of insect um so if
you're looking at some of the the j a d
a m organic farming
uh
recipes there is a bio control one for
roly polies in there
i'm not really sure what the natural
predator would be that you would launch
for something like that
but it you know that's a type of
uh insect that you need to
probably deal with multiple parts of the
life cycle and i also would be curious
if the
addition of
predator nematodes would help
with some of the earlier stages of life
um
you know getting them down you know when
they're they're kind of hatching as eggs
in the soil
um or what i'm not quite sure what their
life cycle is like how they're born or
hatched
so
understanding the life cycle of the
insect
is usually a
important way to to deal with it so that
you can deal with not only
um you know the adults but also the
larva
and some of the midlife stages different
predators
have different uh will live in different
zones during their life cycle so
something like thrips
western flower thrips
actually live in both the phylosphere
and the rhizosphere
during their life cycle
usually we see the adults munching on
our leaves
causing problems there
being vectors for disease and other
problems as you said leaving waste
but the thrips themselves the they lay
the eggs on the on the leaf on the
undersides of the leaves and then the
eggs when they hatch they fall down into
the soil
and so to truly deal with um
thrips
you need to deal with them in both the
phylosphere and the rhizosphere
and so you need to treat them with a
combination of different types of
predators to deal with those different
sets
stratiolap is also something that comes
to mind michael because uh those are
also a ground
uh a surface dweller stradiolae lap rove
beetles delosha
um
but um yeah i think possibly some of
those predator nematodes as well
predator nematodes i mentioned earlier
can also be sprayed
so predator nematodes can
attack some of those
pests while they're in the phylosphere
not just um i know most people
you think of predator nematodes they
think about putting them into the
rhizosphere but they can be applied in
the phylosphere
so in addition to the dom i would check
with one of the
beneficial insectary sites
one of the insectary sites like
beneficial insectary is one
arbico
and see if they have some
[Music]
recommendations you could also look for
i don't know if he's covered at peter uh
but uh matthew gates has a show he's uh
zenthanol uh so he's on
uh instagram under uh
sink angel
but he's also on the future cannabis
project with a ipm specific show
which you might be able to check out and
talk to matthew gates
to see if he can also help you with your
problem
appreciate it thanks for all the info
you're welcome you're welcome
anybody else down in the audience has
questions comments wants to come up and
talk about anything we covered tonight
on the rhizosphere of the phylosphere uh
or just some general stuff feel free to
go ahead and raise your hand and come up
uh was there anything specific to the
rhizosphere that you wanted to get into
tonight nick
no i mean i think we covered most of the
things that we wanted to cover it seems
like the filo sphere is the one that
is a little bit unique for people you
know hopefully you heard about it it
inspired you to think a little bit about
um what's going on up there and then you
know maybe how it's connected
to the rhizosphere physically or also
metaphorically you know there's a saying
as above so below and this is one of
those
perfect instances where it's applicable
to say that there's a lot of stuff
happening in the roots that is also
happening in the leaf surfaces and in a
similar way i think the uh
you know the the trick will be to try to
figure out how do you take good care of
the air quality for your phylosphere
just like the question has been how do
you take good care of your soil for the
rhizosphere
so yeah i think we got into all the
things that we wanted to cover
awesome and
brian thank you for joining us how are
you doing tonight sir
uh did you have a question or comment i
see you're a no-till living soil
backyard greenhouse cannabis grower
in minnesota
right no
sorry
orange exposed me
it cut off the letters cut off and for
some reason my brain went mn but thank
you in oregon uh how are you doing
tonight brian welcome doing fine uh i
had a comment on uh
the rolly pollies because i had i've had
to deal with them in the past
uh i have a similar situation with the
fabric pots mine are 65 gallon pots but
i did not cut the bottoms out of them
uh i've had them for years
probably like five years in my
greenhouse which has a bed of gravel
underneath of it but like i said they're
not cut out anyway the roly-polies
the life cycle seems to be independent
of my pots because i've had i've seen
them they come in and they come out of
the greenhouse they just
you know
they're everywhere
but i've never had a problem except for
one year and that was the first year and
i had no cover crop
i didn't know about cover crop and i
have a similar soil like what this guy
was talking about where i mixed it
together myself out of all the
ingredients
and
so that year i had problems where they
were actually nibbling on the stalks of
my plants and
that's the only time i've ever seen them
on my plants at all because since then
i had this like
11 seed mix cover crop mix specifically
for cannabis
and since then i've only seen them in
the cover crop
awesome
really didn't have a problem since then
yeah i know um
like mites love clover
yeah there's three different kinds of
clover in this mix yeah
yeah fantastic fantastic
um i i'm a big fan of uh of like vetch
uh some of the grasses
but yeah there's definitely some nice
mixes out there
there's also almost every seed company
uh natural farming seed company like
baker creek or any other ones they all
also sell
cover crop mixes
that have peas and vetch and grasses and
clovers and all sorts of good things is
is that uh um that mixer using something
that you come up you came up with or
something that you
yeah i i ordered it i found it online i
think i just searched on amazon it's
like an 11 seed mix it has yeah i think
it's four types of clover but it does
have hairy vetch and another kind of
it has uh beans some other things
uh but what here's the thing is it seems
like
it's the it's the canary and the coal
mine for me because the only time
you know i had problem with mites before
they came up in my cover crop and they
never once got to my plant that was when
i had things under control
not last year but the year before that
and
they didn't yeah last year everything
went south because my blue mat system
somehow my reservoir went dry things
just went off the rails and so i had
russet mites and spider mites so i think
last year doesn't really count
yeah prior to that everything was in
pretty good equilibrium in my greenhouse
yeah the um i love the blue mats but um
it is hard especially if you let them go
dry to get them back to where they need
to be you have to re-get the soil back
to that level and then you gotta re-dial
in each one of those individual carrots
and
it can be a little bit of a challenge uh
sometimes working with those blue mats
although i do i do appreciate them and i
think that is
probably one of the best ways to keep
the rhizosphere happy is that
you know that that ability to only
give the right amount of water
to keep the right amount of water in the
zone in each of those zones all the time
yeah i highly recommend the blue mat
system especially the blue soak i have
both the drippers and the the blue soak
tape
and it works like a charm like i said
it's worked for me great for years but
last year it was my own fault you know i
let the reservoir run dry because i shut
the water off for some crazy reason
and other than that you know it's been
great for me
yeah that maybe that's why the the uh
roly-poly stay down there i noticed they
like to hang around the the blue soak
tank
so
yeah the environment they appreciate the
most
awesome stuff i appreciate you joining
us brian thank you so much for coming up
yeah
and and
i hope you have a much better year this
year
definitely
that time of year to get to get things
going absolutely and and you know with a
65 gallon pot uh you're not that's not
the type of thing you're cutting the
bottom out of or moving for that matter
so yeah no
no
i can't move them at all not like a
forklift or something no yeah definitely
not that is a huge pot
um
especially when it's wet
awesome stuff awesome stuff all right we
uh do we have any other questions or
comments anybody else want to come up
and join us and add anything else before
we wrap up tonight
no it does not look like it and again i
keep looking at my uh it's funny i keep
looking at my ipad expecting some
questions to be coming up on the youtube
feed like i'm trained at this point uh
it's you know this was episode 27
tonight
uh we are here at hota herbs grow and
tell like we are
every thursday night at 9 00 p.m eastern
6 p.m pacific uh next week we will be
i believe talking transpiration
uh with jesse porter uh from inspire
transparation uh solutions he also uh
was did a whole bunch of stuff with um
uh the uh oaksterdam university a while
ago he's been around the industry for
ages and ages and as i mentioned he's
been on the future cannabis project on
peter's show as well
so i think we'll be talking with jesse
next week
nick unfortunately i don't think nick
you said you're not going to be with us
next week so
maybe you'll be able to sneak in for a
little while and if you are we
appreciate that but if not you will be
sorely sorely missed
yep i'm going to be in oklahoma
unfortunately
um
so i won't be able to make it but i am
gonna try to pop in if i can for a
little bit and just listen because it's
a topic that intrigues me so i'd like to
come in here
well you know you can
if you want
always catch the replay
uh each of these rooms is recorded and
simulcast
on the future cannabis project on
youtube so you know you're never too far
from being able to catch the rebroadcast
of the show if you happen to miss it
uh something to uh maybe fall asleep to
uh after spending the whole day at uh in
good old oklahoma uh maybe just
something to help you wind down
good conversation around transpiration
to help you wrap up your day
um so uh any final closing words tonight
nick
no i'm glad everyone joined us you know
this was not an announced um
event and we just seem to have uh
curated the finest selection of
listeners to come in and listen to us
talk about the phylosphere and the
rhizosphere so yeah thank you guys all
for coming out to listen to us
absolutely absolutely we had 55 folks
jump in tonight and that's greatly
appreciated i
i'm very happy and thankful that
everybody joined us
i was a slacker and did not properly
promote the show this week so
i do appreciate everybody who did jump
on and spend the couple of hours with us
tonight
thank you peter for popping in while
cooking dinner and for uh posting this
show
after the fact uh and and we'll make
sure to have
better future coordination uh for the
next upcoming shows i'm going to try
uh my darndest to uh
do this show every week uh regardless of
uh what's going on um so we will try to
continue to to uh to be here for you
every week at that same time i think
it's consistency is important uh so i
i'm going to make every effort to be
here every thursday night for folks to
continue this uh fantastic grow and tell
tradition uh for anybody who may be uh
in maine this weekend uh you know i'm
gonna be at the regen conference up in
dresden maine uh which is a
about an hour northeast of portland so
we'll be way the hell up there in maine
um chilling out with all of our
no new england regen family
uh enjoying uh conversations around all
things regenerative cannabis cultivation
so gonna be good stuff uh doctor you're
too late man i'm just about to shut down
but i do appreciate you
and thank you all for joining everybody
have a fantastic
fantastic weekend and we will see you
here next week for
hope to herbs grow and tell and a
fantastic conversation with jesse
porter on transpiration thank you
everybody have a fantastic night