how's it going future cannabis project
Community Lobster fam Farms here today
I'm going to be going over my low-tech
home grow strategy on collecting male
pollen from the canvas plant
so this would be my first time
intentionally pollinating female
cannabis plants
there's a lot of things in life
necessity is the mother of invention
so something I'm looking for that
doesn't quite exist yet or that no one
else is trying to create so it seemed
like a worthwhile goal
what I'm looking for is something that's
very flavorful very energetic
and it's going to be a type 2 variety
that's going to be very rich in minor
cannabinoids
and to anyone making a living off of
seeds out there it's not my intention to
sell them
this is just to learn more about the
plant
initially it's just going to be
something for me in the squad if it
turns out to be something nice and fun
and eventually hopefully it'll make its
uh patience if it's deemed Worthy
let's go let's see what's doing
so these are some of the strategies I
set up and I feel like most people could
replicate this in any home environment
that also has a flowering room close by
that could be vulnerable even if you had
to use a sheet or just something simple
so I have this closet door opened
I have the humidifiers cranking create
this little
micro climate
we got it at 75 humidity so my intention
and hope is that anything that creeps
out of here
is going to be made non-viable if it
does when it creeps out not if it does
and so my next step is going to be to
use the pump sprayer and I'm going to
spray all around the door forgive me
house but I'm just going to drench
everything
and uh I'm gonna have to tune out for
this I'm going to try to Stage all the
stuff I have to bring in and then we'll
rock and roll
let's rock and roll time to creep in
here and creep out all stealth style
bing bang bada boom let's go
all right we're in
let's see what's going on in here
so the temperature and the humidity
temperature is a little bit warm for a
normal Garden but I'm more stoked on the
low humidity so I think the pollen that
I collected yesterday
is going to be good to swoop up and
store
possible
this is what I scored yesterday not a
whole lot
but from what I've heard
a little goes a long way
now yesterday I collected this on
parchment paper
in the same room
that the males are in
now I think I can improve this after my
first time what I did was I set the
dehumidifier in this room
and after I collected the pollen I tried
to spray everything down and that jacked
humidity way up I think I could be more
effective by just tossing the dehue into
the closet
keeping out here very humid not very
humid keeping out here as dry as it is
now collecting my pollen
in the closet
closing the closet behind me with the
dehumidifier inside there and then using
my pump sprayer just spray everything in
here Down Jack the humidity way up spray
myself down
let's see how it goes
so I've got my business card
my storage container
lightly sweep it up
I got a little bit of soil mixed in
there on the first batch
I don't think it could be that bad
as soil typically found out and about
but not too often in the air
on the female pistols
but I'm hoping that that little bit of
soil in there
doesn't make too much of a difference
time to pack it up
let's take some pollen in the vial
not too much but I think it's more than
enough I'm gonna gather some more today
let's do that
so now I've got a new setup
in the closet
I'm going to bring the plants in here
and shake them
now we can shake some pollen off
what's interesting about these plants
was that I never flip them
to 12 12. they started showing full male
maturity
under 18 hours and I asked uh big
respect to sapo I asked him if like what
the variables could be for that and he
said it was sometimes when inbred lines
were veg too long in small containers
so appreciate the knowledge it seems
like both those variables were present I
was ensured that the pollen would still
be viable which is why I'm collecting it
and even if it's not
good practice I got some protocols in
order and if it is sterile there's no
risk to the rest of the garden so
just doing it
[Music]
moose
this one smells very very good I'm gonna
keep this one separate and collect the
pollen on its own in a couple days
foreign
flowers
because they might contain moisture that
will make the pollen non-viable
it's kind of tedious
got to be done something new
so I've got everything separated all the
plant matter out that's what pollen I'm
left with I learned a valuable lesson
not to do hold your forehead over it if
you're sweating there's a little puddle
of uh no good in there but work with it
then I'm going to leave this here in the
closet I'm going to set the D Hue one to
40 percent humidity relative humidity
and then I'm going to creep out and
start spraying these plants
so we're up to 40 and up a little warmer
since I've been up here so it won't take
too much but I'm going to give them a
squirt
now my logic here is that I can try to
neutralize any pollen that might be left
on the plants or in the air and then if
any what does creep out through the door
will be neutralized by the little
humidity zone out there if not there's a
couple more doors and attempted barriers
but I know this stuff finds a way so I'm
going to spray everything down
forgive me room
got everything sprayed down
got the closet quarantined I'm just
sitting here and smoke one
let the humidity jack up
then I'm going to take off everything I
wore put it in a pile
I'm gonna spray that as much as I can
any tools that I brought in here that
I'm bringing out including my cell phone
I'm going to give those a spray down
then I'm going to bring me and all that
stuff right to the bathroom even the
sprayer even though it was spraying
water I imagine there's some pollen on
there so I'm going to rinse everything
including me
right after the humidity gets to about
60 65 in here then I have my little
buffer zone out there that's like 75 and
then it's right to the bathroom
start throwing water on everything
and that's going to be too hot for TV so
I'll check you guys a little bit
so I'm out of the shower
I tried to rinse everything that I
brought back out of the room
and dry it off
and maybe take this time to do a little
outro or some closing thoughts
so while I do think there is some skill
in gathering the pollen and pollinating
the female plants
I think the real labor and time is going
to be through running through the
generation the next generation of seeds
I think that's going to take a lot of
time
I don't know I've never done this before
but I know just from you know running
other people's stuff it takes time
so I imagine this is going to be a long
while but I'm rather excited
I don't think I mentioned what plants
I'm using the whole time
maybe get into that now the males that I
was collecting pollen off of were
Mendocino pineapple I believe if not
bread popularized by Ringo
the ones I got come by way of ital
foundation adamando
I believe they were labeled Island
Paradise but uh I think they're
f4s of the Mendo pineapple which I've
never grown myself I have some friends
that have worked on farms in Mendocino
that have told me about the plant
I've definitely ran through a bunch of
it and uh we always dug it we always
really liked it
um I did not know that it had so many
minor cannabinoids in it which is what
truly interested me and motivated me to
try to collect the pollen and throw it
it seemed like it would be a little bit
easier of a learning curve it being an
F4 and pretty stable
and when I asked ital about it
he was kind of saying that like you know
any mail will be the pineapple which uh
was very encouraging
and maybe it will limit the amount of
population I have to run through to look
for what I'm looking for if it is in
there
the female that it'll be hit on is an
early flowering Northern Lights number
five Haze which is donned the PC3 by
piff Coast Farms this is something that
I very very very much so enjoy myself
the people around me very much so enjoy
it I think that in itself
has medicinal value I haven't had a lab
tested yet it's going to be lab tested
within a month or so
but I feel like both of them together
could really be something first and
foremost I want to try to combine the
flavors because I'm very flavor based
with my consumption so the way I
Envision it and again I do not know what
I'm doing this is just the concept in my
vision we'll see what comes of it but I
would love if there was a nice pineapple
inhale
and then a nice hazy piffy exhale
if I go find something in there with
that I'd be very very very happy
um I think
the energetic nature and just generally
soaring Good Vibes
of the PC3
and kind of like the no ceiling
high on it I think that might pair well
with the pineapple as well as the
pineapple is kind of more like a feel
good mellow Buzz so I think that they'll
marry well
I don't think that
at least for me and my crew most people
that like the hazy ones are usually not
super Discerning on THC numbers
so I think that's one thing that's cool
too if it does become something fun and
worthwhile to like run and share
I don't think people that were looking
for a type 2 variety would care too much
about high THC
and I don't think too many Haze heads
are ever concerned about that at all I
think it's just a bonus if it tests like
above 20 or is kind of like you know
some interesting numbers
so I'm very encouraged to do it and um
I'll be making seeds I just put the uh
the couple pc3s into the flower room
with the males they're not on the same
schedule but I'm just gonna start there
get their hormones going 12 12 now
and um
so it'll be about 10 11 weeks until
they're harvested I'll be popping seeds
immediately after that and uh by then it
should be close to Springtime as well so
I can see what the first generation f1s
are gonna do out in the main sunshine
and also what they'll do in an inside
environment so I'm very excited about
that
um and thank you to everyone who's
anyone who's ever shared knowledge about
this stuff like most things I kind of
take what I like
like a salad bar of information
try to formulate my own strategy but a
lot of these Concepts being implemented
were suggested or talked about by
someone else
um
can't think of too much more I'm very
excited I hope to document the process
some more I don't know if it'll
necessarily be here on FCP but certainly
I'm going to keep track of it very
excited I'm going to go collect the rest
of the pollen I
grab tomorrow let it sit for like 12 20
hours and that little dehume environment
I threw the pollen that I did collect
directly into the freezer
um after collecting it I was a little
nervous about the little bits of soil in
there I imagine they're holding a fair
amount of moisture so my logic was to
put it right in the freezer
and kind of just get everything real
cold before too much moisture could move
around I don't know if there's any logic
in that but when I gather the batch
tomorrow I'm going to try to be a little
bit more cautious and not leaving any
little bits of soil in there
um there was one that smelled very
special as I was shaking them all
earlier one of them and it wasn't so
pineappley it was like a deep note like
it wasn't sweet it was like a low end
kind of funky note
and uh
I thought I was just imagining it I gave
it a little stomach stem rub and it was
very very strong aroma so I have that
one set aside I'll probably let that one
flower out a little bit longer and
collect that pollen individually maybe
put another female in there a week or
two behind it after I've sprayed down
the room and jacked the humidity and uh
I'm very excited thank you future
cannabis projects for all the knowledge
thank you to everyone else who's kind of
like open source with their stuff much
respect and uh wish me the best I really
don't know what I'm doing I mean I know
what I want like most of us do but uh as
far as how to get there
only one way to start we'll see where it
goes appreciate everyone