[Music]
ah yes oh when you wake up and you feel
like you need a little upper or when
you're down and outer and you need to
get a little higher if you feel like you
need a blessing now and you're feeling a
little high today welcome to the church
welcome to Cali High season 6 episode 60
this week we visit Rancho Verde Farms
close to harvest and talk with my old
friend Peter G out on the California
coastal plains Peter G has medical grow
at Rancho Verde Farm where it gets Sun
all day from sunrise to sunset we take a
stroll with Peter through the garden and
learn some of his clever growing
techniques Peter has been a friend of
mine for 44 years we were in an
avant-garde band called The dadas in the
late 70s and in recent years he has been
a mentor to me helping me with my grow
and sharing his knowledge expertise and
techniques of growing high quality
healthy cannabis
Peter is a drummer and after the garden
visit we composed a small duet for drums
and melodica of which several Clips are
interspersed in this episode this is a
fun episode to watch if just to watch us
Circle the garden and uncover gems of
knowledge while checking out Peter's
growl not to mention the musical reparte
between us
check it out
kzog classic ogila
needs three more weeks and what is the
classic OG look
it's too slow in the car usually kind of
dark green and the edges the leaves fold
up and you get little snow drifts on
them yeah so I think that my Formaggio
has those characteristics as well really
you can see the little the way the
leaves do that on the edge I don't know
this has the same
Peter always has the nicest looking
leaves
a very party plants
very forgiving very easy to grow
super sturdy branches
can grow big Casey OG yeah I think
that's a OG KZ
from the Ohio State organization you
gave me from what was the name
it was a guava gelato oh the guava
gelato
yeah shout out to you looks very similar
it's even darker green
and very tight serrations reminds me of
a Northern Lights I grew on wow bro I
need to have a butt of that because I
don't I didn't even grow any myself just
to taste it when it's done
how's it looking how's it smelling man
smells indicate yeah
dank rub some of it
freakiness
oh gee I don't know
thank you
interesting pretty Point very sticky
it's a it's a limey
chirping right is that lime in them yeah
it's lime
and with a little like gelato is that
what it is yeah yeah you gave it to me
oh yeah
we're gonna refer to him as yonsai
okay
[Music]
foreign
just like you bro and then I just put it
before I put it on the ground there's
also a cage in the ground so the Gophers
connected to it but before I did that I
dug like 20 gallons out and put some
it's old soil and put some of that
tomato
fertilizer in there
and wet it and then set it on top so now
it's growing into the ground
oh that is excellent happier yeah yeah
to grow into the ground yeah yeah you
can grow trees if you grow in the ground
I'm forgiving too because it always has
more how's the soil here well
it's like sand super fine and hard
uh-huh it holds water forever right so
you have to mend it yeah it's like sand
it should Dig Down
it's trippy
[Music]
foreign
now that I take the net off I let them
go this one's going to be ready real
soon
look at it's [ __ ] beautiful
if you see this when the sun gets over
there it just gets all white
what are the tall ones in the back well
let's go around this way and then we'll
get to the back I suppose
which way do you want to go Petey gosh
this is
and the fruity tree
favorite flavor
oh my God
he got grape
I don't know you tell me
they're all different
this one's a more of a sativish looking
whereas this one's more OG looking right
oh my God this reminds me of something
that holds old
something else this is more OG looking
you know what I'm saying yeah yeah yeah
yeah the fluffier this is nice even
supposedly a 70 Indica 30 sativa mix but
it grows like sativa and my fingers are
all sticky
they're both three blue Kings different
yeah tell us about your pruning method
Peter
as you can see I stripped the bottoms
out
um
you can look right through them
come out here and see the ants going up
and you're going
let's see I got the tangle foot tangle
foot tangle foot no way up into the cap
canopy but when they get up there boy
they go on the highway and they just
will spread out through all the the
canopy yeah yeah yeah oh my God
in my ropes and what are they doing up
there when they do go up there they Farm
aphids right and they turn into the
scale right aphid scale I'm not sure
what it is but no the scale is a
different thing I think they Farm those
too right
they milk those things
yeah averies are different than the
scale for sure also three
three Plies this again today
because it's
still fluffy
it is still fluffy right
I could it's got these long hair up top
but you know it's a lot of popcorn
mm-hmm
fluffers
it needs two more weeks look at it's all
white still there's that one the hairs
are already
right on so you're
you're Harvest Time becomes more like
the valleys huh you have a drier climate
it becomes more like my Harvest Time
as far as
yeah I get a little deal right on the
leaves the farm seas and they form on
the ridge tips of The Ridges
[Music]
what is this this is the three blue
Kings too oh my God bro look how thick
that is massive look at this over here
it's the size of my freaking head
wow right
unreal buddy
fluffy
yeah I think she's ready to go bro look
there's hardly any white hair well a
little white here is
just take down the Choppers
look a little bit around underneath
it could be like a week
do you get out the scope and look at the
truck it's different I remember she was
young she had the fattest leaves of all
of them uh-huh
and now they're sitting out in the bud
stage
isn't that funny how they do that
that's so massive right there Peter
that's like eight inches across there's
functors every yeah big giant Clunkers
it kind of has it's like a big it's a
donkey dick structure but not really
but the buds are so big
coming down yeah whereas you see that
and then what's that one again
the one that we went to just there with
the white hairs
but so it's that one's later he put that
shade over here so you got some light up
under it okay just flash on
oh we we got light in here I think look
at that oh yeah and Petey want to tell
us about your reflective uh medium
and what is that stuff Petey right tell
us what that is so you know you can
really
oh my God you're right let me let me
take it still here let me interrupt
[Music]
there's a nice afternoon Breeze
notice the airless paint sprayer for
polar feeding your plants
handiest thing in the world
oh wow bro and it gives a fine Mist oh
yeah yeah it's the best
done I used to get out there with a
little sprayer like ow
this is uh the blue Kings three boot
clean Liberty blue Kings so three months
and three days old okay all this was
just
so let's for people that haven't
actually watched a prior episode with
you
this is Peter G of Casa Verde Farms
Rancho Verde Rancho Verde okay
and I started in the cloth pots here
[Music]
and as they grow I can shift them around
which one I want to plant where you just
drop them right in the soil
and they just grow right through and you
built these beds I think I started in a
little cloth pot eventually I dropped it
into a 20 gallon cloth pot and you cut I
do cut slits in the bottom of the pots
but they still grow right through them
yeah
it's the handiest thing in the world I
just did that my first time one of your
tricks then I pushed soil all all around
it uh-huh you know I'll put some kind of
reconstituted amendment now do you have
to water all three of those yeah use
water right into the first one yeah and
then go around it but then the the other
side you're like the rest of it stays
moist also though right huh it seems
like the outer soil also stays moist is
that water it outside the thing too yeah
my water I pour like four gallons in
uh-huh I pour two or three gallons
around it takes I see seven or eight
so I'm going to do 12 gallons for the
bigger plants and how often do you water
every
every four days unless they're in a pot
and they're not in the ground then I do
them every day to have every other day
if I'm lucky yeah yeah I'd do the same
over here
this one
letting it dry out I'm picking it
tomorrow because it's just too down so
it's starting to rot and it is what
uh-huh
this was an off to the side part it was
started in like one gallon then I put it
in like a three gallon I kept on
dropping in a bigger cloth pots
concentric rings
just [ __ ] hard makes it harder for an
ant to crawl in there
oh speaking events what is your uh
smaller pots and I just keep dropping it
into a bigger pot and you're just
filling around it and just
the way to go
see what I'm saying yeah and you use
white plastic to keep the heat off your
pots yes I do yeah a little bit of
tangle foot
I believe like Pine tour you get a new
hardware stores okay first you put a
little tape around it and then you put
it on the tape right but then the add
let the ants live in the pots because
they're good for the soil they make
little trails and yeah they'll eat other
insects from living in your soil yep yep
yep it's just as long as they don't come
up into the buds I'm good with them yeah
they can not get up I will sometimes
they find their way up this pole and
along this wire oh yeah I watch for that
like in here they did that they came up
this pole over here
there's no way for them into the canopy
without having to go over the school I
got all these goo there who there
cross over here yeah which I leaned into
earlier in there has the little goo
around the bottom and they just can't
get up there oh yeah I see they're all
stuck on it as well there's some kind of
insect stuck on it
dirt but as you were saying this year
there's less insects right
yeah in general I got aphids but they
come off the bamboo over there I just
got my
bug sprayer out my airless and sprayed
all the bamboo on the other side of my
enclosure
the Bougainvillea doesn't pose any
problems
and this used to be all open now I
planted the boat in Via and the yuccas
and
[Music]
foreign
so how many three kings do you have like
five
and here we have the concentric circles
of potting
and the outer
bed of soil
I think I started off in a plastic pot
and I just sliced it down the side
I should have taken it off but it
doesn't matter
yeah I cut the bottom off it and sliced
it all the way down one side
oh that's cool
it's dropped in the pot another pot and
then in here it's growing into 200
gallons of soil right that's why it gets
so big it's just endless
repo forever
takes right 12 gallons every time I
water it now let me ask you another
question at the end of the season do you
pull the pots out of the beds
no I'll let the roots rot and just at
the beginning and next Four Season I'll
just
twist that stem out of the soil uh-huh
and mix it up and then I get a new
bag a couple cubic feet of
new soil right which is I've been using
Aurora
original mix or something anyway so
and I put that in the pots and all the
stuff around it is reconstituted soil
from the year before
and next year I'll push it off into that
way and sometimes I carry it out of here
uh-huh
very cool
yeah you put the amendment in the old
soils Home Depot tomato whatever they
call it
which is organic
microbes and all that uh-huh
this one I just dropped on another pot
and she's rolling down into the other
one I'm sure
you see she's
[Music]
she looks very happy
so we go there's no cut through kind of
is there
what is my look at the difference a
little tanning held
[ __ ] bro it's so bright I can't see what
I'm filming but I hope I'm getting this
on that one oh my goodness
look at that fluffy
three pounds of fluff
every year my three pounds of flour
is it it's huge bro
the Jazz look at it it just goes like
Haze right
very strong smoke the the THC uh
trichomes are actually smaller on the
tree blue Kings where some of the
indicas are big trichomes you know what
I'm saying but this is a very it's very
Stony
look at the lineage yeah
look at that plant okay let's just let's
get it from this side
oh my God
yeah what's under here Peter more soil
waiting for something
but over here gets blocked out
uh-huh
nice having an open space
for here when they get crowded
The Vault sorry
that's the three months
three months and three days
how does the plant do that
something must be done right
90 days Petey from seed to [ __ ] bud
unreal
yeah you did start late
June
all of them are kind of massive bro
and of all your fertilizer what you you
would say how much percentages organic
I start out using Advanced Nutrients
they're full line
I use very little nutrient on grow
because there's so much in the soil I'm
also using in between liquid nutrient
feeding I will use a Aurora dry nutrient
feeding so whole feed schedule so it's
just attack them with everything they
don't seem to uh get them as Hardy as I
can when they start butting
and then I switch to only organic Aurora
dry nutrients organic
something looks like it was done right
here for sure
the whole garden actually flush I use
flushing agent from
Advanced Nutrients called Flawless
finish
good or bad I don't know but
interesting everything they do seems to
work pretty well
I think going this way is probably not
the best idea
of the
let's come down the other rows
[Music]
foreign
there is another one of those kzs which
you can see this one here
the one next to its sugary
different
same string
and you you planted all these at the
same time or what
Norm I started later like a week or like
June 25th or something
probably some of the smaller ones who
knows yeah
this is a vertical stack you're always
like I better plan a few more because I
know bro right yeah then you end up with
too many I know well and then you don't
want to kill them I have very small
plants this year so I'm except for my
own genetics
and you know I have to grow small in my
own little hoop house anyway
yeah you're uh I'm limited not a lot of
sun it's a hard place
yeah stuck in between
up in our hearts
but you know
but you make it work I make it work
Ed yes we did
yep we smoked a joint of my delicious
weed okay it's been in my freezer for a
year pulled it out last week been in the
refrigerator since freaking amazing
blueberry muffin needs
they have one more organic
feeding this is a giant kg from
oh my God no this is the three blue
Kings
huh Kings yeah oh my God
it is a tree
she had the biggest
that's a very fruity but Floral
smell
right
I didn't mean to squeeze your bud so
hard I hate when people do that to my
buds
I'm sorry
bad me
this is beautiful look how sugary these
are
the Casey
yeah yeah
the green is the color green is
[Music]
this one here yeah yeah look at those
knees right yeah I'd say OG has a sativa
element right
an indica or something the black dog
always produces quick very quick this
string
I already harvested one of them
very beautiful from the inside here
and there's a giant
two weeks
it's all spread out I sure do
giant fan leaves in there every branch
is tied up with a [ __ ] wire
yeah I've had to tie up some of mine as
well yeah sometimes the buds flop on
each other yep yep
okay back out of this rail
go on it
how would you describe it
tobacco
um
and
three blue Kings smells like
some old strain
it's really fruity and Floral
right am I I don't know is it three this
is this is it right here right
and so with those that one over there
all of these
except for that one which is the kgog
massive growing
you get three different
four different Thanos from it
each one of them smells a little bit
different right yeah
yeah I had one last year though and it
had the pungent flavor like the old
Bubba Kush
used to taste from Dr Greenthumb when he
first had it tasted unbelievable you
know pungentas yeah I do
I use that word sometimes
[Music]
[Laughter]
oh bringing leather
that is a kind of an interesting so I
think I prefer my Formaggio
huh the cheese smell the cheese taste
okay so what haven't we seen what's down
here Petey
the blueberry on the other this is the
blueberry right here oh my God
oh my God
sorry bro
sorry I didn't mean to like walk into a
place it's of Hazard
this blueberry muffin looks exquisite
bigger than my blueberry muffin buds
yeah small slow plant I started at the
same time as those two blue Kings and
look at the one
I know bro another freaky
calyxes are giant can't understand
uh-huh
Kings with the massive buds
[Music]
it's got to be at least
and when do you start to defoliate Peter
I already have on these bottoms on the
bottoms you have definitely
up in there you can see it's only sparse
leaves uh-huh
crowded somewhere on the plan I'll pull
some of the leaves out and constantly I
cut branches off like that one had no
room huh
cut that off cut that they were big long
branches and you're in the way and to
walk through here I couldn't get through
uh-huh like you're gone yeah unless they
were some of the slower plants yeah yeah
yeah look at the beautiful purple color
on the three blue Kings oh well I've had
stems that purpled I have well my
Formaggio had syrup strain has
completely red stem
Leaf stems
like a purpley stem without tail all of
them I used to get buds that were purple
what's up with that remember that purple
buds yeah the calyxes were actually
perfect yeah well I've got one plant
with the pink hairs all over it it's
beautiful the the squirt that I grew it
has purple in it one of them is totally
purple the purple kind
and I mean the one that takes after the
blueberry muffin watch me like this plan
out this one over here with the shade
watch
[Music]
oh
this one here is pretty impressive too
Wild
insurance
wow
this is the difference
more OG ish looking right same strain
but different looking not the fluff
she's [ __ ] pretty hope I don't [ __ ]
it up
I hope not sometimes they go south some
you're like what did I do
beautiful
not the biggest producer but those are
pretty funky thunkers
come on
yeah Petey these are massive
compared to my upholstery Garden
but
my phone is completely sticky actually
my favorite plant was the fluff
hmm
good yeah let me smell that one more
time
just the leaves both the bud leaves yeah
just squeeze the leaves
yeah the candy flavor
yeah it's a different
kind of
old school
[Music]
and on the edge over here Peter you have
the parts what's in the parts again you
have a
this one with Bud Rod is a what
black dog and where do you get the black
dog seeds
humble seed organization so you've only
the source of all your plants are two
organizations
and that one gelato
um guava gelato the guava gelato looks
pretty nice though right
it's flushing it for two weeks and it
wouldn't get yellow
I actually fertilized it again today
like one more did I
think so
yeah these outside ones I I play with
I did something right
they're growing in a pot it's pretty
nice huh absolutely bro
20 gallon pot this is what mine's going
to look like
[Music]
could be the weather here it has
something to do with these but I think
it's more of your growing technique
[Music]
but I don't I got smaller birds smaller
plants
you'd listen to what I told you
if I just listen okay just listen all
right
I'm gonna listen we're gonna try next
year is going to be different
you're a little you don't have to mix
your head
from this watering and
of course you'll watch the plants if it
shows some
sign of stress like all your hair start
turning brown start flushing it
right because they will turn down if
with heat or something yeah too many new
transactions when I was flushing this
pot I tested the runoff
and it was like
1900 PPM like wow oh my gosh that's
really a lot maybe even more I can't
remember some outrageous number and I'd
indicating that it's got too much in
there
last runoff I got when I flushed it was
like 900 or the one before it anyways
right enough water you're starting to
turn brown you got to cut you down sign
them in the barn and this middle one is
what it what is this one it's another
crazy OG
that's how it usually looks the same as
this one yeah look how black to me is
the classic OG structure
the blueberry muffin looks like it's a
lighter color right and pinkish you see
pink he's in there it's also got the red
um same thing as last year on the bigger
shade leaves Leaf stems
it's like it needed some more or
something
the whole thing it's like malnourished
all right
I can fertilize the [ __ ] out of it and
put dry organic nutrients on it
I'm just flashing it looks like candy
I hope it is here it's
cool
very nice
well that was a great tour of the garden
PD and thanks a lot