[Music]
welcome to cali high episode 32 i'm your
host chenzonico and this week our guest
is reggae great richard daley bass
player and founding member of the iconic
reggae band third world he joins kelly
high for an amazing interview about his
long career his early days in kingston
and he talks about working with various
producers of reggae notoriety such as
lee scratch perry chris blackwell and
damian marley
daley speaks of memorable gigs and
staggering crowds we also talk about
third world's new album produced by
damien marley and find out about classic
reggae tunes that richie played on we
never knew about and more a classic must
watch for reggae fans
stay tuned this is
cali high is blessed today to be with
one of
reggae's royalty
i'm here with richie daly
who i've known for a good 45 years and
he is the bass player of third world
richie thanks for joining us buddy
it was a bit of pleasure friends um
but we have history that goes back so
long yeah
you're talking to it's hard to believe
we're that old
somehow i don't feel that old you know
so
well richie um
where'd you grow up and how did you get
into music
well you know i just desire to learn to
play the guitar
my brother used to be in a band and um i
used to watch him rehearse and i said
i got to do this
yeah i must do it you know so i got
hooked into it and i was self-taught
and um just scrambling around kingston
jamaica
pick up what i can pick up from other
people you know yeah added to my
um knowledge bank and
some years afterwards i got john of the
third world and started the ban in third
world and
you know mm-hmm
it's kind of history playing itself out
yeah and were you from i saw some
interviews said you were from the
neighborhood of trenchtown is that true
yeah
were you from trench down
not yes close to it next door to it
uh-huh you know and i'm very close to
trench down a place called rose stone is
about 100 yards that makes a difference
you know yeah
you know
i've known you for so long but i
realized
that the first time i ever heard your
bass playing was on johnny too bad by
the slickers
[Music]
correction actually i played guitar oh
you played guitar in that song yeah
i was like
wow
that's cool
who is the organ player
[Music]
oh yeah
yeah he was amazing
what a great
organist
you also played with ken booth is that
right
yeah it toured him you know on and off
uh-huh
yeah yeah what's bass or guitar
guitar yeah
interesting do you still play guitar a
little
yes i still play guitar in the last
album i played mostly rhythm oh wow
yeah yeah and a few guitar tricks uh-huh
that's cool
uh are there any other tracks or the
early tracks that weren't third world
songs that you played on that we might
know
uh when i did some bob marley thing in
the early days but this is during third
federal time
punky regular party and um
lord i got to keep on moving i played
this on those tracks with bob marley i
love those tracks and
you worked with so many different
producers you worked with
lee scratch perry you worked with chris
blackwell who actually signed you guys
in 75
right and then
when you worked with bob
um
was that a self-produced album by bob
no scratch fairy was produced as that
what was it like i mean those guys are
all pretty different i mean first of all
you guys at least scratch perry we got
chris blackwell
bob marley oh you say
lee scratch perry produced the bell
marley toons yeah bob marley
executive producer yeah yeah he would
come and give his um opinion
at the end of the session but not
necessarily
you know but his presence made a
difference yeah
yeah
and then the last album you guys made is
produced by damian marley that's amazing
can you give us a little insight as to
how all of those different personalities
produce
there's a similarity between bob marley
and damon marley unbeknownst to him you
know
because um i was in the studio at bob
marley back in the um
late 70s and
our earlier early early 80s
and um
just his attitude and his old
work ethic
there's been some similarity
today
amen
and leaving to him
and i'm just it's just quite amazing
you know saying that they have the
tendency to say the apple don't fall far
from the tree that is so true in that
case yeah you know so they both have
amazing work ethics it comes out in the
music too yeah
yeah so
um
can you tell us some of the like the
more memorable moments of recording your
last album i know you got a lot of you
had a lot of
uh guest artist on that album
yes the collaboration was endless you
know and yeah damon picked all of them
and thought they would be more suitable
because
we weren't we didn't work at producers
much shortly
but to work a day man was
exceptional you know we decided to say
yeah you're the younger cat
because um cat used to drive him to
school
you know his son and
damon went and damon went to the same
school and showed my son to
yeah
and my son luger man who was with sean
paul daughter cup crew
um did the same
did god did the same school and you know
let
parents get together and say hey you
need to pick up this evening
you take who to go to music lesson about
a music person but you know
who who writes the the songs for third
world who traditionally
traditionally all of us all of us good
group effort everybody puts in that's
that's good
you know i've always wanted to ask this
and it might be obvious but a
brand new beggar was one of my favorite
songs and it always has been um
what is the uh with the meaning here
in brand new beggar even though we're
we're not brand new beggars this is a
change of a brand new
yeah change i'm a brand new bed in other
words my outlook on life has changed
you know and i'm developing to another
person
right yeah
but um i'm still in need of things
absolutely
i'm a brand new beggar you know
it's a great concept and uh it's you
know
shows a lot of humility
were you there when when the uh the
guest artist did their part on the new
album
sometimes some of them some of them the
truck was sent to their
part of the world that they were at the
time you know yeah yeah
yeah well that's interesting
there's some great people i like to you
know you got chronics on there you got
taurus riley
tasan chin
yeah
and uh pressure bus pipe and of course
damien singing on one
yeah
that's cool
so
what are your what are some of your most
favorite
reggae bass lines concrete jungle
uh-huh um yeah that's a great one
so much of them
yeah well i i must say that you are
an amazing bass player
and
i hope we can collaborate that would be
great yeah man we're gonna do that
absolutely
any current or future projects you guys
working on
well
you know just meeting getting our shots
and everyone is getting vaccinated and
yeah
you know
yeah and they will move on because
yeah we have uh a whole year as an and
some has been taken
i promise you that in that sense
i know so we gain knowledge from this
and inspiration still you know it's
nothing that's a lot
you know yeah
um if you if you
live through this and you haven't
learned anything
shame on you
exactly the world should learn something
the whole world can learn something here
yeah
so let's just you know just for the hell
of it who are the current
the current members of third world
on drums it's named leonardo williams
keyboards norris webb
guitar stephen cat core
and uh myself
and richard daley bass yep
followed by um aj brown and
lee vocals
yeah um
i didn't mention one of the keyboard
player because he's
one of the keyboard players over the
years he's decided that he's going to do
a solo carrier
singing it murray's clergy very
brilliant musician yeah and this guy is
his desire to be a
solo artist and
wish him all the blessings you know
uh-huh
so yeah i i think he's in italy right
now i saw a post
eating gelato
so
i asked him it was if it was delicious
in italian
you know what do you think reggae means
to the world richie i know that sounds
like a
a broad question but
and
to what it means to the world i wouldn't
deem to answer that but you can i can
only tell you what how it affects the
world right okay
fair enough um
through the years you know when it
wasn't virtually unknown when i met you
mm-hmm you're the prep you're probably
one of the few white persons who knew
reggae yeah
i turned all my friends onto him
yeah and you know your first album was a
big hit here in the san fernando valley
i must say right
everybody i knew had it
agreed here we are you know and um i
watch it grow radio stations never used
to play the music
nobody very rarely ate the top
mm-hmm
but then you know i watched it growing
up and
i think what made the team more popular
is when they start to have more reggae
festivals yeah
you know yeah people just all over the
world carries this regular festival you
just have that hypnotic thing about it
that brings people out
and um during my experience with
jamaican reggae music and jamaican food
you know so
it is what it was guess what it is you
know so um
that much i can tell you well she brings
a lot of positive neutrality
water generation
yeah generation you know
yeah their parents learned it acquired
it but they are they are from in their
infant state
their parents are playing it
from they were like tiny talk
you know so it's a whole different look
for their needs yeah
well it's it's been a an inspiration to
at least me and
the world as far as i can say
great um and does that
do you feel a weight on your shoulder
being
one of the world's reggae ambassadors
not to wait away to something on your
shoulders means a burden hard to carry
right
yeah yeah i will look at it as a crown
yes sir
absolutely
so
i have a kind of a question here
about
um
order of distinction
the jamaica awards these orders
of distinction
and
do you have one of these
richie yes
yeah
okay well i thought you should have one
so
the honorable richie basie but i want to
just say
that
[Applause]
cali high would like to award you
the cali high order of highest
distinction awarded to richard daly
april 3rd
what it's 2021 for being a cool guy
great bass player
and turning the 818
cali and the world onto great music for
more than four years
blessed be
much pride well this is the first cali
high award of highest distinction
and um
i will be sending that off and we can do
a medal ceremony when you come to cali
what do you think is the time frame for
concerts to open
i don't think we can catch nothing major
for the rest of the year because
whatever there is to be
you know it's it's in place it would
have to be in place already yeah but a
few things that was like contracted some
years ago and the people are still
holding us to those agreements
what should i say see all this covet
thing work out and just just watching it
from the ring yeah well
do you plan to do any like
virtual live shows
um we might end up doing some and then
we might not because i've seen out of
out of a hundred of them
there's only two of them i might have
seen and that one was impressive yeah
you know some of them that seem a little
bit too sterile
yeah i hear you bro
you know so no audience no feedback and
yeah no interruption on this thing you
know bears for haman is very good
so what were some of the most memorable
shows you played over the years
uh
opening for bob marley in 1975
at the lyceum in london
that was that's a special
um working at santana
on the west coast east coast of um
united states toured him for about three
weeks santana
yeah you requested us to be there with
him as he's open
to this superb that's cool
yeah
well and you all i remember on our last
interview you talked about
the uh the show at heroes stadium
two nights after bob got shot also
that must have been
the this the show at heroes stadium
in jamaica two nights after bob got shot
oh yes yeah he was he
yeah
so
what do you think was the largest crowd
you ever played for
um
i remember the name of the country but
it was close 10 million people
was in the audience somewhere in europe
wow
a million people
that's like it's called it's called
woodstock uh-huh
yeah a woodstock in europe
yes yeah yeah
interesting
900 something thousand
wow
and what does that feel like richie
amazing yeah i bet i've you know i i had
a band we played for small crowds and
even small crowds were amazing but i can
imagine of course yeah
so
well i want to thank you for talking
with us today richie
yeah blessed love man yeah and uh we'll
be talking real soon
and uh
yep
so this is cali high and we would like
to thank ritchie
daley of third world for joining us
today
richie yeah
all right thank you for the kali hi
award please
thank you
and
like i said i'll be sending it to you
and we'll we'll do the medal ceremony
out here in canada
okay so richie cool have a great day
you too man okay
[Music]
we sigh
we believe we know we're right no matter
what they taught us for how we were
brought up here we dream we hope we pray
we work we tall and we
where we come from this
[Music]
find a way to is along with each other
do it for the children
[Music]
with each other
we see we learn we teach
we search
we
[Music]
we all think
no matter where we come from this is
[Music]
unity we have so many possibilities
and i've got so much love to give
put some difference outside yeah i know
so we live
creating the world foreign
strictly positive yeah
[Music]
is
foreign
[Music]