hello everyone and thank you so much for
tuning in to Royal ground radio I'm
Michael Beck joined as always By the
Fantastic Rick Elliott hey hey and today
we have a very special guest
um founder of CHA education educator
inspiration
regenerative farmer research scientist
and general
participant in life
Russell Pace pleasure to meet you
Russell thanks for joining us thanks
guys I appreciate the invite thanks for
having me so it's really nice to kind of
sit down I know we actually cross paths
one other time last year we probably
crossed pasmore but we hung out last
year
at the emerald cup and it happened to be
on opposite sides of a conversation with
Brandon rust kind of me not knowing who
you were probably you not knowing who I
am and over the last year we've kind of
chatted about trying to make this happen
I really enjoy your content I've been
consuming it for a long time thanks
there's a wide variety of like
incredibly useful information and right
on beneficial information for the people
out there
so thanks for joining us I want to kind
of dig into
a little bit of what got you to where
you are what inspired you to take the
path and yeah you know you know get to
where you are today so so how did you
end up in Humboldt first yeah
uh well funny story no I mean there's a
long backstory I suppose I you know
it you know in a bizarre way it kind of
started when I was 12 years old and I
went to Tibet when I was 12. and wow I
saw weed growing in the mountainous
Hills and even at monasteries high up in
the mountains and I kind of I don't know
it was just like this thing where I was
like that plant what is this plant like
you know and I didn't even know what it
was and my dad was like Wilson that's a
marijuana plant and I was like oh I like
it even more I don't know it's just this
weird Affinity you know I can't explain
it just like this like magnetic
attraction to this plant
and uh honestly at 12 years old you know
what weed is right yeah well I was
pretty sheltered and I mean I knew what
it was I had never I'd never smoked it
before but I was a little bit of a
you know I could see growing up in
Humboldt at 12 you smoked but growing up
where I did you know it was like not as
common you know dare you hear about it
but I went through the Dare program I
know yeah back in Michigan yeah it was
like a funny start because me and my
buddy Riley Berry I went with this kid
from La that I grew up with and his
grandmother his family actually was the
Barry family who um his great uncle
wrote Peter Pan
and so they were like you know loaded
and had money from the silk trade and
the Orient and stuff and so that's how
this whole trip kind of got set up it
was like this weird little thing with
them wanting to do this we were like
with a film crew they were making a
documentary about like the Warriors of
calm and these like high mountainous
planes in Tibet and we just like tagged
along in this like crazy Saga anyways
and but we were there and and so we were
I'd never forget we're outside this
Monastery high up in the hills and we're
like dude let's like steal some let's
try to smoke some weed and we didn't
know what we were doing and it was July
so the plants were just vegging so we
just like ripped off some fan leaves
when no one was looking we like took
them and this sweet old Chinese lady
named Bernice that we were with was
smoking cigarettes and we got her to
bomb us a cigarette we like emptied out
the tobacco dried out the leaves a few
days later and then like packed the leaf
in we're like smoking this fan Leaf out
of a cigarette and they were like would
you feel anything like no I don't feel
I'm like I don't think we're doing it
right something's not right you know so
but you know it's kind of a funny like
backstory yeah it's a good start first
time I smoked weed yeah
yeah into bed CBD and that was just
growing growing wild somewhere I was
just good yeah well that spot was
cultivated like it was that was the
first I think I have a photo of it I
have an old photo book of all these
photos
when you walk up to the monastery it was
like a you know six by six plot like it
was like a actual you could tell that
was a cultivation patch the other
patches growing out were just like fair
you know wild wild growing like it was
growing up and even now to the streets
some of the streets you know the cracks
like just wherever but
um yeah it was interesting that was like
that was off then that was it that was
off to Off to the Races and just like
kind of dabbled in weed and I bounced
around a lot I moved back and forth
between California and Virginia okay
quite a bit and so
you know like high school you try to
grow in the red Solo cups you know oh
yeah like you know that all that jazz
and you know in college was it was in
college back in Virginia and then just
um you know we grew out in the in out in
the hills of West Virginia up in the
mountain like trying to like find little
patches really it's very more dangerous
out on the East Coast with laws oh yeah
so we just try to be more careful
gorilla style yeah for sure
um and then so I'm kind of like
backstory okay re reorient here uh and
then
um I I got my degree in geology I had a
Bachelor of Science in geology and so I
was working down in Orange County uh
after after college and
it was just I was just getting burnt out
by the SoCal Vibes you know like all the
gas stations are leaking gasoline and I
was like remediating those and I was
just you know growing weed on the side
you know indoors a little bit
and just like tired of driving through
traffic and I was like I got I gotta get
out of here
and I was like and I was going through a
lot of existential healing you know I
had like bad allergies and you know
other immunological like imbalances and
I was like I I just wanted to get the
[ __ ] out of there I was pretty much done
with the LA Vibe you know grelly's great
and all but I just and and for some
reason it was just you know my mom she's
from Mount Shasta so I'm familiar with
Humboldt you know even though I'd never
really been it was sort of like this
magical mysterious like land
yeah of weed it and it is yeah it is it
totally is and I came up here in 2006 to
work on my master my excuse was I'm
gonna just go get my Master's Degree in
geology
and then I joke around I dropped that I
I never completed my masters and I just
got a masters in botany or whatever you
know
biology or you know plant chemistry or
yeah cultivation and yeah yeah all of
the above miners in maybe a minor in
mycology and entomology but you know
kind of like just studying just I spent
I just switched gears because geology is
cool but it doesn't really do much good
for you know solving immediate problems
I mean some of this stuff does like I
said he's a great role I studied
hydrogeology and geochemistry and some
soil science it has a great yeah com
side component like it it but you know
anyways so a lot of times yeah yeah tie
in it tied in it tied in nicely and then
yeah I just came up here and I was like
on this existential healing Quest I was
like I gotta I gotta repair whatever
this this illness is and I met this guy
in Arcata John yamas God bless that man
he was this crazy acupuncturist on top
of it G Street and he was like just do
this and this I'm like I don't know man
that sounds like kind of weird he's like
just do it and I switched my diet up and
then like over a course of a few years
like I had massive changes in health
which is Improvement you know so like
that's sort of what like home it was
just like you know thing with Humboldt
is weed and healing that's like what
drove me to go into Humboldt and I found
both of them
quite quite you know extensively and
I've been here since ever since you know
that's the Back To Nature movement man
like you know tapping in and finding all
of the medicine not just cannabis but
man yeah there's a ton of people in here
with some yes you know yes incredible
knowledge super shout out to Humble
herbals those women were Angels they
guided me through so many hours I just
go in there and just like what's this
herb do what's this do how does this
work you know just like kindly like I
would buy buy stuff and then ask
questions but they were such a huge
Catalyst for so many people in the
Herbal Healing like cannabis brought a
ton of people here and I've seen it
we've all seen it
the healing medicine at cannabis brings
people here and then they're like wait
this plant heals what about other plants
what about tea what about diet like yeah
it's a catalyst for a greater
Consciousness and movement for health
and healing and I agree those women at
Humboldt herbals were certainly really
important in kind of sparking
the learning of a lot of people in our
Circle that's awesome I'm glad I you
know that's really cool I'm actually
super jazzed to hear that yeah yeah
because it's true it's like cannabis is
it's funny because people always talk
about cannabis is um
it it occupies so many roles with
increasing Consciousness so to speak you
know like some people would say it's it
helped the the regulations and and
testing on cannabis help people
understand how many pesticides were used
on food products it kind of increased
awareness in that field you know and
especially then with herb herbal
medicine you know it opens people's
doors so oh well if this is Herb that he
helps me what other herbs also help and
it's a huge thing yeah I I could go on
and on like this is like really gets me
Jazz it helps drive people into the let
your food beer medicine Consciousness as
well in a big way I feel like it
certainly did that for me I started
smoking weed and not long after started
choosing healthier foods and starting to
be like wow why is why do I feel this
way and cut Dairy out of my life and was
like I feel so much better and just it
it opens the doors to exploring health I
feel like yeah yeah it's it's pretty
magical I wish yeah I don't I mean yes
so amazing and the depth so
part of what I love about your content
is the focus on the details of
regenerative growing gardening
understanding what's happening
above and below the soil line and kind
of connecting the dots yeah and that's
something that's really intrigued me
about some of you know
you're on Farm experiences where you're
pulling back the tops of the soil and
you're showing your inoculation of
mushrooms and how it's you know a
symbiotic relationship in the soil and
sure tell us a little bit about how that
like Consciousness changed after you
moved here kind of tied into this yeah
yeah so that's another great tie-in too
because it's like I was like had you
know three quarters fully inserted in
the anthropogenic western world really
you know this like one quarter trying to
figure out what this other thing is
and and then coming and then as on this
quest of like you know learning about
herbal medicine and health realizing how
mushrooms were a big important part of
tying it in you know and it's like the
whole Synergy between you know taking
psilocybin and
expanding that level of Consciousness
and then understanding from a
mycological standpoint how adaptogenic
mushrooms are good for your body and
then how mushrooms also um you know
grow in the in the soil and have a
decomposition process and generate life
that way as well that the whole tie-in
really and humble to me is like the
mycological like it was like a giant
heightful Network every all these
mycologists are all like super hyped
they're all you know passing around
we're getting connected through South
sybin and then there's like the Redwoods
and there's these like typhy layers in
the forests everywhere everyone I know
hunts mushrooms almost like I'm still
the weak weak link I'm like take me out
and I've hunted oyster mushrooms and I
need to go out and do chanterelles and I
haven't done it much yet well this is a
perfect list you should come out with me
yeah I'm right on the in the coastal
Forest before the Redwoods yeah up north
of McKinleyville and it's really cool
because
this entire area the Redwoods everything
it's just like a giant mycelium slick
almost right but the coastal Forest the
spruce Hemlock
um Alder Willow forests of that like
kind of coastal Wetland produce
mushrooms way more than a lot of the
Redwood forests at least the Edibles So
Dope yeah I'm all about it sidebar let's
go yeah let's go hedgehogs and some
chanterelles yeah let's go because other
I've just been cultivating them in my
own you know getting my cilia flat mats
or flats you know from like Levon from
fungi Farm yeah levon's awesome and he
you know just cultivating kingstropharia
and some shiitake logs and that's been
really cool but yeah I definitely like
to get out in the woods but all right
we're kind of tangenting um we do that
here going yeah yeah it's awesome
the whole principle of humble represents
this like
interesting ecosystem where it is it's
it's sort of pristine I don't know it's
got this element of like
I don't know it's magical it's sort of
magical it's like it's disconnected from
the rest of the world in some degree and
in a way it is yeah the Redwood
curtain's real yeah the Redwood curtain
is a real thing and it's like kind of
this I'd often joke that a [ __ ] tree
is blocked capitalism from coming up
here and fully developing it like
literally 100 like a tree has stopped
that development and I don't know it's
kind of interesting to me just from a
metaphorical standpoint I guess it's
metaphorical but it's so real like the
Caltrans project to try and widen the
101 coming up here has been stopped by
the redwood trees for those of you at
home that don't know the kind of
background of that statement it's
actually true that the redwoods have
stopped the wholesale
you know you know capitalistic
development correct because this area
there's two trees to be specific I think
there's two they're like really the base
of the argument yeah right there two
trees are just stopping that from
happening it's amazing yeah so it's a I
don't know it's like Humboldt's really
special people don't realize out there
in the world you should come up and
visit Humboldt we have like an amazing
Redwood forest and a beautiful Pacific
Ocean and not far off for the Trinity
Alps and it's just a really unique
microsystem yeah like you know Patrick's
Point you know just so beautiful it's
incredible it's amazing it's really when
I got here almost 30 years ago there was
a feeling that hit me like a bag of
bricks of comfortability and a sense of
home like a you know like I'd been here
before and I and I knew that there was
no way I was going to be able to leave
ever and then I went to Ireland where
100 of my ancestors are from on the west
coast of Ireland and and it was just
mind-blowing how similar it was in the
west coast of Ireland and I was like
well [ __ ] no wonder why I [ __ ] love
Humboldt so much and I felt like I was
home right isn't that a funny thing yeah
that's such a funny thing like my mom's
family's from Italy Northern Italy and
then they migrated up to Mount Shasta
and then I'm like looking at photos from
where they're from in Northern Italy I'm
like holy [ __ ] this is like they just
like went like it's like a micro fractal
of where they were they just found it
somewhere else in the world it's kind of
it's cool it's really interesting and
where I came from in Michigan my family
is mostly from Germany going back and
it's a huge German Network and very
similar at least especially 100 plus
years ago very very similar to the black
forest in those original deciduous
forests in the northern part of Germany
laying on the similar latitude just like
a similar latitude to here
it's cool it's like really interesting
to me how that works like that
but so kind of tangenting back to the
topic yes you know the development of
like the regenerative agriculture
mindset was really stimulated by
mycology that was the root of it and you
know over the years you'd see all of
these
people performing these types of
um you know DIY projects
and you know I would try some and just
fail and they would like shank hard and
be like what how does this you know how
does this work or how does this and I
was always I don't know I was always
driven by wanting to try to
figure out the science of it you know
just how it works once the science is
figured out you don't need to think much
about it but once but the key is like
figuring out how the science works like
like dosage you know like I have a
willow bark tree well it's the bark is
salicylic acid how much bark do I need
to boil to get the right salads like I
don't know like I [ __ ] like I don't
know what there's no answer to that
there's this really is it how how that
works you'd I'd have to send a sample in
and like tat and run tests and that
costs money you know but I've always
been driven by that principle to figure
that out or like you know with that's
that's just the bark like then you go
with the willow shoots that are more for
the cloning solution you know it's like
what's what percentage of indo-butyric
acid is in the shoots like how do you
figure out how much you need to clone
you know to make like a cloning gel and
at what point in its life is it does it
possess the most aggressive quality in
the spring I know I know that's in the
spring spring months with the fresh
shoots right when we have the highest
yeah of the rooting hormone IBA yeah
okay but you know it's it's essentially
like I mean if you want to like drive
home an overarching principle like
the plant medicine healed me I'm
indebted to plant medicine and I want to
figure out how to
to to figure out I want to figure out
how to measure it at a like a level for
home Growers so everyone has like a base
sort of analysis of how that works you
know like with like con so you know
with the dynamic accumulators like
comfrey and yarrow and nettle and Mullen
whatever blah blah blah like that's
probably the first main research science
that I conducted where I was like well
let's figure out what nutrient values of
these are you know if you're going to
grow them and then add them to your
soil for fertilizer can you do that
successfully with knowing and so I
that's a it's a it's hard because some
of this is tricky the the tricky part is
that there's not it's all turkey it's
there's there's there's ranges of values
that's the tricky part well that's very
similar to cannabis like you can grow
the same cultivar region or region you
know from from one Valley to to the next
and you're going to see those
differences it's not gonna yeah be the
exact same yeah that works for all herbs
and that's kind of the Alchemy of the
process is that there's like the people
that do it are just like artists and
sort of Alchemists I feel like it makes
it difficult to put a full 100 stamp of
science on yeah plant medicine for that
reason yeah you know because there are
just variances yeah for sure it's like a
controllable I could tell you if you
want to have like time in your tea for
respiratory issues to use a tablespoon
of it but if you grow it in depleted
soil and it doesn't have the same
concentration of essential oils maybe
you need two tablespoons to get the
right dose you just that's like this
like unknown or the same with like the
dynamic the biggest pushback I've had
with the dynamic accumulators like well
you can't really use that as a value
because the soil they're going to
accumulate nutrients differently in
different soils truth and based on a lot
of factors what's in the soil yeah what
fungus is in the soil what's what
bacteria is in the soil what's
liberating those items and making them
plant available those interactions
between you know microorganisms
inert chemistry and the plant all make
such a difference yeah and that's what
it's really hard to drive home so I'm
trying at least with the dynamic
accumulators to provide I think I've
gotten to a decent framework of
understanding so I have this I use Sam
at soilscape and I did some tests a
number of years ago I have these mpk
values and I have like the main values
of their spikes of you know it's like
calcium magnesium
um there's even silica potassium
and uh and and then what I did was is
that
um Dr Duke has this this guy Dr Duke's
created an ethnobotanical database have
you guys ever heard of this
it's a U.S department of agricultural
website this guy Dr Duke did a long time
ago and it's a huge giant database of
phytochemistry of like plant chemicals
he created this like huge database of
like I don't even know how many hundreds
or thousands of different plant species
and it has a lot of the different
chemicals like the terpenes or the
Esters or whatever other plant compounds
there are yes and then it also has
nutrient values to the best of his
ability it doesn't have them all there's
missing gaps but there's quite a bit of
data that he's collected so I've been
taking the data that I've aggregated and
comparing them with his data so like
I'll look on the web on his on the
website and see like okay his comfrey
says yada yada and then I'll be like my
Humphrey says this this this
and what's like sort of the correlation
what's this you know statistical
correlation and there I can post it I
can show you guys like it's actually
pretty good like I'm actually impressed
how much overlap there is with nutrient
spikes you know what I mean so for mine
the potassium will be like 70 000 which
will be really high because well it was
just grown in soils with a lot of
nutrients
and but his will still be thirty
thousand you know and the baseline's you
know like 10 PPM you know like it's like
right so there's like
relative spikes between all of the
nutrients that are higher in all the
main
groups of accumulators so I it's it's
cool for me because it's like a clear
correlation it's like okay well maybe
it's not sucking up like a ton ton
you're not you're not going to get an
exact value but you of like say
potassium but you know that comfrey is
going to have a high overall high level
of potassium
if you grow it and add it apply it I
guess so it's you know some I'm trying
to establish some baseline you know yeah
of that you know if I can that would be
cool and I want to write a book about it
that's fascinating to me and you know
I'm really interested to start taking a
look at some of this data and see the
relationships and these accumulators
between yeah related nutrients like
magnesium calcium and potassium they all
have such yeah a unique and integral
link together right because they bond at
the same sites within the plant roots
and kind of can cancel each other or
prevent each other from taking up
nutrients and you know reaching Peak
potential so yeah yeah that just and
then you know it's like because also I'm
just saying I mean I don't know but it's
like we got tons of land people there's
Fields all over the place like how
difficult would it be to just like plant
a field of comfrey and just go out and
harvest it for fertilizer you know what
I mean yeah like it's like free just
take it and try it and powder it and
just like add it to your soil mix I
don't know it's like I'm just saying
it's not necessarily
I don't know to me it just seems like a
free
free source of fertilizer potentially
well and potentially such a deep root
system that pulls roots or pulls
nutrients from down it elevates them to
the top and that's someone once
explained to me Casey yeah you can check
out an earlier episode Royal grown radio
with Casey from Phoenix Rising Farms up
in southern Oregon
he's got these comfrey plants that his
family have been in his family for like
70 or 100 years or something yeah and
from the Carolinas I want to say yeah
heirloom oh wild you know
strain and he's been propagating and his
family's been passing it down and his
explanation and I've heard it other ways
is
it's its job is to pull those deep
rooted nutrients that shallow rooted
plants can't access and it pulls them up
to the top and you chop it and drop it
and it creates it's nutrient cycling
through the layer of nutrient cycling
yeah I could see that that's yeah that's
the only thing I could see like over
time if you're like continuously
harvesting a field you might start
depleting all of the nutritive values
maybe over time you'd lose some of the
you know concentrations of of plant
fertilizer but I like I plant my country
next to my compost pile I have these I
have a boxing 14 but I got from flying
Blue Dog shout out to Rita and the
Flying Blue Dog ladies in Willow Creek
they're awesome they they have a big
herbal Farm too I've gotten a ton of
herbs from them yeah yeah I buy a lot of
stars in them every year yeah they're
they're awesome and and she gave me some
uh starts of this boxing 14 which is a
clumping comfrey yeah so it doesn't
spread like crazy I've had mine growing
next to my compost pile it's about the
size of this table people it's been like
that for about four or five years
and so it just like mines the new all
the nutrients that might get leached out
under the compost pile it just like
mine's that and I just chop it and put
it back in the compost pile for nutrient
cycling seems to work pretty well that's
cool yeah wow yeah I mean all of these
concepts are millennia's old but the
understanding is new the depth of the
understanding the ability to test the
nutrients to isolate these nutrients and
to start to do the sort of research that
you're talking about that's a fresh
thing we haven't had the science at our
fingertips to be like I've got a tissue
sample I want to know exactly what's in
this plant I'm actually at the same time
going to take a soil sample and know
what's exactly in the soil so I know
what the plant's taking up yeah yeah
what it's utilizing what it's leaving
behind and why and then you go to say
Earth Fort and do a biological assay and
you're like okay well look I've got all
this nitrogen my plant can't take it up
I'm missing these nitrogen cycling
pieces from my biology or you know just
one example of ways that modern science
is giving us the why behind yes things
that people have observed yes
observational science for Millennia and
now would be the time to plug if there's
any really rich philanthropist out there
let's start a research science
laboratory here in Humboldt where we can
study all this stuff so if you really
want to get into it
I'll be the lead scientist to run it and
we'll just start testing all we'll
really that's that's really would be the
dream to just have like a research
science laboratory where you test all
this stuff out you know
like um Cutting Edge yeah it would be
dope you know it's like with the
Chrysanthemum flower you know that's
what perithrum comes from yeah and it's
like well can you just like grow this
flower and use it safely you know like
could you I don't know can you let's
find out right you would think that
aren't harmful to yeah Aquatic Life yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah and it's like could
you I don't know could you well there's
only one way to find out and that's to
like run some research science on on
these topics you know it's it's tough I
mean obviously there is some science
involved in that you know for whatever
reason and obviously there could be a
monetary value behind it and there's a
business and so yeah it comes you know
Narrows that down yeah like but most of
our medicines out there from penicillin
to anticoagulation meds I mean it's all
plant-based yeah all of them are that's
what I tell people I'm like like you
guys don't realize like how much
science cops plant medicine field like
uh what's that Theraflu is from star
anise
aspirins from willow bark
tecnu the poison oak treatment is from a
plant called grindelia I believe or gum
gum weed that's the nickname I didn't
know that one yeah yeah that one's cool
we have that one growing it's really
cool we have this huge plant if you guys
are ever out in the summertime it's
really dope it's this huge yellow
beautiful bright yellow flowers and it
has a sticky super sticky white gummy
substance that's you you I guess make a
tincture with it and then it treats
poison oak but anyways it's
anticoagulation meds like Warfarin and
stuff like that that you know yeah my
dad had to take that one sure I mean
it's really common these days and that's
all from Clover yeah oh no kidding yeah
oh I did not know that that was that was
discovered by cows bleeding to death
internally oh funny because they ate too
much Clover interesting mind is blown
add one to the list cool yeah so you
know it's like plants
have all the answers we just need to
figure out what those answers are and we
don't need to rely so much on this like
pharmaceutical Matrix for telling us
what we need as far as they're really
helpful I'm not going to like totally
knock it because they like when they're
when they when like they're really good
for surgery they're really good for
technical highly technical surgeries
when it comes to internal medicine they
fail horribly it like with diet and
nutrition and health like sure they
don't they they get an F minus
for that understanding well I feel like
that's a lot to do with the isolation
you're you're recognizing oh this plant
does this but then you isolate a single
component or compound within that sure
plant and use it
as a medicine and you're no longer using
a whole plant medicine that's balanced
through Millennia of evolution totally
and that's just like the problem we're
having with cannabis in like uh was that
a pityolax or you know just like the THC
pills that they sure synthesize the
Marinol yeah the Marinol yeah yeah you
know oh yeah Felix I think is okay yeah
they tried 30 years ago that's what they
were married that was going to be the
answer yeah any kind of question for
medical marijuana yeah they thought that
that was just going to nip it in the bud
right there and obviously they were
wrong yeah because there was an entire
culture based around it like no other
plant I mean it wasn't an entire 30
years of black market sales of comfrey
and clover you know what I mean like so
that they're they and that's where it's
it's difficult because the Cannabis
culture it was market-based as well and
that's where plant medicines have always
fallen into that for the same reasons
where you have big Pharma you have
pharmaceutical companies and obviously
you know the scientists just can Zone in
on what plant is benefiting you know a
certain ailment or an illness and then
of course you know that's where they're
trying to tackle it yeah how do we
tackle this from a monetary and that's
the problem it's like Farmers the
science is really good for identifying
the compounds like without them we
probably wouldn't know all these
compounds in cannabis in the very good
identifying that's where they come in
very valuable the money to identify the
compounds and to understand how they
interact with us but then when it comes
to the monetization it gets ruined it
yeah it gets around it's the same thing
that's happened with psychedelics right
now we all know that there's a power in
psychedelics and and mushrooms and and
and we're creeping down that road now
where so much is still way on not
understood and I don't think that my
ecology and mushrooms is going to be I
don't think it's as easy to understand
and break it down as as plants obviously
we know that there's a whole
communication
uh language that's happening under the
ground that you know might take us all a
long time to really truly understand
that you know but as you as we start to
see this industry now unfolding around
that
you know it's got me a little uh
trepidatious about you know like how we
do this with such little knowledge when
it comes to that and as far as getting
into the wrong hands and and the wrong
you know
um intentions
you know yes yes it's all valid concerns
well and
the the interesting part of that to me
is
finding the balance between a plant
being illegal or a fungus or whatever
being completely illegal so there's no
research happening there's no
you know motion forward in the general
populace understanding how it benefits
Humanity
and then it goes to regulation
and instead of improving that
information it becomes stifled in a
different way because it's focused
in a unique way to to control yes it's
hoarded the knowledge becomes hoarded to
control the outcomes yeah exactly yes so
it's like basically the freedom of the
plant was made criminal or the fungus
what have you and then it becomes
regulated and stifled on this greater
level and like how do we get back to a
Freedom of Information and research to
actually get the truth behind these
compounds at a larger level
citizen science some type of like
Collective Union of you know concerned
citizens that pool money to perform
independent research perhaps citizen
science what a great segue for me to ask
you a little more about the cha
education platform oh sure the entirety
of the kind of concept of that business
so tell us for those of you that do that
don't know what chai is it's cannabis
Horticultural Association yep
cha colloquially known as cha just for
fun but yeah the Cannabis Horticultural
Association was founded in 2016.
and it was founded to essentially create
a platform to promote organic and
ecological management for cannabis okay
to and I built it it was going to be
well it still is is a website it has a
membership you sign up to be a member
and then you get access to this database
and it's essentially like an online book
that's I'm able to you know populate
with new data as it emerges I've been
working on that
I'll admit the last few years have been
rough and I haven't updated it as much
as I should but it still contains uh
quite a bit of knowledge and it's still
being updated pretty regularly
when I can and um
you know I I really see this as a long
long standing project I modeled it after
The Royal Horticultural Society because
this was an association or a society
that was been around for 100 years you
know and it's for promoting plant
science and I hadn't seen anything like
this in cannabis and I wanted to create
something that was unique and and
something that meant meant something to
me in terms of
so what type of world I want to see
exist in the future for my kids which is
you know organic or ecological or
regenerative you can just like label it
one of those words I've started leaning
towards ecological because other words
are you know a little bit loaded
sometimes people you know always like oh
well organic is like just a USD label or
regenerative there's no definition it's
subjective yeah it's a subjective thing
and it's hard to quite pin that down but
anyways all that aside I created it to
do just that which is educate and
promote these these Concepts and
hopefully
as this Association grows I'll be able
to have more and more research money
where I can actually conduct more and
more research science like that's really
what I want to do I do want to set this
up to be like the consumer reports for
cannabis we're like we can like test
products be like okay like let's test Dr
Earth's powder versus green you know uh
what's the other company I can't
remember green group yeah thank you like
let's just like test like friendly
competition like let's like test these
products out and like test them out
against each other and see how they
perform and then like do side by sides
and have like you know research science
are like let's see what happens if you
know a plant gets infested with spider
mites like can we how do we treat it
with let's see about uh this persimilus
you might
um Can it withstand Bavaria basiana as
well if we have this aphid problem you
know like try to test some of like the
more complex science behind bio merging
bio controls in horticult culture and
that's what I'd like to see long term
with this you know this business I love
it it's an enduring tribute to the you
know grander scheme of the plant and
cultivation I think I really love that
and
personally that really speaks to me I do
a lot of the research and development
for Royal gold so it's always about
accelerating the knowledge and changing
the game I there's no need or desire to
try and do what other people are doing
let's find a new way to do it
differently not necessarily better not
necessarily worse but let's do it
different let's find different ways to
create new expressions of the plants
yeah and to feed the biology and the
entirety yes of you know
the yeah how do we optimize plant growth
with the combination of biology and
chemistry how do we do that very
succinctly put I like that yeah yeah
yeah and that's come a long way when you
look at the the Cannabis industry
already in the last 15 or 20 years
the way we've figured out how to grow
cannabis definitely is has definitely
opened up some eyes in big AG you know
they've learned a lot from us yeah and
see that's another thing like another
window in the Cannabis is open not
identifying pesticides herbal medicine
just practice biological practices ways
to streamline nutrient management for
sure it's another awareness period you
know a big AG man they've just yeah it
was a world that they really weren't
familiar with yeah until a couple years
ago oh man a couple decades ago yeah
they're freaking killing soil and
producing cardboard plants and there's
so much more to it than that yeah it's
so true that's another system of control
if if you kill everything off
and destroy the cycling then you become
dependent on the supplier to put new
available form of this nutrient back in
the soil so it's essentially control and
you know that that biological feedback
loop keeps forcing larger and larger
consumption of nitrate nitrates
nitrogens potassium
you just triggered a very deep level of
awareness Beyond because I had thought
about that in terms of the human aspect
but I did not consider that for the
Earth aspect and it's creating this
interesting merging of awareness now I
get it well and tie it back to fossil
fuels where are all of the nitrogen
sources coming from for commercial
agriculture
it's all this oh that's the depth the
depth timer
I forgot to shut it off I've done that
before I'm like I'm on airplane mode oh
this is my take the laundry out yeah and
shut it off from the fall well lucky you
you're not pulling tarps right now no
thank God that was the alarm to be like
congratulations yeah yeah I kept it on
just like you may yeah it was like a
victory alarm yep exactly
yeah have a drink and relax and just
yeah but yeah I hear you man so it's all
that nitrogen's coming out of the fossil
fuel industry yeah the blue nitrogen
coming from natural gas refinement and
so it's so ubiquitous
um you know go to this
um you know fertilizer conference every
year app go it's you know the
association of fertilizer producers
basically and you know go in we're
sitting down at these meetings you know
because it helps us understand how to
label products and create new products
within the system that's allowed in ways
to label and create new things
and just standing there sitting and you
see the lobbying happening in these
meetings
for blue nitrogen and for fossil fuel
products and you see
the kind of behind the scenes workings
manipulating the regulation bodies to
lean towards these types of products and
it's it's just fascinating to me coming
from a world of yeah you know fighting
against these systems and then going and
sitting in these meetings and being like
Oh my God it's real it's happening you
get to see it the real it's like an idea
until you're actually there watching it
happen yeah it's a conspiracy theory
until you see it happen yeah yeah if
you've always often joke I heard some
rapper recently is like joking around
it's like people always like talk about
conspiracy theories and it's like
there's unions all the time working you
know lobbyists working to like con
conspire to create rules and regulations
like it's not that outside the scope of
reality to consider like how much
conspiring actually occurs like
absolutely it's like it's a joke if you
think about it like it's of course it's
of course it's going on right and that's
where I think you know associations
foundations
collaborations
like the Cannabis Horticultural
Association
placed such an important role like
some of these enduring bodies things are
kind of feeding the comments I just
gotta I just gotta I gotta bear down and
like I've been in my little bubble like
metaphorically like building the root
system and now I think we're ready to
like grow and go you know on the
national level and they need to figure
out a way to probably create like
chapters
you know in each state probably
something like that has been rattling
around in a subconscious and figure out
who's going to run the chapters and then
that way we can pull resources and
collectively build if I could do that we
could collectively build the information
on the website it will grow
significantly faster
so I'm trying to I need to figure out I
think it's an important thing you know I
mean coming out of Humboldt obviously
you know we've always been kind of a
leaders in
in cannabis everything yeah I mean
honestly we just got we saw you down the
emerald cup you know Emerald cup was
it was a testament to that I felt like
there were Growers from all over the
country and so many of these new states
that have gone legal and changed their
laws recently
and I and I kind of enjoy it and and was
uh I adored the idea that some so many
of them felt the need to come humble
yeah and and to tap in to be like you
know hey if we're gonna do this here in
New York or oh yeah Missouri or
something like that where else to go
than to tap in
Trumbull County Northern California
Emerald cup and talk to Growers and talk
to some of the companies that have been
around since the beginning and and the
network and and also to feel the culture
you know I think that there's a big part
there not everybody in every new state
is uh an MSO looking for for the next
best uh you know publicly traded
cannabis company a lot of them are
getting into it in their state and
really wanting it to be a part of the
old cannabis culture
um that we've had here for 40 or 50
years you know and I think there's no
place in the emerald Cup in a lot of
ways to go in a tap into that and
experience that and see what it's like
and I mean the industry is you know it's
not at its best right now Market wise
especially and people are struggling but
you wouldn't have necessarily known that
or felt that at the emerald cup no it's
pretty vibing this year rainbows and
unicorns last year was a bit like shaky
but this year I talked to people it
seemed like way more stable sales were
up at least from some reports yeah so I
think you know overall it seems like a
good rebound so far and I agree with you
I think
Humboldt is the it's the epicenter of
this whole explosion it's like the micro
the the the the the root the fungal
Network that like sporulates out I mean
the whole Pacific I shouldn't just say
homo because I got friends it's really
the Pacific Northwest from British
Columbia to Humboldt it's like the micro
belt even down yeah
I don't want to single eye because then
you get people you know it's like it's
like more of a metaphor like because I I
obviously favorite favoritism to the
place where I live but but you're
absolutely right this whole sort of band
along the Pacific Northwest is this like
epis and then humble almost as like this
because we're near the Redwoods it's
like maybe the center of it well we were
obviously pushing out the majority of
the weight that was going out to the
rest of the world indeed for the most
part I mean Mendo and Trinity were in
there and obviously you can do you can
throw Monterey and Sonoma and everywhere
Southern Oregon you know yeah but Weight
Wise I don't think anybody that's not
even a bait I don't think right I mean
I'm almost definitely kicking out the
majority of the weight yeah so and
people would recognize it and I mean I
remember going back to Virginia
10 years ago and be like oh where are
you from I'm like humble and they're
like oh you know just immediately it's
like oh you're weed you know you don't
have to say anything you just said
humble and it was like oh weed yep it's
just like known yeah people stop you on
the streets if you have Humboldt on your
hat or your shirt and they're like oh
humble huh yeah hey we have made and
humbled on the back of our shirts I
can't tell you how many times I was at a
restaurant somewhere out way far from
this place and somebody would come up to
the restaurant and see the back of my
shirt and have to ask me about it you
know yeah exactly and so it's really
interesting and you know one thing that
kind of drives me crazy and I'm not
trying to take direct shots but the
Humboldt tourism Board needs to get
their heads together and recognize that
this community is going to benefit from
Cannabis tourism and there's this
problem and they just need to recognize
that they need to incorporate the
Cannabis community and not ostracize
them for for some perception of some old
way of life because there's plenty of
old people here that also support
cannabis yeah and I don't know I've just
heard you know I've heard it they're not
very friendly to cannabis and it drives
me crazy yeah it hasn't really started
very you know I mean you think at this
what are we five five years past yeah 64
just about three four years
you know we've been talking about that
for 10 years I mean there was talk about
you know cannabis farm tours and the bus
that goes up the hill and takes you to
three Farms on one Hill and and yeah and
it hasn't really happened they could
just make an ad like show the redwoods
in the in Patrick's Point and like smoke
weed come to Humboldt and just get
really High Grade weed from the farms
and have a good vacation and it's like
you can tap it into some culinary stuff
yeah with the Avenue of the Giants yeah
and the seafood with the ocean and just
like oh man it would be so easy to do I
really feel like
so many farms
and Mom and Pop
people that would have survived this
falling out of the Cannabis industry
didn't because people haven't acted fast
enough on some of these Concepts the
people that had you know a small
Greenhouse but extensive Gardens and
produce most of their own food who
aren't growing cannabis anymore because
they just can't yeah they lost their
licenses didn't get the license
etc etc we've yeah as a community in a
large way turned our back on the
Heritage that these people brought us
yes and it has affected their ability to
hold on and contribute yeah I agree I
have a lot to say about that actually
um maybe in as few words but you know
from my there are certain members of the
community you know in positions of power
or influence that you know always even
just member community members always you
know they ripped the humble Community
because of these grow dozers and Hill
grows and like big money and they're
just like spending money and then
leaving and going to Costa Rica which
did exist it was your thing but what
they didn't realize is that there's
actually a proportionately much higher
number of Growers that are just families
and they're community members that are
serving the fire departments and the
local soccer leagues and the local
community centers and the businesses and
and the schools and they're donating
their volunteer time to all of these
organizations that are fueling our
social network and and they don't and
and so and the problem also then existed
in the permitting regulations where a
lot of them lived in on pieces of land
that weren't able to get these permits
they should have set up some type of
variance permitting that allowed like
neighbors to agree or you know something
there should have been a better
permeating system for small-scale
cultivators and Humboldt and and then
you know having some type of collective
you know group of them come together
might have been a better situation but
it didn't happen and it's tough it comes
from years of everybody not necessarily
you know
working as a unit you know what I mean I
mean for for the longest time even if
you're friends with your neighbors on
the hill you know you still for the most
part you'd keep your distance you didn't
necessarily want to tie in or be too
close to the neighbor because you never
know what's going to happen with that
neighbor yeah or who the workers that
they were going to have over that year
or maybe they're going to get busted and
Lead over to you I mean there was still
a very you know private yeah I'm doing
my thing over here you know and that's
tough because we needed so much more of
a Cooperative relationship yeah with
everybody right out of the gates and I
think because it was every man for
themselves for the most part that we
didn't have yeah that maybe the voice
The Voice putting that towards the
community no one wanted to talk because
they didn't want to we're all scared to
death then you get abated oh you're who
right here's your abatement I know like
yeah well again it's a systemic and
systematic oppression by separating and
dividing the people that created the
culture to try and keep them from
growing enough yeah to actually Ascend
and when it got past the point of no
return then it was regulated in a way
that kept them out of the new system
yeah and it it really basically
set up the failure of all of these farms
and it's limiting the knowledge it's
limiting the community and it's allowing
big money and big agriculture to take
over what community yeah created and
it's really sad and baffling but I think
we do have a voice and we do have a way
to continue to grow this community amen
and to bring it back and change
culturally from the inside out these
systems that tried to oppress it in the
first place I like that I think that's a
positive outlook and I fully support
that it's sure not going to be easy no
but we have to work together and that's
the key I think now
we're a tight enough unit
that were like so when I went to this
showing of tending the garden that movie
so sad I missed that that was put on by
you know Claire and Jesse and those guys
everyone in that theater it was like it
was it was really interesting because a
lot of those people I knew and some of
them I had never met before but it was
it was a giant family it didn't matter
it was basically if you are here now
you were a family and we're here to help
like it doesn't matter who you are or
what our differences have been like if
you made it this far like we're here to
like Network together and and provide
resources and put pool resources and
share information and figure out a way
we can make this work that's literally
where I feel like from the small scale
farm that's where we're at in Humboldt
is like everyone's here to just band
together now at this point against the
big corporates man that's so amazing I
was talking to Jesse about the event and
the way you just described it really
kind of summed up what he was saying
nice in a whole different way and you
know it was really special it was really
awesome I was like I felt like I don't
know it was a really cool connection
like I felt like we've made it this far
yeah we can make it the rest of the way
yeah exactly and I wish there was a way
to like you know
lock in some of the funds that have been
allocated to helping Humboldt County in
the Emerald Triangle because there are a
lot of funds out there
and some of it's been used in Sacramento
you know to keep in state hasn't really
we haven't gotten anywhere there's still
I think probably half the counties in
California that still really don't allow
any right cannabis or dispensaries or
anything like that the outdoor Market
you know in the major cities in in San
Francisco and L.A you know it's it's
always been favorable towards Endor yeah
you the way out is to go over out of
state to go to be allowed to sell your
product throughout the entire rest of
the country is it possible to secure
some of those funds and actually have a
Lobby you were saying every industry's
got a Lobby and they're all making these
deals and right I mean that's exactly
what the Emerald Triangle needs but it
has to go to Washington yeah I mean I
feel like that's the only way forward is
to be able to because yeah this flower
is completely in high demand for the
rest of the country it's just something
yeah for sure California and you just
got to figure out right you get the
group together then you have to figure
out
because collectively it would be nice
but probably still low on the money
monetary end of influence so to speak
then you'd have to figure out some type
of incentive what incentive are you
going to give to the congressman I mean
this is how it works exactly I mean like
what are you gonna do oh well we have
this app that you know if downloaded
then we'll allow interstate commerce
we'll give you a percentage of the app
right it's very words like you know like
that's just a stupid way Congress works
and it's unfortunate but that's like
play the game if you want to play the
game like figure that out you got to pay
to play it's crazy but I mean that's
something that you know if that had
happened even just a couple years ago as
all these new States go legal you know
it's an amazing thing so many of them
don't have any kind of history in
cultivating themselves you could still
probably allow a home grow as part of
your legislation that passes but for the
actual overall populist Market of each
of these states you know right up into
places like New York you you know what I
mean like you could probably just go out
open up dispensers everywhere and not
really even have a cultivation part of
the bill knowing that you could be
supplied from a place like California
whether it's indoor Greenhouse like that
and indoor we could take care of you in
New York and all the other states too we
got you right you know but as if we're
still legal and you can't go over over
state lines every state that goes legal
has no choice but to set up an entire
brand new infrastructure on cultivation
yes yeah yeah yeah no it would be nice
to tap interstate commerce and it's like
you said it's crazy like 50 plus percent
of the counties in California don't
allow anything retail sales anything
it's crazy that's a crazy thing
especially how big California is yeah
that that would be 29 counties I want to
say yeah that's crazy who did who who
just passed that the beard bro is just
uh you know they had a news article it
was about that it was about some senator
tacking on uh interstate commerce little
blit do you guys remember that was that
I must have missed it well yeah Oregon's
pushing for it pretty good there was
like a blip in a congressional Bill
about allowing interstate commerce
for small farms I don't know if it was
Mike McGuire like he was some Senator
representative that'd be amazing I I'll
find it for you guys I'm pretty sure
there was some little blip that got it I
love the writer I would love that a
Maguire did that yeah no no I'll find it
I'm pretty sure like something did not
do that
oh amazing so
this is
a very deep conversation we've got a
long way to go here I'm going to propose
we take a quick break yeah let's do that
I'm gonna fire one up sweet those of you
who know at home the conversation gets a
little looser once we start blazing and
we'll be back in just a few minutes to
delve a little bit deeper thank you for
listening to Royal Grill radio
[Music]
foreign