[ __ ] you passport
[Applause]
[Music]
hey everybody Chad Westport here and I
am here to give you my updated
impression of the SE 5000 light from
spider farmer
now about six months ago I did an
unboxing video just kind of show you how
to assemble it give you my immediate
Impressions but I said that I wasn't
ready to give it you know a two thumbs
up or a review at that point simply
because I hadn't used it yet and a good
review
you gotta use it so
I've used it and I've got two full runs
under my belt using the SE 5000 spider
farmer light and I've been pretty stoked
I mean this is top of my head this is
all in one take because I wanted my
opinions just to be natural didn't want
to use script or do anything like that
with this one uh but what can I say you
know I don't have expensive light meters
to give you precise numbers with par in
the corners and in the center I don't
have all that but I can tell you how the
plans performed for me now I also
haven't used every single light that's
out on the market this is a 480 watt
light so what I'm going to be doing is
comparing it to similar wattage lights
that I've used in the past
comparatively
I'm stoked with this one this one is a
good one
um the plants overall they were happy
you know when you've used like blurple
or you know like HIDs and you switched
lights you can almost tell that plants
for some reason just like seem happier
if that makes sense to you but you look
at your plants and you're just like
you're happy today aren't you so that's
something that I could tell you that I
witnessed that I saw
um even with the lights you know like
right on the canopy I didn't witness any
type of light stress or burning of the
leaves or bleaching of the colas and
again 480 Watts probably not going to do
that but still providing enough light to
get me some nice fat colas
um I didn't raise or lower it really I
kind of let things grow up into it I use
the dimmer which I'll get into here in a
second
um and that's fine the the plants didn't
really stretch to the light either see I
mean they're kind of growing nice and
compact naturally how they want to grow
how they're you know genetic morphology
is it's not stretching up it says I'm
getting enough right here we cool I'll
just grow slowly so that's that I did
mention the dimmer though just kind of a
few of the features that I liked about
this light that I used you know pretty
much all lights are dimmable these days
we got the dimmer right up here
so yeah that kicks ass use that the
driver too which it's on it's mounted
right here for me I keep it inside the
tent but it's something that you can
mount outside of the tent if you live in
a really hot climate or you need to keep
the heat down in your tent where I live
I'm not too worried about it and
actually for the winter it helps it
offers a little bit of heat it's not a
very good heater but you also don't want
it to be a heater so there is an
advantage to This Light it runs
relatively cool especially for the
wattage and the little trick for most
LEDs if you dial it down to 80 percent
the heat signature is half of what it
would be if you turn that light up to
100 so keep that little trick in mind
this light is no exception
um power cord again is long enough that
you can mount it outside you can raise
and lower it without having to move your
power strip I've had to do that in the
past if you wanted to you know from your
end of your flower to the beginning your
veg the cord's too short so now you got
to readjust your power strip and you got
to do everything no it's got a long
enough cord thank you for that spider
farmer
um another big advantage that I liked
over the blurpose which was my
introduction to the LED world there's no
fans there's no Motors there's no
humming there's no loud noise it's a
quiet light and you know to that it
effects too it's not really a power hog
either
um no noticeable like bump in my power
bill switching from some smaller lights
multiple smaller lights that equal the
same wattage uh to the one big light of
that wattage no no big bump there so
that's cool
another thing that I really like and
this is kind of almost common for most
lighting companies these days people are
going with the bar style lights uh after
the blurple I moved into the quantum
boards which is just kind of the
rectangle uh it doesn't cast the light
as evenly as the bar style does it
tended to create a hot spot in the
middle but with the bars kind of spread
out the light disperses there's airflow
in between I like it doesn't create
those hot spots as much so Booyah to
that
um also full coverage I'm in a 4x4 tent
okay so we got edge of the light edge of
the tent edge of the light edge of the
tent safe distance away not going to get
too hot to start a fire or nothing in
the tent but it covers the whole
footprint which is freaking rad no dead
spots maximize your space this light
perfect for a 4x4 grow tent uh
proof is in the pudding right I mean
here is some pictures of plants that I
have grown in here as you can see you
know nice Bud formations on this one a
nice chunky all the way from the top to
the bottom
you've got this plant here which is just
a trichome machine again all the way
from the top
down to the bottom and here's some other
plants that I have grown in this tent
under the SE 5000 light from spider
farmer and I tell you what no complaints
here Great Smoke grow in the fire as you
can see too you know the light it gets
good penetration that's something that
you always want to test how far into the
canopy is it going to go you don't want
to trim larf so you trim the bottoms up
well where do you stop I think I found
the sweet spot with this light and it
goes pretty deep so stoked on that more
Bud the better less trimming the better
too so don't grow larf everybody
um
that's top of my head
I think that's kind of it you know I'm
I'm happy with this light it's a good
light it fits the tent keeps the plants
happy grows me nice colas it gives me my
return after just two runs the light
itself has already paid for itself with
the money that I've saved from going to
the store and that weed sucks I grew the
fire here at home in my tent under the
SE 5000 spider farmer light so should
you everybody overgrow grow your own at
home lights are an important part of
that so if you're looking if you're
curious if this one has been on your
mind
hey I'm stoked with it I would
definitely use it
I spent money with spider Farmer in the
past buying their lights this one comes
from the factory I did not pay for that
I want to let you know
again I've did my research in the past
I'm a Frugal guy I choose where to spend
my money and spider farmer is where I
spent it which is why they were the one
company I said yeah okay we could work
together on a light thing because I've
been approached by many they're the only
ones I said yes to and that's for a
reason so if you have any specific
questions hit me up in the comments if
you have your own experience with these
lights or maybe compared to something
else if you went here went there and
then came back let me know that's what
the comments are for so I appreciate
your time today I hope this was
beneficial for anybody and everybody
again specific questions hit me up I'm
happy to answer them but in the meantime
you can catch me on my website
chadwestport.com
Instagram is chad.westport and right
here on YouTube Chad Westport so yeah
thanks for hanging out thanks for
checking out the lovely ladies and the
se5000 light from spider farmer stoked
party on
I believe
[Applause]
[Music]