Audi okay next field notes we're in our
African sativa section now so this is
Senegal this is from Senegal this is in
African land race and uh
this and it's October 23rd and this one
I would say these are getting very
close to harvest time we may be
harvesting uh within like five days or
so
um but I'm really impressed with the
Senegal as a uh potential uh production
plant because it really actually has
very thick chunky colas it actually
finished October 23rd is not
a crazy finish time and uh yeah it's not
super late
um
nice chunk
and the smell
it's just all different kinds of
perfumes and astringent sort of mothball
cleaner smells
um I wouldn't say really sweet I smell
like one more time
yeah it's like soft
but kind of uh
yeah like a cleaner kind of smell with
some perfume in there and then here's
the other one from Senegal so we'll take
a look at this uh this one has very
similar just a little more uh maybe
slightly more torpedo spear shape
uh this one has the more pleasant
African sativa sort of grassy actually
it very much smells like this may sound
a little weird but um
if you cut a parsnip or a carrot but
really a parsnip and a fresh astringent
parsnip smell that is actually very
that's that's the smell that's coming
off of here a freshly cut uh raw parsnip
anyway again this could make a nice
production oh yeah actually a nice
chunky sort of modern looking colas and
it's actually finishing up uh October
23rd so I'd say by Halloween we'll be
harvesting though so uh very excited to
sample so anyway Senegal
cool