hey tyler mr trees uh today we're
setting up a little garden vegetable box
and i wanted to give a little tip on uh
slug and snail prevention as well as
other bugs and stuff and show you kind
of what i do
to set up a little mini garden box so uh
first things first i get my
box
i get things planted seeds put in you
know et cetera et cetera
um and then i want to get it covered up
and i want to get it protected put a
barrier so i always set up
some copper tape
basically copper
is what's up buddy
doing your thing
so copper actually interferes with
that
yeah that's you look at you yeah yeah
rocking and rolling yeah we're talking
shh
so
copper actually uh interferes with
the slime of slugs and snails it gives
them this
electric shock or charge as they get
near it and try to cross over it kind of
like a an electric fence for a dog or a
cattle or chickens or whatnot it just
gives them that kind of jolt pisses them
off just enough to send them the other
direction doesn't kill them doesn't hurt
them just kind of lets them know that
they're not allowed to go in this little
area you don't have to re-apply it you
don't have to buy anything new you don't
have to use any types of products and
other things like that
ultimately you're just
sticking and forgetting and then your
your slug is now free so the copper
copper tape
comes from a lot of the different
nurseries
uh you can get it home depot you can
order it online you can do all kinds of
stuff but you just get a roll this
little tape here copper on one side and
it's a sticky back side here you just
peel it off
slightly and then
usually on the top of a garden box or
around any
rim of any pot
you can put it around anything it will
stick to most anything which is pretty
cool
and as soon as a slug or a snail
tries to pass over it
they will not be able to so
we just run this around the entire
top rim
or bottom rim or
whatever you want to do
and
you ensure
box
just like so
if it breaks off like it just did just
tape it back on
and you start working it
all the way
around the entirety
of the box and when we're done
it breaks off super easy
tuck it in the roll
and we're good to go
this box is now super protected now you
can go around and you want to press it
you want to make sure that you got it
stuck on there nice and
you can do some reinforcing of
you know various kinds to make sure that
it sticks perfectly but
that's essentially all you need to do
you don't have to reapply it you have to
do anything that's enough to piss off
anything so slugs and snails are taken
care of
next
we get some pvc pipe
and
the edges of all
get another one
about you know a foot
foot and a half
to two feet usually is where i start
setting them
every foot and a half two feet in the
ground it goes boom
two
turn that up as best you can
grab yourself another one
stacked in
and you just do this
for however long your
boxer bed is
got another one
basically you're building a little
tunnel a little hoop
it doesn't even have to be crazy
or super secured unless you're in a real
windy area and then you can you can
pound these in and make them really nice
and tight
demonstration purposes we don't need to
do anything crazy like that then we get
my favorite thing in the world mosquito
netting
blocks out most
most pests
and
i'm not sure if this piece is going to
be big enough but i got lots of other
pieces here
but basically you get yourself a piece
that's going to cover your box
you can order it uh online
you can get it at fabric stores
stuff like this
and you basically
cover
cover up your box
you can throw a couple of bricks or
something on here to keep this down so
you can get in and out of it easily but
bang you got yourself a vegetable box
um
95 of pests
they're not going to be there they can't
get there
nothing get there through the air
nothing can kind of get through on the
underneath
so you're in great shape
you can kind of take extra precautions
and
tuck this around your tape and really
make it nice take some time or you don't
have to but i just wanted to throw it
out there just quick and easy it took us
just a few minutes set it up it's done
and over with i can walk away and not
really worry much
tyler mr trees throw your comments or
questions down below we'll see if we can
get to them i'll do my best to touch
everyone and uh we'll uh we'll keep
rolling if you got ideas or questions
just just hammer them at me
have a good day take care of each other