hello how are you doing today i'm going
to give you a tour of my garden today in
southern oregon
my name's mike i go by the name dozier
grower on discord and southern oregon
soil on instagram i'm gonna go ahead and
give you a tour starting with the
strains and the breeders
start with this first plant uh this is a
pre-98 bubba kush from 2020 mendocino
she's about 65 days flowering time it
says
she's just now starting to put on some
thickness
and stacking up
it looks really good
uh these next three plants are going to
be from humboldt seed company and their
pineapple muffin
they say about 45 to 55 days for flower
and they're taking just a little longer
might because i'm further north and
humble
but they're putting on a lot of good
crystal a lot of good terps on them
this is pineapple muffin as well
and again pineapple muffin
by humboldt seed
these next ones are also humboldt seed
they are all gas og
they all seem to be different phenotypes
they are 55 to 65 days
they are just really putting on some
weight now
this one doesn't seem to have any purple
in it yet
this
one is the biggest of them
um
and she is just now starting to put
color on
and the third one here
has decided to just put the color on
right away
as you can see
very pretty color
this next one here is gorilla skittles
from barney's farm
and she is doing very well she's another
65 day
55 to 65.
um
definitely leaning towards the gorilla
glue side of it not really seeing any
skittles colors coming out but uh
her coal is
really nice
these next two
are
[Music]
melon runts from elevate seeds
really impressed with uh
the smell
um and the bud structure on these
this is another melon runts and again
these are 55 to 65 days
and then these last two girls down here
are again by humble season they're
stupid fruits and they say they're at
about 70 day flowering time
i need to clean them up a little
very nice putting on some
really good buds and coalish
uh as you can see i like to clean up
inside the plants
i'd also like to give a shout out to
soilscape solutions
i've been using their four-year program
not the complete program but the uh
nitrogen phosphorus potassium
the micronutrients
as well as the humic
and i think i've been getting a really
really good response to it
as you can see
um quite frosty
um
have a lot of ladybugs and um
the ipm's been really good this year i
have a feeling it has to do with some of
the companion plants that i'll get to
here in a little bit
but again
really impressed with the soil escape
solution
for your feeding
i believe it has a helped immensely with
the uh
crystal production and the terpenes
so again big shout out to soilscape
solutions i'm gonna go over
my soil and my pots i am using living
soil this year i'm using a blue matte
system
with blue matte carrots and blue matte
soaker hoses
i actually am very lucky i have well
water that runs at about six five
ph um so i can just run it right off the
tap
it goes into a psi reducer which i don't
let it get above 40 and then that goes
into
a blue matte reducer which takes the psi
down to 15.
then i've run
the soft eight millimeter line
and made a manifold
and
it runs down
either inside of the pots
and then there is two carrots in
each pot
as you can see let's look under here
lots of worms
um and as i say the roots do
grow up to the hoses
so
i'm using a straw cover
as well as a clover i have
basil i have chamomile
and i believe lemon balm in here
i put a ant trap near the bases
of the trees because they that way i
don't get any aphid problems from ants
it goes straight for that i also have 18
inch blue matte
digital monitors
in pots
keep it a little drier during flowering
so
they don't need as much
again the hoses are in a ring
as you can see
and one last thing you'll notice is uh
they're 200 gallon pots that i've
wrapped with pallet wrap
to kind of mimic the grassroot fabric
pots living soil pots
to kind of reduce the evaporation
so that has been working well
we had a really hot summer up here this
year
um a couple weeks and over a hundred
consistently on the days
um and the system worked really well
uh the plants loved it
and you know for everything said and
done with all the smoke and the hot days
this year
uh my first year living soil
i think it's turning out fairly well and
i'm very impressed with uh
the process and i think i will stick
with it
thank you very much and if you have any
questions please get a hold of me