so I'm driving down the road and it's 6°
uh Canadian I think that's what the C
stands for uh 6° Canadian but what I'm
really driving down the road for is as I
passed coming down the other way all
these super gnarly mushrooms growing and
uh going to have to take a little stop
to to see what's going on nope not this
one got went into the wrong [ __ ]
house they might not like me there but
we'll go over here because they got them
growing right up off the side of the
tree but what we got to do is Park real
quick poopity boop hey
people uh I don't know who you are but
hey it's all good uh where's the weird
Canadian flashers I don't know Canadian
stuff let's go see the
mushrooms let's go see the mushrooms
it's
mushrooms look at these
guys
look at that just popping
[Music]
up so
cool look at that
beautiful slug's been
munching oo these have already
G oh that one's a g
there it's cool that they only grow on
one
side
you guys want to see something else
that's really cool big ass Burl W look
at
this so
cool all slimy
stuff