foreign
hello everyone coming at you still live
Royal grown radio from the summer arts
2022 on the county line Ranch
we're super stoked to be sitting here
with Ted from Canada country farms
somebody who's been Legacy growing
cultivating bringing unique terpenes
unique profiles unique flavors to the
people
and we're stoked to sit down and kind of
get a little bit of an Insight on what
you do where you're at thank you yeah
you got to be here thanks yeah I'm
loving it finally get something to do no
doubt some activities been a long couple
years yeah I was like going through the
emerald cup 2021 with the whole kova
thing and it's like we won second place
in Sun grown and Breeders Cup and it was
like no one knows yeah totally so thank
God we're out here and we get to show
the trophies and get that herb out to
everybody and I'm so glad you mentioned
that because we were at that award
ceremony in LA
and afterwards we're like I'm not sure
who won what yeah it's a little
confusing I get it though you know you
did a great job yes or what it was good
job yeah absolutely make the best of
what we had yeah I mean they had one
right so exactly and we did good so
we're proud and it was one year that
that we had just entered in Three Blind
strains that he had been working on I
mean blind like no one knows they're
there
um just things we've been developing on
the farm for years and we finally
decided that we're gonna get them out
that we've gone and threw our Fino hunt
and we've picked and we made sure these
are the ones that we want and uh we had
three different strains and they placed
um second 19th and then we missed the
top 20 by one so out of the three
strange we were up in the top
20s
right yeah and uh having our our
forbidden fruit cherimoya 26 be you know
THC and take second place in the sun
grown and the Breeders Cup was just like
finally we got you know over the THC
thing and it's really about what it does
to you the effects the the high how you
feel the taste the smell the look it's
not just a piece of paper that says yeah
you have THC hot you win you know and so
it was just really good to see that what
we're doing is going in the right
direction and then just having those
strains low in the low THC Place High
was just like that was it for us
something we talk about often here you
know I'm definitely one of those people
that appreciates those main teams right
when it comes to THC yeah me too that's
what I want to smoke yeah one-to-ones
are going to be the future you own the
next couple of years watch if any of
these one-to-ones are really going to
take off where people are like I don't
no need to get that high I want to get
high and get influenced to do things or
get motivated and that's the you're
going to get that one-to-one where
you're really
comes down to where you can profile
yourself and you can find what works
good for you there's so much more
science involved now than when it was
just like here here's smoke that and see
if you like sativa or indica and now
it's like so far past all that those
lines are so blurry yeah because there's
sativas that are uplifting yeah
it's not just like it was where
everybody says sativism there's no
ground at the turkey most everything's a
hybrid these days anyway and they call
it an indica or sativa but really it's
been so breads both ways that those true
lines aren't really there exactly I feel
like the terpenes play such a role in
combination with the cannabinoid blend
it's not just THC it's not CBD it's CBG
it's CBN it's all these it's lesser
known and even under yeah even
undiscovered terpenes absolutely that's
the next thing it's like you see these
big spikes and they they do tests for 20
25 some tests for 85 different terpenes
but really you're not getting that you
know a terpene could have this much of a
mark on your graft and then one could
have this much but you're gonna taste
that little bit of that one because it's
so strong there's so many variants in
this terpene space that we don't even
know yet sorry and the way they interact
with the Cannabis receptors with the
cannabinoid receptors in our body like
oh there's just so much more science
that we need to continue to push to
learn this stuff but it keeps coming
back over and over to that sun grown is
better and you know as somebody who is
an indoor grower for most of my life I'm
a huge fan of indoor I love that loud
fresh yep but the science is proving
what we've known up here for a very long
time is that sun grown is better there's
a wider profile it affects you in a
different way I wouldn't have I I don't
know if I could say that in in just
saying it but having the data behind it
and the testing to to also back up my
nose which tells me what I'm looking for
you know it's really come a long ways to
where we're just we're really getting
that
that nose that fresh
I lost my place
that's awesome because that's actually
it sparked something in me that I
remember when you stopped by the booth
or we were talking to think Emerald cup
or Hollow flowers but since that moment
I've been wanting to get an opportunity
to speak with you you dropped a jar of
this on me and you were like yo take
this home yeah and it was like okay wait
but I want to talk more and we're both
going different directions and so we
didn't even really we're like we'll
catch up with you later all right and
this is the first opportunity since then
that we've gotten to connect yeah I have
to say tell us a little bit about this
genetic because it absolutely floored me
this is the forbidden fruit cherimoya
yes this is a forbidden fruit Jeremiah
it's a black on black it uh it'll turn
black only when it flowers the plant is
really almost a lime green and then as
soon as it starts to pod out the pods
are black from the beginning they're
that dark they don't get dark here
necessarily unless it's like a really
awesome cold snap at the very end but
that is what it's going to look like so
dark 100 degree weather it'll look that
way so you don't need the cold snap you
don't need anything
purple yeah I'm coming into the camera
Emily shout out to Emily our fantastic
visual coordinator
it makes me drool so I hope you at home
can really get yeah and that cross is uh
chedimoya forbidden fruit and the
chedimoya version of it the end of it is
is basically is a really good friend of
mine who helped me breed all these he
had this lineage of this plant that he
had taken from Humboldt to Maui and
mixed in things like princess Bob and
Columbiana and Chris and headband and uh
like old school
granddaddy purps wow and he's been
breeding Out The Greener portion of it
all and getting like the really dark
black on black and then he crossed that
with the forbidden fruit that came up
with the chadamoya and then there was
green and totally dark purple phenos
through the whole thing and in every
spectrum of it in between and so this
one was the one that my nose it brought
me back to when I was in high school and
uh my senior year I was working for my
my girlfriend's dad in the field you
know out in summer growing some herb and
that's that smell I smell that I
remembered smelling back in the day and
it was this Indica Burmese
that he was uh he had his cross of and
it was just like train wreck just Groove
big buds purple on the stock as well as
green and just had this beautiful ribbon
running down it and that was the smell I
remembered looked totally different
growing than what I remember it looking
like but the nose was there and so it's
it was just like the one for me I picked
out before it was even done this is the
one I'm Gonna Keep I mean that's the
thing that you know the visual on that
obviously it's beautiful yeah the color
is just unreal the nose on them so
intricate and and unique yeah it hits me
right in the face it's like nothing I've
ever experienced before yeah this is my
experience too I looked at the jar I'm
like sweet thanks and then like get back
to my room and open it up I'm like whoa
this is special this is unique I've got
a good friend Jason Kane who did the
piano Bibles and he actually is out in
Maui and we've had this discussion a few
times and doing some judging for the
books and stuff
plants change when they go to Hawaii
like you can take a genetic that you
grow on the mainland you take it to Maui
and there's just a little bit something
different and special about the Hawaiian
Islands yeah absolutely I feel like you
can get that tropical
like floral bouquet from that that it
kind of takes you there like yeah yeah
or like we were saying earlier like
almost rotten papaya like when you're
walking through the jungle you can smell
the papaya trees because they'll drop
them and it's like alcoholic on the
ground but I was like this is like that
it's almost boiled it's almost sourced
you're like oh a couple more days of
this and you have to throw that away
right and then the flavor actually
translates from that flour that's right
so that's one thing we breed for you
know if it if it looks good and smells
good but then it only tastes okay you're
cut from the team and it's so common it
can't can't play that b grade you got to
have all three at least if not you know
it's got to look good it's got to smell
good and it's Gotta smoke like it smells
yeah just the three Basics yeah you know
now you can work on well I wanted to
yield or you know is it a is it
resilient or it depends on what you're
breeding for you know we're breeding for
straight nose and then we wait until a
month after it cures before we pull it
out and smoke it and test it so we still
have once we're done we still have tons
of work to do it's never done and we
have to go through and I know we have to
right I'll go through but we have 25
Finos of one strain so we have to smoke
all those and we did five strings so you
know there's a lot of smoking a lot of
smoking well and it's not just they're
smoking it's like strength critical
analysis this is of not just smoking
exactly paying attention to everything
that's going on and we ran into some
strains from the 26 I think I had to get
cut from the team just because I ran out
of room to hold genetics but they were
like not the tastiest didn't have the
osamine but I smoke 20 joints that day
and this was like the 19th 20th joint I
smoked and it opened up my lungs like I
had never experienced before it was just
like was the smoke wasn't hot it wasn't
harsh it didn't even feel like smoke in
my lungs I was just
yeah wow and you're like I already feel
like you have oxygen in your lungs it
was like something I want to hunt in it
again I still have seeds to go through
and and find that strain but this is a
medicine strain this is it's got uh if
you add water to it it bleeds out like
wine okay we're smoking a joint my
buddy's boat fishing and uh you know
it's windy and I got a plate and it's
messy so I toss it the wind blows it
back in the cabin you know we're walking
back and forth catching fish and then
next thing we look down at bleeding
purple throughout the whole floor of the
boat wow where every little speck hit
just from the salt water mixing with it
I've never I went and did some tests at
home on my own and just it's amazing I
have some on my Instagram where I just
broke up some seeds and then I had all
this stuff and I threw some water on it
and poured it through the plate and it
just started turning more like wine and
more and more purple and it was just
kind of just an amazing strain that has
a lot of different properties for
everyone at home what is that Instagram
there's more for me but for you guys too
can of country farms okay yeah check it
out out yeah and Humboldt and we're
doing uh just a lifestyle living you
know Hunting Fishing and growing our own
herb next to our our fruit trees and our
veggies and raising our family right
where we're growing so it's a part every
day it's like our own kids like we're
taking care of them they're taking care
of us it's a it's a full circle you know
effort yeah yeah it's funny we call this
a living conversation but we also talk
about cultivating Community people we
say this is a cultivation focused
podcast and we talk about growing but
it's more than just growing cannabis
it's about growing your community your
family growing your Wellness yeah and
that's what this event's about proper
Wellness the Cannabis Village and summer
arts coming together I feel like it's a
really special time and absolutely I
really appreciate this opportunity to
sit down yeah I'm not surprised that it
happened here like this yeah I know
naturally yeah it's a perfect spot
we're three generations deep again A
Country Farm my kids are are really the
Legacy and they're the ones that are
going to be sitting here doing the next
interview well you know I'm on the farm
they're gonna take over this part but uh
it for now it's an honor being here and
and just loving the vibe here the roots
and back to the humble living you know
this is what brought us here is this
Market switch has been like a nightmare
in one way and an eye-opener in the
other of like where we are today and who
where do we want to be and this is where
we want to be this is why we came here
in the first place is that we have
Community we have great neighbors we
have food water we've got a clean living
we got a lifestyle that we still live no
matter what yeah you know it's just like
back to why are we here anyway we're
here because of the people we're with
we're here because of the atmosphere you
know and what it provides so we almost
couldn't do anything else anywhere else
no no I've where do I want to go is my
thought like okay this isn't working
like what what would I do if I didn't
live here and I
is there a better place to go and I'm
like no that's not I think that's what a
lot of us keep coming back to and
there's a lot of people leaving for you
know different pastors some people say
greener pastures I say different because
fast is always greener on the other side
of the hill but you know I think it's
very well said when you were mentioning
it it gives you a chance to kind of
reevaluate and reassert where you want
to be in life and follow that path so
yeah are you really dedicated to the
plant or are you really there for
certain reasons like maybe it's money
maybe it's who knows you know but it's
really comes down to like for me it's
back to my family and having that extra
time to take to be with them and then
the plant has always been number one for
us as well just as a family we we just
love doing what we do so we don't want
to stop doing it we want to we want to
create create great things for for
people to be just blown away at you know
we got 10 different strains that we're
just starting out with now and we're
doing all these crazy inner breeding
with them this year to come up with 100
different strains out of the 10 that we
have already and I love it that you're
not once have you mentioned or focused
on any of the like over hype streams
that everybody's talking about right now
all the genetics you're talking about
are relatively unique relatively unheard
of in the grander scheme of things and
people get stuck on all this hype [ __ ]
I've got to have this I gotta have what
this guy's doing I gotta have the thing
that I saw on the thing and you're just
like stick to your guns we know it's
always going to be hypesters out there
yes if you really are a conditioned
smoker you're going to be looking for
something else it's not like the college
kid that wants to go get drunk he's
gonna go get the cheapest beer you can
get it's like that THC High thing where
I'm gonna go and I'm gonna go in the
dispensary and get the cheapest highest
THC I can get well after a while you're
gonna get sick of that you're going to
win that you're going to learn about
wine you're going to learn about food
you're going to learn about different
kind of herb that you want to smoke
that's like you're graduating now you're
getting older you're getting more
experience with your cannabis
consumption and now you want something
different well we got something
different always we're always coming up
with something different so friends yeah
thanks that's not that we're not playing
The Hanger no doubt man well thanks for
bringing that uniqueness because that
hype [ __ ] comes out of people creating
with passion and all of a sudden people
start to discover it so you know I would
not be surprised to hear one of these
unique strains being the next type thing
that people are chasing from all over
the country yep so that is that's that's
the hope but we're also like keeping it
down home we want to be like if things
do happen here for us we would like to
be able to spread to our neighbors first
and help support them and then move on
from there and try and get it out but
we're really we're really trying to hold
on to our genetics and not get them out
right now just because we think that
having in-house genetics is is going to
be a good play later on to have the you
know exclusive genetics that you can't
find anywhere else that's grown in this
tear walk so I completely really trying
to keep it in the community first but
then get it to everybody at the same
time yeah that's so amazing dude thank
you so much Ted for coming and sitting
and taking the time with us today I know
it's a busy day people are trying to
come over and talk to you about Europe
and you're here sitting with us so my
pleasure thank you so much thank you
guys appreciate you right on thank you
thank you cool once again from Royal gun
radio
live from summer arts 2022 thanks again