finally live everyone chad's hair is
looking fabulous
and we're going to kick it off with a
little song i want everyone to sing it
with me so
just sing it
come and knock on our door we've been
waiting for you
chad i don't hear you where the kisses
are hers and hers and his threes
good job oh my god
yes no no cookies genetics
all right the hair stylist is working
overtime today for us today we're going
to have to put them on retainer
check my nails baby so that's always fun
when you you know you get to see a
friend's garden and you get to talk
about it that's what we're here for so
everyone just smile and look
sexy
for a three
that's a beautiful structure on that
plant
yeah she's really nice isn't it yeah i
like it a lot and i think kind of
learning what you can from every method
is really what i've always tried to do i
love talking to the synganic guys i love
talking to the hydro guys you know i
love talking uh
going from the land race and you start
reading it to one specific direction
describing them as like effects of
indica or sativa
really give a
a slight misinformation to keep that
going properly as well one of those
things like people will put seeds out
and you don't really hear much about it
and then all of a sudden like 90 120
days later you see a lot of a lot of
cooks
and so these are these are a couple
weeks old now these are these have made
it past the first live welcome everyone
to the perfectly imperfect grow show
candies to flower to dabs is that when
people
you know when people are saying that
they've had other dabs and other rosin
products and that they've been cheaper
packaging smaller and stuff like that
but
yeah that was a weird no again this is
something that i've just heard
secondhand from many people but
thanks for joining us i've been already
reading the comments in chat i
appreciate them we were peter was doing
a little training on
i did do par tests for um
yeah i stopped doing them a year ago but
i did them for a year
and this was basically just you got that
one hold on to that one forever
how about yourself indica you're out
there in the ground in the hoop house or
in your pots
what did you do there did you just dig a
hole did you remember
but i had to put like brackets to hold
it up and everything
nice
we're coughing you know it's been a good
pre-show
and the show has grown
yeah
little bit different so
and actually since we're on the subjects
buffery cocoa support what do you do to
buffer your cocoa how do you buff your
cocoa because
[Music]
that came through yeah yeah that came
through yeah
okay my my day is complete we can get on
with the show now so welcome everybody
i'm chad passport and we're here on the
perfectly imperfect grow show
yeah
we're here to have good times talk about
tent tours and home grows and uh
coffee up i don't know i don't know what
to say after that so i want to thank
everyone who showed up to watch this
video today and come hang out with us
and be a part of it all um thank you to
everyone in the community because we've
always reached out to each other and
asked questions and learned things off
of each other and sometimes watching
these future cannabis project videos and
chat we learn a lot going back and forth
about different things so i'm just so
thankful for everybody in this community
and i'm so thankful for fcp
uh i mean
i wouldn't have been able to learn a lot
of these things that i'm doing these
days if i didn't yeah happy 420
everybody i mean check my nails baby how
you feeling feeling good as hell
all right thank you everyone that is
yes no no cookies genetics
all right