[Music]
[Applause]
hi everybody chad westport here to give
you an update on the video i made a few
weeks ago about with my new space
whether i should go organic or stay with
what i've been doing and i've been
having success with
i've got to say thank you everybody who
commented you guys and girls gave me a
lot of awesome information a lot of
different approaches and actually saw
some of the questions that i had so it
was very useful i know that had probably
the most comments on the future cannabis
project channel ever
so again thank you everybody for your
help and your support
i don't want to delay this anymore
let me
i'll explain but let's
let's see what i am doing or what i'm
not doing so let me open the tent and
we'll get right to it
all right before the big reveal i also
want to say that i've been getting a lot
of questions about this spider farmer s
e 5000 light people are eager to know
how's it going for me what's it growing
like
i don't know yet but the good news is
this grow will be fully documented
you'll be able to see what the spider
farmer sc5000 light is doing for me
let's reveal my decision
all right so the hippies won but i've
got a long hair and a beard so you
really should have seen that one coming
and i actually did kind of change the
plans and some of this was based on the
comments that i got in the previous
video so again thank you uh as you can
see i've got two different soil blends
so i'm not going with the bed instead
i've got some seven gallon pots that i'm
going to rock these two soils in
now this
sohum living soil is a water only mix
so is this kiss organics makes
some people have poo pooed the thought
of
water only bagged soil
that's why we're going to put it to the
test and one thing to consider too is
i'm not going to be growing production
sized plants i am growing what the
average home grower is going to be
growing so we'll keep that in mind along
the way and see exactly how far these
are going to get us
you can catch updates here on the scp02
channel on the perfectly imperfect grow
show i'll be doing a monthly update
there as well as more updates on my
youtube channel it's chad westport i'm
also going to be doing a breakdown of
the ingredients and all of that for each
of these bags so head over to the
chadwestport channel
get more information about this soil but
i just wanted to let you all know
hopefully you're dancing in the streets
kumbaya i'm giving up the bottles for
this run and who knows if i'm impressed
it may stay like that so
i guess in the words of uh nate diaz
i'm not surprised mother
party on
[Music]
[Applause]
you