how I took over the
yard I started
with that one single 4x4
bed and then I added that one and then I
added added added and then I added
around the
tree and then did all that stuff over
there I'm also G to rip out
all these uh fabric pots and put
in uh wood and
octagon around the
tree we have a little Garden Project
right okay yeah I think so what are we
going to
do build a hexagon that's right so we're
going to take no bro why so see all
these wood pieces so what we're going to
do you sand them uh I have not sanded
them yet but we're going to make a
hexagon to go around so I'm going to
pull all these pots out of here mhm and
the
hexagon is going to go around there it's
basically a little over 3
feet uh actually yeah diameter
uh or from like middle to middle of both
sides Bubba are you just making more
space well that's a good question what I
wanted to do was if I could get rid of
all these pots and then I could build
the hexagon and then I could fill it
with all the soil from these pots and
then when stuff grows down it would also
grow into the
ground see like this morning glory right
over there which just yes baby
cake ba that is the Morning Glory I
think I think it was a very good idea
for you to make that axon because this
Garden looks like a junkyard with all
these thank you it that is true we're
going to make it look less like Sanford
and Sun's
junkyard so here here is our cutting
station right that's not really a good
cutting station all right so there's our
saw all right who doesn't touch the saw
you I am allowed to no definitely not we
don't want is it the opposite exactly we
don't want to chop your fingers off no
it's the opposite about you right and
about you you will not be touching that
saw but anyway so we're going to cut
each of the how many pieces of wood are
in the hexagon okay so we already have
two then four five I'm guessing about
six that is exactly right there's six
pieces of wood in the hexagon B why does
that look like deuce water that looks
like dece water look like I dropped a
big deuce because it has um I just it
has some uh I poured some water through
the worm bin and then I also put
some uh if you ground up
fish and it would be a little stinky but
plants love it
[Music]
make sure you don't okay so see how this
all right look at that with the
camera ready tap tap on I tapped it bro
you did bro are you my super camera
woman or how about you're my bro so now
so watch this so now I'm just going to
turn turn it this way and we're going to
do the same thing can I tell something
before you do that I would love but you
got the camera at me one
time so
here I think that's
[Music]
actually so basically what I'm going to
do is I'm going to
dump all these re amend them and then
put them in the use that soil in
the in the beds and then a lot of times
when I have way too much food scraps
baby cake they go and don't tell Mommy
but they go under all that
stuff but I can see a butt that well I'm
sure and is it a cute butt no no
[Music]
nice
see is that a good
cut is that the 30° angle you were
looking for that is not what it needs to
be 90° no 90 we we make a box make a
square or a rectangle
[Music]
we okay here the practical uses of your
high school geometry
[Music]
class
okay was anything on my face like any of
the w none of the wood dust is on your
face well some wood dust is
[Music]
flying so it's funny I was going to come
out here with a big bowl and smoke do
this
like there goes
this all right five
down one more to go for the bottom row
show that turd who's
boss show that Pooh who's BOS who's the
boss you are the
[Music]
Poo who does number to work
for oh you know what I was not paying
paying attention to which side I want on
the
outside that makes me
sad on the early ones I wor start you
will be the
[Music]
inside all
right so we got
here that's the bottom of the
hexagon so we got six
[Music]
pieces and those are going to
go around the outside around the
outside so anyway this will change from
and I'm waiting I just harvested a bunch
of this waiting for this stuff to finish
but as that finishes I'm just going to
amend all the soil in
there and use that as the
volume for the
hexagon
so
yesterday we
cut so we're making a raised
bed that is going to go around this tree
so I'm going to make a
hexagon and
so yesterday we cut the wood so we have
these
30°
Cuts so if you keep going that would be
a perfect hexagon these are each uh 3
and 1/2 fet
long
and basically what we're doing is we're
going to replace all these um Fab big
fabric pots with just one raised bed
around the tree
uh and then once uh like here I have
some tobacco finishing seeding out so
when that's done I'm going to cut all
that down I'll dump all the soil in here
but one of the thing so this is some
heart
Redwood and one of the things I'm going
to do right
now is actually Char it uh so I know
like
um I guess
like ancient Romans when they uh went
into like modern day Germany and France
and were building forts they would
uh Char the the tips of the Timber that
they would stake into the ground so that
it wouldn't
rot uh and in Japan they have a building
technique I think it's called Yaki Sugi
uh that may be a gross
mispronunciation but basically I'm going
to Char this and then I'm going to uh
stain it with
some uh I'm thinking flax seed oil uh or
teak oil or walnut oil but I think flax
seed basically something that's not uh
toxic but that's also uh while I do have
a whole lot of olive oil inside I'm not
sure if that's going to go rancid
and although I'd love to use the olive
oil but anyway first up
let's smoke some
weed so this is
24K cross with
uprise very
tasty all right and here we
go cuz what project is not more
fun when you are super high
so I do not have my little helper today
she's it's about to grab the torch for
the be a little less
aggressive all right
so let's do one of these at a
time uh the good news is I really don't
care about this grass I'm actually
trying to fill in this
divot so I uh have been dumping biomass
in there to build it up and then just
letting any
seed right like this
is Mullen
seed so you see a bunch of mulling
growing in there and then I'll uh I put
like
I don't know heavy on top of it to
kill it
down but anyway Let's uh
[Music]
this is the home stretch last uh of the
six hexagon
boards uh so we're going to
[Music]
finish
[Applause]
[Music]
Charing fine in all
the so where the knots are need to kind
of penetrate a little deeper
[Music]
sadly I cannot find the compressed a
so been blowing these off with my
[Music]
Mouse okay we'll just use our
hands that is also
effective they're going to get all Su
anyway soft supple
hands all
right oh Lord oh
my soak it up
all right we got all three kids to
school now it's Daddy time before
work packing up seed packs
all right we'll let these
dry but yeah that looks
dope look at that know you can see the
but yeah this will look nice so these
six boards are the
bottom 6 in of the uh raised bed so
we're going to go 12 in up around this
tree on the
nerum it's almost done seating catching
the seeds down
there
yeah at the
hands and the wood wh oops little
fingerprints so yeah we'll let this
dry we have five more pieces all done
it's the last of the bottom
row so we'll let you dry right there
boom
well get some soft hands from the flax
seed
oil all right
that's good
enough so now I'm going to pull all this
stuff
up just get out of the way
but yeah I'm kind of trying to time
everything like
the these seed pods are almost done see
this one's
finishing I can't really touch my phone
with
my yeah so you can see the seed pods
here finishing
up and then
here's the nestum seed
pods and then there's the MH and the
holy basil also finish in so I'm going
all right let me pull all this
back there's the Roman Esco
broccoli from right over there
[Music]
the
there we
go all right we're
ready for the
build so yeah
basically hexagon right around this
[Music]
tree all right so
now yeah this is not
nice to have like a
workbench could put
on let's
see okay
that the
bottom and we'll put you on the top all
right
so here we
go all
right all right you know what we can do
let's start by just getting
one
right there
[Music]
all
right
okay and down
here let's see if you're
there and you're kind of right there
[Music]
m
the ice cream
truck w
[Music]
okay that
there's the hexagon
[Music]
what's
up
[Music]
yeah all right look at that the ground
floor
is down look at that yeah that's
going to look
nice all
right so the
downside is that I need to torch wipe
down and oil six
more of these but basically what I'm
going to
do is
get some of
these right so you
go let's do the 10
in but basically do row number
two right
all
right but
that looks like it'll be pretty
cool
anyway this is pretty
cool it's going to look
nice well I love the
Grassroots fabric pots
having like six of them around this
tree I think this will look pretty
cool make a mess again yeah I won't make
a mess again I'm making a little mess a
little
mess yeah yeah Daddy's making a mess
daddy what's this that is
lemongrass yeah did you have a good
nappy nap yeah yeah I just wake up
amazing I just come here
amazing dad want see what's Mimi making
what's Mimi making go check what Mimi is
making you go look I'll be inside in 1
minute okay you just make a mess yeah
I'm finish I'm making a mess and then
I'm going to clean up okay and you clean
up who loves to make messes me yeah you
sure do there some kids over there there
kids over there yeah
oh okay well go inside and I'll be in in
1 minute okay okay okay just be
careful thank
you the home
stretch two more of these to go
[Music]
ha
and there we
go so we got this one we got one
more and then we'll start putting the
second floor on which adds another 6 in
so we'll have 12 in in
total and if we want to get crazy at
some point I could
buy more lumber and add a third story on
but to start I think we're going to be
very happy with this one of the
neighbors cut a tree down
so I have some logs in there
now and I keep getting
more but yeah so very satisfying all
right we'll let you dry for a little
bit wait wait wipe wipe
wipe wipe wipe on the
legs all
right all right one log to
go oh
my oh my my my my my my my
[Music]
[Laughter]
again this would be much better if I was
not hunched over
but we play with the cards we're dealt
with all right
so wipe you
down my
back my neck my
back who knows that
song My Neck My Back
[Music]
this thing drinks up the oil
though so again of
if I were the next one of these I do
I'll try to add
some anti fungal and
anti bacterial stuff to
the to the flax seed oil
all
right so we'll let this dry overnight
and then we'll
do second floor tomorrow
we'll see what my kids think my
toughest
critics all they do is tell me I'm fat
and
old all right
oh my
back my neck my
back sing it people my neck my
back my neck my back
all right
so there we
go there we go all right oh the
back oh the
back all right now I got to order
dinner before the Celtics game for the
kids going eat some
pizza pizza
pizza all right
[Music]
it's the home
stretch we're looking pretty
good got two more to go and then we're
going to
put some of those so kind
of like that actually let me find the
10in ones where are you you are 12
in where are my 10 in
my big 10
in I don't
know but anyway we're going to
put some of these like
this and then I have some
30° I have some 30° brackets that I'm
going to put here and there and then you
basically have one two three four well
could even put two on the inside of each
one
right like one over here and one over
there but anyway we're getting
close those logs are from the dude
cutting the tree down right
now so I grab those it's
fortuitous all right home
[Music]
stretch bird P I'll put this on the
bottom of the
[Applause]
inside all right what do you think so
how about this can you help me hold ah
no no no no no no
no all right so now these since I didn't
have anyone helping me this whole
project e why is it Mak well because
it's I charred the wood see that lighter
why do you Char it well I'll explain it
later but okay how
about why did you do that uh because the
wood lasts longer it doesn't
rot are you supposed
to uh it's one way of skinning the
cat right there are many ways to do
things all right so I just hold it don't
let it
move you just let it move I'm going to
be put Gemma
okay don't let it move
baby what there you just keep it let go
for a
[Applause]
[Music]
second nice
okay now so try
to I don't want to do that no no no just
like that okay perfect all
right pal stretch we're so
[Applause]
close
nice okay you can let go okay so just
hold on all right all right just just
over here wipe it on the grass over
there see the grass over no not on your
beautiful dress just on the grass over
there wipe your hands on the grass I
don't want want to wash it well first
wipe it on the grass and I'll be done
here why don't you just help me with
this and then we can both wash our
hands it smells bad well it's yeah
doesn't smell like anything it
smells it doesn't smell like anything
that's right
okay so hold
[Music]
on Papa yes baby when can me and Julia
have um when can me and Julia go to
Sephora and the thing again okay well
you're going to Taiwan in a couple days
so probably not till you get back okay
so here we go can it be like when when I
get back and we're waiting to go to RH
Island yes okay so just make make sure
you don't get your beautiful dress
uh okay so hold on that
side all right so I got to do this on
both
sides so this I want to so you're just
going to stay black like this exactly
but why do you need it and and will the
Char eventually go in and it won't stain
anymore uh I
yeah okay that's not perfect but so how
long did you spend like charring
it that was a good question
uh probably took
like I don't know two hours or an hour
and a half to do all the
charring okay so I'm just thinking about
this okay can to Ching you you want to
charm me yeah okay so hold
on can I try tring your hair to make get
black
oh
okay sorry I'm trying
to hurry up yeah
well okay how about this can you come
over here and just kind of put one hand
just a hand here pushing down and a hand
here pushing down actually no just just
right there I'll do over here yeah just
don't let it move
boom good all right let me get thep one
no please okay I'm really worried about
your dress so let's just be super
careful
smells so
bad it doesn't smell bad what are you
talking about
I I quit no I I give up I do nothing's
good enough for
[Music]
[Applause]
anyone boom all right
Gemma you are all done thank you for
your
help so it's the home
stretch uh what I'm doing the last thing
is I'm going to put these uh
support pieces up so
basically possibly two on each one but
at least one so either two or just one
in the
middle and then I was going to do corner
brackets so angled brackets uh I ordered
these but they're even though it said
30° I think yeah they're 15 they're
basically not the right uh
angle but they're also uh ridiculously
thick I was thinking more something
that's
like that
thin uh so what I got instead
was just
uh these little thin pieces of
aluminum uh which does last a long time
and I was just going to cut them angle
them and then drill so that at
least uh yeah anyway some additional
support but it should be
good so anyway let's start with
these
[Music]
ones these are 1 and 1/2 in
screws figured since the thickness of
the wood is 2
in we did all
right so how many of these do I
have we got one two three four five six
all right I only have eight of them so
we're just going to do one on each
but that should
be this one
looks let's get
this yeah we'll get you out of the
way we'll
go all
right here we go
[Music]
so conceptually what we're doing
did
too see we'll just keep going
around getting
close so then this
stuff I still would like to find
that stray
screw basically I'm going to cut
it but it'll go there anyway I was
thinking just kind of like
that
not I should probably go thicker
but that can be the first
one so anyway if you
had since finding 30°
angle
brackets it's not as easy as IID hoped
so if I just do
boom and boom
right all right
yeah so in retrospect I think like 8 in
would have been this is 10 and 1
12 which unfortunately you can kind of
see from the
[Music]
top we're getting super so Clos I
can I can feel it
[Music]
good be careful car so remember you have
to listen to Nora okay see the
cars when Nora says stop what do you
do you have to stop right that's right
when
nor that's right so when Norris says
stop it's because it's dangerous and
there's a car okay
[Music]
didn't daddy say put your helmet
on yes you got to wear your helmet when
you scooter outside thank you yeah go
get your
helmet yeah my
2-year-old loves to
scooter so we have
one
two
three 4
four
[Music]
five
six and
flexing my ninth grade geometry
skills all right so I'm going
to uh switch this up drill some holes
through the aluminum
and do the corners
[Music]
ice cream truck all right this
part we go two
all right
so we'll go
[Music]
thicker okay so we'll do the bottom row
later
but all
right here we go
[Music]
so we'll give
it just kind of like
that so at some point I
might well want I'll probably sit on
this or put weight on it and my kids but
then I was going to put like a sitting
bench on the
outside so
[Music]
this
thing is feeling
pretty pretty solid
[Music]
okay so first of all come here you are
so
cute my helmet you want to take off your
hel so adorable in your helmet do you
want me to help yeah okay hold on I go
fast you went so I caught Nora you
caught Nora yeah I got okay come over
here where are you going come over here
what do you see in
there do you like
it so we're going to put plants in there
what do you think
[Music]
yeah those are flowers
too okay
bye-bye so the last thing I'm going to
do is
put uh let's see if we can get some
rocks that I've been collecting from
around the
yard so there are spots where obviously
isn't flatten level so I'm going to take
some of this the soil from the yard I'll
uh break it down but uh build it up and
then basically
put kind of as much rock well once it's
built up but basically put Rocks Under
here so that uh the wood's not just
sitting straight on moist wet soil all
the
time so but yeah so I need to take I'm
going to put this in water and break it
down also get all the rocks out of it
and then the rocks will be used uh kind
of under
here and then we'll fill it with soil
and we'll be done but let's take a look
at our
handiwork yeah so what I was
saying so I'm going to sand
down like for example Le
here just that little Edge right there
and then I'll torch it again and then
here kind of where this sticks
out but I mean we got this thing is not
it's going to be
rugged we got some support there and
then on the
corners
uh I might put one here but I don't
really think I need
it but yeah that
is very
nice yeah so here we're just going to
put a whole bunch of these in the water
so I
can make it more like mud so I can
actually break it apart
and then that is going to build up some
of
these low points and then we'll put the
Rock in but like here yeah so basically
I need to level the whole thing that's
the next project level and get
rock
under uh the wood
yeah look at that boom all
right see yeah basically I have this uh
this low area here that I've been
filling in over time with
[Music]
biomass so I'm going to build this up
but then keep
going over
[Music]
here all right let's go and
food
[Music]
scraps B I can only put so
much kitchen throughput through the worm
bins so I'm constantly looking
for places for the
[Music]
excess F scraps
he
[Music]
nice that is a nicer
Edge okay and then over here we're going
to do the same
[Music]
thing I've been filling this with
logs such as this one oh wow I see some
snails underneath and uh other stuff I
cut a lot of branches off this tree so
I'm going to fill it's going to I've
been letting it dry for the past couple
days so that's all crunchy throw that in
and then some of the soil from the
pots and then we will plant some plants
[Music]
you
yeah so I think next I'm going to
put I'm going to
build probably like a
4x8 over
here maybe two of them going that way
but this is looking
[Music]
dope speaking of
dope it's time to smoke a bowl
[Music]
all right so we got some ABC plants that
are going to go in here Australian
bastard cannabis get rid of
[Music]
who CU we don't want that to die while
we're
gone all right
so this is definitely a male cuz I
revegged it and then this is a cutting
from it just in
case and then one two three
more I have a whole bunch of other
seeds we're going to do a seed increase
of the Australian bastard cannabis
so all right M go on the back back side
right
[Music]
m
all right getting close so a couple
weeks later this is the end
result we
got the hexagon around the
tree we got
the
rectangle and then right here we're
going
to do some other random
shape and now I'm trying to uh I'm going
to cut down some
bamboo and basically create
staks and uh create some height and
structure so some of the viny stuff like
the
uh the Morning Glory can climb and then
I have these
little pieces of uh branch that
I've kind of created a little ladder so
they can plants can VY plants can grab
on
anyway for