hey uh field notes again we already
started covering uh the transki uh we
showed you another Fino now we're at the
other side of the garden so this is from
our African sativas today is October
23rd I want to show you uh up close here
uh this plant is actually
in my opinion it's very close to being
ready for Harvest so if you want to come
in close on some of these buds see what
the final bud structure looks like
um
so I probably can go for a few more days
but it's just very very crystally but
they're tiny tiny tiny Teensy little uh
almost like pixie dust trichomes so when
you look at it at first you're like
where's the Crystal and then you look
closer and you're like oh it's totally
Crystal coated
but they're just tiny little trichomes
so um and the smell
oh my God
oh it's like it's Piney
also like a fresh parsnip a little bit
of parsley and Dill so very Savory herbs
but then also there's kind of a thicker
creamier almost like chocolate
almost like chocolate mint
um
but with
that's amazing
um but also with like parsley and fresh
parsnip like an astringent thing going
so very interesting so this is the
furthest thing from fruity Tootie
uh modern cannabis flavor this is very
Savory herb Piney astringent uh with a
little chocolatey yumminess in there so
really amazing very excited about this
one we're going to be harvesting this
this week again this is transky