[Music]
okay
so today i'm going to be sharing with
you the first of many tips
just little things that can save you
time or make your life a little bit
easier
some of you may know these things
already but for those of you who don't
you'll see it and you'll face palm
because there's a lot of things that we
can do
that save us a lot of time that makes
life easier
that are common sense but you don't know
until you know
so that's the point of these tips so
today what i'm going to do is show you
how to make transplanting a little bit
easier on your life
i've already started we're going to be
up potting and i've already started with
a new bucket i call them buckets they're
containers they're pots they're whatever
they are
i call them buckets and i've also
pre-filled a little bit of dirt
because when you put your existing plant
and root ball in
you want to make sure that it's sitting
at about the same height
you know you might be able to bury a
little bit of stem if you need to in the
earlier
ages i'll show you that in a minute but
for now
we would typically be putting something
with a decent size root ball
and we want to make sure it has some
extra soil to go down into
i'm going to leave it exactly like it is
it's at the nice height
good equal distance all around it so let
me just start filling in the soil for
you
and i use you know a little tray
underneath try to
prevent it from getting all over the
place obviously if you're on a concrete
floor or if you have a tarp that makes
life a lot easier and clean up
i've got a broom i'm not too worried
about it
i'm just going to keep filling it in and
if if the soil goes into
the middle pot don't worry about it
we'll take advantage of that later
okay so we're getting close to the top
of it
i'm gonna just smooth it out a little
bit and i am going to give it a little
bit of a push down just
gently kind of make sure it binds
against the side of the pot you know
solid wall
you don't want to push it down too much
you don't want to create compaction
a good root zone needs oxygen if you
just push it all down
you're not doing yourself any favors so
just go gently but
do get it a little bit tight
okay looks good to me i have all this
stuff in the center
i told you not to worry about it and
here's where it kind of comes in handy
you can take it
and you just scoop it to the outside
and that kind of fills it in and brings
you to the level
that you are going to need so nice and
simple there
again it's gonna bring that to the level
that you need nice and simple
life is good happy little pottery
potty pot pots happy little perlites and
soil clouds for microbes good stuff
okay so what we're going to basically do
is give this a little twist and a shout
then we pull it out and now you have a
perfect hole
so when you take your pot or your plant
out of here
and you're going to plug it in boom you
got something perfect to plug it into
and again it's not super tight we want
that oxygen we want that air in there
we get our new plant we'd plug it right
in
maybe give it a little bit more of a
temp down maybe put some extra topsoil
on top of it
give it a water and you're good to go
and now that we've covered the big pot
we're gonna do the little pot this is
typically
my progress of a potting i like to start
all my clones all my seeds in a small
four by four tray
i typically will then move them up to a
gallon pot
and finally into a three gallon pot
which for the size of the tents that i'm
growing in
is really the maximum size that i want
to get i could use larger pots but i'm
going to get a lot larger plants
and while larger plants sound great
i don't necessarily want that because of
the amount that i have
and the space that i have so
plug that back in there we're going to
walk through this just like we did the
other one
doesn't fit so i need to add some soil
in the bottom
of the pot first all right let's do that
and i'm gonna say that that is a little
too much
a lot of times when you put a seed in
there it'll get a bit of a stretch so
the cotyledon which is the very very
little first leaf
um not even really a leaf but let's not
get too technical
it will stretch up so oftentimes you can
bury
the stem up to that so what i'm going to
do is i'm just going to take a little
bit
back it out basically let's do that
so that actually looks like it's going
to be perfect
and it is a tighter fit so again this
time like i said last time
if you spill the soil into that middle
container don't worry you'll use it at
the end it's actually very useful so
let's fill it up again
and now i'm just going to take the stuff
from the middle fill the outsides and
make it perfect to
my heart's desire yeah
okay that looks like it's ready so just
like the last time little twist and
shout
and pull it out and you got your perfect
hole
to put your seedling in now see
i hope you guys enjoyed i'd love to hear
any tips you guys have
and we will be doing this every show
thank you for tuning in
i'm chad westport