very groovy
like
[Music]
all right here's jay opening day of
valley purveyors what do we got for
promotions today jay
what do we got for promotions today we
got a wheel grand opening we got
freebies for everybody three pre-rolls
if you spend 25 dollars you get to spin
the wheel of luck
sick yep 10 off everything free gram of
flour
you get raffle tickets to put in for our
raffles the main raffles 150 school gift
certificate
nice i think you got the raffle stuff in
here right should we check it out
[Music]
yeah
we're doing uh
a hoodie from max treehouse and a bag of
coastabane from
lobster fan farms
basically a bag of extracts from soccer
river green and
from the store we're doing a hand carved
stone pipe of your choice comes with a
free
bubble hash ball and then that's the
that's the big ticket the big one
good luck everyone
howdy we're here at opening day of
valley purveyors i'm
what has been the funnest thing and the
most draining things of today
i would
[Music]
um
so what do we have going on today for
promotions miss abby i hear there's a
dart throw
so it's a pin yeah do be on willy so if
you can't get the dart you know right in
the mouth or anywhere really close to
the mouth you get a free pre-roll
that's awesome
strike one
strike two
and you're out
a little high
oh
[Music]
with jessica
and it looks like we got some free food
and some good vibes how's opening day
going
awesome having fun
good times seems like positive vibes
awesome
very cool
[Music]
yeah it grows just like
it's got that kind of fox taily
looking kind of button
[Music]
that smells good
yep yeah
there we go
[Music]
you didn't have a vehicle
oh
[Music]
max treehouse and that
of course it's in
knock it in don't be afraid
is
[Music]
you