welcome to the Church of C high
c
c welcome to CI High episode 69 Brett in
the backyard this week CI high in
conjunction with the future cannabis
project sit down with Brett Feldman of
wonderbrett for a backyard discussion
about origins of strains and the various
crosses and progenitors of the now
famous Wonder Bret varieties such as
pink p also an orange Sunset we also
talk about long forgotten buds of the
San Fernando Valley I ask Brett about
his outdoor grow in Santa Barbara and
how that's going as well as out ofate
collaborations with Wonder brt lastly we
look into bird seed genetics Wonder
bre's new seed line stay tuned for this
highly informative talk also in the yard
for this discussion our Peter chieri
founder of the future cannabis project
and Gabe cannabis somia extraord a and
Shakespeare of cannabis reviews for FCP
as well as myself chenzo stay
tuned all right so chenzo we're in the
valley we're in your casa your backyard
we are in the backyard here at the we
got airplanes airplanes coming over
we're in a flight path but military
aircraft patrolling all the backyard
grows that's Joe Biden's uh c5a
in his H1 in there uh now of course we
have our the land of fagio in the back
here and we have Brett Feldman of Wonder
brt today Brett how are you buddy I'm
doing great we we are GNA double mik
you so
Brett what are we rolling right now uh
I'm rolling some pink Picasso right now
and what is the pink Picasso pink
Picasso is oie Kush crossed with with
Candyland very cool and Candyland is
made up of uh granddaddy per and the
original cookies cut so like two of like
very iconic great strains make up
Candyland Candyland was like one of my
favorite cookies like type genetics that
were around in the early you know 2010
2014 like kind of space around there so
crossing the O mail into that like it
just
I didn't know what I was going to get
but Pig Picasso is a special strain it's
like very cool now I'm super excited to
try it it has a reputation the preds it
to the Candy Land is that from one of
the cookie fam guys originally or no
it's it was like um somebody just in the
bay uh bred it fire but it was it was
definitely like a a notable strain
during that time cuz everybody was
really looking for like the the form cut
cookies and and then to have that cross
L into GDP the granddaddy
per well and it came right on the like
the cookies came on the crest of the
pers thing yeah so like it made a lot of
sense and maybe there's even perss in
the Cherry Pie who who knows yeah
totally and let's not discount the GDP
yeah no GDP is a great strain when like
it's awesome I mean Urkel I think is
like as good as this plant can get yeah
yeah which all all used to be known as
the purple
Nepal any want to dry hit this yeah yeah
I love your pink Picasso by the way yeah
it's a it's a crowd favorite it's one of
my favorites like one of the things that
that like we created where I was just
like wow we I think we created something
really special and um it unique it was
just it's really unique like the tarpine
profile on it is is different than a lot
of other strains it's cool you get like
that little bit of candy from the Z but
you still really get that like Smooth
cooked
yeah perss it's nice um and so the OC
seems like a staple throughout a lot of
your work I think definitely the first
time I tried anything for you was
probably like 2018 on the rec Mark and
was O K was fire really honestly some of
the best quality I've seen on Metric
awesome um but so why the O like why is
that one that you've well uh it has the
the OG in it which was what I grew for
like you know probably like you know 20
well for from now to when I started it's
like over 20 years um got that ligh um
but uh OG's just always been a great
strain like straight up and um it's I
think it'll always be one of the best
strains that we're ever discovered and
found and created
um and then Skittles came on and you
just you're like wow what a really
really special tpine profile it you know
when I saw it it was just little when I
first saw it it was just little tiny
buds it was like you you couldn't at
least from when I first started getting
it was like you couldn't find like good
nugs of it or I think the good nugs are
is a lot of the 2.0 it's like a back
cross workor I think if you have that
first real cut like Cooks you're getting
Pebbles grateful to have those so we
were we were all like pretty Blown Away
with the turpine profile on the Skittles
what year was that that was
when let's see I would
say
2017 when I think I first stumbled
across it maybe like and I was looking
for it and I I bought a bunch of it cuz
I was like well maybe I'll find a bag
seed and I did find a bag seed I I
started to pop that bag seed and then
like two months later a buddy from
Humble actually gave me the cut oh wow
so I got the original cut and I had a
bag seed cut I don't know if it was 17
or 16 but a lot of people got introduced
to it at an emerald cup or like di had
had a booth and people were like you
said just buying ounces hoping to get
like one bag see it yeah uh cuz it was
so wildly different and tasty yeah it
was it was crazy um the lines were long
and you know you would buy an eth and it
you'd pour it out and it would just be
like literally like uh a like a tin of
Smalls or a plastic quarter of Smalls
you know like gnarly little nuggies yeah
they were tell tasty though for like I
was like not impressed lookwise but as
soon as you kind of start to break it up
and smell it You' be like oh this is
special and then you soon as you tasted
it you're like yeah this tastes like you
know Froot Loops and candy and Skittles
and you understand why they called it
Skittles because it was yeah so what did
you do with that first cut of Skittles
and you had also the ozk which was came
from the original kush yeah so the ozk
came like about a year later when they
released the seed
uh of uh the Eddy LEP OG crossed
with with Skittles oh oh so EUR o k from
dying grd yeah fire yeah no doubt um and
that was released at this
like uh double
weekend like High Times event and
uh they they were releasing it and then
this their trailer got broken into and a
lot of their seeds got stolen at the
hotel then then like the night before
everything was getting released I
remember we were all like setting up
everything I was setting up my booth
they were setting up their Booth we were
right across like the courtyard from
each other that they had set up and I
was like talking to the guys and they
were like yeah we'll have everything I
I'll put aside some packs for you
tomorrow and I was like cool I wasn't
worried about it they said they set it
aside and then all that stuff happened
that night and uh I didn't get any packs
from them cuz it all got stolen and it
was really like a shitty deal shitty
story for them I can only imagine how
depressed they were like seeds are not
are very dear I guess yeah those those
are not I don't know what happened to
all those seeds that got stolen or where
they went because I feel like whoever
stole it like I never heard about those
seeds popping up on the black market
like I feel like whoever stole it didn't
know what they stole and just kind of
probably were like this is worthless you
know like just probably threw all that
seeds yeah just probably like threw all
that [ __ ] aside had no idea what it was
and and you know got rid of it um maybe
the the packaging was opaque and they
thought it was weed or
something who knows you know I mean we
were all out in uh the middle of nowhere
out there at uh Glenn
Helen uh wherever that is bont or I San
berino somewhere over there yeah yeah
the the fairgrounds or whatever right
and so before before you got the Z were
you just growing OG is that how it I was
growing OG for for since '98 and then
um in like
2006 2007 I started doing my own
breeding cuz I kind of just I loved OG
but I was getting tired of the strain
cuz it was just you can't smoke the same
[ __ ] forever and I feel like if they if
there is one it would be OG but I and
you know he still got you high no matter
what like even if you got had like a
crazy tolerance for OG you still got
stoned off of it which was the what was
so special about it it was like whereas
other Strang
if you spoke that whatever it was for
like a few weeks like you were just not
getting stoned off of it well also I
feel like that's what's the not to go
back to the ZK but that's the real
benefit of that cross too like it can
really ring your bell whereas Z unless
you take it just way too long for it to
be delicious you're not going to get
that high I agree uh and that was why it
was so special cuz OG potency and the
Skittles turps I was blessed to get a
seed pack of that about 2 weeks after
the event was this guy it was the guy
from CES he was hanging out with the
guys from dying breed and they gave him
two packs of seeds when they were at the
hotel so CES Solutions was a like a a
extraction company back in the day okay
some were local around here and and the
guy and they were just like Boston BHO
they
were everyone was right yeah like Rosen
was just kind of getting start starting
like I was hanging out at uh Professor
siff's house and they were
pressing uh fresh flour like fresh press
flour where and that's how he got his
start right he was didn't he work at
somewhere else in the valley and he was
yeah Hospitality making flower RS and
then where that's taken him BR gets the
the Redwoods cup thank you
brother get the turtle cup and um so I
was heading out to his house and um I
had brought him some of my strawberry
bubble gum to press and uh the guy from
CS was hanging out there and I was
telling him how bummed I was I was
telling him the story about how I was
looking forward to getting that OC and
dude was like yeah I think I got two
packs of that from
them uh the night before all that stuff
got
stolen and uh he went he went to his
house and he's like yeah I think they're
in my kitchen drawer and so I followed
him home and he was like we went to his
house and he opened up his kitchen
drawer he had two packs he just gave me
one he was like bro you're a really good
grower here this doesn't belong in my
hands he was like I'm not going to be
able to grow this out so he he blessed
me with that pack and um that's awesome
it was just kind of like destiny that I
ended up with it still in the end and I
found out of that pack I found you know
there's only 12 seeds in there I only
pop half the pack of seeds I still have
the original half pack of that oh wow
and I found what is the that ozk cut is
like the Pinnacle definitive o cut that
everybody loves that's that Perfect
Blend of Skittles and and OG that has
the potency and the of OG and the the
turps of o were all the seeds
consistent um no yeah no there was like
two other females that
were contenders but they just they were
leaning more OG and not leaning as much
Skittles and then there was the you know
two males I think that I got out of as
well I think I popped six of the seeds I
think only five of them
popped did anything have any color or
was it all just green we no it has color
if if you can you know you can shock it
with some cold um it'll put a little bit
of purple in there for sure H yeah um
but purple wasn't a thing at the time
like like it is now you know like purple
weed is desirable really right now what
year was that
again early 90s no we're talking 2017
yeah 2017 probably 2018 at that point if
you look on my
Instagram I post and show all the stuff
of like even when I was popping those
packs of seeds when I found the bag seed
a few months before that um how long
have you had your Instagram since
200 uh I think 13 or 14 yeah when if you
go all the way back it it goes back that
far wow it's it's nice to have like this
record timeline absolutely well for and
for the recent stuff but then everything
before that I mean the forums are useful
but I think yeah one thing I wanted to
ask about is like what do you think OG
Kos is I know there's a lot of stories
in you're pretty associated with sort of
it's come up in California yeah yeah I
mean when I first got the cut everybody
said you know this came this cut came
from Florida and it used to uh be
potentially called the crippy or or
super
not um was kind of like some of the
rumors were going around when I first
got the strain like you know during that
first year or two of growing it
um but everything you know that is
there's been guys who talked about it
being like from California NorCal like
like I don't really believe any of that
I think it really did come from Florida
but did did you get the cut from a guy
who got the cut from Josh yes okay yeah
I got from Josh's friend and uh he lived
in the bay and uh that's it seems like
there's consensus among a lot of people
that like it can't like Josh got it
via SHP or whatever like yeah Mt and as
far as I know from talking with Josh and
and all the updated stories that that
have came out
like which I believe you know Josh he's
reputable no reason to and and everybody
backs him up around it too so
um and Matt Bubba Burger as well you
remember the Irene yeah and the Irene
being from the valley you must remember
Irene a buddy of mine so that for so the
the Irene OG is was actually my OG and
my buddy Cody shout out to Kodiak um if
you know Kodiak around the valley he's
been a a guy been around for a long time
yeah do know um wait why do I associate
it with rude boy I have no idea okay
sorry but Kodiak was yeah I I brought
him uh a batch of my OG that I grew and
a batch that a buddy of mine Kirk had
grown and we would both we just both had
two small spots and you know I would
take some of his work he would take some
of my work whatever we needed to and
they were both really great batches but
uh Cody was like we're going to call
this one Irene and we're going to call
this one Larry and so you had Larry OG
and Irene OG both named in front of me
that day were just be re were just
renames of the original cut oh wow and
there weren't anything different about
now maybe once those names caught on
over time like other Growers were like
I'm going to call my [ __ ] Irene and I'm
all this will be I'll have the Larry OG
or whatever or something like that but
but I remember the Irene from way
back yeah I mean how far back though cuz
that to me is like I would say let me
see I would say like 2004 or something
2005 is when I think that kind of
happened really yeah cuz I remember it
from like ' 80s yeah no I I think there
there's there may be a different might
just be recy
mayene but the Irene like uh I was still
just like playing with GI Joe you
know anybody remember Barefoot Mike
no probably not he was he was the
connect for the
Iran that's was it was it a was it an OG
Kush the the IR in your time was it an
OG Kush it was that's what I mentioned
it why I mentioned it because it was
very similar to OG before OG interesting
um I could see that being a possibility
I mean things move around the world and
things get recycled and rened yeah and
you know if something came from Florida
there's a good chance it could have been
Colombian related you know what I mean
CU all the Colombian came in through
Florida yeah I mean the the guys that
come with their their Florida story
about you know talking about OG before
Josh brought it here with with Bubba
they would say you know it was like you
know taii and Afghan or something
crossed or
like oh I heard you talking about the
the tie and looking for a real cat I
found a guy with the real tie chocol you
do have the real that's this guy speaks
thae too I speak Tha he spoke we met
grocery store yeah you smoked it right I
smok yeah I would love to get that cut
um supposedly he's coming down and he's
going to give me the seeds but uh he's
been a little sketchy Andrew if you're
you're watching somewhere uh come on
down we're waiting for you I called him
this morning his phone's not taking
messes and weed yeah and maybe more
that's maybe we can have some m
some hacky sack so you're rolling up the
uh the
Cherry I grabbed a jar of this actually
off you at our homie P polari S I have a
show on FCP and Brian came on a couple
weeks ago it was awesome um I feel like
this jar was like a hot commodity I
maybe got like one of two that you had
on it it's an interesting Turf do you
want to talk about what this is yeah so
this is uh Cherry cookies from
Relentless genetics his I got a pack of
seeds from him uh and um I didn't really
find any great you should try this have
you tried that uh-uh you'll be very
pleas they released a new the 2.0 today
oh oh I know what you're talking about
this type of grinder yeah the mill yeah
I like the hemp shredders but yeah let's
see how this works but the the Cherry
cookie was the uh the pack of seeds that
I got the mail out of cleaned it from
Relentless from Relentless right and
what is the Cherry cook so if you're
watching now you look at the bong and
notice how clean it is it's like fire
cookies he had this and who cleaned that
so what's crazy is I would be seeing him
on Instagram posting all the time and uh
he' always post this I think it was
called fire cookies or Fire Cherry
cookies yeah yeah and um it it looked
just amazing and I I didn't know that uh
he was selling the seed packs like I
just didn't click or something and until
like a like a year or two after like me
following him and I don't maybe he
wasn't selling the seed packs at that
point when I started following him and
it just kind of he started that line or
something but that's where I got the uh
um the Cherry cooking mail from and do
you know what the Cherry in that
is again I have to look like charts yeah
but it's that I'm sure Relentless he's
pretty meticulous about his like family
tree breakout you know like yeah um so
that was that was where I got that and I
used the mail from the the cherri's
cookie pack pack um and it might have
been like an F2 pack or an F3 pack as
well
um and I used that mail into the
ozk and um found this what was the The
Keeper pheno of that which is the Kush
Cola which I didn't want to put the word
Cherry in the title because I just feel
like Cherry would have turned people
into thinking that it was like a lcg
cross or something for sure because lcg
is you know the Lemon Cherry L is so
popular right now in in in certain
circles and has been for a while so I
didn't want to put the word Cherry in
the title even though it could have
easily been called like Cherry Kush Cola
or something like that but it just went
with Kush Cola and then let people read
the description very cool and let them
see that like oh yeah this does have
cherry in it and um and it could have
been a Cherry Cola yeah it it honestly
tastes like I one of my favorite sodas
is the Virgil Wild like Virgil's Wild
Cherry Cola and that's what it tastes
like to me like um
so that this is one of my favorite
Creations uh and do you do you do all
the artwork don't you are you the artist
on all these um me and uh a good friend
of mine Eric uhhuh what you're rolling
up now yeah and his his uh Instagram is
zxu
um and he's he he and I made every logo
for Wonder Brett since Inception like
the first logo was the The W and then
the pineapple and then we went to like
the orange and the orange Sunset was
their first original orange I love your
orange Sunset that was so orangey it was
the first time I'd ever tasted anything
orange yeah it's different than the
Tangi cuz it had the O K crossed into it
and it was it was a cross of
uh of banana split M yeah you told me
that yeah yeah so Banana Split from DNA
genetics is where I got uh I found this
like well it was crazy cuz the
weed the weed taste smells good the weed
tastes like um no the weed tastes like
straight oranges when I got it but the
it smelled like bananas when you smelt
it it was like the first time I'd ever
it's still the only time I've ever been
like wow this tpine this [ __ ] smells
like like flowery bananas really fru
like like really really floral banana
non mistakable yeah and then when but as
soon as you light it up and smoke it
You' be like this [ __ ] tastes super
orange but you said it's different than
like a Tanger or drop so when what way
does it hit the pette differently
um the orange Sunset really tastes like
probably like orange sun-kissed soda oh
cool like like mandarin orange like
really sweet too like cuz that Skittles
in there the cuz the OC was the receiver
the ozk was the male oh was the D so
You' used the OC as the donor and the
receiver yeah yeah
yeah cuz when I used the mail it was my
it was like the I was still early on in
the breeding like
education cuz people wer really talking
about breeding and I I don't maybe they
were I was just not in the right Circle
yeah but um people just were just
everybody was clone chasing constantly
like there wasn't a lot of seed popping
or feno hunting like it smells good also
like I wasn't paying attention but I
feel like it's I've come to realize that
like that's really Al a super intensely
Southern California thing to be like
[ __ ] the seeds [ __ ] like I'm going to
get the elites and I'm going to run the
elites and I'm going to have packs of
Elites I agree yeah that's nice it's it
is very much that scent uh that that
type of scenario going on right now and
it has been for a long time like there
are people that love the weed for the
sake of growing it and there's people
that like making money straight up and
so they're just the people I think that
are chasing that are really just chasing
the money
um and they're they're just going to
jump from one bandwagon of strains to
the next like whatever and I get it
listen growing weed can be very
expensive the learning curve to figuring
it out and then the cost of of where you
do it how you do
it putting it on Metric that's what my
wife's been telling me I mean even
listen uh growing it at Mass scale are
you about to talk about your love of
metric is that where this going just
that's another it's another cost totally
you have you know what I would you know
Brett as a teacher I would love for you
to tell your how weed helps you focus
and how it did it yeah yeah um yeah I
mean I've always had ad and dyslexia
kind of not a great student and um they
put me on some of once they kind of
diagnosed me they were like hey we we
should give you Ridin and they you I
took this Ridin stuff and Dex green is
one of the other ones too it's basically
like speed yeah like methamphetamine
speed whatever used to snort riddling
late at night yeah I didn't realize what
it really was when they gave it to me
cuz I'm like oh doctors are giving to me
and I was like in like 9th 10th grade
and
um I didn't really and that was so
common yeah actually no it was much
younger than that that was actually like
in like seven there was like sixth
seventh grade actually he was the very
first kid to ever that there basically
Whispers that he was on some super drug
that made him like study
bionically because all he would do would
sit in the library and read like physics
textbooks chemistry textbooks and we'd
all be like how does he do it yeah you
know definitely like what I I remember
realizing you know it kept me up a lot
at night and I would just be like it was
cuz I didn't really like to to geek out
on like computers or reading like we
just got a computer for the first time
in our house it was like a one of those
early Macintosh you know like and I was
like I'd play with it for like 20
minutes and you know video games here
there but mostly I would just stay up at
night and just like make artwork yeah
you know like um and when did you make
the transition to not on a computer too
like freehand yeah and this this is
before you kind of discovered
weed yeah this is like right what
started to discover weed like at the
same time
and weed and fun activities like
learning how to play the guitar
and I didn't realize like until I got
enough
weed access to it like what it was it
was how it it was really that for a
second like it helping me you know that
sense of and so then you at some point
you just ceased taking chemicals yeah I
was just like I don't want to take these
like uh not
yeah I was I real I was just getting
like a a better level of uh like
comfortability and focus you know I mean
MH and what were like the early insights
like did you notice certain strains
affect you certain way certain time of
days made sense for smoking like what
were your early learnings around the
plan as medicine for you well we that's
what I think why it took me so long to
really kind of just hone in on it
because it was like it you got such
random [ __ ] straight up right like in in
like the mid99s like early '90s you
would you would get like a an ounce of
um oh that just Boomerang nice yeah you
would get like an ounce of um like
stress like seated weed you know from
South of the Border or something like
that or wherever it came from and uh it
would be like you know 80 100 bucks for
an ounce and you'd be deeding all day
and trying to learn how to that was I
just like sit there with my cousin Eric
and we would just try to learn how to
roll joints all day buy an ounce of weed
like that and we would just try to
practice rolling we were we were just
enamored with also just speaking of that
like I all the Growers I know roll like
this no filter just straight up weed on
the
tray yeah but like yeah do you want to
talk about like how you like your joints
and like basically filter I guess no
filter cuz the second you put these like
little pieces of paper right in your
mouth like that like and you're
breathing over it you can I can taste it
yeah now some people maybe can't but I'm
kind of tips ever I do like the glass
tips but they're kind of a pain in the
ass to you know keep clean and and have
a fresh one all the time and like it was
it if maybe if I had started smoking
weed like two years ago and I that's how
I got introduced to weed was with a
glass tip and all that kind of stuff
then maybe that's how I'd be stuck on it
but I learned how to roll joints where
you roll them properly and you th this
is my favorite way to smoke if it's
rolled well because when it's not you're
like sucking yeah you're getting bit
none of us have we two three joints
already none of us has been taking bits
out of our mouth I appreciate that yeah
it's like it's you just have to know how
to roll it with confidence that you also
you do the little tuck at the end that's
yeah it that's what whatever it is the
technique is is described as it's just
knowing that you're you're not rolling
it too tight and you're not rolling it
too loose it's like you've got it tight
enough with a little with confidence
where you're like this will be the right
draw and that just comes with rolling
like for years you know after a Time
some people just don't take the been
rolling for a long time yeah you know
some people just learn on that that
roller that zigzag made my brother two
little wheels you know with the piece of
fabric and like shout out to Chris you
know I'm like or cones people are
masters of that thing but I never really
[ __ ] messed with it you know like I
always just rolled on myself yep I've
been Rand since I was like 12 my brother
was a master he taught me how and that's
a long time ago yeah
yeah I learned from this like one kid in
high school he was like you do it like
this you press it all down you fold it
you you know pinch it down get it
situation situated he was like you can
from here he's like I can move it around
without even rolling it then roll it I
like oh okay I'm like and I like the no
filter thing too and you know after our
last interview I started rolling no
filter but then I I thought to myself
wow am am I wasting these this this
would have been a whole Summer's worth
of stash you know the the little roaches
you know and so I don't know sometimes
they're old to filter I must say yeah
but I think it's best not to you maybe
just for economic purposes I prefer if
there going to be a filter it' be a
glass one and you know if it's a nice
clean one it's great you know like shout
out to be real for I think putting that
on the map yeah um that was the first
time I ever saw it was there and then
they made the funky Fel tips and those
little glass tips made it so that you
could actually roll out a piece of
bubble hash and wrap it around and use
hash as a paper for the first time that
was like the first time we ever did that
like those people get the bottles and
like yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah uh the I
don't know if those are I feel like
those are wasteful I've never smoked one
I was like that was an economical use of
really good hash the I've heard them
called pixie sticks they done a bunch of
different names but where you actually
use create a paper out of press dryft
yeah it's a little wasteful it must be
yeah you do with a group of like 18 guys
like we were all at the studio and we
were they were doing their first uh like
podcast shows like this it was on these
like platforms I can't remember what
they were called uh but it doesn't
matter uh it's not I don't even think it
exists anymore the platform but it was
like one of the very first ones where
people could go on and like broadcast
streaming Periscope or something some
crazy yeah it's like one of those early
ones and maybe another one that that
still was around at that time to but uh
we had a bunch of guys bunch of guys in
the studio cuz we're over at B real
studio and um I'd always wanted to try
it and then be had uh those glass tips
it was the first time that we I'd ever
seen them like they were using them
rolling them for Jo you're friends with
be yeah yeah for uh for a long time now
so that's cool yeah sometimes I just you
know have to bust out my side for sale
he first met him in like 99 or something
or yeah right around there it was yeah
99 or 2000 right around there but I
remember like
92 was either 92 or 93 like being 16 in
high school listening to Cypress
Hill I have a lot of yeah a lot of good
early youth memories with Cypress Hill
yeah like some of my early days of
teaching when I went to I went to
granard Hills High School for 10th grade
um in the valley here and that was where
like really it was like there were three
major bands at that time that were
dominating it was Cypress Hill tul and
Rage Against the Machine like that was
on rotation pretty much in everybody's
car I got into it was like one of those
what year was this this is like
93 maybe like early 94 yeah yeah yeah
yeah I like cyers cell more than tul and
uh against turned
it was all about the base
dude people would get the big Kicker
speaker in the back of their like Ford
Explorers it was just all about the
base but actually to go back to
finishing your question so we started
with stress and then uh I started
getting introduced to like uh Indo what
every was calling it for like these like
$50 eights that were amazing from Humble
and that's when I kind of realized when
I got enough of that that I was like oh
this weed is like way better than this
medication they're giving me and I don't
I didn't like the feeling of the
medication anymore cuz I was I I was
able to identify it yeah yeah I remember
Indo I'm like does that mean it's Inda
indoor indoor Inda what was people would
say people would say that it's both it's
it's indoor grown so it's Indo and they
would say this is Indica as
well and what is this it's more of the
Cherry uh the Cherry is really nice
there yeah it's very you get a good
combination and you get the little
Cherry a little Z it's good hey let me
ask you an outdoor grower question um
what have you learned from growing
outdoors in Santa Barbara well I never
ran those Farms but i' I've definitely
studied the guys that do it you know
when I'm there and ask a lot of
questions and
anything there's yeah for sure as far as
like there's great knowledge there you
know like if you know when you when
you've planted 10 20 acres of canopy or
something like that uh or even you know
five to 10 or whatever it's it's a
massive canopy it's you you don't work
the crop the same way um it's all
preparation in the field before you
plant to get to have a great outcome you
got to prep the land really well got to
gr the land yeah grade it set it up get
your your Irrigation in right get your
your holes dug get your you know get
everything ready for properly for
planting and and fertilized if you're
going to fertilize what do we fertilize
with yeah what's that what do we
fertilize with they were just using just
a base out there I don't even remember
what the bags were called on it it was
just some basic a stuff it was nothing
like no nothing special like yeah it was
all being grown uh to for concentrate oh
yeah I was going to ask like what is the
function of outdoor within Wonder Bread
so it's for concentrating then Edibles
too or yeah we would use the the same
for that too and how do the way to
create Frozen like economically trying
to grow Frozen in a indoor grow like is
there market so there's no market for
the outdoor
flower there is but Peter is just
sitting there foaming at the mouth in
Anger sadness sadness no there's there's
there's a great demand for outdoor
flower from guys like that yourself that
would that love to get great batches of
that have have you smoked both of the
same straint and how did they compare
the outdoor was incredible when it was
fresh right you know like and it had a
nice freshness for a few months can
outdoor couldn't be great sorry outdoor
it was literally incredible I was going
to pass this one to you it was literally
incredible I saw that you still had one
like uh did you actually did you see
higher turpion numbers in the in the
TS yes yeah absolutely like in out yeah
the like when we grew like noticeably
the orange
banana uh is has always been one of our
highest like washing yield strains like
it's hit above seven in in washes and um
that's nice it's it's an incredible
genetic uh is most of your concentrate
uh ice water or yeah now everything is
is basically um when you see like
dabbable concentrates from us it's all
rosin when you have a guy like Brian
come up yeah do you want to tell that
story I mean he's a friend to the show
yeah no Brian uh let me just finish the
the the the orange banana
story someone can remember what this is
the add I've gotten better at this over
the years I'm should be
producer ability do that but yeah so the
the orange banana outdoor yeah so that
was the like wait for the plane uh yeah
that was thanks to Van airport for
having training fights over my house
damn
government uh no definitely like the
banan G and the orange banana were the
ones where I was like wow like you know
the difference is with Outdoors you have
these massive Fields right and the Sun
and all this nature and the plant just
becomes Hardy and it's in its natural in
state where it wants to be so it can
express I think higher tpine notes of
certain like markers that just don't
become more flavorful that don't come
out like you might indoor it might just
look like this right like these certain
ones hit their higher numbers merine or
luminol or whatever limine and um I
don't think luminol is a thing
actually some other one I like I think
that's the purple lemon are we thinking
lemon uh and then there's chinaline the
bad one the feel bad one yeah the haze
one yeah so sorry yeah go ahead let me
just check as when I noticed I was like
okay our orange banana indoor tastes
delicious it's really good but the uh
orange banana
in the outdoor field when I I was able
to take some of it when it was fresh and
and uh they had a space where they were
able to dry it where it was air
conditioned instead of just being in
like you know that's the problem with d
there massive fields and they don't have
any drying facilities so it all just
kind of gets hung kind of the problem
with the licensing structure and it's
really hard for these guys to have the
field just process that's a whole other
license you have to acquire I think that
it gets back not to to cut you up but I
think that if regulations made it easier
for guys to execute the guys have the
talent and know how to build this build
the [ __ ] out you know they just don't
have the ability to dry it and cure it
on large scale so that's why so much
outdoor kind of just comes out like the
way it does Colombians would bail theirs
in brown paper bag paper large 25 lb
bricks in the paper you know what I mean
and the paper I C when I'm tired of like
trimming and c I just stick the rest of
the weed in Brown Bags huh I still have
some brown bag weed that's actually
pretty good from last year I know people
who put you know brown bags in totes to
get the yeah after you've sort of done
your dry for the first stage of it also
kind of leeches the
chlorophyll who
knows not completely yeah or quickly but
it's anyway it cures it well interesting
I've never seen that never seen that
yeah yeah when it was the orange banana
though versus The Outdoor and the indoor
the outdoor just like every good part of
the indoor that I love from it was just
ex like exacerbated in the outdoor is
that orange jar orange banana um I don't
think it is I believe this jar is
Northern Lights uh number five the
original oh so that's cool you have the
nl5 yeah I'll roll this up too um that's
the original cut we'll go old school w
that rules
that
rules that it still smells good too yeah
surprising yeah Peter that's my own
string called the
formio okay oh sorry so what are the
what are the other two that you brought
I guess I feel like we're relate in the
show that we should
ask
um I think
these I have to I have to open the
look and okay so this is more Kush in
here actually I think IA yeah this jar
actually I think I just filled it cuz I
was I needed a jar to fill up and then
this one I think is the uh yeah purple
papaya ruts what what is the weight of
each of these jars like a seven a
quarter a 1 these are actually 1 oz jars
1 oz jars how cool yeah and uh I had a
lot of fun designing these and uh making
the the paint can look and can look and
they I've seen other people buite the
the can almost immediately after after
you guys roll yeah I saw that too I was
like I I don't mind it I'm like I'll
take it as a compliment imitation is the
the greatest form of FL I I heard that
there's like a second Clause that's a
part of that quote there is a whole
second finishing of like the bit part
but uh like when you sneeze God bless
you but the second part is and may the
devil miss you uh so what's the purple
papaya runs that is uh run cross with
Papaya oh okay straight up super
straight up like like I it was just
literally like okay this is you know
runs is very popular as well as the
lcg um and you know we didn't do a lot
of stuff we've been very stubborn in in
the sense of like making our own strains
and our own menu and having everything
be very different from everybody else's
how about this what would you grow
different if you didn't have to cater to
the wreck Market in California and you
could sell around the country to people
who appreciate what you would want to
grow that's a great question I think
it's so I think it's really about just
growing good quality mhm it it is of
whatever strain it really is but would
you grow some like longer flowering
uglier looking yeah like if if
economically we can make sense of it too
like if the industry is in a really
California is in a tough state right now
like prices are are are totally changed
um the cost of operating the taxes like
the the economy is not in a great state
either like a lot of people aren't
spending money on flour as much as they
were uh there was a lot of excess money
running around when you know the
pandemic was was going and before that
too the economy was Stronger before the
pandemic started I think as well so
people were spending more and now
there's just a very
like the black market is expanded cuz it
there's I think it was a great
opportunity for them you know to be like
like the stores are 38% tax the flower
cost you know more all this packaging
all this testing people have been
smoking weed and buying weed from their
friends and you know having it brought
to them while they're just hanging out
on the couch like they don't have to go
to the store you anyone like that they
never met anyone like that they're
mostly myths you know don't even exist
anymore mythical people yes like
leprechauns
and that's just kind of an Testament to
what the the weed Market should probably
be it should be so loose and LAX that
you can just sell it from your house
maybe you should still have to have some
testing on it you know and testing can
come down in pricing if it's on a larger
scale so that there's access to safe cuz
the best thing about recreational weed
was the fact that the testing you know
like at the very least now whether the
numbers are cooked on THC or not yeah
like the heavy metal contents like those
things are yeah like pesticides and like
that having clean weed is was probably
the best thing that came out of all of
that cuz everybody was doing crazy [ __ ]
before that the peak of Happiness was
pre
2018 so there you had 20 TS no no no no
you you had a lot less I mean it was
testing was going on yeah but then you
also had like people could grow at home
and get it in the shops right 2007 to
2012 yeah there's a lot of gray area
like I was very skeptical of like this
is just some measure D prop D was
2012 I was like they're just going to
get everybody to give them their info
and then come arrest them or something
so it was like I never signed up for
licenses yeah early on it was
regrettable because the people that did
got you know grandfathered in they they
actually probably like one of the very
few groups that actually maybe yeah made
money I was pre yeah like made money
during you know the the Cannabis history
over the past 20 years um and
um you know they they provided a good
service but it was a really great area I
mean You' basically you'd have shops
that had phony paperwork you had shops
that maybe had real paperwork these ones
would get rided one day this one would
there was a federal agent going around
raing legal places and telling them they
had three days to shut down yeah they
were threatening you know landlords that
they would seize their property at one
point if they you know didn't evict the
the tenants yeah there was all types of
you know all types of weird hurdles that
that Canabis has been thrown over the
years people being able to operate
safely is another benefit of totally
it's that's one of the things that
attracted me have changed yeah was
definitely one of the big things that
attracted me I was like I'd been you
know you're just looking over your
shoulder for so many years you're just
like I'm so tired you don't even have to
look in the mirror anymore yeah now you
know now you you know you're like okay
we're we're doing everything we possibly
can to be legal and operate and you go
home at night and feel comfortable and
sleep and not be worried about like you
know some kind of you know legal uh
problem yep and remember always looking
in the rearview mirror always
and I you know that comes from earlier
paranoia parano you guys
roaring paranoid is your best friend he
keeps you out of trouble you know no I
never uh got PO for weed well once but
yeah it's it's definitely something if
you don't have some sense of paranoia
you know keeping you safe then you know
man I'm jealous I know I I still stress
about [ __ ] I did uh like in College yeah
and I think that's probably just cuz
you're a good person yeah you know like
people that but but but just thinking
like [ __ ] you could have done serious
time oh yeah you took a lot of risks you
did it yeah there was definitely like
drives that I went on into the you know
into the humbled Hills where I was like
I could have definitely not came back we
we had like car accidents with on Route
93 in Boston it was like a seven car
pile up oh wow and me and my friend
Ethan had pounds of weed in the back of
his uh his like
SUV and my neck was like completely
thrown up like for weeks later I was
like could barely move my neck but we
just wanted to get out of there yeah and
fortunately the cops were like you guys
are okay your car doesn't look damaged
you can go we're like thank you wow yeah
that blows W yeah when with weed you got
to take a lot of uh you know sacrifices
like that I I flew back from Miami
airport with uh two blue Samson I filled
with Colombian before they had dogs or
or
X-rays and made
it nice yeah yeah it was really good I
was I got it from Rick I'm want to say
the real story Rick hman who was the
original owner of Rick's Cafe in N Grill
Jamaica and I met him in in 1975 in
Negril Jamaica at his bar on the west
coast of the
island and uh we became friends and then
he like called me like the next year and
I flew to Miami to meet him that's sick
I don't know where Rick is but wherever
you are Rick or if you're not with us
anymore VIP
buddy yep Rick was a cool
guy I so that's the nl5 which is super
and so you're doing like a lot of
genetic work now in making seeds and
selling seeds but you're also like doing
archival type work and bringing out
stuff like the nl5 so what's the future
look
like hunting new stuff yeah creating new
with old um like right now I just pop
seeds like of my blueberry strain
crossed with the NL so I'm be like I
feel like these two TPS
can uh you know complement each other in
a unique way and create like like the is
such a a high U blueberry cross with no
it's just nl5 right this is nl5 what is
nl5 uh the original cut of Northern
Lights uh number five from like the
early 90s this was I don't think I've
ever trains that I ever smoked in high
school that I was like this was like a
branded strain at that point like the
name it the strain had a name people
were going crazy for it this is this was
10th grade for me right here well I
didn't realize that like the numbers
were different crosses like I thought
they were just different fenos but I
guess each NL is its own like the one is
a different props from the two from the
five from the 10 they're all their
own yeah and and when when I first got
it here in the valley when I was going
to Granada in 10th Grade it was actually
Hawaiian NL Hawaiian NL number five is
what they called it and uh now I don't
know if someone put the Hawaiian name on
it just for like for the sake of doing
it or was it really a Hawaiian NL cross
at that point too interesting I mean I
I've heard that same story that other
people were getting that I had some that
Hawaiian in the days Hawaiian was just
fire killer yeah I had a friend of mine
that used to get it we will not mention
his name um and uh no two ounces were
the same they was all small little batch
yeah and all of it was Unreal and fruity
limey I remember some Red Buds is as red
as like red red yeah you know uh just
like the col old Colombian but this was
from Kawaii and it was fresh red mhm and
it was just
amazing yeah that that was I think one
of the appeals to cannabis too as you
get into it is like all the different
varieties oh my God you know that that
are out there and like in the stories of
like oh dude there's this amazing strain
and you're like you know when you're
really enthusiastic about weed you're
it's like somebody saying to you there's
like you know if you if you like pizza
or oranges or some kind of food that you
just love right and somebody tells you
that you there's this amazing place that
has the best oranges or the best pizzas
mangoes whatever it is yeah mangoes is
Whatever Gets you going like mangoes and
siky rice yeah it's like I feel like
it's super similar to Coffee Culture
it's super similar to Wine culture yeah
totally like there's a lot of
the direction it's going is is a
path we've already gone down yeah it's I
feel
like it's going to be a few there there
a few lanes right there's the lane of
like the people that are breeding to
just create
biomass right that are like we we create
these strains that are really
vigorous um high yielders and and
numeric Sten T high THC yeah yeah all of
the the metrics based stuff right where
you're just like it's an like yeah
anybody can grow it and but it's like
does anybody really like it you know
like a lot of
times it can be done like I personally
believe that like my new version of of
the blueberry which started with like
blueberry my first Beyond blueberry in
like
2015 uh that I crossed with the ozk mail
became uh bzk then we cross cross that
uh with
um uh cookies and cream ozk mail went
into that bzk to make uh the next
version of the like the bzk 2.0 and uh
is this all written down on a
chart yeah I should I should write it
down on a chart really yeah I it might
be like compan history yeah it might be
in the company stuff like the F we have
a pretty large uh Google drive with
everything we've created yeah that rules
so it's like a I can go and look at it
but it's like it would take me a long
time to try to find that but I should
write it down and just put on the
website like a lineage
chart that'd be amazing cuz it went from
that cookies and cream ozk mail cuz I
when I did that first round with the
mail of the
ozk I was still early on in the breeding
process like I was saying I only used
that mail once I didn't think that I
should keep this mail as a as a cut a
clone off of it and keep that mail
forever because if I would have the
everything that came from that was just
Epic from that male right now the things
that came from that I found really good
males out of all those things too but
that one male was very special like it's
funny a lot of people's one that got
away
is often a female not a not a male
that's that's super cool yeah yeah uh
I've been pretty good at uh keeping the
genetics we haven't really lost anything
you collect pollen no I've never really
kept the pollen I just do the seeds mhm
um pollen is like so small amount it's
hard to to see it and then you put it in
the freezer I mean I tried once and then
I was like I don't know if this is going
to work and then like a year there's no
real like expert around there telling
you how to handle pollen and freeze it
properly um does it get Frozen I mean I
think that's how you have to store it is
as you freeze it yeah but like you stick
get in a glass jar and freeze it is what
I did and uh I don't know yeah I mean
did you ever try to use it fall I I did
throw it on a plant I don't I don't
think it worked yeah you know but the
problem is it doesn't throw it sticks to
the it's like static like just sticks to
whatever it is if you yes it does side
of the bag whatever yeah so you kind of
have to like take yeah like a brush or
whatever it is and try to get it on
there and even I was like taking the the
jar and like swirling it on the you know
like on that on like like I was covering
the whole plant with it
um yeah and you know what I heard
something about bees having the opposite
um charge of pollen and which makes it
stick to them or something like that
suck it up their legs that Mak sense
makes a lot of sense you know they're
the masters of pollen they we need more
bees yeah uh so when you're making your
seeds it sounds like you're you've
almostly talked about working with males
and making R so you're not not doing fem
or reversals no I haven't done that yet
um I do want to get into it for just
certain preservation aspects to say okay
here's a to lock something in yeah in
that in that time and space of what it
is you know like um not to lock it in
for the sense of that it was perfect and
I just there's no what there's no better
this string can get because I feel like
you can always kind of from what I've
seen I've been able to chase Tarpin and
move a that tpine from through multiple
genetic processes and carry that tpine
over into like five six breeding
projects later and get all the fenos
that I want so you get that perfect one
but it takes time like like that's why I
say our blueberry is one of those ones
right now where after I did the ozk
cookies and cream mail into that pheno
hunted that found the most blueberry one
of that and every one of those things I
was talking about before and then also
then cross it into the GDP oh very Co
right so then that added like something
else to it oh and the GDP is something
you still holds uh I don't have it
anymore because it it just is it's a
finicky plant really was and it was just
there was no demand to it and I still
have like Original Seed packs so I was
like if I'm going to do it I'll go for
the seed pack again cuz the cut was
weakened at that point and there wasn't
really a whole lot of tissue culture
stuff and tissue culture to me is still
kind of on the fence whether it's good
or bad so you're not doing tissue
culture I have stuff backed up in tissue
culture I was just wondering
so like stuff comes out of it after
you've that it just kind of changes your
strain a little
bit now some strains I think it does it
to more than others and other strains it
doesn't affect as much so at what point
are you going to be fenal hunting in the
plant's
growth always feno hunting even when it
before it buds on the stem you do you
smell stems oh are you talking about
like at what point do you start coling
no looking for like a special resiny you
know or punch into I like I rub the
stems before they flower in veg always
I'm rubbing I'm trying to pick up notes
even early on and like and that was what
was so unique about like the ozk when I
was doing the ozk the first time there's
no other way to do the mail well is
there no well you can you could go for
traits as far as Vigor yeah
but I'd already been growing the
Skittles before I got the seed pack
right so when I rubbed this the Skittles
stock it to me it
has like a Savory Menthol type tone to
it like there's something very
like to yeah something there that I
associate with Menthol yep um and then
when I was doing the feno hunt on the
ozk even the the keeper pheno that we
had like it was I think it was the the
the
O3 was the the one we that that we've
kept forever is and um and then the male
they both had crazy
Skittles uh in the stock rub just like
how the Skittles Did so I had something
I could AB to you know and compare you
know and uh those stood out so yeah for
sure like but yeah when you're breeding
you're definitely you're going to rub
the stocks you're going to try to
identify the those crazy turbs but
you're also it's not the only thing like
sometimes it totally changes on you and
or there's something that's just
undetectable till it's finished Y and
um and then this sometimes the Vigor or
the yield of something you know
like you know you might you might make a
cross like
um like the ozk cookies and cream like
from what we did and there are ones that
were super turpy that wouldn't wash
right like how you know a very turpy
string can be is you want more of that
Sandy dry sort of more greasy yeah when
it's greasy it's great for BHO when it's
when it's uh you know drer drier it's
for your you want that for your rosin is
is one of the signs of of testing and
looking at things and that seems to have
held up over the years as a an approach
of philosophy to to detect how things
will turn out and I think it makes some
intuitive sense you're like heads that
are less inclined to burst yeah are less
inclined to bur yeah and then there's
all the whole thing about how things are
frozen and handled and processed without
damaging all the heads too but uh I
think in an ideal world like for washers
and BHO guys that you would want to keep
like two of the top fenos that are
really similar but perform better one
performs better in BHO and one performs
better in a solventless wash and still
actually put a ratio of one to the other
together
and get a blend so it's like yeah you
know what this one only washes at like
one and a half% but it has a crazy tur
profile on it it's more turp and this
one is hitting your 5% and uh has a a
good tur profile too but the two
together will make something even better
you know and knowing that that you're
selecting fenos that taste the same you
know that they're very similar that when
they combine they still don't they just
add to each other you know like um
and how many runs from clone and are you
making these
decisions uh so typically
like a lot of people that are breeding
or that are that are running from seed
packs MH um they'll B be buying tons of
seed and just be planning outside and
they just have crazy varieties and doing
big outdoor or they'll buy like designer
packs like high-end packs like I'm
trying to create these you know our bird
seed line and and have really unique
genetics um but the way I do things is I
I grow up from the seed the plant I cut
a clone off of it or maybe two or three
or whatever then I throw that Original
Seed away so you don't even flower out
the top R your plant no okay it's it's a
it's a waste of time yeah um feminized
what's that are they feminized no not
fiz oh well no and the reason I say it's
a waste of time uh for me now if if you
a big field that one plant is going to
perform really unique and it's only
going to perform that way that one time
mhm after you cut the Clone off of that
and you're like you you take that clone
and you flower out that clone it doesn't
look and perform the same way so if
you're trying to take data that says hey
this plant gets three 6 ounces of plant
or something like that and it grows this
way like the the seed versus the Clone
is are going to be different right so
you're if you're looking to have
something that's going to last a long
time and not just run it once so you can
actually be searching through the seeds
for something interesting it's it's that
first run from GL cuz I heard some
people even try to say that things
stable out
over stabil out stabilize out more over
time yeah um that's why land races are
very similar like pretty much Thai used
to be Thai and it had the Thai smell and
taste it could be grown better or worse
but it was the same plant and flavor
that's why it's like OG Kush was a
perfect example of that type of test
experiment on a large scale because so
many people eventually got the OG cut
we're all growing OG cush mhm and
uh you would see it just look different
from place to place because of everybody
even though we're all growing in the
valley here or in Hollywood or Lancaster
or san berardino is like you could tell
it was OG but everybody's OG looked
different just because of the
microclimates of everybody's different
room the little differences of water
well you mentioned it earlier that's how
so many of the different like phenos
were birthed of
OG it was just like this batch was this
way so we're calling it this and then
this batch and was all the same cut yeah
totally I mean if you had a legit cut or
a descendant of the legit cut you know
well then there were all the s1s yeah
there was fire too for sure yeah and
then you had stuff that like DNA
genetics did with like Kosher Kush I
think and which is I love the
Kosar yeah those were all great strains
like um so you brought up DNA a couple
of times are they sort of like what
breeders did you look up to or did you
definitely DNA were the first that like
I was maybe just at a different there's
these other seed companies out there
that were around like Mr nice or I I'm
not e I wasn't in East Coast I didn't
see that and I was maybe too young to
see that in the 80s so when the '90s
rolled
around um that is what I saw you know
DNA
uh
and you know maybe it was not even the
'90s and more maybe early 2000s even cuz
I didn't really start buying
seeds so probably like after
2005 you know was like I would just find
bag seeds yeah yeah wow you know like
you know when I got bubble gum I bought
enough Bubble Gum to where I found a
really good bag seat of it and I it
turned out just like bubblegum I that's
one of the ones
really what the bubblegum your your yeah
it's cool I've popped a couple bubble
gummy things from bog old seeds they
never they just don't really want to
live yeah yeah um but it's a cool tur
yeah I really like sweet powdery you
know bubblegum like do do some do some
of your strains grow better Outdoors
than
others or they're all I would say yeah I
would say that
um almost like under the right
conditions right with a healthy plant
going outside I feel like the outdoor is
going to perform better tpine profile
every time if it's a if it's a good year
of weather Southern California Sun as an
example yeah but what I was asking is
like
if have you seen a difference
in how the plants grow from strain to
strain yeah like each genetic is vastly
different like our pink Picasso is slow
in veg uhhuh like you can get it to go
faster by using a smaller Cube like on
indoor like instead of vegging it in a
six like if you veg it in a 2x4 it it'll
stretch and get a little bigger faster
and is that just like it just
has that from the Z probably yeah you
know and cookies as well wasn't like a a
fast oh right there's the Candy Land in
it too yeah yeah very cool so none of
those were like vigorous fast vegging
plants whereas like if I do that with
our you know using a smaller Cube versus
a bigger cube in veg will always result
whatever strain to speed up a little bit
and and get a little bigger faster more
space you give it yeah it's like uh no
it's it's actually the smaller and it's
it's it's counterintuitive to basic
logic but it's I think it has to do with
the dry Downs in a 4in cube yeah like a
four like a 4 in 2 in X4 or 4x4
Cube it can only hold so much water and
the plant actually uses what's kind of
there whereas if you're in a six it's
like this small little plant can't drink
that whole Cube and and nor does the
cube like naturally perspire out right
enough water to like give it the right
environment for the for like rapid
growth early on as you put the Clone in
it's like when you put a clone into a
six or a eight that's coming from a 1in
cube like you going to get a slower veg
that first week until like the plant
adapts to it or it could be even two
weeks depending if you're really
overwatering which is something you're
going to run into potentially easily
easier with a bigger cube and a smaller
plant and so and all of your stuff is
grown in Cube
yeah everything that uh we've ever grown
is is been for our indoor line yeah has
been uh in Rockwell in Rockwell yeah and
then if it's for our concentrates and
our vape pens and stuff like that it's
come from outdoor very cool and then
um yeah I guess I but there's no but is
there any flower from the outdoor no I
smoked all of
it it is it's like the for flow it's
week I take a few ounces of it when we
have it you know and then it's like the
rest of it going to go into the freezer
yeah back to my original question did
outdoor in Santa Barbara did which was
the best growing strain that was I think
what I was trying to get out it was
there a Best growing strand or yeah
there's ones that perform pretty crazy
like
um our melon
OG uh would just be like these like Half
Dome Circles of and without even topping
it or anything I mean get Spears yeah it
would just be it would just be made up
of nothing but the spears shooting out
of it and it's it almost looked like
somebody came in and shaped it into
these Half Dome circles like almost
perfect half circles and they'd be maybe
five six feet wide and what is the melan
OG melan OG was from seed packs that
were given to me by Karma uh Karma Squad
oh right yeah yeah the melon they haveon
so hunted like two packs of theirs found
a really good melon OG that was vigorous
and and uh it was a great washer too
yeah yeah so I BR with that to make
washing strains as well too for the bird
line seed that rules yeah yeah yeah that
karma karma every year still in Vogue
still the coolest yeah no he he does you
know really good projects they're large
scale and they take their time cuz they
they have all that ability there so
that's what it helps a lot too like if
you are working with very modest means
you have to be very selective about what
you're doing and if you're working with
mass scale you can be like yeah you know
what we can do you know 30 to 100
different tests right if you if you have
the infrastructure to support it all yes
we all dream of that it would be nice
careful what you wish for something what
is it you have with you see was okay so
uh these are like the newest drops that
just came out on the uh birdseed uh
genetics.com and also on um uh Neptune
so we just got the seeds so they are we
going to put them up on the FCP seed
bank uh yeah sure let's do it I'm of
course I want to share seeds with the
world and a lot of the Creations that
I've created so this is the that nl5
cross with u our jzk 15 which is the
chloroform which is actually
I actually don't have it in here right
now but uh that is the jealousy cross
with the Kush Cola okay so gelousy cush
Cola made a really unique uh like
gassier version of the um the Kush does
it go kind of shy the way um it's it's
got that Cola Cherry turp but it's just
like a a much like almost like just
really gassy is all I can say is and
that's why I kind of went with the
chloroform name because I was like o you
know you're just like it's one of those
ones that is is very you know uh fumy
the train row or no like that's more of
the tendine thing that I was talking
about earlier I'm not into yeah it's
more of like
the
like um I don't know it's like mercy and
yeah it's like a it's like a fuel like a
like a fume fuel gas that reminds me
when I would go to like a hair salon and
like when when I was a kid and like be
like uh my mom would get your hair done
and they'd all be doing like this this
chemical for their hair it was like I
was like how could they handle that I'm
like holy [ __ ] you know what I mean it
reminds me of that so there's like those
latexy rubbery like Botti kind of has
that yeah yeah yeah so it's very
offensive in that side so that's the NL
cross to that yeah and these all uh
these two there's there's two of them
that have that cross right now so Kush
Cola C
which was the wedding cake uh and the
Kush Cola so that's like a more like
powdery
sugary Cherry Cola yeah right and then
this is roadkill cookies which is the
the GMO with the orange banana Picasso
that's the male so the orange banana is
again like one of the highest washers
that we've ever you know come across and
uh crossed out with the pink Picasso um
into that male into the pink Picasso got
the orange Picasso use the orange
Picasso male
into the GMO to make this like
Road totally cool yeah there's there's
some real gas in here and then this is
one I haven't put out yet called Theta
uh this is our Beyond blueberry uh with
the oie Kush cross with of gak so very
cool and the gak also from ding bre no
the gak is um I think it was from heds
oh like okay yeah I there was a group of
guys that that had that g strain and
they were all putting it out at the same
time for some reason like it seemed like
I think it was maybe massive another guy
and uh uh ding breed I think also had
like gak variations and stuff like that
so very cool that one I bet there's some
real winners in there yeah I mean I've
been very fortunate like uh I've been
breeding with very uh unique strains
that I've been able to either create
myself or get you know find and get
gifted or are floating around and
they're accessible um so I I'm I'm not
really just playing with genetics that
are uh random right like I'm picking
very specific things for specific
reasons cuz I think that these two types
of tpin are going to work well together
um and then there your reputation
precedes you appreciate that thank you
uh
as an appreciator of Wonder but buds
from way back it's that's a very nice
compliment um and I I I I really do
appreciate that because it's nice to
know that the all these things that I do
you know behind closed doors kind of
just I'm not showing them but I'm it's I
need to get better at at filming myself
and and creating content um but I just
find myself like doing something and
then I'm halfway through it and I forgot
to turn on the camera right and so I'm
like well I'm not going to go back and
recreate the front half and you know
like just going to just finish this off
and do that describe Peter wor nightmare
yeah so it that's it's one of my faults
like I just start fiddling with
something and then 30 minutes later I
kind of have something and or I've done
something or whatever and um but a lot
of times with the breeding process
though the tpine selections are very
deliberate like with that kush
Cola I was isn't going to breed ozk with
something like GMO which is actually
ended up turning out to be a pretty
decent cross out there which I've seen I
think one of the people call it's the
high frequ corn syrup or whatever
something like that there is a feno of
it that turned out pretty good but
intuitively for the way that I normally
approach things um I'll try to take
something that
is uh like Fruity or not so recessively
dominant that o k or a skittles TP or a
sweet turp profile like that has the
ability to blend together versus just
creating something weird that doesn't
really have a great flavor or like or
just gets weird and just goes into like
this like it almost defaults into like a
a citrus flavor that you don't
appreciate or like M you know like I'll
find that that you know you can find all
these different fenos into something
that are really good but then there'll
be that weird one you're like that's is
just gross tpine of some kind of I had a
z thing yesterday that like this was
like tomato water almost and I was like
just like yeah there's wrong selection
yeah totally you're like that does not
sound good at any even like if
tomato even tomato water doesn't taste
good you know like yeah no I don't know
they were it's it's you know it's
citrusy and it was there was a littleit
Tangi thing there but it was kind of it
was tomato water yeah yeah there's some
really random [ __ ] out there that does
not have like a desirability
yeah to to me well sometimes the things
that you think would work don't like
I've never seen just straight lemon tree
and Skittles Mak sense to even though
like on paper that sounds like it would
rock lemon is just so recessive and
dominant it's like anything you cross
like lemon with is just going to come
out with lemon dominance over it and
that's why that's what I'm kind of
talking about is like allowing for
whatever you're breeding to cross into
something that will where you can still
get a representation of both a dominant
ter yeah and hopefully you're getting it
like a sliding scale this way like 10%
of the father and 90% of the mother or
the other side of the scale you know 90%
of the the father and 10% of the mother
right like in good yeah then you know
there's the 50/50 in the middle like
this is exact like the Oz K is like in
my opinion is is literally half OG half
and half oh you're say the dominance is
not a good thing the breed the half and
half is better no I think you want both
yeah I think you want all I think there
happens you could get one where it's a
perfect blend of yeah like you know uh
like the ozk and
um Clementine like that's what made
really nice that that's what made our
lemon citrine right and the lemon ozk
feno there was two different really
great fenos in there both where like it
just had this perfect really enjoyable
lemon tone to it but also this mandarin
orange aspect to it that came from the
Clementine right and uh which is also
hard to get rid of yeah yeah like but
there are fenos of orange and lemon that
are more enjoyable than other fenos yeah
there's ones that are like really
astringent and offensive that aren't as
that Sting the nose or become just too
offensive in a dab they're hard on your
throat and they're hard to breathe they
make people kind of sensitive and then
there's ones that you're like wow that
is a really smooth lemon you know like
and I think that's where like the lemon
ozk and the
uh the uh the lemon Catrine were were
really great selections of of of unique
lemon turps that had lemon and Mandarin
variations more orange on this side or
more lemon on this side yeah and not as
much as just in the middle you know hey
I wanted to ask you um you said you were
experimenting with some out out of state
Ventures yeah yeah how is that working
and is that does that equal new Brad
stores out of state or no no it's not
retail it's just flower production um
our first expansion was Michigan but
that just came to an end unfortunately
and so you guys are actually expanding
infrastructure not just
IPA uh no we work with cultivations that
like typically what ends up happening is
uh cultivations in other states they
they get set up early they had the money
in the financing so a lot of the out
ofate situations end up being where it's
a really good time for the first people
that get on the scene quickly they can
produce whatever type of product and
it'll do well cuz it's a
very uh like limited quantity right
there's a ton of excitement when a New
Market opens yeah and then competition
comes in and you need kind of a higher
level of expertise to stand out and and
to make sense of when prices start to
come down you need to be able to produce
higher yields with higher quality to be
uh competitive so that's typically when
grow will reach out to us and and or
Partnerships will start to happen when
the markets are getting tougher we've
never been really lucky enough to get
licenses out of state or have enough uh
you know money to to go build $10
million in you know an emerging market
right like with the deals that you have
are you also um I guess are like
prescribed s so is or are they running
your genetics their way no they they
know that they want our help yeah and it
it's been very good in that sense like
when it was Michigan and in Arizona the
the teams that were there that were uh
put together we went there and showed
them our Sops how we do things that
makes you know weekly phone calls uh you
know if there's a question about this
just call us we're you know we're not
you know we we've been doing it for a
long time so we know how things should
work right and you when you go somewhere
that doesn't really have the same level
experience they're still figuring it out
and it's it's normally not like they're
super far off it's just like a few
tweaks here in this phase and a few
tweaks here in this phas you know they
everybody's got lights and air
conditioners and Deus and plants that
are growing and you know got fertigation
going but it's just about how you use
every one of those things you know how
how you're running your environmental
how you're using your lighting and how
you're keeping your plant Health you
know the products that you're using are
they not necessary or are they necessary
and some people have just over
complicated it what kind of lighting do
you like I like a combination of the uh
the double-ended and the LED together
uhuh in in a a room a checker board the
checker board Westing okay cool and do
you notice there being like weaker spots
in the room because
no it it ends up kind of being a nice
throw because on a
checkerboard you know you're getting o
like this this yeah you're getting
everything like uh overlapping MH in
different places and you get a pretty
even uh Lighting in that sense do you
have more lights then per square foot
checkerboarding or is it about the same
it's about the same like every 5 ft mhm
you know um and to me that that always
gave us like
The Best of Both Worlds um I think LED
veg lights are are superior
to um bulbs so we use LED lighting and
veg and MH and when you can when you're
transitioning from led to the your Bloom
room you want LED in your Bloom room so
you don't have this transitional shock
where that's where a lot of people like
their plants go from being like healthy
and veg and they go to their Bloom room
and the environment's different the
lighting's different and everything kind
of just responds in a a negative way
until it acclimates to that new
environment then it starts to grow again
properly but so you're saying keep the
environments the same in each stage of
growth yeah when you're transitioning
from one room to the next you should try
to keep it similar from the transition
yeah don't go from 300 ppfd in veg to
1,000 ppfd In Bloom and not expect to
plants to be shocked you know like um
humidity uh light you know the the air
conditioning the temperatures they
should be relatively similar going from
your your veg space to your Bloom space
yeah sounds logical yeah at a certain
scale is there
like math on having a veg in a bloom
room versus just having stuff go through
the whole process in a single room yeah
no doubt I I think
um it's if you doing like Drop flip TR
with if you're able to transition with
moving your plants into bloom right and
get six Harvest or maybe even seven
Harvest a year out of that one room
depending on a genetic some genetics
like Skittles are like 49 days to me you
know like that allows you to get you
know to get your seven is woof but yeah
you can do it but um certain strains
though that you got to take 56 63 days
65 days you know maybe 67 like that's
about the extent of the length that will
let it go because just economically it
it messes with your schedule around the
whole building and keeping the flow
proper one also just like square footage
utilization you know you can have plants
more compact in vegge and then you move
them into your flower room where the
things are your trays are a little more
spaced out and yeah totally um but I
think that's when they need more space
this has been an amazing conversation
yeah thanks for coming down BR yeah
really could probably talk for a long
time but it would make sense to wrap it
up but yeah thank you so much for being
there yeah dude it was awesome thank you
for having me appreciate you very high
right now oh yeah yeah we SP it so so
unpleasant having to sample all of the
herb thank you yeah no problem no that
was great right on that was awesome
okay uh
yes or when you wake up and you feel
like you need a little up or when you're
down and out and you need to get a
little higher if you feel like you need
a blessing and you feel a little higher
today welcome to the Church of C high C
high C
High you've been listening to C High
episode 69 Brett in the backyard with
Brett Feldman of wonderbrett I'm your
host chenzo and we'd like to thank Brett
for coming down to the
backyard our special guest hosts today
were Peter chieri and Gabe from the
future cannabis
project Brett and wonderbrett can be
found on Instagram at
wonderbrett and at Brett of
wonderbrett on the web
at
www.w wonder.com
the future cannabis project can be found
on Instagram at bud gasm and at Future
cannabis project on YouTube at
fcp1 and at
fcp2 C High's theme written and recorded
by Vince nicoletti Jordan web and namir
blade C High podcast and theme are
copywritten and the logo is trademark
marked please donate to cigh at
okay we're going on
that we going here we going everywhere
else we're going everywhere else you
just got to stand here a turn and do the
clap this is chenzo just do the and a
clap and of course
bre there we go all right that might
beit de out but I think that's a keeper
I think it is [ __ ] right that was one of
your best claps chenzo oh I I could have
done better but I mean for the moment I
accept it