coming up on garden talk so if your
plant's kind of weak
and you're trying to train some of your
plants and get better growth
you got to train it and it snaps instead
of just kind of bending
well that's because a lot of it might be
not
enough silica that your plants are
getting are using or in available form
the chelation is a multivalent ion
with the cation exchange it's another
one of those cation exchanges that
it can chelate and change some of the
multivalent bonds ion bonds
and help with different plants to
chelate different nutrients or to lock
things out
enzymes are what help with how plants
express themselves
how they use nitrogen you know as a
newbie
keeping it simple i can grab a couple
boxes of a couple ingredients that have
some beneficial biology and some good
nutrients
and start with that
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 13.
in this episode i interview medically
fit he is a youtuber that has over 18
000 subscribers
and he's been creating gardening content
since 2013.
he has been gardening for 10 years now
and he grows vegetables
medicinal and house plants in this
episode we talk about
10 different dry amendments that you can
use in your garden
there are so many different amendments
out there that can be used we just cover
a
short list today we talk about what the
amendments are what the benefits are
and application rates don't forget to
subscribe to this channel if you haven't
already
if you're listening on one of the
podcast platforms like apple podcasts
please leave a rating and review if
you're liking these episodes and you
want to support even more
you can do that through patreon the link
to that is patreon.com
mr growit i'll leave a link to my
patreon down in the description section
below
for those of you who are viewing on
youtube that being said i hope you
enjoyed this episode
let's just get into it all right
medically
fit welcome to garden talk how you doing
doing good
how are you doing i'm doing great man
i'm super excited to have you on dude
i've actually been following your
channel since like 2013.
so you were like one of the first people
that i've actually started watching so
i'm like fanboying it out a little bit
that's interesting to me because i
didn't really know that you were kind of
a fan of mine
and so it's really nice to know that you
know you were one of the people who
actually like
i think you were one of the first people
to actually nudge me over to the organic
side of things i remember really came
onto my live stream one time and
i was like checking the ph of the runoff
and you're like why do you check the ph
with the organics you don't have to and
you're like come over to my world you
know come on
yeah yeah you were definitely an
inspiration for me to kind of
transitioning over i mean
the the amount of knowledge that you
have on the organic side of thing
is something i admire so i'm super
excited to have you on the show today
but um thanks for having me very glad to
be here
cool um so for those that don't know who
you are can you just tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
growing
well um i've been a cultivators
since 2000 11 12-ish
started kind of learning uh when i lived
in las vegas
um back then i wanted to know about
cultivating vegetables and
additional you know plants for
me and nevada was a medical state so i
could
so i really wanted to kind of know and
that's what got me into it
um what kind of pushed me even harder is
i lost my father
and like being around
plants and just growing really helped
because i didn't have like the cognitive
skills and understand how to deal with
that type of loss in my life
and it really helped me deal with how to
get through the loss because i was able
to get in and kind of take care of
things and
like just sit there and be with the
plants and it was nice
and so medicinal plants you're only
fruits veggies are you indoors outdoors
or what um i do like
summertime we try to get our garden
going so we'll do vegetable crops
squash tomatoes peppers i try to do
some other like mints and herbs
for in the house outdoor
we do some municipal plants we just
recently moved to pueblo area
it's kind of harder to do it here the
heat
it's really dry it's sometimes almost
just as bad as living in las vegas
um but i do a lot more indoor
if possible um it's easier to control
some of my environment conditions i can
grow year-round
instead of just through the summer and
spring
seasons down here in pueblo we have a
little bit later fall so i can get a
little bit later crop outdoors if i need
to
for some of my vegetables so kind of a
little bit of both really nice nice
cool all right so let's get into the
topic today so we're going to talk all
about
dry amendments so there are so many
different
dry amendments that can be incorporated
in your garden right dozens of different
amendments
we're not going to be able to talk about
all of them today unfortunately we'll
talk about a handful of them
but you have a whole wealth of knowledge
in regards to a lot of these amendments
and that's really what i want to pick
your brain on today
i watched your video that you have on
dry nutrient tea
so your nutrient tea video and this kind
of inspired
the questions that i have for you today
i basically have a list of amendments
that we're going to go over for him and
have a feeling that a lot of my viewers
aren't even going to like be aware
of these amendments so um i guess this
would probably maybe be like a more
intermediate slash
advanced type topic you know because a
lot of these things that we talk about
they're they're not used
in a lot of um normally used
application garden settings like
some of the amendments that i use most
people don't use
in their garden settings i do it for
a specific reason and most of my reason
is
everything that i've been learning and
understanding from
all of the self-taught education growing
up in iowa
around farmers trying to learn you know
understand
cultivation it's about diversity
and so i try to use a vast
variety of different dry organic
amendments and most people are like oh
that's a lot
well i don't know what the plant wants
or needs
i try to give it everything possible
that makes sense
so let's just get right into it then
let's uh let's start with gypsum
so that's one of the things that you
incorporate and so talk to us about
gypsum what you know what are the
benefits
how do you apply it so on and so forth
well
gypsum is it's a calcium
and a sulfur kind of
powder it's really water soluble uh
it works great for a lot of people
find that their plants or soil are like
calcium deficient or the plants
have a little bit of calcium deficient
this is pretty
high amendment like 22 percent calcium
and like 17
sulfur in some of this so it's pretty
high
there's several different ways you can
mix it in i do
a tea i will mix it in a super soil mix
when i'm trying to make
like a soil to grow in
so there's a couple different
applications um
a lot of people really just do it more
as a top feeding
or a soil you know like a uh
super soil like i'm saying or a tea um
just from the solubility
uh kind of repeat myself a little bit
sorry
um some of it also helps with like root
growth
nutrient uptake uh cation exchange
calcium really does a lot for the plant
and this is part of what we're
trying to do is get the plant these
available nutrients
gypsum has calcium sulfur
readily available to it so that's what
we're trying to do
um a lot of what really i found
very interesting because a lot of people
are concerned
with some of my soil mixes being high in
heavy metals
well gypsum actually helps to reduce
some of these heavy metal toxins from
manganese to boron to aluminum it kind
of binds it up so
the plant can't uptake it and so
when a lot of people are concerned about
like using trace miserals
trace minerals like azomite that we're
going to talk about
that's one of them that kind of has some
higher heavy metals to it
but this will help prevent those heavy
metals from being uptaken in the plant
so it's really interesting it helps with
soil structure
runoff um kind of helps retain water a
little bit
instead of allowing it to run off um
balances the ph kind of like
what dolomite lime can do real
similar but it's actually to me and if
quite a few other people gypsum's better
than dolomite lime
in some ways so there's a lot of really
interesting information that comes with
just gypsum itself i know you use the
down to earth
gypsum yes when we talk about
application rates
i mean i know you said you can use it as
like a rich soil conditioner
also as a top rest do you know the
application rates off top of your head
or
just refer to the box um i do
and i don't so i'll give it to you in a
two-part
deal depending on the size of
pot gallon to bale
like my measurements that i have already
on like some of my super
soil it's made out for a bale so it can
be
anywhere from a cup and a half to six
cups just depending on
how much you're really trying to add to
it if you're trying to make it
in a super soil in a five gallon pot
it's like
two tablespoons three tablespoons so
it it really varies on each of these
depending on per gallon per pot or
the amount of soil you're trying to make
so i can give you you know kind of a
just answer but
i'm assuming that most of your audience
are going to make different
sizes of this when they go to use some
of it so
really look on the box see what they
recommend down the earth has
on their website kind of tells you a
little bit you can also
google and some of them do tell a little
different application rates
um so kind of just do a little research
to see what you
what you like i play around a little bit
when i add it
sometimes i add more of it sometimes i
have less of it i kind of see what my
plant is wanting and what's needing so
it's not quite dialed in but i i still
play with my recipe a little bit so
gotcha azomite you mentioned azamite
uh briefly let's talk about that what is
azomite what are the benefits how do you
apply it
azomite is a very interesting deal
it's rock dust that's from ancient
volcanoes
that it's harvested this is where we
talk about some of the heavier minerals
being in the
in the dirt itself because of
everything that's coming up from the
volcano aluminum
magnesium copper lead like
arsenic heavy toxin metals
but it's not so high that i'm concerned
because most of the benefits of trace
minerals
you as humans are we as humans and our
plants both need trace minerals for
major and hormonal functions within the
plant
so believe it or not the plant does need
lead it does need arsenic
it does need copper zinc boron aluminum
not in such high doses but they need it
for
major and minor functions of how we act
how different chemicals are sent
you know through our body through the
plant different hormones
so this really helps the plant basically
be in the homeostasis
so if we can get the
all the trace macro micro nutrients
that's kind of what rock dust azomite is
doing
is giving us that whole variety of all
these different trace minerals
that we don't get from other fertilizers
or amendments
and what that same thing is soil
amendment stools to begin with and also
as a top dress or what would you
recommend
i do it i'll add it to both my teas one
for veg
one for flour just depending on the
cycle i still add it
i do add it to my soil amendments when
i'm doing a top dress
i don't do so much of a top dress with
it because
that's where most my tees i'm trying to
get some of the solubility
if i think i'm having issues then i'm
looking more at my super soil recipe
that i made
instead of looking at like okay what's
going on with my plant
is it because i'm not getting trace
minerals
most of the time i don't have
deficiencies with trace minerals just
because
um i add more than most
because i don't know how much the plant
actually needs
and it needs different minerals at
different times
of its cycle so if i can get the variety
and let the biology and the soil kind of
do what it does
the plant will regulate when it wants it
when it needs it and i just kind of sit
back
rock phosphate what is it what are the
benefits how do you apply it
rock phosphate is really interesting
because
at first i used to use
um i'm trying to remember it's a
bottle of b vitamins um
it's like plant hormones so rock
phosphate
is kind of doing that it's a phosphorus
um that's like the b vitamin
complex that the plant needs for energy
for uh different functions like uh
nutrient fix or nitrogen fixation where
the plant will take different types of
nitrogen and change it to usable
forms it's something that
it helps with photosynthesis that plants
really
photosynthesis is key it
it helps the energy the atp and how the
plant uses energy to create its sugars
produces
its flowers you know and with its growth
so
that's kind of what this rock phosphate
is is that b
complex energy that helps overall with
plant growth
how do you usually use it um this is
it comes a couple different ways it
comes granular or
powder so most of the time i'll mix it
in a tea
try to get the solubility of it not all
of it soluble
um so that's when if i'm trying to amend
the soil i'll just
take that and put it in the soil kind of
help amend it
same thing super soil um if i'm making
a bail um i'll probably use
three cups for one cubic bale
so if i was doing like a five gallon pot
maybe like three tablespoons not
teaspoons tablespoons
because most of it is in tablespoons
it's pretty interesting don't see much
of their
nutrients are on their line or any dry
amendment really
using teaspoons unless you're really
doing like a hydroponic setup or
something along that line
now correct me if i'm wrong rock
phosphate and some of these other
amendments
some are going to take longer to break
down right those microbes that are
breaking down those nutrients
is rock phosphate one of the ones that
take longer like i've heard
on some of these amendments that it
takes
it can take a year to potentially break
down well that's like
green sand for instance and we'll kind
of talk about that later but
greens hands one of them that literally
takes 12 to 14 months before it really
gets
available so yes some of this
takes a while to get and become
available
they're a different breakdown how do i
say
some of it is quick some of it may take
a few
weeks some of it may take a few months
depends on the biology
what the plants really asking for so it
it varies on what's really happening in
your rib zone with the biology
because that's going to be a big thing
that's why a lot of times when i'm
making teas
i'm looking for that solubility of it
where it's readily available almost like
i'm creating a bottle nutrient
getting that solubility ready and then
feeding it to my plant
got it when you talk about solubility
you're talking about basically turning
it into a plant available form
correct a liquid form where it takes
some of that nutrients
and gets it to where it's soluble in the
liquid form
as in insoluble means it's not able to
break down
through water cool how about uh
langbanite
i like that language it's pretty
interesting because it's
pretty much potash it's pretty much
potassium a little bit of magnesium and
sulfur
it's one of those that i put in my soil
mixes
when i'm mixing my super soil but when
it comes to my teas
i try to use it more for flour when my
plants are ready to go
to produce their fruit when they're
flowering when they're ready
to just try to get more flower
development
it's one thing that i'll really kind of
use it's all soluble
it's kind of like a salt but it
when it hits water it will dissolve
basically in the water
it helps with chlorophyll within the
plant
to help get chlorophyll because we
didn't plants need it to kind of help
with photosynthesis
so that's one thing that's kind of key
about using some of this potash
or this langmanite is it only
not only helps with that but it helps
with like the sulfur part of it helps
with
enzyme activation
so it kind of helps some of the enzymes
the proteins
in the plant kind of being able to be
broke down and used
and that's kind of like important
because enzymes are what help
with how plants express themselves
how they use nitrogen how they kind of
develop
so it's really interesting on how some
of like these simple dry amendments
really work on different cellular
levels of the plant and we don't really
realize that
just using them how often do you apply
it do you do a top dressing at all or
just a soil conditioner
uh more of a soil conditioner um if i
wanted to do a top dressing because it's
water soluble it would break down pretty
quickly i'd probably use it
in a beginning stages of flour and fruit
um like if i was flipping like say my
medicinal plants
and i would put it in like maybe two
weeks before they really went in the
flower
because then it's letting the plant kind
of know hey
things are happening things are changing
you know we're getting different
nutrients
and it's kind of where
how people will kind of help the plant
along
doing things before you really put it
into those cycles and that's kind of one
of them
that would be something i would do
dolomite lime
so i think that's probably one of that a
lot of people have heard of it's pretty
common
talk to us about that a lot of people
use
dolomite line for soil conditioning
a lot of people that have acidic soil
dolomite lime helps really buffer and
brings up the
acidity level to more of a neutral
and so if you're growing blueberries you
want more acidic
soil so you really don't want some of
this dolomite lime
but if you're growing plants that
certain crops that more want
your ph to be around six to seven and
your soil
or your water is like a fork this
dolomite lime is going to help
balance it out as it's kind of breaking
down over time
it's high in calcium just like the
gypsum
that's why i try to use both of them
there are two different forms
of calcium and
i'm letting the biology kind of break it
down and the plant
take it up and however you know it's
it's going to be available for it
um zolomite lime also has magnesium
so when a lot of people are like oh i'm
having calmag
problems well i don't quite have that
using
dolomite lime there's so much magnesium
to it that
i shouldn't be having any issues and if
i am it's because it's not
in a form that my plant's able to take
it up now follow-up question on this one
say
hypothetical say you have a grower's
using synthetic nutrients
he gets himself into a bind maybe he
checks his runoff ph
realizes like the low fives needs to
increase that ph wants to utilize
dolomite lime to do that
would you recommend that and then how
long would it take to actually adjust
up that much see that's a good question
because
i haven't really tried that to see
what the solubility is going to do with
ph
so me adding it to uh
a hydroponic i don't know how fast the
ph is going to raise in it
or how much i'm going to have to use for
the setup because if i have a small
setup
it may be like a tablespoon or a
teaspoon
but if i have say 10 buckets that i'm
running like a
dwc or hydroponic setup it may take
a quarter cup gotcha okay so no clear
answer on that one
no not really because i don't i would i
don't play with that enough to really
say
hey if you use it in this fashion this
is
your what your results are going to be
okay oyster shell
talk to us about that that's another
great calcium product
like i don't ever really
seem to have problems with calcium in my
soil
because i have so many different
variances
of getting it in oyster shell
helps strengthen the calcium this is
where it comes back to the calcium again
it helps strengthen cell walls it helps
with different
enzymes um the production in the soil
the shells also give the biology in your
roots or in the soil
like surface area to live off and build
colonies
oyster shell it's not talked about
a lot but it's it's almost like crab
shell
it it can have some kitenase to it i
believe
but nobody's really talking about it and
i haven't seen it but
there's a similar product it's a silica
based carbon based type shell that
to me would have almost like chitin what
crab shell does but
i'm not positive on it i haven't seen a
lot of information on that
and so this can be used soil conditioner
can be used as a top dress all these can
really be used
kind of the same fashion is that correct
yes
and no there's some products that are
more soluble
than others so when it comes to making
teas
some of the products are going to
release more of solubility
it because that's it they're more
soluble
others are not so if you're trying to
make a tea with say
oyster shell it may have to sit a little
longer to break down to get some of the
solubility out of it
as where the lang banite it may sit in
there 20 minutes and already be
dissolved and ready to use
so it does come back to once again some
of the breakdown of
the solubility of these products if
you're going to make a tea
you have to wait for it if you're going
to do a top dress
or amend the soil with it you can put it
right in and let the soil
cook and do what it's going to do and
use it in a couple
30 days or so that makes sense how long
do you usually brew your teas
um 24 to 48 hours
most of them depend on the temperature
and
what i'm really trying to get in my
micro community
and how large of community i'm trying to
build
if i'm trying to water a lot of plants i
may
do more of a heavier tea where i dilute
it
a little bit more after it's been
brewing
that way i can disperse it out and have
a higher count to my watering sometimes
i'll just do
a smaller dosage where i'm like 24 hours
just get a little bit in the water and
then
apply it to my plants and my soil
green sand let's talk about it what is
it
it's basically silica
it's a it's trace minerals
like iron manganese
um it's how do i want to say it's
really different because a lot of like
the green sand that i get is from
glacier rock area where it's really been
pounded and all these trace minerals
from being ground
for however long these glaciers took to
move across
the continent a lot of it's
really fine particles almost
like uh sand like sand
but it's more minerals and not so much
sand
so it's like if you went to the beach
all the sand that you see
it's going to be a little different than
what green sand is
even though it has some trace minerals
to it green sand is going to be a little
bit higher because it's like
an iron content potash
it has like cation exchange
um where it helps pull up nutrients from
the soil
where like calcium is one of those
things that helps
with cation exchange where it helps
certain nutrients be taken up
through an ion exchange and that's kind
of the same thing of what people try to
do with bottled nutrients is they try to
create that
cat ion exchange where it's being pulled
up with all these ions
and that's similar to what green sand is
going to kind of do
but it's in an organic sense it's
straight silica
silica also helps with like the
strengthening of cell walls
and just as well so if your plant's kind
of weak
and you're trying to train some of your
plants and get better growth
you've got to train it and it snaps
instead of just kind of bending
well that's because a lot of it might be
not
enough silica that your plants are
getting are using or in available form
because silica comes in several
different forms
from using like horsetail horsetail is a
another natural product for silica but
that has to take time to break down
just like green sand it's one of those
that's the 12 to 14 month time to break
down
so even if i'm trying to use it now
it's not going to work because like
medicinal users
they plant it pot it four months later
it's done
vegetable gardens plant it pot it
produce
done well this is something that you
want to use more in like a
no-till setup where it has time to break
down
and actually be in the soil help really
build the structure in it
it's funny did you say cation exchange
and i uh
i just filmed a podcast episode and uh
it was released well it would be
released last week
and i pronounced vacation exchange and
that's the improper way and i'm
i'm gonna hear it in the comment section
i know that well here's what's funny
when you look at how it's spelled it's
c-a-t-i-o-n
so you would think that just looking at
it but until you've heard it a few times
to
recognize and go oh that's cat ion yeah
just like uh chelating
right chelating it looks like it's
chelating spelled chelating
yes it's ch but anyways
um okay cool uh how about granular humic
acids
let's talk about those humic acids are
one of those
things that it's created over a long
period of time
there's fulvic in humic acid both are
kind of
takes a long time to develop and humic
acid
comes from like leonard
leonardite slate it's from a slate
almost like a clay material
have you ever seen slate walking around
like beaches or
um like around the great lakes midwest
there's a lot of slate along the
riverbed area
so it's pretty interesting it just it's
real it's like a rock but it's so
thin and it's so slippery that
it's weird because slate
the what is it this product is made from
it actually helps to chelate
different heavy metals
it's very weird what humic acid does
and it actually can detoxify
heavy minerals and soil so going back to
the azomite
heavy minerals heavy metals
this is one of those other products that
can lock it up so it can't be taken up
by the plant so on top
of gypsum kind of helping the plant
with the detox of these heavy metals
this kind of locks some of it up
the humic acid locks it up so the plant
can't take it up
so when i'm using trace minerals that
are sometimes heavier
or hit have higher doses of heavy metals
that's one that i can actually use to
block it out that's what's nice about
um because it does the chelation's a
multivalent
ion with the cat ion exchange it's
another one of those cation exchanges
that
it can chelate and change some of the
multivalent bonds ion
bonds and help with different plants to
chelate different nutrients or to lock
things out
in more simpler terms the way i was
explained to it you can correct me if
i'm wrong on this one
the chelation is kind of like putting
nutrients into like an envelope right
and and making it more available for
uptake is it
yes in a sense so certain
nutrients come in different forms that
are not available
so say you have calcium or
here's a great one iron if you have
iron in your soil a lot of people are
like oh it's a heavy metal your plant's
going to uptake it well
not necessarily if it's not chelated
to an available form the plant can take
up
it's not going to use it even though
it's in the soil
and that's what a lot of chelation is
about
making different nutrients available in
a different form
than what they are all right bio
live talk to us about that down to earth
bio live is the one that i believe you
use
it is um they also have a bio fish and
bio thrive i think there's a couple
different in their bio lines
but what it is is a different
blend of multiple
down to earth amendments from kelp to
soybean mill to gypsum so it's
a variety of all these ingredients
and one but what they added was
beneficial fungi and bacteria
both endo ecto microrhizal
fungi there's several different strands
of bacteria
some of them uh the bacillus if i recall
um but that's what i use it for is to
get those
endo and ectomycorrhizal fungi in there
and not just the arbescule
fungi because there are several
different ones that come from different
nutrient lines um
that all of not all of them are the same
type of
fungi or microarrizal fungi so
i'm trying to get once again a
biodiversity
just like my nutrients i'm trying to do
the same thing in my soil so that bio
line really helps with what i'm doing in
the soil in the soil biology
because a lot of like what we're talking
about today we haven't really gone into
some of the soil biology
parts of it but some of these other
amendments
also really help with
what we're trying to do with not just
the
diversity and soil amendments but the
diversity and the soil biology
because that's they go hand in hand and
you're talking about the microorganisms
right when you're talking about the
biology right the actual
organism everything in the soil around
the root zone
um that's in the top couple inches of
your soil where
everything kind of breaks all the
nutrients down and that's where your
plants kind of get their
roots to these areas to create exudates
for these
to do that symbiotic exchange of
nutrients to sugars and carbs and
and then for the the bio live i'm
looking at it right now
it's a 542 mpk so would you say
that this is more beneficial in just in
veg
or can this be used in flour as well you
could use it in flour
it being higher in nitrogen is not an
issue
plants are still looking to take up
nitrogen
in flower cycle they're not using as
much
but they're yet they're still using
nitrogen to help development
and so using that would not be an issue
on either veg or flour
i use it in both the other part using it
in vet or in flour would be
the beneficial bacteria and fungi
because
if you're an indoor cultivator
re-inoculating the soil every so often
to make sure that
the species are there that the plants
looking for certain ones for certain
nutrients to take up
so that's what part of that diversity is
so if
they're dying off you're just trying to
you know re-inoculate and get them back
into the soil at that time
all right let's switch it up to next one
bokashi
talk to us about that actually just got
some bokashi using it for the first time
yeah not the group it's called growkashi
that's the brand i guess
got it from build a soil and started
using it just sprinkled it like two days
ago
so talk to us about that um well it
depends there's several different brands
on the market
several different companies some of it
is just a
wheat brand oat brand pikashi some of it
has rice holes
some of it has
biochar mixed in with it so it just
depends on the companies
that you're getting it from like elevate
organics is one that does some rice
holes in biochar
um build a soil
they have one that's has rice holes in a
wheat brand i believe
that even if you had bokashi or if you
had compost at home you can throw it on
and create your own bokashi
so what bokashi is is like three to four
strains
of anaerobic bacteria
people think anaerobic bacteria is bad
but these are the ones that are actually
beneficial and good for the soil
they help different functions within the
plant
they help break down different organic
matter
and different amendments that the plant
really enjoy
so these three or four strands are like
yeast
lactose bacillus and then like a purple
non-sulfur are like
what's commonly found in the what
bokashi is
and also it's really doing is helping
get fungal communities
are because bakashi's supposed to help
build fungal communities
but it's weird because it's an anaerobic
bacteria
but to me it's the way it breaks down
everything in the soil that the fungal
communities then want to come in
and start helping kind of like
it's weird because some of these fungal
bile and
bacterial communities really work
symbiotically
and you'll find communities and
understand that
like some are bad
like different anaerobic bacteria can be
bad and harmful to the soil
and that's where a lot of aerobic
biology help go in the soil kind of get
rid of the bad pathogens
the anaerobic if your soil
is getting more oxygen to it will help
get rid of a lot of
the bad pathogens in there and that's
where
understanding the difference between
like these are
beneficial anaerobic as versus the bad
anaerobic bacteria that makes sense
and then one thing about bokashi
is like really it it creates that white
mycelium layer right across the soil
which is pretty cool i had a lot of
people hit me up to like
what is this you know they all panic
mode it's actually a good thing
to see that mycelium layer across
um and that's what's really helping that
break down especially when you have it
like
when you top dress it right and have it
over those nutrients that you maybe this
top dress
that's probably one of the more
beneficial ways to do it right it would
really help
break things down a little bit quicker
because that's what bokashi is really
used for
is for composting breaking down organic
matter
that's where you can create your own
bokashi at home
with a couple different ingredients like
blackstrap molasses
some oat or wheat brand or rice holes
and then some e-m1
and you can create your own bokashi or
you can get bokashi and sprinkle
on your compost and let it start
breaking it down
and if you really went got some yeast
and some brown sugar molasses and you
sprinkle that on compost it would
start breaking it down as well because
yeast is part of
what akashi is so it's really
interesting how you can create your own
bokashi
if you really wanted to or get it
started breaking down your compost from
these other
like uh companies out there that is
pretty interesting it makes growing fun
too doing trying out new things like
that
looking at the growkashi directions
right now just read it off so it says it
can be used as a soil conditioner
one to two percent of total soil volume
is what it says
we could use those top dresses which is
what i did a third
cup per square foot every two weeks is
what they recommend
and then as a soil drink it says use a
third cup per gallon of
clean water or nutrient solution and
then let it sit for 24 to 48 hours
stir in a tablespoon per gallon of
blackstrap molasses that's the food
source
and then a strain to use so just some
couple different ways to to use bokashi
yeah
and that's what's so interesting is
because it's so
versatile on using it for nutrients
to feed your plant with to break down
compost or get a compost pile going so
you can use a compost
to then feed your plants so it's
it's really nice it's very beneficial
a lot of people that's one of them that
a lot of people
don't know about and kind of overlook
and a lot of growers are really
interested in
like getting these communities these
fungal communities
to the plants and that's kind of what
this bokashi will do
is help with the bacteria bring these
fungal communities
so we went over 10 different amendments
there
and you know when i first started
getting to organics
one of the things is that it can be
overwhelming
right you've got all these we we just
scratched the surface today we went over
10 and there's so many more beyond that
you know kelp meal alfalfa meal insect
frass uh blood meal i gotta cheat you
here
feather meal biochar so we could go on
and on we could have a part two if you
guys want a part two
there could even be a part three because
there's really so many because then you
have the fish and the hydrolyzed fish
and the fish meal and right there's
three different ones
and that's that's what's so interesting
is
i literally have a tote full of
probably 20 different products that i
use
and everybody's like that's a lot but
i'm looking at as i don't know what my
plant needs
and all of them work differently for my
plant and the soil biology
and that's all i can do as
a home cultivator as growing my own
fruits and vegetables is try to give the
plants
everything available that they can use
for nutrient uptake or nutrients in any
form that i can find
that's dry and organic
because i don't like bottle nutrients i
prefer not to use them they have shelf
lives
most of these dry organic components
don't really have a shelf life
they're good until they get decomposed
or broken down
so that's why i really enjoy using like
the down
to earth amendments because they're one
of them that's
pretty consistent of their product
and where i can find them as versus some
of these other companies
and their box is environmentally
friendly right it breaks down breaks
down
even says compost on the back of it
use the box for compost yes so i have a
big compost pile that i have all kinds
of boxes that i've thrown in
from making all these different soil
amendments over the last couple years
and it's
they break down pretty quickly
surprisingly so all that being said
what advice do you have for somebody who
is probably new
just getting their feet wet with
organics and stuff what advice would you
have for them
keep it simple so the kiss method
look for a couple things that you want
to try
i would recommend like some bio live
one of those lines maybe
you know a little bit of rock phosphate
for the trace nutrients
either some gypsum or some dolomite lime
just for the calcium magnesium
sulfur to um um
and here's what's so nice about some of
this down the earth some of it's pretty
inexpensive and it's starting to get a
little bit more expensive
boxes i can find gypsum for just about
six bucks
but some of these other amendments are
around twenty bucks for a five pound box
um you can get them in thirty forty
pound fifty pound bags if you want a
larger quantity
but to me it's still really
inexpensive where i can go get three or
four
items just to get started and
mix them in a soil mix or make a tea
with them
and even do a foliar application with
the solubility of some of this
that's another application that you can
do on a lot of this
so taking you know as a newbie
keeping it simple i can grab a couple
boxes
of a couple ingredients that have some
beneficial
biology and some good nutrients and
start with that
i think that's really good advice that's
one way to not get overwhelmed with
everything that's going on is just start
with one
yeah and get another one and kind of do
your individual research and apply it
as you feel best that you've done your
research on and and go from there so i
think that's great great advice
and that's like me i've worked over the
years where i have
20 boxes i don't use them all at one
time
because things change during my cycles
of what i'm feeding them but that's the
whole point
is i have what i need available
for my plants and it takes time to build
it
because it didn't just happen overnight
i don't
the whole product line if you had to go
out and purchase
the down to earth whole product line you
would probably spend fifteen hundred
dollars to two thousand dollars
that's expensive can't
not everybody can afford to do that so
that's where
a box here a box there and you're only
putting
a couple tablespoons here a couple
tablespoons there
it's going to last you a while most of
my boxes
unless i literally have to make a whole
new
super soil recipe i
don't use my it may take me six months
to get through my box or longer
it may take me a year on some of them
the only time i use a large dose of the
dryer granule commitments is when i
make a large tea or do super soil
amending and that's it bottled nutrients
we talked about that shelf life you go
buy a bottle that's got to be used by
x amount of time and if it's not it's no
good
i can sit around for a year and i'll be
definitely a big benefit there for sure
all right so how can the listeners find
you
and what do you got upcoming in the
future well um
we've got quite a bit going on um
we'll start off you can find me on
youtube medically fit
about 18 000 people following me now
it's been a slow progression on
educating people um on the channel
um i've got a lot of great playlists on
the soil amendments
where i kind of talk a little bit more
on some of them on there
as well as you can find me on instagram
or
cannabis if you need to reach out to me
and you want to message me
best place i talk to people and chat
with people it's on instagram
it's easier for me to find messages
there than it is through youtube or
anything else so ah you might want to
take that back
because you're gonna get flooded you're
gonna get flooded with questions i'm
sure that's
okay because i try to answer most
people's questions and help most people
out that i can
um it may take me a while to see because
instagram if
we're not following each other i have to
allow their request to come through and
so sometimes it takes me a while to see
some of my messages but
i usually try to help quite a bit of
people out that want a little bit more
information
try to at least point them in directions
they can find some of the information
that's what the channel is really for is
to try to point people in the direction
of where to find some of this
information absolutely you've done a
great job over the years
providing that information and i thank
you for your efforts there
i'll link medically fit's channel down
in the description section below
so you click on it i'm on his channel
right now i'll also link that nutrient
tea video
that i spoke about in the description
section and then if you look at his
playlist like he said
and he's got one on horticulture body
and plant physiology
he's got a playlist for soil amendments
he's got one for
understanding the benefits of
cannabinoids so he's got a lot of um
educational information a lot over the
years
it's just building and compiling all
these different videos i've found
and watched over the years and just to
have somewhere people can go and find
some of the information or
if somebody asks i can try to go to one
of those and pull it up and send it to
him
so it's always nice having a place you
can find references
all right medically fit thank you so
much for coming on to the channel today
any final words um just do your research
most of like my job is to turn you guys
on to the information
your job from that point on is to do
research and find out
and the only way to grow the best
plants you can is to do it yourself
finding what works for you it works
different for everybody else
not everybody you know like you have
soil growers
hydro growers aquaponic growers
everybody has their niche find what
works for you
don't be afraid to try something
different either because like you
it took you a little while and a little
pushing to try some organics and
what happened you finally tried it after
a while and i even sent you some of
these videos we're talking about
over the years just here check this out
here check that out
i appreciate that definitely appreciate
you pushing me
to wean my way off the bottles you know
and
it just takes people sharing the right
information
and people willing to listen because you
can lead a horse of water but you can't
make him drink
i can provide all the information to my
listeners but i can't force them to read
it or watch it
make sense all right matt medically fit
i will let you go
thanks again and uh have a good one
youtube and we'll hope to see you all
again
[Music]
you