what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you watch a mattress Channel perfect
works sent me over there 1000 W Cree
Cobb plus LED grow light and in this
video I'm going to unbox a unit I will
test the power output and I'll do a heat
test on it I'm not gonna go over all of
the features that the scroll light has
but I will link it in the description
section below so you can learn more
about it first thing out the box here is
a wire hanging kit here's another wire
hanging kit next is a power cord and
lastly is the LED grow light for the
part test I'm going to use the appo gmq
500 power meter this meter measures from
389 nanometers to 692 nanometers and the
measurements are in ppfd I do these
videos just to give you a general idea
of what the power output is it's not
going to be on 2 percent accurate I take
measurements in grow tents which have
reflective walls that could increase the
numbers so just keep that in mind
the vegetative coverage area for this
grow light is full foot by 4 foot
according to the Amazon listing the
flower and coverage area is 4 foot by 3
foot however I was told that the
flowering coverage area was three foot
by 3 foot so when I show you the
measurements you'll see that I'm keeping
my power meter in a 3 foot by 3 foot
space I'm gonna take measurements at 3
different distances these are the
recommended distances listed on their
Amazon listing 18 inches 30 inches and
40 inches I've plugged al-led grill
light into my kilowatt meter and it
shows three point two six amps pulling
383 watts alright let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
just reminder that there is a link to
this grow light in the description
section below and I'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
[Music]
you