coming up on garden talk back crossing
really stabilizes the jeanette that's
how you're able to without femming be
able to go back to the original
characteristics
if you crop out at six week six then
more than likely you're gonna have a
higher percentage of undeveloped if you
allow to go to week eight you're going
to have a better chance of having the
beans not be developed man people are
out here trying to make money left and
right they're not trying to produce the
best product they're just trying to
produce product so either you're going
to be growing flour for yourself or
you're going to be a breeder and if
you're going to be a breeder you got to
be a breeder 100
a true breeder understands you're going
to be getting rid of more than you are
you're going to be keeping final hunt
man it's is truly a skill you know when
you find the one that you're looking for
and your paper and your numbers match up
then the results they speak for
themselves
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this episode number 74. in this
episode i interview cartier crops he is
a plant breeder and has been breeding
for 12 years he talks all about breeding
in this episode from how he got started
breeding all the way to the current
breeding methods that he does today
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible ac infinity is sponsoring
this episode my entire ventilation
system is ac infiniti i have their
inline fan ducting and carbon filter i
love the controller with the temperature
and humidity programming and having
control of different fan speeds this
makes it so much easier to control my
grow environment and i can't wait for
the controller 69 wi-fi version which
also controls their oscillating fans and
grow lights you can use discount code mr
growit for any of their products on
their website acnfinity.com
or use discount code mr grow at 15 if
you're buying off amazon
gorilla grow 10. gorilla has one of the
best double ended grow lights on the
market today the de pro series grow
light has the capability to run both hps
and cmh bulbs you'll get a 50 longer
bulb life and a fixture that runs cooler
due to their engineered heat sink and
thermals and on top of that you can dial
it all in with the optional depro series
controller check out their website at
growstrongindustries.com
and use discount code mr growit for 15
off
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
cartier crops how you doing today
i'm doing well and i'm actually lying
i'm not doing well but we're going to
make this happen today chris
you know we're going to make it happen
today a little low under the weather
some chest pain and and whatnot uh
but let's make it happen i hear you on
that one i woke up with a migraine i've
been battling that all day and then some
nausea and i'm like i'm gonna battle
through it thankfully you'll be doing
most of the talking this time around so
man okay all right
i'm down with that i'm gonna
keep my breath so that way we can make
it happen
all right so what are we gonna get into
today well you are a you not only grow
you're not only a gardener but you're
also a breeder as well and that's what i
really want to dive deep into today is
really all about plant breeding i've
actually had a handful of breeders on
this podcast in the past
and one thing i've noticed is that there
are so many different ways to go about
it there's so many different things you
can do within breeding whether it be
inbreeding back crossing self-crossing
you can create feminized seeds so on and
so forth but not only that but
the characteristics that people are
looking for within plants
males and females vary you know it
really comes down to the breeders so
really eager to jump into this
conversation and find out kind of what
you look for in your plants and how you
do your breeding but first what we do in
every single one of these episodes is an
introduction so can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and kind of how you
got into gardening yeah man so uh man it
was 1996
and uh
my family and i moved to indiana
i was 16 years old
and my mother had had a boyfriend at the
time
and and they you know they they did
their extracurricular activities every
single day
and uh while i was watching them i was
like
hey man these dudes these dudes they
they puff a lot you know and i and i i
was like in my head you know coming from
humble beginnings you know my mind has
always been on how can i add one plus
one to equal to
and so the gentleman did blaze a lot so
i you know i i was like hey
maybe i can grow some of these seeds
that he's leaving down in the basement
and maybe i can provide them
you know
because when you come from humble
beginnings my process is is how can i
get by how can i survive how will i make
it you know what i'm saying and so you
know that was my that was the
introduction now that summer i'll never
forget that summer because i was able to
take the seed
um
go outside we live right behind a a corn
field and large corn field and you know
i had this great idea of taking these
beans and going down the cornfield and
planting them didn't know anything about
anything matter of fact the the bowl i
used
was a bleach bowl
no cap man i used i cut a bleach bowl in
half rinsed it out bro put some soil in
there threw my things in there it
sprouted and it was like the most
amazing thing
then after they got so big i just took
it out and put it in the cornfield
now the interesting thing was
that
each day you know i would go out there
and water and i would go out there and
kind of
entertain my thought of raising these
things to make these millions of dollars
off this one thing right and uh
as i continue to water i started to
realize
something
really cool this you know one of the
things is you know when you take care of
something other than yourself
you you build some type of relationship
no matter what it is or what it could be
and uh at that point in time
you know watering watering my plants and
being there every single day
talking to my plants i thought i was
going crazy but being able to talk to my
plants be it be a part of my plant
uh
started to grow on me and things started
to evolving within myself i started to
learn a lot about myself that summer
it was really interesting because then i
got bit by that bug that summer and it
was something really unique and what was
really unique was you know it started to
take different forms it started small i
started to develop and at this point in
time you know i didn't have a father
figure around there weren't too many
role models around i'm new in a place
and so this plant was really
the only thing that was in front of me
that would watch my tears that would uh
you know what like i said i would talk
to so
it was really a touching moment
throughout that summer and i remember
the time i had to chop it down because
it didn't look too pretty but the time
that came that i it was time to chop
down and uh you know it really touched
me in some type of way but what i
understood is that hey man everything
has a beginning middle and an end
and you know and as long as we continue
to provide ourselves with some of the
best whether it be nutrients or or the
best positive vibes period we can see
ourselves flourish like this plant
ever since that day
every single day of my life i've had a
plant around no matter what it was but
you know the the herb plant has always
been a special thing to me and it's kind
of always been a place for me to go hang
out and really spend my time and reflect
on life and and like i said there's
nothing better than taking care of
something else
uh so
you know you you get there's a benefit
that comes along you know with that and
and i remember when we my mom ended up
breaking up with her boyfriend we moved
into an apartment and i remember uh we
we had an upstairs apartment
and uh my brother-in-law moved in with
us and you know
he saw that i was growing my little
things in the closet i had a little two
by two closet he said hey man i work at
this place and you know this guy has a
light he's from europe and he has this
light this is the first time i was
introduced to hps and i was like i was
like all right man tell them to bring a
light because i needed to you know lead
to the light i didn't know anything at
this point i'm 17. so he brings me this
this big bulb man this hps lives first
time i found out what the hps light was
in 1997 and so he brings this huge bulb
to me and i was like man where'd you
guys steal that from that came off a
light pole or something you know and he
he's like no man it's a it's an hps like
that's an hp i powered situation like i
didn't know what it would admit we
plugged the dang lighting man and it
lights up the whole my mom's like what
the heck is going on back there so you
know i have so many stories of of when
it all started in the journey and how
you know i got involved but you know
realistically
planning that first seat in that field
really really did something special and
uh you know the journey has been
really cool thus far and it's really
helped me out you know as a human being
along along the way man that's deep so
while 1997
here all day long and talk for hours on
stories that i have from the journey but
uh you know that that's 1996 man
1996.
say 1997 is when i started consuming so
that's way back when you started growing
so over 20 years you have experience
there
where did breeding come into play like
you know how long have you been breeding
and what made you get into that
well okay so
it was about two it was like around 2001
uh you know well at this time 1998 mark
emery from your from your spot
so mark emery was making a lot of noise
in the nights right he was doing a lot
of movement and you know being in the
u.s it was difficult to get any type of
beans from anywhere especially in the us
people were really
and if you had something going on you
didn't talk about it right so
i would order from overseas whether it
be canada or whether it be you know the
uk europe whatever
the biggest problem was that i remember
placing the order like in january and
bro
it was like nine months later when they
showed up i think i had like a couple
kids by then you know but it was like it
was like man
it was like it was like man i didn't
know why it took so long to get to me
now when they got to me the dj short
that i did run was fire this was like f
f2 or something like that f2 or three
now they're up to five
so
you know
it was good but there was always
something that wasn't hitting mark emery
had some pretty good stuff before he
ended up you know going under uh with
the law and everything like that so when
they would come over and i would i would
continue to grow these flowers
it wasn't what i wanted then i had a
friend from california 2001. he came
over came to pay me a visit and and you
know we started hanging out and and i
said man how come i'm wondering why
doesn't mine taste like that
you know why is it why doesn't it appeal
to me the same way uh so me i always
thought it was my grow hand i always
thought it was something i was doing
wrong in the garden
something i wasn't wasn't working and my
friend was like it's genetics bro
and so this i was really introduced to
genetics in 2001 so so he said yeah man
you got to have good genetics to get
goods you know get a good product so
i asked him to bring me some sell me
some whatever he ended up going back to
cali i gave him a few hundred bucks
my man sent me like
five beans and i was totally upset
because i've never you know the pricing
in the whole thing so i can't say man
what where's the rest of the beans he
said man that's that's what you get for
good stuff
so ended up growing that and it was like
off the hook right then i knew that hey
i i want to dabble in in breeding now at
that time i dabbled and i was pollen
chucking not knowing what i was doing i
was just crossing crossing and the stuff
wasn't coming out not even better than
overseas and not even better than cali
it just wasn't right i didn't know how
to pick i didn't know how to choose all
the things that come along with the
process i wasn't i didn't understand so
i put it on the back burner and it
wasn't until 2000 i think it was 2012
2008 through 2012 when the cookie
dropped out in cali is when i picked it
back up because i started delivery
service
here in arizona i was a caregiver for
about seven years and i took care of a
lot of patients well at that time they
allowed people to caregive now my flower
was just the same flowers everybody else
because we all had like the same
cuttings and everybody was running the
same stuff so i wanted to be different
and i knew that
you know
breeding was a way for me to really
separate myself from everybody else in
the crowd so the first thing i did was
was go on that journey we could talk
about it a lot later and go in depth but
i went on that journey to really start
to experiment and contacted some people
who were able to uh
first of all i bought a cutting for like
two thousand dollars and almost got me
divorced
uh
you know and then the second cutting for
another two grand
yeah i was sleeping on the couch for
like a month
and my wife people around me just didn't
understand what i was doing and i
remember my buddy and cali he said yo
man if you're gonna play this game you
gotta have proper genetics otherwise
you're just you're just another small
fish in in the in in the sea
and so that's that's what i did man is
that i i
bought these expensive genetics
i started experimenting
and then i started to study and really
dig down and try to understand the plan
and
long story short
i had one of the best delivery services
in the valley for many years called
speedy nuggs and you know so it just you
know that's really where it started
because i wanted to be different and i
wanted to have something that nobody
else had in some different type of
varieties that weren't like anybody
else's that's really that's really why i
started
okay so that's how you started getting
into breeding side of things so fast
forward to today talking about breeding
setup you know you can do breeding
indoors you can do breeding outdoors
what do you do like what's your setup
are you indoors if you're indoors what
size room are you in lighting so on and
so forth talk to us about your breeding
setup
so i won't give you my entire process
but i will i will share with you that it
takes it takes a lot of people to get it
done the right way obviously you know
you can breed within one compound one
tint uh one compound whatever but
you know my process utilizes friends
people i have a commercial facility in
oklahoma where we do our actual runs and
we do our actual actual test
to run many more because here in the
state of arizona we're on them we're in
the limit and we're limited to the
amount that we can we can uh the flowers
we can cultivate now the
the the main thing is that
i knew that i was limited at with my
caregiving card
and
and i knew that i want i need i had to
keep moms around
right and then at the same because i
know i know you're probably going to ask
me about the males and and pollen and
whatever else but you know i focused
more on the ladies now when i say more
people helping out there's people who
would carry the males so that's one
thing cool about being a friend with a
breeder is that hey you know i can give
cuttings to people who
which i think are going to be
some of the best and they hold on to the
cuttings they keep they flower they keep
around and veg and then if we it is the
winner that we need then i bring it back
and then i do breed within i breed
within a tent so i take the best of the
best females and then work with the best
of the best male
um and and i have a process when i go
through that but but i use the 10 and i
and i solo everything out in the room
you know cut off the delivery service
and just really focused in on
on honing that that craft now when we
when we really want to do a major
funeral hunt then we utilize oklahoma in
that manner so we can pop 100 200 beans
and like right now we're running the v12
and the v12 we pop i think around 100
beans but usually around 100 mark is a
good mark to for me anyways that's my
thought process 100 to really get
something swell out of there
we don't bring them back from oklahoma
back here but what we do is we're we're
able to to identify and know that hey we
have something special and you know we
possibly may breed out there but we're
not breeding out there now so really you
know i utilize a few tints
i put the best females in the tent
and then i grab the best male that i can
grab that i find
out of maybe 15 20 males i'll take the
best male from that 15 to 20 uh
depending on the rub the smell test
depending on the the structure
and and then also you know what what i
want to see out of the the crossing
itself
okay yeah i was going to ask you
how many plants you typically are
hunting through and it's funny i was
watching your video where you're talking
about breeding and you had mentioned
that there have been times where you've
gone through 100 and didn't find what
you're looking for so you had to start
fresh
multiple times that has happened to you
so it seems like you have some real high
standards when it comes to finding
exactly what you're looking for
it just happened to me i uh
many people from my network they saw me
go down to costa rica i went landrus
hunting in costa rica and
great experience came back was excited
to do this run
i did the run made the crosses started
to run some experiments
just just wasn't happening and you know
you know in this game and if you
a true breeder understands you're going
to be getting rid of more than you are
you're going to be keeping
and you know i i i'm big on that and and
it's kind of you know i allow like i
always say i allow the the beans to
speak for me i don't i don't run around
the world saying i'm the best and i'm
the greatest or none of that the beans
will speak for themselves
and you know high quality um
health
is huge you know and uh so yeah man i
there's it just happened to me literally
a few months ago got rid of
the females that i thought were going to
be the ones and she happened to her
and then when she heard that i'm just
not with that you know what i'm saying
i'm not i'm not with the herms and got
rid of that if one of them heard within
20 40 or you know vice versa
i really start to remove those and then
pop more because with you know it's just
a process i have but i'm really really
picky and anal about making sure uh
you know i i get what i want out of
work
it can definitely be a long long process
like you just said you touched upon a
little bit on what you're looking for in
a pheno right you talk about stem rub a
little bit i want to get a little bit
deeper into that what exactly do you
look for and i know this varies by
breeder right some people looking for
tricho production some people are
looking for the vigor of the plants
the list goes on what are you looking
for in a cultivar when making your
decision on if it's suitable for
breeding or not
we get our stuff tested
so terp profile is obviously a big one
uh
the the levels the th levels making sure
the levels are where i want them to be
the structure the smell the rub the rub
smell means a lot to me and i think
that's a special skill in itself because
out of 100 plants i can rub each and
every one of them and i kind of know
which way they're going to be rolling
there's characteristics that a lot of
plants carry like the rubber rubber glue
smell like a brand new pair of shoes
smell a grape an apple or fruits some
some of the fruit type stuff
so myself
it's it's it's more than just one thing
it's it's a full collage of what i'm
looking for and what i'm looking to
express
uh for instance i created a one-to-one
that is very rare one to one i mean it's
it was really close like a 17 to 15
on paper
and
you know going through that process it's
like okay
that's what makes the journey so long
because even though you run you can run
a hundred and doing the rub test smell
test doing all this and that
what i'm looking for on the left has to
make sense to the right so the male the
males that i'm looking for when i use
utilize the males the males i'm looking
for strong characteristics strong
characteristics that didn't help the
female to go where they need to go but
i'm also looking for balance i'm not
looking for one to overpower the other
the other like i'm known for the og
cooking you know the balance of the og
cookie not one being more powerful than
the other so you know that
we could sit here all day and talk about
how in in the different ways that i then
look for the feet the the phenos but the
honest to god truth chris it's it's
truly like you said it boils down to to
what the breeder is looking for
and me i'm known for the og cookie
because i love the og
and i love the cookie right but the
cookie will have you somewhere over
there and i owed you how you sleeping
somewhere so i always look for that
balance and you know and and that's just
what i'm known for and you know
i cannot explain how my fingers rub on
something smell rub on something smell
people trip out on it and and it's it's
i believe it's a skill you acquire over
over years of experience you know
because there's different categories and
there's nothing like i recently saw
something with some duck feet i don't
know if you heard of anything about some
duck feet type of genetic
and
everything falls within a category
you know and
from there is when i say okay this is a
okay this is that you can start to put
things in the category you know now when
it comes down to looking for that pheno
or what you're working on uh in the prop
for instance a gorilla butter i'm
working on it didn't have size to it
so i already knew i had something that
was able to bring more size to it but i
didn't want the balance i didn't want
the size from the right i wanted this
i'm sorry i didn't want the size from
the left i wanted i wanted the size from
the right but i wanted the left to be
and speaking to be more dominant
so we had to go through many many many
phenoes to find that one
and and so ron hill from our group was
able to showcase that within our group
and you know the journey's long and when
you find it you're like yes because you
you hit it on the nails now you got the
what's on the left the characteristics
of what's on the left is really shining
and showcasing but you've added extra
weight to it
without without you know
the plan on the right wasn't what i was
looking for but i needed the size and
destruction
um
you know it's a long it's a long process
and and what i'm dabbling with now is is
uh the crispr
uh and and crispr i'm not sure if you're
familiar with crispr many people aren't
familiar with crispr but i'm going to
take that journey because you know as a
real breeder you're really looking to
work with the dna and that's why we
breed we're trying to get the a b c d f
g h i we're working on those
those letters and with crispr we're able
to remove the e remove the f add in the
a's the b's the c's and now we it kind
of speeds up it takes two years off of
this process uh so
that's something we're working on but
the final hunt man it's
it's a it is a skill
it's it's truly a skill
and uh you know when you find the one
that you're looking for in your paper
and your numbers match up and then uh
the results
you know
they speak for themselves
it'll be interesting to fast forward 10
15 years and see dna editing you know
gene editing and how it actually takes
us you know how far it actually takes us
and what we're able to do with in the
future it's uh scary
and exciting at the same time you know
because uh you get some funky stuff
happening i know they're talking about
crispr with human gene editing which is
just super scary we're not talking about
that but plants i mean it's similar
right
well i believe i believe i believe it it
i not only believe i mean china and few
other countries have shown us results of
tripling and doubling and even mold like
for instance that's why people love
blueberry because it's mold resistant
it's you can grow it outdoor indoor
anywhere and it's not going to collect
any mold now inside of that dna pattern
you know you could take that that dna
strand that helix and add it to another
added to another variety that is lacking
that so you can pull that out and put
that in i'm all for that
when it comes to humans that's totally
that's that's totally different but
we're seeing the crispr being used
across the platform on plants in
countries where they're getting low
yield or they need fast turnaround and
faster cropping
i think it not i don't think i believe
and know it will be the future of plants
and food and things of that nature uh
yeah you are playing god but at the same
time
i mean
i mean it's no different than taking
pollen and chucking and doing it's
really it's really no no different
you know a huge difference but i mean
it's really you know you're you're
actually making something better and and
and uh much more uh
something geared and you're like you
said cutting off two years of time uh
doing it the way we're doing it now
saves a lot of time yeah it can
definitely make things a lot easier
that's for sure
circling back to
the pollination process i want to get a
little bit deeper into this some people
will collect the pollen from the males
and then pollinate the females later on
or some people will put the males in
with the females in the same room and
kind of let them do their thing pollen
sacks start to open and things start to
fly around the room so on and so forth
what's your style of doing the actual
pollination process you know i've tried
it all and
the one i really enjoy is the natural
way of throwing the the bad boy in there
into into with the ladies and let them
have fun
um
you know i i've stored pollen and
you know sometimes it doesn't work out
as you know the best you know the way
you wanted to but for myself i
definitely enjoy putting the boy in the
tent with the girls let the party begin
at a specific week and man i mean that's
that's the best way now i do i have and
i do
uh collect the pollen especially if it's
something that i really like and enjoy
then i would do that but at the same
time i will then also tissue culture
so i have friends in the valley who who
tissue culture and they do their thing
and when i really want to keep a male
around as opposed to pollen i will then
make take a slither of a cutting hand it
to a couple of my buddies and then they
will store that for too long period of
time the very slow growth process and
that really helps me out a lot because
then i don't have mounds of pollen just
just everywhere now that's why it's
really important when you you want to
get into breeding or you're breeding in
your room you're right when that
pollen's flying around everywhere man
it's it's it can be it could be a bad
sight for the next breeding or the next
process uh so you really gotta use
utilize the the filtration properly uh
bleach and make sure things are
sanitized properly i actually use like
an ozone and kill everything in the room
at the end of each process like i kill
anything that's living in the room and
make sure that that there's nothing else
living and that can jeopardize the next
process but yeah me putting the the boy
in the in the tent i found to be
i don't know it's like apple trees you
know when you got a male tree outside
and a female tree outside they just seem
to work well together it's nature it's
it's it's the way nature the way it's
intended to be
um
but you know i have taken pollen in in
dabbled but it doesn't produce as well
as as putting the boy inside of there
something special that happens yeah i
definitely agree with you on that one i
just finished up a run where i had the
mail on there with the females
and uh just you know at a certain day
just shaking the mail over all the
females and just completely covering
them you know and then killing off the
male because i didn't need it anymore
but uh you know i harvested now you know
broke up the plant
loaded with seeds you know what i mean
so if you're looking for like
to yield as many seeds as possible
you'll probably get a better result if
you're shaking the plant in there you
know and just you will notice i've done
it with uh you know a little swab and
swabbing different branches and stuff
like that but it doesn't get as much
coverage doesn't produce as many seeds
as keeping the mail in there so i
thought that was a big major call out
and you know
you know what's cool is that you know
after you do that because i have a
ritual i do you with my males in there
and we do a little
we do our little native
thing on it and um
you know
you only need to do it a few times and
then get them out of there so it's it's
you know then you can start your
cleaning process outside in the room and
you really start to sanitize outside
of the room but yeah it's just just a
little dab all over the entire crop and
man you're
you're good to go because even the
leaves carry some of the pollen so when
your fans are moving around in the tent
you know hey
it's still gonna continue to move around
as the plant grows
yep so i got to ask how long is pollen
good for and how do you properly store
pollen for
later use you know i i i've not ever
kept pollen over a year so
i i'm not i'm not sure after the year
mark but if i'm going to use something
and work with something i i i usually
give it that year time frame
could it be longer i'm not sure because
i i like i said if i'm going to use
something a year later from now or
something later down the road because i
do back crossing as well then i i would
i would go tissue culture and tissue
culture because you're able to the plant
continues to grow but it grows at a very
very slow rate uh the male plant that is
that's the way that i keep
my
male around as opposed to pollen because
again you can keep the pollen in the
fridge is the best place to keep it it
actually stores longer than if you just
keep it in a room
uh at room temperature you keep it in
the fridge and a refrigerator and things
just it works you know what i'm saying
but at the same time you got to be
careful because the pollen if you pull
it out the moisture can make the pollen
a bit sticky and gunky you know it can
happen and i've seen that happen so
to me tissue culture is just the way to
go if you're really trying to you know
keep the keep the male genetic around uh
and a lot of people
they don't understand tissue culturing
it's it's a long process i don't even
teach you culture i
it goes somewhere else and people then
store and do what they need to do for
myself but it's uh that's the way i do
it okay so you've pollinated your plants
they're growing they're producing seeds
at what point do you know when to
harvest
number one like i i like to tap i found
out that tapping the ladies in a right
around week three is probably the best
especially if you want to keep your
flower and you want to press the flower
uh you could do one good shake around
week three
you know remove the excess and then
plant then starts to develop now
here's the thing
this the seeds will finish in week six
they can be finished
uh
if you allow them to go any longer which
i
try not to then after about weeks seven
eight they then start to because there's
moisture they then start to open up
so around six to eight i really i'm
really watching the development of the
of the seeds and watching the
development of everything taking shape
i really don't focus on the plant
anymore meaning that i'm not i'm not
looking at the trikes i'm not deep into
the nature of the plant i'm i'm looking
at the creek because not every seed is
designed the same so some some finish
faster than the others the last
blueberry we just recreated finished
really fast to the point that at week
seven it started already cracking the
seeds started to crack open so i knew i
had a pooler and get her out of there
real fast you know didn't give us time
to flush or any of that but my vibranium
and my v12 you know they can run a full
eight weeks and man them suckers are
themselves are like little boulders you
know and then they're really hard then
you have the beans that are really tough
and hard you know like my cartier cookie
it's a very very strong bean
which means that it needs to go the
entire process so really from week six
to week eight is when anything after
week eight i think i think people are
messing up and um i'm not sure if it
hurts the seedling but uh you know
you you can't get the seedling to start
to open up because of the added moisture
and it's like tucked in this ball of
moisture you know what i'm saying so it
may wanna it may wanna start to grow
and i've seen that i'm sure you've seen
that pictures and online uh you know
seeds growing from a plant it's crazy i
actually haven't seen that now usually
the you know i see the calyx open up and
then the sea will kind of drop off the
plant and that's one thing that i kind
of heard in the past is like once you
start having seeds start to drop out of
there each day or even if you like touch
the plant a little bit also when these
seeds are falling out of there well you
probably want to harvest the plant at
that time because a lot of the seeds are
probably developed
now my next question would be
when you harvest and you you're breaking
up the buds and you've got your seed
there it's
pretty much impossible to have a hundred
percent developed seeds a percentage of
them are going to be undeveloped and
then the other percentage is going to be
fully developed
what is a good percentage in your
experience or your opinion developed
versus undeveloped seeds at harvest time
okay so you got to understand you got to
understand what you're working with
because it boils back down to the time
frame and the thing is if you crop out
at six week six
then more than likely you're gonna have
a higher percentage of undeveloped
if you allowed go to week eight you're
gonna have a better chance of having uh
the beans not be developed now people
talk about white seeds gray seeds brown
seeds tiger stripe all this stuff
my cartier cookie puts off gray white
seeds so it can trick you into thinking
that it's not developed but it's really
developed
so
you it boy goes back to
understanding the genetic and what
you're working with so if the if the cg
pop prior were gray whites which i love
the gray whites i mean people say oh
they're not developed they're like no no
no no you're not understanding
because the grays man they put off the
most strikes to me
so when i'm working with that i know
what i'm working with then i watch that
time frame because in when comes six and
seven especially eight i pulled down
i had there's a better chance of getting
your your your ratios would be
definitely better now
yeah when you make it to the latter part
of the of the growth cycle yeah of
course the beans are still developing
but as long as you went and you're
cropping at the proper time then
you're gonna have a better ratio by far
you know better ratio in your week seven
and week eight of cooling down anything
after that your the plant is still gonna
continue to grow and continue to flower
her not herself but the pollen is gonna
continue to be around and it's gonna
continue to produce seeds but like i
said if you crop at week six
uh which i know a lot of people do
because they they want they don't care
about the ratio they're just going to
pull out the best because they're
working with limited amounts of time
and you know when you're when you're
speeding up like that
you don't get a good pop rate so that's
another thing is that when you do wait
the time
and then you do uh then start to
germinate you get a better germination
rate uh when you wait better better
percentage as well of of
beings as well
okay that makes sense
and then i know there are so many
different ways to go about it but kind
of generally speaking how many
generations are you going to in order to
get your desired result so you know many
people have they they work it a
different way i get down to f3
and
at my f3 mark is really my telltale
because when you're in your f1 you can
get many
varieties from an f1 i mean cousins
aunties uncles you get you get it all
right but as you start moving down and
you start pulling back it's around week
it's around the f3 where i really start
to dwindle it down
and
that's when you can really start to see
the prize and stuff happening now
because it is an f3 and because i'm
constantly in breeding in a way
you know at times the f3 i will then
bring in an outside to come into the f3
so i don't hurt
the genetic makeup and create mutants
and because you can really
mess up the genetic the makeup of of the
plant so it really depends on
where i'm at in f3 but f3 is kind of
where
i'm like okay you know i i know i have
something good now if i make it to f3
and it's happened to me before in three
years actually of of working on a
genetic i made it to my f3s and nothing
in the f3s i like
and you know i mean i i mean hundreds of
beans later and there's just nothing
what just wasn't matching up with what i
like
uh because if i want the if i want plant
i'm looking for balance and if if i
don't find that balance then it's not
worth continuing i might as well run the
beans that that favor more this side or
run the beans that favor more to this
side as opposed to trying to really
recreate because i do something special
after f3
f3s are really important to me
um and and into stabilizing the genetics
really important okay so you go to f3s
and then you cross with something i
think you mentioned in the past you're
doing back crossing as well
talk to us about back crossing what is
back crossing and how do you do it okay
back crossing really stabilizes the
genetic that's how you're able to
without feminine
be able to go back to the original
characteristics
now my process is whenever i'm working
on a line
off the f1 i keep the female that i
really enjoy
because that's the staple that's the one
saying hey we're really trying to match
and get as close to her as possible but
at the same time the middle is possible
when i make it down to the f3
that's when i'm ready to come back to
the mom
because when i come back to that mom
what i've done is there remember i
started with f1 i'm getting 500
different looks you know when i get down
to f3 i've really joined it down to
specific looks that i'm looking for now
when i come back to that mama baby i'm
rocking and rolling because now my my my
it's like
here so i'm i'm working with four five
six really you get around from three to
twelve
looks
on the back cross i mean it's not
exactly the same but each beam you pop
off of there are really going to be
within that three to six variety look
and and that's where it really gets the
magic you know starts to happen is when
you get back to the bx one right now i
have some problems some stuff that's on
the bx2 bx3s and
bro consistency consistency consistency
because i'm not a feminized type of
breeder at all i don't i don't rock that
way back crossing
and that's the thing back crossing takes
so long that people aren't willing to
spend the time energy and money to
stabilize something people are just
trying to you know it's a great market
right now we live in one of the greatest
markets in the world right now when it
comes to the flower
and people right here trying to make
money left and right so they're not work
they're not trying to produce the best
product they're just trying to produce
product
and that's a difference you know what
i'm saying so
uh back crossing is the way and the only
way to go uh unless you're using a
crispr program to eliminate that uh but
basically going to f3 is the crisper in
in essence that's what we're doing is is
the natural form of crispr and then when
you come back to the the original mom
you got the original mom and then you
got those other varieties in the damn
you got a closer
big group of uh
what you want now what about self
crossing what is that and how do you do
that
you know i stay away from self-crossing
and i stay away from feminized
and
i i have people hit me up all the time
saying i i would grab from you if you
have feminized and i'm like
self-crossing man
it's two ways that it's done you're
stressing the plant
you're stressing the plant either
hermaphrodite itself
and and if that's not the form you're
taking
uh and it's true you will get the same
almost the same quality or the same
genetic if you do self you do it to
itself yeah you're going to get the
offspring that looks just like that but
what a lot of people don't know is you
are really deter you are tearing up that
genetic because then it doesn't
reproduce uh like it should it just
doesn't
you know of course we would love to see
lebron james cloned over and over again
but it let that next lebron
he might have an ear on top of his head
you know it's like yo man
hold up lebron bro you can hear me on
top of your head bro like you know so
and that's what we're seeing we're
seeing and i've seen this happen chris
i've seen s1s go against my f1s and f3s
and back crosses and i've seen feminize
go against and i don't want to say go
against but the structure of
an fs1 does not look anything like you
know the original process
then it boils back down again to
the marketing side of things when it
comes to s1 but i know guys at s1 and
they have great products and they and it
looks great and all but their plan isn't
as vigorous it isn't as healthy and then
when they're ready to clone and they're
ready to move that genetic down the line
it doesn't happen they the the makeup
goes like this and the cl and the the
offspring aren't producing like they
want them to so it's really like one and
done once you get it once you do it boom
it's over you know uh and when it comes
to films
hey man i'm not big into you know
spraying my plant with chemical you know
to make herself
freak herself
so then she's stressed out that's that's
how that's how it happens so then people
ask me well you know my plants aren't
herming and the office that are not
okay but i bet you've lost
a quarter of the weight maybe half of
the weight or you know some type of
structural
uh condition or you know there's just so
much that goes that's in the negative
and as a breeder myself you know i'm
from the old school man and i believe in
mother nature and i believe in the
natural process because then it isn't
lying to us you know what i'm saying
it's not lying to us
uh and it it's it's a big market i mean
you know feminism i mean as a beginning
grower you know
you don't want i mean i hear he wasn't
oh my god i got four out of 12 four were
males
it's it's it's it's the nature of the of
the regular being
you know what i'm saying
and so you know people would dig to the
films and then then six months later i
hear how come my plans aren't producing
like they should or that
i'm like man i don't even like to speak
on it because i've already told you six
months ago what the deal was and what
the demo was so you know you like i said
this game is not a game of trial and
error because if you want to play trial
and error then if you're going to spend
a lot of time
a lot of time you know going 2-3 months
2-3 months 2-3 months of trial and error
so
it's like yo man uh i i get it i
understand why people use films i think
it's great for beginners to get their
hands in this in the soil and the clay
and start playing with the stuff but
when you're ready to get serious about
your your flower and your genetics
bro
nothing's really going to be beat the
regs man just that's my that's my take
gotcha so we could sit here and talk on
and on and on but uh we're gonna start
to wrap things up just got a couple
final questions for you one of them is
really for the folks that are new to
breeding
what advice do you have for those folks
that are new to breeding it takes a lot
of time money
focus
and
consistency
becoming a breeder
you know it's it's a beautiful thing
but if you're not going to
lay down the cake
for awesome genetics to start with i
always use this analogy you know when i
explain stuff to people you know
if michael jordan and and let's say lisa
leslie had a baby
you're gonna get some pretty good
offspring i mean it's just the way it
may grow i mean you may pop off some
seven footers who are just jumping out
the gym you know it's just that's just
the way it goes even with dogs like you
don't see you don't see breeders
reaching for the mutt that came around
the corner
you know you're not looking for that
much they came around the corner and it
looks like three four different other
varieties you know and then saying oh
i'm gonna make a champion out of that it
doesn't work that way you know i used to
breed dogs and when i came into this it
was the same way same philosophy and
that's why it put me on the couch and
while i was almost divorced because yo i
invested into the proper genetics so
somebody's out there and they're saying
hey i want to go on this journey and
become one of the best breeders known to
mankind start it starts with genetics
and it starts with regular genetics not
something feminized not something even a
clone get away from the clone game
because that you know i had to learn
that as well i can't take in a clone you
don't know how many times that plan has
been cloned so you don't know the
history of that of that situation people
lie everything lies the only thing that
doesn't numbers don't lie is the only
thing that's real so
investing to invest into
uh your your genetics number one but
then also cut out trying to flower in
the same area as as you're trying to
breathe you got to make a choice you
can't chase two rabbits because you'll
catch none so either you're going to be
growing flower for yourself or you're
going to be a breeder and if you're
going to be a breeder you got to be a
breeder 100
24 7 or it doesn't work
you know and and i it's a big it was a
big role of the dice when i decided to
go full-time breeding and you know the
only reason why i did because there were
a lot of individuals who were getting in
pain so much for genetics and yo man i
just wanted to help people out right so
that's what i say if you want to be
someone who helps people out in this
game and give people an opportunity uh
then hey reach for the best genetics and
go 100 don't go 50
at becoming a breeder and do not
practice pollen chucking
that's that that will land you
uh in hot water and a lot of people not
wanting to purchase anything from
definitely some good advice there all
around
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future you know uh
you can google me i've always wanted to
say that
uh
nsgclub.com you can catch me there
cartiercrops.com you know i help people
out in the game and and whatever else
and in the future you know i'm i'm
really focused in on oklahoma right now
oklahoma you know here in in the states
is really allowing us to do our thing
and you see the brand back here we're
gonna have it on packages we just
finished our second crop
and uh it'll be distributed all through
the state of oklahoma so this was a
dream in the vision and it was an idea
that started and so to be able to wake
each day and you know move forward
because you fail many many times but as
long as you continue to move your feet
one in front of the other you're a
success every single day and so this
back here and what's about to happen in
oklahoma is was something that that's
just been planned and it's working out
and i'm really excited to see that face
on packages and and have product within
the market of oklahoma uh but i
you know there's a conflict with me
continuing to breed i love to breed but
it takes a lot of time energy and money
not too sure how long
i'll uh
do that
but you know as long as i'm here and i'm
breathing and i have the resources and
everything around to continue to breed
um then then i'm about that life man
because recreation is pretty dope and
and i want to say this before you
wrapped up
big ups to you chris
big ups to you and for what you do in
the community man once i jumped online
four years ago five years ago you're
like one of the first people i saw
online and and and actually i was like
hey
this dude is doing something really cool
and you know what i want to help people
too
so you inspired myself to to get up and
make things happen and to help people
and use the best side of my of my
passion to help people move along and
you know big ups to you because a lot of
people know you a lot of people respect
you a lot of people
enjoy to listen to the podcast and
listen to you and the people that you
have on and i'm glad you made the
transition from uh the teaching to
really bringing other people in to then
hear other stories and hear other people
that was a great move on your behalf and
big ups to you bro man thanks for your
positive words that's that's really cool
to hear that you've been following me
back then and i was an inspiration for
for you to get going and i'm really
happy for you i mean it seems like
you've you've got your together and
uh you know you're doing some really
good things in this industry and it
seems like you're using the technology
in the future we talked about crispr and
all that stuff to advance
so uh that's pretty cool if you enjoyed
this video click that thumbs up button
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend i'm
releasing a new garden talk podcast
episode and i would love for you to tune
in to future episodes cartier thank you
so much for coming out to this podcast
it's really cool to hear your story
how you do things and i'm excited to see
what you have going in the future so
thanks again peace out everyone