coming up on garden talk bone meal
breaks down a little slower compared to
fish bone mail so if you're going to add
for bloom flour getting the fruit blood
meal is one you want to add kind of in
that transition over from your veg into
the flower state it's beneficial but
it's really helping more the biology
they say it's helping the terpenes i
didn't see an improvement in the
terpenes to me when i use the product
if you don't have protozoa or the other
biology that help eat the bacteria and
fungi your nutrients are being locked up
and stored up they're not being helpful
to the plant micromacro nutrients are
very important because without this we
don't have certain balances happening
within the plant they can't stay in a
homeostasis
if they're low on something it's going
to cause them to start reacting
differently
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this episode number 65. in this
episode i interview medically fit he was
on this podcast once before episode 13
and he talked all about organic dry
amendments that you can use in your
garden that episode currently has over
73 000 plays and there were many
comments left on that episode from
people requesting a part two so in this
episode we continue where we left off
and go over some more organic dry
amendments that you can use in your
garden thanks to all of you support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible a big supporter of this
podcast is ac infiniti they sponsor this
podcast and i use their products
ac infinity now has gardening tools and
accessories such as heavy duty fabric
grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts they also
have all of the equipment needed for a
ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow it during
checkout for a discount on their
products thanks to spider farmer for
being a sponsor a new grow light they
released here in 2022 is the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co280 grow
space and really want to maximize the
light intensity it has a 10 bar design
for an even light spread pulls 1 000
watts from the wall and comes in at 2.9
micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is 4 feet by 4
feet or 5 feet by 5 feet use discount
code mr growth 5 to save on all spider
farmer products and i'll leave a link in
the video description section below
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
medically fit how are you doing today
i'm doing good
just got off work and had to rush home
to kind of get ready for this nice nice
well you are back for a second time i'm
sure a lot of people recognize you from
the first time around that was way back
in episode 13. it was actually uh
released may 8th 2021 and that episode
has over 73 000 views
i know there was a ton of people in the
comments section demanding a part two
they wanted you back for a part two so
you're actually the first reoccurring
guest on this podcast to do a part two
that's pretty cool that's pretty cool
yeah so last time around we talked about
pretty much like dry amendments that you
can use in your garden uh we covered and
have a list here gypsum azomite rock
phosphate langemanite dolomite lime
oyster shell uh we talked about how to
brew teas green sand humic acids biolive
and bokashi so
for those tuning into this episode right
now you do not need to go back and watch
that episode first
you can definitely still what continue
to tune into this episode but i'll
definitely have a link to that past
episode in the youtube description
section below so maybe after this video
can tune in on that video and uh see
some additional amendments that you can
use in your garden or for you that's
already seen it here's part two yeah
exactly so yeah we're gonna continue to
talk about the organic dry amendments to
use in your garden um for those that
don't know who you are can you do a
quick introduction
yeah so i am a living soil cultivator
i've been
cultivating since
mid 2000 2010 11ish
when i lived out in las vegas nevada
and ever since then i've continued to
kind of research and want to know more
and more about the plant and
about the soil uh i look at
it being like a symbiotic relationship
of one
so i wanted to know more about it and so
it set me on my journey and my youtube
kind of video creation of just putting
out videos for like video logs for
myself
and it turned into more than that okay
so let's pick up where we left off
talking about the various amendments or
organic inputs to use let's start with
alfalfa meal can you talk to us about
that what is it what are the benefits
and how do you apply it to your garden
so alfalfa meal is basically the
byproduct of them breaking down alfalfa
for either feed or essential oil extract
fatty extracts things like that
and
what you can use it for is to
kind of feed your plants
it still has
plenty of the
npks it's got some micro macronutrients
it also has a hormone called
trichantinol
and trichantinol is really a plant
growth regulator or plant growth hormone
it helps the plant finish a little
faster
it helps with some of the root root
expansion um
but alfalfa
it uh it kind of helps with this oil
amendment uh building the biology the
they like to break it down it helps with
some protozoa
especially if you do it in a tea
so alfalfa milk is really great i like
to i
like to use it throughout my whole grow
feeding my plants
but when my plants are going into
fruit flower stage
sometimes i bump it up a little bit more
trying to help them ripen a little
faster finish up a little faster
uh something about the trichtanol seems
to help them do that a little bit
so
i can
say harvest my tomatoes a little bit
quicker than
say the 45 50 days it might i might be
able to do a little sooner and what's
the application rate for that uh
application rate is like a tablespoon
per gallon
but if you're doing a top dress
sometimes you have a five gallon pot so
you you probably use you know a couple
tablespoons
if you're making a super soil depends on
the cubic foot because then you're
talking a couple cups to you know three
and a half to six cups
uh
you can make it into a tea
down to earth
likes to state that you can't make teas
out of their products but
it's a soluble you can
it breaks down over time so you can
extract and make teas with them
so there's uh three different ways you
could really apply it you can actually
do a foliar spray if you wanted to
and apply it that way
awesome i actually mixed in some alfalfa
with my fox farm ocean forest soil so
the bag slow and that's already
you know quote
hot soil right so it's already got tons
of amendments in there yeah and so
a lot of people were surprised that i
added in alfalfa with it actually added
in alfalfa and insect frass
and we'll get into insect frass here in
a little bit
but um i had i got some really really
good results off of that and that was
just the veg stage right
but it wasn't too hot
and
i did hear that alfalfa male in
particular somebody had mentioned that
you should avoid using it in flour for
some reason is that just bro science
far as i understand it's bro science
i've never had a problem using alfalfa
in my flower stage ever and i've used it
10 plus years more
and
i i highly talk about it and a lot of
the videos about using alfalfa and
trichano especially in flour to help
them finish up quicker
in a living soil
uh bed
my plants seem to really start finishing
anywhere around day 50 to 60.
63 to me it's almost going over
or the point i like but
that's kind of what that does and what
trichtanal as a plant growth regulator
kind of helps the plant do it's supposed
to help it finish
it's supposed to ripen i think a lot of
people hear plant growth regulators or
pgrs and they kind of
they proceed with caution right because
there is a pgr out there that is uh
known as a carcigen right yes well and
that's the one thing
the difference between organic and
other products that are chemically
changed to get that
that hormone
with organics most most of these are
natural plant like
cytokines and
oxens and
uh tricantinol
these all
happen within the plant and they're all
organically part of the plant so there's
not much you can do to get away from
them using these
and it's not
in the sense like hey i'm going out and
i'm finding this bottle of this plant
growth regulator to help my plant just
do all this crazy growth no that's not
the purpose of it that makes sense let's
move on to back guano so it's something
that's uh very commonly used i know
there's a ton of different guanos bat
guano in particular seems to be very
popular
um i believe that it's high in nitrogen
can you talk to us about bat guano kind
of
you know what it is the benefits
application rate so on and so forth yeah
so you have bat guano and you have
siguano both of them are high in
nitrogen and phosphorus um
bat guano
it's
you're looking at it as the bat is more
of an herbivore eating small insects and
bugs
compared to
like sea birds sea birds
they can eat different
like not just small they'll eat fish
you know different insects sometimes
small animals
uh just depends on the the sea bird
but
the
the bat guano a lot of people look for
it to use a lot of the flower helping
with soil biology
it helps with the soil biology because
they like
the guanos they like the the frost the
poop the manure
manures are higher in nitrogen higher in
phosphorus
and that's where a lot of people
like those especially in flour i
personally don't use a lot of guanos
i've always
felt that they've gave my plant kind of
a odd taste
and i wasn't sure if it was
the guano itself or
the cure method but when i took it out
of like my super soil recipe
i don't get that same taste that i used
to get using guanos so some people
do some people don't use it
it just depends on your preference and
down to earth they have one right yep
they have one theirs is something like a
731 i think something like that okay
gotcha
how about blood meal can you talk to us
about that blood meal
if you're
veganic or vegan you don't want to use
blood meal it's made by animal
byproducts
blood meal is fast acting
like an amino acid type
nitrogen
that if you're top feeding
your plants or making it into a tea it's
going to help your plants
take up nitrogen a little faster
compared to say like feather meal where
it's a slower breaking
down
amendment versus the blood meal so if i
put blood meal in my pot i can expect
within
a week to two weeks it's pretty well
broken down into the soil and the
biology starting to break it down
allowing the plant to uptake it there is
some solubility to it so when you do put
it with water or top dress and add water
some of it's going to get released right
away so your plants can utilize it
but
to me it's one of the things that i do
use
especially in my veg state qrikmit from
wrong but this is one of the amendments
where there's quite a bit of controversy
around it as far as people talk about
organic
organic amendments and they're like well
blood meal isn't organic because of the
source
and you know what were the animals fed
and so on and so forth is that right
that's part of it
so here's my response everything's
organic chemistry when it breaks down
it's organic in nature
it's carbon-based
so these amendments that are
carbon-based and all of these are
carbon-based and that's kind of a source
of nutrients our plants need
um
i
like that
versus
hey it's came from a cow and it was
slaughtered
and it went through this whole horrible
process just to get it
um well the cow is going to be
slaughtered anyhow
for the butcher to produce meat for
people that want to eat it
this is some of the byproducts that
they're just going to throw away
so instead of it sitting there
decomposing bringing in bad pathogens
they're using it and breaking it down
and making it into
an amendment or something that you can
use to
top dress your you know your soil and
help condition your soil because the
biology they love it
they really like what it does
it really helps them with
getting that ready to
be taken up by the plants
bone meal is next on the list and i
could imagine there's some similarities
between blood meal and bone meal can you
talk to us about bone meal yeah so
there's a couple different types of bone
meal you have bone mild then you have
fish bone meal both of them are pretty
high in phosphorus that's one of them
that i really enjoy using
bone meal breaks down a little slower
like a slower release
phosphorus compared to fish bone male so
it's a great deal that if you're going
to add for
bloom flour getting the fruit
bone milk is one you want to add kind of
in that transition over from your veg
into your flower and into the flower
state
because plants are really looking for
phosphorus
and that's really a good source for them
to find it that's
to me a nice organic
there's other amendments you can use
still for phosphorus but
bone meal or fish mill um
i like them i i i think what the biology
in the soil how it helps them
beneficially is the reaction i'm looking
for and not so much that oh it's derived
from a fish or it's derived from an
animal you know from bones
bone meal is more that phosphorus you
still have some nitrogen to it but it's
more that phosphorus and that's when
your plants are producing the fruits
flowers and they're looking for that
phosphorus and not just potassium
and so that's where adding that to me
like in that transition
of from veg over in the flower state and
then into flower
first couple weeks
is uh
a good recommendation for it not so much
not i mean plants like phosphorus for
helping with like rooting and
other growth
but to me it's not crucial where you
know you're looking for certain flowers
to develop and be
dense and full
and so like certain points of
a plant's growth
and their life cycle it's you're trying
to hit certain nutrients
trying to help with that so they they
get a better production during you know
like the tomato wanting to produce more
tomato spots or starts that's kind of
what i mean by that more sights
yeah one thing i learned is that
phosphorus you know you hear about it
being uptaken and flowering it's
actually part of the biomass right so
the actual flowers are mostly
phosphorous so
yeah very important how about cottonseed
meal now cottonseed meal it's derived
kind of like alfalfa it's it's a
byproduct
there's some trace minerals to it not a
lot of npk there's a little bit
but it's mainly like protein
and proteins are what amino acids when
they're broken down
and so
that's where i'm looking at it from
it's good to add for the soil
conditioning to help build the soil
biology
plant use it's it's like the amino acids
that plants are looking for
to help like the building blocks of
leaf tissue and cell development and
things like that so
it's a great use but do the plants
actually uptake the amino acids it's got
to be broken down so that's where the
biology really helps out
your plants still take up amino acids
like
uh keto life makes a product called
green nine which is a amino acid
nitrogen complex
um that it's soluble so it will take up
um just add it in water and water it in
or even top dress
cod seed mill similar to that it's it's
not so soluble like this powder form the
green nine but once the water hits it
and the biology kind of breaks it down
it's gonna make it plain available in
amino acid form
now is it safe to use throughout the
entire grill or should you only use it
in veg or only use it in flour for
example
i would use it through veg and partial
flour like the beginning stages and kind
of wean off because you're not gonna
your plants don't seem to use
in my opinion the amount of amino acids
laid in flour as they do
during flower development okay gotcha
let's move on to crab meal what is crab
meal and what are the benefits of it so
crab mill similar to like what oyster
shell is it's
the crust up
like outer shells of crap
it's
kind of like kitenase chitin in a sense
how do i describe it because oyster
shell has a lot of like calcium to it so
this is going to be similar
but
crab
is similar to like crustacean meal
they both help with the salicylic
jasmonic kind of
part of the plant the self-defense
mechanism because the chitinates
they're great for calcium
so when your plants looking for calcium
outtake especially during bloom flower
uh fruit production
uh it's that's really when it's going to
be kind of like beneficial
getting more calcium into the soil or
it's better to kind of mix it up it's
harder to
make it into a tea
it takes way too long to break down
like
anything that's like
a calcium a crust a shell
it's hard
and so it's going to take a while to
break down similar to what egg is
so like a lot of people use egg for
example and like compost well when
you're doing the whole shell it takes a
while for that all that calcium to be
broken down in the biology to actually
break it up it's similar with
crab meal crustacean meal what is the
application rate for that i imagine that
like a lot of these products i think a
lot of folks are
used to bottled nutrients and having to
do like a half dose for example but a
lot of these organic amendments
i believe correct me if i'm wrong that
you can generally go by
what it says on the instructions is that
true or false i would agree with that
the reason being is they all break down
a little differently
so when you're doing bottled nutrients
you're it's readily available right then
with adding dry or men dry organic
amendments it takes a while the biology
actually has to break a lot of it down
it's not soluble like the percentage on
some of these products are like two to
three percent soluble
the other 90 some percent is insoluble
it has to be broken down
and so
if i'm taking a tablespoon per gallon
which is five milliliters
you know for bottle
it's still pretty much the same ratio
it's just in a dry form
i'm gonna have to try to figure out how
to make it spread evenly
where it you know when you mix
fertilizer up in water it it kind of you
can mix it a little bit evenly through
the water but not the soil you know
compared to dry amendment so
that's the application to me would be
pretty spot on
sometimes
depending on the nitrogen source
i think it could be a little high
uh i think
blood meal
uh if you're adding that to with other
nitrogen sources you might back off just
a little bit
i think you can create a toxicity to it
especially if you're say using like neem
seed meal and
kelp and oyster shell you know other
things that are higher in nitrogen
then you're to me you're going to really
create a toxicity because your nitrogen
levels are high
even though they're in different
amendment sources it's still going to be
high so yeah
when it when you're adding several
different sources of nitrogen yes i
would consider backing off as well okay
and then one last thing on crab meal you
mentioned earlier
defense it helps with defense mechanism
i think you said it like that right
yep so
my question regards to that would be i
think a lot of people's ears perk up
because one of the things with that
plants produce as a defense mechanism is
trichomes so does crab meal you know
this may be a dumb question but uh
does crab meal help with trichome
production in that sense
so
what the plant does is trichomes are
like part of the secondary metabolite
issue
uh your salicylic your jasmonic
pathways are some of the stressor
pathways that when the plants being
attacked by a pathogen kind of triggers
these pathways
well these pathways are kind of also
releasing these
smells
like terpenoids flavonoids um
that actually will help protect it
either
causing the plant to be more stressed
out causing it so see trichomes are
resinous so as like a plant a bug walks
on it it will start to stick to it and
kind of trap itself
it's really if the plant's sick
it's going to be attacked anyhow
when the plant's stressed that's when
it's producing the trichomes the
secondary metabolites that's when it's
really
they're talking it's more active and why
it produces more trichomes so when you
create stressors
over watering underwatering
changing your temperatures i mean low
environmental stressors can help with
production of trichomes
and crabmeal
it has chitin
and so that itself helps with
those metabolites and helps to build
kind of those
trichomes the secondary the stressors
that the plants looking for to do that
gotcha next on the list is crustacean
meal
wanna talk to us about that yeah that's
gonna be similar to crab just a little
different type of
crustacean
sea animal
it's gonna have a little bit of nitrogen
to it a little
uh
like
minor
micro macro type nutrients to some of it
but it's still going to have chitinates
the same thing as crab and kind of
insect frass it's going to help with the
secondary metabolites in the plant
so using that to help
in the soil pre
and i don't believe in top dressing in
some of these i think they take way too
long to top dress
um
i believe if you're going to do it you
maybe scratch it in or kind of try to
blend it in a little bit in the top part
so the biology really gets all over to
help break it down sooner
uh
but adding it to like a tea or something
there's not a lot of solubility to it so
it's it's not worth it so if you really
you are utilizing crab crustacean meal
even oyster shell i recommend doing it
in the soil like a super soil mix i
think it'd probably be beneficial for
those folks that are reusing soil over
and over again right even though it
doesn't break down on the current growth
cycle well next growth cycle it's still
in there it's still breaking down it can
be beneficial so i think some of these
things that you mentioned that take a
long time to break down
well if you're reusing your soil over
and over again then it's certainly a
benefit to to use these longer breakdown
ones soil conditioning and that's what
it's doing helping condition the soil
helping the biology it's giving them a
surface area to kind of live off of as
they're breaking it down building the
colonies
so it does quite a bit it's it's
beneficial
that's one thing that i really enjoy
about using like crab meal crustacean
mill
there was actually a question in the
comment section on the last video we did
and i want to bring it up to you here
the question is do plants benefit much
from the added fatty acids in crustacean
meal
so this is what i
i'm understanding is that's a yes and
the reason being is because plants
produce fat lipids
biologies bacteria they like to break
down fats
doing your compost if you're adding such
things as avocado
that's fat
they love the fats i mean
you got to understand like you can't
just don't grease fat from your some of
your animals you're cooking i'm sure it
could be beneficial in small doses you
know they might enjoy it but
foods that are kind of naturally fatty
oh yeah the biology really go crazy
i try to give my plants dairy cream or
do it in my compost which is a fat
the whole milk
there's a lot of fat content to it
but it's also the lactose the sugars
that's with it that they enjoy
so there's two benefits to it
okay that's good to know moving right
down the list here uh there in
alphabetical order for those of you who
haven't caught on just yet feather meal
how about that talk to us about feather
meal feather mail
is awesome for
long term use
if
you're trying to build a soil
that's going to go
five six seven months
adding something like feather meal to it
will help it's a slow releasing nitrogen
and so it's going to take its time
breaking down and making it available
for your plant
and so it's going to go longer in your
soil than most your blood meals or
knee mills other sources of nitrogen
it's gonna
it's gonna be there a little longer
biology love it it really helps
condition the soil
that would be
so
i would mainly try to focus it
to
not work so much during the veg state
but as i'm getting into flour and laid
in the flour that's what i'm hoping that
the feather meal is going to last that
long because i like
to do bigger pots
get a bigger root base so my plants can
veg a little longer before i start
fruiting them
because i want the bigger the root the
bigger the fruit right if i can get
a basket of tomatoes versus just a
handful i think i'm going to take the
basket
so
if i let my plants veg a little longer
so they get a little bit bigger
then as they move in the flour that's
what i'm hoping that feather meal it
lasts to i get in the flour because my
plants still need nitrogen there's your
flowers your
produce it still needs nitrogen to
produce
and do the cell division and everything
else that it needs to do
i think that's one of the common
misconceptions out there is that uh
plants don't need nitrogen and flowering
you hear about oh it's heavy in nitrogen
for the veg stage but when the flower
stage you don't need it that's
completely false right i mean they need
some form of nitrogen they may need more
potassium and phosphorus in flowering
but they also still need nitrogen it's
not like nitrogen just completely falls
off the map on that one they still
uptake nitrogen believe it or not even
into late flower
plants are still looking for it
absolutely
how about fish hydrolysate so fish
hydrolysate
it's kind of like
it's a processed
hydrolysate which means it's
almost like a fat
most hydrolysates are a type of like a
fatty acid in a sense um
and the way the amino acids and the kind
of like the fatty acids are processed
down
um
and made
into these hydrolysates that are made
like kind of plant available
they have like
different proteins amino acids peptides
to them
um
but it's it's a process that
uh
done to the fish
to get them to be easily uptaken for
plants
they're good but they can be a negative
at the same time
you can overdo the hydrolysate versus
some of the meal
so i i would use a little less i do like
to use it more in a tea
versus
like a top dress or amendment
where the hydrolysate is more soluble
it breaks down a lot faster adding it to
water it's like once you add it to water
it kind of like disintegrates and it's
readily available
and so
that's where it's great to for a quick
feed in your plants because it's great
for nitrogen source amino acids uh but
if you go back to like some of the fish
meal it's slower it doesn't break down
the same way the biology has to kind of
break it down over time
so there's a little difference in the
hydrolysate versus meals especially when
it comes to that you also mentioned fish
meal along with that fish hydrolysate
would you say these are pretty
pretty similar in the sense as what like
the npk is
they're just kind of different forms
or what um
yes
so
they have a nitrogen they have some
phosphorus some potassium but they have
more like the amino acid complex
okay so it's a different form of
nitrogen
more in an amino acid form than it is
like a nitrite or nitrate that's my
understanding of it okay and then so for
fish meal
when would you typically apply that uh
well fish mill kind of works through
a lot of the veg state
um
you're looking to build that soil you're
looking to build the biology you want to
take up the nitrogen
but as you're getting into
flour that's when i'd kind of start
cutting back i don't need all those
amino acids i'm already having some
stuff that has nitrogen that's releasing
i don't need to add more to it if i'm
trying to help with the biology i might
add a little bit but i'm not gonna add a
lot
okay that's good to know moving on to
insect frass so this is something that i
use i know there are a couple types of
insect frass the one i use is uh black
black soldier
insect frass
and i know one of the most important
things on this is chitin is what it's
known for can you talk to us about
insect frass what is it one of the
benefits and how you apply it so this is
something i've talked about for many
years since insect frass came out with
their insect frost
i always kind of followed subcool's
recipe on this super soil and then i
really started learning about amendments
and learned insect fast
insect frass
is great it most of them are either like
a three one two or two two two when it
comes to mpk
but most of it's frass
poop
another name is guano
so
that's where
plant bugs eat plants and so their frass
is not
it's more
omnivore not herbivore it's plant-based
where you're eating
uh all this plant tissue you're eating
cytokine
so that's where the scidic in their
shells like the the exoskeletons
are the cytokines for these bugs so when
they're dying off their shells
are part of the frass as well
and that's where some of the cytokine
comes in
cytokin
so
insect frass has a couple different
brands
black soldier flies
you have
different
type of mealybugs or different type of
bugs
that they use to kind of harvest the
frass but frass
is great
for
protozoa as well
so when people do
soil biology
they talk a lot about bacteria and fungi
they forget about needing protozoa
helps eat the bacteria and fungi to
release the nutrients that they're
storing in their bodies
insect fracks is one of those things
that actually has protozoa to it like
alfalfa meal
it's kind of in the plant tissue
it it seems to work its way where
it's part of this
byproduct that when it's in the water
they kind of start hatching and
releasing like they go in a dormant
stage and just
kind of wait to be hatched in a sense
uh but insect frass has always been a
great amendment
uh for the cytokin for what it brings
for the biology because it also brings
that bacteria fungi and different
strains of it to the soil and that's
what you're looking for is a little bit
of diversity in soil biology
so insect frass
is to me one of the better amendments
that if you're looking to add just a
couple
that would be one of them i would be
wanting to add the cytokine alone that
you get
just from the frass helps with that
trichome development
that secondary metabolism and the plant
to fight off pets and pathogens
so it's that beneficial
it to me it's more beneficial than crab
meal
crustacean meal
a character from wrong but
there's something in it that helps with
resistance to pottery mildew as well
it's a chitin that's the chitinase
that's the different strains that are in
it
of bacteria
that you can do a foliar application
that's supposed to help
fight off the omyces the molds
mildews
so definitely super beneficial
especially for those of you who are out
there that
fight pottery mildew right i have issues
with that
this can be something that you add in as
an amendment and could help fight off it
so yeah to me like when we were talking
about how
the crab meal the crustacean
have nitrogen ratios well so does insect
frost
those others don't have protozoa to them
protozoa is one of the parts of the soil
food web that you need to have
when you're doing gardening outdoors
indoor cultivation and you're trying to
mimic mother nature it's like
bacteria fungi protozoa
and on down
that's the third one in the chart
that's what helps eat the other two
if you don't have protozoa or the other
biology that help eat the bacteria and
fungi your nutrients are being locked up
and stored up they're not being helpful
to the the plant
so that's why to me it's one of the most
beneficials
of
the crab crustacean insect frass even i
i'd rather use that over the guanos
and that's what i do i use both
types of insect press
and i think there's a lot of people like
oh well i use microbial inoculants i
don't think there's a whole lot of
microbinoculants that have protozoa in
it right i think it's mostly there is
not right
that is correct yes
there is a show that we were watching
the other day talking about the same
problem
what is one of the things missing in
most people's soil protozoa
well protozoa is really key and there's
not a lot of products out there on the
market that you can buy
that are going to retain
the protozoa in it
like if you did a bottle of nutrient
they have it has a shelf life protozoa
is only going to live in there so long
before they start dying off because
they didn't hibernate they thought they
were being active
kind of that suspended animation type
deal
once they you know kind of hibernate
then they get rehydrated reanimate come
back a life and
do their job but some of those microbes
are dying off right once they go dormant
they die off they don't fully die off
but a lot of them it dies back they kind
of hibernate a lot of them really
hibernate
and they found that
it it takes either high temperatures or
like a major disturbance to kill off
most of the biology
but for a drought to happen it happens
naturally most of them don't all die off
they kind of hibernate until the
conditions are right before they come
alive again same thing with
salmonella e coli they're around you
every day
it just everything is keeping them at
bay until something causes them to get
out of hand and out of control and then
that's when they become deadly
fascinating i didn't know that you would
be really surprised that's why a lot of
people become
in fear of bacteria always washing and
cleaning and that phobia
that's one of the that's why they're oh
my god it's really all around me it
could kill me at any time
it's it's sad but it's not as deadly as
they make it out to be okay good to know
moving on to kelp meal talk to us about
kelp meal kel mill
is
very beneficial
it has
up to 70 micro macro nutrients
it has different
plant growth regulator plant growth
hormones pgrs
such as cytokines and oxins
also has some gibberellin in it so
this is one of them that people really
like to push
but you have to watch out kelp can have
some heavy metals
same thing with alfalfa or some of these
other amendments but
there's ways around that and we can talk
about that another time
but kelp
it's just an all-around
one of the better products really for
the overall
nutrient availability it provides
it provides more than two-thirds of
these products together with the amount
of micro macro nutrients the npk to it
like that's why a lot of people
down the earth most of their bio lines
have kelp to them
because they really consider that
beneficial to their product
that it has so much nutrient to it
and its nutrient density
that
that's why they really look to use in it
there's not many other
amendments that have
70 micro macronutrients
and that's the one thing i preach a lot
on my channel is micromacronutrients are
very important because without this we
don't have certain balances happening
within the plant
they can't stay in a homeostasis
if they're low on something it's going
to cause them to start reacting
differently
and
plants need heavy metals
despite what we think they need some
lead they need some arsenic they need
boron but very very trace minutes amount
like
just you know you a droplet's too much
if you went like a tenth 100th of that
maybe
but that's
that's why kelp is so important is
because it has a lot of this
what the plant needs in it as humans we
need the same thing we need a lot of
these trace elements
we don't get them in our diet
the soil doesn't have it these bottled
nutrients they don't have a lot of these
trace elements
that's why we
find that
using
amendments that have higher amounts of
trace elements
produce a better
profile with the plant terpene profile
they're healthier because they're
getting the full
spectrum of elements that they need here
but a lot of people talking about super
foods to eat
would we consider this a super amendment
for your plants
in a sense yeah
it would be something it would be almost
like a super amendment it's one of those
that
i would put a top of my list above most
of these other other amendments
it's not the end-all be-all i would take
a few other amendments over it but
that's me
but this is one of them that
if you're not using something like
azomite
to get the rock dust the like you know
the trace minerals from the rock dust
this this works great it helps to get
those
tray smell elements in there that you're
not getting from the rock dust
we talked about azomite in the previous
episode we did together so once again
that is linked down in the description
section below for you guys to tune into
that
let's go over one more and then we will
wrap things up how about neem seed meal
can you talk to us about that yeah so
neem seed meal
it's
it's a great product
a lot of people over concerned about
something called asteractin
as directin is toxic to bugs
not humans it can be if taken in high
doses
but
azeractin is
part of
it's how do i want to describe it it's
extracted so the neemc mill
is a by-process of different extractions
methods pulling
some of the oils out of the neem
they use either alcohol or water but
names made into so many products
from toothpaste to different
vitamins that we can take as humans
people in different countries actually
eat some of the neem themselves to help
so it's not bad as people make it out to
be
neem
seed meal also helps
with bad pathogens and pests that are in
the soil
they keep away bad
nematodes so if you have root feeding
nematodes
neem seed will help prevent and keep
some of them away from your plants
neem seed milk is also great when it
comes to me a terpene production
something about the neem seed
and i not sure or heard a lot of people
talk about it but i know when i add a
higher
concentration of it to my soil
the smell and the aroma i'm getting from
my plant like it really helps with the
flavonoid or the terpene production in
those plants
yeah i know there is a lot of
controversy behind neem in general and
uh i think you hit the nail on the head
there with the acid reactant
is what a lot of people are really
complaining about and like you mentioned
it is commonly used in so many different
products
and so um well
their concern is hey you're spraying
your plants with neem oil
right because you're trying to use it as
a ipm
well oh it's systemic it goes into your
plant it's not systemic
it does not go into the plant cell
tissue and stay there
that's not true
what it does is it kind of biodegrades
over time it's just an oil just like
everything else but they're concerned
that it's leaving as direct and as a
residue
well first of all are you spraying it on
your plants
when they're fruiting or in flour
because most of the time we tell you not
to do it then
you don't want to spray your fruits and
your your flowers your herbs if you're
going to be using them to consume
so
you're not going to have a concern of
any as
direct in
residue
but first of all if you actually read
the label in contents it says there
should be none in it
should be all extracted out
and the might new traces that are left
in it
it even will tell you that they will
cause harm to bugs
not earthworms not bigger like birds or
other rodents
insects because of what it does to their
reproductive organs what it does to the
extosin
that's
the harm it doesn't do it to us though
yes people i've talked about oh well
there's deaths in these other countries
if you read what happened that said they
too consumed a large amount
more than they should have and that's
what
ended up killing them and it wasn't
just hey they took the recommended
dosage no they took more than what was
recommended didn't kill them
so
when people talk about a concern of
asteractin it's not a concern
you're not putting high doses of neem
seed meal
for your plants to even uptake it you're
not spraying a lot of neem on your
plants for it to be a concern so okay
that's good to know
so i asked you this question at the end
of the last episode that we did together
i really want to ask it again because we
have a lot of new folks that are joining
i mean
we filmed that episode a year ago and
between
now and then
there's been a countless number of
people who have just started gardening
for the first time so for those folks
that are pretty new maybe starting to
use some of these organic inputs these
organic amendments
what advice do you have for them well
some of it's going to depend on if
you're indoor or outdoor cultivating
outdoor
you're going directly in the soil so
you're
you can have problems with pathogens
right away
indoor you're you're you're getting a
soil you're kind of creating it you're
putting in different biology so you kind
of understand what's in there
so
if i'm looking at amendments and i'm
looking at both conditions if i'm doing
a big garden and i'm trying to prepare
it
i'm going to put down
something that has some micro
macronutrients either like azomite
or kelp
kelp is going to give me some of the
plant
hormones that my
my seedlings are looking for to get
started growing
and grow healthy start shooting out
and up and root growth
so kelp like we're talking is one of
those super ones you would put up there
i would look at insect frass and not
over guano because the protozoa
so you're getting the bacteria the fungi
the protozoa you're getting chitinas
you're getting stuff to kind of help the
plants defend themselves
building
the soil diversity as well because
it is about soil diversity the soil and
the plant are one they communicate they
talk
the plant actually eats up the biology
and spits it out that's a whole other
talk
and if you talk to dr james white he
could go into that but
so that would be two of them would be
insect frass and the kelp meal you don't
really need nitrogen some of these
products have nitrogen so when people
are like oh i need nitrogen you know i'm
not so worried about nitrogen these
products have it i don't need high
amounts of nitrogen like i've been told
for years by all these big ag companies
so you need nitrogen nitrogen no no i
don't i don't need as much i need it but
i don't need high amounts of it alfalfa
mill would be a good one
neem seed mill would probably be another
good one
if i was looking to add a couple
but
i would find something that's
not an all-in-one i don't believe in the
all-in-ones
because a lot of people
like down earth has
biolife which is like five products in
one
i don't quite believe in that i believe
doing it yourself so you're getting more
instead of us like
i can discuss that later but
humic acid
that's another one
that would be up there in my super ones
because your plants are trying to create
humus when they're breaking down this
product and the humus is retaining all
the nutrients all of your ion bonds
cations for the plant to take up that's
where it stores the energy that's where
it stores everything is in the humus
humic acid
so i would look at that because it's
very beneficial for soil biology as well
lots of good information there
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future well uh you can
find me on youtube and instagram both uh
youtube
just over 20 plus thousand followers so
it's been growing uh we're trying to do
some changes with the channel it's gonna
take a few months um
but i want to make it more about a brand
and not about
me as the person
i want to get more content on there from
other
people in the industry kind of like what
you've been doing
um with some of your channels but i want
to get
more
scientists
people that are botanists
people soil biologists people that
are really in the science of everything
because a lot of people that follow me
we really try to turn you on to the
science of things
and give you just enough that you want
to do the research yourself
oh i heard him talk about this
oh i heard so-and-so talk about oh well
maybe we need to look it up and see what
this is really about
you know like
that's my job is to try to turn people
on to that information so
i want to try to do more with it
i want to try to do more with my youtube
channel try to get more information out
and not just through me
i'll definitely be looking forward to
that i've learned so much from you in
regards to organic gardening and
just the science behind the plant and uh
i think it would be awesome to see you
like interview or like have discussions
with people who are on that level
because i think you'd bring a ton of
value you do such a good job of taking
that information and
putting it into a form that's digestible
to somebody who's pretty new you know
without and i tried to do that keeping
it simple so it's easy to understand
because there's a lot of big complex
words and i'm like oh my god like how do
you even say that
you know and
i know that even me being an educated
man
it's still easier for people to get it
at the simplest form and move into
something a little harder than trying to
start off with harder information that
they don't even understand
yeah it can be confusing a lot of things
can go over people's head for sure so
i'm looking forward to that i'll
definitely have a link to your channel
down in the youtube description section
below if you're tuned in on one of the
podcast platforms just search for
medically fit on youtube and his channel
will pop up lots of good information on
there
if you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up button subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend i'm receiving a new
garden talk podcast episode and i would
love for you to tune in to future
episodes medically fit once again thank
you so much for coming on the podcast
once again second time around uh i am
happy might need a third one potentially
right
if i create controversy over like dr
bruce bugsby
uh comments i made we might be able to
get the third one on here for sure
yeah we could definitely go down that
because i know you had uh quite a few
things to say about that particular
podcast that i did with him and uh yeah
maybe that would be a good episode for
the next time around it's kind of going
over some of the things that you had
thought that you didn't agree upon with
him because there is uh i know you
mentioned we won't get too deep into it
we're closing things up here but uh
you had pointed to some studies in
regards to that that conflicts with some
of the things they had mentioned so
maybe we can go over that in the next
episode yeah that might be pretty
interesting for some of your
viewers to really hear
some of the information from another
point
absolutely
alright everybody hope you enjoyed that
one and i will see you in the next
episode peace out