what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching my extras channel
mars hydro sent me over their sp
3000 led grill light and in this video i
am going to test the par
output and i'm also going to do a heat
test on it i actually already did
another video
where i unboxed the unit and i tested
two of them in a four by four grow tent
in this video i'm gonna test one in a
two by four grow tent
i'm not going to go over all of the grow
light specs but i will leave a link down
in the description section below so you
can click on that if you want to learn
more about the light
for the part test i'm going to use the
apogee mq620 extended range par meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers
and the measurements are in ppfd i do
these part test videos just to give you
a general idea of what the power output
is
it's not going to be 100 accurate i take
measurements and grow tents that have
reflective walls
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind i'm going to take
measurements at three different
distances 18 inches
24 inches and 30 inches and this light
does have a dimmer on it i'll set it to
i've plugged the led grow light into my
kilowatt meter and it shows
2.44 amps pulling 290 watts from the
wall
alright let's get into the measurements
[Applause]
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
hey
[Applause]
[Music]
three
so
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
this grow light in the description
section below
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching
and until next time peace
[Music]