what is up everybody feed that don't
only my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and today I got a part test video for
you this is a 315 want
CMH grow light it has a vertical bulb in
it 90 percent reflective material built
in ballast and this actually covers a
three foot by three foot gross space I
actually got this one straight from the
manufacturer I was at an Expo in Las
Vegas the name of the manufacturer is
sino well I'm not sure what the spectrum
looks like or what color temperature the
bulb is unfortunately they don't list
that in the listing description I'll
lift this link in the description
section below so you can click on it if
you want to learn more I'm using that
apogee MQ 500 quantum sensor this is
going to give up our measurements in
ppfd for this part test video I will of
course let the measurements do the
talking I'm going to do distances at 12
inch 24 inch and 36 inches away those
are the most common distances for CMH
grow lights alright let's just get into
the measurements
[Music]
all right they're the results for the
315 want CMH light the one with the
vertical bulb pretty standard
measurement there for 315 Watts EMH 36
inches is what I would run for seedlings
clones 24 inches of veg and then 12
inches for flower although I might even
go up to 13 or 14 inches since that dead
center reading was about 1100 just like
I mention in the last part test video
you can get away with 1,100 if you're
running co2 but just keep in mind that
you could experience some burning in
that dead center cuz that is a little
hot I'd like to know if you guys running
CMH grow lifes what distances do you
have your plants on different stages of
growth let me know in the comments
section below
so I've lots of videos coming up more
part test videos I think I've got like 6
more videos so hope you guys are digging
these so far and yeah I will leave it at
that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]
you