what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extras channel got a
topic video for you today
well actually topic / discussion video
for you today something I definitely
want to get your feedback on so every
morning I wake up and I drink a cup of
coffee and I pull out a book and I can't
start drinking my coffee until I'm
reading my book that's how I get myself
to read in the current book I'm reading
right now is MJ horticulture the
indoor-outdoor medical growers Bible and
this is by Jorge Cervantes absolute
classic I believe this version came out
in 2006 I've browsed through this before
but now I've gone back to it and now I'm
reading it cover to cover and one of the
things that really jumped out on me is
on page 164 it's the section on lighting
and I'm gonna read this off to you and I
want to get your feedback in the comment
section below so this is something that
I've done to my plants which is give it
a period of darkness between vegetation
and flowering I gave my plants a period
of darkness and thought that it went to
flowering faster so I thought it started
flowering faster then I did it to some
other plants and didn't think that was
the case so I'm not really sure if this
truly works or not but reading this book
kind of gave me some hope again now I
have talked about this idea to others
and for example Mike over on patreon as
a patreon supporter he said that he
experiment with this as well and I
forget what he said off top of my head
but I believe he said that it did work
for him um let me read off these few
sentences here and then and then we'll
talk from there
so what it says on page 164 give plants
36 hours of total darkness
just before inducing flowering with 12
12 photo period this heavy dose of
darkness sends plants an unmistakable
signal to flower sooner growers using
this technique report that plants
normally show signs of flowering such as
pistol formation within two weeks and
develop pistols after a week of
flowering growers ever experimented with
giving plants up to 48 hours of total
darkness to jump-start flowering and
have found that 36 hours three
continuous 12-hour nights is most
effective I'm so again this is something
I've done with my plants actually before
even reading this I've
my plants a period of darkness just
thinking that the additional darkness
would kind of give them that jumpstart
into flowering now we're not talking
about Auto flowers here right Auto
flowers stay on the same light cycle you
can keep them on like an 18-6 light
cycle for example throughout their
entire grill this is for a photo period
plants which need a period of extended
darkness so around 12 hours of darkness
complete darkness and then the plant
will start flowering so during the
darkness beard what happens what
actually happens with the plant what it
does is it produces a hormone hormones
called Flor gentle it's called a
flowering hormone and once those
florigen levels have built up then it
will start to flowers so my thought
process behind this would give that
plant an additional period of darkness
than those florigen levels will build up
and then it would start to flower sooner
I did this for several grows and I
thought I could see the transition
happened faster but then I did it for
another grow and it didn't seem to
transition faster so I kind of just
shook it off and then stopped doing it
but then reading this makes me want to
do it again and experiment with a little
bit more but I would love to know you
guys out there who are growing who have
maybe tried this do you give your plants
a period of darkness between the
vegetation stage going into the flower
stage again I'm talking about photo
period plants so for photo paper plants
do you give your plants you know 24
hours of darkness 36 48 hours of
darkness and then go into the flowering
stage and if you do that have you seen a
faster transition of flowering so
showing signs of sex faster than when
you don't do it let me know down in the
comments section below that's really all
I wanted to cover in this video I will
link this book down in the description
section below definitely recommend it
for intermediate to advanced growers
beginners I mean I bought this when I
was beginner I just a lot of it's just
one over my head to be honest with you
but if you're trying to take your grow
up to the next level this one is
definitely good read so it's pretty much
it for this video guys if you enjoy it
please click that thumbs up and I will
leave it at that thank you so much for
watching and until next time peace
you
[Music]