what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris okay mr. grow it and
you'll watching my extras channel Mars
hydro sent me over there TS three
thousand LED grow light in this video I
am going to test the power output and
I'm also going to do a heat test on it I
actually already did a part test and he
test and actually in Box this unit in a
previous video however in that video I
adjusted the dimmer to go up to 100%
Amara's hydro doesn't recommend
adjusting the dimmer to hundred percent
because it decreases the lifespan of the
fixture and I had some requests in the
comments section for me to do a part
test at factory settings which is 450
watts so that's what I'm going to do in
this video if you want to see the other
part test on this girl light I'll link
it down in the description section below
I also provide a link to this grill
light in the description section below
for the part test I'm gonna use the
apogee MQ 620 extended range par meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd if this is your first time
watching my part test videos I do them
just to give you a general idea of what
the power output is they're not meant to
be a hundred percent accurate
I take measurements in grow tents which
have reflective walls that could
increase the numbers so just keep that
in mind
while on coverage area for this grow
light is 4 feet by 4 feet I'm taking
measurements in a four foot by four foot
Grovetown I've plugged this LED grow
light into my kilowatt meter and it
shows three point seven eight amps
pulling four hundred forty nine
watts from the wall alright let's get
into the measurements
[Music]
[Applause]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just reminder that there is a link to
this grow light down in the description
section below along with that other part
tests I did where I adjusted the dimmer
to 100% that's pretty much it for this
video guys if you enjoyed it please
click that thumbs up and I will leave
that that thank you so much for watching
and until next time face
[Music]