what's up everybody feed that don't only
my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watch a my extra channel here I
have the plant max jungle g6 LED grow
light this LED grow light was sent to me
in order to do this unboxing and part
test video so in this video I'll do just
that I'll unboxing and I'll show you
what comes inside the box and then I use
my Apple gmq 500 power meter in order to
do the part test this meter measures
from 389 nanometers to 692 nanometers
plus or minus 5 nanometers and the
measurements are in ppfd
so if there's any light being emitted
outside of that range it will not show
on this meter okay first thing out the
box is the grow light it is folded in
half and nicely packaged to prevent
damage then there are two boxes inside
one is labeled accessories and the
second one is labeled LED driver inside
the box that's labeled LED driver is
surprise surprise a driver inside the
box that's labeled accessories is a user
manual controller connector cable an AC
power cord and in this bag there are two
sling hangers a 120 volt 240 volt power
adapter and some screws to mount the
driver to the back of the fixture if
this is your first time tuning into my
part test videos I do these just to give
you a general idea of what the power
output is this test isn't going to be a
hundred percent accurate I'm taking
measurements in a grow tent and a
reflective walls in the grow tent could
increase the part numbers so keep that
in mind the coverage area for this LED
grow light is 4 feet by 4 feet and I'm
taking measurements in a 4 foot by 4
foot grow tent I'm not gonna go over all
of the grow lights features but it will
provide a link in the description
section below so you can click to learn
more this LED grow light does have a
dimmer on it for the part test
I'll have the grow light on 100% when
the grow light is on and turned up to
100% it pulls 659 Watts from the wall
with five point four six amps alright
let's get into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think about this LED grow
light let me know in the comment section
below
just a reminder that this grow light is
linked in the description section below
so you can click on that link if you
want to learn more about this light and
I'll leave it at that thank you so much
for watching and until next time peace
[Music]