welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into the
garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 130 in this episode I interview
welcome to the grow tent some of you
longtime listeners of the podcast May
remember him from episode 5 back in
February 2021 great episode there where
he gave a ton of advice on beginner
gardening this time around we get into
plant breeding he has been breeding for
the past 7 years and has created many
amazing crosses he talks about some of
the crosses that he's done and his
methods for creating his own strains if
you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow I'll have both those channels
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the General Public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that go possible thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their humidifiers which can
help increase the humidity in your grow
space their humidifiers have 10
different levels and Smart Control
features such as VPD and humidity
programming so you can get precise
humidity control click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their humidifiers and
the discount code Mr Grow 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend stash blend is
a 215 plant additive that can used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash Mars Hydro check
out their all-in-one grow tank kits
their grow tank kits include everything
you need to start a new into a grow
system grow tent LED grow lights inline
fan filtration clip fan grow bags and
other useful tools on their website they
break it down by beginner kits Advanced
kits and premium kits there is a special
price for these grow tank kits so go to
the website mars-hydro
code Mr Grow to save on any of their
products and we're back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with welcome to the grow tent how you
doing hey what's up buddy it's long time
no see right you've been on the podcast
before uh I looked it up February 6th
2021 is when that was released and here
we are in 2024 so it's been several
years yeah last time we linked up we
talked about well the topic was the best
advice for beginner gardening indoors
and 300 45,000 views that episode went
insane yeah and uh dude you had so much
great info on there I'm so happy to have
you back here and this time around we're
going to talk about breeding something
you kind of dip your toes in over the
several years now and uh we're going to
get all into this your story and so on
and so forth first I do want to say
congratulations to you for passing
200,000 subscribers on your channel man
that's unbelievable back when we first
did that interview back in 2021 you had
20,000 subscribers so your channel has
exploded over there but yeah 200,000
subscribers not easy welld deserved man
you have put in so much work over the
years man I'm just so happy for you so
congratulations can you introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together yeah if
they if they haven't seen that episode
they should go back into your older
videos and go watch it's great
episode uh my name's GT I run a website
and a YouTube channel called Welcome to
The Grow Tent where I still focus on
brand new Growers and teaching them the
vernacular uh showing them that they can
grow this plant without a ton of
equipment a ton of you know expensive
equipment and uh I just wanted to show
everybody that they didn't have to pay
high dispensary prices and that they
could do this even if they were having
trouble uh getting started with it in
the beginning or they've had a few bad
grows in their belt I just wanted to
show them like I can teach you how to
use this equipment that you have you
didn't have to go out and buy anything
else I could still show you with
whatever ever you had I could get you on
the right track to where you were
getting good yields and uh we've had a
lot of successful years with it and uh
it's been a great time I get to meet and
talk to so many awesome people like I
love this community so much like in a
lot of communities you can have very
toxic Behavior I have a lot of positive
feedback and interactions with this
community uh I just I really like this
community and all the creators that are
around it that also put content out I'm
a big fan of everybody so so you've been
many many years just growing the plant
natural and then harvesting and
obviously consuming your Harvest now
you've gotten to the point where you are
breeding what got you into breeding uh
you know it's a couple of things I would
be uh it wouldn't be right if I said it
was just one thing but you know the
Natural Curiosity and just wanting to
you know learn about this plant that I
you know loved so long you know so much
for so long and uh and I just figured it
was kind of the the next steps I'm a
very big uh Chaser of effects so uh
don't really care about the color or you
know what the fade of it looks like or
anything like that I'm very big since
I'm a medical patient with it on how the
plant or the cultiv bar or strain
whatever the hip lingo is these days I'm
very uh I'm I'm a constant Chaser of the
effect of whatever I'm smoking on
because I have ADHD and I have really
bad anxiety and uh I actually use this
plant to control it I used to be on
three different medications and now I
take none and I just you know literally
walk around with dugouts in my pocket
and then just apply kind of as needed so
it's one of those things where uh you
know I really like what this plant does
but I don't really like the taste of it
but you know how it affects like my
anxiety is it's immeasurable on how much
I like it so what if I took this plant
over here and then I crossed it with
this plant over here where I really like
the taste of it and uh you know that's
you know how it all started and my wife
says that uh my ADHD can work as a super
power for me because I can hyperfocus on
things that I'm interested in and uh so
I can pick up learning curves on things
pretty easily because of that hyperfocus
that I get from it and uh uh you it just
uh anytime I turn my attention onto
something I usually go pretty hard in
the paint trying to figure out how to do
it myself so so how many years has it
been now since you've been actually
doing the breeding uh seven seven years
so I still consider myself you know
completely uh like new to this we we'
had some really cool stuff that we've
made I say we but it's just literally me
um we just sounds more normal for some
reason but uh I've made some pretty cool
stuff and I still consider myself you
know new to this field with only seven
years under my belt uh you know breeding
and stuff like that but I've had a
really good time doing it uh whenever I
first started doing it you know I was
putting the videos up and uh I didn't
think anybody would be interested in I
was just kind of documenting what I was
doing and people are like hey how do we
get some of those I was like for what
what are you talking about and then they
were like no we want those and so I you
know whenever originally started it was
literally I was just doing it for myself
and then people are like well wait no we
want to do that we want those and I was
like oh okay and that's that's pretty
much just how it started how it got me
into it so so what do you personally
like for taste smell and effects uh you
know I I I find my my myself changing as
I've gotten older cuz whenever I was
younger it was literally just SK junky
dies and then anything that could kind
of calm my mind down is like the effect
that I was always chasing with it is I
always tell people my brain feels like
it's on a train and it's tring to go
down 30 different tracks at the same
time and whenever I smoke dude it just
like and it just like centers it back
down onto one track and I can like focus
and you know and run down that just one
track at a time like my wife she's very
good on calling me out on it she'll be
like you've switched subjects three
times in the last 10 minutes she's like
go upstairs and smoke and then come back
down and try talking again because
whenever I haven't smoked dude like I'll
bounce I'll get like three you know
three fours the way through explaining
my point and that'll remind me of
something else and then I'll jump to a
different subject and jump to a
different subject and I actually do it
in my videos and I used to have to spend
a ton of time editing it out and like
refocusing it back onto the subject at
hand and so that's kind of where the
channel the little mantra for the
channel where I you you'll hear me I'll
say calm down Focus relax you know and
uh it's just me kind of trying to
reenter myself to stay on topic because
otherwise I get I'll just jump all over
the place and a video that was supposed
to be about this is five minutes in
there of talking about something else
and I'm like all right Cal down and then
uh everybody started saying I got tired
of editing out the videos is all it ever
was and then I just started leaving it
in there and everybody really liked it
and now if you look on all of our shirt
designs you can actually see the relax
calm down and focus always hidden in the
design so you have a couple of your
t-shirts I know you see you wear them
all the time it's great yeah I do wear
them in some of the episodes as a
tie-dye one a couple tie-dye ones you
sent me and then a purple Frost giant
one which we'll I'm sure we'll be
talking about purple Frost giant here
pretty shortly yeah it's a great but as
far as the taste smell and effects that
you personally like are you looking to
do that in your breeding as well like
are those are characteristic or trades
you look for When selecting parent
plants for breeding projects or are you
kind of going after what the market
wants instead well I I'd be it'd be
remiss to say I wasn't paying attention
to the market because like some of these
breeding projects like if you take
anything out like you know seven or
eight Generations you could spend a
decade working on something and if it's
not something that the market wants then
you you spend a decade working on
something that's no longer popular like
you know what if you had somebody that
was like oh yeah I'm really into a track
players and I'm going to spend a bunch
of time you know making a cool a nobody
wants at track players anymore uh you
know like right now I feel like the main
majority of the markets really focus on
like Fruity or dessert kind of stuff and
so I do take those factors in there but
my main my main goal whenever I'm
breeding is effect it's effect driven
sure I love when they smell fantastic I
love uh The Taste but it's and those
those factors do play into it but at the
same time since I'm a med I come at it
with a medical kind of perspective so
it's 100% how does this affect me how do
I like it how do the people that tried
it like it do they like this at all you
know if they don't like it you know I've
had ones where I made where I thought
they were great but they just did not
get a great reception from like the
public and you know that's why you do
tester runs where you're like did you
guys like this they're like yeah it grew
great but I didn't really like the
flavor profile or you know maybe it came
out a little extra mtholly or something
like that and you know it's just you
have to base your decisions on you know
kind of like the majority of your your
clientele what they like you know stuff
like that if I was just making it for
for me then I wouldn't care what anybody
else said you know what I mean that
makes sense I'm sure it's you got to be
a balancing act right a little bit of a
little bit of both you got to satisfy
yourself and the market yeah now I mean
luckily the the market isn't too too far
away from what I like uh some of the
more like candy smelling strains you
know I'm not terribly fond of but
there's a big there's a big push for
them in the market so I understand that
and I take that into consideration when
I'm thinking about like crosses or which
phenotypes I'm hunting down and stuff
like that because what I exactly want
might not always be exactly what the
market wants like I've had bags where
open it up and it literally smelled like
you stuck your head in a bag full of
candy and I'm just like me you know but
other people like I would use that bag
to show off to people I'm like here
smell this and they're like oh my God I
freaking love it I'm just like
amateur you know it's just it's just one
of those things where like I can see the
appeal to it it might not be my favorite
thing but I understand where it comes
from because you know whenever I was
younger smelled like that it just it
just smelled like you know skunky you
know easily kind of now it like you can
smell candies and different you know
scents and flavor profiles and uh but
it's not to say I don't appreciate it
cuz I do because I I appreciate every
you know every single thing about this
plan I love it man I totally hear you
with the candy stuff I mean I I'm not
too crazy about that either I'm more of
like a skunky even like I even favor
earthy more and the candy type stuff and
yeah yeah but everybody has their own
thing you know everybody has their own
likes and preferences so dude that's
what's so great about this plant is like
you're like oh yeah I really love this
strain and the next day is like e that
was okay to me but I really like this
one and there's just so many different
varieties and variations of the plant
that well I didn't really like this one
but I really like this one and that's
why I always tell me I was like try a
bunch of them until you find something
you really like I call it when you find
your soulmate strain where you're just
like oh my God this this is exactly what
I'm looking for and then you go on this
thing where you're like this is all I
want to smoke I imagine it's kind of
like a Rob with his like headbanger or
whichever or whichever what's that one
he likes really a lot hard to grow yeah
headbanger but yeah like I found a
really one I really liked in your your
Gen 2 genetics uh it was super earthy
and like super lemony and uh as soon as
I found that one I was like you're my
mom I was like and then I pulled it and
then turned it to where I pull all my
clones from of it so I was like Yep this
is the one I want come with
me yeah I definitely want to get deeper
into that one that's one of your recent
crosses but I want to start with your
first cross you ever made tell us a
story about that uh you know this was
one of the ones where I was not a huge
fan of like uh like the smell or the
taste of it but the effect it had
remember I'm a super effect driven
person since I was using it for medical
stuff you know I was not a huge fan of
the taste but the way it it would work
with my ADHD and how well it worked for
me it's just one of those things where I
smoked it all the time and it was
literally just White Widow cross with
big buds and I would smoke it all the
time just because of the effect that it
had now regular white widow I was a
pretty big fan of taste and smell some
reason this white widow cross with big
buds it worked like I it used to be what
I would call my soulmate strain where
I'm like it works so exactly for what I
need and like you know I can I can smoke
it I can still go do a ton of stuff it
like quiets my mind as I would say and
then it calms me down and it was just it
worked so well it was actually the
strain that I found that got me to I
went from three medications down to one
as soon as I you know started smoking it
was it was like a god that that was
given to me
and I was like now if I can just get it
to taste a little bit better that was
the whole point with I mean the whole
thing this is like the whole reason to
start into the journey was literally
just for that and uh that was the whole
thing like I crossed it with this Alas
and purple that I really liked because
I'm a huge fan of like like a birthday
cake or like cake batter like taste and
uh so I crossed it with this Alaskan
purple string that I had that smelled
exactly like I used to say it was like
right if you pulled like a confet you
just made a cake like a confetti cake
vanilla confetti cake base and then you
put like vanilla icing on it like that
smell that you get when you put out with
like the icing on a hot cake like that
smell that you get was the exact smell
that I was getting off of this Alaskan
purple and I was like if I could get
this into here and I was like wait I
might be able to do that and then I
started you know that was kind of like
where I took off with with that and you
know just I never went into it with ever
thinking about doing it for the masses I
was literally just doing it for myself I
didn't think there would be ever be any
any interest in it I was just you know
showing people how to grow on video and
and I was literally just doing it for
myself so it was one of those things
where it was never like even a thought
in my head of ever bringing it out it
was just something I was just doing for
myself that's crazy and then what was
the name of that cross I don't think you
mentioned it uh that one was in it I
called it giant purple mon
oh okay all right got it so one of your
more recent crosses is a collaboration
between you and I which honored that you
reached out to me and you wanted to do
this collaboration I thought that was so
cool yeah it's called Magic Candy
Mountain OG talk to us all about that
well you know whenever I was coming up
with the name for it well just even back
that up even further you know I had you
had sent me some of your stuff before
and I was a big fan of it like that
earthiness and like the lemon that I got
from the first time that's like right up
my alley and so I grew it it it was a
great grow Fant the plant responds to
training fantastically I you know every
aspect about the chill out OG I was a
fan of already and then I was like well
what if I take this and I I had a super
grae feno of the purple Frost giant that
I ended up with that I keep mothers of
that that's like my now soulmate strain
that I constantly am walking around with
just because how well it works for me
and even as a guy this is hurts me to
say even as a guy that is super like a
skunky dies kind of guy to walk around
with the strain that smells like
freaking grape soda you know like at all
the time I'm
like you know at the same time cuz I'm
like I've transitioned I've transitioned
over to the other side I like something
has happened to me I'm walking around
with a strain I mean it literally smells
like grape vest soda like that smell you
get when you first open like a can not a
bottle but an actual can of like grape
soda like that smell from that fizz that
initially comes out of there it smells
exactly like that and I was like okay I
can never get rid of this and I'm
actually into generation three I'm
working on to it right now and it's uh I
was like how cool would this be to cross
this with Mr growz I was like I think it
would be amazing and then I designed a
whole thing of merch and you know I you
sent me
those uh a while ago last year and I
pled it all 5050 all at the same time I
think I got 50 or 60 I pled them all at
the same time and then just and I was
like you know keep super dedicated
labeling of everything I end up the one
I I like the best was uh from a second
generation one of the ones you sent so I
was pretty freaking stoked with it and I
think I put some pictures up on my
Instagram cuz YouTube yells at me
whenever I try to show any kind of plant
on my videos and uh and it could be a
drawing I put a drawing a drawing it was
wasn't even a plant it was a drawing of
the plant I put on there and I got age
restricted on it it was just a drawing
of a leaf it wasn't even the whole plant
it was literally just a leaf and I got
age restricted from a hand drawing of a
leaf I was like all right all right I
apologize I give up I won't even show a
cartoon drawing of
it so it was just it was just one of
those things where I I had liked it in
the past and if I like something you
know you know I want to explore down
that road
and then you know it was just it was one
of those things and then like I got the
name from an old internet video that I
used to watch and I thought it it worked
well with it and uh once I had that once
I had the name kind of figured out for
it and then I did the artwork for it
because I like to do artwork for
everything and it was just it it seemed
like a no-brainer to to mix the two with
how much I liked both so I save the
artwork right
here yeah there you go I love your
artwork man all of it's kind of similar
style and it's really cool that you do
that for each release and you do shirts
too right yeah so I mean I got one on I
got one on right now I've sent you a few
I think I've sent rob a few uh pigeons
I've I've I've messaged him a few times
about getting an address from I've never
got an address from them so I can't I've
never been able to send pigeons anything
up there in Canada and uh but yeah I do
artwork for every single drop um I spend
a lot of time on the artwork and uh I do
I individual it for the drop and then I
never I never do them again so they're
kind of like time stamps as to where you
were kind of like hanging out with the
channel because if you have a shirt I
only make them once and then I never
make them again so you either got them
whenever they dropped or you don't ever
have the opportunity to get one again
and I don't ever even tell the public
whenever they're going live I might for
like a Black Friday thing once a year
but in general you have to literally be
on the patreon to even see when the
merch store is going to go live live and
then whenever it does I usually only
keep it up for either a weekend or four
or five days and then I close it back
down immediately you got to get it while
it's still there yeah yeah the magic
Candy Mountain OG I'm looking forward to
Growing myself I haven't grown it out
yet just got my hands on it and uh got
one that just sprouted so I'm eager to
see how this one turns out and I'm super
excited so appreciate you doing that
cross yeah I got pictures of it on on my
Instagram and I just went by and just
clipped off a few Buds and I have my
hand laying out like in the picture and
I just grabbed a couple buds and you
can't see my hand under the just the
three buds that I clipped off like you
could maybe see like a fingertip over on
one side but the coolest part about it
was like everything turned purple on the
whole thing like all the tricomes were
purple the sugar leaves were purple all
the bud was purple I was like this
really is
Magic I like this is
fantastic that's incredible that's
really really cool he must be growing
some pretty big plants there how big of
plants do you grow for breeding projects
and container what size container you
putting them in uh I don't really like
growing in anything over a 5 gallon pot
I'm just not a fan of the of the bigger
pots uh I don't have a problem with them
per se it's just three to five gallons
depending on my plant count per tent uh
if I have a higher plant count I
probably won't go over a three gallon
pot if I have uh like if I have like
four plants in a 5x5 I'll go up to a
five gallon pot so it's not anything
crazy
I like the amount of uh dry days I get
out of the slightly smaller pots than
the than the than the slightly bigger
pots and uh you know just personal
preference I don't I wouldn't have a
problem if somebody's like yeah growing
seven or 10 G I don't care you know
doesn't I don't think it has you know
too big of effect the only thing that
you know I like I just that's the style
of growing I prefer is just the slightly
smaller slightly smaller pots and the
nutrients you use is going to have
impact on it as well what are you using
for nutrients and how are you doing
feedings throughout the life of the
plant now when you're breeding some
people do it a little bit differently
than when you're growing the plant just
regularly so what do you do yeah so I I
Still Rock General Hydroponics uh
three-part and it's not like because I'm
like oh my goodness these nutrients are
so much better whenever people are
getting
into uh growing uh I generally if they
go to their local stores or whatever the
likelihood of them finding the General
Hydroponics three part is probably along
the top of the list of things they'll be
easy for them to find so it was really
it was never that I like that brand
better it was literally just about if a
new person does this what would be the
easiest nutrient line for them to five
cuz you I mean or to find cuz you could
go get some you know oh well I really
like this you know uh nectar of the gods
or whatever it might be way harder to
find for somebody at their grow store
than something else they might not carry
that line they might only carry Flex or
they might you know whatever you you
could go through there's you know
thousands of nutrient manufacturers so
it was literally just about what's the E
what would be the easiest for a new
person to find or what would be the most
recognizable and uh that I still grow
with it to this day just for that reason
and uh but yeah like you were saying I
100% treat them different rather we're
breeding plants or if I'm just growing
them out
regularly the only thing that kind of
stays the same is in the veg cycle cuz I
generally don't be while they're in veg
because I buy pre- amended soil and the
pre- amended soil I don't know if people
know this but it already has the food in
it that's why you cost so much because
the nutrients that you would need to
give them they're already in the soil
the plant can literally break down
what's in the soil and eat it's just
like if you took something in nert and
put like dry slow relase dry Ms in it
it's the same principle the food's
already in there you don't have to feed
so since I'm transplanting going from
like cubes to Solo cups to one gallons
to threes and then maybe to fives
whenever I go to flower every time you
transplant you can't think of it as
you're just putting in new dirt you're
literally you're feeding the plant
that's all new dirt it's got new new
nutrients in it so you're technically
feeding I just am not going in there and
manually you know making uh a nutrient
mix but the whole time the plants and
flow I just treat it like it's uh like
the end of veg and I give them equal
parts of nitrogen potassium and magnes
or uh phosphorus so I just give them
equal amounts whether it's four four and
four or five five and five I just give
them equal parts throughout and the only
other big difference is I never switch
over to mag sulfur from cow mag I give
them cow mag the
whole the whole way through the grow for
the extra calcium and they always need
magnesium so I just don't need the
bulking agent with the sulfur I know
some breeders who actually will stick
with the veg nutrients throughout all of
flowering yeah that's exactly what I do
it won't do anything that's exactly what
you do yeah that's exactly what I do I
do it like it's transition week so just
literally like it's the last week of
edge is the the method that I go to and
it's literally just four of nitrogen or
let's just say it's five of n five
milliters per gallon nitrogen five of
phosphorus and five of potassium and
they just stick with I stick with that
one because it's a nice balance of
everything it needs cuz I'm not going
for giant flower bulks or anything like
that uh it's a nice you know like a well
balanced diet for them hitting that food
triangle and I just carry that all the
way through and then normally if I was
doing a normal flower cycle it would be
at the end of week three I would switch
off of cow mag and I would switch on to
mag sulfur product uh because the
stretch is over I no longer need the
calcium there's mag in both products so
I need mag all the way through and then
since the stretch is over and now I'm
going into the bulking phase after a
transition week of flow and week four
I'm now going into the bulking place of
phase of flour I don't care about the
bulking phase of the flour that's not
where my attention is nor is it where
the attention of the plant is because
it's received pollen by that point the
plants make you know that's one of the
tricks to making you know bigger buds is
we are denying them pollen and by
denying them pollen it causes them to
swell their buds because they're trying
to get bigger because pollen floats in
the air or to attract flying pollinators
anything like that by denying them
pollen it makes the bud get bigger and
bigger because they're trying to
increase surface area to catch that
pollen that's in the air well whenever
I've given them pollen I've specifically
got pollen painting it on like Bob Ross
on on each of the buds uh that that
thing for bulking up the flowers isn't
there anymore because they've already
accomplished their life goal and their
life goal is they were trying to
reproduce and now they've reproduced
because they're making the seeds so so I
want to get into pollination I know that
you actually reverse plants and I want
to get into that afterwards first I want
to find out you talked about pollinating
females that needs to happen in order
for seeds to be developed right around
what day do you typically pollinate your
female plants
uh it's not really a day I really do it
based off Bud size and how the plant's
progressing because you have some
strains that you might have a you know
10 week strain versus an 8we strain or a
12 week strain so instead of hard
focusing on a day I actually do it by
plant development and size generally if
you have a 8 to n week flowering strain
it's going to be around the end of week
three somewhere in the beginning to
middle of week four is kind of like The
Sweet Spot I've found with them but if
you have a strin that takes longer to
flower and I go in and I pollinate it
week three my bud structure I might
still have those little tiny golf balls
with just the you know the starting
sprinklings of pistols that's way too
early to do this because if you
pollinate too early the bud size never
gets as big as it could have gotten if
you waited just like another week or so
and then plus you don't just don't have
a ton of pistol hairs to paint yet you
know like those pistol hairs are your
those are your receptor sites for the
pollen if there's not a ton of them yet
it's just it's too early to bring pollen
into the mix and uh it's really just
around generally it's just shoot for
week four and generally your buds are
big enough but if they're not just wait
a week it's not like it's there's a
timer on this like if you pollinate a
plant you ask anybody that's ever Herm
to plant you pollinate those plants at
week five week six of flour they're
making seeds they're going to do it uh
you know and if you look out into like
the you know you know the nature that
pollen's flying around the air all you
know all year and they got way longer
flower times whenever you're out there I
mean we all remember the the we used to
get back in the day what did you do when
you first got it you had to sit down on
your your TV tray or your little little
uh your rolling tray that you had and
what we had to do we had to pick out all
the seeds and all the stems on it and
that was somebody's job you had to sit
there and you had to pile the start and
then by the end you had what the shaky
stuff that you had left you had a pile
of seeds and a pile of stems and that's
what your job was to sit there and break
it all apart and now you can put that in
your bowls or whatever
yeah we didn't have this luxury of
having seed free back in the day I'm
glad those days are behind us and we
don't have to worry about seeds within
the buds yeah I've brought myself right
back around to it because pretty much
every month I'm harvesting seeded stuff
so luckily now I have machines that do
it for me though yeah so you bring up a
great point about when to pollinate the
females now there's a couple different
ways you can do the pollination process
right you could the way you're doing it
what you mentioned is you're actually
painting the pollen onto buds other
folks what they'll do is they'll take
actually take the plant that they've
reversed or the male plant and they'll
stick it in the same room and just let
them let the wind naturally bring it
through air circulation or they actually
shake the plant within grow space why do
you choose to use the paintbrush and
Paint The Buds versus just shaking the
plant in the grow space clean up mess
that it makes uh whenever cuz I've done
I've done it a couple different ways
like there's actually videos where you
see me and I take the plant and I set it
on like a upside down 5 gallon bucket
and then I get a leaf blower and I stand
at the back of the tent and I pretended
like I was like Dock and I'm like all
right we got 88 gigawatts or whatever it
is and I'm blasting or 1.21 gigawatts
and I'm blasting the uh the the fan the
leaf blower fan right through the back
of the plant and the only Pro the only
the only reason that I don't do this is
just because of the mess it makes I mean
the entire room I don't think people
understand especially if you're working
with males the amount of pollen that
they make it's
insane that's why you don't have to
always you don't have to reverse a whole
plant you can just do a couple branches
just because those couple of branches
make so much pollen that it's you know
it's crazy how much that you're going to
get off of there and whenever I make a
mess with it I mean it's just I detail
clean very well in between grows and the
amount of Gunk that I have to get off
the walls and off the fans cuz I I like
I take the fans down I take the fans
apart I clean them I take the lights you
know I just detail clean everything in
between grows and the amount of extra
work it provides whenever I don't just
paint you know it takes me 30 seconds to
just sit there with I have this Barbie
brush you know it's hot pink like this
thing right here I have this Barbie
brush that I stole from my daughter's
makeup you know kit and it works so well
like I can absorb so much pollen with it
I can do the whole tint I can do the
whole tint with just one you know just
pick up a bunch of p i can I can paint
the whole tint with just one brush and
so uh the amount of work it saves me is
the main reason that I do it with a BRI
because they all work all those methods
that you mention whether you just put
one in if you're going to do that you
put it in front of your your fan so it
blows it out towards the rest of the tin
or whether you shake the plant all those
methods they all work just fine the only
reason I do it is just really simply
because of clean
up that's a good reason to do it right
yeah cuz I got a ton of other stuff in
the room and the amount of pollen that
gets everywhere in the room and then I
look it looks like I've been doing
drywall work in there only it's got a
slightly yellow tinted drywall and I've
the amount of area that I have to clean
up is just ridiculous so I like to say
it was some for some really cool reason
but it really just saves me work yeah I
know how it is I've had some grow tents
that you know yellow sides and it gets
tough with the ventilation socks are and
they like you know come in and getting
every single nook and cranny it's it's
difficult so I hear you on that one so
so are you collecting pollen from the
Reversed plant and putting into a
container and then doing the paintbrush
process and also do you store pollen at
all yeah I do it live in real time so I
don't ever store any of it I've had had
you know there's a reason there's no
company that just sells pollen it just
doesn't it once it leaves the plant its
life is cycle is is not greatest like
they don't handle like can you imagine
if you if you were like just brought up
a company they would be 100% legal you
could ship sh it everywhere just
feminized pollen the amount of money you
can make it just doesn't survive very
well the shipping process and I've
always just live timed it to where my
males were ready around the time that I
need my females ready because even if
the plant is dropping pollen you don't
have to collect it right away like let's
say your female isn't ready you can just
leave it on that plant yeah it'll be
spilling stuff onto the leaves and stuff
but you can literally just leave it on
the plant and then wait your extra half
week or week cuz you shouldn't be that
far off and then collect the pollen and
then put it on there so you know I can
use the the male or the feminized female
as kind of like a little storage locker
for it and then livetime collect it and
then immediately use it I just never had
the best luck uh with like trying to
store it or anything like that so I just
always live time it got it and then one
other thing that is vastly different
from just growing the pl naturally is
the length of time you're actually
growing the plant right so you're not
looking for a specific Harvest window
you're not really looking at the
tricomes to see y okay they're ready to
harvest right you're letting it go
longer than that in order for those
seeds to develop how long do you
typically let a plant grow until you
harvest the seeds now I know that's
probably going to vary depending if you
have an eight weer nine weer so on and
so forth but generally speaking how much
longer is the plant growing until you
harvest the seeds I always tell
everybody it's it's around 7 to eight
weeks from pollination date so I always
tell everybody you're pretty much
restarting your flower the day you
pollinate them and what I always tell
everybody is the second we pollinate
them we no longer look at the tricomes
for when our Harvest is done now we
actually use the seeds as our like kind
of like our triome markers because they
go through color stages just like the
tricomes do they'll start off green then
they'll turn to White then they'll turn
to gray then they go brown with Tiger
stripes and you can they're never all
going to be on the same page so we do it
just like we do with our tricomes we're
basing off of what's the majority of
what we're looking at on the plant at
this time is kind of how we dictate with
when the plant comes down so if I'm
looking and I'm like H we got the
majority green we know we're way far
away and then you know we come back a
few weeks okay the majority is white
with a minority of gray like okay and
now the the pods are starting to split
open on the top which we get a really
good view of when we can start watching
them because the tops of the pods they
actually split open like this and you
get a really good view window right on
the top of them on how they're doing but
as soon as I see where the majority are
brown and tiger striped and there's a
minority of gray that's whenever I chop
down so it's just a based on visually
whenever I look over the plant what do
they look like they're doing right now
and that's you know it's the same way
whenever you're looking at
tricomes the plant functions the same
way it lets you know when it's ready to
chop got it and so you are really ju
Cree femin seeds correct me if I'm wrong
there I do occasional RS but not many
okay so you're focusing on feminized in
order to actually get feminized seeds
you have to basically reverse a plant
that is already growing as a female you
reverse it and then all of a sudden it
starts creating pollen sacks and then
releasing pollen let's talk about the
way you reverse plants there's a couple
different ways you can do it there's
clodo silver there's STS some people
combine the two what's your process for
reversing the plant so I've done all
three of those I've done just colloidal
silver I've done just St spray and then
I've done done the combo of the two so
I've done all of them you know multiple
and multiple times and I've always found
that the combo of both has got me the
best results as far as pollen production
is what I'm looking for um because like
with the colloid I have the least
effective way with colloidal silver I
get a lot of plants that will they'll
make the sacks and then the sacks will
be empty there won't be any pollen in
them and it's literally only the main
problem with that one is just with the
colloidal silver and run into that
occasionally with STS spray not as often
but I've always found that whenever I do
the combo of both of them
together I usually have really really
good results as far as pollen production
of the plants and the amount of sites
that I get to collect it from so for
clodo silver C fromong you're supposed
to be spaying once a day some people do
it multiple times a day to spay the
plant for the first what is it two weeks
or three weeks or something like that
three weeks is what yeah so yeah if in
the parts per million they they come in
different parts per million you can make
your own colloidal silver too it's not a
terribly hard process but the minimum I
found that works is 30 parts per million
but I found kind of like the sweet spot
right around the 50ish parts per million
and then if like if all I had was cido
silver it's three times a day from the
last week of veg through the first two
weeks of flow and then I cut it and then
that gives us enough time because the p
the tree or the plant should be dropping
its pollen around week three to three
and A2 of flour which puts you right on
where you're normally would be attacking
your females with it so and then if
you're using STS STS is a little bit
more I say hands off but less work to
where you're only spraying once every
five days which I've tried before and uh
unfortunately quite recently actually it
didn't reverse you know the plant didn't
actually reverse it was like what the
heck I planted all around this and it
didn't actually work yeah so the with
the STS spray I found that once every 5
days is a little bit long for them so
and then the time frame slightly off too
so you have to account for that whenever
you're doing your females so whenever
I'm doing whenever I'm going to make the
male version of the female plant and I'm
going to use just STS spray I actually
start them into their flour a week or
two earlier than the other plants go
into flour because whenever you're doing
just STS spray it's once every 5 days
for the first 30 days of flour so you
can still be spraying four weeks and if
you stop there before the four weeks are
up you can actually it'll end up with no
pollen at all you won't even get the
reversal so it's it's very important but
I've dropped it down to every 3 to 4
days that I'll do it and I'll just do it
once a day right before the lights go
off you know it's a big thing is the
light actually damages the STS spray and
then whenever you're combining it if you
don't combine it in the
right uh order which there's only two
parts but if you put it in wrong and you
don't get that cool fizzy reaction that
happens in it and if you don't get it
that right or if you add it too fast it
actually will make it inert and uh you
have to watch for the Fizz so you want
to keep it just to where it keeps
fizzing on itself and then you know
you're doing it right interesting yeah
I'll have to go back and try doing both
the combo like you mentioned in order to
try to get a better result there the
combo's great so whenever it's a combo I
kind of switch it up so for the last two
weeks of EG I'll do just STS spray for
once every 3 days and then whenever we
switch into flour I switch over C
colloidal silver and I spray it once or
I spray it three times every day for the
first two weeks which is the literally
the worst part of the grow that I have
to go into there three times a day every
single day Monday through Sunday you
gotta do what you got to do in order to
get that reversal right you gotta do
what you got to do it's my least
favorite part though I'm just like H and
it's not like it's it's crazy hard but
it's just my finger gets tired cuz I
have like you know the pump sprayer
bottle like this because you don't need
a ton of it and you can go through it
way too fast when you have like the big
spray bottles so I just have this little
spray bottle and my my it's my hand just
gets tired of spraying all the different
branches so and you had mentioned that
you only reverse a branch or two you're
not reversing the entire plant it
depends it depends on how much I need so
the biggest thing uh especially because
you can run into problems where you
don't get any pollen from the pollen SE
or they don't reverse so if let's say
I'm trying to pollinate six plants I'll
grow nine and I have three different
plants that I'll pull into a different
tent to reverse just because I I want to
weigh out my I don't ever just put all
my chips on one because I don't store
pollen so I will grow extra plants just
to have backups in case you know hey
that one what if something happens what
if a fan falls on it and breaks it and
kills it and now I have nothing because
now I have no males that are or females
that are anywhere close to being ready
to reverse and so I always just have
backups on backups whenever I'm getting
ready to you know go through that proc
process cuz I want to make sure that if
I want to make a line like oh no this
didn't reverse or I didn't get as much
pollen as I wanted which is never
usually the case but it does
occasionally happen but I always have
backups on backups just in case but it
makes me go through a lot of colloidal
silver and sdn and STS spray though got
it safe sided right yeah exactly because
know maybe if I had a giant store room
and the pollen stayed really well it' be
one thing but I just don't like the
staying power of the pollen once it
leaves the plant so I just make sure I
have plenty of females on deck that are
giving me pollen got it so we talked
about the reversal process we talked
about really growing the plants you know
the nutrition you use container size how
long you're letting the plants grow when
you're pollinating now what's your
process for getting seeds tested right
uh you know an ethical thing to do would
be before releasing to the public would
be to get them tested yeah what's your
process for that well I actually have a
beta tester program built into my
patreon and then on top of it is you
know I never sell anything so all my
stuff all the stuff I make I give away
completely free to the people in my
patreon I don't ever charge for it so I
have a huge sampling audience that does
a lot of testing for like hey we like
this hey we don't like this these are
the germination rates that we got these
are you know like of the ones that that
came up this is what we're having with
it and I know before it even ever goes
out to the mass of the patreon because I
have a a b tester program that helps me
with the testing of them and we go
through a pretty extensive back and
forth with everything we're seeing and
then when it goes out to the patreon I
get this huge you know envelopment of
information from Growers of all styles
whether they're doing Hydro or whether
they're doing any kind of media based or
whether they're new or very expert
Growers I get this just this huge
information dumps every time and every
time I release a line I just feel like
it makes me a better and better grower
and what I'm trying to do kind of refine
the process every single time we do a
drop and I mean I've got to the point
now where I'm doing usually five to six
new drops per year so it it works out
pretty well and uh dude the patreons are
awesome I mean they're just they're such
they're such great people
and I just I really am thankful for this
community and what it's done for my life
it's it's amazing and I really love
interacting with the people of this of
this community every day so it's been
great sounds like you have a great
support system over there I know a lot
of folks breeders in particular who look
for testers or have testers some of them
just ghost like when I first sent out
the chill at OG that cross that I made
testers 80% of the people just didn't
even respond after respond you never
know yeah you never know what happened I
got nothing from them and I was looking
for the feedback so sounds like you got
some pretty stable stuff over there on
the patreon side of things yeah we built
a pretty in you know amazing Discord
that I actually had turn the
notifications off because it it's you
know thousands and thousands of people
in there some of the best Growers I've
ever seen and the feedback and the
picture up you know I it's livetime real
pictures every new line has its very own
dedicated you know browser section to it
and you know you can just sit there and
look at the progress and see what kind
of if people are having problems or the
luck or the different tpine profiles
that we're having through there it's
it's been great like oh this one's super
Menthol or this one's this it's it's
it's really great to get that kind of
feedback on something that you're making
to have thousands of people all doing it
usually whenever I release it they all
are planning at the same time to have
that kind of feedback and
information instantly back on it it's
it's been great so that's awesome so
what advice do you have for those that
are just getting into breeding don't
trace hype would probably be my number
one and figure out what you like first
and think of the reasons you're doing it
you know the main one would be think of
the reasons you're doing it and don't
chase the hype um I think you'll find if
you you go after what you like uh the
process won't become arduous or like
work because you're going actually enjoy
doing it because Crossing things you
know it's it's not a ton of work it
depends on what you're doing but it's
definitely more work especially if
you're reversing and feminizing and then
getting all the seeds if you don't have
the cool machines that do it for you
it's a lot of work to pick all them
freaking seeds out of there I think
that's some really good advice there is
one more question I wanted to ask you
that wasn't actually on the list which
is talking about hype chasing the hype
there's a lot of hype around triploids
right now what are your thoughts on
triploids got a lot of I got a lot of
heat I got a lot of people that agreed
with me and then I got a lot of heat
from it I think my view on it is just
maybe jaded because you know I grew up
in the midwest so uh I was watched a lot
of my friends families really get messed
over with not reproducing seeds and
stuff like that so for the new Growers I
think they're fantastic
for I don't I just I'm not a you know
I'm not a fan personally but for new
Growers for something that won't seed or
Herm I once again I think it's a crutch
but I understand why you would like them
I think it's the same thing as like when
Autos first came out you know there like
oh you don't have to switch them over
they do switch over to flower all by
themselves not that hard to switch a
timer but you know I'm a photo period
guy so it just it's not one of my
favorite things but I do understand why
people would like them especially where
they you know they won't make seeds no
matter how bad you treat them I would
rather just become a slightly better
grower so I didn't worry about herming
my stuff that's going to get me in
trouble anyway I got I got a lot of hate
from that video I got a lot lot of great
views on it but I did get a lot of hate
from that video yeah the video I'm
looking on your page right now the
dangers of triploids and the problems
coming 31,000
views to click I clicked on it I listen
to you and you you brought up some good
points in there now you mentioned that
they they're not supposed to Herm right
so like yeah unfortunately we're not
they're not seeing that now like there's
a we've got the the donuts triploid from
Humbolt people reporting Herms you know
people reporting Herms happening there
which like to hear they not supposed to
but we're are seeing it so yeah that
that makes me sad you know CU like I
understood like how cool that could be
especially for new Growers like you
don't have to worry about this herming I
understood the point of it and I
understood the appeal of it uh at the
same time that's like as a new grower I
would want people
to treat you know I would want you to
treat the cold not just the cough like
why are you coughing why is this plant
doing this oh no we're just going to
make a plant that doesn't do it yeah but
you'll get better results in the long
run if you figure out why this is
happening what stressor are you doing to
it that's causing it to
harm and that's just crazy cuz that's
that was supposed to be a plant that
just genetically wasn't allowed wouldn't
been allowed to make seeds life findes
away so want to wrap things up here tell
us how can the listeners find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
how they can find me they can either
just go to my uh my YouTube channel it's
called Welcome to The Grow Tent
especially if you're looking for any
kind of new information on uh on how to
grow these plants I can definitely show
you how to do it with uh any equipment
that you have I'll be able to show you
how it works um or you could join the
patreon and we can do one onone sessions
just like me and Mr Gro are doing right
now I will actually sit here in my box
and on the other box will be your garden
and I work with your Gardens just like
I'm sitting there in your grow room with
you and uh I do that all the time and uh
then I get on there and I answer
questions every single day on my patreon
uh we have one of the biggest can
content creation uh patreons uh there is
we have close to 700 and something
members it varies up and down of course
but uh uh it's a it's a good time and
then as I said earlier all the crosses
that I ever make those uh patreons get
my stuff absolutely free I never charge
a penny for it and then you get access
to all my cool merch that I make there's
a link to it in all my video
descriptions in on my YouTube page now
we have a good time and uh it's a
freaking blast so and then far as uh
upcoming uh I have a bunch of new
crosses we're call it GT's year of fire
that's coming up this year we have uh
the very next drop is blueberry muffins
crossed with blueberry pie and then I
have early lemon berry that is getting
crossed with super great
PFG uh then we have runs getting crossed
with strawberry mimosa and then the kind
of like the biggest thing for the end of
the year is I have a collab coming up
with dark horse and we are crossing
there uh Bruce Banner S3 with my PFG for
uh maybe some of the coolest artwork
ever made I just have to figure out how
to not get sued by Marvel for the idea I
have in my head for it
so awesome lots of good stuff I'm coming
I will be tuned into that and hopefully
I can get my hands on some of those
crosses because they sound amazing yeah
they're I'm looking forward to them and
uh I tell you I'm super excited about it
I'm super excited about uh the collab
that we just got done with I mean the
people are planning them they're having
you know it's like 900% success rates
through germination and they're talking
about how fast they're growing and stuff
like that so you might want to go check
out Chris's site exciting well GT I
appreciate you coming on to the podcast
once again I'll definitely have a link
to GT's Channel down in the YouTube
description section below if you're on
one of the podcast platforms just search
for him welcome to the grow tent you
search for that on YouTube his channel
will pop up and give him a subscription
GT thanks once again and hope you enjoy
the rest of your day all right see you
brother peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode