welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned in
to the Garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 132 in this episode I
interview Michael box from sustainable
Village he was on the podcast once
before episode 50 where he talked about
the different methods of Auto watering
and his recommendations for auto
watering setups for different Siz
containers this episode we continue
talking about irrigation he talks about
moisture release curves moisture meters
new irrigation technology and more check
out the garden talk Clips Channel if you
haven't already that's on YouTube and
it's short bite-sized clips of these
episodes I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow I'll
link both of those channels down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their Advanced
grow kits which include nearly
everything you need to start growing
indoors they have several different size
kits and they all come with a grow tent
grow light ventilation system
oscillating clip fan a controller 69 Pro
and so much more click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their grow kits and the
discount code Mr Grow at 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend is
a
215 plant additive that can used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and microle fungi check it out at
stash blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash and we are back and I'm joined
with Michael box how you doing today uh
great great yeah glad to be back happy
to have you back on the podcast you were
on episode 50 and I was just I actually
relistened to it yesterday great episode
so much good information there at had
85,000 views on it so far on YouTube so
monstrous number of views there and
there was an overwhelming amount of
people in the comments they're just so
thankful on the knowledge that you would
Dro in there so thanks for that and I'm
really happy to have you back on the
episode today in this episode we're
going to get into what's happening in
the industry you know particularly
relating to irrigation we're also going
to get into some of the new watering
technology that's going to help maintain
that perfect moisture level that
everyone's seeking and we're going to
get into moisture release curves but
first can you introduce yourself for
those that didn't catch the first
episode we did together well yeah sure
man um so my name is Michael box um I am
I'm based here in Boulder Colorado and
I've been out here for um 20 some years
I uh you know my as far as my background
uh as it relates to
irrigation um I've been in that industry
for probably 20 years as well um I have
worked on a number of uh organic farms
and Market Gardens when I was a younger
guy and we used to run a CSA program
here in Boulder um got into the uh uh uh
medicinal production world of probably
back in 2008 or something like that in a
kind of serious way and was in some
businesses related to that um but uh
yeah I really started off as just a
Hands-On guy a grower um and and
producer for for farmers markets and
then uh moved into you know other crops
and and and also did a lot of uh
irrigation installation during that time
too so uh you know a background in
permaculture agriculture irrigation
installation um and now u i my my
current role here um I I work for a
company called sustainable Village and
um run all their operations and I'm the
lead designer for the company um we uh
we produce designs irrigation designs
and supply parts
for uh lots of controlled environment
agriculture so think indoor grow
facilities uh green houses um people
that are growing at home um as well as
AG projects so uh we do large scale
regenerative egg irrigation and we work
with a lot of really cool Partners in
that space all around the Front Range of
Colorado
um and um yeah and we have a we also
have a line of products for house plants
and things like that but um they're
they're fun and useful but uh the really
exciting stuff I feel and what I feel
passionate about is systems you know
I've always been really uh a student of
systems and um whether they're human
systems or or uh flow Technologies like
like water and um yeah
uh you know like a lot of us have done a
lot of things in our lives and but it
keep it keeps uh uh circling back to uh
water for me and um whether it's you
know how how it flows and moves and how
plants use it and we've been able to
build a
really uh cool team of people that I get
to work with on a regular basis um you
know I'm not alone and anything I
present here today really I want to just
be upfront that uh I've got a couple
other guys that work with me here on our
design team um Izzy Becker and and
Cooper Didier uh are kind of my my two
um main main supports for research and
uh information and and helping with the
Design Systems as well yeah that's a
kind of basic background awesome and
then uh we've met at MJ biscon years ago
and every year I think you're there and
we bump into each other 2018 I remember
meeting you back then that was yeah that
was a long time ago yeah and then uh
soil Summit which was a few months back
that was a great event you were there
Izzy was there I think he had a talk I
think you had like a Hands-On thing that
you were doing can you give us a recap
on the soil Summit and kind of talk
about some other educational events that
you've participated in yeah absolutely
um for those of you that that don't know
the the soil life Summit was an event
that Grassroots fabric pots they put on
it's their second annual and um this one
was really cool it was it was out in
parump Nevada um it was on the farm uh
that was owned by Steve canwell he's a
has a a business called Green Life
Productions and he's a you know really
kind of early adopter pioneer here in
living soil and a cool guy and he was it
was hosted on his his farm and uh it it
brought together a really
wide uh smattering of of really smart
people in the living soil world and so
we had a bunch of the major soil
producers were there um we had some
great agronomist giving speeches and and
talks um there's there was a a lot of
workshops Hands-On workshops and it's
overall just a really great event and
you know I hope they I hope they keep
doing it I know they're they're talking
about it um keep keep doing those events
and those are really kind of a a a
followup to there were these um the
regen conferences they were called it
was like the science of regenerative
production or something like that that
uh were were held there was initially up
in Humble County Josh Rutherford put all
those on and um
and then they they were up in hot County
and then they they had a bunch traveling
around the US and then that that that
project uh transitioned out and and
Grassroots took up a similar version so
um those are events that I've been
participating in for for quite a few
years now uh either usually just as a
speaker and attendee um there always
great learning environments we uh at
this last one our whole team went Cooper
Izzy and I and Izzy Izzy did a really
great talk on
uh basically soil moisture data and um
moisture release curves uh some of the
new tech we'll we'll talk about some of
those things today I imagine um and then
uh Cooper and I built out a big display
station with lots of raised beds and
pots and all kinds of different water
sources and and built blue mat systems
all throughout those and operated them
and then gave a couple hour workshop on
how to do that which was great I mean we
got it was it was really great to put
all that information in one place and
and kind of show it off and answer
questions in real time and um yeah
honestly we if we do some of these
events in the future we're we're kind of
kicking around the idea of maybe having
like a really a longer form irrigation
workshop at something like that so um
you know we'd love to I'm really curious
what people's feedback would be on that
if it's something they'd be interested
in um so that we do trade shows
periodically we were just out in
Minnesota uh maybe two three weeks ago
um I he gave a presentation there and
that that got a lot of really good
feedback um and yeah so like those kind
of industry trade shows we go to
sometimes they're hit or miss and um you
know whether they're worth going to or
not but think the last one was Minnesota
was an interesting Market to be in um
like a new state that recently changed
their laws to allow different kinds of
growing
um so those are always kind of fun
places to be there to be where there's
where there's new people that are uh
learning for the first time yeah what
did you think of the soil life Summit
there I thought it was great I was able
to catch Izzy's talk and uh it was
loaded with information actually I'd
like to get him on the podcast if he'd
like if he want to come on maybe you can
hook me up on that Avenue but he had uh
so much good information the moisture
release curve which is what we're going
to get into here in a little bit I
remember him talking about that and um I
didn't get a chance to attend the
workshop but that whole Summit was
fantastic and I'll definitely be there
next year if it does happen now before
we get into the moisture release curves
is there anything else happening in the
industry particularly related to
cultivation or irrigation that you want
to talk about that's a good question we
we're in a unique position here uh
because we work with cultivators all
over the US Canada we have um a lot of
big projects in a Australia right now um
I just sent a big system to Thailand
this week uh you know so we're all over
the globe actually working with with
Growers and so we get to talk to a lot
of people and see what they're up to and
what they're what their pain points are
what their struggles are you know how
they're doing what kind of prices
they're getting for for products things
like that and um so there's a yeah it's
a really it's a it's a cool spot to be
in um you know we also work with a lot
of the different soil companies so there
most of the other major kind of living
soil companies recommend our products
and so we have a lot of U uh you know
get customers through that and and
clients to work with what's happening
man it's all kinds of stuff's happening
depends on which state you're in uh you
know there's there's markets that have
had you know like these legal markets
for long long periods of time and
they're really established markets um
we're not seeing
as many like new facilities going in
there like Colorado's a good example
there's not a ton of new projects
happening in Colorado we do even though
we're based here we do probably 95% of
our work outside of here
um and the ones that do go in in those
established markets are are very large
so you know it's not it's not crazy for
us to be working on 100,000 square feet
of you know indoor production um in some
of those in some of those markets which
we do do with uh and with more of our
kind of traditional drip irrigation um
designs and
Engineering the the places that are the
most fun to work are are states that are
are newer markets um or kind of markets
that have have something's changed or
shifted and there's like a re kind of
revitalized energy around it and you get
these kind of like medium-size
facilities and a lot of them are in
green houses and again back to that
living soil piece like a lot of them are
uh living soil Growers that are that are
growing like a boutique product that
might fetch a higher price um we like to
yeah I I like working with those with
those folks too cuz they're you know
they're the new newer newer Growers are
are always really um open to to new
ideas and not to say that that that
seasoned uh experienced folks aren't
either I mean if they're still
successful they probably are pretty open
to new ideas um but uh yeah I it's it's
um sometimes a little easier to to talk
to the empty cup versus the one that's
already overflowing you know what I mean
um and yeah I mean we could go on about
specifics there but it's uh it's a it's
been I think the last year has been
really challenging I think overall that
that industry has was was kind of in a
bit of a slump last year and a lot of
the folks that are in other kind of
ancillary businesses like ours that you
know maybe provide soil or lighting or
uh nutrients or whatever
uh had kind of tough years in 2022
2023 and I think it really speaks to you
know I think this I think a great thing
to do is like look around and see who's
still operating you know as businesses
that are kind of providing services in
the industry and also um the the Growers
and suppliers and who's still operating
and and not to say that lots of really
good people that knew what they were
doing weren't able to continue running a
business but um the ones that the ones
that are still operating
probably have a a pretty good product
and and um know what they're doing and
if they stuck it out through those last
couple years I
think um I think I think this next year
is going to be there's going to be a
bump I think there's be a kind of an
upswing in in in sales and all all
products related to that and and to the
actual material itself
so yeah I think uh I look forward to
2024 we're already seeing kind of a a
pretty pretty massive
spike in in what we're doing just in the
last two months um which is which is
typical for like springtime we always
see a big boost in in in sales and in
projects being you know actually
launching um this time of year but yeah
I'm just seeing more and more I'm seeing
more and more homeg Growers uh really
really doing their thing and and that's
that's a group of people we've always
worked with closely uh you know for IR
ation and and helping them kind of
automate their their home grows and and
you know free up time and have better
success and better yields and better
product and all that um so that group of
people that home Growers you know that's
we they've been with us for a long time
and we don't ever forget that and um you
know are really excited to serve them
even better moving forward here yeah the
home Growers that's really most of the
audience listening into this right now
grow at home you know whether it be
indoors or outdoors and yeah talking
about the industry and how there's been
struggles we've seen it with
particularly with lighting companies
getting closed down left and right I
mean there's been a handful of companies
within the past couple years that have
closed down and uh it's it's sad to see
but hope we go back to an incline here
where as far as uh more and more States
legalizing it more and more people
getting into it so on and so forth so
we'll just have to kind of wait and see
no totally and like our strategy with
that with with Staying Alive in there is
to is that constant innovation piece
like look what we're doing and look
what's going well what are the problems
and like okay how do we go and solve
those problems and you know get a better
product and and really just being
staying on the you know the uh ahead of
the curve as much as possible always
looking at new tech as it's becoming
available or we're developing it and
yeah again you know you look at like
lighting companies there a lot of them
were doing the exact same thing right
they were kind of selling very very
similar products and coming out of the
same production facilities you know
maybe overseas or whatnot um
and uh yeah I think I think Innovation
and forward moving is is is a is a good
strategy for for Staying Alive in a in a
competitive world I completely agree so
we're going to get into new technology
here in a minute but first I want to get
into moisture release curves now that's
something that I don't think a lot of my
audience is really aware of so talk to
us all about moisture release curves
moisture curve is a is a graph the chart
and it's got uh you X and Y uh axes
right so a vertical and a horizontal
axis and the vertical AIS is often
represented uh by volumetric water
content so um let me just jump into this
point there's there's there's two main
ways to measure soil moisture and the
first is through vwc volumetric water
content your
vwc and the the second is uh soil
moisture tension so these are are two
different uh data points that you can
pull out of any uh soil solution and
they're going to give you different
numbers in different in different uh
units of measurement so volumetric water
content is is the percentage of water
that is that this is made up of the soil
so um you know maybe it's 50% right so a
soil a soil solution might be 50% water
or 40% water or 30% water so by volume
it's the 30% water and there's a lot of
really cool data that you can pull out
of that and strategy that can be
developed based on that that information
um the second way to measure uh soil
moisture is is through
tensiometers and tensiometers are
devices that measure pressure so what
those devices usually look like well
honestly they look a lot like the blue
mats do it's a it's a ceramic tip uh
like a ceramic cone with a with a tube
on top of it and then attached to that
is some sort of uh pressure gauge so as
the soil dries out it it creates a
negative pressure inside uh that tube
and that so and then that uh negative
pressure is expressed as a vacuum so uh
it'll it'll read in units of pressure
and um it's often often measured in Cen
bars or
mbars uh which is U just this little
like something to note one bar is is
equal to one atmosphere of pressure or
15 psi and it's really it's like the
metric uh style of of measuring pressure
so we use the PSI and and um standard
measurements but then in uh in metric
it's it's in bars so a milar is 1,000th
of a bar or a centa bar is 1 100th of a
bar so these are these units of pressure
that are measured and most most of those
tensiometers either measure in Cen bars
or mbars so if we jump back to the
moisture release curve itself uh we have
that vertical axis that's measuring a
percentage and we're having the uh the
horizontal axis which is which is
measuring uh
mbars and what we see is a a a there's a
graph that gets expressed on this and
that's that this it's a curve curve and
it starts high on the on the on the
vertical axis and then it will uh Be
steady for a little bit so that's that
that indicates a really high percentage
of water and when it's it'll be flat for
a little bit and that's a uh that'll
translate to a low uh tensiometer number
and when it's flat at the top that that
indicates a full saturation so you're
you're at a point of of
runoff um so if any more water was added
it would immediately run off out of the
pot
and then that curve it's flat for a
little bit and then it it falls off
precipitously and plunges down and
that's that's the soil drying out so as
the uh percentage of water drops um the
uh the tension the soil moisture tension
starts to grow and uh it drops off
pretty steeply and then it starts to
kind of ease that curve off and um so
you get this kind of nice rounded piece
of the graph and then it flattens out
and when it flattens out again very low
on the on the graph uh that's that's
your permanent Wilt point so the soil is
be is say dried out there's no more
moisture left in
it and each uh soil medium out there has
a unique uh uh moisture release curve so
it's like a it's almost like a a
fingerprint for each soil has its own
particular moist moisture release curve
and there are methods for determining
what a you know a custom blend
might be specifically a lot of major
manufacturers of soil have that data
that you can get um there's also some
pretty
clear uh there's it's pretty standard
for certain soil types so they'll
measure it in like you know Sandy LOM
soils or uh like bark they usually use
as one of the controls like pine bark um
but then coco or Pete or engineered
potting soil Blends that use organic
material which would kind of be like a
living soil mix something that's has
peite and either Pete or cocoa and
compost in
it um and they all kind of have
different shaped curves and they they
dry out in different ways um and why
this data is really interesting is you
can determine the moisture release curve
of a particular soil uh medium or soil
composition and and then find that chart
and then
understand what is the best what are the
targets that we want to hit for
irrigating that particular soil so when
do we want to start an irrigation event
um and and then we when do we want to
stop it so if we say we uh we
irrigate like a um like a cocoa based
soil um you know it's going to start at
one point it's it's we're going to the
irrigation going to turn off it's going
to be high up on the percentage and low
on the tension and then it's going to
start to dry out and it's going to dry
out it's going to dry out it's going to
get down to a point um that's that's
approaching uh the the wilt point which
we don't ever want to hit and then
there's a there's a point on that curve
we can kind of identify it very
specifically and we can say that's our
trigger point for another irrigation
event and that's going to then it's
going to go back to the top of that
curve and go back down again
so um we're keeping
we're keeping the moisture level uh in a
within a window where it is plant
available and because we don't want to
oversaturate it because then it's not
going to be plant available and it's
going to do harm to the to the to the
plant itself and we don't want to dry it
out too much uh because again we're
going to do harm and damage to the plant
um there's some other factors to to look
at two which is the nutrient content in
the you know your EC in the soil
um as the percentage of water drops your
EC
increases and that's because uh as the
as the percentage of water drops the the
concentration just becomes greater of
whatever nutrients in there so if you
took I don't know you would like have a
pot of coffee like on the burner and it
Cooks down and it Cooks down and
eventually would turn into like kind of
a sludge right because we've removed the
water but there's still material in
there that's the same kind of concept
with with drying it out and a lot of
what like crop steering so that's a term
that gets thrown around a lot in
different ways what that is is cycling
plants uh back and forth on that
moisture release curve and drying them
out to a point where the plant is still
uptaking water it's still nutrient
available so so so plant available the
water content in the soil um but the
nutrient level is very high so it's able
to uptake a lot of nutrients and then
taking it right down to a point before
it's starting to damage the plant and
then introducing another irrigation
event and um kind of repeating that
process so it's this kind of pulsing
cycle that you know looked at over time
is up and down and up and down and so
it's dry wet dry wet but within a very
specific um band
of of measurement so you know if you're
measuring in tensiometers and you're
using uh mbars to measure that something
like a like a Coco has a pretty pretty
large window you know you might be able
to start um irrigating when it when it
uh when it dries down to 70 mbars and
then you want to irrigate back until it
hits about 10 mbars which is very wet
and then let it dry back down to 70 um
you know more of like a like a Pete
based living soil kind of thing you're
going to you're going to start U uh
irrigating around 100 100 between 100
120 depending on the composition and and
water it down to like 40 or 50 mbars and
then repeat that process and yeah
there's some really cool stuff that
happens in there to the plant um you get
these generative cues that are
introduced to the plant when you when
you cycle it through that dryback phase
so it's you know the one of the other
terms get thrown around a lot is like
dryb backs what's your dryback are you
doing this and and what we're looking at
is is running the soil down that uh
moisture release curve um and and and
drying it out and why do we do that well
we don't want to dry it out to a point
of of Wilt that stresses the plant it's
going to be permanent damage it's going
to impact yield it's going to impact
Vigor it's going to you know all all
that stuff but by by drawing it back to
just before the point where we're
hitting that we're introducing the
concept of stress we're not actually
stressing the plant like on a real level
but we're letting the plant know and you
know going an anthrop more I'm going to
I'm going to turn the plan into a person
here for a second and uh you know we're
introducing that concept of stress and
um when we do that it it's it's it's
kind of reminding the plant that hey
there's a there's a you know there's a
there's an end to this there's
impermanence that does exist and um it
uh it'll it'll can trigger you you know
doing it within certain Windows like
having a longer dryback period will help
induce flowering in a plant keeping it
in a narrow wetter band will will keep a
plant in a vegetative state longer but
by drying it back a little bit more um
we're going to see a u we're giving it
we're giving it a generative cue so we
we're telling the plant hey it's time to
start the second half of your life cycle
it's time to start producing flowers um
and to and to start uh fruit set so
there's again there's things with
moisture levels that can be um can be
done to
manipulate um those functions in the
plant I know that's a lot and there's a
lot you can kind of take each one of
those little places there and jump off
and talk more about it and talk about
specific strategy that's that's species
specific or strain specific even um but
that's the general concept of a moisture
release curve I appreciate you breaking
that down for us we have lots of people
that do dryb backs or drought stress
Precision stress in that method in order
to you know try to achieve several
things right whether they're trying to
stress out the plant to have more
secondary metabolites or or what now the
numbers that you mentioned there it's 70
mbars at that point to aate and then
it'll go down to 10 which you said is
considered wet is that using the blue
mat moisture meter I was told now here's
so much conflicting information online
where I believe the general range for
those meters would be you want to stay
in between 50 and 100 mbars is that not
correct or what would be the ideal range
to stay in so 50 and 100 m bar is a
great range for a living soil blend for
a living like so or really most potting
soil mixes right so anything that is in
U yeah so it's like again that's like
that's a blend of some sort of compost
some sort of Iration material like
pearlite and then and and something that
holds a lot of water like something very
porous like uh like peed or cocoa it's
going to absorb water um that 7010 range
that's if you running pure cocoa so
that's more of like a hydro kind of
application um you can kind you can it
dries out quick cocoa dries out pretty
quick so that's why it does have a
little bit wider and you can you can
bring the moisture level um you can get
a lot wetter and operated at a much
wetter level so that's why that 10 is
the number um again yeah so if if you're
running in a hydro kind of uh
environment where you're using synthetic
nutrients and cocoa uh that's that's the
range I'd go with but if it's in potting
soil like an amended potting soil
engineered media however you want to
describe it living soil mix um that 50
to 100 is is accurate you can do that in
large field applications with overhead
watering um and a lot of sensor data you
can do that with drip irrigation like in
a larger Hydro facility or something
like that um or you can use blue mats to
do it and the the the bloats um are you
know
like we you know we've talked about them
before but just to give a a quick recap
what they are is they are they're a
tensiometer they're um you know for the
for the people that are watching this
visually it's it's one of these things
um it's a tube it's a plastic tube with
a ceramic tip on the top and then there
is a valve at the very top of it with a
tube running through it and that valve
opens and closes based on the soil
moisture level so as the soil dries out
the tip dries out the a negative
pressure is uh created inside the tube
and um there's a diaphragm in here that
is is sucked down by that negative
pressure which opens the valve
physically uh on the on the top of the
comp carrots blue mat carrots and that
valve opens and water is able to flow
through the tube and it'll drip out
either into um just directly into the
pot in a very small container um it
could feed into uh a drip ring there's
um some really interesting kind of
products like these these drip rings
that they they can feed right into that
have emitters in them and then drip in
in many different spots um or we we use
a soaker hose uh we call Blue soak and
it's it's made out of tyac it's it
operates at really really low pressures
and anyway so these are the water
delivery mechanisms and the basic uh
functionality is that soil dries out a
valve opens um the system Waters up to
that to a certain trigger point then uh
the water turns off and then you get
that dry back so again that's the same
thing with that moisture relief curve
you're you're watering uh the soil is
getting wetter and wetter towards the
top of that the curve um the water turns
off and then it dries back and the soil
dries back and dries back and dries back
until it hits a lower set point and then
it turns itself on now if you're using
some sort of like um digital sensor or
something like that that you might have
that that's operating a pump or solenoid
valves in a drip irrigation system to
turn turn it on also so those are some
of the more sophisticated ways of doing
it with traditional drip irrigation and
you know more expensive uh uh electric
all there's lots and lots of sensors
that that can that can do that you know
some better than others um and again
when you're in that uh vegetative state
of of growth you're keeping it wetter in
a narrow band of wet and in a uh the
flowering State and particular in
stretch uh at the transition point you
want to have a wider you want to have a
bigger dryback period there too and what
we found with the blue mats is that they
kind of do that on their own so when
they're when they're placed in the soil
and operate
when the plants are smaller and they're
in veg they are keeping it in a in a
pretty narrow band because they're able
to water and keep up with the that
moisture level so the it's a much more
static uh wet dry wet dry period uh in
veg and then as soon as the plants hit
stretch they start consuming water much
faster and that and then it takes a
little it takes a a little bit of time
for the for the for the bloat to catch
back up so you get so you without
adjusting anything you're you're you're
getting longer dryback periods during
the stretch and flower uh periods when
there's more water consumption so when
you want more uh dryb backs they're kind
of automatically doing that and um and
and cycling through that uh that
moisture release curve and and really
they're kind of doing this automatic
crop steering uh just on on the
individual containers got it and for
anyone wanting more details on blue mats
or what blue mat setup to use for each
container size we did all of that in the
last episode so I urge you to check out
the last episode that Michael and I did
uh he went into detail about all that
stuff I want to flip it up though and
talk about some new technology for
watering plants there is new things that
are coming out and I think that's what
excites people a lot talk to us about
some of the new technology for watering
plants sure yeah um well what we've
we've been doing here we we do our own
R&amp;D um and we do that through some of
the uh some of the uh we have a facility
we have kind of just a small operation
here at our our warehouse and offices um
a lot of the people we know and work
with have their own home grows and then
there's quite a few uh you know larger
commercial um Growers either in here in
Colorado or in other places of the
country that we'd like to collaborate
with to to really do all this R&amp;D so you
know the process that we go through is
yeah usually one of the guys here at the
office starts messing with some idea at
home and then we try to replicate it
here in the office and then we and then
we send out a bunch of systems and do
some pilot programs with um a bunch of
different folks and uh yeah we've had
really cool um kind of you know that's
how we've done a lot of stuff honestly
is in collaboration with with the
customers and that we work with and the
big thing that we've been doing is um is
with blue mats because that's kind of
you know kind of our our wheelhouse
mostly is to uh preset the blue mats so
in in the past when you would get a blue
mat carrot and you would set it up and
you hook it all up to the system there'd
be a process where you would would dial
it in there's a little brown cap on the
top that you can spin and it open
changes the flow rates and stuff like
that um or the moisture level that the
the system turns on and off
at and what we're doing now is uh we we
going to built a station here at our
office where we're able to to to set
them ear ahead of time and um you know
like the visually here it's like we
we'll set them and then we put a cap on
the top we put this protective cap on
the top and underneath that
um just going to pop this off underneath
that we'll put a few marks so there'll
be a red mark and a blue mark on there
and what we can do now is uh when these
things come in the mail all you have to
do is soak the bottoms screw the top on
and it's going to be it's going to be
set um to produce a certain moisture
level at a particular pressure so the
back the pressure on the back end of the
system um you know say it's a it's kind
of like the full pressure like 12 to 15
psi if uh you know if you if you keep it
right at this blue Mark here uh lined up
with this this fin piece if you keep it
at the blue Mark um you're going to hit
a certain moisture level like that's
about where you want it if you're
running it off of Gravity so you'll need
have 1 to two PSI you're going to move
it closer to the to the red mark on
there and we've produced a chart that
has a kind of all these corresponding
values that represent the backend
pressure where this dial should be set
and it's really just like a quarter turn
of the dial that you're ever going to be
moving through yeah so that's that's
kind of the newest thing we're doing and
what that allows us to do is is send out
uh carrots for for you know just a few
plants in the basement or for you know
hundreds or thousands of plants in a
facility and each one of these carrots
is going to go into each one of the
containers and they're going to produce
extremely consistent results from
container to container so without any
real dialing in process you're going to
hit uh extremely consistent moisture
levels for every container in the space
whether it's 6 or
600 and then you can you can then
manipulate the moisture levels um just
by changing the backend uh uh pressure
on the system so if the pressure going
into the system is you know it say it's
coming in at 15 psi and everything in
the room is at like 40 mbars and you
want to kind of dry that out to like you
know 60 mbars as your low low low end
you would just drop that backend
pressure down to like you know 7 PSI and
that's going to automatically drop like
change the moisture level of every every
pot or every container in the in the
space
um and you you know it seems like a
simple thing but it's really
revolutionized the success uh of for for
Growers that are doing it because it
takes the human error part on someone
that's new to using blue mats um just
right right out of the equation um so
that human error part just kind of
becomes becomes a much less of a
factor um and it makes the whole systems
way more kind of plug andplay you don't
get the kind of overwatering that might
have have come or or flooded or anything
like that with with you know setting the
the blue mats incorrectly and getting
over watering that's been eliminated
with this process um and then really
just redesigning the water distribution
piece so I mentioned these the drip
Rings um we have them in a a 5 in and uh
and in a 10 in also so like you know
anything up to like a 5 gallon pot would
go with the 5 in and then kind of your
like 10 gallons up to 30 gallons would
go with one of these 10in rings so so in
um you know one of the one of the
carrots with one of these drip rings per
container uh is is like it's a great way
to be really really consistent and give
good water distribution nice and even
moisture levels in the soil and then
have them operating within those
moisture ranges that we were talking
about like a narrow wetter band during
veg and then during flower a little bit
more of a swing of of wet dry um overall
uh so yeah I mean I would
say I would say that's like a big
advancement we've we've uh assembled a
new pump kit that um we just started
releasing like two months ago um people
might have seen them they have a nice
blue tank and a and a and a pump
integrated right on top of it um and it
comes with this adjustable pressure
reducer which is a new product that
we've integrated into the system so that
um you can you can again adjust that
backend pressure of the system just at
one place so the pressure reducer itself
has a dial on it that you can turn and
drop the pressure and watch the pressure
drop on your pressure gauge uh that's
mounted on it and you know with with
that new pump kit with the adjustable
pressure reducer with the pre- dialed
carrots um and the drip rings for pots
or our manifold beds
uh with the soaker hose for raised beds
um you know this this system we've we've
taken like we've done like so many
different systems that are experimental
and like maybe we're going to try it
like this we're going to try it like
this what's working I feel you know
after hammering away at this stuff for
six or seven years now we've we've
gotten to a place where we have a really
awesome kind of line of really simple
designs that are scalable and um
consistent with what they're going to
deliver and um we're actually like in
the process of like revamping our
website right now so that we can um
we're going to have a a sustainable
village.com there'll be a um a build
your own blue mat system and a page
there it's not quite functional yet as
were recording this but I'm hoping in a
couple weeks it will be um and for the
smaller systems you know for up to like
a 10 x10 growth space you could go in
there really easily and customize your
own system and just order it right
online without even really having to
talk to anybody and you're going to get
a you're going to get a package in the
mail that has everything you need from
from pumps to supply lines to um
to the to the carrots themselves and the
water distribution um so that that kind
of like Suite of technology and services
we've been working on for pretty much
consistently since the last time we
talked two years ago on this show and um
has gotten to a point where We've ran
through you know like a year of pilot
programs with with hom Growers and
commercial facilities um gotten gotten
feedback made some adjustments and and
now we have like I said that that kind
of like sweet of products that and and
and designs and Tech to uh to give
people like a awesome experience from
irrigation uh perspective and you know
like I'm a water nerd and an irrigation
guy and like so for me it's really
exciting especially to take like take
problem points that were like man these
are this is real pain in the butt and um
put those
into uh you really solve those pain
points and and get a and get get um a
design out that's that's easy and makes
people successful and it's going to
result in you know significant yield
increases and healthier plants and way
more free time and that's the Innovation
you were talking about earlier you know
it definitely sounds like it makes
things easier for the end consumer and
uh less mistakes happen you know I know
a lot of people who get the blue mats
and just dialing it in it's that little
tinkering that needs to get done it's
It's Tricky for them so having a precept
blue mat is uh pretty awesome I do have
a question in regards to that I think I
know the answer to it but I'm still
going to ask know you have it dialed in
it's preset so it's it's Watering your
plant as it needs if you want to add in
say microbes for example so you have
like a/4 gallon or half gallon of water
and you just pour it right on the top of
the medium so it's going to make that
Medium more moist right more wet so it's
going to lower the Miller bars right now
is it going to throw off the preset blue
mat or is it going to dry back to that
certain range that it's in as far as
moisture level yeah no you're you're
answering your own question it will it
will not throw off the preset blue mat
so like your questions about liquid
inputs and um it's really really common
way to do things is to run clean water
through the blue mats and then if you
want to do an a liquid input like a like
a compost tea drench or just a nutrient
drench or anything like that uh that's
fine that's no problem at all um you'll
just you will bring the moisture level
down um or you know it'll it'll become
more wet uh for for a short amount of
time but the blue mat will just turn off
and it'll stay off until it dries back
to its trigger point so the trigger
point is really about when does a blue
mat turn on and then when does it turn
off
and um that is uh yeah so no it doesn't
affect it is the is the short answer
there and I think you you nailed it okay
and then you also talked about PSI and I
know there's some folks that are hooking
it up to their spet for example and
they're doing it like have an outdoor
setup and they have a a pressure reducer
so they're dialing that PSI to to 15 or
whatever they set it to right but a lot
of folks are growing indoors and they're
just doing the gravity Fed so they're
hooked up to a reservoir so they don't
really have control over that PSI in a
sense now in our last episode we talked
about you had mentioned that when you're
setting those blue mats it's best to
have your Reservoir half full and then
dial it in that way when it lowers
you're kind of getting less pressure or
you if you increase the amount that's in
the reservoir that's a different
pressure as well now will that throw off
the preset blue mats to to the folks
that are doing gravity fed should they
have their Reservoir half full then
install the preset blue mats or does
that not matter anymore because it's
it's preset well what you do there
because exactly right because really
what you're doing for your water source
when you look at your water source you
have a few different options you can
either come right off of a pressurized
water source like a hose bib and go
straight into a pressure reducer and
knock that down to to 15 psi anywhere
from 15 to 2 PSI um you can use a pump
kit like a pre-assembled pump kit that's
basically going to do the same thing
it's going to create a constant water
sources under constant pressure run that
through another pressure reducer or
through a pressure reducer and kind of
hit that same consistent level or you
can M you can achieve that constant
pressure with a with gravity so um you
know the calculation for that is uh uh 1
psi equals 2.31 ft of vertical head so
for every 2.31 ft of of vertical um
elevation that that the water is above
the soil surface that's one PSI so we
like to see about two PSI to get good
uniform operation it'll they will
function closer to one PSI but I'd like
to see two um so three or five feet you
know four to five feet of head um yeah
you can just do that you can uh you can
use a a 5 gallon bucket that's like a a
popular thing we send out these bucket
kits you can use
a plastic tote from Home Depot or
whatever just drill a little hole in it
and put a little a bulkhead in it and
then run off that and um have your
supply line creating that kind of
constant pressure and as far as the
preset carrots goes um I'll pop this top
off again the uh there's like I said
there's there's a blue mark on it and
there's a red mark on it and these are
all in relation to this there's a
plastic fin right there on the top and
so when you're when your backend
pressure is higher like with off a
pressure reducer you're going to put it
towards that blue Mark when it's drier
or when it's when the lower pressure
like a 2psi like off of Gravity you're
just going to want to turn that to the
to the red mark and like I said these
things come with this plastic cap
snapped over the top as protective cap
and there's actually a little key that
we have now too I don't have one sitting
here but um there's a little key that
that inserts into this hole and then you
can just turn it and you just move that
between the blue and the red um to do
that without having remove the cap so
you know if you are running a gravity
system they're going to come set with
the at the blue mark But if you're
running the gravity you just adjust it
so that that the red mark is lining up
with that plastic fin piece there and um
we have some really nice uh you know
kind of like infographic style
instructions that go along with this
that'll that will show how to manipulate
that um and also a chart that's that's
part of it too that'll show you know you
look at your backend pressure and the
moisture levels you want to hit and then
where to adjust it within that range
between the red and the blue Mark so
yeah that's for for Gravity systems we
would just move it towards the red mark
nice yeah it sounds like it makes things
a lot easier for the hom grower and I'm
all about easy so I have to see if I can
get my hands on on those things so what
other advancements in irrigation
technology do you anticipate in the
future so what what we're doing with the
blue mats and and we we do this with
other things too and other people do it
it's that that kind of that sort of Holy
Grail of irrigation is is all about
plant demand irrigation so using some
sort of sensor to trigger irrigation
events and again that's really happening
with the blue mats um I would say that
the like the place where where the blue
matat isn't as effective as in like
large scale outdoor applications um
because because of some of the flow
rates involved um some of the materials
involved are a little more prone to
invol like UV degradation or like they
get chewed up by animals and things like
that um anybody that's growing Outdoors
we have strategies for coping with all
of that if they're in containers but
they but work if you're in direct soil
like um native soil applications things
like that the blue mats aren't
necessarily the best choice so you know
I see just the evolution of sensors you
know there's like all kinds of different
moisture sensors out there whether the
volumetric ones um or tensiometer based
ones or there's there's a Third Kind
called the solid Matrix um sensors which
are a type of tensiometers that are used
in uh clay soils like clay based soils
like you would use outside in a in a
large scale field or something like that
I mean some of the stuff I'm excited
about is like completely not related to
um you know that that indoor industry
that we've been talking about um it's
more like in the regenerative a space we
do I I designed systems using a product
called K kfco Water re they these large
water guns that can water anywhere from
like 1 to 60 Acres at a time and that's
like a it's a larger amount of space
right in general um but it's not as
large as like a center pivot irrigation
piece so I mean this is just a pet
project of mine that and I'm working on
with uh some some of the people in the
regenerative a community but uh you know
when you fly over United States or
anywhere and you see all the center
pivots so you look down at the field and
you see these uh these large circles
with then they have brown in the corners
where they're not growing anything
because the center pivots are just like
that's what they are they're a giant
sprinkler that just like operates on a
big boom arm and spins around in a
circle and that leaves these corners of
the fields uh
uncultivated and um yeah something I'm
just kind of getting kicked off and as
like a side project on my own is is is
is irrigating those corners and and
putting those into regenerative
agricultural practices that can be um uh
ecosystems for and Native habitats for
for pollinators and for for uh plants
and animals that um will benefit the
larger ecosystems and even the monocrops
that are that are being grown there um
for carbon sequestration all these sort
of like the benefits of regenerative a
there's a ton of there's like just
thousands and thousands of acres of land
out there that's not being used because
they can't hit them with those Center
pivots so we're putting together some
designs to uh irrigate those those the
corners like you know the corners of the
fields um again that's kind of outside
of it that's something I'm excited about
as a as a as a designer and someone
that's like you know passionate about
regenerative EG in general yeah and then
you know and then in the controlled
environment space like yeah it's just
the evolution of sensors um the drip
irrigation companies that we work with
uh like irch rivulus neim those kind of
companies you know they're all
producing some new technology uh in drip
IR ation a lot of it's you know it's not
super Innovative but there's some new
stuff that comes out periodically and
they get better quality products so kind
of cool to see that come out but yeah I
think like the sensors and the data
that's produced and um a lot of that's
now being integrated with like you know
cloud-based technology so you'll have
like aerometer we we sell a lot of those
like aerometer makes a tensiometer it's
similar to the blue matat digital moist
meter but um it that you can connect it
back to this Hub that has a SIM card in
it and that that shoots up data to a
cloud and you can go on your browser and
see like real time uh it's not really
real time they give it it's like every
hour they give a data set but you can
see historical moisture data for a field
um or you can put them indoors too and
see that over time in your in your
indoor grow um but uh yeah just
collecting more and more data and
getting more sophisticated with the
application of water and nutrients so
that we're never using too much and
we're never overwatering or over
fertilizing um to kind of create healthy
soils and ecosystems nice yeah the
moisture level having the data for that
kind of reminds me of the Eco wit
moisture meter not sure if you're
familiar with that one or not but uh
that one basically connects to an app
and it gives you that display right
there so you could have multiple all see
it right there now one thing that would
be really cool and maybe this already
exists and I don't know about it but
what if that was connected to like a
blue mat for example and you could set
on your app what moisture level you
wanted and then it would adjust
automatically yeah Eco is a volumetric
water sensor so that's measuring that
percentage of water in the soil and you
know if you have done enough of the math
and kind of calculations to you can um
strategize your irrigation events based
on those numbers um you have to like be
more familiar with the soil types and
blah blah blah um and then I know those
are really popular and I you know I
think people have good results with them
they're they're kind of on the lower end
of the spectrum of like sensitivity and
and functionality that sort of thing
there's some other brands like tarot
sensor or um someone call acclima and
these are like kind of more higher end
lab grade ones that that give really
specific results but that's exactly how
uh you know a lot of Growers will will
do crop steering within um uh like Hydro
systems if they're in rock wall so
they'll have like those their prongs and
they'll have a biometric water sensor in
the rock wall and it's giving it once it
hits a certain trigger point it'll it'll
open a solenoid valve and it'll irrigate
every piece of rock wall and then it'll
up to a certain point and then it'll
turn itself off um so yeah that does
that that that Tech is is out there I
think that it's there's ton there's a
lot of people doing some really cool
stuff and that are they're building
better systems better sensors better
platforms for like looking at that
information and hooking it up to the
water distribution system itself um so
yeah we seen some seen some cool cool
things like that I like you know that's
great and when I I'm more of an AGM
minded irrigation guy anyway so like I
try to go towards Simplicity I I think
that Growers have created technology
problems for themselves that they don't
necessarily need by like getting too
complex with uh with some of those
systems but you know if if if you have
the bandwidth and the budget to to
implement that sort of thing it can be
really effective I completely agree with
you and it's kind of funny sometimes
hearing you've got people on both sides
some people are like um handw watering
be with the plants know the plants
versus Automation and kind of being
hands off and being the garden less you
know so whichever way you decide to go
about it that's up to you I overall
think it's exciting to see this
technology in this space and I'm a
person who would actually implement it
in my garden without losing touch of the
plants you know I I love getting in
there and breathing on the plants giving
some fresh CO2 you know but now good
stuff a lot to look forward to but
appreciate you coming on today for the
second time can you tell the listeners
how they can find you and what you have
upcoming in the future yeah sure um so
like our our main thing is uh uh our
website sustainabl village.com like I
said that's actually currently
undergoing some upgrades now I hope it's
going to look you know fingers crossed
like really kind of nice and slick and
useful and a better tool for actually
finding and buying the products you want
to buy um um you can always uh request a
free design from our team so our blue
matat designs are free of charge um if
you go to the website you can um just
there's a request to quote button fill
out some information and we kick you
back a uh a drawing and um parts list
itemized parts list for a blue mat
system um you can also email us at info@
sustainable village.com um on Instagram
that's always there's like a ton of cool
content on there you go to Blue matat
watering systems on Instagram b m a
watering systems um lots of great
content there lots of you know reposts
of people using our stuff all over and
yeah you might also uh you can always
just hit us up through that Instagram
Channel too we we're really responsive
there um our phone number is 303 9981
1323 uh here in Boulder Colorado but
yeah mostly just go to website hit that
request the quote button um or give us a
call you we got guys here like really
really talented design guys that are
just going to answer the phone for you
um or get back to you really fast if you
if you leave a message um I'd also
recommend checking out uh Cooper one of
our designers has a great Instagram
Channel I recommend you guys go check it
out that's upaya Garden so uh u p a y a
garden um he's got really he's just
taking the R&amp;D blat thing to a new level
and um yeah I would check out some of
those sites but blue mat watering
systems Zay Gardens uh and sustainable
village.com are kind of the best ways to
find us um as far as upcoming events I
don't have a lot on the calendar right
now we've been we're pretty uh pretty
locked into the office right now doing
design work um at
Springtime and you know just keeping the
business humming and uh most of that's
happening here so if anybody's in the
you know Front Range of Colorado and
they want to stop by and say hi we'd
love to see you that's always welcome
um and yeah I'm not sure I'm not sure
about a future events at the moment
definitely we'll be going back to the
soil life Summit once they announce a
new event we'll probably hit a few trade
shows we always do the Colorado farm
show every year but it's not till
January um
yeah that's that's the where to find us
awesome I'll definitely have a link to
you down in the YouTube description
section below so people can easily find
you Michael thanks so much for coming on
again this was great episode this time
flew by I can't believe how quickly this
time flew by here yeah well anytime you
know I love talking about this stuff so
awesome all right well we'll leave it at
that thank you so much and hope you
enjoy the rest of your day I really
appreciate it Chris thanks so much peace
out everyone catch you in the next
episode