welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey everybody for those of you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
145 in this episode I interview C bunny
some of you might recognize her from
homow the community a hom Grow Show on
YouTube she has been gardening for 2
years and grows both indoors and
Outdoors when growing Outdoors she takes
an organic approach which is what we're
going to get into in today's episode she
talks all about her style of organic
gardening outdoors and how she keeps it
simple if you want to see short clips of
these podcast episodes search Garden
talk clips on YouTube I also have a
gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of to's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their controller
69 which can help automate your
environment's conditions it'll
automatically turn on and off equipment
to help control the temperature humidity
VPD light schedule and even the
oscillating fans click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about the controller 69 and
the discount code Mr grow5 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend consists of
several ingredients in one so you no
longer have to buy individual bottles it
includes Quant Ste liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and Ed to
discount code the stash and we are back
and I'm joined with C bunny how you
doing today I'm doing great thank you
for asking thanks for coming on to the
podcast today I'm familiar with your
show your channel we got you Mama Kush
Mr ganx doing your thing on is it Friday
nights and Wednesday nights or or what
is it yes so every Friday and Wednesday
night at 900 PM Eastern we are over on
YouTube great show hom grow the
community I'll definitely have a link in
the description section below and uh
yeah I appreciate what you guys are
doing over there thank you in this
episode we're going to get into organic
gardening outdoor so lots and lots of
people have been requesting outdoor
content uh we do a lot of content
gardening indoors but first can you tell
us a little bit about yourself and how
you got into gardening so I go by SE
bunny grow I'm a single mom of two sons
with uh special needs I'm French
Canadian up up until I'm a late bloomer
so up until 7 years ago I had never even
seen this wonderful plant that we all
come to know and love so I started by uh
helping defoliation defoliated started
watering them and about two years ago I
decided I wanted to do it solo I grew a
great passion for it and I just couldn't
wait to learn more about it and learn
quicker than I was being shown awesome
so you're mostly outdoors I looked at
your Instagram I I believe you do a
little bit of indoors as well but uh see
a lot of big plants outdoors I got to
ask do you start your seeds indoors and
veg them for a little while and then
transfer to Outdoors or are you planting
directly Outdoors so for indoor what
I'll do is I'll start in a Solo Cup I'll
use promix and I will start it in the
tent till they have about their first
set of leaves then I'll transfer them to
to the secondary location where the
outdoors go so that hardening off
process right I assume you're not just
taking them from the indoors and then
putting them into Outdoors direct
sunlight and just leaving them like that
right there's a hardening off period so
they don't die can you talk to us about
that period like how do you do that
transition so when they do go to the
second location they are put in the
garage and I do put them on the window
seal so they do get a little bit used to
hard in off and then um once they're a
little bit bigger I do bring them
outside so I'll put them in the shade
for most of the day and then I'll put
them in the St for a couple hours let
them get uh used to the to the weather
and the change of of lights because you
go from an LED to the sun which is a big
big difference so you're starting off
like day one they're doing maybe what
two hours direct sunlight and then
you're kind of gradually ramping up day
by day one of getting like full sun once
they're once I transpl plant them from
the Solo Cup into the bigger cup so
they're decent size when I transfer them
into their fore ever home then they get
a full sun all day long and then full
sun are we talking 10 hours are we
talking 12 hours so depending the month
usually we'll
say
from 6: a.m. till about 9: : p.m. okay
and then the entire time they have sun
on them or is there some like shade uh
no direct sunlight okay now are you in
containers or are you planting them in
ground I actually use plastic containers
uh plastic pots they could be anywhere
from 25 gallons to 10 gallons depending
how many I'm doing if I ran out of the
25 gallons and I'll I'll do the the 10
gallons usually I'll put the Clones in
the 10 g g in and I'll put the seedlings
in the bigger pots then what do you have
what's your in your soil mix there are
you in a cocoa are you in a soil what
fertiliz you using so on and so forth so
for outdoors I've actually this year I'm
using um old Marsh soil from a swamp
down the road from the secondary
location um it's mixed with old uh horse
and cow manure and about I'll say 15% of
perite for better drainage got it and
then so that's what you're starting with
are you doing any sort of like top
dressing of amendments or anything like
that throughout the grow at all or is it
just kind of water only for the whole
grow cycle having the marsh soil it
already has a lot of life in it you
already have fish poop you got
everything else and then with the manure
it is high uh very rich in in nitrogen
so you have your nitrogens but I will
also sometimes use a slow release
pellets I'm not sure the brand and in
flour I'll add a potassium nitrate when
do you usually add the potassium nitrate
uh when they start flowering oh start
okay so the start of flowering I know
some people will wait until like mid or
late flowering you're doing it from the
start of flowering and then throughout
the whole flowering stage depending
again what the plant is telling me so
you're just looking for reading the
plant looking for deficiencies and then
kind of feeding according to that
exactly and then what are you using for
a water source are you using like a
local tap water well water are you
filtering your water so I actually use
two different kind of water I use well
water and I use uh collected rainwater
that we collected in a rain barrel so um
most of the time I'll if I use the hose
then it's it's well water and then if I
use the rain water I'll I'll do it by
hand got it now have you ever done a
water test on your well water to kind of
see what the balance of nutrients are in
there or you just kind of assuming that
everything is good and hoping that the
microbes kind of work things out just
assuming so far it's been working over
the years cool I figured I'd ask that
because I know some well waters are high
in um what is it I think it's iron I
believe so some people yeah some people
get into hot water because they're
adding this well water and then they
they're seeing problems with it and then
they're come to I out there's just an
excess of some elements in their well
water that's causing a lock out of other
elements so big I asked that just to see
if you had done testing or not how about
compost teas do you do those at all um
no uh not outdoors I do not again they
have a lot of stuff already in them from
the soil so already got that microbe
life indigenous microorganisms from the
the soil that you took from from that
area in the local so yeah that's pretty
cool it's local exactly yeah so let's
get into plant training next what do you
typically do for plant training when
growing Outdoors so considering where my
second location is there is no neighbors
I am not worried of smell I'm not
worried about uh the plants being seen
so all I do is absolutely nothing I let
them grow wild and free and how nature
intended them to so no bending no
topping no super cropping no f no
nothing huh just naturally Wild and Free
now when I looked at your Instagram one
thing I noticed is that I believe you do
have one steak in the middle there and
then there's a cup at the top of the
steak what's that all about um that's
just to know what which kind it
is okay so it's a label basically for
you yes yes the blue cups are uh clones
of one kind the red CL cups are clones
of the other and then the bigger pots
the seedling have actual like popsicle
sticks inside that you can't see okay
now do you ever get without doing the
training I'm I'm just curious do you
ever get plants that are so big that
we're just kind of flopping all over the
place towards the end of uh flowering
there it's kind of hard to manage or or
no yes but that's where the bamboo
sticks really come in handy tying them
up to keep uh keep them straight because
otherwise like you said they will start
to to flop so in flowering you are going
in and adding in support staks what is
it like mid or they flowering or
something like that just just as needed
or what it just as needed yes some
plants may not need it some plants May
got it that makes sense and so how big
do your outdoor plants typically get so
typically they'll get anywhere from
seven to feet uh 7 to 10 feet tall on a
good good harvest typically okay lots of
time trimming I assume right oh my
goodness that's a whole different show
yeah would not want to be in that trim
jail that's for
sure that's something I feel like that
like a bow trimmer would be super
helpful if you got the money even one of
those larger trimmers more
commercialized but they make up like
more commercialized ones for hom Growers
as well yeah I know they can get pretty
pricey there but jez if you're dealing
with with 10 foot plants and you've got
multiple of them worth the investment
now I want to get into something that's
going to potentially hurt yields which
is pests what is your IPM routine
consist of like what are you doing in
order to prevent pests from invading
your grow space I've been very lucky
knock on wood and I might regret saying
this but I do not do any IPM management
um Mother Nature has been good to me so
far and with the ladybugs we have out
there and with all the amazing life in
the marsh soil uh both good and bad it's
it's helped keep keep it pretty pretty
steady so no no major pest so far we've
had a couple caterpillars but you just
flick them off and it's been good
indoors however I've ran into uh a lot
of knots yeah that's great to hear about
Outdoors usually uh you know usually
hear about some infestations happening
but there are a lot of beneficials out
there that's really going to help combat
those pests exactly now caterpillars
have you been doing any sort of spraying
I know you said you you're flicking them
off by I know some people really
struggle with caterpillars it's just
it's all over the plant is is you just
find here one here and there or is it
like does it get really bad sometimes
again knock on wood I've been pretty
lucky where I do have uh the plants I do
keep them away from other trees and
other uh plant life that is in the area
so they don't have like caterpillars
falling on it and stuff like that so I'm
I'm assuming that's why I haven't had
many or it could just be luck how about
beneficial insects do you have any of
those like kind of flying around or that
you can spot that you're aware of that
you know are doing a good thing in your
garden not that I could really think off
the top of my head like just the normal
like of course the ladybugs they're
they're our favorite uh our favorite
one but besides that I can't just think
right now okay how about cover crops and
mul layer and then you mention your
growing organically mentioned the inputs
and what you're using for a soil now
some people are going to do cover crops
as well which could be very beneficial
for a wide variety of reasons or mulch
layers are you doing utilizing either
one of those in your containers uh I am
not but it is something that I want to
start doing um I haven't yet again with
the soil I'm using it already has a lot
of those microbes a lot of bacterias a
lot of everything I need
which is great but I know covered crops
would be good for um pest controls as as
well for keeping certain pests away
certain smells will keep certain bugs
and so that is definitely something I'm
interested in my next gross but not this
one not yet all right well I'll
definitely be staying tuned to your
Instagram to see once you start using
those things how you use them because uh
yeah it's definitely definitely
beneficial I like to see what the
difference would be between using them
not using them that'd be cool yeah any
advice for the flowering stage I feel
like this is somewhere a lot of folks
they just struggle they have a really
healthy veg they veg their plants for
however long then flip the flower or in
Outdoors it's just automatically
transitioning the flower as there's less
light naturally right but in the
flowering stage people come across
problems potentially with deficiencies
or whatever what advice do you have for
getting through the flowering stage to
be honest the best advice I can give
is to just not give up um reach out to
the community don't be afraid to ask for
help be patient because that is my
biggest uh challenge in flowering is
being
patient um but yeah definitely uh if if
you don't succeed just don't give up
keep moving forward again ask for help
there's no shame in asking for help we
all started at the bottom and that's how
we will learn
what kind of deficiency we have what
kind of what kind of nutrients you may
need to add and so on and so forth good
tips I want to go back to the Harvest
process cuz you know you mentioned these
7 to 10 foot plants and it's a lot can
you walk us through your process of
harvesting like when do you harvest what
are you looking at to determine when or
not to harvest and then walk us through
your process in detail like cutting down
the Plant and what you do from there so
ideally
I would like to cut down I like to cut
down uh Thanksgiving Canadian
Thanksgiving which is in
October um I do like to check my
tricomes I'm looking for something
that's no clear I don't want any clear
on my
tricomes but um due to our weather which
is very up and down it's very hard to um
get that far so um we do get a lot of
rain a lot of frost cuz I am up North so
we tend to get a lot of uh Bud rot which
causes us to cut down very very early do
you typically just cut off that Branch
that's infected or are you like getting
rid of the whole plant well if it's not
bad we'll cut off the plant that's the
just the branch that's infected but once
we notice that it starts to spread I
will cut the whole plant and then cut
out the pieces that have been
um that have Bud rot and just hang it
and go from there so once I do cut them
um I will hang them usually the whole
plant would be hung in a garage in the
top Loft on strings so in the garage on
strings hanging upside down and then for
drying what does your setup look like
are you just in that area and then also
are you setting up like humidifiers or
dehumidifiers fans like what's your Dy
set up for drying I do look for
6060 um it is much cooler in October
especially up north again so I do not
need to have any um extra humidifiers or
air conditioners or fan knock on wood
it's I've been pretty lucky
for between the 55 60 is what I I've
been getting but ideally I aim for 6060
it must be nice to have that natural
humidity there I live in a dry climate I
have to say that in almost every episode
here because uh people need to be
reminded every
episod but it's 20 to 30% I mean I had
winter time it was 16% relative humidity
and so I'm always trying to crank in
humidity it is not fun yeah and in
drying it's so easy to over dry and I
can only imagine being a place like you
where it's just it's naturally around
that 55 60% yeah relative humidity which
is ideal for the drying process so I'm a
little bit
jealous I will notice that like if it
does rain a lot the humidity it is very
humid so I will put a a dehumidifier but
it it's very rare thankfully better safe
to deploy that out and uh try to start
removing that humidity rather than come
across that bud Rod right because that
that mold can even happen in the drying
stage and yes that happened to me
unfortunately I uh I went through a grow
my fan died within the last couple weeks
and I noticed it after 24 hours so the
fan died I looked at I'm like oh what
the heck the fan died so I added in the
fan let the plants continue to grow for
those past two for the last two weeks
yeah harvested and then it's during
drying when I noticed that I actually
had an issue there was white Buzzy mold
on the inside of the buds I'm like oh no
what happened I had to think was it my
drying conditions no it actually wasn't
I had to think back and be oh I had a
fan die for 24 hours and sure the fan
died and was only down for 24 hours but
that's enough time for that to establish
and start the Bas to start to grow right
and so like even though I add it in fans
that doesn't eliminate the problem right
that the the the mold has already
started and it would slowly grow Grew
From there so Bud Rod is definitely not
a fun thing to come across that's for
sure oh no especially when it's baked
plants it's sad when you have to cut
them down to early and they don't
they're still good but they don't get to
the full potential they can be I can
only imagine I can only imagine so after
you're done drying the plant so it's
brought down to that kind of shelf
stable percent what are you doing for
curing are you putting into jars or
using bags what go through your curing
process so for curing um I do both I do
the jars and I do the Grove bags um the
reason I do that is because again having
so many so much to harvest um I only
have so many bags so I go to the jars I
do the rest of the jars and I do like to
see the side by side difference I didn't
notice much the only thing with for
myself personally with jars is I tend to
forget to burp or I forget to tend to
put the jar lid back on so with the
curing bag I don't have to worry about
it I'll open it once in a blue moon move
the buds around to make sure that
everything's good and and then just
leave it yeah so those Grove bags you
don't even need to burp at all
technically right it's kind of like a
self burping thing you just as long as
the buds are dry once you're putting it
in there and sealing it up now you also
like heat sealing it as well no uh it is
Rec recommended to uh heat seal but but
I do
not but even when you're sealing it it's
it's burping itself so you don't have to
uh actually open up a jar every day so
that makes things a little bit easier I
like to move it around just to make sure
there's no no more moisture I just just
to make sure because sometimes you think
it's dry and it's not 100% you get that
moisture in the bags and so I like to
check on it definitely sounds like a
good thing to do now are you using the
large Grill bags that hold like a pound
at a time or whatever I got to imagine
using the larger ones since you're
having such a big yield out there right
yes so I do have a lot of uh larger bags
I do have some medium bags but uh yeah I
I tend to stti stick definitely with the
larger bags how long until you actually
consume um ideally I want it to be a
month or two for curing but that all
depends on how well I did on my previous
Harvest if I need to uh get into it
earlier or not okay and then did you
mention trying to remember if you
mentioned what you usually get for yield
when growing up to ideally what I'm
looking for and what I normally get is
anywhere between a pound per plant a
pound a pound and a half per plant it
all of course that all that all depends
on the feno as well is there any
particular strains that you recommend
being so new to Growing I haven't tried
many St strains yet so I can't really uh
recommend
I do like to grow um Outlaw seeds that
has been one of my favorite braiders um
I do like like the Forbidden fruits um
the Mery Berry they're I really like
that gassy fruity turp is what I like to
grow yeah I like the gassy fruity
citrusy I like that more than like the
dessert super sweet but everyone has
their own preferences they're real
skunky gassy fuy like I love that that's
that's that's all me for
sure so misconceptions I want to ask you
this question here there's a lot of
misconceptions when it comes to Growing
Outdoors can you give us uh maybe a
short list of things that people think
of the case when it's when growing
Outdoors but it's actually not the case
so growing
Outdoors um again people think it's it's
very easy but it it again it's not the
case weather has a big factor to do with
it so um always have a backup
plan for bad weather so if you know it's
going to rain have tarps ready if you
know it's going to be windy get ready to
tie them down uh because that kind of
stuff can definitely ruin a good uh
plant all right and then do you have any
advice for beginners that are just
getting started growing Outdoors so I
definitely um never give up like I said
previously is one of my big things um
learn from your Stakes again don't be
afraid to ask for help um and when you
do ask for help you always got to keep
in mind that everyone's environment is
different so their advice might work
great for them but it might not work
great for you and that's okay just keep
looking until you find what works great
for you and till you dial in um your
craft but yeah definitely never give up
and be patient that's my biggest don't
cut too early yeah it can be kind of
difficult when you're so excited you're
like oh is I ready to harvest ready to
go and then cting too early that's a
common mistake yes that is my biggest
fault so you have a pretty simple
straightforward approach to Growing
Outdoors now I know you mentioned that
you've been growing Outdoors for a
couple years now so arguably you're in
the the kind of newer stages of growing
Outdoors but you keep it very simple
right using the soil that is at your
local Marsh from down the street or
wherever using inputs manure based
inputs locally right you're growing
Outdoors you don't have to worry about
lights lights on or off or any
controlling the environment conditions
because that's all done naturally
outdoors you haven't come across many
pests fortunate enough for that right so
not using any cover crops or mulch
layers just keeping it simple all around
and you're getting all the way to
harvest I think this is a good example
of a way that you can keep it simple and
get to harvest a lot of folks will do
the process and they'll overthink things
or they'll complicate things and they're
getting the same result that you're
getting and they're doing a lot more
work so yes I think that comes with
being um again a new grower is I haven't
gotten to over complicate things yet and
I'm trying very hard not to I'm trying
to stick to if it's working stick to
that what works works
what you don't know you don't know and
just doing things trying it out and and
having fun with it yeah awesome well
that was a quick episode we uh they're
straight to the point I appreciate your
time coming on to the podcast today can
you tell listeners how they can find you
and what you have upcoming in the future
I could be found over on Instagram under
C bunny grow I could also be found over
on YouTube under hir the Community um
official
um where that we do interviews every
Wednesdays and every Fridays it's come
and show your grows uh you could also
find me on Spotify under uh
hgtc uh
podcast um recently we had hor savantes
on so that was a great episode I got to
meet him in person as well so that was
pretty awesome um I'm excited for the
future because we will have a Mila the
Queen coming on sometime in September so
that will be uh it's very exciting time
and I definitely recommend to tune in
and not miss out well I'll definitely
have a link to C Bunny's YouTube channel
down in the description section below so
you can easily get there and give her a
subscription shout out to all the folks
that are supporting on patreon long list
of you I'll put it on the screen right
now the folks that are in the producer
credit tier there's a couple different
tiers that you can join but 100% of what
is donated through patreon goes right
back into the podcast so everything that
the you need to pay for in order to run
this podcast gets paid through the
patreon members so thank you so much for
your support there
patreon.com grow if anybody does want to
support appreciate you coming on and
spilling your process with us and hope
you enjoy the rest of your day uh thank
you so much for having me on I greatly
appreciate it and thank you to everyone
for tuning in all right peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode