foreign
[Music]
all right here we go AC Infinity sent me
their ion grid t24 full spectrum LED
grow light and this is the unboxing
this LED grow light has a coverage area
of two feet by four feet it pulls 260
Watts from the wall at full power and
has an efficiency of 2.75 mic moles per
joule
[Music]
first thing out the box is the user
manual and it has things such as
installation instructions programming
instructions and more
this Peg has things for cable management
such as zip ties and velcro straps
two light ratchet hangers
two uis extension cables
two stainless steel brackets one for
each side of the fixture
two DC extension cords
two driver adapters
and there's a 12 foot power cord
attached to the fixture
[Music]
picture has 560 diodes all of them are
Samsung LM 301h
[Music]
it also has a digital controller that
you can use to program light schedules
mimic sunrise and sunset and dim the
fixture
as you can see here I have it hung in my
grow tent this is a two foot by four
foot grow tent also by AC infinity and
the clip-on oscillating fan that you see
here is once again by AC Infinity I'll
have a link to the grow light grow tent
and oscillating fan down in the YouTube
description section below although this
light is for a two foot by 4 foot grow
space they make this grow light for
other grow spaces as well they have the
t22 for a two foot by two foot grow
space they have the t-33 for a three
foot by three foot grow space and they
have the t-44 for a four foot by four
foot grow space I'll link all of them
down in the YouTube description section
below along with my discount code Mr
garage 15. that discount code works on
both Amazon and the website
acinfinity.com would you like to see
another video where I go over the
controller settings in detail let me
know down in the comments section below
thanks for watching and I'll catch you
in the next video