AC Infinity just launched a brand new
series of grow lights called the ion
frame that sent me the ion frame EVO 3
LED grill light which is great for a two
foot by four foot coverage area but they
also have grow lights for other size
coverage areas such as the EVO 4 for a
3X3 Evo 6 for a 4x4 and the evo 8 for a
5x5 hey everybody welcome back to my
channel for those of you that don't know
me my name is Chris aka Mr grellit and
today I have a product highlight video
for you this is a brand new series where
we highlight some of the best gardening
products on the market today in this
video I'll talk a little bit about the
ion frame LED grow light while I
unboxing it so you can learn more about
it and see what comes in the Box I do
have a discount code for this grow light
code Mr Gold 15 it actually works for
all AC Infinity grow lights and all of
their products in their Hydroponics and
grow as category as well as the grow
accessories category upon opening the
box I noticed that they put some
information on the inside flap
first thing out the box is the driver
this driver can be mounted on the
fixture or can be kept off the fixture
and kept outside of your grow space for
example pulling out the grow light from
the box and then opening up this smaller
box inside this box is a uis M2M 10 foot
cord uis MTM two foot cord stainless
steel wire hangers
a wire tie set hook and loop ties
various screws for mounting and some
rope ratchet hangers here is the driver
extension cord
these are the driver brackets in case
you want to mount the driver to the
fixture here's the schedule controller
where you can set daily light schedules
and even simulate sunrise and sunset and
lastly they include a user manual and an
intro to Growing book the first thing I
noticed when handling the light is that
it is extremely light the frame is
actually magnetic so you can pair the
ion frame with the ion beam light bars
if you choose to provide supplemental
full spectrum or UV light the unit pulls
280 Watts from the wall at 100 the
diodes on this fixture are Samsung
lm301h Evo diodes this is Samsung's
latest diode and is a top of the line in
Horticultural lighting these diodes are
very efficient and algorithmically
placed on a bar style fixture to admit a
uniform full spectrum of light
efficiency comes in at 3.14 micromoles
per Joule wow in the user manual they
show you how to hang the fixture
although I personally like to do it a
little bit differently I use two light
ratchet hangers only simply Loop each
light ratchet hanger over the top of the
grow tent bar then connect each end to
the grow light as I'm doing here this
makes it so much easier to move the
light up and down by simply holding onto
one side of the fixture while pulling
the Rope it is part of the uis platform
so you can connect it to a controller 69
or controller 69 Pro I'm using the uis
mtam cord which is 10 feet long to
connect from the driver to my controller
69 Pro I then go to the AC Infinity app
tap on the controller in my 2x4 for Port
2 which is the port that the light is
connected to I'm changing it from off to
schedule I'm then setting the start time
for when the light should turn on then
setting the stop time for when the light
should turn off easy also to set the
dimmer percent I'm going from schedule
to on the setting of six shown here is
60 I'm going to change it to 5 for now
which is 50 lastly I'm going back to
schedule so that the light will turn on
and off according to what I've said AC
Infinity recommends hanging this grow
light at least one foot above your
plants and to set your percentage to 40
for the seedling stage 80 for the
vegetative stage and 100 of the
flowering stage the height will vary
based on the plant you're growing they
show the coverage area for all of the
LED grow lights in their Evo Series in
their user manual like I mentioned
earlier I have the EVO 3 which has a
flowering coverage area of two feet by
four feet but they have other grow
lights for larger spaces such as 3x3 4x4
and 5x5 there is more to this grow light
so for more information click the link
down in the description section below
I'll place the link in a pinned comment
as well what do you think about this
grow light let me know down in the
comments section below I hope you
enjoyed this product highlight video if
you have any suggestions for other
products I should highlight in a future
video let me know thanks for watching
and I'll catch you in the next video