what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and today i've got an unboxing video for
you look what we have
here brand new not even released yet ec
infinity cloud ray s6 clip-on fan
developer edition i'm so excited for
this one i actually had the idea for a
clip-on fan that connects to the grow 10
clips onto the grow 10 back in 2016 a
few years later there was a company that
released one however the quality wasn't
really that great a lot of people
reported problems and of the few i had
one of them died out which the company
replaced and then another one that
became extremely noisy over time so not
really the best quality but this one
right here ac infinity is known for
their quality they're certainly changing
the game with this one ac infinity
actually sent me over this one and they
hooked up my viewers with a discount
code you can use code mr growit for 15
off on their website and if you're on
amazon you can use code mr grow at 15 to
get you 15 off okay now let's unbox this
thing
all right so nice looking box i have
here you can see on the side adjustable
tilt digital 10 speed ip44 temperature
and humidity proof
[Music]
on the side here it says ec motor runs
quieter more energy efficient and has a
longer life span than ac motors it's
ip44 rated components are sealed to be
highly resistant to heat liquids and
dust digital control pwm technology
enables a wider range of 10 fan speeds
and uis compatible connects to uis
controllers for temperature humidity
cycle and schedule programs
first thing out the box is a user manual
in the user manuals you'll find some key
features
installation instructions programming
instructions and warranty information
here is the circulation fan color is
black
pretty sleek very lightweight you can
see the buttons on the back
one is for the different fan speeds and
the other one is for the oscillation
feature there's a power cord it's pretty
long i believe it's nine feet long
here is the grip clip so you'll attach
the circulation fan to the grip clip and
then you'll be able to clip this onto
the pole of your grow tent
in this bag right here there's a few
different things an extension cord
there's an adapter dongle
a cable tie
and a cable mount
it's actually pretty easy to put
together all you have to do is unscrew
this piece that's on the grip clip
you'll slide in the circulating fan
slide that piece back through and screw
it together
and then it's good to go
okay so in my two foot by four foot grow
tent this one's actually by ac infinity
as well
clipped it onto the side of the tent and
pressing the button to turn it on
you can see there lights up on the
different speeds so i pressed it six
times it's on speed six out of ten if i
pressed it eleventh time it would turn
the fan off there's a spot there for the
uis and then the button there for
oscillation feature
super quiet fan i was really shocked by
how quiet this fan actually is
stays close to the grow tent doesn't
take up much space and yeah i can't say
enough about this this is very high
quality i will leave a link to ac
infiniti's website down in the
description section below this fan isn't
released yet but once it is i'll put a
link down there as well and one thing to
mention is my discount code works for
all ac infinity items not just as fans
so check out their other products while
you're there that's pretty much it for
this video if you enjoyed it please
click that thumbs up and i will leave it
at that until next time
peace