welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this
episode number 166 in this episode I
interview Matt Powers he has been
gardening for 16 years and is an author
educator and a citizen scientist he has
advanced knowledge when it comes to
gardening and that's what we're going to
get into in today's episode we get into
a variety of topics such as pH redo
potential mic risal fungi mushroom
blocks the 24-hour light cycle and more
if you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow both of those channels will be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who help
make that go possible thanks to aec
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their instant potting mix a
soiless grow medium made from 100%
organic cocao fiber it's buffered and
triple washed to maintain pH stability
and reduce salinity it comes in a 2 lb
brick which expands to fill up to a 3G
growt click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about their instant potting mix and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and the website AC infinity.com
stash blend several additives in one
blend so you no longer have to buy
individual bottles check it out at stash
blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with Matt Powers how you doing today I'm
doing good thanks for having me yeah
thanks for joining the podcast you have
been on my list for many many years and
to be honest with you you're one of the
more advanced folks it's taken me a
while to kind of build some knowledge
that I'll be able to ask you some more
advanced questions I feel like because
you do have just a huge like very
extensive background when it comes to
not only teaching but being an author
educator we're going to get into that
we'll do an introduction here but after
that I'm just going to fire away some I
say difficult questions but we'll we'll
we'll get you some uh decent questions
here that are going to make you think I
hope heck yeah can you introduce
yourself maybe just tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah so I for many of us in
this space uh John Kemp when I recently
interviewed him uh he said this and I
completely resonated with it is that
many of us got into this because of
Health crisis I have Crohn's and I
started trying to eat better uh I
discovered like organic and stuff right
around the time period when I met my
wife uh and I was I was 131 lb I'm
almost almost 180 lb just give you an
idea I'm 6 almost 6'2 so it was 130 lb
uh I couldn't really hold on to any
muscle uh no fat and my wife also got
cancer uh second year into our marriage
and when our our firstborn was 1 years
old and food was the thing I could
control cuz the doctors were were liars
and they caused more cancer than they
than than they didn't solve anything
they cut things out uh and then they
created more cancer and so it was a real
difficult time because I didn't know
what I could do I started trying to do
the Gerson Therapy and then I just
tapped out financially and mentally and
cuz I was the person doing the juicing
and the like like removing the fibers
from the food
and two years of that I went crazy uh my
wife was like please stop you know
you're stressing me out more than I
think it's helping uh and and and so I
started gardening but it was 140°
soils you know I'm in the Foothills
above Fresno so a bare soil in 112
degree ambient compounds so I thought I
was crazy for gardening I felt like I
had a choice and so I started gardening
the initial year before the animals
found it looked really good and then the
second year they all found it and
destroyed it and then my father-in-law
brought
in uh bull manure that wasn't finished
so it all turned into we seeds and then
great vegetative
overgrowth so it was like like a huge
amount of trial and error and it was all
motivated by getting my kids safe food
and my wife food that can actually heal
and nourish her and also food that I
could eat so we really were
bound and and had really these
strictures on our life that forced us
into this in many ways but we feel
really blessed uh and retrospect because
we made all these choices really early
on with our kids and our own health and
our own marriage you know we because of
our health issues we decided to have
kids early turning 43 this year and uh I
have an 18-year-old and a 14-year-old
right so so we made these decisions and
gardening was one of them and it's just
a a fundamental foundational piece of
our lives and and yeah it all started
with the health thing incredible yeah
I've heard that story that you've
mentioned uh in other videos that you
filmed you have a really extensive
YouTube channel for those that haven't
checked out his YouTube channel I'll
definitely have a link in the
description section below one of the
things I know you for most I feel like
is the book this regenerative soil book
this is my go-to if anybody is looking
for an advanced type book highly
recommend this book it is uh definitely
one of my favorites I made sure I think
this one think you signed this one and I
also have your microscopy book yep
signed on there so um that's pretty cool
yeah you must have gotten it from me cuz
only people people will buy them from me
I sign and you know the thing is that's
my 23rd book in the permaculture
gardening era of my writing I wrote
science fiction books before I wrote
visual music theory books for
guitarists and and even before all that
in high school I wrote like fantasy
books I never finished but but I've been
writing and trying to figure this out
and trying to serve and and you know do
all these things as a writer the whole
time and so a lot of people see the
success of that book and they're like
holy cow and I'm like yeah that's I'm 10
years in that's my 23rd book there's a
reason kept hitting and hitting until it
broke through you know so so yeah no it
definitely was uh an incredible journey
to to get there
and then it was wild because I wrote
that book for gardeners for Growers and
then John Kemp really kind of leaned on
me to make it more for
farmers and so I was like oh yeah I can
figure out how to generalize and jump
out and like then have it go to scale
and
bulk and when I did that I didn't
realize the impact it would have and how
because I stretched the the context from
small scale to large scale and then went
from micro to macro
how much it would help people and
because I've got my own interpretation
in its nature I'm looking at other
people saw other things in it than I saw
because I'm simply showcasing nature and
and so it it went beyond
me and so because I focused so much on
just showcasing nature it allowed people
to go deeper than even I I learned from
my students I learned from these other
farmers who were using it and applying
it and it's been this wild gift not just
to to me and my life cuz it's a it's a
bestselling top selling book uh but also
to everyone that has has reached and
touched and where they've been been able
to apply it so so yeah no I just want to
give context so that it's it it was so
much like led up to that moment and and
it in it had this power that transcended
so much of what I was doing and and
hoping to do
and so it just uh it's just a wonderful
thing a wonderful thing that happened
it's an incredible book and I talk about
it all the time in my content and I
refer people to it all the time because
it is really that good and uh I'll
probably have a link to it down in the
description section below so people can
easily get to it and check it out but
yeah let's get into some gardening
topics so I have a wide variety of folks
in here as far as experience levels so I
got a lot of beginners intermediate
probably less advanced to folks on here
but yeah I just want to give you a heads
up on that right off the bat so you're
aware who the audience is I want to
start off with ph so we know that the pH
in the rizosphere can be two points
different than the pH in the medium so
for example if it's 6.5 pH the
rizosphere could actually be 8.5 pH or
be 5.5 pH so because of that many people
are completely ignoring pH talk to us
about pH and do you recommend pH
measurements or not okay so I totally
recommend pH measurements what you have
to recognize is that they expend energy
to do that so the energy is protons from
photosynthesis that are used to change
the
pH right and so they're expending energy
so the closer you are to the Goldilocks
range around that route the more energy
you can dedicate to other
things and those protons can then go to
releasing more nutrients releasing more
things and also energizing the microbes
the other thing to think about is the
roots the root Marist stem cells which
are the tip of the root that's the most
acidic point and then as the root ages
it becomes more and more
alkaline so so the tip is is the most
acidic and then it's more alkaline as it
goes and so you get a gradient
effect and what happens essentially
is the tip is where everything happens
so your your root is boring through the
soil and it's actually seeking nutrients
and in microbes like hunting that's why
it does its whole Behavior it's
following the path of lease resistance
following water Pathways nutrient
Pathways and it's breeding microbes
sucking them in and removing their
nutrition and then pushing the remaining
microbes that survived this process
out or they're staying in cuz they're
endites and they can just release
nitrogen to hang
out while it's doing that it's releasing
all this this energy and it's acidifying
it absolutely but it's causing a
nutrient release because it's a
differential so it's like yeah it's two
points different so what's that going to
do it's going to release the nutrients
that are held there comfortably in that
pH now not not because you lower the ph
it's loosening things up and releasing
them you have a depletion Zone following
that tip there's like a wake of
depletion this is where micro risal
fungi when partnering it sends its Hy
out past the depletion Zone and gets
more nutrients this is why partnering
with it expands the the actual root Zone
we talk about we talk about it makes it
more surface area it's expanding past
that depletion Zone and and sucking in
more nutrients um and then transforming
them and bringing them directly to the
root so
and that also changes the pH
relationships further down so if you
don't have a micro risal relationship
the gradient is going to be much more
severe but if you do it's going to be
less so because it's still going to be
able to reach past that Deion Zone and
it's still going to be able to to
release digestive
enzymes and and and and and solubilize
nutrients and bring them in and so it's
a a little bit more complicated you know
of a space than people have you know the
problem is folks don't think about time
and they don't think in three dimensions
and they don't think about stacking
effects so people talk about like oh
it's
chemical in part but there's also
biological things happening and there's
also electrical things happening and so
all these things are happening all at
the same
time and so it's hard for people to
visualize
and so that's why I draw so many
pictures and that's why I separate it
and then I put it together in my
teaching so that people recognize that
oh this is all happening in the same
time or like the soil food web
conception where there's like microbial
manures and then they get eaten by the
plant that doesn't happen like that's
not happening instantly that happens
over time and the manur build up in the
soil so that when the root arrives and
depletes that zone it gets those manures
so again time that's like a huge span of
time we're talking about maybe years to
build up that
effect um so that it's
noticeable and then we've got things
that are happening sandwich right on top
of each other you know what I mean
so just like rise of fasi is happening
and micro risal fungi can be doing its
thing at the same time which is to a lot
of people are like but but how you know
um yeah yeah they they they allow things
to flow through themselves uh and it's
it's it's remarkable and it's actually
uh visible you can see it so so Roots
they acidify they're releasing we have
to remember that it's an it's a release
of energy they're creating a
differential but they also can create
that differential with a lot less effort
if you're closer to the goldilock
zone and and and the goldilock zone you
know depending on your plant type could
be very different blueberries are going
to be way more acidic than your corn and
and that's going to be way more acidic
than your you know beets right and so
you need to know your goldilock zone for
what you're planting or you plant in a
mix and know that some of these things
are
simply uh hormesis hormetic stress in
other words like when we work out we're
stressing the body but it makes us
strong stronger but if you work too much
way to be like ripping and hurtful you
know there's a there's a right level of
stress cuz we need that
differentiation and so I Do cover crops
and I mix in some things like amaranth I
mix in some things like
brasas and I also have nitrogen fixers
and more and more evidence shows that
just doing nitrogen fixers a whole field
of nitrogen fixers not a good
idea so so that mixture that that I
created this mix called the five cousins
because they kind of all like Bully each
other a little bit like cousins do and
it's like that's good for the soil you
know what I mean and it's like the the
you know the buckwheat stealing nitrogen
from the cow peas and the cow peas are
going past their normal expression of
nitrogen fixation to this genetic full
potential because they're like it's not
piling up properly and so you get this
push and pull you know uh daon ratus
Sops up all the available nitrogen in
the soil so that the cies are like
there's nothing here and then they're
like going extra hard and so we can
create those kinds of antagonisms and
differentiation and all those kinds of
things to stimulate things to a
degree but we also have to make things
as easy as possible for the plants cuz
when the plants have
discretion and they have excess funds
they invest them so what do I mean by
that well they create those chirpings
they create those they create the smell
taste they create all the things that we
love and associate with food are only
created at that like abundance level at
that oh everything else is taken care of
now we're going to taste good everything
else is taken care of now we're going to
smell good and that's where all the
medicinal qualities happen too and so we
really need to recog recognize that the
next stage of our growing of making food
into Medicine of regenerative egg is
getting to that place where we're not
stressing plants out past their ability
we're stressing them out just enough so
that they're like H immune system on you
know they're like we're going to trigger
you know their immune system like ISR
right and and we can do that with just
applying microbes that are that are
beneficial so it's like the right kind
of Strat
is an
Endy that it's already inside it to a
small degree but now we amped it up and
so it's at a beneficial degree it's like
probiotics you know for plants but it
triggers them and so it's in that
goldilock zone of
stress so I I I really I really value
all these paradigms I do test for pH
even though it's a it's an
average it's you're going to have pH
jump four to nine in most most healthy
soils like micr meter to micrometer but
it's we're always taking
averages uh and and and I always do that
that gives us a really good window and
then when you're looking at at your
tests and you got your parts per million
or you have you know even even your
microbes and your biological testing the
pH gives you so much context and then
reference point so you may not test for
redo but if you know what it is you know
know that it's drier or wetter right and
so you could be like wow this nutrient
is being locked out it's in the soil I
added it and the plant's not getting
it oh man I think we need to water
more or oh is the intern watering too
much because they usually
do too much and so and so you you can
track these things down when you have
the understanding and pH isn't
everything like I said you got to think
eh too to know what's missing why when
things don't add up and then pH is also
contextual for instance if you are doing
compost and it's hot compost please pH
test it you're going to go oh it's
ph8 huh that's very high in nitrates huh
well just slow down for a second because
no one was testing this until I started
bringing this up and and they're adding
it and so they're maybe they're at
they're in California they're already pH
7.5 do you think adding ph8 is going to
help
no no and they're like most of my Gess
has 50%
compost and it's like you know they just
shifted their whole garden up to pH 7.8
and now everyone's unhappy you know and
they're locking out all the nutrients
and the nutrients are there but it's
alkaline and oxidized so it's locked out
so it's like really critical to have
these things in our in our knowledge so
that we can evaluate things in a way
that actually serves our comprehension
most of what I teach is allowing people
to see things as they actually are for
themselves in such a way that you don't
trust me bro stuff instead it's like if
you see this you know then test and you
can see and like you can actually prove
it to yourself and it's like not me
imposing not us imposing in it's us
asking questions that lead to answers
that we can then test and
verify and and that that has been the
like the the turning point for me in
many ways and that's why this book I
think is so valuable because we
co-create the future together as people
read this because they can see and test
and see it for themselves and then make
decisions based upon what they know
now so it's been it's been awesome and
and the the database that I'm creating
now is so that people can see all these
things in the open because before people
take actions they take a test and well
all right well people take a test at the
beginning of the season they take the
action then they eat the thing at the
end of the season and go we did it and
they don't test anything else right I
want to do before and after testing with
the actions in the middle so that we can
see what you added when you added it in
your methodology in reference to what
happened before and afterwards and then
have that be ubiquitous so that
gardeners Market gardeners small farmers
midsize and large scale farmers can see
the gradient of
expression and they can see also like
they can kind of see the future too
they're like looking at the market
gardeners applying regenerative methods
that they haven't figured out how to
scale yet and they're like H and the
people who figure that out will be and
that's viral I want things to become
viral uh and it it really goes back to
just a simple idea that when we have
have enough information and we look
through the lens of
nature Things become self-evident and
people make really good decisions uh
because people then are empowered and um
when people have the right people have
the right lenses and ability to
critically think and the right
information sets they make really good
decisions and that's always been my
experience so so that's what I'm doing
um I'm really trying to stay out of the
way
and let nature do the talking and the
showcasing and the speaking for people I
mean h there are things I've discovered
in microscopy that I haven't said
publicly yet and I'm letting my students
discover uh and and they're all like and
I'm like yeah I know but this is part of
the reason why I'm want the database
because then everyone's going to see it
and they're all going to go wait because
that's how we really cause massive
change big change and fast so that's you
know that's that's kind of like the
larger Vision around all that stuff we
need
testing really interesting stuff there
now you mentioned redo and eh and I feel
like that's something that we should get
deeper into I don't think a lot of
people really talk about it what is soil
Redux potential and how can gardeners
manage
it so yeah if we go back to high school
chemistry we remember redo or maybe some
of us don't remember high school
chemistry and that's okay Redux is a
combination of two words reduction and
oxidation it reals reveals a fundamental
truth about life on Earth and all life
and
biology if you look up oxidative
stress it's the
underlying symptom that leads to disease
Cancer all all illnesses are linked to
inflammation and inflammation is
oxidative stress they're one thing so
you're like whoa why what is oxidative
stress what is oxidation how why is it
inflammation when we take a piece of
wood and we light fire to it and it
combusts it is flame right because it's
oxidizing the
wood so oxidation is the liberation of
energy so oxidized food would be dried
out
food so so and and then an oxidized soil
is dried out soil all the energy has
been lost and and and and and water is
also uh in many ways functions as energy
or a storage of energy uh for so many
things in life if you think about
photosynthesis as one input um light
into photosynthesis as one input water
is the other and they're doing
hydrolysis and they're releasing protons
energy so so we have to recognize that
oxidation is the loss of energy and that
means reduction despite it sounding like
we're reducing something Matt reduction
is the gain in energy I know the
chemistry folks you know they like to
confuse us and have their own little
Ivory Tower of comprehension and
confusion uh many many different
branches of science do this right
language is a way that back you know
hundreds and thousands of years ago you
would keep people out of your special
circles
so what they've done is made it so that
people don't realize that their bodies
are energy
based it's the drop in energy in our
bodies that leads to cancer and all
these different things this is why Dr
Zack Bush when he tests for people and
their health he's testing the charge on
the outside of their cell he's testing
the Redux potential of the
person and that's how he's telling how
healthy they are so energy is fun
fundamental to everything and in fact if
you go back 50 years ago I sing The Body
Electric um everything was energy based
and there's all this stuff and then
suddenly all these people came into that
area of new discovery and became very
woow woo around it and then created this
Kickback reaction and uh and then it
became something that no energy ooh no
one talks about that that's that's
pseudoscience meanwhile all the chemists
know energy is how everything is done
in fact the charges on the outside of
every you know nutrient and element is
actually the the combination lock piece
that fits into each reaction inside the
plant is the charge difference that
creates the POS the ability for it to
finish that that reaction so everything
is energy based so Redux is the gain and
loss of energy and the potential to to
to to to it is the holding of the energy
and also the potential to exchange
energy so so if it's oxidized well
there's not much energy and so you can't
exchange much energy you know what I
mean it's already been
lost you know it's it's it's already
been burned right there it's you know
it's Ash now it's lost all that BTU
right all that potential burning energy
and so that's really what we're talking
about is the actual energetic
possibility and potential of your soil
and what's what I've already said is
it's linked to
moisture so your soils are all dried out
and
oxidized they're going to La they're
going to to be lacking
energy now this doesn't mean that it's
um all alkaline if you're in
Montana Idaho and Eastern
Washington you're going to have a lot of
aluminum and you're going to have things
in the soil that are going to Mineral
wise be
acidic but it's all dried out high high
desert and all that makes it
oxidized so so that's a more difficult
environment no doubt because as you draw
down the pH you start loosening things
and releasing things there needs to be a
lot more um solar organic matter a lot
more buffering and then you need to be
testing your pH regularly so that you
don't dip too much
um and and and you stay in that
goldilock zone in that situation the hot
compost that's ph8 is exactly what you
need right to keep it in the goldilock
zone right and so it's very very
personal very specific to our climate
when we're talking about eh and pH and
for a long time I taught
because my original Mentor you know
Elaine Ingam taught that there's this
there's this line of secession between
the desert and old growth forest but
that's actually a diagonal through an XY
P eh chart so I've been teaching just a
bandwidth of Truth and it's
true but all those montanans and
idahoans and Washington folk were
like
oh what the heck is wrong with my oil
then cuz it made no sense to them and so
so it's really important to understand
your situation from both pH and eh cuz
when you put them together you go oh I
see where I am actually that's why
that's that way and then when you're
doing testing for minerals and you're
super high in aluminum or super high in
something else you know that's causing
antagonism that's causing alkaline
alkaline uh state
I mean cuz we got Limestone Bedrock here
so it's like when it rains it's like and
you flood the field you have an
alkalinizing effect actually because it
all that acidity then combines with the
with the Limestone below and the
Limestone goes well there's a lot more
of me than you and then and then it re
Rel lowers your pH so so we have to
recognize these effects are real these
effects are trackable but these effects
are also you can deal with with them
because like you said at the beginning
you need to be worrying about the pH
around your roots what if you added
things in the root Zone and this is what
a lot of people are doing that are
acidifying in the root Zone that give
the plant the energy it needs to to
change it
itself um and so there's a lot of
options on how to do that but the reason
we pay attention to redo the wetness and
dryness of a site is we can easily go
too far in both directions
and depending on where we are it's going
to release completely different things
and so understanding where you are tells
you what dangers you have and and where
to push and and and then what techniques
will work best for you you explain that
better then I think anybody has ever
explained it to me before so I
appreciate that one now you you
mentioned a little bit about micro risal
fungi and I'd be willing to bet that the
folks listening in there's there's got
to be over 50% of the people are
supplementing they're adding in some
micro isal fungi into the medium I feel
like a lot of the grow hom Growers here
that are tuning in majority are hom
Growers indoors versus Outdoors now that
being said you hear a lot of people
talking about the application of micro
isal fungi if they're using a product
it's often said that sprinkling it
directly onto the root Zone during
transplant is the best way to go about
it now I've heard people saying that
it's significantly less effective to mix
those microbes into water micral fungi
into water and then do a soil drench
with it of course is it is it less
efficient doing it that way versus
sprinkling directly on the roots or or
what's your take on that so I have more
information that is going to provide a
new way so the way the microbes work
with seeds is they they they partner
immediately with the root coming out and
then they stay in tandem with the root
grow
so let's just like think about surface
area and
application if I take the seed and some
of you are going to be doing tiny seeds
right not like big pea seeds or bean
seeds so you're doing a Tiny Seed think
about the surface area and requirement
of microad fun and realize that if it's
there when it begins it's going to be
there the whole time
okay so giving them the initial microbes
then is the smart hardest move because
you use the least amount product now
imagine you have these already grown
roots and you're putting trying to dust
these things on them and you got a speck
here a speck here a speck here a speck
here well those could they'll go in and
do their thing if it's um not spores and
if it's uh propagules which is sections
of root that are inoculated from last
year that's effective not spores spores
would germinate when they want to and
spores are in case we get ice ages so
think about that it's in case everything
goes wrong so you're going to put
propagules so MCO
apply um
momax uh
MOS by extreme garding those are three
that I know that do that and then it's
going to start from there there and
there and there it's fungi so starts at
the point of contact and then spreads
out from there
so if you have powdered like the
wettable powder WP MOS from extreme
Garden or if you just take mortar and
pestle to like your your your uh
pelletize stuff and then add it
on then your seeds are going to
germinate and it's all going to just
immediately bond with it and then it's
going to keep Pace with it as it grows
and it's going to become this big old
plant meanwhile how much did you
actually spend per plant very very very
little cuz it just coated the seeds
and this goes with all your microbes
think about inoculating with the
endophytes that can reproduce inside the
plant because they're feeding off photos
synthetic um sugars and nitrogen that
comes in and and so so they're actually
completing photosynthesis and nitrogen
synthesis so they're replicating so
again we add these in
initially and if you're doing lactic
acid bacteria that's an Endy that also
stim micro risal
bacteria so you're partnering with all
these different things and they're there
the whole
time so it's about it's about timing and
it's about like being able to visually
verify this like I can just and most
people don't have this yet my a lot of
my students do but I can just turn on
that light that little blue light and
then I can see that it's that's bound to
the seeds so I could take five five of
my seeds inoculate them with the powder
put them in a a like do a germination
test put them in a folded over napkin or
paper towel that's damp inside a p uh
plastic Ziploc bag that's not fully
closed on a warm surface and let it
germinate and look at them under the
microscope and I can see that they fully
take so I can verify this for myself
that yeah Matt is telling the truth BEC
and that's what this is the kind of
science I like because then everyone
else can verify it for themselves and go
yeah yeah I've done it that's how it
works and and that is the kind of ground
we all can stand on and then we can put
the images on the database and then have
that replication play out in in public
and so all the people who have paid more
money than my programs who have
cognitive dissonance and
cannot let go they'll be able to let go
cuz though I have seen people literally
look at things and go you yeah but how
do you know and I'm like well you can
see it and they're
like right but you could have made that
picture and I'm like oh
dear because the reality is it's like we
can all just go look you know and but
there's a lot of people I mean we live
in a day and age where there are people
that have see things right in front of
their face and can't see it and I think
part of that's the food I think part of
it's cognitive distance you know they've
invested in a way of thinking they've
invested in a methodology or a program
that they paid more money you know um
but we also see it playing out all over
in science and everything so we have to
create things that are self-evident and
also so that people can move forward
with confidence improvising and
innovating in such a way that uh the
science moves forward in a viral way um
so so I mean if you think about
automobile that's how it worked there
were a thousand different automobiles
before the the Model T emerged and it
was in that innovation in that back and
forth that really citizen science you
know that created that and right now
we're the product all of us are the
products of uh indoor
Growers for 30 40 years doing the R&amp;D
that we're all benefiting from and again
it was citizen science again it was
people doing the work and and then
sharing it you know these these forums
with secret names and everything you
know for years getting that feedback
loop and that's that's all I'm doing you
know that's all I'm modeling it
afterwards is allowing that natural
feedback loop that natural replication
science and that V virality to quote
Brendan my brenon Bard um to actually F
uh change uh so so that's you know
that's that that's that's what's
happening and that's what I'm building
incredible yeah so if you're you're
basically saying coating the seed before
germination is actually effective so if
they're doing the paper towel method
they could just put the seed on the
paper towel sprinkle a little bit of
micro isal fungi on there it'll then
germinate and they can plant that
directly in there now what if they
instead germinate I would I wouldn't do
that for like my planting like I would
do that to verify that my micro isal
funga that I bought is good and that
also proves to ourselves that it it
stays in tandem as it grows and we're
like once it's inoculated it's
inoculated right um but that's how all
the plants evolve to do it and so being
able to see that and verify that a tells
you this is something that's strong it's
a good inoculant it works and then B I'm
going to be able to inoculate all my
seeds this way and that's what I care
about so if you germinate a seed and
then just dip that Tap Root in microle
fungi and then plant it that's perfectly
acceptable and then would you Rec it's
not recommended to do any micro isal
fungi applications after that because it
kind of grows with the plant what I
would do is I would actually not cuz I
mean they're so sensitive those those
emerging Roots I don't mess with them so
what I would do is I would do a soak of
the seed with micro isal fungi and
endites like effective microbes em or
the equivalent which is yeast purple on
Silver bacteria and lacad bacteria would
do those three and then you would soak
it and so it would be soaked up into the
seed the seed would have nutrients and
have microbes and all this stuff
happening all at the same time cuz I
mean with em there's some leftover you
know car carbon from the molasses and
stuff so it soaks that up it has that
extra energy and potential and then you
plant that so after like you know like
an hour to six hour this a smaller seed
mat so I would do an hour to two hours
uh of soaking maybe Max two hours I
would observe uh different I different
seeds are going to behave different ways
the larger the seed the longer the soak
the smaller the seed the shorter the
soak and so I would soak it in that and
then I would so what I do is I pour off
the excess and then a lot of this
inoculant heavier especially if you let
it settle for an hour so it's at the
bottom like a slurry and then I would
mix it with the seeds and it would like
subtly scarf ify the seeds a little bit
you know CU a little bit grit to that
and get that all deeper and embedded and
coated and then I would plant
those so it's and and you're like oh
Matt well you know I'm doing a large
farm and can I just add it as a powdered
Amendment like my rise oia you can
totally do that that's totally okay uh
though you want it to stick as much as
possible so maybe adding a little bit of
water or a little bit of binder or
something um maybe something that's damp
maybe something like um like compost or
something as a carrier that'll keep it
in contact with the seeds uh so that it
goes in together and is right there but
most of us if we're doing small scale
we're doing plantings that are indoors
we're going to be babying our seeds we
paid a lot for these seeds and so you
you can do that slurry and then you can
plant them
individually and again doing the testing
on your micro risal F before you you use
it on everything proves to yourself a
that you made the right purchase and
then B that this is going to be a good
inoculation let's go for this understood
yeah thanks for breaking down the
details on that one good uh good
actionable advice for sure I want to
flip it up and talk about something
which I believe I heard on either your
Instagram or your YouTube channel and it
was in regards to mushroom blocks like
oyster you had mentioned that it
actually kills off beneficial nematodes
can you talk to us about that yeah it's
pissed off so many people so so the
reality is there are papers where
they're deworming cattle and sheep with
oyster mushroom mycelium and oyster
mushroom blocks with which are mycelium
right and
so my idea was like oh this is a natural
dewormer this is awesome because the
effect of this are
temporary what happened was people that
didn't understand the science around it
got really mad and I actually had a a
person that used to be a friend freak
out and kind of lose their minds cuz
they thought I was assaulting their
business cuz they they do mushroom block
gardens and it was super upsetting
because it's like they don't they didn't
even hear me uh and then it became this
weird thing it it was just really wild
uh and so I don't know if it was this
was like a a thing that they attacked
because of other things in their life
but it was weird they they basically got
so upset because they felt like I was um
saying that the oyster mushrooms are
going to destroy soil the reality is
oyster mushrooms you know when you add
them to the soil will kill all the
nematodes that it comes in contact with
but this is the same with RI this is the
same with turkey tail like a bunch of
mushrooms so I'm not talking out of
school this is already published and
well known and so I just was sharing the
information I didn't like invent it I
didn't you know what I mean and so it
was shocking in that regard but then it
was like they're not even reading cuz I
literally posted like after I said that
in the next post another article showing
that within days and up to like a week
you have that die off being replaced by
a flush of beneficial nematodes
so it's sessional so just like when we
like clear the Slate the Right Way
beneficials come back and not you know
like using chemical ster sterilizers
causes bad things to come back when you
do a biological reset you have good
biology come back so it I I I I was
really bothered by by their attack um
because I you know I've been trying for
years to help this person person uh and
and so it just was something that I put
out there because it's true um it's
functional you can be deworming your
animals and you could be using a
microscope and a hemocytometer and
checking their stool to make sure that
you dewormed them you know what I mean
and then you can verify with the same
microscope that those soils go through
that dip and come out the other
end so so I was sh ing something that I
knew that people if they just took the
time could verify could
follow and and then could do confidently
and what you know my good friends um
like uh Angel shatz who literally has
given out thousands of these blocks
heard me say the first part of it and
she literally was like that's awesome
Matt I never knew that and had no qualms
nothing was upsetting to her she's the
best so Central Texas mology has been
giving out these blocks but she knows
the gardens are beautiful and so she
knew because of her experience that it
was okay you know and and and so then
when I followed up with that second
article she was like ha that's what
we're seeing on our end you know because
she's in she's in my college she's
looking at all these things with open
eyes and allowing nature to speak to her
and so um it is the case that they do
that it is the case that we can replace
all this dewormer that people are using
which hilariously enough is often
Ivermectin
but so so so we can use oyster mushrooms
and replace all that uh and get our
animals manure to a place where we can
use in compost again you know some
people are using dewormed compost and
it's ruining their compost and they're
all freaked out so we can do incredible
things with natural modalities but so
much of it is U not letting hysteria
fear or just like unbridled uh optimism
you know so that people generalize like
the winds it's like we got a
contextualize the winds so that we see
the caveats the ranges of expression and
also just the limitations right so so I
definitely brought that up and I
definitely uh saw Wild reaction ction to
that uh
and you
know it was it was sobering because I
mean yeah they said crazy things they
were saying that I was stealing the the
microbes with the the microscope by
seeing them and naming them and I was
like well no actually someone already
has named all
these we're just seeing who they are and
yeah so it's uh it's it's quite a world
we live in uh right now there's a lot of
people who are freaking out there's a
lot of people that um need need to go
out in nature and
meditate I hear you yeah that's that's
one thing with content creation where
it's you do your best to try to share
good information that's going to be
valuable people and there's always that
somebody who takes spins it and turns
into something negative and then you get
attacked for it it's just that's part of
the job I guess right
yeah definitely I I was a high school
English teacher and I've seen it all um
and most of the time the attacks really
just our Reflections on the other person
and the hardship that they're going
through uh and uh like this person I'm
talking about I wish them nothing but
good things uh I really hope that uh the
animosity
drains all right so uh switching it up a
little bit here I want to get your
thoughts on the 24-hour light cycle now
we have so many folks out there that
they want to get you know grow plants
faster get a better result so they're
putting their indoor plants on 24 hours
of light and zero hours of Darkness now
the night time when you know lights are
off that's when sugar Transportation
happens so my question for you is does
it happen less with that 24-hour light
cycle therefore negatively impacting
plant growth at all yeah so so we have
to remember that um there's a wide range
of plants and plant expression right and
so um there are some plants that are
going to grow really well in the land of
the Midnight Sun right um and they're
going to have mechanisms that allow them
to just keep going and
growing uh but we're also we also have
respiration plants respire and they only
do that when they're
resting and
so my instinct is that you'll get
different
things like we're going to get different
relationships of microbes and
different different like uh tpin and
different medicinal qualities from both
these methods I want to see side by
sides and full workups on like the parts
per million on the Felix the tpin all
those things uh to really to really say
and you're going to probably have
differences in expression in in terms of
like where the plants from so let's say
you're growing a a you know a certain
plant from like the Himalayas right
those are going to behave very
differently from like the same family
from Africa right uh and those genes do
exist in strains right and so what I've
seen in practice with people doing
indoor grows from them flushing things
to like the artificial light cycles um
they're all trying to imitate or short
uh cut
nature why do we do light depth we do
light depth because we're trying to
imitate the end of the season when
there's less
light and so if we take that as the as
the guiding principle you got to do
what's most natural and like that's the
principles behind this I literally ask
what's most natural how did nature
originally do this um and and and
whenever we see amazing plants um and
we're obviously talking about a specific
amazing plant um there's abilities of
these plants that kind of blow our
minds but what's best for the plant and
what creates the best product is really
the question the plant can do crazy
things like for instance Canadian
Growers when I talk to you know Joy
Beckerman you know Joy no uh she's the
reason that the fiber cousin of the
plant we're talking about is legal she
was the lawyer who fought the federal
government sponsored by you know John
rach's nativa so that they could do that
those
Foods um she had me talking to Canadian
Growers and they're they they figured
out that there's no ceiling on
nitrogen so they're raising the
synthetic nitrogen Higher and Higher and
the plants are getting bigger and bigger
and because they don't care about the
seeds they only care about the fiber
they're like well no one's going to eat
it let's go oh and so it doesn't matter
if it's high in nitrate it didn't matter
that it's like anible it didn't matter
that it never left vegetative state and
went didn't go to reproductive and
didn't form seeds so they're just like
throwing it on there and the soil is a
desert they're destroying the soil so
the whole narrative around like well the
soil will be saved by this
plant no no no no no not the way they're
doing it not industrial industrial
growers in Canada and they're modeling
for
Americans and so so we have to recognize
that there are aspects where you can
abuse the
system but is that good because it's
like yeah you get two years where it's
like
phenomenal and then your soil is dead
and then they have to rotate
it and then they go to this thing which
is so depressing and this is most of the
Pacific Northwest this is most of Canada
they're like well we'll come back in 3
years and farm it like abusively again
and then we won't be able to do it for
another 3 years but then we'll do it
again and so they leave it follow and
they let it Let It Go and they show back
up and then they abuse it again and then
they like leave it for 3 years meanwhile
they could be farming that patch of land
every year and having the soil improve
their products improve and their bottom
line
improve so so that's really like a lot
of what I'm doing is getting people to
re recognize the
Holistics involved and to be able to see
and and understand the longevity of
their
operation because yeah there there
there's there's plenty of things that we
could do that could stretch it this way
or that way or or push things you know
but asking what's most
natural has a holistic
effect you know if we're not burning our
soil you could amend and use that soil
again or you could treat and then
ferment and use that soil again like a
bunch of things you could
do um you could even dump them all in
the backyard amend it tarp it ferment it
and then use it all again you know
there's a bunch of things that people
can do uh that they're not doing so so
that's that's really my instinct when I
hear like that like can we go all the
way it's like you know plants are pretty
amazing they're want to survive and like
we can do like these hoops and make them
do these weird things like I mean they
have plants now like imitating plastic
leaves you and they're like the plet can
see and it's like yeah the plantet can
see cuz it's trying to survive you know
what I mean he like you know we're
torturing things to see how far they can
go we're like we're doing all this stuff
instead of saying like what would be
best for the plant and letting that
speak to us and looking
at what that actually looks like because
when a plant's super healthy it's going
to actually invest in the Next
Generation so when a plant's super
healthy partnering with micro razal
fungi it actually leaves the hyul uh the
hyle expression of the fungi around the
cell so you'll have like this lipid Rich
H that's just sitting there and that's
what becomes the inoculant when that
root dies for next year so and a new
root touches it and inoculates the new
root what happens in hard times is the
plant actually reabsorbs that and it
eats the lipids as energy because lipids
are like the best form of energy the
longest lasting form of energy we know
it's fats right so it's an investment in
the micro risal fungi that they can
liquidate in times of stress or they can
pass on to their children next year
because who's going to be growing in the
soil of their root Zone most likely
their seeds their
children so plants when they have enough
are going to do things that are going to
enrich the soil going to have secession
and and and and regenerative quality so
that it goes happens the next year the
microbes are preserved for next year and
passed
on they're going to do things that we
can't do or we don't want to spend the
money you know in the time doing and
they're just going to do it for us so so
so that when I hear that and I think
about that that's really what I see as
like what we should shift to got it yeah
reusing the soil for example that's
something I've been reusing the same
soil now for seven gross and uh you know
ever since I started really getting into
Organics and realized that it is
possible to reuse over and over again I
have been and I've been saving so much
money it has been has been awesome
keeping on that topic when you kind of
re-enrich your soil with minerals I want
to get into your recommendations a
little bit what minerals you recommend
gardeners use to replenish their soils
did you recommend things like rock dust
seaweed compost manure what's your
general recommendations I know you
should get a soil test and see what is
missing from your soil and then kind of
go from there but generally speaking
about the types of minerals what do you
recommend and also what should Growers
avoid yeah so there's a few different
things um someone just in Florida
recently figured out how to remove
arsenic from
seaweed so all the fears around like
arsenic buildup in our soil because
we're using seaweed uh we're going to be
able to figure out and avoid right I
really like seaweed makes sense we think
about lead Zeppelin rubber plant you
know mountains flow into the sea it's
true they do and that's where all the
minerals have gone right and so bringing
those back is really effective I really
like ocean minerals I love the idea of
farming the coastline to bring the
utopic down and then return those
nutrients to the soil in such a way that
sticks this
time and so I I I I really I really like
that cycle because it permacultural it's
like the bior regional solution right
we've had all this runoff all this
phosphate nitrogen fertilizer from all
the Lawns it's actually right there
killing things in the waters like you
know Coastal Florida right and it's like
if we just do vertical farming we just
do seaweed farming uh crustation farming
you know those things can be turned into
fertilizers very easily and then and and
not only that it can be done in such a
di di DIY way crean natural farming you
know all we can do all this uh and so I
really like that as a modality and as a
generalized system for fixing a lot of
things
I like rock dust but with the caveat
that if you don't look at what's on your
rock dust test you may be adding a lot
of
aluminum so right Dan kitridge years ago
said whatever local rock dust you have
is the best rock dust uh not in my
experience I've had too many students um
and I've seen too many examples of of of
local areas that are just like no you
know might want to bring something else
in uh and that's okay but it's knowing
that moving forward with open eyes I
think that is the most critical so look
at the test readouts and different Kelps
different seaweeds are from different
areas and they have totally different
readouts so so I would look at those
things um and
and you know depending on what you're
growing if it's a heavy feeder I would
be doing you know I really like bunny
manure bunny manure has been like the
gold you know and so many operations
that I've done I've been like where's
the local FFA or FAA instructor who's
doing rabbits uh because it's like they
have the best manure um of course you
got to monitor what they're eating you
got to know what they're eating and what
they're giving them um but man I I I in
terms of manure goat and body manure cuz
it's cold it's not already hot Marco
microbes Marco's microbes originally
talked about how he loves it too uh I I
I think that's a great great usage um
great great Amendment but in
general other than like those minim
minimal mineral kind of amendments I
really rely upon microbes cuz so much of
the the nutrients that we want are there
they're just not solubilized and the
only way to solubilize them is either
crazy extremes with ph or something or
you just simply have microbes and the
microbes are mining it and unlocking it
and solubilizing it transporting it
transforming it and that autonomy that
we give to the microbes and the plant
and the soil microbes it creates this
economy that that ends up feeding things
better and and at such a rate and
complexity that we can't imitate
so I really like seaweed I like rock
dust with a C yet that if we don't look
we don't see and we can easily get
bitten so do that all right some good
recommendations there well Matt this
talk has been awesome I mean I'm sure we
could go on for another two hours if we
really wanted to but we're going to wrap
things up here can you tell listeners
how they can find you and what you have
upcoming in the future yeah if you go to
the site regenerative soil science.com
it'll have and you just type that in
it's a lead link so I I'm not super
sophisticated the internet I figured out
like lead links um and they all lead to
my courses and all my stuff on the
kajabi platform so I've got like 15
online courses I've got you know over 24
different books but regenerative soil
science.com is the place to start with
everything it's a place to go next month
I'm going to be starting regenerative
soil microscopy the new season and the
month after that we'll restarting
regenerative soil both those are open
though so you could hop in and take it
self-paced and then you have lifetime
access to the lives so you could join us
at any point this month I'm going to be
doing an advanced permaculture student
online session as well so all this stuff
where I'm zooming out and talking bi
regionally and talking about all these
kind of things that kind of thinking
started there so that is Advanced
permaculture
student.com uh you can check that out
too uh but if you just type my name in
Matt Powers into Google not B for some
reason but Google you'll just see the
whole first page is me uh and you can
find me at mattow soil on Instagram on
Twitter and uh just type in Matt powers
on YouTube and you'll find me there I'll
definitely have a link to your YouTube
channel since this is being posted on
YouTube down in the description section
below so people can easily get to it and
want to give a big thanks to the folks
on patreon
patreon.com 100% of what is donated
through there go right back on the
podcast thank you so much the folks that
being scrolled on the now we in the
producer tier special thanks to you Matt
once again thank you so much for coming
on the podcast I have learned quite a
bit and this is one that I'm going to
replay over and over again to continue
to try to grasp this information and
hardcode it into my brain and uh like I
mentioned we could continue on the
conversation what I'm going to do is ask
the audience if you want to see a part
two with Matt drop it down in the
comment section below put part two and
then maybe uh maybe we can get him back
on here to to continue the conversation
heck yeah all right everyone thanks so
much for tuning in and I'll catch you in
the next episode peace out