welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody if you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into the garden
Talk podcast this is episode number 118
in this episode I interview Big Daddy
buds he is a content creator with over
100 videos and 6,000 subscribers on his
YouTube channel called The Grow the
stairs and this episode is a little bit
different than any of the other episodes
on this podcast we're talking gardening
content creation although this episode
isn't focused on growing plants I still
thought it'd be valuable to hear how
gardening content is created gardening
channels he watches gardening channels
he recommends other people to watch
where gardening Condit will be 5 years
from now and so much more if you want to
see highlights of these podcast episodes
search Gard talk clips on YouTube that
is a channel dedicated to short
bite-sized clips of these episodes I
also have a garden Channel where I have
over 130 videos showing the plants that
I grow I'll have that channel linked
down in the description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
cloudray Gen 2 oscity clip fan their
next gen clip fan has been re-engineered
to provide a long-lasting motor and
customizable air flow for all stages of
your plan's growth cycle it features 10
speeds and 10 Dynamic win modes to
simulate outdoor air flow in links with
uis controllers for Wi-Fi app control
click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about their cloudray clip fans and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and the website AC infinity.com
stash blend I've been using stash blend
for over a year now and it's awesome one
of the things that I really like is that
it saves me money it's a whole bunch of
different input puts in one so I no
longer have to go out there and buy a
silica bottle then a separate seaweed
bottle beneficial bacteria then a
separate one for microle funi all of
that plus more is in this one blend go
to stash blend.com to learn more about
it and I also have a link down in the
YouTube description section below Mars
Hydro check out their new ad light
series UV ir and deep red supplemental
lights it's said that UV light will
increase the production of secondary
metabolites and that it also enhances
plants resistance to pests and diseases
irite is said to stimulate stem growth
and flowering as well as induce plants
to enter their sleep stage quickly deep
red light is set to promote flowering
and fruit development discount code mhad
light works on their website mars-hydro
docomo and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with big daddy buds from the grow under
of the stairs how you doing today I'm
doing great man how you doing I'm doing
good man man thanks for asking when we
hop right into an introduction tell us
about you a little bit about yourself
and how you got into gardening uh well
uh my name is Big Daddy buds you know I
got the channel called the ground of the
stairs of course uh and I'm a content
creator been doing this for about 18
years now started on YouTube right along
when YouTube started when there weren't
that many people doing it yet when it
was kind of weird to do it so uh I made
a living off of this and now I'm trying
to do it over here in this side of the
garden that's awesome man this episode
is going to be a little bit different
you know when we were first talking
about things usually what we do is we
talk about Garden fundamental things
that you can do in the garden so the
folks that are hearing this can
potentially take some of those practices
and Implement their Garden you talked
about how you potentially want to get
into content creation talk about content
creation and at first I was like I don't
know if this is really going to fly but
I thought about it for a little while
longer and I'm like it's gardening
content creation it totally relates to
everything this podcast is about you
know you're in the gardening niche
we can totally get into that in this
episode and I think I think people will
definitely gain some value out of it
something different you said you wanted
something different and so uh yeah glad
to have you on here yeah you know what
it is I figured I've seen so much on
your channel and so so many people that
are educated already uh that have phds
that do this for a living uh and have so
many different angles to come at uh when
when we talking about this plant that I
just felt you know let me bring
something different to the table what I
have experienced is my PhD is in content
creation and it has to do with the plant
and it still has to do with how we
distribute information about the plant
that we love so I figured you know let's
bring that to your channel and hopefully
uh give the people a different Viewpoint
of what it is that we do well said and I
think it's going to open up a some eyes
too because there's some some things
behind the scenes as content creators
that we do that like the viewers don't
really realize like how much work gets
put into it how we are so suppressed and
so on and so so forth so we're going to
get into all that today which which is
really going to be a fun conversation
but how did you how did it all start for
you how did you get into content
creation I guess something that content
creators all have in common is H the
need to to want to be liked and accepted
and I feel like I had some of that
growing up I also uh have led a kind of
very interesting life I've done a lot of
things that I think are cool and I've
always wanted to share that with other
people so when I was younger I used to
travel a lot that was what my first
channel was about was about traveling
and showing all these experiences that I
would have I I used to send all these
videos to my friends you know like B
them like look what just happened to me
look at who I just met look at this look
at that I'm in this hotel I'm here and
they would get tired of it they don't
really want to be bothered like that not
everybody's into that type of stuff so I
started uploading the content to YouTube
and people started following I found an
audience and since then I've been hooked
and you started a long time ago you said
I mean before we even hopped on here
started recording you had mentioned 2006
is you your first YouTube video which is
a very long time ago so pretty
impressive there yeah I had to look back
on mine 2007 was the first one for me I
upload 10 videos in 2007 definitely not
gardening videos you know completely UNR
related me do just doing crap with my
friends but uh it's wild to see like how
far it's come and um just thinking back
at all the work that was put into it
it's wild right it's crazy because back
then it wasn't cool to be a YouTuber at
all it was actually kind of weird you
know and there was a very small amount
of people that would even put themselves
out there you know once you put yourself
on on screen it's like it's there
forever so back then even 10,000 views
felt like a lot because no one else was
doing it you know so I remember those
times were so weird I wanted to be on TV
and now look how things have changed
instead of me wanted to be on TV it
seems like TV people want to be on
YouTube like U movie stars have their
own YouTube Channel and this wasn't like
this before it would be kind of weak
even for like a a famous person to have
a YouTube channel back then so the way
that things have shifted uh is is has
been amazing to me yeah it's been crazy
to have kind of like an open source to
where anybody can go in there and upload
videos and make it impact get scen and
so on and so forth versus uh you know
back before YouTube you had to be kind
of an actor or some sort of celebrity to
to get on camera so uh yeah it's kind of
up the floodgates there for anybody to
really have an opportunity so for your
particular channel the grow under the
stairs can you talk to us about that
channel like what it's about when it got
started your style of content over there
so on and so forth okay so so the reason
I started growing at home the medicinal
plant that we all love was out of fear I
found myself one time we all have these
stories I found myself in New York
needing to to buy something because all
of my usual people didn't have it
anymore and it was one of those sketchy
situations where you're in one of these
dark rooms with some people that you
don't know they're all looking at you
funny their weapons on the table there's
that type of deal and you're you're not
part of that world I just want a little
something to relax and uh I had that
situation happen to me I I I got scared
straight I came back home and I said
listen I'm going to have to start
growing because it's not worth it to
keep doing this so this was back when it
was super illegal and I had to go into
New York to do that so I figured you
know what I mean if I'm going to take a
risk let me take a risk and start
growing at home from there I'm a content
creator by trade so I it just became
part of what I did I'm like let me start
a channel then and let me uh showcase
what I'm doing and I I teach as uh at
the same time as I'm learning and I'm a
comedian so that would be my angle that
that's what I could offer different to
this community it's like let me make it
entertaining so that while you're
learning you're also laughing I feel
like that's a a nice niche that within
the niche that I'm carving out for
myself and nobody else is really doing
that you know what I mean you have that
unique style of both education and
entertainment humor that not many people
are doing and and one thing I like about
your content is that you're you're
showing the plants right you're in your
garden you're giving them valuable
information but you're also showing a
little bit about your personal life as
well you know you're showing your cats
you're showing you going out to dinner
you're showing this massive snowman that
you saw uh down the street that broke a
record I think in Anchorage Alaska which
you live now so seeing like all of that
together it's like it's different than
everybody so I think you have some
really good content and you also grow
some really good looking plants you grow
some fire and you know another thing I
was thinking about before we you know as
we were planning this is like okay if we
start talking about content creation
some people are going to want to
actually know how you how you grow your
plants they're going to be disappointed
like oh man I want to know how to grow
his plants like him you know so maybe
we'll we'll do something like that that
in the future to where we do talk about
you know break down your style of
growing and stuff like that because I do
have a feeling that some people are
going to be like what the heck I want to
know how he grows fire you know yeah
yeah but you know um the videos
themselves are about that I do weekly
videos that that display weekly what the
plants are doing and I feel like a lot
of people have strayed away from that
kind of content because you know YouTube
restricts what they show and who they
push if you're showing certain things
and saying certain things but I think
it's still important to to look at these
plants as they develop and Tackle these
problems that arise on a week toe basis
you know I love the whole uh from C to
harvest videos but I feel like there's a
lot that gets missed you know you're not
going to throw in that you
sprayed iron for an iron deficiency for
one day and it fixed it in in in a video
that's an hour long from C you know
you're not you're going to forget you're
not going to forget in a weekly video so
I feel like uh uh I'm going continue
doing this and hopefully people would
just learn to have a little bit of
patience and come and just look at the
plant and learn from it uh even if it's
like little by little you know that's
how they grow it takes time it takes
patience so that's kind of what I'm
offering too yeah really good point
anybody could go to your channel which
OB have linked down in the YouTube
description section below or if you're
on one of the audio platforms just
search for it the grow under the stairs
search for it on Youtube it'll pop right
up and you could see his grow and he
does weekly content and uh yeah you
definitely learn from him there and to
touch about the other the other thing um
when when you spoke about sharing my
personal life in the videos and
everything like that it's kind of crazy
and and I wonder if it's the same for
you since we've been doing this for so
long but when I started the the the
videos that I was doing were about
travel you know about my traveling and
my experiences after that I switched to
Comedy you know I started doing the
comedy after that I switched to to
cooking I was doing cooking and and now
I'm here in this gardening space but all
of the stuff that I learned before I'm
able to apply it here so I am using
comedy still you know what I mean I'm
just mixing everything together is it
the same for you where you get to it's
almost like you you're acquiring skills
in every step of the way and then you
end up here you just know how to do so
much you know what I mean yeah for me
kind of like I started out doing just
dumb videos with my friends uploading
those and then I actually did I was
recording prank videos on the Strip here
in Las Vegas going there filming hidden
camera prank videos and then yeah I
guess some of the stuff I think some of
like more like the behind the scenes
YouTube stuff like the titles
descriptions tags all that stuff that
kind of get you farther over reach that
stuff can be applied to this so yeah I
totally get what you mean by what you've
learned before definitely comes over to
this same Niche because you're still
making videos yeah I totally get what
you mean by that and I I completely
agree so you're wearing a mask right now
and you wear a mask in all your videos
what made you wear a mask you need to
HDE your identity are you doing things
illegal over there or or what and will
your face ever be revealed or is this
always gonna be like that I am not a
crook well you know there's there's two
reasons for the mask the the first one
being you know when I started this it
was it was super illegal where I was at
so uh I didn't want to get in trouble as
I kept doing the videos the law started
to change in my favor
but then there was the second thing and
that's that I've actually found success
before in content creation so I didn't
want to mix the audience that I've
already created on another space with
this audience because I already know
that that audience uh is not all there
when it comes to the medicinal plant
that you know I like to talk about but
hopefully uh as things keep changing
people will be a little bit more
accepting and then I'll be able to take
off the mask but it is something that
I'm I'm really close to wanting to do
you know like is in my heart I want to
be able to uh show uh share with the
public and you know and intermingle with
people and you know it's kind of fun
when you're in an event and somebody
says hey you know I saw your video and
everything like that and I missed that
so hopefully I be able to be fresh face
with y'all soon yeah that'd be cool
that'd be cool to see a face reveal and
I get what you mean by you know you can
be recognized by people in your that
were watching your old videos right some
might not like that regarding the the
niche that we're in also I actually can
totally relate I had to hide my face
when I first started making Grill videos
cuz I had an employer right I was afraid
I was a manager at
amazon.com and so like I was afraid that
my associates were going to be
recognizing me and they be oh you grow
weak huh so it's like H you know so
hiding identities I I can relate yeah
and you know it's funny
um when I first started watching trying
to to learn to grow I was actually
watching you guys so I was watching I
was watching pigeons actually you know
and that was before he showed his face
that was the OG pigeons that was the
pigeons that I you know that I was uh
that that I could relate to and and and
it was it's crazy
cuz the reason I was able to figure like
the mask out is because I'm like hey if
he could do it without a face everything
else I had been doing before had been
with my
I've never seen anyone do it like that
you know like without a face so I'm like
if he could do it if they could do it
then I could just you know I could do it
too and actually that gave me the
courage to start that's actually a
question I was going to ask you is where
do you get your inspiration from was it
it seems like part of it was pigeons was
there anybody else that kind of inspired
you um Mr Canucks I I you know I
definitely uh watch a lot of his videos
and the fact that it seems like he put
so much work into it you know there's
people that really do like they they go
to work work on their videos and and to
me that's inspiring because it makes me
be better you know I don't I don't have
a problem watching a hayen video uh or
Mr kug video and
seeing uh that their images look so Cris
you know and and and trying to adjust my
settings so that my stuff looks that pis
I love to learn from everybody that I'm
watching so inspiration that's why I
want people to to continue showing their
plans in their videos I want to invite
more creators that are doing this at
home to come to this space and normalize
it not only uh for for the sake of the
plan s but for the sake of people like
me that want to learn you know whether
it be uh uh how to get better shots of
the plant you know how to get those
those really close triome shots that
that you see on Instagram you know like
all of these things to me are important
uh or are interesting to watch and I
want and and I keep learning it from the
people that I watching so the more
people we have in this space the more
Talent the better that we're going to uh
continue to be you know as far as the
video quality and for me that's
important as a as a content creator yeah
I totally get what you mean there are
thousands of content creators in this
Niche now I making gardening videos
right who do you watch I mean you
mentioned pigeons you mentioned hay
again you mentioned Mr canox who else do
you watch I watch a bunch of people from
small creators to those the big names I
mean I made a list I didn't want to
forget nobody but uh how we grows I
watch debacco University Rosa green uh
like I said Mr Canucks Mr uh hom gr TV
build the soil Bill Ward you know what I
mean a whole bunch of people if you make
content uh about the plant I'm probably
trying to learn from you some way or
another like either by watching your
videos as far as quality and how you do
your thing or watching how you grow so
of those content creators or you can
expand it to even beyond that which one
do you kind of recommend to people if
somebody were to ask you hey where can I
find good content besides your channel
who would you say I mean definitely you
you know I mean you guys should check
out Mr Grow you know check out your groc
series and everything like that but uh
you know I I like I like Mr Canucks man
I think he's a a a person that everybody
could appreciate or in general you know
like you could appreciate the art he
also grows a lot of fire and he's not as
abrasive as me I'm I'm in your face I'm
right here I'm right you know he's not
he's more like laidback so are you which
is a better entry point for more people
I I I think uh if I were to recommend
somebody I would do either you or Mr
Canuck I think that's a great way to go
how about uh Dakota from homeg gr TV you
ever uh you ever tuned into any of his
videos yeah that's another that's
another one yeah hom gr TV you know I
was I was telling him the other
day like like I can't believe the amount
of work that you put in your videos man
like that's another level of of work and
and and I don't I haven't met him in
person I don't know his personality if
it's the same as in the videos but when
I when I watch stuff like that it makes
me want to grab the dude and and and ask
him a whole bunch of questions related
to how his day goes and how he plans
these things because he's really really
uh he you know his work speaks for
itself it's one of those I would
definitely also show that I love
watching his uh his work as well yeah
basement Grow Show is another one that
that's uh really really funny I think
he's the funniest dude on Instagram I'm
not gonna lie so you know I I
I sometimes I'm like man I need to do
this kind of content too you know I want
to do this this is very exciting stuff
this very fun short to the point kind of
jokes uh so I would recommend for jokes
man basement Grow Show on Instagram
that's that's that's right at the top of
the list for me yeah grower Joe is funny
he's so funny I met him in person I met
Dakota in person he is the nicest person
both of those guys are extremely nice
but Dakota is just he's just so humble
and like he's just so appreciative you
know and I give him feedback hey dude
your videos are awesome totally Next
Level if anybody hasn't tuned in to
homerow TV on YouTube search for it and
check out his videos because that's like
the number one guy right now who's
really pushing it to the next level when
it comes to video production
storytelling educating the viewer so on
and so forth so I can't speak uh highly
enough about him he's a a great great
dude another one I would personally
recommend is build the soil I know you
mentioned him right but as far as
organic gardening definitely the the
education is there if you want to learn
how to grow organically just build a
soil by far is is probably one of the
best if not the best channels out there
for sure but this is uh you know like I
like to categorize some of these into
different Cate you know into uh
different places like some of these I
only watch for entertainment purposes
build the soil is one where you're going
to school so you know to be honest I
don't know if that would be the first
place I would send you if you don't know
what you're doing at all H you know I
feel like he speaks about a lot of
advanced stuff and a lot of things that
that
people you know I feel like you got to
have your foot in already maybe to to to
check out Builder soil you know what I
mean I totally get what you mean yeah I
completely agree with you there are
things that be brones beginner walks in
there and starts listening to to him
talk that things might go over his head
left they're walking right
up forget this I'm sticking on my
bottles you
know right yeah I completely agree there
are different categories you know the
humor there's education things that's
just entertainment there talking head
videos there's people that show plants
people that don't show plants you've
actually been pretty vocal that you had
some concerns about yeah say the current
state of content creation you know
people showing plants people not showing
plants can you kind of expand on that
yeah you know YouTube is it is kind of
not clear on as far as like the rules
when it comes to what we're doing
because it says that we're okay it says
that we're okay to say it it says we're
okay to show certain things you know but
then it doesn't it doesn't act like it's
okay
so my problem is when when when us as
creators stop showing the plant we're
also saying it's not okay we're we're
it's like I feel like we're agreeing by
by by doing it so in my opinion I feel
like if it is okay then let's treat it
like it's okay and let's show it like
it's okay let's talk about it like it's
okay instead of doing the opposite you
know that and it's not as interesting
for me to hear people just talk about
something that I love to see part of the
reason I wake up every day is to see the
changes in the plant I actually enjoy
that that gives me energy I'm able to
record the videos because that same
excitement that I feel I'm able to
capture it you know it's easy to go
there and like oh my God look at this
plant and then just put a camera in
front of it that did itself you know and
and when you sit when you take that the
aspect of the plant away for me it takes
some of that excitement away as well so
as a fan I would love to to continue
seeing plants as a person that's a
proponent of the plant I would love for
people to make it more to normalize it
and act like if it's okay you know yeah
I understand and YouTube has changed so
much I mean back in you could monetize
the content you know what I mean you can
monetize and actually get paid for your
work a lot of people don't think that oh
you're just uploading YouTube videos why
should you get paid for it's like it's
work it's videography you know you're
filming you're editing you're putting in
hours you know you saying that oh people
making TV shows they shouldn't get paid
you know oh forget the people who film
there forget the people who do the
editing you know none of them should get
paid they're just making videos you
could say that about anything oh Uber
drivers they're just driving people
around why should they get paid driving
it just doesn't make sense driving yeah
I don't get when people oh you're just
making YouTube videos you shouldn't
really get paid for that don't worry
about getting paid and so like I don't
know I'm kind of against that I
personally I have a clean Channel and
dirty Channel now I have a dirty Channel
which I which I show my plants because
YouTube is very restrictive now
everything has to be 18 plus they
suppress your videos you can't monetize
it right so I'm not I don't get paid at
all right all the all the time energy
I'm spending on creating those videos I
get nothing in return for it you know
now luckily I have sponsors who help
with uh you know funding my content
creation Affiliates uh things like that
so that's kind of helping me keep a flow
but I want to get paid for my work and
so kind of having a clean Channel where
I abide by YouTube's guidelines and and
still be able to reach an audience and
still be able to relay things tiptoeing
around their guidelines in a sense I
think that's a good thing I want to kind
of reach more more of an audience and
not be suppressed for once and and be
compensated for my work so I I could
kind of see it both ways I can see why
people stopped showing plants you know
it makes you put all this energy into it
you get nothing out of it okay well I'll
just sit back and make talking head
videos and then I will get paid for it
you know what I mean so it's like I
understand why everything shifted the
way it did but uh I I'm with you like I
I really feel like it would be nice if
people still made videos about plants
and just yeah I enjoyed that content as
well so and you know even in the the
parody that I did I mentioned uh
specifically that that the way that you
did it is good you have a different
channel that you show your stuff and I
can't tell people how to run their
business you know at the end of the day
this this is just my opinion and I'm
coming at it from a Fan's perspective I
want to see the plant you know what I
mean I want to put on my YouTube and I
want to see the plant bro like that's
what it comes down to so I'm going to
push for that just for my own personal
uh Gams you know but I also think it is
important to to normalize it you know I
don't want to I don't want to hide it if
it's not something that needs to be
hidden if that's not how you feel and
you know like I'm G even take it
further you know we we we come from the
era of where it was really illegal you
know like it it people really went to
jail for this people were the only
reason we even at the point where we
could do these videos is because they're
people that gave their freedom for it
they're people that you know stood
outside and said I'm going to sell this
I believe in this I'm going to smoke
this I believe in this outside even if
I'm getting arrested or whatever the
consequences are so now it's like I'mma
lose my YouTube channel like that's okay
bro like I'm GNA take that L if if
that's what it comes with at the same
time I have a mask on so I don't want to
pretend that I'm toly I'm still not
risking anything you know what I mean so
uh uh I feel like my channel could be
the sacrificial lamb if if if it needs
to be in my case because I saw so many
other people risk so much more got to
keep fighting the fight you know but
yeah it is tough that YouTube is really
suppressing people I mean I actually had
another content creator hit me up this
morning he's like dude I received a
strike what do I do and I'm like what do
you what do you think you received a
strike for and he's like I think it's
because I I promoted Grove bags I'm like
think in my head what Grove bags and he
sent me a clip of his video and he's
promoting Grove bags he has the the the
website for Grove bags he's got his
discount code and he's showing the Grove
bags empty and then he's showing them
with buds in it so YouTube probably
thinks that hey you want to buy these
bags see the bag actual full thing
strike so they think that hey he's
directing them to where they can
purchase it and that's where YouTube has
a huge no no you can't link to anywhere
we can purchase it um also with the
seeds as well you can't link to anywhere
where you can purchase those I know a
lot of people shy away from even talking
about it because I I think you can get
strikes for that I don't really know
YouTube's so unclear and you kind of
touch upon this it's
like it's like we're walking on a tight
rope we don't know which way to go in a
sense how to kind of balance things out
it's it's tough right so I so so so
because of these things like like look
at that right there he says he thinks he
thinks is because of the growth backs
like we don't know it's not even that
clear so that's part of the problem so
because of that I also understand when
when people do choose to just do talking
head videos and and you know find
different ways around it because like
you said you know these these videos
take take a long time to do we do put a
lot of work into it and not only that
man like these videos stay on our minds
the whole time we're working on them you
know it might look like I'm only editing
for for two hours today but I'm thinking
of the storyline the whole day like it's
burning me it's burning it's burning me
down to ashes so I understand when
people change the way they do things
because they need to get paid they need
to make a living off of this so it's
there's no knock to them I'm just again
as a fan and as somebody that enjoys the
plant that's why I wake up uh I want to
see it I want you to show it
baby that makes sense this next question
it kind of relates to just talking about
I think is like you the fact that lots
of YouTube content creators that are are
filming their plants they start a
channel then they disappear within the
first year or two because either the
video gets no traction YouTube
suppresses them they get strikes so on
and so forth what keeps you going you
know I I'm a fan of the videos
themselves at the end of the day uh it's
kind of weird and I know I know I I
don't know if I'm going explain this
well but I know I'm doing the videos I
sit there I edit I record I'm thinking
I'm burning my brain I'm whatever but
once the video is done and it's on the
TV and I'm playing it on YouTube or
whatever I'm a fan of that video like I
am if I become a different person it
becomes magic to me I don't know how I
made it I was there the whole time but I
don't know how that came out it makes
sense what I'm watching make sense and
it's
own apart from me so that is a that's
like a high that I need in general I
need to get that video I need it for
myself that's the main thing I enjoy
what I'm doing uh the second thing is
the response from the public I'm able to
see you know as a YouTube you can go to
YouTube and check your analytics I love
the fact that I made a video that's 12
minutes long and I got 70% retention 70%
of people that started watching that
video ended that video to me I feel like
it feels like this to me it's like man
you guys like what I like we just
connected you laugh probably like I
laughed when I watch it my jokes hit you
know you enjoyed the plan like I enjoyed
it just talking about it it gets me this
is where I come from you know like this
is my video right here like this energy
that's what keeps me going and the
actual creation process certainly get
you fired up as well uh you put so much
into your videos I can tell just by
watching it me being a content creator
I'm like looking I'm watching your
videos I'm like man this is this must
taken him 10 plus hours per video I mean
the amount of uh effects transitions
overlays uh you're doing skits in there
all that stuff the filming part of it
how long does it take you to film a
video edit a video like what's that
process look like for you it it feels
like the whole week you know it feels
like a working week even though it's not
40 hours because it's in my head the
whole week it feels you know it feels
like the whole week but I'll give you an
example the narration part of it which
is the last thing I
do uh to record a a 12 minute it takes
me about one hour to record two to three
minutes of
audio so if that's just what it works
out to and um so that that that'll give
you like an idea of how much effort goes
into into one of these things so I'm
sitting there for hours hours trying to
just come up with silly things to you
know uh and and the rest of the video is
sort of as it happens I record things as
they happen as I need to do them so this
week I need to water change the
reservoir I record when that is going on
you know I don't I don't try to make
anything happen I don't try to change
anything it's more like I want to take
notes of what I'm doing Are there
specific topics that you feel like are
kind of more popular than others oh yeah
for sure so the howto this is listen if
you guys are starting a Channel howto
videos are going to get you everywhere
you know uh how to maximize yields those
type of
videos uh you know those are going to
get you very far but uh you have to know
what you're talking about I think that's
important a lot of people just
regurgitate the same information and
they just want to do it because it gets
a lot of views and they end up putting
the same wrong information don't do that
you know if you wantan to in my opinion
if you're gonna do a how-to video make
sure you it's from experience I think
it's always it comes out better bro yeah
I remember I've had so many of those
videos pop off I think I I did a podcast
episode how to grow dense Buds and that
thing got like like three 400,000 views
I was like oh my gosh how two videos
definitely it was your most popular one
I think that was the most popular one
let me look it up yep 579,000 views wow
that's
crazy so actually can I ask you
something real quick on a personal note
what is it like going outside for you do
you get recognized a lot because at this
point you are like a thing you you know
how does that look like for you oh man
I'm just a small small hom grower you
know no no tell me the truth like when
when you know what is it what does it
feel like do you actually feel it when
you go outside or is it something that
stays on the internet no I mean I've
gotten recognized a handful of times I
got recognized at a Raiders game one
time randomly there was this guy sitting
next to me and he's like looking at me
all weird and stuff and finally he asked
me if if is he yeah finally and he was
like super pumped and stuff super cool I
I was out to eat with my fiance and her
family one time a pretty nice restaurant
too and I'm in the bathroom and some
guy's like hey how you doing today and
he worked there he was a cook like
pretty good and then he you he my just
hear my voice he's like do I know you
from somewhere no I don't think so and
then like later on he came back out when
I was sitting down with the family he's
like oh I do know you you're from
YouTube and stuff oh great how did you
feel man did that feel like cool or are
you
embarrassed uh I mean it's just a little
D you know when you're in front of now
luckily my fiance's family is very
accepting very accepting that could go
go south I guess yeah yeah yeah very
accepting so that that was fine a little
embarrassing to just be recognized in
front of family and stuff but for the
most part everything's super cool I mean
when I went to MJ biscon recognized
probably about you know a dozen times
two dozen times but that's a that's an
event for that you for the thing itself
right yeah yeah but no I mean for the
most part I just I don't really care to
be recognized and stuff and if somebody
does recognize me and comes off to me
and says what's up that's cool like
let's have a conversation about growing
where I said in recent podcast is kind
of a rare breed in a sense like there's
not many people really in the grand
shika things in like this the world that
actually grow this plant so like we got
something in common like let's hang out
and talk you know so exactly yeah it's
cool I think it's I think it's one of
the most enjoyable parts of of the
situation is connecting with the person
so it's it's cool when you connec in per
on the internet and in person is even
cooler absolutely so we talked about
like hot topics things that are kind of
popular what about cold topics that
people kind of don't seem interested in
these days uh well you if you want the
exact titles for the cold topics you
just go to my page and check out all the
titles that I
have but um you know yeah I think it
used to be when I started watching it
used to be week by week that used to be
what people did week one a flower week
two of flower and again I guess those
topics have died down and now it's more
more like the SE to harvest situation
which is more popular but I still like I
said I still enjoy the week to week but
uh those are the topics that like week
number one of flower number two number
three uh you're not going to get much
attaction if those are your titles
you're going to get a very specific
amount of people that are looking for
that specific information and that's it
yeah me personally I feel like things in
veg like the vegetation stage nobody
really clicks on those videos as much as
flower stage right we know it's all
about the title and thumbnail to whether
or not the person clicks whether or not
they watch is a whole different story
but to get that initial click which is
what shows up as a view on on YouTube
showing a flowering plant you're going
to get a lot more clicks than you would
just showing a veg planter or even a
Seedling plant although some Seedling
videos do pretty good like if you say
week one video you typically does pretty
good for me you know week one seedling
just starting a new grow you know people
want to start from the beginning and so
those videos do pretty good but the veg
videos haven't been doing good good for
me flower videos do a lot better seed to
harvest videos like you mentioned do
really really well where people can see
see everything you know from seed all
the way to harvest so yeah there are
definitely some some cold topics I'm
trying to think of other coold topics I
think like unboxing videos are cold now
like nobody really clicks on those yeah
it might be too saturated and you know I
think you guys spoke on this uh but uh
the light technology seems to have
slowed down as far as like how uh fast
it was moving so it feels like now you
kind of getting the same light over and
over again as so now where I used to
watch Channels and I didn't mention them
because of this that that used to just
review lights uh now I'm not watching
that anymore because this seems like
it's the same the same uh we we maybe
reached a little ceiling for it so
perhaps that's why unboxing
videos have also maybe fell to because
the the the equipment doesn't seem to be
advancing as fast as it was just a a
couple years ago yeah I completely agree
yeah it's the lighting technology just
just in the past year in particular it's
kind of gotten a little little boring
all these companies are releasing the
same diodes and not really doing much as
far as upgrades and it's good on price
it's good it feels like the pricing is
now getting better because everybody has
the same uh components but so that's
good but as far as yeah unboxing and and
the excitement of a new toy you know it
that that excitement is not there right
now for me do you think it's still worth
it to create beginner type content on
like basic topics like how to germinate
how to train plants how to set up a grow
tent when there are like a countless
number of other of these types of videos
on YouTube already you know it's like
saying you know the same reason why
movies keep getting
remade uh it's a new generation there's
PE new people being born every day so
you know I think there is a space for uh
let's say even somebody that's watching
this video right now that's thinking
about joining YouTube and thinking uh
what what what can I contribute what you
got to contribute is your voice and your
style the way that you're going to say
that information to others so I think it
is important to still make those videos
in your way cuz uh there might be a
person that specifically learns the way
that you teach so is your duty to do
that for that
person and uh not only that
but if you're a content creator then you
moving off of energy of of excitement
I'm very excited every time I set up a
new tent I'm very excited every time I
plant a new seed because I don't know
what it's going to be you know what I
mean like I'm excited to see what's
going to happen why not record that and
share that every time I do it every time
yeah you make a good point there for
sure you especially as legalization
sweeps Across the Nation here it's like
more and more people are new you know
it's it's more and more people coming on
board so having these basic beginner
type videos is is valuable and I think
with YouTube the ranking comes into play
like you know how old the video is some
old videos certainly are still going to
show up on the ranking when you search
for them but newer videos could
potentially show up newer on the ranking
so yeah no you bring up a good point
yeah and you you should always be
looking for new content you know even if
it's the same thing again uh you're
doing it again it's new you know it's a
new day you might do it a little
different maybe you're you're using
different kind of people P than you used
before you know like anything you
anything that's different could be
beneficial to somebody watching to a to
a beginner just like you said uh with
legalization just about to well it keeps
getting better for everybody I'm not
going to say it's going to Fally be
legal because that just keeps taking
forever but um every day you get new
people that are interested so so be
there for those people just like
somebody was there for you yeah
absolutely well said we've been talking
a lot about YouTube and YouTube videos I
mean that's where you know me and you
are kind of our passion that's what
that's what our focus is on but there
are other communities on other platforms
right what are your thoughts on
gardening content on the other platforms
like Reddit Facebook Instagram so on and
so forth man you know
um I haven't had the best of luck on
other platforms I just joined X I just
followed you over there so I heard that
X is actually uh uh very friendly to
creators on on our side so you know I
got the verifi badge and and and let's
see is if that's a that's a fact so I'm
excited for that Instagram has been bad
for me you know I've had profiles get
banned a bunch of times uh and and and
you know it makes it it it's to the
point where you can't really they just
ban you they don't even tell you why you
can't contact anybody it seems like you
can't uh plead your case to anybody it
seems like so definitely don't recommend
that one uh Discord has been good so far
you know um those are the ones that I'm
using at the moment I focus mostly on
YouTube though so that's where my bread
and butter is I've tried to go on
Facebook they slap me on the wrist
before on my page on there I still have
one but they don't like some of the
content I post there I tried joining a
lot of the Facebook groups because
there's like a lot of grow groups and
man I have not signed up to a group and
left a group so quick before the
toxicity in some of those groups I just
I could not stand you know somebody post
a picture of a plant they're like what's
wrong with my plant and you get 50
million replies from people and some of
them are hating on the guy them day with
the
Forum it's so crazy man it's like so
much mixed information and just hate and
H same thing with Reddit like haven't
really had a good experience it's just
at least for me there was negativity a
lot of negativity on there and it just
it didn't feel like a community and I
don't want to speak it like it's a
blanket right I'm sure there are good
communities out there within redit good
subreddits I know there was one science
back one I think was like R Bud science
which had some good information on there
they're really trying to break things
down there but uh yeah my experience on
those platforms hasn't been that well
Instagram they're always penalizing
people and and they they have this
review program when you appeal stuff
that's automatically automated I don't
even know if real people look at these
posts that get appealed and stuff and
you just get shot down and accounts get
deleted and then they come back and it's
a mess over there so yeah I I personally
haven't had a great experience on some
of these other platforms as well but
looking into the future how do you see
gardening content on platforms like
YouTube five years from now I I think it
could be to the point where we're
cooking you know how you have a bunch of
cooking people showing you how to cook
and it's a thing and everybody does it I
feel like this has a potential to do the
same I don't know if it's I don't know
if it's really going to go like that but
this has the potential to do the same I
feel like uh once hom grow is legal if
you consume the
plant I don't I don't see a reason to
not get into it yourself and just have
like a little tent or something going
you know like a the the expenses that
you would have to pay to get any grow
going pays itself back if you're
somebody that consumes already just by
The Grow that you're going to get so for
me because of
that as as long as we the content
creators keep doing what we're supposed
to do and getting people excited about
the plan I feel like we could get more
people joining and and and making it a
community just like the cooking
Community is just maybe in a smaller
scale but um there's there's so much so
much business opportunity and in in what
we're doing so many ways to monetize
channels that I just don't understand
how YouTube is not letting it happen
there's medicinal plant companies that
want to actively uh uh uh they want to
advertise in our channels that's a
that's a money Revenue that you know
you're not letting us have you not
letting the company do what they're
supposed to do why would you get in the
way of that you know there's so much
there that's left on the table right now
that I can't wait till that starts
happening where YouTube says hey we're
going to allow these companies that want
to be in your channel to monetize their
product in your channel that's going to
be so good I can't wait for that to
happen do you think this space is
oversaturated or do you foresee
oversaturation happening in the future
it's like anything else you know just
just like the cooking thing it's the we
can go right back to that you know
you a matter of fact let's let's take it
away from that I watch a whole bunch of
different content creators so for me if
you love The Plant if you really want to
learn you're going to eat this up you're
going to consume and you're going to
keep wanting that information from as
many different people as you could get
it so while yes you could have a bunch
of people doing it you're only going to
have a certain amount of people that are
going to be doing it good you're only
going to have a certain amount of people
that are going to be giving quality
content you know as far as how it looks
how it sounds and people that that you
know that actively uh trying to find an
audience not everybody's going to do
that so I'm not really worried about
that as long as you focus on doing good
work you're going to find an audience
eventually you know cuz cuz it's not
like I'm only going to watch you and
then not watch high again you know
because I watch turpy he I'm not gonna
watch Bill Ward like it doesn't matter
I'm gonna watch everybody I love it you
know I totally get what you mean yeah
there are a lot of content creators
coming into the space some have really
good content starting brand new starting
fresh some content isn't so good but uh
but they try what advice you have for
those that are just getting started
creating gardening content just in
general I guess it doesn't have you know
not not only gardening but just since
I've done so many different types of
content uh what has always motivated me
is is showing what I'm excited about I I
saw somewhere that if you want to be
interesting you have to be interested so
just show the people what it is that
you're interested in you know it becomes
very easy to put that on camera
if you think that oh my god I've never
seen this on a plant
before then then record that and show me
that that excitement is already there
you already saw it you don't have to
make it up so for me the best advice is
that is show me what it is that you're
excited about and I'm I'mma connect with
you on that same level and if you could
continue to do that through the video
then you have a fan I think that's a
good advice and I think for those folks
that are looking to start that haven't
started that feel like they aren't able
to start because of equipment I know
I've talked to some people like oh I
don't have a camera yet I don't have a
DSLR you know I don't have a a $3,000
camera to get started you don't need
that a lot of people use their iPhone
you know you get away with using your
iPhone you could buy a $15 tripod on the
hand and just go around and doing that
microphones now for a really good one
you could get a good one for 100 bucks
even cheaper than that on sale so you
can start off with really not spending a
whole lot of money you don't even need
the microphone right just just your
phone but yeah you can definitely get
started with little to no equipment and
still make some good quality content so
I figured that was worthy of mentioning
as well yeah and and uh also I always
say to people start with where you from
where you're at with what you have like
start from right there you don't have to
buy new running shoes to start running
you know you don't need the the the the
fancy stuff to start doing it when I
started doing comedy
I didn't
uh I didn't have anyone to do the SK the
skits with
me so what I ended up doing instead of
uh you know beating myself up over it or
not doing the sketch that I wanted to do
is I started dressing up as different
people you know sort of kind of what I
do now in my channel you know how that
that transferred over I would play
different characters I would play my mom
I'll play myself you know and just set
up the cameras and just record myself
that's how I started once those videos
started going viral everybody wanted to
be in my videos famous people wanted to
be in my videos I couldn't get enough
people in my videos so you know and it
just started because I just didn't have
anything else so you start with where
you're at with the idea and that forces
you if anything to be more creative
because you don't have the fancy
equipment you got to figure it out and
figuring it out is what's going to make
you different Look at me now I'm the one
dressing like this because I don't have
the people but I'm now now I'm the guy
now I'm the guy you know I made it work
so uh don't think of your situation as a
disadvantage think of it as an
opportunity to be creative and show who
you really are great point and bring
your own style right I mean you have
your own style that you brought to the
table you put yourself out there you
didn't copy anybody right I think that's
uh people get themselves in this
situation to where they're trying to
copy somebody because they see oh
somebody else's success well let me do
what they're doing I've probably about a
half a dozen people copy the way that I
do interviews and that's fine you know I
I appreciate that I'm humbled that
somebody was inspired by my work and
wanted to want to copy the way that I do
it but um people quickly quit because
it's not them you know they're not
having fun creating content the way that
somebody else is creating content right
so do what you want to do your own style
and have fun with it I think those are
good ways to go about it I mean gez you
even went to uh you even went so far to
create parody videos right he created
one on me on my
Chanel yeah so so that's actually a
great segue for that because you know
the reason I was trying to get on on
your Channel at that point was because
because of how suppressed you feel and
and when you're making content and
you're putting all these hours and no
one's watching your content so I'm like
man like this guy has a platform you
know let me figure out a way to get
there so I just reached out to you and
unfortunately you were booked till next
year
and uh and and I said well you know what
I still want it and there you go back to
use what you have I have myself so I
disguised me as you and interviewed me
as you you know I made it work I still
did what I needed to do I didn't do it
with you but I still did it you know so
don't ever let your situation limit you
if you have a great idea you know it's
going to work try it out with whatever
you have around you that's going to make
it stand out even more and the and the
cool part about this is that I'm now
here with you in real life you know what
I mean like with episode 11 the same one
the same number as the Parry that I did
I thought that was a great that was
awesome I had to do it yeah I had to do
episode 118 because that was what it was
in the parody so I thought that was like
fitting for that to happen but yeah my
my list of you'd be surprised there's at
least I say one to two people per week
that reach out to me and want to come on
the podcast and the list I have of
potential guests exceeds 200 people now
so yeah I was booked out for the rest of
the year I felt really bad I always feel
really bad when somebody has to come on
the podcast I'm like h i just I've got
so such a long list right now I'm sorry
like maybe in the future type stuff so
yeah I couldn't get you on at that time
but you got my uh got my attention and
uh you know and that worked we made it
happen and it worked out you know got it
done oh man what a great talk different
talk I hope uh hope the listeners enjoy
this if you enjoy this definitely click
the thumbs up button and leave a comment
down below and let us know what you
liked about it you know should I do
something like that this in the future
you know or should I stick to just
talking about gardening specific topics
let me know your thoughts down in the
comment section below Big Daddy buds can
you tell the listeners how they can find
you and kind of what you have upcoming
in the future uh for sure just uh on
YouTube is my main platform so just go
to YouTube and uh go to the girl under
the stairs and check out the videos that
I have over there uh if you want
somewhere easy to start starting season
10 uh episode one this is when I just
moved to Alaska I got dumped in my last
season so I had to move to Alaska so
that's a nice fresh start for me and
that's a nice fresh start from this
series if you want to know how I start
my my seats if you want to know how I
start from clone that starts from zero
so uh season 10 episode one as far as
what's coming in the future uh I would
actually like to do an extra SE ction in
in my Channel with some interviews that
that just deal with content creation so
I would love it if you guys are
listening if you like this type of
content uh about content creation uh to
jump over to my channel and see uh what
we're going to do over there hopefully I
can have you in there as one of the
guests that'd be an honor for me that'd
be cool yeah I'd love to come on and do
that yeah so if you did enjoy this type
of content Big Daddy bud is going to be
making similar type of content in the
future so yeah I'm looking forward to
seeing what you come up with in the
future once again thanks for coming on
man appreciate it and hope you have a
good rest of your day thank you so much
man I appreciate your time peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode