coming up on garden talk there's kind of
this mindset that we're trying to
replicate what the roots are
actually like what's actually happening
in the soil and that's sort of
impossible because the system is so
complex
and there's so many physical and
chemical and biological variables that
are interplaying together that you can't
actually see what's happening and the
biggest issue i see here is there's this
elevated magnesium at 149 and that's
really going to prevent the uptake of
calcium and potassium i would rather
have that around like
35 parts per million if your plants are
uptaking those amino acids
it's saving a bunch of energy that they
can put toward shoot growth or flower
development
or root growth or any number of
metabolic
activities but ultimately if i had a
magic wand i would reduce your nitrogen
magnesium i might push up your soluble
phosphorus a little bit
and your iron and from there things
would really just fly
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden dog
podcast this is episode number 26.
in this episode i interview bryant mason
some of you may know him as the soil
doctor he is a certified crop advisor
and has been in the business of soil and
crop health for over eight years
in this episode we talk all about soil
testing he takes a look at a soil test
that i got
and gives advice on optimal levels and
balancing
he also talks a little bit about
nitrogen phosphorus potassium
amino acids and heavy metals big thanks
to all of you that support this podcast
or patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get to the episode
i'd like to give a quick shout out to
our sponsors
ac infiniti is a sponsor of the podcast
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now
and absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high
and low humidity this greatly helps
control my indoor garden environment
so the temperature and humidity stays in
the ideal ranges
i will leave a link to ac infinity down
in the description section below
and don't forget to use coupon code mr
growit for discount on my products
a big supporter of this podcast is dutch
pro they sponsor this podcast
and i use their nutrients i have been
using their base nutrients
formulated specifically for auro and
soft water
i also have been using some of their
additives like calmag
silica and their root stimulator called
take root they have a few other
additives on top of those
and ph regulators coupon code
mrgrowit10dp
will get you a discount on their
products and i'll leave a link to their
amazon store
down in the description section below
big shout out to spider farmer for
sponsoring this podcast
spider farmer is well known to produce
high quality led grow lights
at a price lower than nearly all other
companies they have
board style led grow lights as well as
bar style led grow lights
i've used their sf 1000 sf 2000
and sf 4000 led grill lights in the past
and i got some excellent results with
them they also have grow tents
inline fans and carbon filters i will
leave a link to
spider farmer down in the description
section below and you can use discount
code
mr grow at 5 during checkout for a
discount on their products
okay now let's get into the episode
all right we are back garden talk
podcast i am here today with
bryant mason aka the soil doctor how's
it going today
going well cool oh thanks for joining me
today i've actually seen you on a couple
different
shows i saw you on one with uh brandon
russ talking about some clustering
nutrients i thought that was super
super interesting i also listened to you
on
ted hussey's podcast you did a great
episode with him
and you get real deep into things and
once i heard those two
i really wanted to get you on the show
and i'm super thankful to have you on
here
today um in this episode today what
we're going to go over is we're going to
talk all about soil testing
so uh my audience is say mostly
beginners
intermediate home growers i'd like to
say a large majority are home growers
of course there are some people out
there that do outdoors and they are
commercial facilities and so on and so
forth but
i would say indoors mostly and so we'll
talk all about soil test today
um an introduction to it also i have a
soil test that i got from logan labs i
got a soil report
and also a saturated paste test so we'll
go over some of the results
in this podcast today and then if we
have time we can get into
some of the nutrients and what you know
about them particularly like
macronutrients maybe like the npk
type stuff so i'm excited for this one
usually when we start off the podcast
we talk about introductions so can you
give us a little introduction about you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
kind of how you got into gardening
yeah so i live in colorado and
i am a soil and crop advisor through the
american association of agronomy and so
what that means is i help
farmers in various aspects of their
operations but unlike other
crop consultants i specifically focus on
nutrient management in organic systems
so um i do help you know answer
questions for
for growers about cover cropping and
different farm practices but but i
really really focus on
nutrient management and i do that
through extensive soil testing tissue
testing
plant sap analysis so all kinds of
different laboratory techniques
to really hone in on the nutrient
bottlenecks that are preventing greater
yield or photosynthesis or quality
in crops on a garden level actually
before i was a consultant
i started a business in colorado called
the urban farm company
and we installed um raised bed organic
vegetable gardens for homeowners
and taught people how to grow their own
food in their backyard at night i
built that business for about five years
before selling it
but we installed probably two or three
thousand vegetable gardens
across the front range of colorado and
that enabled me to see
really um it's sort of a hyper
data set of gardens in different
environments in different backyards with
different crops and crop types and soil
types and so
in a sense we were able to observe um
very quickly what was working and what
wasn't and i learned a
tremendous amount about gardening
specifically in the high desert
in the arid west and i was i've been
able to translate that
into more technical and data
driven soil chemistry and fertility
recommendations so
i work with all kinds of of crops
i have been working more and more in
soilless media and potting soils
in indoor environments but i also work
with a
small organic veggie producers uh tree
fruit and i'm actually
currently starting a peach orchard in
western colorado so i have a
my hands in a lot of different
agricultural enterprises and i get to
see things from a lot of different
angles so
that's that's just in a nutshell kind of
my background awesome
now let's get into talking about soil
testing
and the soil audits that you do first
off
what is soil testing and why should
growers get them
yeah so a soil test is essentially uh
when you take
a sample an aggregate sample from your
garden so
you choose multiple locations around
your garden
and you mix it all together into an
aggregate sample and you send it to a
laboratory and there's there's
university laboratories there's third
party private labs and the labs
use different data or i'm sorry
extraction techniques
and they extract the nutrients from the
soil and give you a
chemical nutrient analysis of what is in
your soil because
all soils are different you can actually
see this map behind me there's a map of
the united states that shows
all the different soil orders and you
can just see there's just tremendous
variability and diversity in soil
so it's really important to to test your
soil to understand what you're starting
with
some soils have really really high
magnesium some have really low magnesium
and you can go nutrient by nutrient and
and there's infinite iterations so um
the reason a soil test is important is
because there are
you know somewhat of gardening
prescriptions that exist on the internet
like
feed your tomatoes epsom salt but that
only works in one specific soil type or
one specific context sometimes
there's enough magnesium and you don't
need epsom salt so
the best way to to apply nutrients is to
first figure out what's actually in your
soil and that's the purpose of a soil
test
and to go a little deeper what the lab
does is there's a number of different
kinds of soil tests there's and and
usually they're
specific to different parts of the
country so they use
different acids and they mix the soil
with an
acidic solution that extracts the
nutrients
so um you know i like a soil test called
a maleic 3 and they use a
an acid with a ph of 2.5 to extract all
the nutrients
and i also like what's called the
saturated paste test which just uses
water
to extract the nutrients so i can go
into that more if you'd like but
the point is there's a lot of different
kinds of soil tests
and um there's a lot of nuance
so what's important is to choose a lab
and choose a specific soil test and not
change because all labs and all
protocols and soil tests are different
so it's important to stick with one over
time and really calibrate
to one specific kind of test gotcha i
know
one of the most popular testing
facilities is logan labs
and that's the one i went through from
my soil report
that i have in the saturated pace test
now you can either go through a lab or
like on amazon you can buy the home test
kits
so are they worth it i've seen some
video where this guy did a test on the
home test kits and he compared it to it
i think he had a couple different home
test kits and one was like extremely
inaccurate and one of them was like
pretty pretty on point to what he saw
got from back from the lab so
you know in your opinion are home soil
tests worth it or
is it really kind of a waste of money
you know i
i fall in the ladder camp where i think
it's a waste of money now
let me let me explain why there's
essentially two reasons
the first is that they're not very
accurate compared to what a commercial
laboratory would use
they use um equipment like uh
um an inductively coupled plasma mass
spectrometer it's a big name for a
piece of equipment that costs about two
hundred thousand dollars
and is extremely accurate in identifying
each and every macro micronutrient down
to
the part per million so the garden kits
are not accurate usually it's a it's a
color metric
type of thing where you're matching the
color um to
a certain chart that tells you the level
now that's not my biggest issue with it
actually because precision you know
super super accurate data isn't
necessarily the goal the goal
of a soil test is just to give you
direction in terms of what you should be
applying and what you shouldn't so
the accuracy thing while it is
surely a problem isn't the reason i
think these tests are a waste of money
the real reason is that
if you use one of these kits usually
there's not
a good um standard
or target level that you'd be familiar
with using these kits it may say hi
low or medium but the reality is
you really need to see data
over and over again like i've probably
seen five or ten thousand tests from
logan labs so i've
i'm hyper calibrated to
logan labs uh test reports if i were to
change labs whether it's a home test kit
or another commercial lab the data would
would essentially be
unhelpful and so the biggest issue for
me around these home test kits is that
they they don't really give you a good
quality
baseline i don't think high low and
medium is actually
a very good approach to managing soil
and so
it's better to either have a consultant
or an agronomist even if it's with the
commercial lab
doing the interpretation because there's
a lot of nuance in interpreting a soil
test
so that's sort of my my two cents on
that i've also mentioned that i've used
home test kits where i've taken the same
soil
and i've tested it twice and the results
were different between
the two the two tests so that that
didn't really give me much confidence
wow yeah and like you said there's a
difference between getting a soil test
and seeing the results and then knowing
what actions to take
after the fact right or getting
consulting
and that's where soil audit comes into
place can you
tell us about soil audit yeah sure and
let me add one thing to the last
question a p
a ph a home ph uh test
i think is pretty good um if you're
trying to figure out if your ph is
five or eight i think it's it's totally
worth it to do a simple
ph test with litmus paper whatever
whatever the the test is those tend to
be accurate enough to
actually get a sense of if you should be
increasing your ph or not
um i also just want to add that when it
comes to soil testing
there's there's kind of this this
mindset that we're trying to replicate
what the roots
are actually like what's actually
happening
in the soil and that's sort of
impossible because the system is so
complex
and there's so many uh physical and
chemical and biological variables that
are interplaying together that you can't
actually see what's happening but these
soil tests are just a proxy to give us
sort of a
a sense of of what's happening so
anyway that the the purpose of me saying
that is there isn't
i'm not here to promote one specific
soil test i think what's key is to get
comfortable with one
as a proxy and be able to relate that to
plant health and stick with that so
to get into the soil audit what i do
i probably do 20 to 30 of these a day
it's my primary
role as a consultant is growers send
their soil to logan labs and they get
two separate soil tests on the same soil
one is the maelic three which i already
talked about it's called a standard test
and the other
is a saturated paste test and so
the maelic 3 is a strong acid extraction
it looks at what's theoretically
available in the soil so all the
nutrients kind of like the bank account
of nutrients and the paste test is on
the other end of the spectrum and it's
showing what's
immediately available today so not all
the theoretically available nutrients
just what's soluble in the soil solution
and the soil solution is a term for the
water in the pore space of the soil
uh that plants roots have access to
right now that's it's the water that's
actually uptaken by the roots
so the paste test is a really really
good test to see
what's what the plant roots are actually
swimming in and so i look at both of
these tests from logan labs
and i do a whole bunch of agronomic math
and write recommendations for growers on
how to amend their soil
so it may be and most of the time this
is a pre-plant recommendation so before
the season or before they
put in their new round of indoor plants
uh they
send me the soil test and i write a
recommendation of how many
pounds per cubic yard of soil they
should apply of let's say
alfalfa meal or gypsum or a
micronutrient like manganese sulfate and
i go
nutrient by nutrient and i write
customized recommendations and the goal
that i the approach that i take is the
first thing i'm trying to do is achieve
sufficiency so i'm trying to make sure
there's enough of every nutrient in the
soil for the plants to be healthy
and this varies by species so
you know a recommendation for lettuce is
going to look different than
for tomatoes in the same soil and then
this and then the second thing i'm
aiming for is balance so it's very
important to have balance
between the different nutrients in the
soil so um
you know there needs to be enough
calcium and there needs to be enough
magnesium but there also needs to be a
good balance between those two nutrients
to optimize
the nutrient uptake by the plant and so
the recommendations or the audit that i
do
is giving people more information about
what their soil
looks like and the chemistry of their
soil but there's also a very actionable
recommendation of how to
amend their soil to move it closer to
sufficiency and balance and that's
really
a soil audit they're 40 dollars per test
and usually i can turn them around
within 24 hours of receiving the soil
test results
and then growers can actually take it
and implement it immediately and the
beauty of
of the my business is i get to see over
time how the nutrient levels in the soil
change
and so i've really calibrated very very
accurately
to hit specific ppms in the soil using
organic amendments
and i've optimized it for a number of
different crops so i have a model at
this point that gets
pretty pretty close in pre-plant
amendments
okay and just to touch back on the
pricing you had mentioned forty dollars
for is that just for the audit or does
that also include the
testing through logan labs it's just the
audit so the forty dollars goes to me
and that's for the recommendation okay
the foil test through logan labs cost 55
for both the standard and the saturated
paste test
and um that can the growers can either
purchase that directly through logan
labs or they can go through my website
and purchase it as a package
with the soil test and the right and the
audit so
it doesn't really matter to me um but
that's kind of how the pricing works
i feel like for home growers you know if
you're reusing your soil and over and
over again maybe
what do you think like once a year maybe
get their soil tested
or in between grows or what is the
general recommendation for that
yeah it really depends on the economic
value of the crop
so commercial growers i work with who
are growing really high value
medicinal plants are testing every two
weeks because
any increase in yield pays for itself
a hundred fold because the tests you
know 100 bucks every two weeks for
nutrient management is nothing compared
to the yield that they're getting
if you're a home gardener and
it depends on how serious you are if
you're an enthusiast
if you're kind of a hobbyist once a year
is the minimum
i would say every time you plant every
time you're
you're replanting you should you should
test so in my garden
in my vegetable garden i test
once a year i put down the amendments
and i let things rip
when i'm really trying to optimize
specific
plants my medicinal garden plants i'm
testing usually
once before planting and then once in
veg immediately before flower
to really give myself the opportunity to
top dress or just see where things are
to adjust my feed uh my liquid feeds
so that's kind of the minimum amount the
other thing i'd mention
is i recommend that if you're going to
test mid-season you also do a tissue
test and the tissue test
is where you take you know leaves off of
your plants um you send it in again
logan lab says tissue test for 40
a pop and you can actually see the
nutrient concentration
in the the plant because what i like to
say is the plant doesn't lie
so just because you can have you can
have a perfectly you know sufficient and
balanced soil but at the end of the day
the plant is going to decide
um what it uptakes and so
to have a soil test alongside a tissue
test is really
the best thing to do so for a home
grower
i think what i would recommend if you're
really an enthusiast is to do
one soil test before planting and then
one soil test
right around that time when the plant is
transitioning from
a vegetative state to a reproductive
state with a tissue test
gotcha okay cool now let's get into
the soil test that i got so i sent it
over to you prior to
filming today there is just the the
regular test and then also the saturated
pace test so we won't go over every
single line item
there but maybe just take a look at it
and kind of what stands out to you
and kind of general recommendations so
on and so forth yeah yeah so let me walk
through how i would
how i would look at a test okay so the
first thing i'm looking at is the
standard soil test which is in blue and
gray
um when you when it's received from
logan labs the saturated paste test is
kind of in a
pink orange color so first thing i look
at on the standard test is about the
sixth line down it says organic matter
percent
and that gives me an indication of if
it's topsoil
so you know real soil that has sand
silt and clay or if it's soilless media
or potting mix that's primarily composed
of peat moss coco coir
aggregate and compost so the first thing
i see here is that the organic matter is
so that indicates to me that it's a
soilless media so it's more of a
of a engineered media and this is
typically used
for high value crops in indoors or in in
raised beds
or in pots you really only want to use
soilless media in pots you don't want to
use
topsoil so i i first determine if it's
topsoil or soilless media and that that
totally changes how i analyze things
it completely changes the analysis so
i'll walk through how i do soilless
media
next thing i look at is the ph ph of 6.6
um i think anywhere from like 6.0 to 7.2
is a great range for soilless media
plants tend to do just fine in the high
fives but
you start to see issues with calcium
uptake below 6
and micronutrient issues that really
appear visually
below about 5.5 but it kind of depends
so 6.6 is perfect i i think six four to
six six is really
optimal um actually i'd say six four to
like
six eight and okay so the next thing i
look at i skip sulfur and i look to the
it says maelic 3 phosphorus and it's
reported in in
pounds per acre of p205 i like that
around about
1500 but it really depends too on
how well that phosphorus is is becoming
available in the soil solution so i pop
over to the paste test
and so i'm going to be jumping between
the paste tests and the standard test
and i see that the phosphorus
on the saturated paste report is 2.88
ppm so i think that's a great level so i
don't think you necessarily need to
have more phosphorous i might apply
maybe five
cups of bone meal or soft rock phosphate
just to keep moving that phosphorus
number up
but ultimately biology is going to cycle
that phosphorus into availability and
create good availability
right around 3 ppm so i'm happy with
that so
i keep working down i skip on the
standard test i skip
the exchangeable cations calcium mag and
potassium
i would not skip those on a topsoil but
for soilless media
i much prefer to look at the saturated
paste report
and the reason for that is because
soilless media doesn't actually have any
clay in it
and clay is what when you're looking at
um
the cation balance in the
these the malik 3 is developed for
topsoil where clay
is holding different cations within its
clay has a
slight negative charge and so it holds
these positively charged cations
but because loyalist media doesn't have
that i'd rather just see what's
immediately available
um in the soil solution so i pop over to
the paste test
and i look at calcium mag potassium and
sodium calcium's at 170 parts per
million
that's very sufficient pretty good level
magnesium is 149 potassium is 230 parts
per million and sodium is 33.
okay so when i look at that great
calcium levels
great pretty pretty high potassium
levels
really low sodium which is great because
sodium is not actually a plant nutrient
so you want to minimize
you want to absolutely minimize sodium
in your soil because it's going to
compete so all of those four cations are
going to compete with one another for
plant uptake
so all of those are sufficient the next
thing i mentioned is balance and it's
really important that these are balanced
and the biggest issue i see here is
there's this elevated magnesium at 149
and that's really going to prevent the
uptake of calcium and potassium
i would rather have that around like 35
parts per million so that's it's it's
much higher than i would want it and
that's reflected in that
percent magnesium on the on the paste
report
a little bit lower in white
it's magnesium is 44
of the cations on the paste report i'd
rather have it at about 15 to 20 percent
so one thing one little trick is i
actually like to have
epsom salt which is magnesium sulfate on
hand i like to run magnesium levels low
and then if i need if a certain cultivar
needs more magnesium i like to apply
a foliar spray of epsom salt to just
kind of help it along and that really
maximizes the calcium and potassium
uptake
so anyway there's a whole there's a
whole game there's kind of an art
game with balance when it comes to
cations and one of my biggest issues
with calmag is there's too much
magnesium and so you start to see these
elevated magnesium levels which can come
from calmag
dolomitic lime compost a lot of compost
or high in magnesium and so
a major issue this is very common is
high magnesium now this isn't going to
create toxicity you probably won't even
see it in your plants
you can still have really really healthy
plants but
if you if you're really trying to
maximize and optimize yield and quality
you want to get that magnesium down i'll
take a breather for a second and take a
sip of tea do you have any questions
at this point uh i think just basic
question would be like you had mentioned
uh
foliar spray for magnesium what would be
like
the kind of the ratio the recipe for
that uh i say a tablespoon per gallon
of epsom salt uh tables a per gallon of
water
you could do it's like one to three
teaspoons so
and and i think it's forgiving i've
never applied it more than that but i'm
sure you could do
two tablespoons with no issue but i'm
all about frequency over intensity so i
would much rather
apply three foliar sprays maybe four
days apart
then then do one massive application
because the reality is the the phylo
plane the leaf
can't uptake that that much and one
in one fell swoop so frequency is always
better
and then there's some folks that say you
need to you should be spraying at a
certain time
is there a recommendation for for you on
when the spray should happen
yeah absolutely so
there are stomata which are specialized
guard cells
in a leaf and they open and close uh
and they're critical for photosynthesis
because they're exchanging gases
co2 and oxygen in and out of the leaf
and
turns out that stomata can actually
uptake nutrients as well so
the best time to spray is when the
stomata are open and that will maximize
the nutrient uptake in the leaf
most stomata in uh in
dicots which are the majority of the
plants we're growing our dicots are on
the underside of the leaf
so when you apply your foliar you kind
of want to aim
up if possible and
you want to apply it when the stomata
are open which tends to be
early in the morning or later at night
really it's a function of vapor pressure
deficit or vpd
so height you know when it's when it's
humid and kind of cool
that's when you want to be applying um
because in in the middle of the day when
the vpd's high
the the stomata close because they're
trying to preserve
water they don't want to lose too much
water
in hot dry environments so that's
that's definitely what i'd recommend
most growers do it first thing in the
morning
or you know real late at night okay cool
uh i also if you're indoors i turn my
lights down when i do foliar
applications
yeah i know there were some concerns
from people that uh the the
the light will come down and kind of act
as a magnifying lens
on those droplets um and that could burn
your plants or
or whatever yeah it depends on the
product
but in epsom salt probably not but a lot
of the ipm products for sure
if you're using synthetic like a calcium
chloride that could really
you know burn um it just depends on the
style of grow and the product being used
and
the rate okay gotcha okay let me keep
let me keep walking through this test i
never finished um
okay so that covers the phosphorus and
the cations
and the ph the next thing i look at
on this saturated paste report is the
soluble salts so soluble salts
is essentially the same as ec it's just
electrical conductivity um what you'd
usually see
as an ec of one you multiply that by
640. so
the the soluble salts are just an
aggregate measurement of all the the
total nutrient load
in the soil solution and this one is
1800 ppm
that's a pretty high level uh most
plants maybe
beans and more sensitive veggies
wouldn't like those levels but heavy
feeders
you know your medicinal garden plants
tomatoes
even peppers can really handle those
high levels and will thrive at those
nutrient levels but i wouldn't
want to push my nutrients much higher
um i think the sweet spot is actually um
for for indoor cultivation right around
like
900 to 1200 so right around a thousand i
think is
is all you need so um this just gives a
sense of how heavily
this soil should be fed or amended
and in this case there's total
sufficiency at these levels and we're
really just going for balance
so reducing the magnesium
maybe reducing the sulfur so let's jump
down to chloride
i like chloride less than 120. your
chloride's at 83. so no problem there
bicarbonates are 43.
bicarbonates really aren't an issue
below 100 or
120 so there's no issue there
bicarbonates can can tie up
nutrients because it's a it's an anion
so it can it can
tie up iron and magnesium um in alkaline
environments
so then i go to sulfur on the paste test
which is a much better and more accurate
measurement than this
the standard test and it looks like your
sulfur is 75 parts per million i think
that's great i think 40 is the minimum
for medicinal plants
20 for veggies so that's great
and sulfur just comes in naturally
through most
amendments that are bringing in cations
so
gypsum for example is calcium sulfate
uh potassium sulfate or magnesium
sulfate all these are just naturally
bringing in
sulfur and so you usually have elevated
sulfur just from
the application of gypsum or
some a product like that okay so
next i jump down to the micronutrients
we're looking at boron iron manganese
copper and zinc so i
copper and zinc i always look at on the
standard test so on the standard test
you have
0.96 so less than one ppm of copper and
1.7 ppm of zinc
totally depends on the crop but i would
want to move both of those levels
up with a little bit of copper sulfate
and zinc sulfate by the way all the
amendments that i recommend are organic
so if a soil test validates that you
need micronutrients you you
can use trace mineral or micro
micronutrient sulfates
looking at boron iron and manganese on
the paste report
boron at 0.24 is great iron at 0.17
should probably go up and manganese at
0.28 is great so you always want iron to
be higher than manganese
so i'd want iron maybe a 0.75 and
manganese maybe at 0.4 or something like
that so your manganese is actually
pretty good and the biggest priority
here is iron there's two ways to get
iron you can use
iron sulfate or you can use a product
like blood meal that's naturally high in
iron
to fulfill your nitrogen requirement and
get iron
as a secondary nutrient so let's jump
over to nitrogen because nitrogen is the
final thing that i would look
at and that's on the standard test at
the very bottom
um in the other category there's
ammonium and nitrate
those are two different forms of
nitrogen they're two different
um they're like two different molecular
forms of nitrogen
nitrogen is a really interesting
nutrient because there's actually
multiple forms of nitrogen that the
plant can uptake and they're
they act very differently in the plant
and in the soil for that matter
so ammonium is nh4 plus it's a cation
and nitrate is no3 minus which is an
anion so it has a negative charge
and in most soils
what happens is an organic amendment
will go into the soil
so let's just say soybean meal is
applied to the soil and the microbes
feed first so the microbes
break it down mineralize it into
ammonium
and then very quickly another set of
microbes takes it from ammonium and
converts it into nitrate
so what happens is over the course of
maybe two weeks in a warm moist
environment
you'll see almost all of your nitro
nitrogen in the nitrate form
so sure enough there's only one ppm of
ammonium and 420 of of nitrate
so that means that your amendments have
fully mineralized or broken down which
is a good thing
and nitrate is definitely the preferred
form of nitrogen for most crops
unless you're growing rice or something
you really want
nitrate not ammonium so um
i think it and and nitrogen management
is totally
context dependent what i mean by that is
if you're growing in pots
it depends on the volume of soil if
you're growing
in um topsoil
it's it it changes everything
because in topsoil you're also
i also look at how much nitrogen is
going to be contribute
contributed by the organic matter
breaking down so the nitrogen
calculation may be a little bit too
uh detailed for this podcast
but what i'd say is you'd want i i think
nitrate
is is good at about 100 parts per
million for heavy feeding
crops so you're a bit high and i would
say the combination of your magnesium
and your
and your elevated nitrate is what's
leading to that slightly elevated
soluble salts level
so if you could um the good thing is
that in soilless media
after harvest you could you could leech
your soil you could just run like
you know water through your soil until
about six to 12 inches of water
leeches out the bottom of your pots or
your beds or whatever
and that would bring the nitrate down
and the magnesium down
dramatically probably cutting it
anywhere from like 50 to
80 percent so the
different cultivars of heavy feeding
medicinal plants
will perform way differently at these
nitrogen levels
but for most cultivars in my experience
you'll get
your internode spacing will be too too
wide and the
and the flower buds will be a little bit
too kind of loose and fluffy
when the nitrogen is elevated you can
also screw up
um the profile of secondary metabolites
so like you know terpenes and different
aromatic substances can really
be decreased at those nitrogen levels
with sensitive plants like
um i'm trying to think there are certain
veggies that would actually
be burned at those levels you'd start to
see like the traditional burn symptoms
of necrosis on the on the outer leaf
edges
um for you know legumes
for sure and and other sensitive plants
any questions on that no so that that's
pretty much it huh so overall it's
pretty decent um
there's a couple areas that can be
improved upon but yeah that's that's
pretty much uh
pretty much it for the audit yeah yeah
so the the
analysis is you know there's a lot to it
um it totally depends on if it's topsoil
or soilless media the nitrogen
concentration totally depends on the
soil volume
the cultivar the species etc
but ultimately if i had a magic wand i
would reduce your nitrogen magnesium i
might push up your soluble
phosphorus a little bit and your iron
and um
and from there things would really just
fly cool now
there was one talking a little bit
deeper about nitrogen there was one
i think was your instagram video you
made on nitrogen
and i believe it was something along the
lines of like 18
of the energy has to do with converting
can you talk to us a little bit about
that
yeah so um
what happens in the plant is the plant
uptakes either ammonium
or nitrate or amino acids
which is an organic form of nitrogen so
there's a third form of nitrogen that
the plant can uptake
and again they act totally different
depending on what happens when it comes
to nitrate which is
what the vast majority of nitrogen is
taken up
as the plant has to convert that
nitrogen
in the form of nitrate into complete
proteins to actually
put into its leaves so nitrogen is sort
of the backbone of proteins
in the plant and so it actually has to
take that no3 molecule and and make it
into a protein and that
process is metabolically uh very energy
intensive and so
you know i've heard and i heard this in
a podcast
put out by john kemp i can't i haven't
been able to validate it in a textbook
but that upwards of 18 of the plant's
metabolic energy is used to convert
nitrate into complete proteins
so in theory there's a there's a sort of
a hack
and that is that if you can feed the
plants amino acids
so amino acids are the building blocks
of proteins if you can feed them
a soluble amino acid that they uptake
they don't have to convert it into
proteins they don't just spend as much
energy because it's already in that
building block
of an amino acid and so i really like
um there's a there's like a soluble
there's a number of soluble organic
amino
acid products that are in liquid form
that you can feed your plants i like
soluble soybean meal there's like four
different brands
that are probably all manufactured by
the same company and just branded
differently
but the theory goes that if your plants
are uptaking those amino acids
it's saving a bunch of energy that they
can put toward
shoot growth or flower development or
root growth
or any number of metabolic
activities so
i'm not sure if that actually works
there's no way to actually test that
i do know that plants perform extremely
well when you feed them
soluble amino acids but the question is
really do the
do the roots uptake at first or do the
microbes get it first because
if it goes in the soil and the microbes
um
get it first then they're going to
convert it into ammonium and then
nitrate and the plants going to have to
convert it back into amino acids but if
the plants can uptake it in amino acid
form
it's definitely definitely a superior
way to go
gotcha okay yeah that's that's really
good information i was
super intrigued when i heard that you
know amino acids hack
i'm hearing more and more about amino
acids and how they're beneficial
and i know there are some nutrient
companies that are they're using them
as kind of like a primary thing for
uptake so um
that's super cool yeah and i also
mentioned that they're the most
efficient form of foliar for nitrogen so
if you're gonna
if you're gonna apply nitrogen foliar um
you wanna you want to be an amino acid
form
um and yeah they're definitely more
expensive
but at the end of the day almost all of
these organic amendments are
in protein or amino acid form and
because they're dry and in chunks if you
can imagine soybean meal or any kind of
meal feather meal blood meal
they're going to get there the microbes
have to have to mineralize them
but in a liquid amino form it's much
better
so yeah they're very popular really if
you ferment
any organic substance it's going to end
up in amino acid form
interesting let's move on let's talk uh
let's get a little bit deeper into
phosphorus can you tell us a little bit
about phosphorus i want you to know
about it yeah phosphorus is
the primary function that i think of is
just energy transfer so
so phosphorus is the you know the
primary
uh element in atp which is kind of the
the energy transfer uh
money in in cells so all metabolic
processes need
energy phosphorus is the main energy
source um
you know phosphorus isn't needed in as
high as quant
in as high of quantity as most people
think and actually if you push nitrogen
traditionally people have pushed knight
or i'm sorry phosphorus way too hard
and that can create major environmental
issues especially outside so
i don't necessarily believe in in really
pushing soluble phosphorus in outdoor
environments because it really
it's leaky it leaves the farm it leaves
the garden and ends up in ecosystems and
really wreaks havoc
so phosphorus is super important and
there you definitely need to have a
certain concentration of phosphorus in
the root system
for root growth and for flower
development and
for just reproductive energy in general
but i think it's oftentimes overdone
in uh conventional systems especially
with people are using phosphoric
acid or monoammonium phosphate or
you know triple superfos but underdone
in organic systems
so i like to i like to have luxurious
levels of phosphorus
in organic systems yeah i've heard that
in some of these bottled nutrient lines
in particular that they way over doing
phosphorus
that it's just it's an overkill and then
people are adding pk boosters on top of
it and flowering and that's
causing problems down the line now will
phosphorus in excess of that will that
lock out other
nutrients you know it takes a lot it
takes a lot
i mean hydroponically we have to have
100 ppm
to start but but absolutely it'll start
to antagonize or lock out other
nutrients such as zinc
iron uh a lot of the i mean it's a
it's an anion so it'll lock out any
cationic
micronutrient which is zinc iron
manganese
um and copper but really zinc and iron
are the ones to be
uh aware of the most okay
uh moving on potassium talk to us a
little bit about potassium yeah
potassium is a fascinating one
potassium is responsible in the plant
for
and by the way when i when i do this
very quick overview of what these things
do in the plant
these three nutrients really all the
macronutrients are ubiquitous
they have so many roles in the plants
that you would have to be a phd in plant
physiology to even understand all the
different roles of potassium so
high level stuff um i'm saying what they
do maybe one or two things but
they they have their hand in almost
every metabolic function
but when i think of potassium i think of
um
the it's it's like cell balance so the
opening and closing
of stomata and the movement of nutrients
through the xylem
and the translocation of nutrients and
carbohydrates
it's all about potassium because it's
it's um
it's a very high concentration cation
that helps open and close
um cells so
yeah potassium is very important it's
also as if people who
are growing for flowering flowering
plants know that
whether you're trying to size up an
apple or a tomato
or a medicinal flower you you need to
have a lot of potassium in the
reproductive
state so to me there's this very
interesting relationship
that i focus on a lot between calcium
and potassium they're both cations with
positive charges
and they're both very antagonistic to
one another so i like to really
push calcium and veg and try to maximize
the plant
uptake of calcium and then in flour when
you're really trying to fill flour and
hit yield and create density you want to
you want to switch that ratio and really
be pushing potassium
so yeah potassium in the soluble form
there's a number of different
organic products um i was about to say
potassium silicate
it's actually not considered organic
unless you're using it for ipm but
i don't have any issue with it
whatsoever but potassium sulfate is what
i tend to recommend
and you can really push potassium levels
up i've noticed that it has a bit of a
of a delayed effect so if you want to
size a flower
it's not going to be a 24 hour effect
you should be applying it like
weeks in advance of when um the flowers
are really sizing so
uh the rule of thumb i use is like a lot
of
growers uh understand the idea of like
the plants stretch like
at the end of stretch that's when i
really hammer down on potassium
okay and then yeah there are some
growers out there that swear by
potassium towards the end of flowering
they're just
absolutely yeah um so and i do too i
think that's critically important
the interesting part was there is you
said after stretch is really when you
want to start to apply it so when would
you stop
applying it a couple weeks before
harvest okay i mean
it it totally depends on your and this
is why soil testing is so important
it depends on your soil levels right if
you go into flour and you're at
where you are at 2 2 30 i don't think
i'd apply potassium i think that's great
um but in a perfect world your your
calcium's at 170 your mags at 35
your potassium is like under a hundred
and then
and then once you enter flour you've got
to get that up to over 200 so that's
when you really just got to hammer down
on it
so it depends on where your soil's at
and it depends on the tissue levels too
like if you haven't loaded calcium then
you may not need as much potassium
um so it's important to kind of
understand that it's it's hard to give a
set recommendation but in general
in general feeding potassium
is going to help and it's the
interesting thing about potassium is
it's not going to hurt
so plants
like potassium won't lock anything out
it won't antagonize anything because
plants most plants have
um the ability to to uptake luxury
levels of potassium
so they can just keep up taking it they
can eat it like candy
and just store it in vacuoles or in
different cellular constituents and and
not use it
but they like to just uptake it in
luxury levels
and it's not gonna tie anything up um
so it's not gonna hurt to feed potassium
and flour and i and i don't
have an issue saying that because i
don't think it's a major environmental
concern outdoors
so if someone's slamming down on a
phosphorus
during flower that bothers me someone's
slamming down on potassium
excessively it's it's not that big of a
deal okay i did want to touch
on one more thing and that is heavy
metals
so i know you did the the talk with tad
hussey
you went into detail with heavy metals i
know like on the commercial facility
side of things it's
it's pretty important i mean they can
fail testing
for heavy metals now on the homegrown
side of things we don't really
hear about that much but can you talk to
us about heavy metals and soil and
plants
yeah so the interesting thing about
heavy metals is i think that it's it's a
little bit over
hyped but but
not over hyped the the issue is
if you fail your tests you have huge
economic loss
so they're so it's this this high risk
low probability event
and those are the worst um
that's what that's usually in life where
there's a high risk low probability
event
you buy insurance so like you know
for a fire or whatever but you can't buy
heavy metal insurance so
the the goal is you just try to minimize
a few risk factors that may be
contributing to heavy metal failure the
first obviously is genetics
you know plants medicinal plants are
often
just natural hyper accumulators and
different different
uh cultivars have a much higher
proclivity to accumulate heavy metals so
so part of the failure issue is just
growers have just certain cultivars that
unfortunately accumulate it in high
quantities but beyond that
there are certain inputs that
bring in heavy metals and
and there are certain soil conditions
specifically
ph and redox which is like how saturated
your soil is
that will influence the uptake of heavy
metals so usually heavy metals are
coming in through
a bad compost source so oftentimes
historically biosolids
have a lot of high so compost made from
biosolids which is like municipal
sewage sludge have a lot of heavy metals
which sounds disgusting but
it's interesting the stuff performs
super well i've used it
it's it performs extremely well but it
often has higher heavy metals
inputs like kelp meal which is such a
staple in the organic program for most
growers
can have it pretty much always has
elevated arsenic so a little bit
a little bit is fine but if you're
applying
huge amounts of kelp meal you could
start seeing failures
again depending on the cultivar soft
rock phosphate and rock dust which are
mined
products often have elevated heavy
metals it's kind of brand
specific from my research so you just
want to make sure you're sourcing the
right
amendments um i help growers source
amendments that have been screened
and they have the the lowest levels of
heavy metals if they're going to get
tested
and then it kind of depends on the state
right because some states don't test
some do and sometimes
the the levels can be really rigorous
some s states test for barium
some don't so it's kind of again context
specific
then the final thing is just foliars
most most people
avoid foliar applying their um
final product whether that's a vegetable
a melon
or a flower and um so if you're fully
applying kelp meal on your flowers
you're gonna you have a hundred times
higher likelihood of failing
than if you aren't so
you just wanna be very conscious of
foliage and then all the branded
nutrients just
any org certified organic product
has to get tested they have to meet
certain i would say fairly rigorous
standards for heavy metals
and so i'm i have the heavy metal levels
of all
organic products at my disposal and so i
can actually just look
if a product's not certified organic and
it's from some
bottled nutrient company you have no
idea and so
if you're really trying to minimize that
risk you really need to either have
those products tested
um or i would say demand from the
manufacturer that
you get test results or you need to
eliminate them
and so what i do is i help growers use
the raw mineral ingredients and put
together customized fertility programs
so they can get off bottle nutrients
i'm not saying i mean i have bottle
nutrients in my shed right now just
because if i need to do a quick fix i
can
just slam it with something quick but
ultimately
i'd say that's a big question mark in
commercial operations in terms of
figuring out where heavy metals are
coming from
final thing i'll mention is that logan
labs does heavy metal testing they do
all the epa 503 heavy metals so for 150
bucks you can test your soil and
actually see
what the heavy metal levels are in
addition to the nutrient analysis
um so those are my thoughts i have more
thoughts that get more technical but
honestly i don't think it's that
it's it's too theoretical like i
understand when cadmium becomes
available
but i don't think it's a relevant
conversation to the home grower
or even to the commercial grower because
certain things just are out of the
out of control of a grower like you're
not going to change the redox state of
your soil it's just not
realistic gotcha gotcha really good
stuff there
for sure so wrapping things up how can
the listeners find you
and is there anything special you got
upcoming in the future that you want to
talk about
um i've got a i've got a number of
things in the works that i can't wait to
launch i'm not talking about them yet um
but there's some really exciting things
that i'm going to launch in the next
year
and i'd say the best way to follow me is
on instagram
um soil underscore doctor i haven't
posted for a while because the busy
season just sweeps me away i'm starting
an orchard i'm helping hundreds of
growers i'm not producing content but i
will be
as things slow down so follow me on
instagram
you can order soil audits consulting
phone calls anything you want on my
website which is
soildoctorconsulting.com
awesome i will leave a link to brian's
instagram
and website down in the description
section below if you enjoyed this video
please click that thumbs up button that
helps tremendously it helps with ranking
it helps
show up on people's recommended feeds so
on and so forth if you're new to the
channel
subscribe that way you can be notified
when
new episodes are released i release
every single weekend
so either saturday or sunday usually
it's saturday but if susan
over youtube decides that she needs to
manually review a video
it'll come out on sunday instead so also
if you're listening on apple podcast
leave a rating and review that helps out
a ton we're just about to reach 100
ratings and reviews so thank you so much
to everyone who has left that so far
and lastly sharing that's probably one
of the biggest things you can do is
share this podcast reddit is a good
place to share
facebook groups is a good place to share
so thank you to everyone who decides to
share this podcast
brian thank you so much for coming on to
the podcast today i have learned
so much and uh there's a really a lot of
knowledge here that i think is going to
help out the audience so
thank you so much and i hope you enjoy
the rest of your day
yeah thanks chris thanks for having me
[Music]
on
you