welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the guard Talk
podcast this episode number 105. in this
episode I interview Dr MJ Coco he has
been gardening for 25 years and is
regarded as an expert on growing in Coco
coir and that's what we get into in
today's episode he talks all about what
Coco is rinsing it buffering it
p-h-e-c and so much more I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring free gardening
information of all plants to the general
public that being said I like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
their grow 10 kits are incredible you
get their eye on board LED grow light
their grow tent which is currently the
thickest on the market the ventilation
system clip-on fan and their controller
69 to control it all you also get their
fabric pots trellis net plant ties and
Tremors definitely a good price for all
the you get in the kit I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these grow tank
kits and the discount code Mr Grodd 15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infinity.com
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Dr
MJ Coco how you doing today I'm doing
good and I'm excited to be on the show
I'm excited to have you on the show we
actually met a few months back at MJ
bizcons so we had a little face-to-face
in person and we talked about you coming
on the podcast and we talked about
something doing something a little bit
different I've never done this before we
actually do back-to-back episodes with
Dr MJ Coco so I mean your knowledge on
both Coco and led are just extensive and
I didn't really want to merge that into
one episode so I figured hey let's do an
episode on Coco then the next episode
will be on LED and it'll be back to back
so I'm really excited for this one I
think the audience is gonna like it as
well cool I'm excited for it yeah you
know there are two of the sort of things
that I've devoted a lot of time and
energy I started off you know in this
space really talking about growing in
Cocoa
um and a few years ago I got heavy into
researching lights and doing the grow
light calculator and all of that so
that's really where a lot of my passions
been for the last few years but yeah
it's it's fun I'm excited to just to be
able to explore both sides of that with
you cool so the way I like to start all
episodes is really with an introduction
so can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening yeah so
um I have a PhD I actually study
um economic and agricultural
anthropology I work primarily with
farmers in Central America and southern
Mexico
um peasant farming communities and
understanding sort of how how they
manage livelihoods to put a very simply
so how they do their agricultural
production and how they sort of make a
living for themselves
um that got me you know as an
undergraduate and as a graduate student
doing Horticulture and botany classes
especially in in grad school I started
doing sort of more specialized
horticulture and agricultural classes to
understand it and to be able to to sort
of work with Farmers so understanding
both the the you know Horticultural and
Botanical side of agricultural and crop
production and doesn't understand the
economics and and a lot of the social
dimensions of of that
um as a grad student I was one of the
supervisors of the the university
organic garden so
um you know we had a cool organic garden
students could get little plots to to
take care of we had some research going
on out there and we had some classes
that had part of the the garden where
they were doing things I actually taught
a class on small-scale food production
in my garden later on
um so you know in terms of of that
background and then I went and did my my
research and
um you know lived in communities of
farmers for about two years
um doing my dissertation research
um got really
hands-on experience working in those
kinds of of communities but still all
dealing with with you know other kinds
of crops I mean those Farmers grew
primarily the muscle American Trilogy
corn beans and squash
um and you know a few other crops around
the edges of that
um working in the in the gardens growing
you know all sorts of fruits and
vegetables and things like that and here
in Southern California were a lot of
different fruits and vegetables can grow
um and you know it was actually in grad
school that um I was recommended medical
for my arthritis my my rheumatologist
actually and that that sort of brought
me into
that dimension of horticulture
um but I've been studying kind of
horticulture and working with Farmers
for for years leading up to that awesome
so lots of good stuff in your background
in regards to gardening and farming and
even on the Consulting side of things
and teaching people which is really
really cool yeah yeah I've always liked
to teach you know one of the the great
things about sort of moving into this
space in particular is all of our
students are really interested to learn
um I teach University classes too and
then you know University students are
primarily interested in getting a grade
um and most of them will do what they
have to do in order to get the grade but
they're not really interested in
learning the material
and so dealing with Growers who are
growing plants and whether they're sort
of you know commercial scale Growers
they do Consulting work with they're
small home Growers that just have a
couple of plants in a tent in their room
they want to learn I mean they don't
give a crap about doing well on the test
they need to make sure that they Master
the material and like from a teacher's
perspective it's so much more like
joyous to teach students that are
motivated by learning rather than sort
of just motivated by grades
um which is really I want to learn as
little as possible and still get the
grade that I think I deserve that's sort
of the mindset behind that you know and
then there's this other cohort in in
universities that are are just there
because they don't know what else to do
with themselves at that age and time in
their life and they were always told you
know this is the next thing you're
supposed to do so they can go there sort
of somewhat mindlessly I mean the number
of students in your standard university
they're actually primarily motivated by
learning it's like five percent and you
love them when you get those students in
like a regular University class but yeah
as you know Dr MJ Coco I would say it's
the obviously like 95 of the students of
the people that come and that I interact
with are really anxious to sort of gain
access to the knowledge that's so cool
yeah I can imagine that makes your job a
little bit easier
it's so much more fun yeah you're not
sort of force-feeding people stuff and
like this is important is it going to be
on the test yes it's going to be on that
it's just what he wants to teach like
that all right so let's get into growing
in Coco coir and I guess first thing is
to talk about the uh pronunciation I
want I used to say Coco core and
somebody had corrected me and they're
like actually it's Coco coir and I
looked it up I looked on Google and
looked at pronunciation and blah blah
blah and found out they were correct I'm
not going to do the pronunciation police
and say nobody should say Coco core but
I thought it was worth mentioning that I
guess that the proper way to say it is
actually Coco coir you know I'm also a
linguist and I'm more of what we would
call a descriptive linguist than a
prescriptive linguist so you're talking
more like a prescriptive language like
there's a correct way to do things and
we should all follow that Norm and this
is the prescription for how you're
supposed to talk that sounds like you're
high school English teacher taught
English right like there's a proper
pronunciation or proper grammar and all
that stuff most linguists that study
real language they they're they're
descriptive so they'll they'll describe
what people are actually doing rather
than pontificate about sort of what they
should do but they don't you know like
ending a sentence with a preposition or
something like that you know your
English teacher is likely to give you a
prescriptive rule but you go out and
like listen to how people actually talk
in the world and most of them break
those rules all of the time so with this
one in in particular yeah they're I'm
willing to accept different
is sort of pronunciations on it
um but I guess
chewing closely to sort of the the
origin it would be coir
um but I don't know I'm often guilty of
just pronouncing things that the way
that they're written especially on
scripts I did that quite famously in my
how to buffer Coco video or not only do
I call it Coco core but and and I know
better than this I I said
um education instead of ion but it's
like almost impossible for me not to do
that well it is now because I'm sort of
been pounded with that but I was reading
it so reading that word written I just
I'm very tempted to pronounce it and
actually since my background in Spanish
I'm very
tempted to pronounce it according to
Spanish pronunciation rules oftentimes
um that's funny well Tomatoes Tomatoes
right yeah and tomatoes Tomatoes
um and what's really actually
interesting is from a Linguistics
perspective I think it's watching how
language does change and how particular
people influence that language change so
us talking about whether it's Coco core
or coco coir or however you want to
pronounce it has some influence on you
know how other people then go about
talking about it very true so what is
Coco coir it's just coconut husk okay so
it's like the the brown husk of the the
coconut fruit
um which is dried and then ground into
pieces
um and there's basically three different
types of of cocoa you'll get like the
fine particles that are almost like dust
um which we call peat it's cocoa Pete
um and then you can have the fibers
which are like these stringy things
which are the cocoa fibers and then you
get like chips which are
like less broken down still hunks of the
the coconut husk basically
um the the chips have the best uh air
holding capacity
um although the fiber holds on to a lot
of air too so if you have a higher
enough concentration of fiber you'll
have a good air holding capacity the the
peat or the dust holds on to more water
um and less air so it you know you want
to have a blend of peat fiber and chips
when when you're growing and through the
course of time the the chips will break
down into fiber and pee and the peat
breaks down into smaller and smaller and
smaller pieces of peat basically a lot
of that's caused by root action
um we don't want to grow in cocoa that
has too much of the finest peat so
oftentimes we'll rinse it
um through a colander or another screen
or a sieve or something that that lets
the the finest particles sort of rinse
out and keeps the larger particles
behind
um and and doing that you can actually
recycle cocoa
indefinitely
um because
you're sort of getting rid of the oldest
cocoa that's broken down the most each
time and you'll have to add more cocoa
on the top but
um I recommend Growers do that with
their with their cocoa grows there's no
reason to sort of throw it out and get
new cocoa okay and then when you get
cocoa you can either get it in like a
brick form or a bagged form those breaks
of cocoa are compressed just like like
the brick used to be compressed and it's
kind of a lower quality but you can
rehabilitate it to a large extent
um the the bricks have a generally a
larger proportion is dust so a larger
proportion is the finer particles and I
always recommend rehydrating it and
rinsing it through a screen
um and you'll yield less you're gonna
lose a lot of that dust that's kind of
the point
um but you'll end up with a pretty good
quality cocoa if you end up if you sort
of do that the bags
the bags usually have more chips and
more fiber sort of a larger particle
size
and you know you yield more from the bag
the bags are often also pre-buffered so
in theory you could use it sort of right
out of the bag there aren't a lot of
brands of cocoa that I trust right out
of the pack so I almost always end up
processing my cocoa to some extent
before using it even if I buy sort of an
expensive bagged cocoa but the the
processing is certainly less than it
would be with a brick which you have to
go to several steps and you rehydrate
then you rinse it through a screen then
you do a couple buffering soaks then you
drain it off then you rinse down the
residual EC so you don't burn your plant
roots and all of that you know it takes
time
um a couple of days so the bag process
oftentimes you know some Bag products
good bag products I'll just put in a pot
and run some water through it to
saturate it and test the EC of the water
that's coming out and as long as that's
low enough I'll Trust the cocoa
basically sometimes you have to run more
water through it some products I'd
recommend doing a buffering soak and
then rinsing it down but generally
there's just less work to do to get them
prepared they cost more money
um so you know each individual grower
needs to sort of put their own
drudgery to cost index which is actually
one of the things that I study with my
my Farmers
um it's like how much drudgery are you
willing to invest in this and how much
of you know is just spending an extra 20
40 60 80 bucks and you know with that
drudgery are you willing to to pay to
avoid yeah the the rehydrating rinsing
and buffering of the bricks is
definitely time consuming I've done that
uh a handful of times and I personally
prefer buying the bagged cocoa now to
avoid that process but you can imagine
being in a different financial position
and being like I don't know I got time
to burn and I do not have any money so
you know there's there's different sort
of people are at different points of
that continuum absolutely let's get
deeper into the rinsing and buffering
because I know there's quite a few
people who have no idea what that is I
don't know how many Growers have hit me
up over the years with problems of the
plant showing problems there in cocoa
and ask them if they've rinsed their
buffer and they're like What's that so
talk to us about rinsing and buffering
why is it important and how do you go
about doing that I know you have a
really good good video on it so you can
keep it pretty brief and we'll refer
people to that video but yeah if you can
kind of give us an overview here that'd
be great yeah so Coco we talked a little
bit about the dust and particularly in a
brick of cocoa it's going to have more
dust than you want so you're going to
want to rinse that dust out rinsing is
largely just about sort of getting rid
of the smallest particle sizes you're
also going to knock some of the sodium
out of of the cocoa if it comes with
sodium but most of that's going to be
bound in in a you know a cation Bond
um
and you're not going to really deal with
that until you buffer so buffering is
the next step so rinsing I just rinse
through a literally a colander or a
sieve a screen and get rid of the
smallest particles
um collect that and you don't want to
rinse it too thoroughly either you don't
want to get rid of all of the P because
the peat is really what holds the water
but you don't want it to just be sort of
swimming in in the smallest particles
and you'll see this when you start
rinsing it out there's like the water
that comes out is brown and after you
know just a few seconds it's no longer
Brown and that's fine you don't need to
sort of like keep rinsing it out
um then you want to put it in a strong
solution of Cal Mag calmag and iron and
sure but primarily calcium magnesium
um which are both double charged cations
and you know we talk about cocoa being
sort of an inert growing media and and
that's one of the things that we really
like about cocoa I would actually argue
that the air water ratio is a is a
better selling point of cocoa than just
the inert aspect of it
um but it is pretty inner in in that it
doesn't interact with the nutrient water
that we're providing it doesn't interact
with the nutrients it just kind of like
sits there like a sponge and holds the
water but doesn't engage in exchanges
with them the one exception to that is
Coco comes sort of naturally with some
single charged cations that it will give
up and it take double charged cation out
of the solution
and that cation exchange you know
generally Coco comes with some sodium
and some potassium so
um okay
um cations that are sort of already part
of the cocoa
um and in the presence of calcium or
magnesium
the cocoa will release that sodium and
and that phosphor sorry the potassium
and grab onto the calcium or the
Magnesium it creates really strong bonds
with the calcium or the magnesium and
it's unlikely in any situation to
release those calcium and magnesium I
often get this question like once it's
buffered is that like those come on
Exchange sites are buffered they have
their calcium they're happy they're
basically taken out of the equation you
can do almost anything that cocoa at
this point and and not cation exchange
site will not give up its calcium cation
um
however so one of the things that we do
with buffering is we're just trying to
get as many of those exchanges to take
place as possible before adding plans
right so we take this cocoa that's got
this potassium and the sodium and we
soak it in really strong cow mag water
basically and it releases all the
potassium and the sodium and grabs on to
the calcium and magnesium and once it
does that it's it's considered buffered
um if we don't do that in advance and we
use unbuffered cocoa and I don't know if
you've ever had the The Misfortune of
using really unbuffered cocoa but it
will stock all the calcium and magnesium
out of your plants and it's almost
impossible to sort of keep up with
because the cocoa will get the calcium
magnesium before the plants can get it
and almost no matter how much you
provide you're never going to provide
sort of enough to get out of that
deficit
um
if you do a good job buffering before
using the cocoa you can definitely keep
up with the Cal Mag requirements during
the rest of the grow they never fully go
away and and that's important to sort of
understand remember we have cocoa chips
and and cocoa peat
um and the cocoa fibers that are sort of
constantly breaking down largely due to
root action of the plants that we're
growing so as the plants themselves grow
through they break apart the cocoa and
that exposes new cation sites and that
exposes sort of new potassium and sodium
that the plants wanting to release and
grab onto the calcium and magnesium so
the cocoa is always a little thirsty for
calcium magnesium and in Cocoa we always
sort of provide a bonus dose which is
not for the plant it's really for the
cocoa itself the other thing to sort of
be aware of with Coke go is we're almost
always running high in K and that's
because the cocoa has k
um Growers often get themselves in
trouble later in the cycle because
they'll add a PK boost
um a bloom booster which just creates K
talk so so potassium toxicity potassium
toxicity can lock out calcium and
magnesium it can create other issues so
growers in Cocoa often face issues when
trying to use those those PK boosters
just because there's already a lot of K
so be aware of that other sort of
dimension of it so let's say they have a
properly rinsed and buffered their cocoa
organic or synthetic nutrients let's get
into that so do you use or recommend
organic or synthetic nutrients when
growing in cocoa that is an interesting
question in an outdoor setting in field
Agriculture and in gardening I always
recommend and organic models and really
biodynamic models where we try to sort
of cultivate the ecology on the farm so
the soil level and farm level ecology so
you
I mean to increase sustainability and
decrease the the throughput of chemical
fertilizers right of fossil fuels I mean
most of what we're growing our food with
these days are
nitrogen potassium phosphorus
fertilizers derived from natural gas
fossil fuel and the the process to
create them is incredibly energy in it
you know intensive so
um they're they're made with and they're
made from fossil fuels
um and you know Global agriculture on
the large scale is is supported by that
when we think about sort of how we use
fossil fuels going forward to so much of
our Global agriculture sort of dependent
on natural gas as a feedstock for
nitrogen fertilizer that like it where
you know you could argue we're eating
fossil fuel energy on a massive scale it
would sort of puts a lot of those
considerations into a different
perspective I think than people are
often used to looking at fossil fuels
um and that's something I'm really
interested in you know since my
undergraduate days is sustainability in
agriculture and
you know one of the rubs here and it's
something that
we've all decided to sort of go past
this but indoor farming under artificial
lights is not sustainable and it's very
energy intensive and
um it uses energy in sort of a wildly
different way than Farmers have ever
used energy before
um you know for the first 10 000 years
that our species was Farmers like we
used almost exclusively human and animal
energy
um and as we started sort of
supplementing fossil fuel energy over
the last just you know 150 years
um for the first half of that time it
was it was basically for transportation
of the food but now again so much of the
energy that we used in in regular
agriculture outdoor agriculture is in
the fertilizers that we're applying to
maintain crop yields
um and so
like that just use of energy and the
sustainability of that have completely
shifted into this dangerous sort of
territory and I think rightly a lot of
people have become concerned with global
agriculture
um and sort of the the source of our
food and and whether we'll be able to
maintain these kinds of yields under
biodynamic models that was something I
looked at a lot as a graduate student
you know how can we conserve how can we
maintain sort of the the Green
Revolution yields without using the
Green Revolution fertilizers and it's
possible and we need to sort of continue
to investigate that
foreign
we definitely understand that
crops
are you know more efficient in in their
specific return when we're able to dial
in nutrition so crop yields for example
in the global North crop yields on
um conventional acreage is a little over
and this is somewhat dated information
from like the
2010s around 2010
um crop yields were about two and a half
times
um as on organic cropland
primarily due to fertilization issues
um in the global South
biodynamic farming is actually able to
match the yields of conventional
agriculture but they invest a
tremendously tremendously more labor per
acre than they do in the global North
and so basically we're able to to
exchange our fossil fuel energy for
human labor can can take over a lot of
that but where the cost of Labor is high
those those balances don't work out and
I've spent literally years sort of
trying to understand and asking students
in questioning classes like do you guys
want to become peasants because like
that's one way we can create sort of
assist animal worlds we all go back to
being peasants
um but if we all insist on having these
you know consumer Lifestyles it's more
sort of problematic and where we demand
other people produce all of our food so
we don't have to produce any of it
indoor agriculture it's all about lights
and it's all about maintaining climate
and like we choose to do that because of
legal concerns and I think I think you
know that makes sense with some other
crops
you know they choose to grow indoors
other crops in places like Iceland
Iceland's got a thriving indoor
Horticulture industry for you know
vegetables because they don't have any
sun or not enough of it and they got
tons of geothermal energy so energy is
cheap they can power you know LED lights
indoors and and justify growing lower
value crops
um you know otherwise we're spending so
much energy on the lights and the
climate control growing indoors we have
to be growing a high value crop
otherwise it doesn't even make sense and
the amount of energy that we're spending
on lighting
absolutely dwarfs the amount of energy
that we're spending on fertilizers just
dwarfs it just like makes pennies out of
it it's like the amount of energy that
we're investing in fertilizers is now
like no longer even part of the equation
that makes sense to pay attention to and
if we want to farm sustainably indoors a
we have to recognize that we really
can't we're choosing to do something
that's unsustainable because there's no
other way to do it and we've decided
that you know a certain crop is valuable
enough to us that we're making that that
decision anyways basically and I think
all
you know Growers that are growing
indoors for legal reasons for other
kinds of reasons are making that that
decision like look growing this plant is
important enough to me that like I'm
doing that even though I got to run
these really powerful lights indoors and
even though you know it's not going to
be the most sustainable thing in the
long run when you're making those
decisions I think it becomes imperative
now that you think about how to limit
your overall sort of consumption how to
grow the best crop you can with the
least amount of energy and since we're
already sort of blowing our energy
Budget on lighting and climate control
then you know how do we tap into the
best of what we know about all other
forms of Agriculture so that we can have
these plants humming so that they don't
you know have to want for anything and
so that we can guarantee Harvest success
and the reality there is the most
sustainable I mean I really looked into
this before growing myself the most
sustainable way and the only real way
that I could justify indoor Horticulture
coming from a background of of a sort of
sustainable agriculture was to grow
conventionally and to grow
hydroponically so soillessly cocoa is a
form of Hydroponics I think that growing
in Cocoa is far more efficient with
water than dwc for example this is the
reason I don't grow in dwc you know dwc
Growers dump far more water down the
drain than cocoa Growers do even cocoa
Growers they have the the sort of awful
name for this which is drained to waste
and that is the way that I grow drain to
waste but the amount of water that I'm
sending on the waste is is dwarfed to
whenever a dwc grower has to change out
their tanks and they're sending all
their water down the drain or they're
sending all their water someplace
um I'm only sending a cup a day for my
little grow you know or a quart a day or
something like that really small amounts
that aren't actually repurpose all of my
runoff for house plants
um this tiny amount of it so drain to
house plant or whatever
um but yeah so that's basically and and
you know there are ways to do this U.S
this original question with Organics or
conventional fertilizers or synthetic
fertilizers so I use synthetic
fertilizers there are some organic
fertilizers that that can be substituted
for them but I I haven't found them to
be you know an advent an advantage from
a sustainability angle in in terms of
thinking about how much energy are they
going to slow my crop down at all
um because if I have to run you know an
extra week in veg I've blown my margins
and whatever you're trying to save for
me or if this puts you know in any way
my crop at risk like I've blown my
margins I'm also aware now that a lot of
people sort of follow the way that I
grow you know pretty closely in terms of
my specific dosages of nutrients my
recipe my frequency of fertigation all
of these things and so it's important
that you know cumulatively
we're aware of the impact that we have
and and that we're sort of doing this
consciously in a way to to try to reduce
that I get a lot of pushback from
organic Growers that think that their
style of growing is responsible and my
style of growing is sort of
irresponsible and I I want to just
suggest to All Growers that it really
requires thinking deeper through these
problems and recognizing especially in
an indoor Horticulture like where does
our impact really come from what and how
can we responsibly sort of work to to
minimize that
um
so it was from that perspective that you
know my background's not in in grad
school my background was working with
field agriculture Farmers that were
using synthetic and kind of organic
styles of fertilization but like they
weren't growing in Cocoa core they
weren't growing hydroponically
um all of that that really came when I
decided to to grow my own
um indoors that yeah I I wanted to be to
figure out and to sort of use the
experience that I did have and kind of I
was still a grad student sort of my
penchant for doing that kind of research
to figure out the best way to minimize
this impact to to do the most efficient
Garden this is also incidentally why I'm
so sort of interested in lights and what
I really test about lights is how
efficient they are and sort of how well
they distribute the light and all of
that because we're doing this for making
that decision to grow indoors let's do
it as well as we possibly can understood
yeah I think a lot of my audience are
indoor home Growers kind of similar to
me and I feel like a lot of folks are
using synthetic nutrients so let's
narrow down the conversation a little
bit to indoors and let's let's talk a
little bit about using synthetic
nutrients with cocoa before we get into
like EC and pH and stuff like that
aeration options I know there are some
people who are adding in like I used to
add in perlite some people had Thomas
vermiculite lava rock there's a lot of
different aeration options what aeration
options do you recommend and at what
ratio aeration to Cocoa
if
they even container size
um container size depends primarily on
watering frequency
um
so if you're going to be the type of
grower that only wants to to water their
plants once or twice a day and I I
realize that might sound like pretty
frequently but I advocate high frequency
fertigation in in Cocoa so
um higher than that so once or twice a
day
um you're going to want a larger
container
um if you're going to go five six times
a day you're going to be able to get
away with a smaller container and I
encourage you to kind of think of the
container that you're growing in as like
the cup that you give like your your
guests at a party okay and so if you
give them a small cup you better be
running around and refilling their cups
all of the time right if you give them a
larger cup like you know you don't have
to fill up their cups all the time so
watering in a sense is filling up the
cup right
um and yeah if you're going to water six
times a day then you can grow big plants
in a one gallon container and I I
totally endorse that style
um if you're gonna only water once a day
then you can grow that same plant in a
three or five gallon container and that
would be a better option now your
question is actually about perlite right
so perlite ratio depends on the size of
the container and to some extent your
watering frequency as well
larger containers I like to put more
perlite in more of that aeration in
General it certainly aerates per like
certainly aerates it's really what we're
hoping to get out of that perlite is
improved drainage
um
cocoa holds on to water a little bit too
well
basically so we like to encourage the
water to to drain out a little bit
easier and that's one of the good things
that the perlite does coco unless you
have all dust remember talking about
like chips and you have fibers in
addition to your dust then cocoa stays
pretty well oxygenated even if it's pure
cocoa and even if it's at Field capacity
which means like fully saturated
um there's still oxygen available to the
plant
um so
but what happens if you're in a large
enough container and
you know it's the dissolved oxygen in
the water accounts for a large
proportion of the available oxygen to
plants and if you're watering
infrequently especially if you're
watering less than once per day
especially if the the water sitting in
the pots is above 70 degrees which it
almost always is in our Gardens after a
few hours there's not going to be a lot
of dissolved oxygen in that water it's
going to be hypoxic and if you have an
area that doesn't have a lot of roots
um
so the roots are actually where most of
the water gets taken off right we often
think about the water sort of like just
pouring through the pots but we're we're
filling a cup and then the the plant is
like drinking that cup right this is one
of the reasons we transplant up to make
sure there's Roots all the way in the
center because it's really in the right
in the middle of like you have a big pot
right in the middle of that pot The
Roots tend to grow around it they grow
out to the edges they grow it onto the
bottom and they'll leave this area in
the middle of the pot that doesn't have
a lot of roots sucking out the water and
the water is allowed to get sort of like
stagnant there if it doesn't have enough
perlite to sort of vertically flow
through it'll become hypoxic and that's
basically a dead zone for roots because
there's no Oxygen for them so if you're
growing in like a big container get a
lot of aeration in the middle of that
make sure that you know the water is
going to continue to move through there
because Roots like that area less and it
tends to become sort of stagnant and and
not
as as well sort of oxygenated
um conversely if you're growing a big
plant in a one gallon pot you don't need
perlite in fact hey adding too much
perlite just sort of cuts down on the
amount of water that you can store in
that pot because you know a one gallon
pot that's full up with 100 cocoa can
hold a little over half a gallon of
water
um a one gallon pot that's stock full of
like 50 50 cocoa per light can hold less
than half a gallon of water
um so you're you're sort of cutting back
sort of the reservoir function of the
pot for the plants and that's going to
require you to increase fertigation more
um so yeah it depends I go anywhere from
no per light to only like 10 to 20
sometimes up to 50 per light in a larger
container with less frequent watering so
perlite is your go-to you don't
recommend like vermiculite or lava rock
any of those other options
um
and per lead's definitely my go-to or
one of the the specific perlite
substitutes I I don't think vermiculite
is a good substitute for perlite in
Cocoa for this purpose at least
vermiculite tends to hold on to water
more
um it does do some of the same aeration
but it's not as good at sort of eating
and drainage as perlite is
um Lava Rock can work for this
um there are other things that you can
substitute per life for and I'm aware
that some Growers don't like to use
perlite specifically I will say there's
a couple of drawbacks to using perlite
that should be mentioned I think
whenever it's brought up do not allow
yourself to breathe perlite dust ever
ever it's rock dust it it
causes it it's like so much worse than
smoking I mean it's moments worse than
like anything else you can do get a
respirator a ventilator do it in an
outdoor space at least we're like a n95
mask or something just I see so many
people either on sort of videos or in
real life or walking through commercial
facilities where people are dealing with
perlite just breathing In This Cloud of
perlite dust
um disaster don't don't put yourself in
that situation it's rock Dusty it kill
you so that's one of the issues
perlite's also you know a mind resource
and there's a limited sort of Global
Supply of perlite
um but we're not sort of at a threshold
I actually think the
peat is a bigger issue to be worried
about and concerned in those regards in
terms of you know how how sustainable
the mining of the resource is good
advice on the mass I don't wear a mask
and I probably should I don't really
hear people talking about the safety
behind handling perlite so I'll
definitely be wearing a mask moving
forward yeah get the vents on or
whatever you can do to I mean whenever
you pour and get it wet right away is to
knock down that cloud of dust right but
if you get a bag of perlite and you pour
it you're gonna have this like cloud of
rock dust that you get to breathe in oh
yeah let's switch it up let's get into
pH of uh you know specifically when
growing with synthetic nutrients in
Cocoa what is the optimal PH range
it's hydroponic So the plan is for the
most part interacting directly with the
water it's not sort of mitigated by any
other cation exchange or microbial
activity or anything like that so we
keep generally for for hydroponic
nutrients the pH between 5.5 and and 6.5
is what's often quoted I would never
kind of push out those extremes
um calcium is more available at the
higher end of that range so early on I
usually recommend growers in Cocoa start
at like 6.2 ish
um but then by early veg have worked
down you know in the high fives and
allowed the pH to sort of drift up pH
almost always drifts up if you're mixing
nutrient water so to set it like 5.8 and
allow it to drift up to six and
6.2
um you know in that range allowing it to
drift back and forth a little bit
ensures that plants have good access to
the different chelated nutrients that
are sort of more accessible at different
points along that pH scale
um you don't want to drill it in at 5.6
for too long basically because calcium
is not very available that low you also
don't want to sort of drill it in at 6.4
for too long phosphorus isn't very
available there so keeping it kind of in
the middle of that range the other thing
I suggest with most forms of a
Hydroponics certainly with any form of
drain to waste Hydroponics
is to only measure the inflow pH don't
measure the outflow or the runoff pH now
in our dwc recirculating systems you
know you got to measure both it's all
kind of the same thing
um and in dwc you got to just measure
the whatever they're sitting in but in a
drained away setting where you're doing
top feed in Cocoa the important thing
about pH is that the water that you're
providing has nutrients that are
accessible you are not you really can't
stress this enough you are not trying to
like change the runoff pH by altering
the inflow pH that's a Fool's errand
I've seen dozens and dozens of Growers
torch their plants by doing that their
runoff pH starts to drift High often is
what happens and so they'll just go
lower and lower and lower with the
inflow and they're telling me I'm
feeding at five and I'm still getting
these plant issues and my runoff is
still 6.8 or something it's like okay
stop feeding at five like you can't you
can't do that that's a problem you
should never go so you can chase Your
Tail like that so easily and just run
yourself right out of sort of what the
acceptable range is so much so I tell
Growers literally don't measure the
runoff pH expect it to swing because
because of cation exchange with the
plant
um you know things are going to happen
to that water it's going to knock around
that pH oftentimes it's not a problem
we'll never look at the pH the runoff pH
except as a secondary sort of diagnosis
diagnosis tool if you're having problems
with with maintaining EC for example if
you're runoff EC is always high so you
do check the runoff EC but not the pH
but if it's always high and we can't
knock it down eventually I'm going to
tell okay let's figure out what the EC
or what the pH is and we'll try to get
deeper into a diagnosis about what's
going on like that but no as part of
your general practice make sure the
water you're providing to the the plant
is in the correct range and just don't
even worry about what the runoff's
coming I'm glad you mentioned that I've
always had good luck going 5.8 pH going
in and when I first started using cocoa
I was checking the runoff I was coming
across that same exact issue that you
mentioned it's like why is it 6.8 feet
why is it 7 pH runoff right and so I was
scrambling and it's so tempting to go
like five and then lower on the inflow
right I read to ignore the runoff pH and
so ever since I've been doing that my
plants have been fantastic so um yeah
I'm really glad you mentioned that one
yeah now as far as water that they that
you're giving it to them and that's the
cool thing about about this style of
growing anyways is like no matter how
screwed up Situation's gotten in their
pot like I can still give them good
water that I know is is correct now
that's the most important thing give
them good water that you know is correct
now
um now EC sometimes we do sort of if the
EC is getting too high in the runoff you
go lower on the inflow to sort of
correct for that
um
and I don't know if that's where you're
going next but that's probably where we
should that's why I was going to ask
about next is EC or some people actually
you know measure PPM instead you know
same thing just different calculation
but different stages of growth the
plants different nutrient requirements
some people start with a low EC and then
work their way up talk to us about EC
and Coco yeah so first let's talk a
little bit about EC versus PPM EC is a
measure of the electrical conductivity
and if you have an EC or a PPM or a TDS
or what's just called a quality or water
quality meter what it's measuring is
easy it's got a little probe two little
electrical Pros it's passing an
electrical current through the water and
it's measuring sort of how easy that
current flows through the water
um
what
why that's important is well a few
things but it that tells you how many
sort of dissolved solids are in the
water if there's no dissolved solids in
the water then you know it's very hard
to pass an electrical current through
water but if you have a chock full of
calcium then it's pretty easy to pass
the current through the water so the EC
reading tells you sort of how salty
because all those things that are
dissolved in the water we can just
consider them and think about them as
being salt okay so it's basically
telling you how salty the water is
now PPM
is parts per million
and parts per million tries to tell you
how many sort of parts per million in
this water are are different things so
for example how many parts of calcium
and phosphorus and iron and potassium
and sodium like are in this
now would a PPM meter does is it
measures the electrical conductivity and
then using a formula it says okay if the
electrical conductivity is this then I
assume so much of this water so much of
that is coming from calcium because in
most water in most places around the
world the bulk of the electrical
conductivity comes from calcium calcium
is a double charge count on so it has
sort of a bigger impact on electrical
conductivity than on PPM each
unit of calcium there's only one PPM but
has a double charge so if you have one
unit of calcium and one unit of sodium
you know you're gonna have your PPM
would be maybe two out of a million
right
um but your electrical conductivity is
going to be higher because of that
calcium being one of the two so in order
to make an estimate about sort of how
many how much stuff is in the water all
we know is how easy it is to pass
electricity through it how much stuff is
in the water you know there's different
formulas for for figuring that up this
is why we have different PPM scales in
Europe there's less calcium in the water
than there is in the Americas in general
so when you're making an estimate about
from electrical conductivity two parts
per million you're going to assume that
sort of there must be more other stuff
because I think there's a little bit
smaller ratio of calcium and and that
gives them sort of the scale the 700 PPM
scale in the United States where calcium
is is tends to be in larger proportion
throughout the air Americas calcium
tends to be in large proportion we use
500 scale and that's just a different
formula for going from you know what the
meter is measuring is the electrical
conductivity to like different
assumptions about what must be in that
water to arrive at a gas and it's really
just a guess about what that PPM is so
if you have a PPM meter your meter is
measuring electrical conductivity and
then using a formula to guess what the
actual PPM is
there's another way we can approach
coming at PPM right where we could like
get a a scale and you know dry nutrients
and we can actually
weigh out and and know exactly sort of
how many parts calcium and how many
parts phosphorus and how many parts you
know everything that that we put in the
water and we could describe that and you
know you can reverse engineer this if
you get good information from your
nutrient companies in terms of what your
PPM actually is and from that angle we
think about PPM in terms of dosing like
how many parts per million do we want of
calcium how many parts per million do we
want of phosphorus how many parts per
million do we want and I think when
we're thinking in terms of parts per
million like people tend to think about
it in terms of all these different
nutrients and like you know that's one
thing that I often get from people it's
like well why does the PPM matter
doesn't it matter like what the PPM of
nitrogen and and phosphorus and and you
know potassium is why do I just need one
number that describes all of that and
and that's a damn good point we don't
need one PPM number and that's that's
not why we're measuring EC
now all you have is a PPM meter you can
basically sort of crib off of that
because what your meter is actually
measuring is EC anyways right but what
we're doing this for and why we measure
it has nothing to do with making sure
there's enough nitrogen and enough
phosphorus and enough potassium and
enough calcium and and making sure those
dosages are right we never use
electrical conductivity to measure dose
of specific nutrients we measure
electrical conductivity to understand
the overall salinity of the water
because the overall salinity of the
water it affects the plant's ability to
get water not the applicability to get
nitrogen and phosphorus and calcium like
we basically assume oh that's there
because I followed a recipe and I'm
using like reputable nutrients right so
the ratios better be there based on the
products that you're using but if you
provide too much of them and you're
giving your plant the this water that's
then really salty the plant will not be
able to get the water so we need to be
able to keep the the sort of overall
electrical conductivity in a Range where
the plant a sort of is trained for it
and B expects it
um and for the most part I think Growers
try to sort of push their plants a
little bit too much in electrical
conductivity thinking about it in terms
of I want to provide more nutrients I
want to provide more nutrients I want to
like push the gas pedal but what you
don't realize is as you're pushing the
gas pedal you're making osmosis harder
um so in order to get water
right if there's like a cell membrane
there's water inside the root and then
there's water like in the cocoa in this
case on the outside of the root right if
the water outside the root is really
salty
and the plant gets water through osmosis
so the plant needs to increase the the
concentration of the solution of the
water inside the root basically it does
this by manufacturing sugars so that
there's a higher concentration of sugars
in the water inside the root than the
concentration of salts in the water
outside the root and and that allows
water to flow into the root because
water flows from osmosis across that
sort of gradient from the area of of
lower concentration to the higher
concentration of dissolved solids
um so your plant can be trained for a
higher a higher electrical conductivity
basically you can like gradually work
plants up and up and up and they'll keep
manufacturing more sugars and more
sugars in their roots to be able to sort
of continue to absorb this water despite
the increasing salinity and some Growers
can get away with sort of Tran training
their plants to take a pretty high
electrical conductivity
um I don't necessarily think that's
beneficial but like plants can be
trained that way but if you jump
electrical conductivity too fast they've
been used to say like 1.0 and you
suddenly go to like 2.0 like you've
doubled it
there's not going to be enough sugar in
The Roots
and there's gonna be so much salt in the
water outside the ridge that water
literally gets sucked out of the root if
you ever poured salt on a slug that is
what happens in this situation so water
actually can get pulled out of the root
through osmosis so the reason we test
electrical conductivity is all about
osmosis and it's really all about
keeping that electrical conductivity in
the range that the plant is expecting if
it goes down too much the plant starts
taking in more water than it wants to
take in it quickly has to convert those
sugars to starches and and sort of to
stop that process that that requires
energy that the plant is not growing
with and if the electrical conductivity
quickly goes up then the plant has to
manufacture new sugars using energy that
now it's not using to grow with so if
you're swaying the electrical
conductivity up and down and back and
forth I know a lot of Growers do an
alternating flush where basically it's
one watering at like a really high EC
the next watering plain water the next
watering really high EC the next
watering plain water your poor Plant is
just like oh I it's salty I gotta
increase sugars oh it's not salty I
gotta process those sugars into stalts
or into starches oh it's salty again I
got a menu and you're just making your
plant work every single day to adjust to
the salinity level of the water so sort
of the the number one thing that I think
if you're using you know an EC if you're
and some people fertilize with much
lower ECS and that's sort of okay to go
back and forth in in terms of that but
it's
in a style like Coco certainly you'll
pick up a lot if you just go to feed
every time at the right dose key plants
love consistency plants really love
consistency that's like my number one
sort of theoretical idea about plants
um keep just keep them at that level
that they're good with the electrical
conductivity don't be swinging them
around and they'll be able to sort of
invest much more energy into growth than
than they would if you're swinging them
around like that
um
so when we're growing in Cocoa
we want to know the electrical
conductivity of the water that goes in I
have a fairly low Target uh 1.5 is
pretty much the the highest I'll ever
put my inflow uh um so 1500 or 1.5 on an
EC scale
and
you know we want to monitor the the
runoff
so that the runoff is not getting too
much higher than the inflow
um so if I'm going in at 1.5 or 1500 and
again this is like late flower like
that's the highest that I ever get my
info EC up to
um 1.2 is sort of where I'd be in veg
for most of the time or an earlier
flower
um so if I'm going in it's a 1.2 then I
want my runoff to be within 1.5
1.6 is going to start raising my
eyebrows it goes above 1.6 and I'm going
to start to take action to bring the
runoff EC back down
um so I want to keep it within 300
within 400 it's usually okay but in that
range so above what the inflow is
um usually we can expect the the
electrical conductivity will go up in
between watering events so when you
think about the water that you're adding
to the top of the plant that's new water
the water that comes out the bottom is
not that water the water that comes out
the bottom is all old water it's already
been sitting and it kind of gets pushed
out the plant as what new water gets
added to the top the old water has been
sitting there for a while and we would
expect that the EC is going to be higher
because generally the plant removes
water faster than it removes nutrients
and so nutrients sort of accumulate in
the pot and the electrical conductivity
goes up in between fertigation events
and if we notice that it's going up too
much so the runoff is now like two right
I I fed at 1.5 or 1500 and it's coming
out at 2 or 2 000 then the problem we
need to feed more frequently that's the
first thing that I would think I'm
giving too much time in between these
events and that's allowing the EC to
creep up too high increasing the
frequency or the decreasing the interval
between feeding events is likely to
resolve the issue and that's the best
way to resolve that issue
um if you can't for whatever reason
um you know you can try increasing
quantity but that results in additional
runoff or lowering the the inflow
electrical conductivity to sort of allow
for a light or larger rise now Growers
that are in that are only able to
fertigate like once or twice a day
generally have to sort of allow for a
larger rise than Growers that can
fertigate you know five or six times a
day so lots of good information there
one area I actually want to get into
which is somewhat controversial
inoculating with microbe specifically
when growing cocoa and using synthetic
nutrients now there are some people that
say it's beneficial they've seen a
benefit inoculating with microbes
utilizing microbes during that grow
there are other people that say this is
completely false you should not be
inoculating with microbes because the
medium is inert the nutrient parents are
already in a form that's available for
the plant uptake so the microbes don't
have any value what's your take on that
you know I certainly think they have
less value than they do in other styles
of fertilization
um but regardless of style of
fertilization there are some microbial
activity that works in this energy and
in the rhizosphere so in in the roots
that Aid in nutrient uptake
um even in a cocoa grow even in a dwc
grow even in a dwc grow that that's
running sterile
um you know with like a high
concentration of hydrogen peroxide there
are still symbiotic relationships with
bacteria in the roots so there are like
every style of growing
sort of requires some bacteria in some
Styles we need to maintain that better
and you know I think organic Growers
that are depending on sort of breaking
down organic fertilizers
um into sort of plant accessible Farms
can really get a huge Boost from sort of
inoculating with some bacteria or
inoculating with different
microorganisms that at the right time of
their grow
um and you know treating that one of the
challenge is with any kind of is
synthetic drain to waste system in
particular is
you know the whole idea of drain to
waste is we're getting rid of some
things we're sort of flushing a little
bit out each watering event
um and it makes it somewhat harder to to
maintain uh you know microbial
communities we're also not necessarily
feeding them anything so you know in
organic nutrients Growers sometimes use
stuff like for example a fairly famous
one is molasses
um which is really used primarily to
feed you know microbes that then feed
the plant it's not necessarily used to
feed the plant directly
um and you know if you're not using
those things it becomes a little bit
sort of less beneficial
um but there are still times and places
for that I don't do a great deal of
inoculation
um but I'm aware of that I kind of lean
towards the side where we are able to
take control of of a lot of the
fertilization and sort of you know a lot
of what the plant's able to absorb and
uptake
um I guess the downside would be wasting
money and resources using a product that
you're not sort of getting a benefit
from
um but I I don't think that there's a
downside in terms of you know doing that
is going to screw up your plant or is
necessarily going to cause problems
either
um so I like to I always like to
separate practices grower practice
because there's all sorts of different
grower practices out there into things
that are you know
beneficial harmful and then probably not
either
um you know beneficial or harmful
practices and I I would put a lot of the
ways synthetic Growers use
microbes as
probably not beneficial or harmful
um
at least in the root zones like that
it it's it's tough
um I mean I suppose on the other side of
this is that is one of the reasons why
we're growing this style
um why we're investing in in those
nitrogen fertilizers for example at this
scale I think that it makes sense but
we're like I said at the top of the
podcast we get those nitrogen
fertilizers from natural gas and in a
really energy intensive process in order
to sort of separate the nitrogen from
the the not hydrocarbons
um
and I I you know at the scale that we're
growing and considering these other
things I I tend to think that that makes
it worth it and that does sort of
alleviate the need to practice dpology
within our Gardens
um I still like taking that ecological
approach where it makes sense to and
where it makes sense too at that point
is more in sort of the IPM side on the
pesticide side on the you know
beneficial insects and and that
ecological approach in terms of working
with Biology to solve our problems as
opposed to sort of trying to be God
um but I'll admit there's a certain
aspect of my style of growing where I'm
trying to sort of be God in this
situation I figure I have to create the
Sun for these plants so I'm gonna try to
sort of hand feed them everything else
as well that makes sense so we are
coming up towards the end of the episode
here and I want to ask you is there
anything else in regards to growing Coco
using synthetics that you wanted to
cover in this episode that we didn't
cover you know I think
we come
um I I don't think that that's sort of
the only reason to grow in Coco but I I
think that it's important it's a point
that I like to make to people because
it's something that's important to me
and if you if you guys are interested
out there in the audience in terms of
sort of being sustainable with your home
grow to think more about some of these
other dimensions I think sometimes
choosing quote unquote organic options
is sort of like you know in maybe more
about the the karma relief as opposed to
the actual environmental relief that
you're getting out of that in certain
situations so to think through this and
and I think that that's important I
think talking about calcium magnesium
and cocoa is always important in sort of
getting that message about buffering and
continuing to provide a calmac dose in
the water
um high frequency fertigation you know
the fact that cocoa even at Field
capacity holds on to adequate oxygen for
the roots so I'm definitely on the side
that there is no such thing as over
watering
really in any kind of Agriculture what
happens isn't that the plants have too
much water what happens is that the
plants don't have enough oxygen so all
of the things that we're used to
thinking about in terms of quote unquote
over watering and if you're coming from
peat or if you're coming from heaven
forbid soil which isn't peat most
Growers that think they're growing in
quote unquote soil are actually growing
in peace soil and in this sense would be
like dirt like you know sand silt clay
um
you're used to having to really limit
the amount of water that you provide or
having to create a dry bag period and
all of this is really about maintaining
adequate oxygen for the roots it's not
about starving the plants of water but
the only way to get them adequate oxygen
in The Roots is starving them from water
but if if over watering was just about
over watering like dwc would not be a
thing it wouldn't be a way to grow
plants right because they always have
too much water it's not about too much
water it's about oxygenated water
and yeah so cocoa can be watered almost
constantly because it maintains adequate
oxygen and when you're watering it you
know frequently a lot of the oxygen
itself comes from the dissolved oxygen
in the water it's important to keep your
water if you're depending on that below
70 degrees Fahrenheit so I usually like
to keep my water right at like 68
degrees Fahrenheit because above 70
there's not the ability of water to hold
dissolved oxygen basically drops off a
cliff at about 70 degrees Fahrenheit
like at 68 water can hold a lot of
dissolved oxygen at 72 it can hold
almost none so it really helps to sort
of think about that in terms of water
temperature that's also if you're ever
running a res with these systems to keep
the res cooler because if it gets above
70 degrees Fahrenheit the oxygen levels
drop and that's when you start to grow
bacteria in your tanks and you're going
to have to do cleaning more frequently
and all the rest of that so if you have
a watering system or a tank that you
have to clean all the time get it a
little bit colder drop it below 70
degrees and you'll sort of resolve those
issues
um
I I think that's most of it I could
probably ramble on for a few more
minutes but I think we did Cover a lot
of the the key points and you know I got
a lot of other
resources and and articles
um videos on this stuff so if you're
interested in in more of that I invite
you to come and check out our stuff
definitely some good information there
uh yeah we touch upon a lot you know
growing in Cocoa using synthetics I mean
I think that we could even do another
episode in the future at some point
cocoa and Organics or even cocoa and
synganic right because a lot of people
are mixing the two and growing the cocoa
yeah maybe we could do something like
that in the future you know this organic
mood is like I'm gonna take what makes
sense from different things and apply
them to my grow and I like that style of
growing where you know you think through
things and you figure out what makes
sense as opposed to just going with
something because of the label that it
has or thinking that it's safe or not
safe because of the label that it has so
I I endorse and sort of
identify with that style if you guys
tuning into this want to see that talk
definitely comment below and let us know
you want to see a part two on Coco and
we can definitely get into that but yeah
let's wrap things up final words how can
listeners find you and did you have
anything upcoming in the future that you
want to talk about yeah so I have a a
YouTube channel Dr MJ Coco on YouTube
um I have some videos like we mentioned
about Coco
um and growing and Coco like my
germination tutorial I do a lot of of
grow light reviews and I know next time
that we come on uh we'll talk about
Horticultural lighting and sort of what
we're interested in in Horticultural
lighting how to compare evaluate
different lights and so you'll find a
lot of that kind of content on my
YouTube channel
um I also run the website Coco for
cannabis.com
um so you'll be able to find uh my
articles we have a big Community
um we do grow challenges which are
basically collaborative grow alongs
um right now we're in the middle of the
New Year grow challenge which started on
January 1st
um and a few hundred Growers growing
together in that
um we also find all my my grow light
reviews and everything else there so and
those are the two big ones I'm also on
Instagram
um and and do some things there but I do
some other podcasts and stuff but um
yeah check out my YouTube channel and
come visit us awesome well I'll
definitely have a link to YouTube
channel down in the YouTube video
description section below so you can
easily get to his channel and stay tuned
for next week next week he's gonna be on
again Dr MJ Coco and we're going to talk
about Led LEDs are the present and the
future of of Horticultural lighting
there's really sort of no question about
that
um regardless sometimes hit me up with
questions about like well something else
is going to come next or some new
technology it's like ain't maybe but
LEDs are already about 90 efficient in
terms of energy transfer so it's it's
hard to see sort of how another
technology could come on I'm gonna be
much more efficient than the they're
pretty phenomenal in in terms of sort of
how LEDs themselves work I think
understanding a bit more about them can
really help Growers become better sort
of consumers of grow light fixtures on
the market too because I think a lot of
Manufacturers are taking advantage of
the fact that Growers don't know a lot
about indoor lighting for Horticulture
and so
manufacturers are able to sort of
manipulate Growers and and try to
convince them of a bunch of BS and
that's been happening for years and my
big passion there is to try to arm
Growers with sort of the the knowledge
that they need so they're not sold a
bill of goods right so that they
actually can go out there and evaluate
grow lights and and make good product
decisions so yeah I definitely look
forward to getting into that and talking
about how to evaluate and why even what
we're looking for why LEDs are what I
say the future of Horticultural lighting
all of that so I'm excited about that
topic I'm excited for that one as well
so look forward to that next week as
always hit the Thumbs Up Button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend I'm
releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode I love you too tune in Dr MJ
Coco once again thanks so much for
coming on I can't wait for that talk
next week hope you enjoy the rest of
your day peace out everyone take care it
was a pleasure girl we love everyone