coming up on garden talk
so like when you look at soils or like
pro-mix hp the pro-mix high porosity
with mycorrhizae it has almost no
mycorrhizae in it because they put it in
it like a per yard rate and it's really
small to begin with but they have
mycorrhizae on the label microbes are
able to act like a buffer and they're
able to deliver nutrition at much wider
ranges of ph especially when you have a
good consortia or breakdown of the
different microbes that are in there a
lot of people don't realize with amino
acids if they're not in their l form
they are not plant available at all so
like it has to be l amino acids or your
plants not going to be able to utilize
them at all they actually make compounds
that help the plant be able to have a
more like fibrous and dense root system
the bacillus and the different types of
trichodermal fungi that can be in there
are going to be the ones that are doing
the majority of the work for everything
while mycorrhizae gets all the fame
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this is episode number 27. in
this episode i talk with guru from the
do grow show he has been gardening for
11 years and grows a variety of plants
such as tomatoes cucumbers blueberries
blackberries medicinal varieties beets
and more in this episode we talk all
about microbes he talks about several
different types of microbes and how they
benefit plant growth thanks to all of
you that support this podcast through
patreon if you'd like to support you can
do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before i go any further i want
to acknowledge that this podcast is part
of my desire and effort to bring zero
costs for information about gardening to
the general public in keeping with that
theme i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's podcast
a big supporter of this podcast is
spider farmer they sponsor this podcast
and i use their led grow lights spider
farmer now has a bar style series of led
grow lights they have the se 3000 a four
bar fixture for a three foot by three
foot grow space the se 5000 a six bar
fixture for a four foot by four foot
grow space and the sc7000 a six bar
fixture for a five foot by five foot
grow space i will leave a link to spider
farmer down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
grow at five during checkout for
discount on their products thanks to ac
infiniti for sponsoring this podcast
they sent me over their grow tent which
has a canvas density of 2000 d making
them the thickest grow tent on the
market today it has an aluminum plate
that mounts your controller to the grow
tent with the light proof pass-through
for cable routing the frame has 50
thicker steel poles and carries two
times more weight than the standard grow
tents coupon code mr growit will get you
a discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their website down in
the description section below dutch pro
is a sponsor of the podcast coupon code
mrgrow 10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit10dp for a discount on
their products all right now let's get
into the episode
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast i am here joined
with the grow guru from the dude grow
show how you doing today what's going on
man how you doing happy to be here
super excited to have you on man i mean
you're i've been watching the duke road
show for a very long time and you came
on i knew you came on like three 400
episodes deep or whatever
and uh you just add so much value to the
show and it's
your knowledge is extensive in so many
different areas
and um yeah it's definitely really fun
watching you and it's an honor to kind
of have you on here and pick your brain
even deeper so oh i'm excited pick away
but before we get into
microbes which is the topic today we'll
get all into microbes so many different
microbes so much to talk about
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening
uh so i mean it started when i was
really young uh my grandmother got me
into gardening and one of my
grandfathers was also a master gardener
growing up so i mean it just plants were
always around my mom has a beautiful
garden um and it was just always
something that interests me a lot um
plants are really cool and i
specifically like to take a much more
science-approached or science-backed
approach to medicinal herb gardening for
sure nice
and so you decided to you join the dude
grow show how did that all come about if
you don't mind me asking how did you
kind of join the team there and that was
in 2017 right uh 2016. um it's when i
first moved out to colorado i had met up
with scott a couple years earlier um
they had been talking about black dog
led and saying that there's no good leds
out there they're all blurples and stuff
and at the time i was in uh in school
and designing and building my own led
lights and selling them to some people
uh ended up not going along that path uh
but i got in touch with scott and was
like hey you guys are giving people
really bad advice about this leds are
the future uh hps is like a thing of the
past this is something you need to talk
about you need to let people know that
there's uh good information on this out
there and there are good leds out there
that far surpass what or what hps could
do so scott flew me out to
uh one of the cups came hung out with
them for a while decided i was gonna
move out to colorado i was still in
school at the time and
moved out and then scott had a job for
me right away and started getting
rolling with the dude grow show that's
awesome i think you you guys really
complement each other you know you all
have different personalities you know
you dude scotty and you guys just flow
so well together it's pretty cool i
actually hear that a lot with on my
podcast from the stash with me rob
kendrick's lifestyle tv and pigeons420 i
feel like it's similar you guys just
flow so well together it's awesome and i
actually do it
i was going to say we're all uh and you
guys too we're all really good foils for
each other um everyone has different
approaches to things and it's cool to
get those different ideas uh for so as a
listener to be able to listen to that
and be able to make your own decision
off of stuff and hear just a variety of
ideas
well said i do have a few numbers here
you guys have on the dude gross channel
over 67 000 subscribers
1892 videos
over 9.3 million views combined so you
guys have been very successful and uh
definitely thank you for your efforts
there and i'm excited to see what you
guys got in the future thank you yeah it
was really cool to be able to like i
grew up in virginia where i mean
everything related to medicinal
gardening was super hush-hush
um and getting out here and being able
to be on a youtube show and share some
knowledge with people and get everyone
uh just growing better has been really
cool
living the dream
right and helping people which is uh
like one of my favorite things to do in
educating them and helping them at the
same time and then like my favorite
thing is hearing a new grower get back
in touch with us say they found the
podcast or the youtube show and they got
their first harvest and it was awesome
and how happy they are that that
gets me
super rewarding absolutely
before we get deep into specific
microbes
tell us what are microbial inoculants
and how are they beneficial in the
garden
so there's a couple different ways that
those microbial inoculants are going to
be beneficial in the garden first and
foremost they act as root growth
promoting rhizobacteria where they
actually make compounds that help the
plant be able to have a more like
fibrous and dense root system
which i mean we've all heard it before
more roots more fruits and just an
overall healthier plant they can absorb
more nutrition because plants can only
absorb nutrition from the tips of the
root
and these plant growth
plant growth promoting rhizobacter are
able to get more tips around by growing
out more tertiary and secondary roots
but at the same time those bacteria have
evolved over
millions of years in a symbiotic
relationship with the plant where not
only do they do that the plant puts out
carbohydrates
as exudates to feed them and kind of
control the microbial population that's
there so that it can uh like
exponentially increase the surface area
of its root zone and just those microbes
are able to break down nutrient um get
it into an ionic form and hold on to it
until the plant signals that it needs it
and then they can get it to the plant
and none of that is it
that that's all as far as like plant
nutrition and plant growth um they also
put up like a no vacancy sign to
pathogens they would normally get into
your your garden and there'd be room for
them to grow and expand and that's when
you end up with something like pythium
or phytothera
those really bad root diseases but when
you have good beneficial microbes in
there uh they are making compounds that
uh make it not a hospitable environment
for those uh bad actors um and also just
puts up the no vacancy sign telling them
like hey there's no room for you here
man go somewhere else that's pretty cool
that makes sense now some folks i think
it's pretty well known you know if
you're a beginner you might not know
this but a lot of folks that are above
the beginner stage intermediate stage
know that
there are synthetic nutrients that are
plant available they're already in a
form that the plant can uptake then
there are organic nutrients
which need to be broken down by microbes
first and that's where microbes are
especially important you know having
these different microbial inoculants
adding them into the medium to help with
that breakdown process is key on the
organic side of things now there's some
folks out there that are going to say
well i'm using synthetic bottled
nutrients or mineral based salt based
whatever you want to call it
microbes aren't going to be beneficial
for me at all can you give us your
thoughts on that is that true or not or
well first and foremost definitely not
true i hear this all the time and it's
one of the big myths in gardening
especially in that
synthetic style of gardening uh
those nutrients there's a big problem
with them just washing away or they're
being uh like ph lockout in the soil um
microbes are able to act like a buffer
and they're able to deliver nutrition at
much wider ranges of ph especially when
you have a good consortia or breakdown
of the different microbes that are in
there um so yeah i mean you
microbes are key and in synthetic
it is important to note that like
endogenous microorganisms ones that are
just in your yard in the backyard or in
your compost when you brew a compost tea
most of those don't persist
that great in like an agricultural
horticultural system um just the higher
salinity environments much more
environmental stress on those microbial
populations
but one of the cool things about
microbes is you can go through
successive generations of breeding them
really quickly and kind of select for
the environment that you want to be in
and not all microbes are created equal
you can kind of think of them like
technology products
um where someone's bacillus subtilis uh
it might say this exact same thing on
the label that is bacillus subtilis but
there can be a wide variety of like
different strains of them um and how uh
the different environments that they're
able to operate in our so i mean you can
have one thing on one label one on
another but like one might work way
better because it's been designed to
operate in like that higher salinity
environment containerized gardening uh
like high turnover crops where like you
really want to get the best growth you
possibly can uh as early on and through
the entire life cycle of the plant so
it's definitely still beneficial even if
you're using synthetic nutrients
in an ionized form it's still beneficial
to have microbes to use microbial
inoculants oh most definitely because
another cool thing they're able to do
it's called adsorbing uh the microbes do
kind of the same thing soil particles do
uh when ionic nutrients flow through it
those nutrients absorb onto soil
particles and then are kind of stuck
there until a root comes along with a
higher affinity to that ion that's stuck
to the soil particle
microbes kind of act like in that same
way where they can absorb this nutrition
and then be able to hold on to it in a
plant-available form and deliver it to
the plant so you don't you can when
you're using good microbes you're able
to cut back on your nutrients too just
because you're more efficiently and
effectively getting that into the plant
that's so cool that's really interesting
so yeah i mean the big big myth that we
hear all the time and uh
it's taken a lot of education for people
to be like no no no like you still need
to use it and that's just talking about
in terms of plant nutrition um as a
bioprotectant in the soil and prevent
especially if you're in hydroponics
preventing pythium and phypothera i
don't know if you've ever had those in
the garden um
if you're in a hydroponic system and
it's connected together like on a
central reservoir that can wipe out an
entire garden in a day and a half um
where it turns all your roots your
pearly white roots to just mush
um and a good way around not ever having
to deal with that is using good microbes
in there that act as a bioprotectant in
the soil or in whatever media you're
using so the idea is kind of like pest
management um but with these pathogens
where get the good microbes in there
inhabiting the root zone so that when
pithium of hypothyroid shows up uh it
never has a chance to even take hold the
good microbes are just there and out
compete it um for the same resources in
the same space what about hydrogen
peroxide i heard that as a remedy for it
that is one of the remedies uh kind of
going with the old uh style of thinking
on things where like i need to keep
everything as sterile as i possibly can
like a operating room at a hospital um
and i mean the same thing kind of
happens in operating rooms and hospitals
uh they have pan resistant uh bacteria
um that just like no antibiotics work on
uh you get into that where like if
you're just always sterilizing things
nature's not sterile and it's really
hard really really hard to keep things
sterile especially a plant and you're
losing all of the good uh
like bio protection features of good uh
microbial consortium living in the root
zone because hydrogen peroxide's gonna
kill
whatever microorganisms you have good
and
good ain't good and bad it'll just murk
them all um and it's kind of the same
thing have you ever noticed people that
like going really heavy antibiotics
uh they're not the same like initially
afterwards you have to eat a lot of
yogurt and probiotics were like it just
wiped out your gut microbiome seventy
percent of your immune system is in your
gut microbiome and like it's ex
extremely uh necessary for your your
health and everything there's a direct
connection uh just to analogize people
to plants um
our intestines are like our root system
um where they're inhabited by our
microbiome that lives in there they help
break stuff down and deliver the
nutrition to us your gut is connected
directly to your vagus nerve uh all the
way straight to your brain um and
they're starting to find more and more
that the
consortia or the proportions of
different microbes that are in your gut
can have a huge turn-on effect for more
than just like your gut health like
there's certain ones that uh
like they're starting to find like might
have more to do with like anxiety and
depression or different mental disorders
are really just uh an imbalance in your
gut microbiome wow that's really
interesting and then kind of sticking to
the topic of the amount of microbes
let's talk about cfu
colony forming units so i've got some
recharge right here i've got a microbial
inoculant recharge
it says what the microbe is and then
next to it it says for example 6.4 cfu
slash g
so what is what does that mean what is a
colony what is cfu colony farming unit
why should growers care about it when
they're shopping for microbial
inoculants
so colonel colony
colony forming units or cfus uh that's
in a per gram ratio um so that's how
many different uh like actual spores of
that and generally it's just used for
the mycorrhizae that's in there but how
many uh active growing spores are in
each gram and are able to uh start to
inoculate and uh grow along the route so
the the more the higher the number of cf
use you have uh the more of the actual
spores that are in there um and it's not
usually a like necessary thing to be on
there so like when you look at soils or
like pro-mix hp the pro-mix high
porosity with mycorrhizae uh it has
almost no mycorrhizae in it because they
put it in it like a per yard rate and
it's really small to begin with but they
have mycorrhizae on the label where it's
something else like recharge uh we have
a ton of mycorrhizae in there and not
just uh
it is a blend of endo and ecto um for
short day flowering plants uh we do run
into ecto is really meant for trees like
christmas trees is a really good example
um where it branches out away from the
plant um ecto meaning it's it's outside
of uh they've had different studies and
stuff where they had like a whole
commercial christmas tree farm
and they decided to put a fence around
it uh that fence when they did it they
like cut through the ground
um
it was surrounded by a forest they cut
off that christmas tree farm from its
mycorrhizal network to the force that's
around it and when it did that it uh
it put the whole christmas tree into the
christmas tree farm in decline um
because that mycorrhizal network was
using the forest around it to support
those trees growing there not
necessarily that they had all the
nutrients they needed right where they
were but the force was able to support
that and when they put that fence in it
cut it off from everything and they
like drastically noticed that their
force was going or their christmas tree
farm was going into decline
that's insane that's so crazy
uh i want to bring it back to what you
said which you had mentioned that there
was a product that has mycorrhizae on it
but it's like barely anything right so
i've actually interviewed somebody on
this podcast before and and this person
had said that some products on the
market today don't have enough cfus to
actually be effective i want to kind of
highlight that point that there could be
some products out there
where they're on the label but there's
really not enough amount to be effective
now when we go through these individual
microbes here i don't know i'm kind of
kind of putting you under the gun here
if you have any information on
what cfu should be for each of these
microbes as we go through of it please
you know let us know so we're not
getting ripped off here oh for sure
generally it's look for the highest
numbers you can find um just uh in my
opinion having more good microbes in
there like those uh those populations
will figure themselves out once they're
in the soil um and into that environment
where they actually start to uh get
selected for the environment that
they're in um but yeah generally just a
bigger number is better in this case
and so we don't really need to worry
about like a balance we don't have to
like look at the back of the label and
say well this only has this cfus but
this has a lot higher and it might throw
off the diversity do we have to worry
about that so that's so like labeling
with things uh
is a big game that you have to play uh
the back of labels it's almost always
even your your fertilizers that you buy
where it'll have like 20 20 20 on the
side of it um that's a guaranteed
minimum
um that's not necessarily saying like
the exact proportion of everything
that's in there um so it's
it's so hard and like soil they don't
have to list the ingredients in order of
what's in there the most they put
mycorrhizae first then list everything
else because they think people will just
think it's the same rules for food where
like the thing that's in there and the
highest amount is in there so i mean
it's kind of hard without actually
trying stuff um or getting it tested is
even better to see uh like what it
actually tests out at
wow i didn't know that about yeah i
thought the order was in just like food
i thought the order it was in was the
most amount
yeah no it's it's all a game of
guaranteed minimums on those things so
that makes it like as the end consumer i
could deal with it all the time with
regulatory bodies and stuff but the end
consumer it's really hard to look at
something and just like uh by the back
of it be able to know if like one if
that is completely truthful um or yeah
it's it just makes it really difficult i
can't say with recharge uh everything is
in there
far exceeds what we have on the label
that was like we we just put a lower
number on there to be safe with
everything there's a lot more of uh
those microbes in there uh when you
actually get it tested
gotcha just to touch on recharge real
quick so that's a microbial inoculant
it's got a whole bunch of different
things in there um a long bunch of
beneficial microbes along with like kelp
molasses humic acids fulvic acids amino
acids we we really like to think about
that more uh there's a lot of microbial
inoculants out there this one comes
together uh like a really good instant
compost tea where not only does it have
the uh wide range of bacillus in there
that are targeted at horticulture and
agricultural systems it's got the
trichoderma fungi
molasses is a food stock for everything
they're built on kelp as a carrier it's
got the l amino acids and a lot of
people don't realize with amino acids if
they're not in their l form they are not
plant available at all um so like it has
to be l amino acids or your plants not
going to be able to utilize them at all
and then humic and fulvic acids which
just act as like chelators
so they help
the microbes be able to do their job a
little bit more effectively so
not only are the chelators they act as
kind of catalyst for biological
reactions too
where they lower the energy of
activation needed to start a reaction so
that it's just a more efficient
metabolism going on in there gotcha and
just for trans transparency purposes
what's your affiliation with recharge
uh i am uh an operations manager over at
recharge so yeah i do have to
represent just being just being
transparent yeah exactly yeah i do work
for them yep yep no makes sense but it
is a great product something i use in my
garden off and on like i mentioned in
scotty's episode is like
i try to switch things up for my viewers
you know and i have to do the same thing
over and over again viewers get bored so
every once in a while i'll kick in some
recharge but i love it so it's very nice
now let's get into some of the
individual microbes you have
knowledge on quite a bit of them let's
start with uh tragoderma wanna talk to
us about that
okay trichoderma is one of my favorite
ones um
it is a voracious decomposer um it's
probably the class i would put it in uh
like it it's origin story of where
trichoderma actually started comes from
a single point of contact in the south
pacific during world war ii
um
they had set up camp somewhere like in
the the monsoon season uh in the south
pacific believe in the philippines they
had wax canvas tint everywhere like at
that time that's what everyone was using
they had set up camp
within three days
their wax canvas tents which are
extremely waterproof and just resistant
to anything going on environmentally uh
started literally melting away and it's
because they had come into contact with
some trichoderma fungi
that was collected as a sample brought
back to labs and then a lot of work has
been done with it since then
it's used in a lot of industrial
processes that like never really get
mentioned it's used in stone washing
genes
trying to think of something else that's
used in but in gardening they found out
that uh it is able to really really
really uh quickly
break down those organic nutrients that
you'd be putting into your soil um so
that they are able to get to a plant
available form much faster um and yeah i
mean it it also is very competitive um
with other fungi that are around um and
is able to out-compete uh most of the
pathogenic ones um that it's gonna come
into contact with and so
there are different strains of it um
just kind of looking at recharge
it's uh let's see what you got you got
trichoderma reese i'm gonna butcher
these names by the way so fair warning
these names are easily uh be able to be
butchered trichoderma horizon
perezium
horazinium
i struggle with that one too
do you have anything to add like on
those specific types of strains uh it's
not
it's not super necessary to go into like
uh the specific strains of those just
that trichoderma is like a class uh it
is very quick at breaking stuff down
especially organic nutrients um it it's
uh like a single celled fungi so it's
not uh where it's gonna have like
mushrooms growing off the top of it or
anything like that but it really is able
to get in there and it's good for bio
protection um and preventing any of
those root pathogens from popping up
okay gotcha another one that uh bacillus
you know let's move on to that i see
bacillus in almost every single one of
the micro products that i that i have
and um
looks like you guys got three different
strains of them is that right strains
different strains of them oh yeah yeah
strains of them um talk to us about
bacillus so bacillus is really cool it
is one of the
like real turn-on effects uh
in microbial inoculants um most people
give the credit to michael rizzi and
that's been like a buzzword for years in
gardening uh most people don't realize
that ecto-mycorrhizae can't even infect
short-day flowering plants um or the
medicinal plants people like to grow uh
it just doesn't have enough time to get
in there and start to build up that
network
uh where the endomycorrhizae is actually
the one that uh is able to do stuff in
there um but those have been buzzwords
and don't really do that much in my
opinion bacillus are really the like
main turn on effect for root growth
promotion in the soil um where they're
able to make uh like
endogenously inside of themselves iba to
help uh plants root out and get more
root shoots uh and secondary and
tertiary tertiary rooting so it has uh
like exponentially more root tips to be
able to absorb nutrition from
basils are really cool
they're also really easy to start
selecting for different environments
that you want them to be able to persist
better in
and then
my favorite fact about them
it's all called a consortia uh when you
have uh like a population of different
microorganisms um and when you have the
right proportions of the right ones you
get uh an effect it's like much more
than the sum of their parts where it's
not just like an additive effect where
they're going together it's uh like
uh exponentially making it better um and
able to have a more uh turn-on effect
for the plant what about geobacillus so
that's one i'm not super familiar with
uh
i know that uh it was discovered inside
of like geysers
um or hot water vents like at the bottom
of the seabed uh where these uh bacillus
i don't think they have
too much uh use in plants um just where
their like preferred environment is over
like 95 celsius
so like right near the the boiling point
of water um but really cool microbes uh
i know in industry they're going to
start to use those a lot more just be in
the the type of applications that
they're in like higher heat environments
and stuff um and i think they also live
in like your hot water heater they'll
find them in hot water heaters sometimes
just because it's a place where it's
like right around 100 degrees celsius
all the time and they
are basically the only thing that lives
in that type of environment and can uh
can thrive there what about glomus
i see that on a lot of products
glomus uh is mycorrhizae um so there's
an and an ecto form of it ecto is on the
outside of the root uh and grows like
out into the soil and in an effect it
does exponentially increase the surface
area of the soil it helps the plant uh
deal with environmental stresses better
um just
endogenously it is able to
uh kind of handle those stresses better
uh the the microbes can help elicit a
uh like acquired resistance response
from the plant where it knows like hey i
need to close up my uh my pores um
because i need to
conserve water in like a time of drought
um they're pretty cool again so like
cfu's just kind of going back to that
when somebody's
you know this right here has you know
6.4 cfus per gram
you just just the more the better huh
like can you over do
the more the better generally uh no
you're not going to be able to overdo it
uh i mean i guess you could in a like
financial sense yeah okay hey where
you're just throwing money away at some
point um i generally don't think of the
mycorrhizae that's in most microbial
products as being something that's
really doing all that much just because
you have to get it on super early um in
the the growth of the plant when there's
not that many roots so that it is able
to grow alongside the root as it grows
uh in microbial inoculants in
microbiology and soils the the bacillus
and the different types of trichoderma
fungi that can be in there are going to
be the ones that are doing uh the
majority of the work for everything
while mycorrhizae gets all the fame now
mycorrhizae i heard that it's a lot like
significantly less effective
watering in mycorrhizae versus
sprinkling onto the roots
oh
most oh most definitely uh that's one of
the things a lot of people don't realize
with it is that for that uh colony
forming unit to be able to actually
infect a root a root has to come in
direct contact with it uh it can't just
pass by it or anything it has to
directly make contact with the root uh
that's why with with recharge water is
always the carrier for it
it gets it evenly and thoroughly through
the soil and if there's a root in there
some mycorrhizae is going to make
contact with it
with just a pure mico product or
something like that
powdering the roots is what you're going
to want to do just because in that case
at least you know you're making contact
uh with the roots like we were talking
about pro-mix earlier where they have
the pro-mix with mycorrhizae in there uh
there's not that much mycorrhizae in
there to begin with and just the the
odds are not stacked in your favor that
a root is actually going to make contact
with like the one colony forming unit
that's around in a pot once you've
planted something in there um so yeah i
mean making sure that it gets contact
with a root is
definitely going to help it be more
effective um at uh infecting that root
and being able to give you those
beneficial effects of it now would you
go so far as to say that you shouldn't
water it in uh no i would i wouldn't go
that that far um i mean there's
definitely times where like
you're just not gonna be able to uh
pull out a plant and powder the roots
with it um so yeah i mean if if you have
a high enough cfu like what's in
recharge
you definitely can water it in
although we really just have the
mycorrhizae in there to be able to say
like yeah it's in there too we have that
but we're really proud of the consortia
of the different bacillus and
trichoderma that are in recharge yeah
i'm really really curious to know like
for example great white is one of those
products that uh is known for
mycorrhizae i'm really curious to know
like of that scoop of great white you're
mixing in the water and putting in there
what percentage
is actually going to be hitting the
roots you know what i mean i think
that's probably the answer you don't
have but yeah
not one i have off the top of my head
and just want to admit like i
uh greatly respect great white and what
they did uh started to bring like a
premium microbe uh
consortia out to the public and getting
it out there
but a lot of innovation has gone on uh
recently in microbiology it's the
biggest expanding field in uh
agriculture and horticulture um it's
it's just gonna it's like the big next
thing in agriculture where people are
starting to realize that like
just dumping fertilizer especially in uh
commercial agriculture out in fields and
everything that just dumping fertilizer
on your land was killing off all the
endogenous microorganisms that you had
and making it really really hard to
garden there uh where you it it's more
treating it like uh hydroponics at that
point the soil is just your media it's
completely dead and inert um but yeah
getting back to bringing the life into
your soil um is
good i mean it it helps everybody uh
and just getting
being more efficient at the fertilizer
that you do use um it's it's pretty cool
i'm i'm excited to be in this field kind
of piggybacking off of what you just
said synthetic fertilizers do they
really kill off microbes or do the
microbes feed off of some of them or
what's your take on that
it uh like we were talking about earlier
depends on what microbes you're using if
you're uh brewing up a compost tea with
some like soil from the forest that
you've gone and collected
yeah the
the different chemical fertilizers and
synthetic fertilizers are gonna kill
some of your microbes but if you're
using uh ones that have been selected
and bred uh for their virulency and
they're able their ability to persist in
those horticulture and agricultural
systems like we as uh medicinal
gardeners use um they are
they thrive in that situation um where
they are able to absorb and hold on to
nutrition act as a bioprotectant they
don't really care that the salts are
around them uh they've been selected to
live in that environment and be able to
thrive there so no um if you're using
the right microbes then no there's no
issue with using uh being in like a
higher salinity environment using
synthetics or anything like that now how
about ph up and ph down i know there's a
lot of people they'll get their water
they'll need to ph adjust their water
maybe the original water that they have
is coming in too high for example as
sodium bicarbonates at high ph so i
needed to add in a couple drops of ph
down which normal ph down i believe most
of them are phosphoric acid right and so
they think that those couple drops all
it really takes is a couple drops two
three drops maybe a milliliter to bring
that down to the acceptable range now
there are people out there that
use that phosphoric acid mix in get
their water adjusted
but then when they water their plants
like you're killing off microbes
what's your take on uh so once you
actually dilute the ph up and ph down
it's not going to have any effect on the
microbes like i was saying earlier
they're able to operate at a real wide
range of phs
and just a a
pretty good point to make the water when
you're doing that is not their native
environment we want to get them out of
the water and into the soil
as soon as we possibly can to prevent
selecting for a waterborne environment
these are root growth or root borne
microorganisms
they're meant to be in the root zone we
don't want to keep them in the water too
long it's just meant to be a really good
even thorough carrier to get them all
the way through the soil instead of just
having like pockets of it here and there
now what about adding ph up a ph sound
directly i know we're kind of getting
off topic here we're talking about
microbes but this kind of follows up
here so when you're adding ph up and ph
down directly to a nutrient mix i've
heard that
that's going to bind with some of those
nutrients and potentially make them an
unusable form so it was recommended that
you should be diluting down right mixing
your ph up and down in water first so it
bonds to that and then putting it into
your nutrient solution is that
a true story or is that a true true
story in general chemistry um that's
going to be the way that you would want
to do that just to where you're not
adding concentrated acid or concentrated
base uh to your solution that already
has nutrients in it just because it is
fairly easy for
some chemical reactions to happen there
and you have some like fallout or
precipitate is what it's called in
chemistry where i don't know if you've
ever mixed up the main one people see is
silica where they'll mix up their
nutrients first and then put silica in
and you just see it get all cloudy and
then there's like
silicate at the bottom of your uh your
reservoir and that's just where that
silica
can't go in a concentrated form can't go
in with anything else it needs to get
diluted first so that when you mix the
other stuff in it's not in that high
concentration that's going to cause a
precipitate or anything like that
most of the time with microbes when
you're watering them in
you want to mix your nutrients how you
normally do so if you're mixing silica
mix that first go ahead and mix up your
a or your b
um ph how you normally do and then go
ahead and add the microbes in as like
the last thing so that they're not
experiencing a huge ph change or
anything when they get into the water um
they do raise the ph uh just as a
function of their biology water is not
their native environment like we were
talking about we want to get them in the
soil as soon as they get in the soil
which is their native environment they
start to
make carbonic acid and carboxylic
carboxylic
uh like there's a whole group of acids
that they're able to make and that's how
they buffer and regulate the ph around
uh
themselves and where they inhabit the
root zone so it kind of makes it to
where ph doesn't matter as much anymore
because a much more natural system
is taking care of that for you gotcha
i'm glad you confirmed that dilute the
ph up in ph down because i actually made
a video on that it has over 100 000
views
and
you know that's what i learned and i
wanted to confirm it with people and you
kind of confirmed that one so there was
people in the comments section like no
way this is useless blah blah
blah blah so
um and just want to clarify too that uh
you can still put ph up or ph down
directly into your nutrient solution
especially if it's being stirred the
whole time because it's only going to be
super concentrated as like the couple of
seconds of that drop hits the water and
then it gets diluted right away and
there's not really that much opportunity
for like a precipitate to form um or you
start to change what's going on in that
nutrient solution so it's not
detrimental
no not not super detrimental the main
one is silica mix your silica up with
plain water first uh and then start
mixing in your nutrients and everything
gotcha okay let me get let's get back on
the individual microbes kind of of
course a little bit but i think it's it
all relates and it's really good
information so
yeah
this next one i'm gonna have trouble
pronouncing pan bacillus
pan bacillus is just another one of uh
like classification of different
bacillus that are out there um and it
acts like a root growth promoting
rhizobacteria um they're in there they
make iaa
into acetic acid um some other root
growth promotion
enzymes and stuff
and
i think that they're able to elicit
somewhat of a sars response from the
plant too
where it kind of just gets it ready for
if there was going to be some type of
pathogen or bug coming around it's just
going to be better able to deal with
those stresses and better able to uh
trigger its immune response coming from
them okay
how about pseudonomus i pronounce that
one right
pseudomonas pseudomonas
that's going to be one that lives much
more like on plant surfaces i'm pretty
sure um so that'll be the one you'll see
in like foliar microbial products a lot
um
not one that i'm super familiar with
that's something i need to do a little
bit more research on myself okay the
last one i have on the list here is
streptomyces
i get that one right
i told you i was gonna be butchering
names
the pseudomonas streptomyces like all
are pretty much just like plant growth
promoters uh make some substances that
kind of uh out compete uh
pathogens that could be coming around
and then can kind of help make the
trigger the plant to start making its
own
uh
like root growth promotion um substances
that it makes in their ia iba
other stuff like that okay is there any
other microbes you that i didn't list
off that you think we should cover or is
that pretty much the
most of it
uh
i think we pretty much got most of it
okay cool
now how about i got a couple other
things for you amino acids you touched
on them a little bit earlier you
mentioned that they have to be in the l
form so anything else you talk to us
about amino acids
oh definitely so l amino acids um are
necessary for all life not just plants
like we need amino acids our body makes
amino acids um they're like the building
blocks for enzymes um enzymes uh act as
catalysts for chemical reactions where
they make them
like
the soil has to exert less energy to get
a chemical reaction to happen so it's
just kind of overall optimizing the
entire system
it helps plants translocate nutrients
better um
they're i mean they're huge especially
in uh
when people in synthetics
are trying to grow high brix plants um
one of their like limiting factors in
being able to get to like a higher brix
level which corresponds with a higher
plant health and resistant to pathogens
and bugs and everything um
like the the main thing that they're
missing when they're trying to do that
is having those amino acids um
and amino acids aren't just
like just singular things too they can
be complexed with other things uh where
it can help
nitrogen get into the plant better it
can help uh
just about anything get into the plant
better um it's it's just one of the big
things in like the
newer uh
trying to think bio fertilizers that are
coming out um the the use of those amino
acids and using them for their intended
purpose to help nutrients get into the
plant and help the plant just overall
optimize its metabolism better uh has
helped a lot of people get to like
another yield threshold in their garden
um or get over a certain yield limiting
factor sometimes those el amino acids
are going to be the limiting factor
there so like you mentioned amino acids
has multiple uses one thing i learned
actually from harley smith shout out to
him i took his master growers course
last year
specifically for hydroponic growers now
correct me if i'm wrong here right so
hydroponic growers
some of the calcium
you'll get like
like the ring around the calcium
deposits basically it it's basically
calcium carbonate is what it turns into
if using hard water for example right
yeah that that calcium is bonding to
like dissolve carbon dioxide in the
water um and making that calcium
carbonate and a little trick to avoid
that is what he had mentioned is
sprinkle a little bit of amino acids in
that water and it'll actually bind to
the amino acid it'll prevent that
ring those rings from occurring which i
thought was super interesting that's
what i was talking about with like amino
complex nutrients uh where yeah it
makes it 100 just more bioavailable to
the plant and prevents any type of
lockout going on there just because it
uh will have a much higher affinity to
that calcium than the carbonate that's
uh in its dissolve or the the co2 that's
dissolved into the water okay gotcha
another thing that i want to bring up is
dextrose so we kind of briefly talked
about this before we started recording
um dextrose it's something that i mean i
got another micro product here is blue
planet nutrients root magic rhizomix and
it says 20 dextrose can you explain to
us what it is
so dextrose is just a a type of uh sugar
that's made by plants um i mean that's
what plants do
they photosynthesize sunlight co2 and
water and turn that into carbohydrates
and sugars for themselves um to be able
to use for energy to uh make the
medicinal flowers that we like debt so
dextrose is one of those like sucrose
fructo fructose glucose um i mean
there's a whole range of sugars i'm
never going to be one to say more
diversity in something is a bad thing so
like if you're trying to do the best you
possibly can using a variety of sugar
sources um is not the worst idea in the
world but molasses um it generally acts
as like the one of the better um food
sources for microorganisms um just where
it is it's a complete sugar
it has everything they need and yeah i
mean
you can use like some people use honey
some people use uh like high fructose
corn syrup if they're crazy um like
there's lots of different options brown
sugar brown sugar out there and the
different types of sugars uh can
actually bloom out uh different types of
microbes will prefer different types of
sugar sources
so yeah using a wide variety of if
you're trying to have the most diversity
you possibly can
or with something like recharge using
the molasses that's in there is meant uh
for the
the microbes that are in there as their
food source molasses
a little want to get a little bit deeper
into that i've been told that
it shouldn't be used as this old drench
at least there's some people out there
that say there's research that backs
that it shouldn't be used as a little
drench because it
uh and i'm speaking about my head a
little bit here it
binds with something it clogs up the
roots prevents nutrient uptake something
along those lines are you familiar with
that at all or it can if you use it in
really really high concentrations um it
can start to claw group force um
and and clog up brew tips so that it's
not able to absorb as much nutrition you
kind of run into the same thing with uh
humic acids too you have to use a ton of
them uh like a ton a ton of them but it
can start to uh clog root pores and
stuff like that generally not a problem
with people's gardens at all unless
they're like i dump the whole bottle of
molasses into my watering can and like
try and go water that in like then you
might have an issue if you're using it
like a teaspoon per gallon or something
like that there shouldn't be an issue at
all i usually use a tablespoon per
gallon tablespoon per gallon shouldn't
be an issue at all either all right guru
we have covered a lot i
have learned so much i'm definitely
watching this over and over again
tell us how can the listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future
uh you can check me out on the dude grow
show uh every monday through friday on
youtube or any of the podcast apps that
you have uh my own instagram is
sean.crayer s-e-a-n dot k-r-a-y-e-r if
you guys want to check me out there uh i
do i'm
a pretty interesting person i like to
think i uh
i'm pretty big into photography and fly
fishing i've got a couple dogs and stuff
um and just recently i've had a little
hiatus from actually growing myself um
but getting back into that too so i'll
start be starting a youtube channel soon
um and gonna be posting content on there
pretty regularly too let me know when
you launch that youtube channel i'll
link it down in the description section
below in the meantime i'll link the dude
grow show down in the description
section below and his instagram
but let me know once you launch that
channel because i'll add that in as well
so
thank you yeah so folks can subscribe to
you and i'm definitely looking forward
to your videos there you have extensive
knowledge in microbes and other areas
chemistry clearly
so i'm looking forward to subbing up to
you there and seeing what you put out
for content it'll be cool yeah i always
have fun watching your content too you
get some really good guests on there all
the time all right everybody if you
enjoyed this video please click that
thumbs up button subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already if you're
on apple podcasts please leave a rating
and review i'm trying to get past 100 i
think we're there almost there but thank
you to everyone who takes the time to
leave a rating and review on apple
podcasts share it share this video if
you found value in it if you know
somebody who would benefit from this
information please share it i know there
have been tons of people sharing it on
facebook groups
reddit pages
individually so any way you can share it
it's greatly appreciated it's going to
help
uh get more viewers here it's going to
help subscribers help with ranking uh be
shown to people as recommended so on and
so forth so again thank you to everyone
who decides to share this podcast well
guru this has been awesome i am so
thankful that you decided to come on
here
and uh yeah i will leave it at that i'm
super happy to be here man it's been a
great time all right man have a great
day you too
[Music]
you