what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watch my extras channel sunrays
sent me over there 2000 watt LED grow
light and in this video I'm gonna unbox
a unit and I'm also gonna test the power
output first thing out the box is this
welcome guide it has some various
instructions on the inside is the
extended warranty card and a little note
there a 5 foot power cord one rope
ratchet hanger and one wire hanging kit
I'm not gonna go over all of the grow
lights features in this video but I will
leave a link to this grow light in the
description section below so you can
learn more for the part tests I'm gonna
use the apogee mq 5 under par meter this
meter measures from 389 and meters to
692 nanometers plus or minus 5 diameters
and the measurements are in ppfd
and really this is just to give you a
general idea of what the power output is
for this grow light this test isn't
meant to be a hundred percent accurate
the reflective walls could increase the
numbers so just keep that in mind and
the Amazon listing sunrays mentions a
four foot by four foot flower in
coverage area with the light 24 inches
away from the top of the plants in this
video take three different measurements
20 inches away 24 inches away and 36
inches away and this is in a full foot
by 4 foot grove 10 with the veg you
switch on it pulls 224 watts with the
flower switch on it pulls 202 watts and
with both the veg and flower switches on
it pulls 406 watts alright let's get
into the Benjamins
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
click that subscribe button if you
haven't already good - Bell to be
notified when I release in your video
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave that that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]