what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you're watching my extra Channel got
a new video for you today
well a new type of video I never done
this type of video before on this
channel I'm gonna answer some questions
I am going to look through my YouTube
channel comments and a lot of these
comments I get I'm not able to respond
to so I figure I'd make a video and
respond to them here I want to do
different types of videos on this
channel the past eight or nine videos
and things have been hard test videos
and people are starting to get sick of
them so I am going to try to switch
things up create more content for this
channel YouTube likes this channel they
like part test videos they don't like
gardening videos they don't like the
plants that I show on the channel so I'm
trying to walk a thin line here
particularly on this channel but anyways
enough of that let's answer some
questions these questions are coming
from my main youtube channel if for some
reason you're not subscribed to my main
two YouTube channel you're not aware of
it I will link it down in the
description section below how many times
you top a great question it really
depends on growth for me personally
everybody does it different what I
normally do is I'll wait till the plant
gets up till about its fifth node then
only the top of the fifth node and try
to do LSD to spread all those lower
branches try to spread them all out as
wide as possible sometimes I want to hit
the fifth note on top down to the third
node it really depends on growth more
stretchier strains I'll probably top
down more and then do additional tops as
well indica strains that are real
compact I don't need to top as much I
might talk once if I top it all so it
really depends on growth for me the moon
and stars are light leaks I don't buy
into that tiny light leaks will affect
your plant enough to stress them out
okay so he is talking about the
equipment to status light on your
equipment such as humidifier or
dehumidifier air conditioner or whatever
you're running those little status
lights that are on that those LED lights
he's saying that he doesn't think that
that's gonna actually cause the plants
stress surprisingly they will
and from experience here I once left my
humidifier light on and my plants and
they were in flowering and they
stretched for longer than the 21-day
period and I'm like what tech is going
on here they seem to have stopped and
then they started back up again as far
as stretching and I was like what the
heck is going on here and then I
realized what happened is that I left
that humidifier light on so it didn't
actually affect it to the point where it
hurried out and was producing seeds
right away which I was kind of surprised
by the Moon and stars a light leak you
can do a google search and it'll talk
about plant photosynthesis and how the
moons and stars actually don't impact
that enough to where it's gonna you know
cause photosynthesis or stress the
plants out and cause them to grow so so
yeah germinated seeds sprout first how
soon can I determine the gender of my
seedlings so there's a couple ways to do
it so seedling send it in to a farmer
Freeman that's my recommendation now
there's a fee for that but what they do
is they'll take a microscope and look at
the chromosomes and they'll be able to
tell if your plant is male or female
while it's still a seedling this is
something that is I want to say new but
it's been around for years now but a lot
of people don't know about it it's all
linked that down in the description
section below so you can learn more
about it but I've been doing it and it's
been a hundred percent accurate since
I've been using that service or you can
wait until the plant is late in the
vegetation stage you know weeks four
five six it may start showing signs of
sex he's up pistols for female and
pollen sacks for males or when you flip
to flowering
it'll then show either or I'm gonna grow
up plant indoors but it turned out to be
a big one and confusing that how is
gonna flower
I seek some help okay so in order to
switch it over to the flowering stage
I'm assuming you're growing a
photoperiod plant if you need to change
the light cycle to most people do twelve
hours on and then twelve hours of
complete darkness now some people will
do eleven hours on and thirteen hours of
complete darkness both of those will
transition the plant to flower stage
that's it that's how you switch it over
to flower house smell proof could this
material make the room he's actually
commenting on
my pop panda film poly film video if
installed professionally with taped
corners wouldn't stop smell sono poly
film Penta film does not stop to smell
at all really if you're looking to
control the smell look at carbon filter
and you can also look at air
purification systems as well something
like in viral cleanse would be something
look into and I'll link that in the
description section below all the
products I talked about in this video
will be linked in the description
section below and don't any discount
codes I have for those products to help
you out but yeah either carbon filter or
air purification system that's gonna
help with smell okay so Greg is asking
so many to choose he's actually
commenting on one of my grill live
videos says so many to choose I have a
small tent and just need a good light
that does everything
anyone have any good recommendations so
Greg it really comes down to what size
gross space you're looking to cover once
we know that we got to narrow down a lot
actually on my website mr. Greg calm
under the article section you can find
articles I've done on best LED grow
lights and I've done those articles last
year 2019 I'm working on new article for
this year for different size grow spaces
so those articles that are o 2019 a
little bit outdated but there's still
some really good grow lights in there
definitely check that out if you can
tell us what grow space you're looking
to cover will be able to help you out
even more if you would have said paper
towel one more time I would have laughed
so hard I was hoping you would keep
saying it much love to you girl so a lot
of people call out my accent it's from
Boston so I say Pepa stay of paper paper
towel paper towel yeah so is the Boston
accent coming out I had a question about
farmer Freeman have you ever gotten a
result that wasn't male or female can
they detect her me or might it show as
bolt or inconclusive just curious I've
had a couple select bagged seeds I'd
like to run good question we were just
talking about farmer Freeman I haven't
gotten a result that says male or female
I have gotten a result that said that it
was pending and it was gonna be another
day and then end up being another day
I don't know if they'd have probably the
sample or if they just it was the end of
the day and they couldn't get to that
particular one but now I haven't ever
gotten a result that wasn't male or
female how long darkness do you give
your plants after 12:12 before harvest
do you do 24 hours 48 hours heard
different reports a good question it
really all depends on my schedule my
personal schedule what I'm doing for the
day well I mean for the week actually
sometimes I'll do 48 hours of darkness
sometimes I do 72 hours of darkness
there's really no set rule that I have
for how long to do it the whole point of
the darkness period is supposedly
secondary metabolites it produces
trichomes while the lights are off so
some people will have a period of
darkness at harvest well before
harvesting right so they'll just put
their plant on 24 48 hours 72 hours of
darkness and then a harvest but yeah I
mean I do a little bit of all 24 48 72 I
think it's kind of marginal as far as
the difference there that's just my
personal opinion
Chris cannulas to know how those fans
hold up please I love design but the
reviews are bad okay so he's talking
about that oscillating fan actually
clips onto the grow tent I got that from
by bosun so far so good I mean I have
two of them running right now and
they've been fine running 24 hours a day
since I got that let's see 50 days so
far so so far so good but yeah I saw
saying bad reviews on Amazon if anything
updates on there I'll definitely
definitely update you guys hey brother
thanks for all the game and knowledge
you share with us how can I get one of
your seeds I live in a 420 friendly
state willing to pay just trying to get
my hands on a good strain so for those
of you guys who do not know I do have my
own strain it's called chill otogi it's
something about working on four G's
I think it's been almost two years now
still I kind of feel like it's in
development of an F to growing right now
I had some testers working on them and
they got some good results but right now
long story short is I don't have any for
sale at the moment but keep an eye out
if I do have them for sale I will
definitely announce some either on
Instagram probably Instagram Twitter
maybe Facebook yeah check those
platforms that's when I word that's
where I would make the announcement that
I would have seats or sale all right I'm
gonna leave it at that just a quick
video of just busting out some questions
what do you think about this format what
do you think about these questions do
you want me to do more videos like this
in the future videos like this are easy
for me to bust out because I'm not gonna
have to do that much editing my main
channel for example videos on there I'm
doing at least 10 15 20 hours of work
per video and includes filming editing
and then posting on to YouTube so
something like this it should only
really take me a couple hours just kind
of cut up and put on to youtube so I can
do a lot of these videos I can do a lot
of sit-down videos I plan to do sit-down
videos and talking on this channel so
let me know what questions you have that
you want to see in future videos let me
know what topics you want to see for
videos in the future and I'm gonna try
to bust out a lot of content this month
and these upcoming months
especially since we are in quarantine or
we have stay at home orders still at
least the state I'm living and has those
day I don't home orders so I hope
everyone out there is healthy and safe
safe
yeah and I'll leave it at that thank you
so much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]