what is up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is mr growit in this
video i'm going to unbox the apogee
mq-500 quantum sensor when growing
cannabis this quantum sensor or often
referred to as par meter is used to
measure photon density
this is the amount of par or
photosynthetic active radiation the
energy that plants use of photosynthesis
that's being emitted from the grow light
this sensor picks up all light in the
400 to 700 nanometer range
okay let's get into the unboxing this is
the shipping box and as you can see when
opening it's packed nicely with some
bubble wrap
there is a small piece of paper in there
which thanks me for ordering and tells
me to go to the website for additional
information
the quantum sensor comes in this
carrying case
and then when i open the case it's
completely padded for protection
here is the quantum sensor it comes with
a two meter cable and i'm just pulling
off the plastic material right now and
the cord comes zip tied as well so i had
to cut that off
there's a cap on top of the actual
sensor for protection and i bought the
wand as well this was an additional cost
it does not come with the mq 500
the one extends to 84 centimeters
and you can just pull it out and that's
how it extends so
no release button or anything like that
it comes with a few velcro pieces and
then lastly it comes with a battery
this battery will of course need to be
put into the sensor before operating and
i'll do that in a minute
now first i'm going to attach the wand
i need to unscrew the screw that's in
the bottom of the sensor
and now i'll attach the top of the wand
to the sensor and then screw the screw
back on
next i'll remove the back plate and add
in the battery
and the battery just slides right in
and then after i reattach the back plate
the quantum sensor is ready to use
since this sensor doesn't come with an
instruction manual i highly recommend
that you watch the instructional video
that apogee created i'll leave a link to
that video in the description section
below along with a link to the mq 500
quantum sensor that's pretty much it for
this video guys if you enjoyed it please
click that thumbs up and i will leave it
at that thank you so much for watching
and until next time peace
[Music]
you