i think the most important thing for
your root system to have to make your
plant grow vigorously is
you need oxygen and you need microbes
see
you want to form an even canopy if you
have a christmas tree you have
you know the lower bud sites that could
be getting the light they're not getting
the light they're being covered up so
they're gonna become airy like popcorn
buds as far as nutrients
i i do start off with the recharge you
know by real growers and
oh my god if anyone's been following the
you know the skittles autoflowers she
like
exploded she's got a trunk almost like
my arm when you micromanage
you are gonna overwater because you feel
like you need to do something
and that's where people screw up
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and this is garden talk episode 10. in
this episode i talk with a grower who
goes by the name
420 scene he is a fellow youtuber that
has
almost 12 000 subscribers he has been
gardening for
over seven years and he specializes in
growing autoflower plants
in this episode we talk about autoflower
plants i try to dig deep and find out
exactly what
he does when he's growing autoflowers we
also talk a little bit about aerated
compost teas
because he does have experience with
those as well click that thumbs up
button if you haven't already
and subscribe to the channel if you
haven't done that already as well i
release these garden talk videos
once a week every saturday and then of
course after the episode
drop a comment down in the comment
section below i'd love to know what you
do when you grow auto flower plants and
also what do you do for aerated teas
drop that down below i hope you enjoyed
this episode let's just get right into
it
all right 420 scene welcome to garden
talk how you doing today
doing pretty good man thanks for coming
on i appreciate it
glad to be on man we'll just get uh
let's just get right into things
so for those that don't know who you are
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into growing
oh yeah absolutely um i'm 420 seeing as
a lot of you guys know
i started back in 2014. um
you know it's funny like i still i still
remember like i was in electrical school
right
and before class i was just like looking
up like the different you know lights
and
you know how to grow and that sort of
thing and you know like it was so
intimidating like at first when i first
started growing there was just there was
so much
like information out there that it was
just so crazy there's
all these different forums out there and
you know all the different resources
youtube you know what i'm saying so
there's like so much
not you know opinions and you know
what's not
like what's good information what's bad
information so like
you know um like when i started out it
was
um i thought it was gonna be like really
really tough you know what i'm saying
and um i remember before i actually got
into growing
i started to you know i started actually
started taking notes about like
everything like ever you know light
cycles and
npk ratios and just like all that stuff
you know what i mean
and um you know one thing led to another
and
you know the thing about horticulture
that i learned is it's like you gotta
practice to get better like you can get
all the information you get but
like you can read every forum everything
out there but
if you don't you know i mean if you
don't practice if you don't practice
your craft you're never going to get
better
that's what i try to tell everybody you
know i mean yeah so many people that
just read books read forums and they
have knowledge
and you know they'll be on the forums
replying giving answers
yet they haven't grown the plant and
yeah right
it's sad that it's like that for some
things but yeah doing your research is
one thing
executing and getting the experience is
certainly another thing
absolutely so now you you're at the
point now where you have a youtube
channel
right um when did you launch the youtube
channel and what type of videos do you
do
and uh i think you're at what a little
over was it 12 000 or 15 000 subscribers
now
we actually just uh grazed past 11 000
subscribers and
um you know i actually started out as
cush life a lot of
like long time ogs of the channel will
know you know we started at it
with cush life and um see
my channel is a little bit different
from a lot of a lot of the other
you know uh horticulture youtubers and
i almost have like a um a really chill
xcode kind of vibe i do like grow videos
i do
um you know sm like uh stoner life story
stuff like that you know what i mean so
i try to mix it up i do
i do news you know within the
horticulture community so like a lot of
people like that so i
i do a little bit i have a variety of a
little bit of everything you know what i
mean
yeah you do those sit-down videos where
you sit down press record button on the
camera and just
fire away talking and a little bit of an
inspiration for me actually
i want to do more of those types of
videos and the way you execute
them i also i also have a grow
vlog series and pretty much you know i
talk about each day
i have like time lapses and i try to
make it like really cool and and
fun for everybody you know yeah there's
definitely a lot of good stuff on
youtube
like my tips from my grow vlogs
you know what i mean because youtube
doesn't like us very much so
you know they hate us they hate us
for those watching and not familiar with
420 scenes channel
i'll have that linked down in the
description section below
all right let's get into the topics
today so today we're going to talk about
autoflowers
and we'll also talk about compost teas
so let's start off by talking about
autoflowers what medium do you usually
grow
auto flowers in you know i was actually
experimenting with a lot of different
stuff
and um you know i'm a huge fox farm guy
everybody knows fox farm fox farm you
know what i mean
um what i like to do is because i do
transplant the autoflowers i know a lot
of people are weird about that
but uh um what i do is
i start them off in happy frog because
it's a it's pretty light soil it's kind
of like
fox farms light warrior you know and um
when i do transplant i like to have the
you know the bottom
like the bottom half portion of
strawberry fields
um you know with some perlite because
strawberry fields does not really
have the best drainage however it's i
mean
it's really good for flowering and um
that like the top layer of the soil i
have happy frog
and sometimes i'll mix in ocean forest
with happy frog you know because
ocean forest has you know like like bat
guano which is you know pretty important
for the veg stage
so like my logic behind that is okay you
know when i transplant they're gonna
have to go through the veg stage and and
all that but they're not going to be in
the vegetation for that long
because they are autoflowers so you know
by the time they start flowering
the roots will already hit the bottom
half which will be the strawberry fields
so
that's kind of my thinking behind it got
it and so do you start in like a solo
cup and then what container size do you
transplant into
i go from a solo cup to like a seven or
a ten gallon pot
okay and then are you using uh plastic
pots fabric pots
what do you want for what you know i
think they're they're great for aeration
you don't have to worry about
your plant getting root bound it's just
you know just kind of start kind of
spinning around you know
you cutting out a little bit did you say
smart pots yes smart pots
and then what do you use for nutrients
when you're feeding autoflowers
as far as nutrients i i do start off
with the recharge
you know by real growers and oh my god
if anyone's been following the you know
the skittles autoflower she like
exploded you know i mean like
she's got she's got a trunk almost like
my arm you know i mean it's
pretty crazy so i start off with a
recharge like during the veg stage
and um and then i give it some compost
tea
once in a while i'll throw in some some
of ilgm's flowering um
you know blood booster nutrients so um i
think it's got a 0
27 27 npk ratio so that's
excellent for flour you know got it so
do you use
fox farm trio as well or no no
i actually used to use the entire dirty
dozen and
and the trio no more
i found that it didn't really didn't
really help me out too much but i do
like the beastie blooms i think the npk
ratio is like
0 56 0 or something like that straight
up phosphorus you know what i mean
yeah yeah i used to use bc blooms i
think it was what
it's like three four and five a flower i
think and that just helps out
tremendously because
you know particularly using fox from
trio i used to get a lot of phosphorus
deficiency mid flowering
and using that pk booster the beastie
blooms helps out so much
so much so if anybody's using the fox
farm trio out there and are facing
phosphorus deficiency in flowering you
might want to try beastie blooms because
that solved my problems yeah absolutely
so do you use any sugars or microbial
inoculants i know you said you use
recharge which has microbes in it use
anything
else beyond that for microbial
inoculants i would say i use
the um you know the organic blackstrap
unsulfured molasses by i use plantation
plantation or grandma sort to do that
that i think are pretty good you know
i also use honey during during the veg
stage i know a lot of people have been
asking me on my channel
oh you know do you have any kind of pest
issues you know because you know honey
sweet you know
that could that draw like have issues
with bugs and sort of you know that sort
of thing and
no and the reason i like using honey is
because it is an
excellent root stimulant and you know um
you know the growth and development of
your roots are like super important
in the veg stage like i feel like the
roots is something that
people don't really like especially a
lot of newer growers out there
you know they just they think what's
important are the leaves and what they
see but like
how they feed you know that you know the
root system that's the most
important thing right there for sure so
when do you usually apply honey
or or molasses and what dosage do you
usually do the honey i do
one tablespoon per gallon and the
molasses i do
about two tablespoons per gallon and the
honey i use
like maybe a week three to
week five you know or until you know
whenever they start flouring it in
and then molasses um like i said
two tablespoons per gallon and most of
the flowering stage
up until maybe week six after that i
kind of just cut it off
and i apply those every like every like
two weeks or so
got it now when you say week six are you
talking about veg or flour
like when i cut it off yeah flour i'm
talking about the
molasses okay so molasses you're only
doing in flour yeah
got it okay that makes sense sometimes i
will i will give it um the first dose
of molasses like when i start seeing
like pre flowers you know
nice okay so in regards to feeding
autoflowers
and comparing them with photoperiods
some people do treat autoflowers
differently than photoperiods when it
comes to feeding do you
treat autoflowers differently when it
comes to feeding when it comes to
feeding
no i treat it pretty much the same
unless i want to veg longer then
the only difference is that you know i'm
just gonna um i'm just gonna keep giving
you know giving it like honey i mean
that's pretty much it
you know but i i pretty much keep it the
same as far as the feeding
and i know that you also do training on
auto flowers so for example that
skittles that you're growing right now
you uh have done some training to it
tons of tops throughout it uh so what do
you
so i assume you'd like to maximize yield
what do you typically do
for uh training autoflowers in order to
maximize yield
um topping i don't do that now the
reason i don't top is because
with autoflower you know you don't have
any control which means
they you know they could start flowering
week three they could start flat you
know they could start flowering week
five or six
and you know if you top too early you're
screwed
but if you top too late that's not good
either you know what i'm saying so
it's a little sketchy you know what i'm
saying so topping is out
lst is king as far as autoflowers lst is
absolutely king
and i i have 62 tops on that skittles
autoflower
dude it doesn't even fit in the closet
like it's it's it's coming out
you know what i'm saying it makes the
closet and the light look
you know it makes the closet look really
small but um
yeah that that one reminds me of
carmilicious i grew
it was similar to to what you what i saw
in your skittles
picture it's just bursting out
everywhere and i actually ended up
getting a half pound off of
an autoflower plant before i was pretty
proud of that i know some people might
be watching this in my life oh that's it
i've gotten more than that but i don't
know what's the highest yield you've
gotten off of an autoflower and do you
think that skittles is
going to be big enough to get over a
half pound or what
i got 10 o's on the master kush
and that was an autoflower 10 oh wow you
know
okay i found you know what i'm saying
i'm telling you it's all about training
and
i love low stress training you know
obviously you're not stressing your plan
out at all so
you know the growth is not stopped the
growth is constantly going you want to
keep moving you want to keep moving you
know
and um see you wanna form an even canopy
if you have a christmas tree you have
you know the lower bud sites that could
be getting the light they're not getting
the light they're being covered up so
they're gonna become airy like popcorn
buds you know what i mean so i love that
i love that
flat top canopy you know what i mean
except my skittles looks more like a
look like a wave you know what i mean
but
um that's what you want you want an even
distribution of light that's what low
stress training is to me
and even distribution of light that's
how you get all those colas you know i
mean
i always try to i was trying to
challenge myself you know what i mean
the most i had
was actually 82 tops on an auto which is
like
ridiculous you know what i mean
yeah that's crazy that's a lot for sure
but i i don't think
as many people really think about the
importance of the veg stage when it
comes to autoflower plants now
like we touched upon before it's on a
living and lifespan
right in my experience growing
autoflowers i've had plants with
no stunt growth for the first 30 40 days
and they just became huge versus
you know you're slightly over watering
over an autoflower and veg
you see a stunt growth or if you top it
or even sometimes transplanting that's a
controversial topic
i've tried doing that before and i've
still seen that stunt growth
you know low stress training is low
stress so you know
that's not really going to stunt the
growth uh
if any at all but i really feel like
there's a lot of people that aren't
aware of keeping the plant healthy
and trying to get as big as possible for
those first 30 40 days because after
that it's going into flowering right so
yeah you know the problem a lot of
people have is everybody tries to
micromanage their grow oh
you know every day oh you know what's
wrong with this leaf what's wrong with
this leaf it's like bro chill out man
you know like dude like when you
micromanage you are gonna over water
because you feel like you need to do
something you oh you know what i mean
and that's where people screw up let me
tell you something this skittles
autoflower
in veg i water twice the entire veg
why i go by the leaves the plant tells
you what it needs
you know like you don't know anything
your plant knows everything you know
you feed it accordingly you water
accordingly you know what i mean that's
pretty much what i do
so for that particular plant you started
in a solo cup what day do you remember
what day you transplanted
into that larger container is it a 7
gallon or 10 gallon
this one is a 7 gallon okay um
i don't remember maybe maybe 10 days
the rule of thumb that i go by once the
leaves start
sticking out of out of the perimeter of
the cup you have maybe like
an extra couple of days before you know
you might
you know you don't want to get root
bound so that's when you
you know that's when i transplant do you
sprinkle any mycorrhizal fungi on the
roots during transplant or
yes i used mycos i i've been using that
since the get-go
um actually i started using micros
because cali green
he's the guy that that i first started
watching you know all these grow videos
like he's my coast and ever since i was
like i'm just going i'm just gonna keep
using michaels all the time
you know so i spread that around the
root ball i think that's one of the
things that's
just so beneficial that some gardeners
don't use is mycorrhizae i mean
it definitely helps with the transplant
shock
reducing the chances of that because it
feels like every time i use that there's
like no
slow growth at all and i think that's
one thing that should be in
everybody's garden is using mycorrhizal
one guy yeah
i think a lot of people here's the thing
though like when you first start growing
and you look at different resources
everybody's shoving nutrients down your
throat you know what i mean oh fox
farm's the best all you know this
brand's the best this brand's the best
nobody really talks about like you know
the microbes and you know
i think the most important thing for
your root system to have to make your
plant grow vigorously
is you need oxygen and you need microbes
you know which equals an aerobic
environment and that's what you want
absolutely so let me recap real quick
before we move on to the next topic so
you know for autoflowers in particular
you start off in a solo cup
around day 10 or so you'll transplant
into a seven gallon
now that seven gallon is a mixture
usually of
fox farm happy frog and ocean forest
is that right and then from there you're
doing a top dressing with
ilgm bloom nutrients right those are
what dry
organic nutrients uh i only do that once
in a while no they're not they are
they're soluble okay so what points do
you
feed again do you do like a top dressing
at a certain point um i actually top
dress with
with down the earth fishbone meal okay
fishbone meal i put around
maybe a week three or four now what some
people don't know
is that fish bone meals week sorry week
three or four of
flour so you've gone 30 days and then
21 days later roughly it's around day
50ish
is when you're doing that day 50 like
are you talking about from sprout
oh yeah from yeah that's about right
that's about right got it okay
i top dressed with fish bone meal from
down to earth and what a lot of people
don't understand
is it's good to start that a little
maybe a week earlier you know i mean
instead of like week five because it
takes a little while
for that fishbowl meal to break down you
know to become accessible so that that's
one thing i try to
i try to tell people about that but
fishbell meal is great man i mean
that's phosphorus right there you know i
think i think the npk
was like i think like 1 12 0 or
something
though got it so it's just that for top
dressing and then you do molasses
every week or so every week or two
throughout flour
and then well up to a week six of flour
and then recharge
every week throughout the whole life no
just veg
just veg okay just veggies and burnt
flour i put in my own compost thing
oh okay all right is that around the
same time the week three or
um yeah yeah that yeah no maybe week two
maybe week three um i think week two is
pretty good
week two of flour that's when i start
putting in the compost tea
and what i like to use with the compost
tea for
and anyone that's interested i like
using alfalfa meal
i like using kelp meal i love
seabird guano likes you know if you want
phosphorus
seabird guano is is what you need you
know and i use earthworm castings
as well from uh you know wiggly worm and
you know of course i also use um i use
the organic blackstrap molasses and i i
put that all together you know
and i i brew that for about 30 hours
after i declare water for 24 hours
so i add that into the flour as well got
it so that's your
flour recipe that was a good transition
by the way to to get into compost lake
tea which is our
our next avenue here oh yeah yeah yeah
so that's your flower recipe
for compost tea and then do you have a
separate recipe
for veg compost teas um no
actually veg i just use recharge because
it's been i mean
you know what i mean and then for
i'm sorry for your ratios what ratios do
you use
for um those nutrients in the compost
tea all the compost
trying to remember i i used two to four
tablespoons of
the blackstrap molasses alfalfa meal and
kelp meal
i do you know i do one tablespoon of
that i do
one cup of seabird guano
and one cup of worm castings i believe
is that for a five gallon bucket five
gallon bucket and i
fill it with uh three gallons so you
know because if i if i have a five
gallon and a five gallon
you know it's gonna be a lot of spillage
you know what i mean so
yeah pretty good with a three because
i'm using a seven gallon pot
three gallons pretty good got it and
then how long do you let it brew for
about 28 36 hours
okay and then do you ph adjust it at all
yes um after everything is done i ph
adjust it because my water is like
7.8 8.0 so i adjust it
i like it between 6.0 to 6.4
you know that that's where i'm getting
the real optimal results got it now do
you also
dilute some people will dilute the tea
so they take the tea
they'll add it in with additional water
do you do any type of diluting at all or
did you just
feed it straight to the plant no i don't
i just pour right in
okay all right and then what equipment
do you use to brew the teas
um i use the eunuch life ul 40 air pump
i think it was like 30 40 bucks
obviously the 5 gallon bucket and i you
know i attach a hose from
from the uniclife to the you know to air
stones
and that's how i get bubbling up i also
think it's important
a lot of people don't really talk about
this i don't know if it really makes a
difference but
i think it might i do like to oxygenate
the water
like um you know when i'm not when i'm
not having the tea
like while it's declining for 24 hours i
just
throw the air stones in there and i i
bubble it for that 24 hours you know
because
i feel like um you know you know there's
different water out there you know
there's different different water
different cities
you know the quality of water is
different sand and some of the waters
don't have enough oxygen
even though you know water is h2o with a
molecule of
oxygen you know i i think it's important
to oxygenate the water i think it's just
going to help
help to help maintain that aerobic
environment for your plants
so how often do you feed in that tea i
feed about
every 10 to 14 days i think every two
weeks is pretty good
so do you check like the ph or ppm of
like the
soil runoff at all or or i do that
i i actually do not i don't check the
runoff i've never had any issues you
know
i think on on the t side of things when
you're using organic
inputs like you are arguably you don't
you won't really need to
check the ph of the runoff uh in that
particular case
so now do you just use the tees as a
sill drench or do you also
foliar feed using the tees i do i use
the foliar spray when i have you know
when i'm
um mixing in the recharge i put i'll put
some in a mist
like a mist spray bottle you know um but
mostly i do a soil drench
all right we talked about quite a bit in
this one actually we hammered through
this pretty quickly here
how can the listeners find you and what
do you have upcoming in the future
we have a lot of great stuff coming up
we got the granddaddy perp autoflower
grow series going
we're going to be doing some live vlogs
we're going to be taking you know we're
going to we're going to be making videos
outside of the studio we are actually
trying to get to the 2021 connecticut
cannabis day
over at hartford connecticut it's going
to be music bands they're just going to
be
you know just going to be a lot of 420
friendly stuff going on over there
so we're going to be vlogging that we're
going to try to get to more events this
spring in the summer
you know of course with like covet it
might be tough but
you know we're going to see what's going
to be available as we push through this
pandemic
but we have a lot of stuff going on this
year awesome
and again for those tuning in i will
leave a link to
420c's channel down in the description
section below so you guys can head on
over there
give him a subscribe give him a
subscription
follow like all that good stuff 420
scene thank you so much for sitting down
with me talking let me interview you and
pick your brains a little bit about
how you do your autoflowers which you've
been very successful on i mean just just
look at his instagram you can see the
size
of his autoflowers that he's growing and
knowing kind of the
the nitty-gritty details on how you do
things when it comes to autoflowers i
think they're going to be beneficial for
for those listening so and also the
compost teas which we talked about
and i think you just did a nutrient tea
i haven't watched it yet or
your a video on the tea that you do
oh yeah i i just put out a compost tea
video
not too long it was just a couple days
ago and i go
over all the ingredients that i use for
the compost tea and
you know i have i have you know i have a
lot of a lot of clips on the stuff that
i use everything brewing it's
it's great you know i mean it's gonna
help a lot of people out actually a lot
of people have been watching it a lot of
people have been thanking me for it so
i'm glad i could help everyone that you
know that you know that needs a good
compost tea recipe that's been working
out for me
i want to pass it on to everyone else
i'll link that down in the description
section below as well
so if you guys want to hear more details
about how he does this aerated compost
teas
click that down there and uh check it
out any final words
no i think we covered a lot today you
know a lot in a short amount of time
so thanks again for coming on and uh
enjoy the rest of your day
all right have a go on man peace
[Music]
you