coming up on Garden talk once I tried
cocoa I just I never looked back you
know the ability to control EC and water
content and all the variables of cocoa
are just so easy if you stress them a
little bit and make them think in flour
like you know this might be the end
they're going to go into a hyper growth
mode they're going to put out more
calyxes and so really you want to make
sure that from the time that cutting
roots or that seed Pops that you have
momentum through the entire process I
found that that's one of the biggest
things that will lead to a decreased
yield and so all of those things are
basically telling the plant like hey you
need to get on it so I do think that
there's a lot of those techniques that
can lead to the much larger harvests
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 72. in this
episode I interviewed Nick Schweitzer he
has been gardening for 26 years and is
an owner of grow strong Industries in
this episode he talks about balancing
the health and stress of plants in order
to maximize yield and quality thanks to
all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com Mr
Grow it before we get into it I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to Gorilla Grow 10
for sponsoring this episode gorilla is
well known for their quality grow tents
they have a super strong frame thick
canvas density and a height adjusting
roof it comes with a one foot extension
kit and a two foot extension kit is
optional so you can grow even taller
plants they also have the light line
same quality as the original gorilla
grow tents but with a few key design
changes go to their website growstrong
industries.com and use discount code Mr
Grow it for 15 off and we are back
welcome to the Garden Talk podcast today
I am joined with Nick Schweitzer how you
doing today doing wonderful how are you
doing great thanks for asking today
we're going to talk about creating a
balance between the health of your
plants and stressing them in order to
produce maximum quality and quantity
with the right tools so things like
Spectrum control nutrients environment
so on and so forth and you have from
what I hear extensive knowledge in doing
this so I'm excited to hear what you
have to talk to us about today but first
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
yeah sure
um so I'm co-owner and CEO of uh grow
strong Industries
um and grow strong Industries is the
parent brand for Gorilla Grow Tent kind
LED grow lights Lotus nutrients and
supraponics
um and so I guess uh my plant medicine
Journey kind of started uh growing up in
Portland Oregon uh in the mid 90s uh and
I was lucky enough to be surrounded
by a very talented cultivators and some
of the best plant medicine on the planet
really at that time
um and so that's kind of really where my
interest in plant medicine uh all
started and then in 97 I moved out to
Colorado to be a ski bomb and a couple
of my friends at the time were doing
indoor gardens uh in the mountains of
Colorado and that's really where my
interest in indoor gardening started or
my fascination with it really you know
the fact that these guys were growing uh
you know huge rooms uh you know above
you know ten thousand feet in elevation
uh you know in the middle of winter when
it was snowing with five feet of snow on
the ground it was really just kind of
mind blowing going to me and that's
really where my interest kind of got
going I was lucky enough to start
helping them you know which is General
Garden maintenance you know start kind
of getting tips and tricks and starting
to learn you know the lay of the land uh
and then in 2001 I moved out to
California
at that time California was just kind of
blossoming from you know some medical
laws that had just been passed about
five years earlier and that's when I
started running my own indoor gardens
um and uh you know I've been doing it
ever since you know I've been involved
in small gardens large Gardens outdoor
indoor I've kind of really ran the gamut
with my um you know cultivation
experience and exposure uh and kind of
through those trial and errors which
every grower goes through you know
that's kind of what led me to be able to
design mean products for gross wrong
Industries and all those brands that
really kind of solve the pain points
that a lot of growers face
and so you know that's kind of a decade
on from now uh you know designing all
those products uh and and kind of you
know doing what our core mission is
which is you know giving everybody the
chance to have availability to plant
medicine that they grew that they saw
through the process is you know I mean
that's kind of what keeps us going here
awesome and I just do want to say thank
you ahead of time because Crow strong
Industries is actually a sponsor so I
know a lot of the viewers have seen
probably the promotions I've done for
your brand in the past and uh you
support me so I just want to say thank
you to that some of these episodes a lot
of these episodes wouldn't even be out
there without sponsorship support and uh
you know being able to release content
normalize is eventually going to help
legalize in the future so thank you you
for supporting the community absolutely
man absolutely I mean we're on the same
mission right I mean we're trying to
teach people uh you know how to have
access to their own plant medicine how
to grow it um you know that goes for
indoors that goes for outdoors
um you know I mean we believe really
that that kind of is a human right you
know is to be able to grow your own
vegetables and plant medicine and
everything else so we're uh we're
aligned in that way I completely agree
so there are so many different ways to
grow plants right different styles I
guess you can call it some people grow
indoors Outdoors some people are in soil
or cocoa or even a hydroponic system
organic synthetic what's your gross
style yeah
um I mean growing Outdoors is beautiful
right I mean utilizing mother nature for
most everything you need uh is is
beautiful uh and I love it but really
you know in terms of plant medicine
indoors has always been my realm
um and largely that's you know what our
company does uh you know is make
products for indoor cultivation you know
there's something about indoor that just
allows you to kind of control uh you
know what is going on control the inputs
to
um you know to the plant and you know
honestly as we all know you know the
quality of uh what comes out of an
indoor facility is is Bar None
um you know so I've always been an
indoor guy
um you know for many years I was soil uh
and I love soil it's great
um you know but once I tried cocoa I
just I never looked back
um you know the ability to control EC
and water content and all the variables
of cocoa are just so easy
um and then you know when you look at
the root base that you can make in Cocoa
I mean you're talking about a medium
that can have 90 water saturation and
still have plenty of air to create a
massive root base I mean when and I saw
the root bases that I was able to
achieve in Cocoa I was like There's No
Going Back you know and so Coco has been
my style for you know probably the last
10 years and I love it you know I use
the two per mix from Royal gold those
guys are awesome they're super good at
what they do
um and so you know it's always been
cocoa for me and then in terms of uh you
know fertilizer you know I tend to move
away from the synthetic terminology but
I do use fertilizer salt formulations
you know I use my nutrient which is
lotus nutrients it's a super simplistic
it's a you know kind of all-in-one blend
I've really never seen anything easier
to use I mean back in the day when I was
doing soil I'd have a 12 part nutrient
recipe that was honestly a pain in the
butt to keep up with it's super
expensive so moving to something like
Lotus was was great you know which is
you know kind of what drove the
innovation of that that product
and you know I in in terms of my end
goal uh in indoor cultivation is always
for the highest amount of biomass I can
possibly get out of the inputs that I'm
putting in uh and that ultimate bag
appeal right I mean I want the plant
medicine that's in a jar across the room
and you say what the hell is that you
know and I've always found that you know
fertilizing salts over Organics is the
way to achieve the combo of both of
those
um believe me I'm an advocate for
organic you know I mean organic out in
the vegetable garden always
and uh you know the flavor profiles uh
of the smoke that you can get from
organic is second to none
um you know but for a lot of our clients
uh commercial and home hobbyists they're
really looking to maximize weight and
quality uh which is why we've always
tended towards fertilizer salts gotcha
yeah I think there's a I think there's a
balance between biomass and quality
right you could just go for biomass
biomass biomass then all of a sudden you
have like Fox tailing buds for example
it's just that it diminishes that bag
appeal so like there are things that you
can do in order to get a high biomass
but also sustain that quality and that's
really what this topic is going to be
today so let's start with uh let's start
with lighting can you tell us like what
grow light do you currently use
obviously kinda LED is the is the brand
that I use
um you know currently I'm growing with
our x squared which is our commercial
fixture
um you know and it's a beast of the
light it puts out you know a ton of
usable photons
um you know and I think it's a this is a
good uh starting point uh you know to
talk about this you know health of the
plant being the base versus the stress
that we're giving you know the plant
um you know because really and you know
there's a lot of uh really high powered
LEDs out on the market today that
honestly I think a lot of people have no
clue what to even do with them at full
power
right if you don't have all of the other
inputs in your room 100 dialed you are
not going to be able to utilize all of
the photons coming out of that light
right and those variables are easy it's
water content it's CO2 levels it's VPD
levels like all of those things need to
be dead on in order for you to even be
able to utilize a thousand ppfd at plant
pnfu level
um you know I've actually seen some of
your past guests that talk about like oh
man I just need to use that light at 50
right
um and uh and so it's like you know it's
probably the fact that they're getting
better growth because some of their
other variables are off and not to knock
their growing style you know but that's
typically if you turn your light up and
you see light stress happening that's
that's what you're seeing you're seeing
that the other variables aren't up to
Snuff and that engine is running too
fast for the other pieces to keep up
with right
um and so uh you know I think it's
really important to have all of the
balance between these things that we're
about to talk about in order to utilize
that high ppfd lighting you know and so
uh and so for me the X2 is the best it's
got a variable Spectrum I can uh you
know tune it to a veg Spectrum I can
tune it to a flower spectrum
and with what we call the targeted
Spectrum which is basically you know us
not relying so much on you know white
light LED that's got really high peaks
and the yellows and the greens that you
know five to six hundred nanometer
wavelength
um you know but it kind of has a more
targeted Spectrum which is a more usable
Spectrum to the plant we you know find
that we can really crank all those
variables up we can get really high EC
we can utilize CO2 to the Max and we can
get some pretty outstanding uh uh you
know weights from our harvests as a
result of it and so you know in terms of
stress for light level typically those
aren't going to be good for the plant
right when we talk about you know the
benefits stressors to the quality of
flour when it comes to light we're more
talking about uh UV light uh you know
and exciting the uvr8 protein to kind of
crank up that secondary metabolite
production
um you know we have people that
drastically change their Spectrum the
last like week of flower right they
crank all their Reds down all their
whites down and go with the heavy blue
and that's same thing it's stressing the
plant out and and kind of kicking up
that secondary metabolite production and
so there are little tips and tricks that
you can do with lighting to kind of
bring out that stress
but if you're talking about low light
levels or highlight levels those are the
typically the stressors that don't
benefit you uh and more kind of lock out
your plant if anything gotcha for the
record I'm one of the ones that dim my
grow lights in order to to get through
my grill because I don't supplement CO2
like I'm not running a 1400 PPM and so
CO2 is my limiting factor right so like
if I don't dim my lights I'm going to
fry my plants because my CO2 levels
aren't up there now I started using some
CO2 and we'll get into CO2 later on in
this episode because that is something
that can be used to increase biomass
which is on the topic here but uh but
yeah for the most part I do like to dim
my lights and make sure that uh I'm not
running into foxtail issues which
happens to me a lot the heat raises up
Fox telling occurs and like we mentioned
earlier the the bag appeal just kind of
diminishes on that Avenue so yeah Dives
yeah yeah I mean look I've given you
know that X2 to friends or the x squared
to friends of mine mine who have been
growing longer than me you know and and
do it on a commercial scale and it takes
them uh you know a minute to get used to
how much light is actually coming out of
that fixture and I'm always like man you
got to go harder you got to go harder
CO2 EC and you know old school grower
mentality it's like ah I can't really
like press this threshold and then they
finally learned that like you have to
Crest that threshold and when they do
they're like oh my God it was like
amazing the results that I started
getting right so I mean the whole
growing in general has been flipped on
its head
um in the past you know five years or so
I mean some of the things that we never
thought to do or never thought were safe
zones and we'll get into that with the
BPD thing
um is now like oh that is where I want
to be and look at the you know look at
the the effect of that so
so you touched upon how you use your
grow light to maximize the yield and
quality you talked about light levels
and Spectrum but kind of getting a
little bit more detailed onto light
levels par now there are some people who
go for specific par levels throughout
the different stages of growth or some
people look at DLI is there any specific
par levels that you're targeting for the
different stages of growth in order to
maximize yield or quality when you look
at certain plant medicines
um you know DLI is anywhere in the kind
of like 40 to 45 range
the problem with sometimes reaching
those DLI levels is that when you're
reaching maximum DLI levels which would
be maximum ppfd levels of plant canopy
to achieve that uh you know divided by
the hours number uh number of hours your
light is on
um you know it really rolls back to all
those other variables you know I mean I
would say in a typical home growth
scenario getting over seven or eight
hundred ppfd at plant canopy level is
probably going to give you more problems
than it is benefit
um and so if we could speak in terms of
like 100 dialed environment
um you know commercial environment yeah
I mean I would say you know clothing
stage you're looking at 150-ish uh ppfd
is plenty
um you know to to carry out the cloning
process uh you know young veg you know
anywhere from four to four fifty ppfd is
usually what we target
um and then in flower you know I do have
people that slowly ramp up through
flowering it's never really been my
style I kind of go all or nothing from
the beginning
um and so you know I'm usually in that
800 to a thousand
um a thousand is tough though right I
mean a thousand like you better have all
of your other variables dead on in order
for that to turn out well
um but if you do the results are amazing
right and so you know I would probably
say I tend more towards that 800-ish
range um because you know I I can be
lazy sometimes about uh you know making
sure that you know my temp and humidity
are perfectly dialed uh you know and so
and so sometimes you know when you don't
have those controls when everything's
not completely automated you know
tending towards the lower end of that
spectrum is better uh and it's
counterintuitive to the way most people
think right wait I give my plant less
light and it does better you know but
but really it just has to do with that
the harmony amongst all of those things
um so yeah you know probably about that
800-ish range in full flower the the
margin of error is much less at those
lower ppfd levels right I mean you can
have a EC swing you can have a water
content swing you know and it doesn't
affect the plant as much when you're
redlining it like it better all be on
you know so so you already mentioned
you're using Lotus nutrients do you aim
for different EC or PPM during the
different stages of growth yeah yeah I
do
um you know and again it really has to
do with the amount of light that you're
giving your your plants you know all
your other variables again all these
variables kind of count on each other to
you know give you the level of which you
know what you take lighting to or ec2
and everything else so you know when
using High ppfd lighting like the x
squared
um you know I mean I come right out of
the gates at about a thousand PPM which
I've told people that and they're like
whoa like really you know
um and you know I've noticed that if you
don't you can get a little clone to lock
out pretty quick because with that
amount of light and with CO2
augmentation it just wants to go uh you
know so 1000 PPM that's what 200 2.0 EC
um you know I'm typically drifting
towards probably 1300 uh you know
towards the latter stages of you know
the vegetative stage
um in into flowering which is about 2.6
EC and then uh you know through the
first you know about every two weeks in
flower I'm stepping it up about 100 PPM
until I get to about 1800
um which is you know 3.2 EC uh and
sometimes I feel like that's not even
enough I mean the plants are just
soaking it up and just taking it
um and I have a lot of commercial
clients that are growing way higher than
that I mean I've got a lot of people
that are in that 3.6 to 3.8 EC range you
know when you talk about uh you know
crop steering techniques I mean
sometimes they're touching the like 5.0
range which is insane to me uh you know
and obviously you know if you if you
don't have an automated system uh you
know similar to like an aurora you're
playing a fire there you know and you're
playing with fire above 3.0 EC uh if
everything else isn't 100 dial
um but so yeah so I kind of slowly ramp
up through flour and you know I usually
end at 3.2
okay and then how about pH a lot of
people monitor the pH I know you said
you're in Cocoa there's different pH
ranges for soil versus cocoa what do you
do for pH yeah I mean I'll have to admit
pH is something that I don't check all
the time and here's why uh it's because
I know the pH of my input water I know
my nutrients really well I know where
when I mix to a certain nutrient
strength it's going to be it about this
pH and I know how much up and down to
choose right and so for me it's like I
don't check it every time but I am
trying to go into that 6.0 to 6.2 range
in Cocoa
um you know soil obviously you're
drifting a little bit higher sometimes
all the way up to like 6.5 6.6 and in
Hydro you're obviously going lower you
know all the way down to like 5.5 Coco
I'm trying to stay in that 6.0 to 6.2
range
um and uh you know it's like that's one
of those things where sometimes after
you've grown for a while after you kind
of get used to the new nutrient program
that you're using it becomes kind of
intuitive right and that goes for
feeding too I mean sometimes I'll be in
there and I'll be on a you know 1500 PPM
level and I'm like yeah they look like
they want a little bit more and I'll you
know I'll give them a little bit more
and sometimes same thing I'll be like ah
you know it looks like a little bit of
Tipper and I'll pull back a little bit
and so you know it's I think it's
important to kind of be intuitive in
gardening too and not just always
following the instruments not just
always following the recipe because that
can get you into trouble you know and
that's largely the you know issue I have
with these full automations that we're
seeing these days is like it's a plant
you know like it wants to be loved it
wants to be paid attention to and you
know every once in a while you need to
kind of adjust your game plan based on
your intuition of what you're seeing in
the plant
I've had really good luck doing 5.8 pH
going in to Cocoa I feel like that's a
little bit more simple than soil at
times controlling BH because I feel like
soil has so many things in the actual
medium that's adjusting the pH right
plants releasing acids there's microbes
in there so on and so forth but yeah for
a p for cocoa in particular since you're
a cocoa girl I forgot to mention it 5.8
pH is is what I do so and I actually do
start a little bit under 6.0 I usually
start at like five nine which is a weird
number uh and then slowly kind of raise
it up over the over the course which
kind of just naturally happens as I
build strength uh in my nutrient program
um and uh you know so it and I mean
runoff is an important one right I mean
I in fact I think it's almost for me
more important to check my runoff every
once in a while than it is to check my
in you know inbound nutrient solution uh
just to make sure that there's nothing
funky going on in the medium so I would
100 recommend that to anybody that's
growing Coke or soil you know and then
in terms of like stressing with nutrient
strength
I don't really think there's anything
there
um you know in terms of quality I mean I
think if you under feed uh I don't think
that will ever really go too well for
you unless your inputs are off and then
it could be as what the thing that saves
your garden right is by interfeeding
um you know over feeding yeah if you
have all your inputs on you can really
kind of get to that you know level of
pushing the plant ultimately making a
healthy base for it but if you talk
about the irrigation side of things and
the water content in the medium now
you're talking about a stress that can
have a beneficial effect on the plant
um you know I don't I I'm kind of a
wildflower nut and they always say the
best year to go out and see wildflowers
is after a drought year which has kind
of counter-intuitive but that's the
plant saying oh my God we don't have
enough water to survive and so they end
up making more seed stock and drop it on
the ground because for an annual that's
the point is to continue on with life
um and so it's the same thing with plant
medicines you know if you stress them a
little bit and make them think in flour
like it you know this might be the end
they're going to go into a hyper growth
mode they're going to put out more
calyxes that are for hopefully in nature
they would want that to become a seed we
don't want that in indoor growing
um and you know but that's kind of the
the mode they go into they go into
survival mode and they say I need to
regenerate as much as possible uh to you
know to counteract the conditions that
I'm being put in
um and you know you want the exact
opposite when you're in vegetative stage
you want that stress to be non-existent
you want the fastest most healthy robust
growth you can get so that's why we want
more water content and soil during that
period but then once you get into flour
letting them kind of dry a little bit
you know it's called a dry back and in
crop steering techniques uh is actually
a kind of a good stressor for the plant
okay so drought stress I was even
thinking about that that yeah so so
you're saying later on in flowering
around what weeks would you say would
you typically do drought stress yeah
typically I mean you know in in crop
steering techniques they say after week
three right I mean weeks one through
three that's where it's still really
kind of in a vegetative stage it's in
that stretch stage once it gets into
week three you've got good flower
development and that's when you kind of
want to start introducing that stress
um you know which is basically you know
when you irrigate right um You irrigate
you cut off your irrigation
more towards the middle of the day so if
in Cocoa if you're doing high frequency
fertigation and you're doing multiple
shots or irrigation times through the
day you want to cut that off you know
three or four hours before your lights
turn off and let that dry period kind of
go for a little bit longer than you
normally would rather than irrigating
all the way up until the lights turn off
or even when the lights are off which
some people do which is basically
keeping that Medium wet enough that that
plant's like I have everything I need
I'm healthy I'm good and it doesn't get
that kind of kick in the butt to say oh
man I need to start going I need to
start really producing you know what's
what's ultimately going to be my
survival
gotcha I have to play around with
drought stress a little bit more the
tough thing is is like when you're
growing with Organics for example it's
often advised to keep the media moist at
all times because the amendments there
need to be broken down by microbes right
then microbes need to be active if it's
dry they're not there breaking down that
organic matter and turning them into
usable nutrients for the plants but on
the mineral nutrient side yeah I mean I
used to actually do that all the time
now that I think about it is when I
water right so anytime I water you do
the old uh stick your thumb down in the
medium and if the top inches bone dry
then you know the water right so maybe
that's a form of drought stress that is
uh actually helping with some of those
secondary metabolites for example so
I'll have to play around with a little
bit more yeah yeah and I mean we're not
talking about dragging the medium out to
where leaves are uh you know folding
down right I mean it's uh drought stress
can be you know just letting the cut the
the medium dry out a little bit more
than you usually do and you know not to
where it's affecting microbial life
um you know but but to where it's you
know telling the plant hey you know you
might not be getting water again for a
while like you better go kind of a thing
and you know that's a good point is um
you know one of the things that I want
to stress the most
about just the overall cultivation
experiences that most plant medicines
rely hugely on momentum right momentum
is so big for having those perfect
harvests with the most weight and the
best quality and that momentum can be
thrown off in a lot of ways you know
either you rooted your clones and you
were a week late to getting them into
you know whatever medium you are using
or you were late to transplant into a
bigger pot or they dry it out too much
to the point where they were wilting
right all of those things will stop that
momentum of a plant and just one event
like that will have a huge impact on
your final Harvest and so really you
want to make sure that from the time
that cutting roots or that seed Pops
that you have momentum through the
entire process I found that that's one
of the biggest things that will lead to
a decreased yield is some kind of stress
event somewhere along or a large stress
event I should say
um you know that that ends up taking the
momentum out of the plan
that makes sense let's flip it up let's
talk about environment so let's start
with temperature what temperature do you
typically aim for yeah
um indoors I mean you know the setting
uh has a lot to do with it you know
where you live and everything else um
you know I think for home Growers
temperature and humidity are obviously
two of the things that are the hardest
to control
um you know in small settings but you
know I'm usually aiming for about 82 is
kind of my comfort zone
um you know all the way up to you know
maybe 85. um you know I know people that
run their rooms even hotter than that
um which you know it's just
uncomfortable to work in I don't think
it's really that great uh you know for
the plants
um and uh anything lower than that
um you know old school HBS days we you
know 76 to 78 um but that was before we
had BPD and all that kind of jazz uh
happening so you know 82 is my sweet
spot
um but again you know adjusting
temperature if you can't get humidity up
that high is a good thing to do I mean
really when you look at temperature you
really want to be looking at temperature
and humidity combined for that VPD
measurement uh and staying within a
healthy healthy dpd range if if at all
possible you know um you know some of
these humidity levels that we're
starting to talk about these days you
know tell that to an old school grower
20 years ago and they think you're
insane right I mean 82 degrees I think
proper BPD in that range is 72 74 ish
percent humidity and all you know oh
girl be like you're crazy that's like
powdery mildew right
um but it's not I mean that's where
stomata are breathing healthy that's
where the plant is healthy and powdery
mildew attack unhealthy plants it's not
humidity that causes it humidity can
exacerbate it uh you know I mean uh you
know sport production uh or reproduction
happens at high humidities but that's
not what the cause of powdery mildew is
uh it's actually an unhealthy plant in
an unhealthy plant is a plant that's not
breeding correctly so it's really about
keeping those stomata open and
functioning and breathing and so really
it boils down to VPD now my next
question for you is what relative
humidity do you aim for and you've
answered that uh so at 81 degrees
Fahrenheit temperature it's around 70
percent relative humidity is that what
you mentioned yeah I think I think at 82
I think it's 72 to 74 I think is this is
the safe range is that for the entire
grow or is that only for veg and then
you kind of lower for flour yeah so I
mean you know typically in veg is when
you will see the higher uh humidity
ranges and a lot of people do kind of
pull back um for flour and honestly even
in late flour I'll pull that back even
further
um you know when you have huge you know
swollen flowers uh you know I always
kind of get a little bit gun shy keeping
my humidity so you know is where I'd be
at 7274 during veg I'd probably pull
that down to like 65 68 during flower
and then I'd probably pull that down
even further to like 60 62 during those
like last couple weeks of flour just so
I can make sure that I don't have any
other problems
uh you know like Bud rot or anything
like that
um so
gotcha and uh CO2 I know you mentioned
that you supplement CO2 how do you
supplement CO2 and then what level PPM
do you typically aim for yeah so CO2
again it all has to do with the other
variables light levels uh you know EC I
mean all of these things are
interconnected as you're seeing that
that's kind of my theme
um and so with CO2 I mean the easiest
way to augment CO2 is probably a CO2
burner
um it's uh it's you know lugging tanks
in and out of your house uh isn't uh
very discreet for one
um and uh it's also a pain in the butt
like Lena lugging the tanks to the Hydra
store and the gas store to get them
filled and so a CO2 burner is probably
the easiest way uh I think appropriate
pain lasts pretty long but you do have
to deal with the excess heat coming off
of a CO2 burner and they might not be
proactive but coal for smaller
applications I mean you know CO2 burner
for a room room four to ten lights is
probably practical and so that's how
I've always done it I've always ran in
the like 1200 to 1500 PPM range and that
seems to work for me I've heard of
people going all the way up to like 2500
PPM which is pretty crazy it's a lot and
it's a lot of CO2 and I've heard you
know people having great results with as
little as like 800. I mean I think
ambient CO2 is somewhere in the 400 to
450 range you know so for someone like
you who's not augmenting CO2 you know
refreshing that room to get that ambient
CO2 back to levels is super important
but I've had great success even at 800.
so I've been playing around a little bit
with supplementing CO2 like I got those
TB Naturals canisters they sent me over
those I tried those out for a while can
be very expensive using those I am
currently trying out the mushroom bags
365 exhale bags and I have that hanging
above the plants and uh it I do have a
CO2 monitor in there so monitoring the
PPM that does raise it but it's not
constant and the way I have my exhaust
set up is it's AC Infinity so it's kind
of automated so once I have the set
point set so when it reaches 82 degrees
Fahrenheit I aim for the same
temperature you do it'll start
exhausting out some of that heat and it
will take some of that CO2 with it so
that's the unfortunate thing about it
but uh but I figured I'd you know try it
out and see what happens and it does
raise up the CO2 quite a bit so yeah I
mean I think whenever you don't have you
know tanks or a CO2 burner I mean any
kind of augmentation that you can get in
there is better uh you know and the
mushroom bags are awesome I mean
mushrooms I think are probably going to
save our world at some point uh so um I
I wholeheartedly support those and uh
yeah I mean you know anything you can do
to get those levels up the better now
how about air circulation and air
exchange both of those things are very
important what do you do for that and do
you use that for precision stress at all
yeah I mean you know air circulation is
probably one of the more underrated uh
and underutilized uh you know theories
in a grow room
um you know getting proper air
circulation in a grower room is a
challenge
um you know a lot of people have
circulation fans that kind of just blow
at their plants uh and you know move air
around a little bit around that you know
immediate vicinity but really what
you're trying to do is get as much
turbulation in that room as possible so
that you're getting air through the
canopy and not just blowing at the
canopy right you know a lot of those
crevices where all those leaves are kind
of in close proximity you know the
humidity levels within those little
pockets can be actually a lot higher
than what your sensor is actually
telling you so getting air movement
through that whole entire canopy is
super super important
um and uh you know it's in terms of
stress yeah I mean blowing wind on those
plants is just like blowing wind in
nature it's going to tell that plant a
you need to produce stockier stems you
know to support
um you know the wind that you're getting
so you can't have light stress on the
plant that actually makes it sturdier
through air circulation uh and then in
your case right turning over that air
and backing that air out of the room so
that you get ambient CO2 to be
replenished uh is super important right
stale air is never a good thing when
you're doing CO2 augmentations a little
bit different of an equation because
you're trying to actually keep that
atmosphere in the room keep those really
high levels of CO2 because you know
again it's either coming from a tank or
it's coming from a burner so it makes no
sense to pull that out of the room but I
would still do probably every 24 hours a
full room refresh just to kind of pull
the staliness out of the air get
everything cycled and then turn you know
the exhaust system off and kind of get
back to you know the ico2 environment so
yeah airflow is very underrated in Grow
rooms and I think you know a lot of
problems end up getting caused by lack
of airflow I completely agree with you
that the air circulation is underrated
and you know air exchange as well I'm
actually doing a grill right now where
I have one plant that is just covered in
trichomes and it's right next to the fan
and then the other one same cultivar
different phenotypes so I can't it's not
really a fair comparison but the one
directly next to the fan is just covered
in the trichomes and there's that theory
of wind stress right is that wind stress
actually causing it to produce more
track homes hard to prove I don't think
anybody's ever proven that yet but uh
but that's something that that is often
said that can help cause Precision
stress you know and help help that
secondary metabolites yeah
I mean yeah exactly I mean that's what
it all boils down to right it's a
secondary metabolites anytime a plant is
stressed it says you know I mean what
secondary metabolites are you know there
for the plant to attract insects uh you
know make more uh seed stock I mean all
of the things that you know are kind of
like it's survival tactics anytime you
introduce stress that's what it starts
to kick into high gears all of those
things that it needs to you know
basically survive
um and so wind stress probably can
absolutely do that uh you know and then
you know really if one plant has better
air circulation around it throughout its
growing cycle than some of the plants
behind it it could just have a more
healthy base and be a healthier plant in
general allowing it to you know be
better quality when it's done right I
mean you need a healthy plant in order
to take the stresses that we give them
if you don't have a healthy plant you
give it stress it's gonna it's it's
gonna go south on you right it's going
to lock out it's gonna you know be a
weak Harvest if you have a healthy plant
and then you bring those stresses in
it's going to have you know a good
effect which is that plant's going to be
like well now I'm kicking all these
processes into high gear secondary
metabolites seed production all that
stuff well calyx production that's a
really really good point there so I
don't think we could talk about biomass
increasing yield and stuff without
talking about plant training you know
that's uh often done manipulating a
plant different ways doing training
whether it be a low stress training high
stress training there are so many
different things that you can do what do
you typically do for plant training in
order to maximize yield or quality
yeah I mean I think you know when you
when you talk about uh you know plant
training I don't know I mean obviously
yield is a huge one right uh you can
train a plant these five different ways
and get five different results in terms
of yield so you know where that
technique comes in I think is when you
are limited in your plant numbers that
you can grow right I mean here in
California
um we're allowed to grow six plants uh
uh you know with erect laws and so when
you can only grow six plants I mean some
of these kind of super cropping
techniques are you know pinching off and
you know really starting to spread out
that top canopy and get a lot of
different flower sites can be massive I
mean you can quadruple your yield that
you can get off of just four plants
um you know in my uh in my experience
it really does boil down to the strain
that you're growing
um some strains just don't take to that
kind of stress as well as others I've
seen certain strains that don't want to
be topped they don't want to be pinched
they don't want anything they do much
better by just letting them grow letting
that Apex flower happen and some of that
lateral branching and that's where you
get the the highest yields I've seen
other strains that perform poorly in
that in that way and they want to be
topped and they want they want to have
you know multiple lateral Branch sides
so I do think that that's uh you know
can be strain specific
um you know but for my style of growing
I'm usually you know want to be as low
maintenance as possible so I don't get
over crazy with my training techniques
or anything like that
um you know and so I usually top once if
it's a strain that allows that and I
kind of just let them go
um I usually flip into flour at a pretty
young age so I'm not doing a ton of you
know stress training or anything like
that you know in terms of um you know
Leaf stripping
um you know the the week before flower
leaves dripping the three week Leaf
stripping I mean again that's that's all
those are all those little signs of the
plant saying wow I just lost all this
foliage I need to kick into overdrive
right I need to kick into overdrive my
you know you could make the argument
that you're now getting light further
down into the canopy because some of
those leaves are you know not existing I
don't know if I buy into that as much
but when you're stripping the plant of
everything it's like man I need to go I
need to start you know reproducing all
those leaves so I can get back to having
my you know my my light pads and you
know I need to start you know hyper you
know going into flower overdrive and so
all of those things are basically
telling the plant like hey you need you
need to get you need to get on it you
know
um and so I do think that there's a lot
of those techniques that can lead to
much larger harvests taking a step back
and thinking about everything that has
to do with growing what other advice do
you have for those who are looking to
maximize yield and or quality
um
don't overthink it you know I think I
think largely people tend to overthink
the growing and you know they they try
to get almost a little bit too nitpicky
on it
um you know it's something that you know
I think that you need to again use your
intuition
um and you need to kind of pay attention
to what the plants are saying you know
pay attention to the little signals that
they're giving you uh you know and and
adjust uh accordingly
um you know again you do in order to use
some of these stress techniques you do
have to have a healthy base first right
and that has that goes back to uh you
know what we've been talking about which
is you know the correct balance between
lighting CO2 EC and water content and
CO2 you know if you have all of those
things in Harmony and working together
then you can go in to do all of those
little stress techniques with UV
um you know with water suppression with
you know stripping of leaves uh at week
three of flower like all those little
things with the the plant will react
great because it's now in a healthy
state where it's like I can handle that
stress and here's the production that
I'm going to put out as a result of it
if you don't have a healthy base to
start with you're just going to ruin
your Harvest you know you're gonna
you're basically gonna you know you're
gonna throw the plant over the edge and
you're going to have decreased yields
and you're going to have poor quality
and so you know it's really
concentrating on getting that healthy
base first then starting to incorporate
some of those stress techniques uh is is
really probably what I would say
I think that's some really good advice
there so wrapping things up how can
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future yeah
um so you know you can find me on
basically
um all of our YouTube channels uh grow
strong Industries Gorilla Grow kind LED
grow lights Lotus nutrients uh and super
products
um or super closet
um all have their individual social
channels um all have individual YouTube
channels we're trying to consolidate
everything onto grow strong Industries
um you know and we've got some great
products uh you know in the pipeline
coming out probably none of which I'm at
Liberty to talk about quite yet
um you know but if you keep an eye on
our websites
um then you'll be seeing them come out
here soon and uh we're just going to
continue doing what we've always done
you know which is try to you know make
world-class products that answer to
those pain points that Growers have
and uh continue making it easier and
easier for people to have access to
plant medicine and to grow their own
because you know it's not only fun but
it's you know super rewarding
um and at the end of the day everybody
should be able to to do that you know
everybody should be able to grow their
own plant medicine and the vegetables
that they put on their table for dinner
I think it's super important I think as
a Humanity we need to get back to our
connection with nature and it's a great
way to do it you know watching that
plant go through all of its processes
and you know it's a labor of love being
able to see it go through those
processes and harvest it and consume it
it's uh there's nothing there's nothing
like it and so you know helping people
kind of get back to that uh is is our
main goal nice nice yeah I saw her on
social media recently you guys announced
a like was it like a signature grow tent
with like Tommy Chong or something like
that that's that's pretty cool that just
launched yeah yeah
it did it just launched it's been a
little while in the making
um but uh Tommy's team reached out to us
and wanted to partner on a grow tent I
was like absolutely you know obviously
you know Tommy Chong has been an
integral part of this industry
um you know he's been a Pioneer in a lot
of ways
um and uh you know he has been fighting
for that same thing you know accident
people having uh you know free access to
plant medicine and so you know we've
always supported Tommy and his uh his
mission in life and he's a great guy
he's funny as hell
um and uh it was a pretty cool project
to work on so we're pretty excited about
it he's certainly a legend in this
industry and we actually had him on
another podcast I'm on called from the
stash he came on there and he was
sitting there he's telling all these
stories and boy can he talk yeah I mean
he's he's such a classic guy I mean
super nice and like I said I mean it's
just everything that comes out of his
mouth is just you know hilarious you
know just said just just just a sweet
sweet guy absolutely well I'll
definitely have a link to your channel
probably I'll probably put the grow
strong Industries one down in the
YouTube description section below if
you're tuning in on one of the podcast
platforms just search for them either
grow strong Industries or Gorilla Grow
Tent Lotus nutrients kind LED all of
those fall under Nick and uh yeah if you
enjoyed this episode click that Thumbs
Up Button subscribe to the channel if
you haven't already every single weekend
I'm releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode and I would love for you to tune
in to future episodes Nick thank you so
much for coming on to this episode today
this was awesome this was really really
cool thanks for having me I really
enjoyed it thanks everyone see you in
the next episode