welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 110. in this
episode I interviewed Dave Hansen Dave
is a father of three a small business
owner and some of you may recognize him
from the perfect Gardens YouTube channel
he has been gardening since he was a kid
and he favors organic methods in this
episode Dave goes over a presentation
that he created which goes over some of
the basics to create a strong foundation
for a family garden I'll show you the
presentation slides as we go along but
if you'd like to download the
presentation I'll link it down in the
YouTube description section below if you
want to see highlights of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube that channel is dedicated to
short clips of these podcast episodes I
want to acknowledge that one of my goals
for this podcast is to provide free
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said a
link to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make that goal
possible thanks to aec Infinity for
sponsoring this episode they have two
different series LED grow lights the the
ion board and the ion grid the ion board
fixtures are board style and use Samsung
LM 301b diodes while the ion grid series
has an open Center design and uses
Samsung lm301h diodes I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these grow lights
and the discount code Mr Grodd 15 works
on both Amazon and their website
acinfinity.com
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Dave
Hansen how you doing today I'm doing
good Chris thanks for having me on
thanks for coming on man so I know you
through a perfect Gardens Community I
know you're very active over there and I
see you just active in so many different
comments section when we cross paths
getting you on this podcast was one of
the things that we had talked about you
have a great topic that you actually
presented which is you're going to be
talking about some of the basics to
create a strong foundation for your
family garden it's really intriguing to
me because at some point in the future I
might have a family so like I have
questions on a personal level so I know
you put together a presentation for this
which I'll have in the YouTube
description section so you can click on
that you'll be able to access this
presentation also be showing it on the
screen as we go along we kind of
flipping back and forth and then yeah if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
you definitely want to head out over to
YouTube and download that presentation
so you can kind of follow along with
this one but before we get into the
topic can you introduce yourself tell us
a little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening yep yep my name is
Dave Hansen and as you said I'm pretty
active in this community you can find me
over at perfect Gardens
the communities are great so I love
going around them all the communities
always giving back and and this was I my
opportunity I saw to to give back to the
community to share my knowledge I've
been gardening since I was a little kid
I've always you know had the privilege
in the summertime going out and picking
up fresh tomato and washing it off and
eating it right from the vine
later in my teens my parents kind of let
me experiment and start my own little
garden plots in the backyard and and
from there you know at a young age I
knew I was pretty connected and I was
going to probably be doing some forms of
gardening throughout my life
and as I got older it held true through
different variations of rental homes and
buying homes and anything in between
adapting so that I can continue my
skills and continue my knowledge so one
day when I had a family that I could
pass it down to them and I do I'm a
single father of three kids
and we recently this will be I think our
fourth year since we broke ground and
our new house and our new garden and and
from here you know it's it's teaching
them the basics trying not to over
complicate it and and and mainly
connecting and you'll see this through
this presentation I'm going to keep it
very basic we're not going to go into
super technical but I'm going to outline
things for you guys to plant the seeds
of questions to ask yourself as every
process as you start your garden and
um and we'll we'll get it started now
awesome talking about my first time ever
gardening from what I can remember it
was with my grandparents and I was super
young I may be around five years old or
something I don't remember the exact
exact age but I was pretty big in their
life but it wasn't big in my parents
life so like it didn't really pass on to
me as a kid as you know I wish it did
you know looking back I wish it did so
um like I mentioned once I have a family
in the future being able to pass on to
my kids so yeah let's get into this
presentation I'm excited you know and I
and I the main thing I tell my kids too
is no matter what you choose to do in
your life you don't have to Garden you
don't have to feel the pressure to do so
but just note that you have the skills
and the power to provide for yourself or
your family in the future if you need to
and they might not understand that yet
but it's pretty powerful because we all
know the economy and things shift and
move around and having this ability is
it's just it's so rewarding not just for
as a parent but just as the children too
um so we'll get started
um uh starting a family garden should be
fun try not to get overwhelmed with all
the different methods and practices that
are out there these things will come
with time and I'm speaking from
experience like if you're if you choose
Organics like don't feel that you have
to do composting and this type of
composting and ferments um stick with
the basics don't feel the pressure of
needing it and especially nowadays with
platforms and the availability of
information is so great you know
including your podcast Chris the
information out there at times can be
overwhelming and we just get way too
much and we feel that pressure that we
need to do it you don't scale your
garden to fit your family's schedules
and demands remember summer's coming
soccer practices cheer practices summer
picnics like what are your demands as a
family and these are things that are
always going to shift as yourself and
your children get older and it'll help
you not bite off too much than you can
take remember you're going to have
awesome ears and not so many great years
some problems may be from your own doing
why others are completely out of your
control no matter what the circumstances
may be you are still connecting and
learning that's really important the
only loss in the garden is the
opportunity not taken so if I plan to
vacation and
I came back and all the by ripened
Tomatoes were bad it's not a lost cause
I can compost it I can I can do other
things there's so many
um Avenues in gardening that you can
take
um and a garden should breathe and grow
with your family and that kind of goes
back to how you scale that and it it
some years you might expand and get it
bigger and other years it might have to
get smaller contracted or maybe some
maybe you move and you go from a house
to a condo an apartment you might have
to go to pots and something that's
smaller to suit your needs
and then and for and for those who are
watching on pitcher that's our our
second year of our family garden where
we broke ground we were super proud of
it and I put a picture on there
yeah that's pretty cool let's talk about
that for a second break it down for us
just a little bit about like how many
beds you have and like what are some of
these plants that they're seeing on the
screen right now yeah so this is two
years ago so a lot has changed uh it
does our garden does breathe quite a bit
um in terms of beds this one had two
raised beds one was for carrots and one
was like this makeshift one that I have
for potatoes and you can kind of see it
in the back there's a long run of wood
and that's all potatoes in there
um this year my kids kind of carved out
paths you can see uh malt paths and we
just kind of Incorporated plants and
plopped them in I did have guidance of
where I wanted onions and stuff but I
kind of left it up to them to explore
and and to figure it out
um it's roughly right now I think it's
it's about 25 by 15 and then we did
another new plot last year and that's
probably about a 10 by 10 behind my shed
um
so it's a decent sized Garden but don't
let the size discourage you because if
you can only have a 4x4 area whether
it's in the ground directly sewed or in
a raised bed like be happy with that and
plant what you can with that like If
eventually you can have a big Garden so
be it but it doesn't make me more
successful than the person with a
smaller Garden by no means in saying
that we're going to go into the to the
second slide and and I outlined them as
Garden elements and basically you need
seeds plants weather and food very basic
and and depending on your type of
growing you can even maybe take food out
because you might be more towards
favoring microbial or letting
um the nature kind of extract and mine
what it needs but for seeds make sure
your sourcing quality seeds that are
suited for your region choose heirlooms
if you're wanting to collect seeds for
the following year so if you have a plan
on planting seeds don't buy like
seedless watermelons or these hybrids
that are really steering towards
genetics that are not going to give you
a seed to to reproduce with so keep that
in mind when you're purchasing seeds I'm
not going to say only plant organic
seeds or this seeds your region your
resources are different than mine so you
have to kind of decipher what's best for
you
plants what plants can you grow in your
soil what will provide you the most for
your time I'm not saying most for your
money I'm saying most for your time
because that's time with your children
that's time at sports events that's
times just around the dinner family
around the dinner table
weather know your growing zone and we're
going to go into this in the in the
future slide but the growing zone is is
really important and what challenges may
arise so my I live in Northern Illinois
my problems would be at times extremely
high humidity other times really dry and
hot and then two days later back to
extreme humidity so if we're kind of
thinking VPD outside my vvd ranges are
all over the place and I have to take
that into consideration of what crops
will grow good for my time in my region
and then the last one is food what
sources of fertilizer will you need what
techniques interest you slash line up
with your values and and this kind of
goes into taking on techniques and all
the other stuff what is to your values
you know not everybody like wants to do
compost
um I I for myself I like doing ferments
but I probably will never try a jadam
wedding agent or something like that
personally just doesn't
do anything for me but I know that I can
source that from other people in the
community over like Green Goblin and
he's very competent and has mastered the
safety and the skills to do so where I'm
like I don't want to do it so
um taking that into consideration
um when picking you know your techniques
or your food you know this will all kind
of line in with plugging in how you're
going to have to do it backing up to
seeds real quick talk about quality
seeds place that I like to get my
vegetable seeds from is Baker Creek I
got some really good stuff Purple Lady
bok choy got some butter crunch lettuce
some bullnose Peppers some modus Ras
it's a sweet melon so really really good
place I know it's one of the more
popular places when it comes to like
vegetables I think they have flower
seeds there as well but uh yeah might be
a place that you want to check out not
sure if you have any sources of
vegetable seeds I don't um I personally
get when I do get seeds a lot of our
seeds are actually from because we have
a routine coming at our house so we get
a lot of our seeds from the garden so
the dill we have our Dill seeds from
last year I have my basil seeds from
last year
um so when I go into further in the
process presentation we'll kind of plant
those seeds of how you can do that if
you want to do that but in terms of
courses um if I do need seeds I tend to
go to my local guy
um and I don't I don't even know if it's
his Brands necessarily but I like
stopping in and getting there you know
growing zones
um hopefully most of you have seen this
and it may be some haven't it's on most
packets of your seeds and your growing
zones is basically your first and your
last frost
um this for those who are listening
there's a picture on the screen of the
United States and a packet of seeds and
it shows the U.S zones and those are
broken down like I said on the first and
last frost
um why is this important because if this
is all about your timing okay and and if
you want to start seeds indoors you want
to try to have the best timing I have
had timing guys where I've had tomatoes
indoors and they end up being way too
big and it wasn't a lost cause I planted
them sideways underground and the root
system was amazing because that whole
stem will grow roots so a two football
two foot tall plant laid down sideways
it worked but it could have been
prevented if I paid more attention to my
zone and timed it a little bit
differently
you're you're out in Nevada and you can
see like you have a whole bunch of
different ranges obviously because you
have mountains and Flatlands and
foothills yeah I'm down on the southern
tip there actually in zone nine which
you don't have have listed there 9A
actually so yeah desert region for me
yeah yep and then that's that goes to
you know what's going to be suited for
your region too
um you know and that's that's
um for for in terms of for planning and
what crops may or may not be conducive
the planting cycle we're going to get
into this very basic planting feeding
watering and harvesting so when I kind
of break this down I want you guys to
think like okay planting what am I
planting when do I need to plant it how
much do I need to plant
um and ask more in-depth questions to
yourself so planting know when your crop
can be planted take advantage of with
plants that can be sowed in the fall or
in early spring
um
feeding what are the plants feeding
demands are you planting a plant That's
Heavy feeding next to one that may not
have as much of a
fertilizing demand and causing an access
watering so how much do you need the how
much does the individual crops need to
be watered if one type of plant requires
High volumes of water you wouldn't want
to buy more sensitive plants that
require less watering and then
harvesting understand the potential
Harvest dates and how to prepare for
them depending on the crop it's at this
time that you can plant for a second
harvest so it for those that don't see
the visual there's planting feeding
watering and harvesting and then there's
arrows cycling back around because if
you understand your your timing of your
planting and you're when you're going to
be harvesting you can potentially sow in
two or a third one depending on the crop
and with harvesting
this is extremely important harvesting
windows are especially important when it
comes to preserving for your Harvest to
ensure longevity you need the freshest
produce and the timing is everything so
if you kind of go back to okay I want to
can what do I want to can I want to
plant tomatoes but you have to ask
yourself what kind of tomatoes because
if you plant the variety that's going to
give you
some Tomatoes trickling in through the
summer and into the fall you're probably
not going to have enough to be to
efficiently be able to can your tomatoes
so you need to get the variety that
you're going to harvest most of them
towards the end of the Fall that way
you're picking the ripest and the most
of your Harvest and then washing
prepping and canning and this is where
your timing is everything moving on
garden layout understand the orientation
of your garden
North East Southwest you know where is
the sun coming up where is the sun
coming down where are you going to get
the most sun and this isn't always the
the most important thing but most crops
are going to require full sun there are
some that are going to require partial
or more light amounts of Sun Well parts
of the garden have long durations of
shade once again this is not a bad thing
I have a small little tree that during
mid-summer it Shades a portion of my
garden but I'm able to plant in like
another row of lettuce and the Heat of
the summer is not going to make it go
bitter because it's underneath the
shading and it still gets enough light
to photosynthesize and produce quality
vegetables you know are you growing
plants that have low light requirements
and it goes to the same mindset what are
the requirements of the plant what am I
planting what am I feeding it just kind
of keeps repeating in our head are you
are you growing plants that have low
light requirements if you're planting
fruiting trees how big will they get
same thing with annuals and if you see
on the screen this is actually when me
and my kids designed our garden
and there's two apple trees and we
planted them I think we figure like
eight years worth of growth
um so depending on how I prune them and
how big they're going to get it's not
good as shade that part of my garden
where I'm growing my vegetables and then
in front of my garden you'll see four
little circles and that is where we put
our raspberries and as of this year that
is a wall of raspberries so it's four so
kind of knowing your plants and what
you're planting I didn't have to spend
all this money to fill it up the first
year I just bought four mother plants
and now it's a complete wall and I can
probably pull out 10 to 20 maybe more
babies every year and plant them around
different parts of my land or give them
the neighbors and have them start their
Gardens you know that's awesome what did
you use to make this to be honest with
you this was some free thing that I
Googled online and people used it it's
kind of like um how some websites do
grow logs where people can keep track of
their grow logs this was one kind of
that was free and a lot it wasn't user
friendly though it's like outdated it
was like I want to do this and it's like
you know working in paint but it's a
really cool concept and it got enough
for where yeah this is my plan this is
my lot and this is what I want to do and
in the back corner behind the shed you
can see that that's the newer the the
newer plot that we put in and last year
we did
potatoes I think we did all potatoes
there last year nice yeah I know some
people probably wondering where that
came from because having a mapping tool
through software seems like it could
definitely be valuable to map things out
just like you show here it is and but
never rule out
um the whole notebook you know I have
notebooks filled of old Garden drawings
and I and I go back to them to see my
mindset to see what I was thinking
um you know and take this line you know
what direction do you want to plant your
rose and if someone asked me I
personally plant mine running north
south because the sun is rising East
West and I plant normally my tomato
plants will can go on the it would be
the east side that way as the sun comes
up and they're they're not shading the
plants of you know the rest of the
plants have their all-day sun and the
bigger plants are not shading the other
plants but at the same time I do have
other rows that go East-West like my
onions my carrots because they're just
small and the Sun is there and they take
it and nothing Shades them out but once
again these are things that you can
consider some things fall under the Bro
Science and I don't matter which way you
plant them then you know that's what you
connect with nice nice well let's move
on to the next slide here I won't I
won't try not to interrupt you as much I
know you got quite a few slides left to
go so I'll let you do your thing okay so
the next one is growing media and
nutrient delivery and this is very basic
so if you are having to do raised beds
if you're on a deck patio consider the
differences between growing Medias and
their water holding capacities when
planting raised beds are planting in
pots so just outlining organic soils
pure peat moss pure Cocos and this kind
of goes into your schedule you know how
much you're going to have to water and
if you have a soil that maybe holds more
water it might be more conducive for
your your lifestyle when you're out at
work and you come home they're not just
wilted because they can't even make it
that far into the day without needing
water this is where Annoying your soil
the cohesions and stuff will will help
you and then from there for your your
nutrient delivery we basically you know
I look at is we have organic dry
amendments organic liquids synthetics
and then synganics dry amendments are
basically just different forms uh
granular sizes
materials in nature comes in many
reduced size forms requires biology to
break down organic liquids or you know
as their certifications
synthetics are just man-made ionic forms
and then we have synganic synganics
which is a blend of amendments and
synthetic liquids mostly in my opinion
it seems like people favor Organics and
they just use that little bit in between
what they need but I think it's
important that you kind of narrow in
your your methods so that you don't end
up wasting a lot of money and having a
shelf filled with a lot of varieties of
things take your time when you're doing
your research and picking your
deliveries system for those are
listening you can't see it on screen but
I have a picture of one of our family
peppers and when we cut it open there's
like a perfect smiley face so I wrote
Nature is always showing us how happy it
could be and we're eating dinner and I
cut it open and I called the kids over
and I said see we know we're doing a
good job and I showed it to them you
know and they're like what you know it
was it was one of those moments where
you know they've really connected with
their hard work you know and they got to
pick it and cut it and see how happy it
was
so going into that it's keep it fun
don't feel the need to incorporate all
the growing methods and techniques at
once you are not going to want to do all
techniques that are oh and that's okay
and I kind of said that before I like
composting and fermenting but I probably
won't get into jadam practices
um for me it's try one new technique or
new fertilizer a year connect with the
visual responses that you see and try to
understand why it may have worked or why
it may have not worked adding too many
things at once may lead to compound
issues and and or you not understanding
why it worked or failed so it's like
okay what can I start off with well get
a good basic all-purpose 444 see how
your plants and your soils respond and
if you're kind of missing something pick
it up you know but
starting all these methods and okay I'm
going to do fermenting in this and then
you just next thing you know you have a
petri dish of and it's hard to go back
once you do so don't compare your garden
to others love what you can love what
you have created and provided within
your means all good things come with
time I do this all the time as an artist
as a gardener I'm looking at other
people's paintings and I'm like oh God
but then I think to myself I'm not
trying to paint that realism I'm trying
to paint what I'm painting and it goes
with the same thing you'll see some
beautiful gardens and people that want
to pick every weed out I'm not that
person I want those weeds in the ground
in the soil so I have an advantage of I
don't weed in my garden learn together
grow together guys if we all learn
different we all learn differently and
we all have our own unique personalities
and we we need to bring this out let
your kids explore and find what sparks
their interest I like to say as adults
our attention spans get better but as a
third 37 year old father it's definitely
not better and it goes the same with
your kids if you had this plan and
planting and doing all this stuff and
they look up and there's a butterfly
flying away and they're wandering off
support it let them don't make it feel
like it's a demand where they have to do
it as a chore and they're in there it's
2023 we you know we don't have food
rations we don't have we don't have that
economical demand where they don't need
that pressure they're so young keep it
fascinating and engaging for them
connect with neighbors and people from
your community you'll be surprised in
how many gardeners are out there and you
just might not have connected with them
there's plenty of social groups that are
geared towards your values and interests
and that's important to find those not
every group is going to suit your needs
or their personalities and and I'm a
part of some like jadam ones just to see
like what they do and they are talking
advanced stuff and you know and I'm just
like wow it doesn't suit my needs you
know
learn to network whether it's a farmer's
market on the side of the road stands
connecting with new people will help
expand your knowledge in your local
produce and local knowledge for me is
really really important like you can go
to your big box stores and buy their
vegetables and a lot of times they might
they have things that are not going to
grow good they just grow stuff and they
send it to these stores like my Home
Depot had lemon trees
like okay if I plant it indoors maybe
but I can't have a lemon tree if you go
to your local nursery and if they're
starting their their vegetables from
seed you can bet they're picking the
heirlooms and the products that are grow
to grow best in your region and don't be
surprised if they're things you've never
heard of where it's not a bigger boy or
bad or boy or you know there's varieties
of tomatoes but they have something
that's more conducive for your your Zone
and your region and you'll it just gives
you more success you know you want to
plant this fancy tomato but it might not
work you know
there's so many hybrids it's crazy this
slide is companion planting and it kind
of goes into what are you planning how
are you feeding that whole cycle we
talked about in companion planting is
when two plants are grown near each
other for the benefit of those plants or
both so that the benefits can be one way
or mutual and this goes it's not just it
could be flowers and a great example of
this is I grew up with put marigolds
around everything if you've looked at
pitches of old Gardens there's marigolds
around tomato plants to to this day I
have tons of marigolds and and there was
as used as a bug deterrent and as a
pollinator so a flower can be a
companion plant because it's bringing in
the pollination bugs the Flies the bees
to hopefully give you that crop
and on screen there's also a smaller
picture of What's called the three
sisters and me and my kids are going to
try this technique this is our one new
thing we're trying this year and it's
basically where you're going to plant um
a corn corn in the center you're gonna
plant squash around that corn and then
you're going to put you're also going to
grow beans around that the beans are
going to use the corn as a trellis the
squash is going to keep the weeds at Bay
the beans are going to bring nitrogen in
for the for the corn and through this
symbiotic relationships we we get the
benefits of the nitrogen being added by
a plant the the cover crop by the squash
and if you look at the pitcher there's
there's varying depths of roots and this
is another big great thing is the
variety gives you the root depths which
are going to access various parts of
your soil and depending where you're at
this could be really important for not
having to use so much fertilizer because
of the access of those roots exudates
and what they're bringing up towards
your plants I illustration there and the
way you broke that down pretty easy to
to grasp onto yeah it's really it's
really easy and and you know it the
chart breaks it down basically and shows
you variations if you plant corn then
you know you can do green beans and
cucumbers and peas and and once and once
again don't feel you need to but these
are things you can connect with and and
just further your knowledge
um and the last slide is just a little
thing that I say it's my quote it's no
Garden it's too big nor too small no man
stands alone under the grace and the
Open Arms of Mother Nature may she
forgive guide bless and lead us to the
steward the land for all and I really
believe that I love connecting with new
people I love sharing my techniques and
and helping them start their Gardens and
it's it's really big in my life and and
I think together in the communities you
know this is the way we're going you
know where we're more self-aware of
what's on the shelves and what we do
want as consumers and it starts with us
it starts in your backyard starts in a
pot on your patio and and from there
it's just years of growth and and
amazing food amazing food that's awesome
I see this last slide here with the
minerals crystals and fossils what's
this all about so if you guys want to
follow me this is my business
um I own unearthedrocksandgems.com this
is where I sell fossils Rocks Crystals
so if there's anything you guys are
interested in make sure to hit me up you
can hit me up on on um Instagram
davemon31 or over on Facebook at unearth
rocks and gems I'm always uploading new
stuff recently doing trying some merch
stuff but if you're into rock collecting
crystals fossils definitely hit me up
um I'll I'll take care of you for sure
and at the end of the presentation if
you guys do decide to print it out
there's a hundred word glossary with fun
facts and variations of things just to
read and some are kind of goofy and some
are factual and they'll have things like
different types of hormone plant
hormones and at the same time have boof
in there you know so make sure you check
it out and in the link and um yeah sweet
I do have a few questions for you in
regards to Family Guy gardening and I
know I didn't send these to you in
advance so some of them are off the cusp
here but uh so introducing kids to
gardening you know what age kind of do
you recommend to get them involved and
when you're getting them involved what
kind of tasks can they help out with to
begin
amazing question amazing question
as soon as their diaper can put their
butt in the soil you know and you know
from they don't even have to be crawling
yet you know
um simple things like plastic shovels
plastic rakes you know you got to use
your your senses and what's going to
keep the child safe you can't go wander
off and leave them there
um but just letting them interact touch
the soil throw it in the air ah get it
on them seeing the bugs just the visuals
Alone
um will will keep them occupied
um and then as they get older you can
start introducing responsibilities you
know like hey can you dig the hole and
then they dig in and it's like ah it's
not deep enough like and you pull out
the plant look what we got to put it in
and they look like oh yeah okay and then
they they'll dig a little bit more
um
but yeah just to keep it simple
um for my family I was very fortunate
um my all my babies we had we made all
our own baby food so blending it and
then freezing it in ice cube trays it's
a perf like when your babies start
eating solids it's a perfect one serving
and then as they get a little older you
can give them two servings and so you
harvest your carrots you blend them up
make a puree freeze them bag them and
your babies will never have to have
Jarred food
and and so when do they start if you
want them not to be picky when they can
first start eating solids introduce it
and then when you're outside be really
like expressive like whoa look what we
grew like oh it's so good because if you
just give them that broccoli they're
gonna be like oh but if you're like oh
my gosh we grew this holy cow try this
and then like yeah Dad's right so
keeping yourself positively interactive
is what you can do nice nice and then do
you have like a top three or maybe top
five plants that you feel like is good
for family gardening
my top would have to be definitely
Tomatoes
um just because you can make sauces you
can add them into salads I mean just
Endless Possibilities with tomatoes
um cucumbers are definitely
um and I would see what would be the
last one onions for sure onions are a
key for me I cook with onions every day
so I need onions and they store very
very very well one last question from me
how do you balance like the time in the
garden versus family time like how often
are you actually going out to your
garden with your family and doing tasks
and then making sure there's a good
balance making sure they're not out
there too much to where they're like
kind of getting sick of it you know yeah
no so
what would be that balance the balance
is is is basically
as as much as you can is it that you're
willing to do and what you're what
you're trying to accomplish right if you
start feeling burnt out you're doing too
much and it's not going to be conducive
for you and your family
um knowing your crops not biting off too
much you know it's amazing to think
about a garden with tomatoes and
eggplants and cucumbers and onions and
all this but if you have yet to
understand how it grows your your time
management is not going to be easy but
if you focus on a few things that you
could be good at as that Garden grows
and especially if you're here in Central
Illinois in the central United States up
in Illinois
once the plants are certain size they're
naturally shading and weeding themselves
and the amount of rain and stuff we get
here it's very self-sufficient so you
kind of have to plug in your location
and and everything else too you know
it's not easy there's no good answer you
can't platform it it's stressful at
times you miss stuff and
you just gotta figure it out I guess huh
yeah you figure it out yeah exactly so
you have any final tips any final advice
that you want to give people here before
we wrap things up just keep it fun keep
it fun and don't let other people stress
you out and and you'll be just fine
um be open to share your knowledge with
neighbors and friends and people because
the more we learn that we're just we're
going to benefit from it and a garden
will really help you connect in ways
that is just unexplainable with the food
and and how you feel and the Domino
effects that your kids will have
connecting with their food especially
with the issues with
Could children diabetes and stuff like
this it's very
to the point to where if you can have
your child connect early on in that age
it's it's going to be good well said all
right so tell those listeners how they
can find you and is there anything else
coming in the future that you want to
talk about
yeah you can um check you can follow me
over on Facebook at
unearthrocksandgems.com uh or at
Unearthed rocks and gems or my website
at unearth boxinggems.com Instagram
davemon31 in terms of future projects
um getting the garden going getting
ready for that
um potentially doing some filming
um and other varieties but nothing too
defined just yet sweet well definitely
have a link to your social media down in
the YouTube description section below
and if you're on one of the podcast
platforms just search for them you'll
find them if you enjoyed this episode
click that Thumbs Up Button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend I'm leasing
a new Garden Talk podcast episode I'd
love for you to tune in to future
episodes all right Dave once again thank
you so much for coming on really
appreciate it and hope you enjoy the
rest of your day thank you you too thank
you peace out everyone catch you in the
next episode