coming up on garden talk thing you want
to do as new growers you want to
eliminate as many
places that you can go wrong as possible
you know take those variables out don't
work hard to throw things in that can go
wrong
we just think more is better you know
more light
you know more nutrients more water
that's going to give me more plant
and until you realize that's really not
the truth just took it and split it
right down the middle
and we duct taped it all up put a
tobacco cage around it and that plant
was the biggest yielding plant that we
ever had whatever it was it just kicked
it into like
some kind of super mode don't chase us a
vpd number a ph number your plants will
tell you what you need to do more is not
better
you know sometimes the more you do the
less you get
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 81 in this
episode i interview cronix grow he has
been gardening for 15 months and has
experience growing in soil as well as
deep water culture he likes to keep it
simple and he talks about what he does
at his garden in order to be successful
this episode includes a lot of good
advice for beginner gardeners thanks to
all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr gohett before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
thanks to vivosun for sponsoring this
episode vivosun has been one of the top
manufacturers of horticulture equipment
for over 10 years as some of you have
seen in my grow videos i have grown
successfully using their grow tents
their inline fans led grow lights hid
grow lights and numerous accessories
vivosun continues to create really
interesting technology that makes home
gardening easier check out their website
at vivosun.com
i will provide a link in the youtube
description section below
ac infiniti is sponsoring this episode
their clip-on oscillating fan is now
released i've been using their six-inch
version for over six months now and i
absolutely love it it's easy to clip on
the side of my grow tent and it has 10
different speeds which makes it easy to
control air circulation they do also
have non-oscillating versions of these
clip-on fans these fans are currently in
high demand when they sell out of the
fans which i expect them to often you
can pre-order them for the next release
you can also use discount code mr grow
it if you're buying off their website ec
infiniti.com that discount code works
for all ac infinity items or discount
code mr grow at 15 if you're buying off
amazon
thanks to ventana plant science for
sponsoring this episode i started using
the bottle flavor in my garden flavor
can be added to any nutrient lineup
studies have shown an increased yield of
and also increased terpenes from 1.1 to
2.4 percent flavor is an all-natural
polymer that holds nutrients in solution
it also prevents precipitants of
nutrients and increases nutrient uptake
flava is available on
growershouse.com i'll provide a link in
the description section below and you
could use coupon code the stash for a
discount
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
chronix crow how are you doing today
i'm doing great doing great thanks for
having me on chris
uh thanks for coming on
today we're gonna go through a ton of
tips for beginner gardeners so there are
so many people out there who are
starting their first garden especially
as legalization sweeps across the world
here so in this episode i want to go
back to the basics i'm not trying to
scare off any intermediate or advanced
growers because i'm sure there's gonna
be some takeaways for you even if it's
just a reminder to to keep it simple but
first let's do an introduction can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening well um i i
mean i look at but i'm 55 years old i
have three grandchildren
i rescue animals i
i got a couple parrots some cats and a
dog
um my first introduction to growing
medicinal plants came when i started
helping neighbor with an outdoor
grow
i was pretty much just a helper you know
and especially at the end when you had
to do all the trimming uh but then i met
a girl and we bought a house and we
moved away and it's a
upscale neighborhood you can't really be
doing that out in the backyard you know
where i live now and plus there's a lot
you know it's a big open area there's a
lot of traffic and
it's you know it wasn't possible plus we
you know we just bought a house we
didn't want to take any chances and then
all of a sudden legalization just
ma'am it was here
um i had a long talk with the girlfriend
to try to get her out i just said it'll
just be a small little thing and
don't worry about it it'll be okay and
uh you know i went on youtube started
watching all the videos and uh
15 months later here i am um i've had
three
[Music]
well i'd call the first one successful
because i finished but i've had three
grows in
in 15 months and i'm about to finish my
fourth
um so you know i'm getting the perpetual
but my perpetual is just about set up so
i'm in a really good spot and
that's about it
sweet and now you have a youtube channel
as well right yes yes i uh i took the
leap um i mainly did it in the beginning
just to kind of record my progress you
know it's good to look back and see you
know where you where you started at and
just have a little fun you know see what
could happen
and then i i was lucky i
the folks from i hooked up with the
folks from mile gm
and they you know they took an interest
in my channel they helped me get over
that you know a thousand sub hump
you know with a couple you know
giveaways and things and
you know and that led to spider farmer
so i you know they've been really good
to me and that you know that having a
channel really helps in that way
um you know you're you're kind of doing
a favor for a company by you know
showing your product and in return
you're getting product you know so
that's a good as long as you find decent
you know
companies to work for in your
you know it's it works out good
yeah absolutely and as always i'll
definitely have a link to chronic crow's
channel down in the youtube description
section below and if you're on one of
the podcast platforms just search for it
you'll find them so what's your overall
style of gardening i mean are you
indoors mostly do due to any outdoors
organic synthetic what's your style
um i'm indoor and soil um i use
synthetic nutrients i i did try the fox
farm dirty dozen
grill ago
it's a little more i guess it's a little
more organic but it was just so many
bottles and
it was really hard for me to really
understand when i was
i was feeding
at times and uh so i went you know kind
of went back on on that went back to the
general hydroponics that he started with
it's just so much easier you know what's
going in there it's it's simple
it's really hard to turn to hard to mess
it up
um yeah and then are you mostly doing
are you doing autoflowers or photo
periods or what
no no i did when i my uh i'll tell you
the
how
i learned to keep it simple it was my
first grow you know i went on youtube
i'm watching all these videos and you
know some of the choices i made i i
started off with dwc
i had autoflowers and photo periods in
the same time
and i had hps lighting in a top over
over the over the buckets so as you can
imagine it was a struggle i was like oh
my my water's getting too hot and i had
to do you know i had to wrap the buckets
and
and and covering so you know keep the
temperature down and
um
i was you had to monitor the ph all the
time
and then the plants they grew so fast
that at the end i ended up having to
switch my hood because they just grew
right up into the hood to the top of the
four by four time even though i had to
put it all the way as high as we go it
was just hanging by the little clips
um i finished you know it you know i got
quite a lot of
a lot of product out of it but you know
the the
the light only penetrates so far so
anything below that you know it's it's
pretty much
you know you know edible quality
stuff there's really you know it's just
larvae
i i just expected it to be better having
seen what it looks like outdoors it just
that it just
you know i i knew i bit off more than i
can chew
so like okay i gotta get back to the
basics you know i gotta figure out what
i want you know i wanted perpetual right
from the beginning i knew that you know
i started small one tap but my goal was
okay if this works out
then i'm gonna go and get another tap
for veg and i'm gonna you know try to
keep this at least get a two light
rotation going
and uh
then uh
you know i i started learning you know
about
over watering um too much light to too
many nutrients
and uh once i
i
learned that i didn't really have to
have to do that much with soil soil
seemed like the way to go
you know i i was just so the the very
first one with the dwc just took up so
much of my time
you know i was down there you have to
check you know that ph is so important
when you're in those that kind of system
on soil it's not so important and you've
got a you got a lot wider range you know
that you can play with uh
and uh
now you know it's expanded and you know
i got a three light rotation going
so it's every eight or ten weeks i'm
harvesting the time
yeah the dwc i mean you mentioned though
the water temperature being high and
that because that's a concern for me
because i live in the desert and it's
like i think it's 113 degrees out today
outside and like inside here my ac is on
the entire time and it's just under
it's like 79 degrees fahrenheit right
now and the water temperature if i were
to run a dwc system i'd be struggling
just like just like you mentioned
because you need to keep the temps at a
certain degrees it's gonna need to be
below a certain degrees or else you can
come across problems so
yeah i can imagine uh why why you're
going towards the soil and how it's more
a little bit more forgiving than a dwc
system now are you still with hps you
mentioned you had that or did you switch
over to led like what are you using for
lighting right now well right now i'm in
flower i'm flowering with the spider
farmer sf4000
in the 4x4
i had
this would be my second flower with the
led
um
i mean the hps was doing just great i
could have continued with that and i may
if if i struggle again i i had a little
bit of an issue with temperature in the
in the
winter
you know i am from uh the northeast so
even though i get heat it i i get heat
and ac from the house it's still always
a little bit
a little bit off than what it actually
is in the house so i you know now i've
added a little bit of i just have a
little oil
heater in there
you know i set that to like 72 and then
it never it really gets below that down
there
um so i'm you know i'm real lucky with
that
but i you know a lot of people would say
i grow pretty pretty
cool you know i i
never get above 80 degrees on the time
you know that's pretty rare that's
that's a real hot day
that must be nice
for me it's a struggle i'm always
running an ac in order to try to keep
things cool but you know when it comes
to lighting i want to dig a little bit
deeper into that because this there's so
much
when it comes to lighting i mean it's so
easy to look at lighting you know if
you're shopping for lighting seeing all
these different technical specifications
and get overwhelmed right so do you have
any general advice for like beginners
maybe that they're shopping for a light
or even using light tips for using
lights well light light's important you
know if you're going to veg lights a
little less you know the kind of light
you veg with is a little less important
than the kind of light you flower with i
mean your your yield is your yield is
based on your light your wattage of your
you know the amount of power that your
light is putting out
um
and you know your quality is is really
the grower talent you know the
healthiness of your plant when you when
you flower it
uh
all the different lights worked um
you know i've seen people
grow under cfls uh you know t flower
under t5s
you can flower under
any of the systems work it really
um it's what you can really if it's what
you can afford and you know that there's
nothing wrong with starting small and
then you know as you
you know it's kind of what i did i just
started i started smalling the hps an hp
system 600 watt hps systems it's nothing
you know with a dimmable ballast
and you get two bulbs the ballast uh
a hood
you know and it's it's pretty cheap and
you know you have the wattage you know
the 600 watts and the 4x4 is kind of
really what you
what you want
you know to really to flower out a plant
and you know and get some yield
um ice i use t5s
in veg i just like the way and i try to
do a little led and veg and
you know
i just i like the way the the t5s work
i mean i i start with very little light
i sprout with a
two foot
um t5 and i just put it right on top of
the dome
you know that's good for two three weeks
you know that will sprout 50 seedlings i
mean if you you could fill all those
plugs and sprout with that one light and
the light will take care of them for two
weeks
um then you know obviously you've gotta
you pull them out and put them in party
cups they're a little more spaced apart
you need a little bit more
i have a tube well
t5 you know i have one of those little
divided up tents you know it's got the
little shelf
i got so i have my little steeling drum
up top down below i've got a little two
two bulb one and if i'm only sprouting a
few
you know i can put them under that and
then i have a four bulb one that fills
up kind of like the three by three space
and then when they get a little bigger
in the solo cup so i can keep them all
in there you know it's all on that 24
hour light cycle
so you know
that all works out great
then i move them
to uh two by four that's got four um
four foot t5 bulbs in it
and that's where i grow them you know i
try to fill that two by four out get a
full canopy in that
once that two by four is full it halfway
fills my four by four
and then when i flip the flower the
stretch you know they'll grow they'll
grow twice as big
and then mine i've got a full canopy
and it really kind of you know i i
i i really try to um stuff the lighting
up it's a very slow incremental process
um you know when they're when they're
little and they're young
they want they don't need a lot of light
and and they just need a little bit of
light in that little bit of light as
well if you're trying to grow roots you
know you're not trying to grow
vegetation you know in that early
seedling stage you're trying to get the
roots to grow and that just a little bit
of light is is all they need
and it's cheap and it saves you a lot of
money too you know you're not you're not
blasting it with a you know more light
than it needs um they respond a lot
better
uh i just you know i i
you know i strongly believe that you
know light is like kind of like shifting
gears in the car you know it's got to be
you kind of work and if you hit it at
the end where oh you know that last
couple weeks you're at 100 percent in
your flower top you know you know you
did it right
and you're getting the mac and then your
your plants are getting the maximum
amount of watts the maximum amount of
light at the end when they really need
it when they're
when they're you know they're finishing
off
and and can use that gas
yeah and i just want to repeat what you
had said towards the beginning there is
the the light that you could use a lot
of people get caught up to like oh you
need 3 000 k for flower and 4 000 k for
vegetation stage and that's just not
entirely true you can literally grow the
plant
from seed to harvest with the same
spectrum so i think a lot of people
there unfortunately are beginners out
there they're spending money on two
different grow lights in order to have
them for the different stages and it's a
little bit of an overkill they're just
they're just unknowingly going on
spending money when they don't really
need to so i'm glad you actually
mentioned that part because uh yeah
that's a common misconception sure about
lighting absolutely
right
yeah you know spectrum is really little
to do with it i mean and if
is
so small i don't think it's really that
noticeable i know people usually you
know can the light companies will argue
differently that you know but it's kind
of like they're kind of like the
nutrient companies you know they say
well my light gives you 20 more you use
mine you know it's the it's the same
sales technique tons of marketing
getting shoved down your throat yep it's
it's
every light company has the best light
when you talk to him so
it's it's crazy
you mentioned too much light being an
issue for a lot of new growers can you
get deeper into that like how do new
growers
know when they're giving too much light
and how do they like
i guess adjust their light to fix the
issue you'll find that as we go through
this thing that the too much thing will
pop up pop up a lot
um i think it's a guy thing you know
that's probably why girls grow better
than we do you know we just think more
is better you know more light
you know more nutrients more water
that's going to give me more plant
and um
until you realize that's really not the
truth and you know you
you step away from some of that and you
give it really what it needs and you
know nothing nothing more
then you know with light
they respond better it's it's
you know you use you can stunt them
real easy with too much light and it
causes you know you you just burn them
up
and you know i've seen people with you
know they end up with a beautiful canopy
full of buds but it's right up in the
light you know and it's just getting
they're just getting cooked by you know
just too much light because it got too
close i mean there needs to be
um like with my led my my spider farm i
put all the way to the top of the top
like that's where i start
even though my canopy is so low down
there i just use the knob
to to you know dial it up you know i
give them a little bit of adjustment
phase and i kind of okay maybe that's a
little much or back it off a little bit
and then from then it's just like every
week when i water i might turn it up a
little bit and
kind of ease it up that way and it
you know it works out fine
when i first grow you know somebody had
i was online it's like no you need to be
hitting your plant with
that's a full 600 watts right now what
are you doing you know and i'm like oh
crap you know i better get down there
and turn that bail stuff you know and
then you know i'm blasting it with 600
watts you know when they they still
should have been way down you know and i
had nowhere to go there was no
you know i was totally out of gas out of
room
to to to bring it up anymore or ease it
up
i have a buddy who he has four solo cups
he's got four seedlings going in a four
by four tent
he's got two spider farmer sf 2000s
both of them going at the same time and
unless like like i told them before too
as lasker i told him like dude you could
like just use one of those lights and
like lower it and dim it down and he's
not doing that he's just yeah all the
way to the top at like five percent
would be plenty yeah yeah it's just it's
tough you know especially the seedlings
you know i've i've
i've i've had a
um
pop quite a few means you know i i'm
pretty picky with seedlings you know
pretty early on you know for plants
you know it's it's genetics it's or what
you're looking for you know i'm looking
for
you know branches because that's where
the buds grow you know
branches and nodes if if they're getting
stretchy and i'm not seeing that no
development or they're falling behind
the other seedlings it's
literally off the cliff i have one in my
backyard with a cook
and they
they take the little ride down to the
river
you mentioned you're in soil
and you mentioned you started with fox
farm nutrients then you moved over to
general hydroponics let's get deeper
into nutrients because that's another
area where folks get caught up a lot
especially the new beginners right talk
to us about you know how do you go about
feeding and what tips do you have for
beginners in regards to feeding well um
current like i said i use a three part i
have r or water so i have to use calmac
a little bit more than you normally see
in the feed schedule
i use rapid start
in the beginning and during veg
floralicious plus and liquid cool bloom
and uh of course great white
um and that's kind of the stuff i use in
veg and flower
seedlings and baby plants i use you know
clonex solution you know the first four
weeks of their life they're getting
clonex solution and and great white
every other week
um
the i'm pretty new to mother plants but
i i i decided to stick with the same
um clonex clonex brand and i'm using the
mother plant a and b for
the mother plant going forward and i
ended up with a
really really nice
granddaddy purple
that i'm gonna be using the clone with
and i'm going to use uh orca ponex
solution and
in the cloner
um
again i i one thing i have today you
know this might
make people's jaws drop a little bit
but as far as npk goes i only feed once
in veg and
at the most twice in flower
um
that's because i keep my you know
i don't want my plants get bigger than
the container that they're in um i try
to you know oh
and you kind of get a feel for how long
the soil's got a couple weeks
um or how long it's you need to feed it
and if you're if they're growing along
in a good place and you're transplanting
it with right stages you don't really
need there's a lot in the soil um
i'm not saying that you know i do give
them like the supplements and the
additives
you know as i water them
but i mean as far as really feeding them
unless i'm seeing some kind of
deficiency
you know nitrogen you know or something
like that i'm you know i don't you know
they look a little yellow or something
like that okay i might need to feed them
a little bit but i just don't i and i
see people that
they water every day they get nutrients
every day
they're just you know i'm hitting it
hard with the newts and you know and i'm
just like oh yeah like what you know
because that just builds up all that
salt and that soil and it's just got
nowhere to go and it's that you
especially you know with the over
watering because because
over watering you brought the root hairs
and um
that's then they can't take up nutrients
um you know they there's individual
hairs that pick up certain
new parts and
particulates you know when you you burn
them up with nutrients or you and you
over water them and they can't take it
all they can take up is water
and i and like you said i have a buddy
that um
every time he gets the fires um
four weeks into flowering my i come home
my plants just fell over
i don't know what happened
and it was you know he over watered them
when he vegeta they couldn't take up the
nitrogen they needed in veg because they
don't take it up and flower
and then they run out and they just go
and they just fall over that's the you
know that's usually the answer you know
the answer to that
and
you know the overwatering thing i mean i
really can't stress enough about because
i think that's probably the number one
problem
that new growers do they think that soil
has to be wet all the time and this this
plant is just not like that
at all
how do you go about watering in order to
ensure that there's over watering
doesn't happen
well i always water when i water my
water to run off i make sure that the
pot is completely saturated i've got
water coming out um
i'm careful that i'm not you know trying
to do it too fast where i'm getting the
runoff off the sides you know i you got
to get a field and then i get to feel
the pot i know how much it is when it's
heavy and then i don't water it again
until i can just pick it up with my
finger it's it's like super light you
know i just wait until it's it's dried
dried out or i see some kind of if it
looks like it's
you know wilting a little bit you know
these are kind of bend down a little bit
i try i don't like it you know under
watering is bad too
but it's not as bad as over
um
you can if you start seeing wilting you
know okay if you write everything down
which i also recommend if you've got a
garden you should be if you're watering
feeding you should be at least
writing that down water feed or
something you know at the very bare
minimum so that you could go okay i
watered five days ago wilted today
next time i water i'm gonna do it a day
earlier
you know and uh my
like my uh the flower plant i have is in
a seven gallon pot
and for the first four weeks i only
watered it um once a week
it just now
you know in week five
i'm starting to water it almost twice a
week it's just starting to take up a lot
more water and
you know it's starting to bulk up so
it's it's drinking
and taking up nutrients
yeah i do a very similar method where i
let it dry out between waterings when
i'm growing with synthetic nutrients in
particular dry backs like that drought
stress a lot of people say that that
helps with the secondary metabolites you
know those trichome production so it's a
form of stress precision stress that's
bringing out what we want in the plants
so uh yeah i thought that was worth
mentioning there now are you aiming for
a specific ec or ppm during the
different stages of growth or what
um well i kind of i kind of look at ppm
like food calories um
you got a young plant um you give it the
kids meal you know the lower calorie
diet um you got a big plant it's you
know it might need the super-sized fries
and to go along with it it's kind of
based on the size
um the type of plant you know some grow
slower than others a slower growing
plant
doesn't need as much as a you know
faster growing one it's not it's not
like the it's kind of like the couch
potato versus the athlete you know the
ones that are
like certain
certain cultivars grow really really
fast
yeah there's a relationship between heat
nutrients in the mild water the plant
drinks
so if it's you've got hot temperatures
and the plants drinking twice as much
water you also got to remember it's
taking up twice as many nutrients as
well
so you know if you're if you're if
you're putting a lot of nutrients in
there and your your tent's running at a
very high temperature you know
you run the risk of
you know
burning your plants up
and you know i i want to say all the
the thing you want to do as a new
growers you want to eliminate as many
places that you can go wrong as possible
you know take those variables out
you know don't don't work hard to throw
things in that can go wrong
um just just because you know you you've
seen it on youtube or you know you read
it on the internet or
you know
some you know so your body told you this
is this is what you do
gotcha
i also want to get into ph you talked
about how ph was super important when it
comes to dwc hydroponics and soil a lot
of people argue that it's not as
important
what's your take on ph specifically when
growing in soil talk to us about do you
monitor ph if so what do you aim for so
on and so forth well i i aim between
five and seven if i'm mixing my
nutrients and they're out of that range
which you know some sometimes i have you
know i'll get i use a lot more ph up for
some reason probably because of the
arrow water than i do down
but you know i bring it back and i'll
add a little bit to it and if it gets
five point something
or six point something i don't care i'm
not adding more to it i'm not trying to
dial in that number
um because that is that
you don't realize how big of a range
that really is because it's not really a
linear scale
ph
like uh the difference between um
uh 6.9 ph and seven is is it's actually
ten times difference
so if you multiply that over the whole
range between five and seven i mean
that's such a wide range that why would
how could there be one
specific number that is absolutely
perfect you know for
every situation i mean really it's about
um
you know i know people argue that
there's a certain ph it makes nutrients
more available to the plant but that 507
range covers it
it really does you know there's not
going to be
any any
kind of thing going on there unless
there's an issue with over watering and
you've brought the repairs and they
can't absorb the nutrients okay let's
move on to environment a little bit
temperature humidity a lot of people aim
for certain ranges for those things
let's start with temperature what do you
usually aim for well i my lung room it
will basically vary anywhere between 65
and 75 degrees you know depending on
what kind of season it is um
and i try to keep temperature i i
basically try to keep the long room
comfortable for me because i know if
it's comfortable for me it's comfortable
for the plants
obviously the lights you know add heat
or whatever
um
but i've i've had no you know when i've
had no issues you know i've had 10 15
temperature swings at night
absolutely no
no real issues
um
the only time temperature really
might be an issue for me is when i got
seedlings or something like that you
know i might use a little heat mat just
to you know kind of a little bit more
radiant heat
um
but i don't really i mean i mantra i
like to know what it is it tells me if
something's wrong if i do you know if i
if i see that my humidity all of a
sudden is is seventy percent
i must have forgot to empty the
dehumidifier or you know it's it's more
of a i'm looking for the extremes
more than a precise
area kind of just like i treat it just
like the ph as if i'm in that that happy
zone somewhere
um i'm not gonna spend a whole lot of
effort to chase a number or get a like
vpd
um
you know i don't really worry about that
that doesn't
you know there's
there's no
vpd in mother nature
i wouldn't say you know the
it's it just it's just not for the
amount of effort that it would take to
try to maintain
um that environment
i just don't see the the need to chase
something like that especially if you're
starting out maybe if you're in a
facility and you're you're trying to
dial you know i mean you're i don't know
even then i wouldn't
you know i wouldn't see the value
there's no value added in it for me and
my girl
let's put it that way i'm not saying
there's something wrong with it or
whatever but it's just not something
that you know that i focus on
a lot of people are actually within the
vpd range without even trying you know
they'll look at the chart and they're
like oh i'm there already and they're
not even like no effort my ac infinity
my ac infinity controllers will it gives
me a vpd reading i know it's a little
off because i don't i don't enter the
leaf temperature or anything but it's
always one two one three you know it's
always right around there
you know it's not that far off
you know depending on what chart you're
looking at too and there's all these
different charts too you know it's like
which chart is the real chart
you know it's it's uh
why check why spend the time
now you're absolutely right there's ours
there are several charts out there and
it makes things confusing because you
look at one chart and you think you're
in the right range you look at another
chart and you're out of range
but yeah there's that that dark green
range which is said to be the most
optimal range then there's the light
green range and then there's the the
yellow range i think is the the
tolerance range and then you've got the
red range right so like there's a really
really wide range that the plant will
grow in so if you're a beginner yeah
chasing after vpd
you probably don't want to do that for
your first several grows well that was
something i picked up growing outdoors
too because i mean the northeast is is
just
it could
you can get all four seasons in like one
day here
and uh i
the first year i'm like are you worried
it's just like it hasn't rained in like
three days you know he's like oh i gave
it water a couple days ago it'll be fine
you know and then
i'm like oh my gosh that did you see
that wind last night you know this blew
the thing it'll be fine don't worry
about it you know and then towards the
end you know that towards the end it's
dropping down to like 45 at night and
i'm like don't isn't it getting too cold
at night no it'll be fine don't worry
about it you know the plant it does
great it i never you know i seen wild
swings and outdoor temperature hail
you know you name it it's it'll throw it
at that plant and it it does great
sometimes it helps you know the plant
like you said the stress
um the stress i remember one plant we
put outside in the wood chuck split
right down and just took it and split it
right down the middle
and we duct taped it all up put a
tobacco extract a tomato cage around it
and that plant was the biggest yielding
plant that we we ever had it just that's
whatever it was it just kicked it into
like some kind of super mode
that's wild so maybe the stock splitting
technique isn't actually bro science
you know if you shake if you shake your
plants up you you inadvertently are
going to split spot and it's it's
you know you remember the first time
that you ever topped your plant and
you're holding the clippers there and
your hands are shaking and it's like oh
my god what am i about to do here and
you cut that off and you know the first
time you're trying to bend the branch
and you just split it or you break it
and you're like oh crap
you know but it's just it's duct tape
fixes fixes quite a bit and they you
know if
it does you know when it does heal it's
a big knuckle it's a you know it's a
the plant responds pretty good to it you
can't be afraid to
manhandle them a little bit i think they
like it when you when you
bend them and break them they are
resilient plants and most of the time
they will recover fully one more thing i
want to touch upon you touched upon it
first when we talked about temperature
and i just want to circle back to it and
then we'll move on which is you talked
about the lung room temperature and i'm
really really glad you brought that up
because
that's an important piece that a lot of
people
don't bring up they just talk about the
temperature in their grow environment in
their their grow tent for example but
the lung room for those that don't know
is the room that your grow tent is in
for example so a lot of people will
condition that room with the proper
temperature and humidity uh and you said
it's between 65 and 75 degrees
fahrenheit which is usually slightly
lower than what people typically run
into grow tents you know 75
upwards of 80 sometimes up to 85 degrees
fahrenheit but it's important because
when you're bringing air into the grow
environment
if you're aiming for 80 degrees
fahrenheit temperature for example and
that's what's in your grow tent and
that's what's in your lung room from my
experience i've always run into issues
if my lung room is similar temperature
to what's in my grow tent because
you're just bringing in more heat right
and your growth your grow light is
creating that heat
and you're just
you're just running into heat issues so
i think that's a great tip is to run a
little bit lower of a temp in your lung
room uh and of course having to be the
proper humidity that you're aiming for
have that in your lung room as well so
the air you're bringing into your grow
tent is of the ideal range right and
when you start having to add um heat or
or cooling
you're adding money
to to your grow that's it's you know
once you do that is it is it cost
efficient to grow
you know if you've got to spend a lot of
money and i'm fortunate that i have the
ducting
you know already there you know and i
could add just a little bit of
supplemental heat you know and one of
the times that it needs it you know and
then
i
can put it away it's kind of like the
dehumidifier
the heater and the dehumidifier i have
they're both about what i think the
heater is a little more watts
but i'll use i'll use the heater in the
winter and then i use the dehumidifier
in the summer and it you know i don't
use the two at the same time
um and it just works out it works out
well i'm just fortunate with the the
grow space that i have
that it that maintains such a good
temperature
it can certainly be super expensive when
you have all this equipment heater air
conditioner dehumidifier
all those things add up in your
electricity bill and i know i've had
shock before looking at my electricity
bill i'm like what the heck happened
here specifically when i was running a
portable air conditioner and i got rid
of it because i was just like forget it
it's not worth it it's financially it's
just it's not worth it to run it all the
time and yeah definitely one thing to
evaluate is how much equipment you're
having and the energy consumption even
the dehumidifier you know i have one of
those things that test the lots i had no
no clue that that thing was drawn 600
watts you know that's as much as that's
another light in your
growth space you know and that's you
know my first girl i was running that
thing all the time
you know i'm i'm glad i figured that out
and i don't have to do that anymore yeah
yeah it's definitely good the less
energy consumption the better let's move
on to plant training something that a
lot of new growers do can be very
beneficial for numerous reasons talk to
us about how you do your plan training
well i start right in the solo cups as
soon as i start seeing those nodes
developing on
on the branches on the stems and i've
got a couple nodes there and it looks
like a good good spot to nip it off i'll
i'll nip that top off right there
you know if you call feminine just
taking the one top note then you know
there's a debate on what
what it means but
anyways i'll do that
and then i also
clean up the bottoms anything that's not
going to catch up to the top any lower
branches
i'll cut them off early too you know so
i start
start there um as the plant goes i'm
always trying to open up the plant my
goal is to make the plant low and wide
i don't want um big tall legs
facility legs you know you see those
videos at the facilities and you know
the legs are like six feet long and then
there's like this three foot canopy
but your light only you know led will
penetrate two feet uh 18
hps three feet maybe
so where did all that time go to grow
all you know all those legs all that leg
is kind of wasted time
um especially you know if you're in a
facility and you have 20 foot ceilings
and you can have your lights all the way
up there you know okay
but you gotta if you're growing intent
you can only get so high
you know the taller you know
you know as i learned on my first grow
it's very you know once
a lot of people don't
don't anticipate the stretch
either that's that's the other thing um
they uh
you know topping your plant i think is
the most important thing i see a lot of
new growers where they they grow like
the the spears where there's just one
giant big bud in the center
and then a couple auxiliaries off the
top you know because it you know once if
you don't top that plant that that top
apical
bud
is going to get all the energy all those
other ones they're just getting the
scraps what's left over you know when
when the big bug eats you know they just
get the table scraps where if you top
your plant you widen them out
um that that is the energy is
distributed more evenly
i mean you might not get this
sphere of a bug but you're going to get
the tops which you know we all know
that's the that's the best part
of the bug
um you know i bend them i break them you
know when i'm trying to widen them out
you know if i get i get i can either top
them to just shorten them up to let the
other branches catch up or i can bend
them down and you know i don't tie them
down
i don't think that's a
um
[Music]
effective way to do it it's really hard
believe it or not the plant's pretty
strong
you know you can tie it down and it will
turn a corner and still go straight up
on you
you know
if you if you if you break the herd you
bend the branch
um when you're down you know i you know
i'll go down there and check to see if
the
buckets are light or something and now
well that that one's a little
too tall get a little twist and bend it
down a little bit trying to you know
always building it it's all about the
canopy you can't be canopy canopy all
right from the first time i'm throwing
the solo cups right up to when i put
them in the flour yeah and just to
clarify you can totally just grow the
plant naturally and let that one cola
come up but you are prone to bud rot for
example i
i encountered that before it's just it's
tough getting air through the buds there
and if there's stagnant air at all i
actually had a fan that died and uh it
died overnight and the mold started to
occur got the fan fixed but
i didn't notice it right away so i had
the plants continue to grow for a couple
weeks well that mold just doesn't stop
growing right it can it will continue to
grow even if you've got the airflow at
that point you're screwed but you know
if it's your first grow grow the plant
naturally that's fine but training is
definitely beneficial so yeah just like
you mentioned it yeah you can't be
afraid of it you really can't be i know
i know for some people that you know
these like they see the beautiful
i don't want to cut that off my plant
you know it's such a it's so beautiful
it's growing so good i'm going to chop
its head off what are you kidding me i'm
not gonna do that
um but the benefits you know of training
far outweigh
you know the you know anything you know
as long as you're doing it correctly
you know you're not
you're not doing anything crazy
um shaping up your clients is you know
is super important
i completely agree with that
so we're coming up towards the end of
the episode and i know we can't talk
about every single thing there is to do
about growing here i do want to give you
one last opportunity to give advice for
beginners is there something maybe that
we missed in this episode something you
think that's super important that new
growers need to hear
um okay uh start small keep it simple
you know you i think you want to make
sure growing's for you first um some
people it's it's just not you might have
a really weird environment you know and
just are you know just
some people just it's just not for them
you know and then they end up spending a
lot of money in the beginning and
they're just you know discouraged just
start small
and you know a lot of in
a lot of most first-time growers they
fit they do fail
um don't be afraid to fail
you know and you know embrace it learn
from it you know i
i really took a hard look at my first
grow and i didn't give up and saw my
equipment you know i said what did i do
what could i do better and i still do
after every girl you know what can i
always what can i do better next time
um and also take everything you see on
youtube read on the internet with a
grain of salt
you know kind of do
you know do your own
back research too if you see something
on one site and i don't know about that
you know go look around and and see
and soon you'll find out that there's a
contradiction for just and for
everything
and then
you start to learn that you know i need
to form you need to form your own
opinions
about about things and not rely on
somebody else there's no secret nobody's
got no there's no youtube channel or
where we've got some secret recipe that
okay here's the list of things that you
do and you're gonna get a tent full of
buzz it just doesn't exist
you know i think that we
think
you know people think we're hiding in
some kind of secret you know secret
sauce or there's no secret nutrient
you know no no
no secret light you know there's no
secret technique or
secret method it's you know it's
a lot of different ways work but you
just can't give up you know don't don't
quit if it's something you really want
to do
and leave your plants alone i don't
think i touched on that
earlier too at all
you don't need to be down in your tent
like 17 times a day opening it up
um
then looking
in there they you know you don't need
you just you just leave them you know
you you do your water and you do things
you got to do and you just leave them
alone you know you're opening and
closing the tank you're changing the
environment
every time you go into your grill your
you run the risk you might bring some
kind of pest in there or you know or or
something you might forget to turn the
light off when you leave
you know go down there when you gotta go
down there i you know i go down check it
quit you know i might go down once a day
just to make sure everything's still
running you know
nothing's going on
what helped me because it was hard for
me to let go of it too because you you
know you're so interested and invested
in this that you would just want to be
down there you want to see it you want
to see what's going on you know i bought
some cameras that i can look on my phone
you know so i thought i'm thinking i
don't know what's going on down there so
you know i'm just you know thinking of
my head well maybe i want to go down
there and see what's going on i can just
go in the camera and look in there
there's nothing going on
turn the camera off and you know thought
leaves my head but it's real important
just
the the plant's been growing on its own
for millions of years it really needs
very little from us
you know we just got to really stay out
of its way and you know let it do its
thing
you know like like protect always says
you know
relax
you know breathe it's okay it's you know
it's just it's really just a plant it's
really just a house plant i mean it's
there's when you look at it like that
and it's it
and you treat them like that
you you get a lot more success it's it's
i really believe that
i like the way you go about things
definitely uh you got the right mindset
for sure thank you i do want to add in
one more tip that's just coming to my
mind i'm thinking back to when i was a
beginner
one thing that helped me was
setting up the equipment and before even
putting the plants in the tent
having the light on having your
humidifier on your ventilation all
hooked up
and then monitoring the temperature and
humidity and seeing if it's in the range
seeing if it you know if your your
temperature spiking like crazy so you
can take action before you put plants in
there and then try to balance it now of
course this isn't going to be foolproof
once you have plants in there the plants
transpire they release water vapor into
the air it's going to adjust your
humidity but it can certainly in my
opinion be beneficial to have the
equipment in there
have your light on let it run and then
monitor and try to adjust things from
there so just think i'd throw that one
out there as well yeah there's nothing
wrong with monitoring
you know it's good to know you know i'm
glad i did there was in my first grow
and i noticed quite right away as soon
as the lights went out because my my
ambient room temperature was low
you know once that hps cuts off it cools
off pretty quick that tent cools off
pretty quick and once that tent cools
off the humidity just like
so it totally it told me something it
told me i needed more ventilation in my
town
you know to account for the fact when
the lights go off and that humidity
arises so that i'm not getting you know
raining in the inside
after the lights go out so
yeah but it's it's good to know all
these things but it's like i said don't
don't chase us
a vpd number a ph number
um
you know the par thing it's it's just
just just look at your your plants will
tell you what you need what you need to
do you know don't just don't more is not
better
you know sometimes the more you do the
less you get
absolutely
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future uh well my my
youtube channel is pretty small it's
chronics grow i think you said you put a
link down there um i'm also on instagram
on the same name i'm gonna be trying to
pump up the membership on that um pretty
soon
uh you know i ended up having covered
twice during 15 months so my youtube
channel suffered a little bit
um
and pretty much just making music videos
with
with plants in them
um as i mentioned earlier i'm about to
start cloning so i'm going to do some
videos on that i've got turbo cloner
um i've got a mother plant and you know
document the whole process hopefully
so
and
that big plant i have that maybe single
plant i haven't flower that should be
harvesting
in maybe three more weeks
so
i last last uh
harvest i i was messing around with the
time lapse video so i had a lot of fun
with that you know condensing the whole
chopping process and tr and
bucking the buds onto like a three
minute video and it really took about it
took all these hours
you know just to watch that was pretty
cool and put some you know i do stuff
like that um i think next up i've got
some black widows and i end up with
three black widows and one white widow
out of the last batch of
beans that i i popped so they're looking
dude they're looking really good
so i'm hoping to get that spider farmer
sent me one of their new um eight by
four they started making the bigger
tents now
so i got an i got one of the eight by
fours when they when they first came out
so i'm just waiting to get the right
opportunity
to get that set up and then double my
flower space
so yeah that's
hopefully documented the whole way and
you know
viewers can follow along and watch it
sweet sounds like a lot of exciting
stuff upcoming in the future i'll
definitely have a link to his channel
down in the youtube description section
below if you're listening on one of the
podcast platforms just search for them
you'll find them if you enjoyed this
episode click that thumbs up button
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend i'm
releasing a new garden talk podcast
episode i'd love for you to tune in to
future episodes chronic thanks so much
for coming on this has been uh this has
been cool going back to the basics
talking some beginner tips beginner
friendly information out there so
appreciate your time and uh hope you
enjoy the rest of your day thank you
see you later peace out everyone see in
the next episode