what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr growit and i'm back with another
q a video
this time around i decided to do
beginner questions
last week i did intermediate questions
next week i plan to do advanced
questions well maybe it might not be
next week it might be the week after
that
i still need to gather more advanced
questions for that
so if you actually have any questions
that are more on the advanced side of
things
leave them down in the comments section
below and maybe i will include them in
that video
but yeah a majority of my audience is
beginners and i get a lot of beginner
questions so
i figured i would dedicate this video to
you beginners out there
before we get into the video i just want
to give a quick shout out to our sponsor
for this episode
big thanks to spider farmer for
sponsoring this episode they recently
sent me their new led grow light
the sf7000 this thing looks pretty cool
i'm loving the color they use sealed
diodes
and an inventronix driver it pulls 650
watts from the wall
has an efficiency of 2.9 micromoles per
joule
and covers a 5 foot by 5 foot grow space
a full disclaimer
i haven't used this light this is just
me unboxing it
i'm currently using the sf-2000 and i've
used the sf-4000 in the past
but i do know several people who already
have the sf-7000
up and running in their gardens and
they're impressed with this so far
i will leave a link to the sf 7000 in
the description section below
feel free to click on that link to learn
more about it and i also have a coupon
code for you
use code mr growit5 for discount and
that code works on both amazon
and the spyderfarmer website it actually
works for all spider farmer products all
right
now let's get into the questions hey
chris just wondering is
5.8 ph fine for soil so far it's doing
fine
what's your thoughts plant seems to be
more compact and leaves are smaller than
my last grow
last was on 6.2 ph so 5.8 ph in soil
should be okay
now general range that you hear on a lot
of
websites and forums and everywhere is
going to say
first soil between 6.0 and 7.0
however a lot of these bags of soil
actually come in lower than that
um i personally use a fox farm ocean
forest soil that usually comes in at
like
5.5 5.4 ph and i usually have to water
in
at like 6.5 to 6.8 ph
and then slowly kind of drifts up over
time the plant's able to take it
the plant uptakes nutrients just fine
there there are some growers out there
that
say that the range instead of being 6.0
to 7.0 for soil
that it's actually 5.0 to 7.0 in soil
that's the kind of safe range however
at different ph levels there's going to
be different nutrient uptake
there are charts online that you can
google search as far as
nutrient uptake for plants ph levels
search something like that
and you'll see what i'm talking about
but yeah the plant should be fine at 5.8
ph
you may just want to water in at like
6.5 6.8 ph and then it should drift up
over time
what would happen if you grew a plant on
12 12 light cycle from
seed to harvest so i've done that before
actually i've done the
solo cup challenge i was at four or
five years ago now so basically that
challenge was to plant a seed in a solo
cup
immediately have it on 1212 light cycle
for the entire grill
so what happens is the plant is going to
spend some time in the vegetative stage
no matter what light cycle it's on so
basically for the first 21 days or so
it'll
just veg up then from there you'll start
to see
you know pistols or pollen sacks you'll
start to see signs of sex
it'll start pre-flowering and then
flowering from there
so yeah you can absolutely have it on a
12-12
the entire time if you want it's not
really recommended because the extra
hours if you put on an 18-6
instead you'd have more light it would
contribute to more energy that the
plant's receiving
and therefore more growth in the
vegetation stage so so yeah you can do
it but
you probably get better results if you
would a veg on an 18-6 light cycle
is it okay to add a single nutrient like
calmag if i'm seeing deficiency on a
water day or is it best to wait for a
feeding day
oh yeah you can absolutely feed in cal
mag on a watering day so
common practice which i think is what
he's going by is the water
feed water feed technique when growing
in soil so you'll feed nutrients one
time
once the soil dries out then you'll just
feed plain water
then once the soil dries out you'll go
back to feeding a nutrient solution
and so on and so forth yeah a lot of
growers what they'll do is they'll do
calmag every time even on their watering
days so that's
perfectly fine to do and then there are
some growers that just feed every time
so every time the medium dries out
they'll feed in but they'll feed in at a
lower dosage
so there are several different ways you
can go about it but yeah short answer is
yes you can feed
cal mag on one of your watering days can
i change nutrient companies in flour
i started with advanced nutrients but
now i am going to feed them
ramo nutrients you can but there's
definitely a little bit of risk there
you know ideally you have the proper
ratio of nutrients
throughout the entire life cycle and
these companies they have
those proper ratios on their feeding
schedule it's just a matter of
you know what dosage do you feed the
plants now if you're going from advanced
nutrients
they have their certain formula
switching to a different formula it
could potentially throw off that ratio
so it is kind of risky you know changing
nutrient companies midflower
however you can probably get away with
it a lot of these formulas are pretty
similar
there's just some small differences
there so yeah you could probably get
away with it it's just a little bit of a
risk there i'd love to know in the
comment section if anybody out there
has done it before maybe somebody out
there does do it and it's a common
practice for them to change
nutrient companies at some point in the
grow so comment down below if you do
that
how do you feel about always watering
coco coir with some nutrients or tea
i've read in a lot of different forms
that you should never water cocoa
with plain ph adjusted water until it's
time to flush
in my experience nutrients can
definitely build up in coco coir
you know me growing in particular there
have been times where
nutrients have built up to the point
where i did have to do
a watering in order to allow the plant
to eat up those nutrients that were
built up in the medium and sometimes i
had to do a couple watering days in
order to
reduce that ppm now coir is an inert
medium
that means there are no nutrients in the
medium so a lot of growers will
feed in every single time but again in
my experience
nutrients can build up and adding a
watering day in there once in a while in
order
to reduce the nutrients in the medium is
just fine some would argue that even on
those days we don't feed base nutrients
you should be feeding in calmag calcium
and magnesium are common deficiencies
when growing in coca-cola so
a lot of girls will swear by feeding
calmac every single time
now as far as reading things on forums
just be careful there
especially with older threads every time
i look back at some of the older threads
i'm talking like from 10
years ago 15 years ago sometimes even
like six or seven years ago
there is some inaccurate information in
there so just be careful
always do your due diligence do further
research beyond what you hear in forums
if i'm using ocean forest and happy frog
mix do i still water with nutrients or
plain water
so when you're mixing those two soils
combined both soils do have
nutrients in them to begin so you won't
need to add nutrients right away
now you probably start to need to add
nutrients in 20
30 days of the plant's life depending on
you know how often you transplant if
you're growing for
15 20 days and you transplant to a
larger container well then that fresh
soil has nutrients in it so you don't
need to start feeding nutrients right
away
so general guidance is 20 to 30 days
roughly this one grows start to feed and
nutrients but you can get a more
accurate picture by using a tds
tester and checking the ppm of the
runoff how can i talk with you without
using facebook
how about personal guidance you can come
onto my forum mr growth.com
forum i'm on there almost every day
answering questions sometimes it might
take me two or three
days to get back to you on things a lot
of people posting on there
a pretty big community that we've built
up over there
there's several active members on the
forum that
will go on there and answer questions so
it's not just me
trying to help people out there that's
the best way if you really want
one-on-one
feedback from me really patreon is kind
of my go-to
i usually prioritize patreon responses
as the first
ones that i respond to is patreon
messages then i'll go over to the forum
and then start answering there but yeah
if you try to message me on facebook if
you try to dm me on instagram
if you try to ask questions through
twitter i send everybody over the forum
because
you know quite frankly it's really hard
for me to try to keep up with
all these different platforms so i send
everybody to mr growth.com
forum and ask questions there and that
allows you to add more details you can
add in pictures
video and i can sit down and give more
detailed responses for you
i'm a new grower and i'm using liquid
nutrients for my plants i just wanted to
know if i make a batch of nutrients and
ph the water how long is it good to sit
for you'll probably get a different
answer
from different people that you ask so i
actually asked this question
to rob from blue planet nutrients i
believe he's one of the owners of blue
planet nutrients his answer was no
longer than
two weeks so if i mix up a batch of
nutrients into a bucket for example
i should use that within two weeks now
there are other people out there that
say it's way less than that some people
say no longer than 24 hours
you want to lose that because those
nutrients can fall out of solution
so your best bet probably is just to
reach out to the nutrient manufacturer
and ask them what they think because
their particular nutrients they may have
different guidance for you what are some
tricks that you use to improve
smell and taste of your buds so the
smell and taste
really come down to the terpenes and
flavonoids that are located within the
resin glands or trichomes of the plant
when you walk into your grow room and
you
smell the plant that smell is actually
the terpenes in those resin glands
evaporating different terpenes will
evaporate at different temperatures
but yeah i think it's mostly going to
come down to genetics you know phenotype
genotype i think environment is a factor
drying is a factor the way it's cured is
factor
so all those different things kind of
combined is
uh going to determine your taste and
smell of the buds
so if you dial in those processes it
should improve it i'm in la it's pretty
dry here too
is it safe to put a humidifier with
thermostat in your dry room
absolutely a lot of growers do that they
need to add a humidifier in there
in order to increase the humidity in the
dry room so the buds don't dry too
quickly
just a couple tips make sure the
humidifier isn't blowing directly onto
the buds
make sure that you have air circulation
going on so
the humidity doesn't reach so high then
all of a sudden the stagnant air
and mold could potentially happen so i
usually put an oscillating fan
on the bottom part of my grow
environment grow tent is what i usually
use
and then air will be able to circulate
down below and it kind of goes up
and i usually leave like the ventilation
sock up top
on the grow tent open so air will be
able to exchange some people actually
use an inline fan as well
for and put it on a low setting in order
for air exchange so
there are a couple different ways to go
about it but yeah you can absolutely
have
put a humidifier in your drying room in
order to increase the humidity
how do you boost rh in a dry environment
i had two humidifiers going full blast
in the tent
and it could only manage 29 would an
external humidifier help
we just talked about that adding a
humidifier will do it so i'm jumping to
an assumption here but i assume that you
have an intake
fan exchanging air in your dry
environment so
with two humidifiers it being at 29 i'm
assuming you're just exhausting too much
air out of the space
if you have a variable speed controller
on the fan you can reduce it down to
like the lowest setting
for example some people actually don't
even use an intake vent
to for air exchange i personally don't
like i just said in the previous
question i'll leave that top ventilation
sock open
sometimes i'll actually leave the tent
cracked as well and then i'll open up
the tent once a day
and completely change the air once a day
but
as long as air is not stagnant you know
adding an oscillating fan down the
bottom
and then you also ask would an external
humidifier help so i'm assuming
what you mean by that is having a
humidifier outside
of the grow tent for example a dry
environment so the air coming in
is of the proper humidity yeah you can
try that as well that should definitely
help
is the fox farm three bottle system
organic quick easy answer on this one
no how to resolve leggy seedlings most
of the time when the seedling
sprouts from the medium and it's coming
up and it appears to be
stretchy usually it's stretching up
looking for more light
so an easy fix is to lower that grow
light so it's closer to the plant that's
way to go about
cell division leads to a closer node
spacing on the plants so
i'm not really sure what light you have
over the plants but keep in mind that
the spectrum could also contribute to it
do you have your lights on
100 power or use a progressive method so
i personally do like to conserve energy
where i can
i actually have a par meter i have the
apple gmq
620 par meter i actually also have their
older model which is the mq 500
parameter and i use that in order to
dial in my light distance so often time
i am dimming the fixture down
trying to bring it pretty close to the
actual plants and then as the plants get
older and larger
i am raising the distance increasing
the percentage so i am able to dial down
the fixture use a par meter and
dial in that distance a little bit more
accurately but yeah generally i'm sure
there's a lot of people out there who
don't have par meters they're so
expensive that's over
i think it's like 575 dollars for the
one that i have which is
kind of crazy but um just going by the
grow light manufacturer's recommended
light distance is
generally where i advise people to start
and hopefully the manufacturer has
correct light distances set so you don't
you know burn your plants and harm your
plants with the lights off temp
what do you like to run the room in veg
and flower ideally it would be
10 degrees lower we're talking
fahrenheit 10 degrees lower than the
lights on temperature so if i'm running
82 degrees lights on temperature you
know 72 degrees
would be ideal for lights off now if it
creeps below than that that's fine the
plant's still going to grow
high 60s even mid 60s when we get into
the low 60 degree fahrenheit you could
see a stunt growth and then also if
you're having these large swings from
82 degrees down to 62 degrees i mean if
you're seeing constant swings like that
that does stress out the plant so you
can definitely see issues if those
swings are too large but yeah
10 degree 15 degree swing fahrenheit is
ideal thanks for your videos i was
wondering on taking oakster dam online
pace classes
it's on sale 9.95 do you recommend
taking this course so i personally
haven't taken that course so
i i can't recommend it okay gm
university is a well-known
university for cannabis cultivation so i
am pretty confident that you're going to
receive good information there
i'm just not really sure what type of
information that course
gives so i can't really tell you if it's
going to be worth it or not for you
unfortunately
i wish i was able to help you out more
on that one all right so a few things
before in this video first thing is my
beginner grow book
this is available paperback form on
amazon it is a complete beginner's guide
for growing
both in soil and coca-cola indoor
cultivation and it's really just going
to give you a lot of general information
that's going to get you through your
first few grows so
really if you're in your first grow
second grow this book is probably more
for you
versus i've actually had some people who
have like five six years experience
they buy and they're disappointed
because well there's beginner
information in there yeah i can't
satisfy everybody
if you do end up buying it on amazon
please leave a review i'm looking to get
500 reviews on amazon currently i have i
think 225
reviews so i have a long ways to go
anybody out there that has purchased a
book
it would mean a lot to me if you spent a
few minutes to leave
a rating a star rating or review on
amazon that helps with ranking
helps more people find the book so on
and so forth so thank you to all who
have
left a review or rating one last thing
would be the giveaway
i'm continuing to give away items here
on every video
until i've run out of items so these
items actually got from mj bizcon
never used them i actually don't use any
of these products
from grow tech so i've got a grow tech
hat
two grow tech hats which you'll get in
this giveaway never used before these
are snapbacks
we've got some mycorrhizae and
beneficial bacteria
again never used i've heard a lot of
good things about grow tech though
and their mycorrhizae in particular so
two of these simple packs
and then last thing would be a t-shirt
so this is a gray t-shirt
with black lettering
can't really see it's in the bag i don't
want to take it out of the bag you know
never used it
this is a size large 10 to the giveaway
all you have to do is click the link
down in the description section below
it'll take you over to rafflecopter
that's what platform it's hosted on
then you just enter a new email and then
there's other ways to enter as well
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
[Music]
peace
you