coming up on garden talk don't ever go
by what the bottle says
just do half so pretty much every line
that i
have run i've basically started off with
a quarter to a half so when i'm
transplanting i basically just do my
bottom layer of soil and then where i'm
going to transplant in
i just sprinkle the the azos and the
mycos right on top of there
you don't have to even use very much
just look at your plants
look at what they're doing do they look
happy are they droopy
do they show signs of deficiencies and
are they nice and green
or are do they have spots on them are
they yellowing
do your research on what your plants
look like
if you're spotting something that
doesn't look normal
research it
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 15.
in this episode i interview painted lady
some of you may know her from the
michigan bros grow show
or her instagram where she shows off her
garden she has been gardening various
plants outdoors
her entire life so you could say her
family raised her as a gardener
in this episode we have a
beginner-friendly discussion on
the basics of feeding plant nutrients
she has experienced using
several different bottle lines of
nutrients and she talks about her
experience using them
she also gives some great tips for
success when it comes to feeding
subscribe to this channel if you haven't
already and click the thumbs up button
if you're listening to this podcast on
one of the podcast platforms such as
apple podcast
please leave a rating and review and if
you're liking these episodes and want to
support the podcast even more
you can do that through patreon the link
is patreon.com
mr growit i'll also link it down in the
youtube description section below
before we get into the episode i'd like
to give a quick shout out to our sponsor
for this episode mars hydro
mars hydro sent me over their new led
grow light the fce
6500 this grill light is a bar style
design
that's similar to the fc 6500 but there
are some differences
this fce 6500 has six light bars
that are detachable and movable on the
light frame this allows you to change
the light intensity
and distribution across the grow space
it has 3978 bridge lux chips
and a mozo driver that is dimmable it
pulls 650 watts from the wall and covers
a five foot by five foot grow space for
bloom
and a six foot by six foot grow space
for veg the fc 6500
also pulls 650 watts and has the same
coverage area
but it comes with eight light bars that
are attached to the frame this led grill
light has 2688
samsung lm 301 and osram 660 nanometer
chips
and a dimmable and ventronics driver
visit marshall.com
i'll leave a link down in the youtube
description section below and use coupon
code
mr growit for discount on any of their
products
all right let's get into the episode
okay here we are painted lady welcome to
garden talk how are you
i'm great thanks so much for having me i
appreciate it thanks for coming on
i actually saw your interview recently
with photosyntec
and uh really good interview you talked
about a ton of good information
get to learn more about you uh and you
know after hearing that i'm like i gotta
get her on my podcast
gotta get her on so oh well thank you so
much for checking it out yeah i was
really stoked to have him reach out to
me and
and it was a fun podcast and and i'm
glad that you saw it because
you know i followed you for years so
this is this is great i appreciate it
again having you have me on
so for those who don't know who you are
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
sure uh yeah i'm born raised in michigan
and
i've always been a gardener my mom kind
of just
uh ingrained that in me as a little
child it was kind of my punishment and
go out and weed the garden
well that wasn't a punishment for me
actually i kind of enjoyed it
so i've always been a gardener and
i started growing medicinal plants about
five six years ago
um and i just i just love it it's just
become my passion
like i said i'm from michigan and it
gets cold here in the winter
and it is so nice i indoor grow i'm a
caregiver here in michigan and i do have
patients
so i always want to make sure that i
have the best possible product for my
patients and
and going down there and spending time
in my garden
especially in the winter and the nice
warm place to go with
artificial sun is just you know just
it's my happy place
and spending time down there just makes
my plants happy too and i think it shows
so
uh yeah that's how i got into gardening
i uh
found medicinal plants at an early age
because of
chronic migraines and i just have really
been
um a proponent of it ever since and
you know it just has been something that
i've been looking at doing
professionally
so um yeah that's a little bit about me
and and i can now be found uh the guys
from michigan bros grow show
found me somehow i was a fan and i would
watch and participate in the chats when
they would have their live
shows and they asked me to join the
panel and so now i'm
on the michigan bros grow show on sunday
and monday nights and
asking questions and answering questions
as best i can
and and uh yeah it's really been uh
fun and i can't even i can't even
begin to tell you how beneficial it's
been in my life so
the gardening and everything about it
and so
yeah it's it's been fantastic and i
can't wait to
keep doing this and hope to do it
professionally sometime soon
that's cool one of the things in that
podcast that really stuck out to me is
that you've
used a whole bunch of different types of
nutrients
that kind of prompted this interview
here is or discussion whatever
um to talk about you know what the topic
is today which is the basics of feeding
plants nutrients
there are several different types of
nutrients out there right there's
synthetic and there's organic now some
people might look at the title of this
video
which is the basics of feeding plants
nutrients and they might say
feed the soil not feed the plant
right so there is actually such thing as
feeding the plant and there is actually
a such thing as feeding the soil right
so that's when we talk about synthetic
versus organic so synthetic nutrients
most bottled lines i believe are
synthetic nutrients
they're smaller molecules and basically
when you're mixing those nutrients into
water
um you know they're water soluble
they're in a
plant available form so the plant can
immediately uptake those nutrients
you're feeding the plant in that sense
organic on the other hand
organic inputs organic amendments
that's not in a form that's immediately
available for the plant right so
what needs to happen first is the
microbial life in the soil needs to
break down those inputs
and put them into that plant available
form so they'll
break down or they'll eat those
amendments
crap them out right and then they're
kind of in that plant available
form that can be uptaken by the plant so
there's a little bit of a delay i guess
you can
kind of say is you know the synthetic
nutrients are immediately
immediately available for the plant they
can uptake it right away if you're
coming across a deficiency
there should be a pretty decent there's
going to be a quicker recovery off of
synthetic nutrients than organics
because organics you need to
it needs to be broken down by those
microbes first
so it takes a little bit longer so
feeding the plant
versus feeding the soil so that being
said
uh do you grow with i know you've grown
with synthetic nutrients
said i can't speak i know you've grown
with synthetic nutrients in the past
do you also grow with organic nutrients
i do
actually i'm kind of uh gap bridging the
gap right now of the two because
i was originally shown and i learned
with synthetic nutrients i started off
with fox farm
which i think we've probably you know if
you've ever run synthetic nutrients
pretty much everybody's either heard of
it or run it and that's where i learned
and so
um yeah i just learned with bottled
synthetic newts
and i've kind of bridged or i've kind of
run the whole gamut i guess you could
you could say between fox farm and then
i moved to gh
and veg bloom and advance and i bought
all those bottles like that whole line i
thought i had to have
all of them you know to make sure that
my plant was getting everything that it
needed
and i i just found that you don't and so
i kind of wanted to
understand what i was actually feeding
my plants
what's in that bottle of fox farm you
know tiger bloom
that i'm going to be given to my plants
so that's when i kind of switched over
to organic and wanted to understand
exactly like you were saying feeding the
soil instead of feeding
the actual plant and the difference
there and it's
you know it's it's definitely a
completely different world
like you were saying deficiencies you
can't just solve overnight
uh that that's a little bit difficult
for me to understand
knowing that you know with the synthetic
line i can just grab that little bottle
of
you know nitrogen or whatever if it's
lacking something and
within a couple you know 24 hours 48
hours
we're good to go but yeah i've really
been
enjoying learning more about organics
and feeding the soil and what i need to
do to keep my plants happy
with that same with me i've used
synthetics for i think i used fox arm
trio for the first six years of my life
of six years of growing uh and then i
started venturing out into other
lines and now eventually work my way
into the organic side of things
so just like you uh but you but both of
us kind of do have
uh experience growing a bunch of
different using a bunch of different
bottled lines right so
before we get into those different
bottled lines that we've used and kind
of tips on using those different bottled
lines
let's talk about water let's talk about
ph ppm and ec
so what type of water do you typically
use
you know do you use tap water do you use
well water ro
rain water i am straight tap water it's
coming right out of the tap here in my
city in michigan
um and you know i run about the yes i do
check ph and ec for sure when i'm
running synthetics you definitely need
to know
what you're giving your plant and what
your plant is giving back out
so uh yeah i definitely check ph
and my water here is not too horrible it
runs usually around
uh an eight um so it's not terrible but
it's not
uh it's not great either so i definitely
have to make sure i adjust
after i add my newts and sometimes you
find with the
bottled nutrient lines they kind of
adjust themselves
they're somehow regulated and believe me
i'm not a scientist so i don't know how
it works
but however it works they just it's some
kind but sometimes after you add
all of what you need to add to give your
plant what it needs it kind of balances
that ph for you but
always check to make sure because you
want to make sure that your plant is
getting
the right amount of nutrients and the
only way that you can do that is by
having the correct ph
and going in and going out so um yeah i
definitely check all that and i just use
straight tap water
ph it and check the ec
ec usually i run uh i usually do ppms i
know that's kind of
most people have a preference i usually
do ppms
and i usually do about a three to six in
early veg three to six hundred ppm's
early veg
and a 600 to 900 mid to late veg
and then bump it up from there into
flower
and and i like to stay about a 6.2 to
6.5 ph
generally when i'm running a bottle line
got it that makes sense
and for watering you know you mentioned
you use tap water
a lot of tap water comes with either
chlorine or chloramine which can be
harmful for the microbes in the soil
do you do anything with the tap water
before you mix your nutrients in do you
like let it sit out so the chlorine
dissipates or do you even have chlorine
or chloramine in your local water or
ours i have checked it and it doesn't
seem to be too bad
the it right straight out of the tap
it's coming out at about 200
to 50 ppms it's not too too bad so i
don't worry too much about adding
extra to the water or letting it sit i
kind of let my plants
tell me how they feel and if my plants
look happy with the way that the
you know with the system that i'm using
now which is generally not
waiting or adding anything to my tap
water then
i i don't i tend to just leave it as it
is if my plants look happy then i'm
happy
and that's something to keep in mind
when you're using these bottled
nutrients is what your ppm
is coming out of the tap right ppm or ec
is coming out of the tap because
the nutrients you mix up is going to be
in addition
to that right so for sure if your
feeding chart says 500 ppm is
is this mixture um you know grow a grow
b whatever
that's going to be on top of what is
coming out of your tap so
actually in my local area we have
chlorine
and it actually comes out of the tap at
like 485 ppm
wow extremely high i think epa
guidelines is
no higher than 500 i think if it's over
500 it's unsafe
to drink or whatever so mine's very very
high and then
i looked at my local water report and
they do have a breakdown of what's in
there
and i was pretty surprised to see that
of the 485 ppm
80 ppm is sodium so actually when i used
i did a grow with tap water i've done
several grows with tap water over the
years but
one in particular i did a grow with tap
water
then i got a soil sample from logan labs
and my sodium level was through the roof
oh wow so for those that don't know
logan labs does soil
samples i think generally it's
recommended to do a soil sample between
grows
uh some of my some may advise
differently on that one but
there are consultants out there that you
can sit down and look over your soil
sample with
and they'll give you guidance on what
amendments you need to add or whatever
to kind of
rebalance that soil which which is
pretty cool but yeah i was really
surprised with
80 ppm of sodium and that there was such
a build up there
so that's something that that folks
should certainly be aware of um you know
when they're using tap water
yeah i definitely did not consider that
when i first started i wasn't even
thinking about until i think i saw one
somebody's video one of the youtube
videos that i might have
even been you actually and uh yeah and i
didn't even think about oh my gosh i
gotta add
the that number to the actual end
result to make sure i'm getting the
right amount of ppms into my plans
so yeah definitely got to keep an eye on
all that stuff for sure
cool so we talked about ph you
talked about what your ideal range is
talk about ppm what your ideal ranges
are
good um now let's talk about top feeding
versus bottom feeding
traditional way to feed your plants is
to mix up nutrients maybe put in a
pitcher or spray or something and then
feed on the top right you do a soil
drench from the top
i heard on your on that interview with
photosyntec that you do
bottom feeding there what you like to
call butt chugging right yeah
can you talk to us a little bit about
bottom feeding versus top feeding and
some of the benefits so on and so forth
yeah um
i i do a regular podcast the michigan
bros grow show and
we they kind of have shown me the way as
we call it butt chugging with bottom
watering i was always a top water
i always just filled up a bucket added
my nutrients and just poured it right
over the top
um just like i do with my plants outside
in my garden
and i i just never really thought about
bottom watering or the benefits of why
you would want a bottom water as opposed
to just pouring it right over the top
and i've found there's so many benefits
to quote-unquote butt chugging it i know
that that's a term that a lot of people
in the industry either love or hate you
either giggle or you don't
and we just giggle at it you know it's
just it's just something
a term that we like to use and it's just
kind of just kind of gives us a little
bit
extra giggle when we're down there
watering so generally i just take the
same amount of water that i would have
poured over the top
and pour it in the reservoir at the
bottom and that eliminates a lot of
problems that you can come across
with fungus gnats and pests with you
know having the top layer of that
soil being a little bit damp can cause a
little bit of a problem if you've ever
found that
and the butt chugging just really seems
to eliminate that problem altogether
and you know it just also it's just so
much
i a lot of people call it the lazy vans
way of watering too
i don't know if you've ever used radical
bags or fabric bags a lot of times if
you pour that
water right over the top it can run
right off the sides especially in those
radical bags
so the bottom bottom watering the butt
chugging sure eliminates that problem
all the way around so your nutrients
aren't going right off the side and
into on the floor or whatever in the
reservoir
so yeah that's i just have really become
a fan of bottom watering for
for all both of those reasons gotcha
okay so let's start talking about these
bottle lines now before we actually get
into each bottle line individually
there's a question i want to ask you so
when i first
started getting i think i was on fox
farm i was growing with that for six
years like i mentioned
yeah and i was just starting to venture
out into new
lines and i asked growers with more
experience so maybe you know which line
should i try should i try this one
should i try this one this one looks
good that one looks good
you know so on and so forth and the
general consensus
among a lot of these growers with
experience with
several bottled lines i was a little bit
surprised on this is that
they're saying a lot of these lines are
very very similar to the point where you
should just pick one
and go with it right and we're talking
base nutrients so it's mostly synthetic
lines they're gonna have base nutrients
and then they're gonna have additives on
top of it right so base nutrients
typically consists of two maybe three
bottles
like uh i know blue planet nutrients has
a blue max
part uh a part b fox farm has the fox
farm trio
three bottles of nutrients there are
several lines out there that have either
two bottles
or three bottles of their base nutrients
and then they have additives beyond that
that being said would you agree or
disagree
with these lines being very similar to
ways you just
kind of pick one and go with it in my
experience i didn't find that they were
similar at all
um i i just the the fox farm
may be a little similar to the gh i
thought
uh but once i switched over to veg bloom
and having the powder noods as opposed
to the bottles that was completely new
for me um and the
advanced nutrients just seemed to
separate every single thing
out into a different bottle and so i
mean
obviously for certain purposes but um
yeah
i found that i think that they all had
a different flavor i think they all had
a different result in my experience in
my environment anyway they did
so i that's why i chose to kind of
experiment throughout the different
lines because
i wanted to see the differences in what
it would bring and if this one would
bring a different flavor or more terps
than this one
so um yeah i i tend to think that they
all have their own
advantages and disadvantages and and
i've really
found my niche now with it's not really
it's not synthetic it's an
organic bottled nutrient with bloom
yellow bottles
which is an australian company who i
found through you
funny enough um i obviously used to
watch your videos when i was first
starting out religiously
and one time you chose to use the bloom
yellow bottles i believe they sent you a
sample or something and
and your girls were loving it and i paid
attention and so when i was uh
at a local girl store i found that they
had had a little expo
and the guy from bloom yellow bottles
was there and sent me home with a sample
of the whole line
and it is organic and but it is bottles
and
um i i just my plants in my environment
just really really love it and i have
stuck with them ever since
nice nice i'm glad to hear that you've
gotten success off of them
and yeah yeah i definitely i like using
them i wasn't too
too happy about the amount of bottles
that they have and then they have like
18 different bottles told
when you talk about their foiler sprays
and stuff like that but
um but yeah again i think you can get
away with just
the grow a and the grill b i think they
have one
grow a grey b for veg grey b and b for
flower i believe right
yeah um do you use just those or
what other um bottles do you use from
bloom yellow bottles and do you have any
tips
for using bloom yellow bottles we'll
start with them yeah sure uh
i do use quite a few but i have found
that you can really narrow it down
to just basically like you said the
bases the a and b's and fly in veg and
flower
and i really think that the plants
benefit from
uh humates humates and then they have a
sea minerals line there's a seaweed uh
sea fuel
and sea minerals that i think have
really
made a difference in the plants and
their health so
those are the main ones aside from their
other
product which is a roots product
obviously
um you know that that helps you know
create your rise of fear and make sure
that everything is getting
getting all good and the microbes are
doing their job to make sure the plant
can uptake those nutrients that you're
feeding them
now do you follow their feeding schedule
that they put out on their website
and uh if so do you do the full dose
like they recommend
or did you do a half dose or what no i
don't i
don't think any of us synthetic growers
or bottlenews growers
ever actually do um i always probably
start with either a quarter to a half of
what they recommend on the bottle
just to make sure i don't want to burn
my plan and you can
always oh you can always correct
but you can take away so if you're
feeding
right out of the gate what they're
recommending sometimes your plants may
not be used to it at that point so
i generally try to get away with less is
more
so i i do i just generally try to
take a look at my plants are they happy
are they showing any kind of deficiency
if they are that's when you can correct
but generally
i take the less is more approach and
that seems to be working for me
got it and then when you add it to your
water
are you adjusting the p are you looking
at the ph then phppn are you adjusting
the ph then
and what do you use to adjust the ph if
you do you know i
don't tend to worry about it too much
with the organics
uh with the bloom yellow bottles i i
generally
kind of leave my blue lab pens to the
side
until later in flower when i want to
make sure
um everything is is okay and towards
you know getting towards the end i want
to make sure that those that plant is
flushing properly and make sure that all
that nutrients are out of there but
um for the most part no yeah i i kind of
put the ph pen away with the bloom
yellow bottles it's only when i'm
running like a
you know a veg bloom or um you know gh
or one of those lines that i tend to use
them a lot but
you know for the most part uh the bloom
yellow bottle seemed to kind of adjust
i have checked it um after adding just
to see
just to make sure that i'm not crazy out
of whack and it seems to kind of settle
around
an acceptable range for my plants so i
generally just don't try to mess with it
i feel like like
going back to what i said before less is
more why add that
acid or you know if you don't have to
with the ph up or ph down and just you
know those blue and orange and
all this you know i just would rather
less is more
that makes sense yeah i would assume i
mean you said you were coming in like
eight
something ph to begin with your tap you
know i assume after
adding those nutrients i would assume it
would drop
into that acceptable range and then once
you add those in your microbes
actually adjust the ph range in the soil
as well and
you know the whole organic side of
things as well so a lot of people say
that
when you're organics you don't have to
check ph you don't have to check ppm
et cetera et cetera so that's pretty
cool that that's how that works out for
you
yeah they're doing well with it and i
can't you know i i can't say anything
bad about that company or um you know
the line it's
it's just really really worked well in
my environment i mean everybody's
environment is different
so for me and you know i'm a basement
grower
here in michigan with you know cement
black walls and
and i do have a a pretty nice setup and
then i have separate veg and flower
rooms
i don't have to grow in a tent which um
can be
trying at the same time uh
not growing in a tent because you have a
bigger space to have to try to control
that environment
but those yellow bottles just i don't
know
with a with my i'm an led grower too so
under all those leds and and you know
the blue yellow bottles just seem to be
really
making my girls happy let's move on to
fox farm nutrients
can you talk a little bit about your
experience using fox farm any tips you
have for that
ah that was the very first line i
ever used coming out the gate my mentor
was the one that used fox farm and so
uh he showed me the way with that
three-part system
and i was always
i don't know what it is and maybe it's
just kind of a mental thing for me but
i i don't like to eat any foods with
like food color like massive food like
blue
and green and red food coloring and like
i noticed with fox farm
i had kind of these weird colors and
and i just i don't know i i just not
that there's anything wrong with it but
i just would kind of put that in there
and in the water and i'm kind of
thinking
this is kind of like miracle grow and i
don't know
it just it just really seemed unnatural
to me
i guess so i i quickly moved away from
fox farm um and
all those other lines i really wanted to
try to kind of get away from
from everything um that just didn't seem
natural to me i guess
and maybe that makes me not a synthetic
grower now but
now that i've found bloom yellow bottles
but um
yeah i really the only experience i had
with fox farm was the
initial first few runs and it works it
works great
um but i found once i switched to
the other lines and especially with the
bloom yellow bottles the flavor and the
terpene
profile just seemed to to explode so
um nothing against fox farmer anybody
who uses it but that was my experience
and i just kind of was like
let's try something different
interesting yeah i started with fox farm
like i mentioned earlier i grew with
first six years i grew with fox farms
started with the trio
um overfed my plants at first that's a
very very
concentrated line yeah and you look at
their feeding chart and their ppms are
way out of whack and
just so people are aware maybe you know
there's
a lot of new growers watching this right
when you're looking at these feeding
charts
understand that the ppms they mention
are for a wide variety of plants
i think a lot of people jump to the
assumption that this is for the
medicinal plant
um you know medicinal plants can take
less than what's recommended on the
feeding charts that's why you often hear
about people doing a half dose people
doing a quarter dose
now for me with fox farm i would
actually do a
third dose so do a third sometimes even
a quarter dose
of fox farm nutrients their fox farm
trio so the three bottles that consist
of
and when i was running hps that's all i
needed was those three bottles
i would you know ph adjust using ph up
or ph
down and then of course monitor the
the r uh the ph and ppm of the runoff as
well and then kind of make adjustments
there
um but uh but i had good success with
fox farm nutrients but actually one
thing i found is that once i switched to
led
i started getting calcium deficiency
okay and i was advised to add in
an additive calmag which a lot of people
are familiar with and that solved the
problem
you know we'll talk a little bit about
additives as we're going through these
lines or maybe after we go through these
lines but calmagg was an additive that
i added with it particularly
particularly when using leds
and then one other thing was i found
with some particular cultivars or phenos
was
i would see phosphorus deficiency in mid
flowering
and i used beastie blooms which is a pk
booster by fox farm
and that solved my problems i would add
it week four five
and six only and that would completely
solve my
phosphorus issue have you used any other
additives at all or no
oh sure yeah i use um occasionally i
will
add i do still have a couple of those
other lines that i use so
in flour i don't really add too many
additives
in veg but in flour i definitely add
uh occasionally some shine by veg bloom
um i think that really adds uh density
and some weight uh to the product to the
end result
and i also like to use new millennium's
um product also and i'm drawing a blank
on what the name of it is
the um the frost booster you know what
i'm talking about
uh winterfell
winterfrost yeah uh i i like to add that
in flower too i think it adds a little
bit of
a little bit of frost to the girls so
um but and obviously bloom yellow
bottles does have
a calcium additive that i do think is
essential
especially with growing with leds so um
definitely have to add calmag
and i do add a couple of the little
bloom boosters there for
for density and shine and that was when
you were using fox farm
oh he's only just in general no but i i
still use them to this day
even with my glue i'll i'll add i think
it adds a little bit of extra
um i've kind of developed that system on
my own
as opposed to when i was running that
fox farm system with my mentor
um he would add budswell i can't even
remember the name of the company i don't
know i don't think it's a fox farm
company he would always add budswell
and a couple other things for late end
stage flower
boost but uh as far as any other
additives
too much with the fox farmland that was
about it let's move on to general
hydroponics
so that's actually a line that i've
never used i've seen a lot of people use
it with success
general hydro can you talk a little bit
about your experience using that
um i know their feeding chart in
particular you definitely have to do a
half dose with that one
as well is that correct yeah yeah i we
pretty much
when i my mentor and i he basically told
me right out of the gate
don't ever go by what the bottle says
just do half
so pretty much every line that i have
run i've basically started off with a
quarter to a half i even would do
a quarter sometimes because i'd be too
afraid to burn them
uh yeah so i would j with gh same thing
i always fed them a half and that seemed
to be doing pretty well i never had a
problem with deficiencies too much with
gh
or anything but i just didn't think that
that terp profile was there
um it just i don't know just seemed to
be lacking a little something for me and
maybe it was my environment or maybe it
was me
i don't know you know i was running it
when i was early growing and
and uh maybe it was something i was
doing wrong but
as far as the gh line definitely half
strength for sure because they are
pretty concentrated
like fox farm with gh did you
run any additives on they have was it
is it three bottles with gh the base
nutrients oh
my god this was so many years ago it was
i think so i've run so many you know
advanced had like 20 some bottles
it seems like so it's hard for me to
remember but
yeah i think they were a three-parter
and then
we used the same additives with the fox
farm
i i just took his additives that he used
with the fox farm and tried them with
the gh so i would add that
bud swell and there was another one that
we used to use that i think got banned
actually and i can't remember what the
name of that one was now but
you definitely have to know what you're
feeding your plants at least i want to
know what i'm feeding them and
you know if that stuff's getting banned
why why is it getting banned
so yeah it might have been a pgr plant
regulator which yeah which is
highly controversial and yes my mentor
was
all about yield and
i am not i am about quality so yeah it
was probably was
gotcha now getting into advanced
nutrients
this is a line that you had mentioned
has a ton of different bottles there
i've never used advanced i've heard
nightmare stories people have a lot of
success with the
the nightmare stories that i hear is
just that
i heard that they're overpriced i heard
that you know the sales people try to
sell you all their bottles and you don't
actually need all their bottles and
and so on and so forth so can you tell
me a little bit about like advanced
nutrients
you know the base nutrients that they
have maybe the additives you used with
them
and so on and so forth sure yeah i
actually
loved advance when i first started
running them as opposed to the fox farm
and
and the gh because they had that ph
perfect system so it was easy you know
you added that three part i think it was
uh
i used the micro grow and bloom
line um from them and so yeah mike
added that every time and uh
my my plants loved it i can't i don't
have anything bad to say
about that about them in any way other
than
they did seem to separate every single
bottle or every single
possible nutrient out into a separate
bottle and then it just seemed like they
had so many different
lines of the same nutrient like they had
three different
roots products and i was always kind of
like
i don't get it but okay you know
and in the end i
kind of thought that everything tasted
the same i
i would run several different strains
together
in the same room and at the end it
seemed to me that everything tasted the
same
and smelled the same and had the same
terp profile so again
maybe this is going back to i know the
gh
or whatever maybe i did something wrong
but it just um
just didn't seem to do it for me so
that's when i i wanted
something else i i knew that there was
medicinal plants that tasted different
from each other
so obviously i wanted to find out how i
could
make that happen and that's when i ended
up switching from
advanced over to bloom i found them
and wow what a difference there's a huge
difference
but advanced it it's good company a lot
of bottles
very expensive but they grow good plants
i i don't have anything bad to say about
them there my plants were happy
let's talk a little bit more about their
ph perfect that you mentioned
i'm a little bit familiar with that you
might be able to correct me from wrong
here but
uh from my understanding it's basically
once you
add in those nutrients into water it's
going to be in the ideal range
of ph for plants so that you don't have
to use
ph up and ph down and go go back and
forth potentially
trying to get it into that particular
range yeah is that correct
yeah yeah and it was great and i even
did check it
um i used to use the old school you know
the little plastic bottles and the
you know check the color with the drops
and everything
before i got a blue lab pen um
makes things so much easier but uh
yeah i would check it just to make sure
it just like this can't possibly like i
just added all of this stuff it can't
possibly but
every time it was perfect and i don't
know
the technology just them the way that
they have
you running their system obviously the
scientists put that together so that
they know that this one is going to
adjust it to this point
so that you know you're feeding the
plants in that correct range that they
can uptake the nutrients in the way that
they need
so yeah it was great for that and it was
it's
great for beginners in that way because
then you don't have that
extra step of oh no you know i added my
nutrients
is it in the right range for my plants
to be able to uptake those correctly
so it's perfect for beginners in that
way in that aspect because
you don't have to mess around with it at
all and the plants are happy
definitely sounds like that would be a
benefit make things easier sure um i
wonder how
it would impact like a half dose of
nutrients versus a quarter dose versus
if it's still going to adjust the ph
accurately like that and also different
water sources right
you know using tap water what you said
has like 200 ppm how does that impact
versus ro water with you know close to
zero ppm
or distilled water you know right so on
and so forth um
and that is definitely one of the lines
that i follow the instructions on to
because i was concerned about that ph
perfect system so i'm like well i must
have to use
exactly what they indicate on on the
directions
to obtain that ph perfect technology and
i so i never did really experiment
outside of that and i should have maybe
that's
maybe that was the problem with you know
the everything tasting the same
like i said i'm not blaming any of the
companies for
you know any of the situation that i
ended up with the result that i ended up
with in the end
other than that was what i experienced
and maybe it was something i did maybe
it wasn't but
i have had other people say to me um
the same about advance that they kind of
found in the end that everything kind of
tasted and smelled the same so
um i don't know my plants were happy it
just
you know it's all about that end product
what is
the uh what is this veg bloom
nutrient you're talking about is that a
company you said you also wanted
yeah veg bloom uh i think it's like veg
plus bloom a hydroponic research i think
is the
umbrella of veg bloom um
yeah and they have like a veg bloom
dirty they it goes they
have their lines specifically for your
water type
so if you have like tap water you want
to use the dirty if you are using
ro water you want to use a different
line so it's kind of like
you know same thing with um bloom yellow
bottles has like a european a and b
and like it's so everything is kind of
different with their bases
yeah but for the most part they and
they're powder newts too so that was a
little different for me i was always
used to
bottles so um what switching over to
that powder was definitely
a different for me but um the plants
were happy the only thing i i kind of
didn't like about the powder was um some
of it's left in the bottom of the bucket
if you don't
you know continuously mix it or you know
make sure you let it sit for a while and
dissolve real well then
you have a little bit of residue at the
bottom of your your bucket but
uh great line i liked it i just didn't
think anything spectacular
came out at the end other than what i
had been seeing so
i just basically have been just trying
to run
everything to see what i like best and
um that's where i've
you know just settled on the bloom the
yellow bottles have been doing it for me
so until i find something else that that
uh will beat them
that's that's it for now but yeah the
veg bloom i i do still use
um the shine product that i was talking
about a little while ago
i think it just adds a little bit of
density uh and that's
in weeks i generally use it weeks
two on until about week five or six
in flower and then i just continue that
and that's when i start the winter frost
from new milan new millennium that's so
hard to say can anybody say that word
right
milady aluminum millennium but um
new millennium's winter frost and that's
when i add that
and on top of the blue yellow bottles i
just think it adds a little extra
so but yeah the veg bloom great company
great line it just uh moved on
i have to check them out i'm not
familiar with them okay
one line that i have tried which i
believe you haven't tried is blue planet
nutrients right
you haven't tried them um blue planet
there was a seaweed i think i bought
like a kelp seaweed
um bottle from them once off of the
amazon because i think
i heard you talking about blue planet so
i'm going to try them
and i i loved it but i never used like
their whole line so i thought about it
for a minute and then i found blue
yellow bottles and so i tried them
instead of ordering because the guy just
loaded me up with
you know all the free samples and then
ever since then i'm like oh
so old on the bloom yellow bottles so i
never went back and actually did the
full line of blue planet but
just that one product but and i did like
it it did you know work really well
yeah i've used blue planted nutrients
for for several years you're talking
about liquid seaweed by the way i
believe that's the name of the bottle is
liquid seaweed yeah
that's what it was yeah i loved it so i
actually used blue planted nutrients
i can speak about them for a little bit
just my experience using them
i use them for several years had great
results with it i started with their
three-part base nutrients that they have
i think it's their high-yield system
it's a three-part
plus a whole bunch of different
additives i think there was eight
bottles total
that i would use so kind of a lot of
bottles there but um they worked they
worked pretty good
um i would start with a half dose and it
you know according to their feeding
chart and
everything went good and i would just
adjust based on what that runoff
ppm was and one thing i did like about
them
is that it almost kind of had that ph
perfect in this in a sense that advanced
has
every time i mix up a half dose of
nutrients i would get 5.8 ph
no matter what you know no matter which
additives i used or whatever
so that was kind of convenient because i
knew exactly how much ph up i should be
adding in
it just made things a lot easier kind of
and then if i'm in cocoa
i usually like to do 5.8 in cocoa every
time just feed it in every single time
and so mix up my nutrients didn't have
to do any sort of ph
when i'm growing in cocoa so that's
something i did liked it but yeah i use
their
high yield system for for several years
i use their
bluemax it's a two part that they have
i used that along with some additives as
well
and uh yeah no complaints uh on that
avenue
so yeah yeah i definitely was going that
route because i saw the
you know your plants were liking it too
so i definitely was looking into them
and did that did buy that liquid seaweed
and liked it but for the most part uh i
i discovered the bloom yellow bottles by
chance
at a local growth stores expo and uh
got sidetracked with them now do you add
any
sugars into your garden at all whether
it be molasses
or honey or anything like that i don't
only because i use a product called
recharge
and i'm sure most yeah i'm sure you
and most everybody that's watching has
heard a recharge before but it's a micro
microbial product uh and
it has molasses in it so i don't tend to
add any extra because i use that as my
once a week treat as scottie riel says
and uh the girls are happy so i don't
tend to add anything extra
but i would if i didn't use recharge i
probably would add some sort of
sweetener because you have to feed those
microbes in order for them to keep
staying alive to do their work because i
do use i'm a soil grower
um you were mentioning you like to do
the 5.8 in cocoa and
and i'm a soil grower i run either coast
of maine or
route 707 i generally like um
and for the first like two to three four
weeks of veg
and then i'll switch over to my blue
yellow bottles after that and feed
after that once they start running out
of food but you gotta feed those
microbes in order
to get you know them to be able to keep
doing their work to be able to get the
plants to uptake those newts
so yeah i would definitely use a sugar
if i was not using recharge but
i don't think it's really necessary they
seem to be doing their job
with the recharge yeah recharge is
awesome that microbial inoculant which
is another thing i was going to ask you
about is
do you use any microbial inoculants i
use recharge as well
so it has the molasses in there like you
mentioned also has kelp
in there it has a ton of different
beneficial microbes in there
as well so i love that stuff do you use
that throughout the entire grill
or did you just use it okay yeah some
people only use it in veg i know some
people only use it in flour
but it is safe to use throughout the
entire grow so i was curious if you used
it throughout the entire growing up
i do i use a couple products upon
transplant every time when i pot up
called azoles and mycos so i use it
every time i transplant up and then i
water and recharge
every time and i use the recharge once a
week
until about five weeks or week five
of flour and then i'll discontinue the
use because i don't think it
you know you know really needed too much
at that point and it finishes off nicely
so yeah i use it through the whole
process and there's also another product
from veg bloom that i
add in every now and then because i mean
what i have the bottle down there
and or container i should say it's not a
bottle but um
of plus life and it's also another
microbial
product that is you know from veg bloom
so i'll add that occasionally every
couple weeks just to give it a little
bit of different
microbes in there that wasn't that's not
in the recharge and
it seems to be working got it and the
azos and micos
uh i've heard of that problem because i
haven't had a chance to use them
i have a lot of good success that's a
mycorrhizal fungi
type products for for both of them and i
assume there's some other beneficials in
there as well is that is that right
yeah i mean i'm not going to be able to
explain exactly what's in those things
but
i used to follow along with you when i
was
first starting growing i used to follow
a guy on youtube called the grateful
grower
and when i was first learning he was
showing how to transplant this is how
you do this and this is how you do it
and he always used
a little bit of azos a little bit of
mycos and
um then explained why and then it's
beneficial bacteria and you've got to
get those roots inoculated and blah blah
and so yeah there i am not going to be
able to spit out
the scientific name of both of those
products or what's in them
but i do know that they make a huge
difference and i get really really
uh wonderful root growth once i do
uh transplant with those two products
and then water in the recharge on top
it just seems to explode the root growth
and
and the beneficial bacteria just makes
everything cohesive
and uh yeah exactly what they need to
get going
yeah mycorrhizal fungi is extremely
beneficial i mean it actually attaches
to the roots and helps with the uptake
of nutrients
some people actually use it as a when
they transplant they'll sprinkle it onto
the roots
other people use it as like a soil
drench so they'll mix it in with water
and then water their plant to use it do
you sprinkle onto the roots at all or do
you use it a soil drench or what
what i do is uh so when i'm
transplanting i basically just do my
bottom layer of soil and then where i'm
going to transplant in
i just sprinkle the azos and the mycos
right on top of there
you don't have to even use very much
it's just very little i've had the same
bag for
geez i want to say probably a year
they're just little small bags and
yeah you just sprinkle a tiny bit of
both of those products right in there
and then the roots that have already
grown
and been substantial they just kind of
make that contact like you say and once
that contact is made it just kind of
explodes so uh and then i water
in the recharge once i've transplanted
that's
what goes in on top of it so i think
it's just kind of like a double duty
hitting them from all sides similar
product to
azos and micos is great white
mycorrhizae
i use that as well and i sprinkle it
onto the roots sometimes i use it as a
soil trench
i know some people use it in their um
compost teas
they'll add that in there okay yeah but
then there's some controversy behind it
as if
microbes kind of compete with each other
and then you're kind of wasting money
because those microbes are getting eaten
and so and so forth but
we won't get into all that but yeah i've
also used uh
mammoth p which is a microbial inoculant
that
uh has microbes in there to focus on
phosphorus breakdown helps with with
phosphorus breakdown
and um yeah so there's so many different
microbial products out there and then
as far as sugars we touched on i use
molasses
i actually created a whole video on
molasses i typically
use it as a soul drench i'll actually
i'll leave a link to that video down
in the description section below if
anybody wants to learn more about
molasses and how to incorporate it into
your garden
so more and more places are becoming
legal more and more growers are coming
onto the market
it seems like the comment sections are
flooded with beginners looking for
advice
what tips or advice do you have for
those who are
new or are struggling to get feeding
dialed in
my advice is basically from my
experience
just look at your plants look at what
they're doing
do they look happy are they droopy do
they show signs of deficiencies
you know are they nice and green or are
do they have spots on them are they
yellowing you know just basically
my advice is just do your research on
what your plants look like
if you're spotting something that
doesn't look normal
research it there's so many great
resources now that we have available to
us
between forums and youtube podcasters
and everything that can
basically spell it out what's going on
with your plans and
basically that's the biggest advice i
can give you is just
take a look at your plants what are they
doing what do they look like
don't just automatically feed that four
tablespoons or teaspoons of
you know fox farm to that gallon of
water um
or whatever that direction says just
because it says it
you know just pay attention to your
plants and i think that that will reward
you in the end
so where can the listeners find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
everybody can find me on the michigan
bros grow show
on sunday and monday nights and also on
instagram
at painted lady gardens and i do have a
cannabis account even though i'm guilty
of not checking it too often so please
forgive me canna buzzers
i can be found over there at
paintedlady13
um and i am excited to say that i have
a a commercial uh
that i am working on right now uh here
in michigan i have a
few partners and we're looking at
opening
um a class c facility here in michigan
hopefully in the next year or two um
fingers crossed granted you know timing
is right and investors are
are willing so that's our next step um
is going into branding and and trying to
get those investors to give us the money
to start growing medicine
um for everyone so i already do that as
a caregiver here in michigan and i found
i love it so much that i just
i just want to do it on a larger scale
and do it professionally so
that's what's on the horizon for me and
uh yeah
i would uh i'll be stoked to be able to
say
that i'm a part of the industry
officially uh once that happens
so yeah come check me out on the
michigan bros grove show
i'll leave a link to your channel to
actually your instagram
down in the description section below
and also link the michigan bros
grows show is that what you say yeah the
girls grow show
awesome tongue twister there
well painted lady thank you so much for
coming on to the podcast today
it was a pleasure to have you on here
and uh hope you enjoy the rest of your
day
thanks so much for having me i really
appreciate it thanks guys
[Music]
you