coming up on garden talk this current
grow i just switched to gaia green and
i'm loving it i love the dry amendments
i love just amending my soil and you
leave it alone for whatever three weeks
and you top dress or you transplant you
meant it again i've seen a lot of guys
use the clear solo cups and they'll put
that inside another solo cup so that
then they can just pull it out just to
see how the roots are water your plants
12 hours in advanced he said it helps
loosen them up and that way you can bend
them a little bit easier once i get to
the vegetative stage i'm able to start
getting into a routine when i'm watering
when am i feeding uh you know what am i
training
i think my with the flowering i'm never
sure how much to feed that's that's been
my one of my main problems be patient
you're gonna make a mistake you're gonna
make lots of them
just don't freak out if things aren't
going right
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this episode number 39. in this
episode i interviewed the rookie grower
he has been gardening for three years
and he has experience with both organics
and synthetics in this episode we focus
on beginner gardening we talk about
problems that you may face while
gardening as well as solutions to those
problems thanks to all of you who
support this podcast or patreon if you'd
like to support you can do so by going
to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible a big supporter of this
podcast is spider farmer they sponsored
this podcast and i use their led grow
lights spider farmer now has a bar style
series of led grow lights they have the
se 3000 a four bar fixture for a three
foot by three foot grow space the se5000
a six bar fixture for a four foot by
four foot grow space and the sc7000 in a
bar fixture for a five foot by five foot
grow space i will leave a link to spider
farmer down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
growth 5 during checkout for discount on
their products thanks to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast they sent me
over their grow 10 which has a canvas
density of 2000 d making them the
thickest grow tent on the market today
it has an aluminum plate that mounts
your controller to the grow tent with
the light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has 50 thicker steel
poles and carries two times more weight
than the standard grow tents coupon code
mr growit will get you a discount on
their products and i'll leave a link to
their website down in the description
section below dutch pro is a sponsor of
the podcast coupon code
mrgrow10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mrgrowit10dp
for a discount on their products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with the
rookie grower how you doing today
i'm doing great how are you i'm doing
good good thanks for asking i'm gonna
get into some beginner gardening type
stuff today so super excited for this
one you know on the podcast i know you
tune in every now and then a lot of
intermediate advanced style stuff so i
definitely want to have an episode where
kind of bring it back and get back to
the basics back to the fundamentals you
know a lot of people that watch me that
are new to growing right they're on
their first grow second grow i get
people all the time that comment and say
i just planted my seeds you know what do
i do next type thing or a lot of people
ask me what problems will i run into and
that's kind of what we're going to get
into today i thought that would be a
good episode to talk about
problems that frequently occur when
gardening and not only that but
solutions you know what you can do to
prevent those problems from happening in
the future so i thought you'd be a good
candidate to have on here today but
before we actually get into the nitty
gritty of things can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
sure so as you all know i'm trg my name
is mark i'm a canadian
i'm a medical license holder
and i started growing around uh three
years ago and it was legalized in canada
and in my spare time i work on my
youtube channel
and uh yeah so once it was legalized i
started uh realizing that i could grow
for myself as i needed medicine just
like everybody else and as we all know
it can get quite pricey when you're when
you're buying it
so i decided to start growing for myself
and
i did my first grow
and it actually went very well i got
about eight ounces off four plants and i
figured that was pretty good for my
first row so i figured hey this is easy
i got this locked up
listen nah
so i went into my second row yeah no
i got like maybe four ounces and it
wasn't very good it wasn't very good at
all so
kind of a little bit discouraged and
said well let's do it again did a third
one still no
stop making mistakes still screwing up
so i was starting to get frustrated this
time
so by that time i'm kind of like well
what am i going to do and through all
these girls so far it's just been autos
that i've been doing i haven't done any
photos yet so i decided i was going to
try photos because i read that they are
a little bit more accepting to mistakes
and you know you're stressing out the
plant and they have time to recover from
that stuff so that's when i decided to
finally try photos and
lo and behold they went through fine
i had a couple times that looked
stressed out but i ended up getting 11
ounces off them and it was a fairly
decent grow
so now i'm into my second girl for uh
for photos and uh it's going very well
actually awesome awesome so what would
you say your overall grow style is i
mean are you into a grower outdoors do
you grow in soil or cocoa or hydroponics
uh my girl style i am an indoor grower i
tried outdoors that went horrible
so when i did that i decided to look at
this focus on the indoor focus on the
basics
get the basics down and then we'll worry
about the outdoors after so
besides that a growing soil i like to
get it just a basic soil with some of
them with the mycorrhizae in it
i do my dry amendments in it
and yeah that's about it it's just in
soil i've started in soil i like soil
and i'm not saying i'm never going to
try anything else but uh i don't know
dwc scares the hell out of me
so indoor grower tell us a little bit
about your current growth setup i mean
what size growth space are you working
in what do you got for lighting do you
have any automation so on and so forth
uh my current growth i'm growing in a
4x4 tent and i have a cmh15 i'm still
rocking that thing
and i got a unit farm uf 3000 that they
sent to me to try out
so that's my light system and i just set
up blue mats i got into the watering
automation and i'm kind of liking that
and i know you just started it so i
don't know how you're liking them so far
yeah i've been using them for a couple
years now actually on and off a little
bit yeah i i used them a while back i
had some issues with over watering i
think i think the medium was just too
saturated and then i added the blue mats
in so it's kept that saturation rate
which was like too much
yeah so kind of getting into problems i
mean it's a perfect transition you know
one of the first things is watering that
we want to talk about when we talk about
problems and you know blue mats
definitely can be a hands-off thing i
actually just installed blue masks this
morning on my current grill and i
watered the plant a couple days ago so i
got nice and saturated the way i like it
not over saturated but
waited a day or two and then sucked the
blue mats in there and now i'm at the
point where i'm gonna
you know doing those little adjustments
to make sure that's dialed in and not
it's not just dripping down more than it
needs to so yeah yeah i'm in the same
stage i'm adjusting small adjustments
you know watching the drip and making
sure it's not dripping too much what
about other problems with watering i
mean you were doing hand warning before
this do you have anything to kind of
talk about with uh problems with
watering
i was just horrible i'm a horrible water
i went from over watering to
underwatering back to over watering i'm
like man what am i doing i just i just
this current grow i just killed six
seedlings because i just i sprayed them
too much i'm like what am i doing
come on but i kind of i'm happy that
that happened because i kind of lit a
fire under my butt to say you know what
let's start getting a little bit more
serious about this because and i can see
it now now it's getting better
my girl is looking fantastic right now
and uh
but yeah again my mostly i've been over
watering it's my biggest problem
it's so easy to over water it and you
know yes
we can you could talk about the whole
finger technique in there you know your
first
finger knuckle down if it's completely
bone dry at that point then there's
watering and then lifting the grill pot
to check the weight you know there's
different techniques you can do but
particularly in the solo solo cups it's
so easy to just over water those plants
and unfortunately if you've if you stunt
the plant within the first
seven days of grow like you could
literally plant new seeds and those new
seeds would
grow faster than the stunted plants so
there has been grows where i've over
watered solo cups and had to start over
you know it's some people would say just
start over at that point but yeah it
could certainly be tricky on that i
don't know
i seem to do better once i get into the
bigger pots and then i'm able to water
and judge better but it's the small ones
that throw me off what i like to use i
like uh i like using a turkey baster
it's just a small turkey baster
and uh one or two squirts and that's it
and i just leave it alone for four or
five days and check on them yeah that's
a good technique and i know you know if
you're starting in the bigger pots kind
of watering directly around the seedling
and just kind of doing that circular
motion that's helpful as well because
certainly if you just have a seedling
within the first week or two
and you're in a five gallon container
for example or a larger container you
don't need to soak the whole grill pot
you know what i mean you're spending
seven ten fourteen days for that thing
to dry out and you could easily stunt
the plant if that medium is
oversaturated so yeah for sure for sure
yeah what else with watering anything
uh well again like i said i went from
over watering to underwatering where i
was waiting too long in between and then
they were drying out too much so that
was kind of a problem
corrected it and i started overwatering
again so
i feel like underwatering is you know
less
less impactful i mean you'll see the
droop and you easily recover off of it
luckily depending on how old the plant
is and so on and so forth you know if
you have a small seedling that could the
medium dries up the whole thing would
die you know the whole plant could die
pretty pretty easily there if you have a
larger plant you know in the vegetation
stage you know you see that major droop
to the point where you know you might
open up your grow tent once the light
comes on and it looks like the plant's
dead but you water it and you know a
couple hours later it's back up to
normal so yeah yeah for sure yeah it can
totally be be tricky but with a little
bit of practice you can definitely dial
things in i have been um you know i've
grown in solo cups to start
four inch nursery pots so they've ran a
little bit smaller than uh solo cups
though
i'm finding myself planting now in one
gallon containers more and more just
starting out in one gallon containers
you know there's just it seems to be a
little bit more beneficial in my opinion
i mean i'm able to have that initial
saturation to the way i like it at the
transplant less you know what i mean in
a sense not as would say not as often
but it takes me a little while till i
have to actually transfer
comparison to a when i'm in a solo cup
at the transmit sooner is what i'm
trying to say i just tried putting
starting them and that's the ones i
killed i started doing the one gallons
and i killed them oh really
yeah wow because i was thinking the same
lines as you i said well i'd rather
start it in the one gallon and give it
more room for the roots to expand right
away you know instead of these little
solo cups and waiting for it to
but it didn't work out wow yeah
yeah i guess you know a little bit of
practice and experience yeah
you figure it out you know for sure for
sure
now how about nutrients i mean feeding
nutrients is another thing where people
have a lot of problems with are you a
bottle grower or you do organics
you know what problems have you come
across there
i started the bottles and i always felt
like i was under feeding
they always looked faded they all you
know i just i found i wasn't feeding
them enough and probably just because i
didn't know when they were supposed to
be fed right
and so this is this current grow i just
switched to gaia green and i'm loving it
i love the dry amendments i love just
amending my soil and you leave it alone
for whatever three weeks and you top
dress or you transplant and you mend it
again
so but uh this is probably the best my
girl has ever looked since i started so
i really love the guy i agree i think a
problem with the dry amendments that
people come across a lot is they
will they switch from bottles to the dry
amendments
and they don't realize that the medium
should be saturated at all times that
you don't have that dry out period that
often people do with synthetics right
normally you would water the pot
let the medium dry out then re-water
like with synthetics with uh you know
organics you need that saturation
because microbes need to be active
microbes aren't active they go dormant
into a sleep state if the medium is dry
so having the medium
wet not wet i don't know what's kind of
a bad word with saturated i guess you
could say right or maybe even saturated
might be it might be
a bad word to use i think moist moist
moist there we go moist so it's moist to
the point where microbes can be active
and even that top layer right that's one
of the first things like if you don't
have your organics that don't have a
mulch layer for example when that grow
lights beaming down on that one of the
first things to dry out is that top
layer and that's where your dry
amendments are right when you're doing
the chop dressing so spraying the top of
the medium in order to keep it moist is
a common practice that people do in
order to avoid that from happening you
know yeah something i'm doing now is i'm
using rice halls as a mulch to try and
help keep the moisture in the soil
so i find that's been helping
nice nice yeah i use barley straw also
cover crops is another thing that can be
used to kind of help maintain the
moisture level down there yeah i plan on
getting into all that stuff baby steps
right
exactly while it costs you know money
and it's time i got to learn yep yep
now how about ph you know ppm ec you
know back when you would were you doing
that stuff when you did synthetic bottle
nutrients or yeah i was i was watching
my ppms a lot and i was watching my ph
but i had cheap amazon
ph pens and ppm pens
so i'm i'm pretty sure that my ph pen
kept going off and i was having a lot of
ph issues now i just bought uh what an
i think that's the uh the brand yep i
just bought that one so
i'm liking that one so far yeah i have
the apparel one there's actually several
different models for a pair yeah i
highly recommend
a pair as well rather than those cheap
ones and also
definitely recommend keeping your ph
meter in storage solution you know those
those probes will dry out
you know if you're spending 75
on a ph pen and it's dead within a year
because you don't put it in storage
solution well you can try to clean the
warranty on it you know the one-year
warranty or whatever but for the mo
that's still a pain to go through that
whole process but keeping it in storage
solution is definitely one of those
things that i feel like is a must
well that's the thing right because you
get the one from amazon the cheap one
you don't get no no kind of solution so
it's just starting whatever yep now do
you check the were you checking the ph
of the nutrient solution going in or the
runoff or were you doing a slurry test
or how would you kind of track ph
i was doing both i was making sure my
water's ph was six three to six five and
then i would check my runoff as well
just to make sure this trying to get the
run off of the story of the ph of the
soil
so that's what i was doing and it was
kind of working i was getting it for a
little bit but it just
it's not my style
yeah it's not
you know it gives you a general idea of
what the ph is you know particularly
we're talking about the runoff right
there have been people who have hit me
up in the past that say you shouldn't be
checking right off you should be doing a
slurry test instead or getting a probe
right he actually said that uh checking
the runoff was the wrong way to do it
which
you know that's an alternate way to do
it
it's an alternate way to do it it's
going to give you a general idea of what
the ph is in that in the medium you can
do a slurry test for sure just take some
of the medium out of the top of it mix
it in with some distilled water
then check the ph that way or get one of
those probes right those those probe
soil probes that go into the actual soil
blue lab has one but they're what like
165 are pretty pricey yeah i think
doesn't appear have one too
i think they do yeah i think they might
they might have one of those as well
now ppm or ec were you tracking those at
all uh i was watching my ppm
for my nutrients when i was mixing my
water
and that was about it i didn't i don't
know much about ec yet i'm still
getting there
but yeah i was i was just moderning my
ppns in my water
would you also do a runoff to kind of
check check it or what um no yeah that's
right i was checking my runoff for ppn
as well and i was using that to
determine when i should feed
and i don't know if that was the best
way to be doing it but
the general way to do it a lot of people
do it that way i still do it that way
you know i don't want to spend 100
whatever dollars for that soil probe to
kind of get a more accurate way when you
know the runoff method that's cheaper
way and you get a general idea of what
it is so i still do it but there is a
lot of guessing
when you're doing that right because you
have to
you know you get that runoff measurement
let's say hypothetically it's the
runoff's 500
and you're aiming for
a thousand that's right so what do you
do for your mixture you have to
have a solution
some people would do a solution that's a
thousand ppm and then put it in there
that's the wrong way to go about it
because you already have
roughly 500 ppm that's right in your
medium right so you would add it to it
so your ppm coming out should be around
1500. now again this is just a you know
gives you a general range
you could check the runoff and it could
be
way above that or below that it's really
tough and then you have to kind of
guesstimate you know because if you're
doing that
feeding when the soil dries out you
gotta factor in how many nutrients the
plant has up taken right so if your last
runoff measurement was 800
and you let the soil dry out you know
three four days later well it's still
not going to be it's not going to be 800
at that point right
it's used up some of the nutrients that
are already in the soil exactly so you
got to kind of guesstimate on that
avenue so i see a lot of people running
into that as a problem wish there was a
better solution out there you know i
wish those probes were cheaper but
unfortunately this is kind of where
we're at at this point
there'll be something that comes along
yeah yeah for sure how about
transplanting you ever had any problems
doing transplanting
no i'm actually not that i'm an expert
at it but i do pretty well at
transplanting um
no real issues uh i got my method where
i just i make my mold in my soil i get
my plants or my soil already ahead of
time i take an empty container and i put
the soil in around it and then i just
pull up this and it just pops right into
the hole so
yeah besides that no real no real issues
i think a common problem is
knowing when to transplant you know
there's some general guides out there
like if you're in a solo cup for example
what i've heard multiple times you know
i've heard and kind of go by sometimes
is this the earliest to transplant is
when the leaves kind of reach the cup
yeah i feel like grow and they re they
reach the outer edges of the cup i feel
like that's the earliest time you should
transplant you know let it grow more
than that you could have a more dense
root ball that helps keep that medium
compact i have come across i've
transplanted before where i go to
transplant all of a sudden the medium
crumbles up because the root zone isn't
established you know so kind of knowing
when to transplant i feel like can be
difficult and i've popped plants out of
you know slowly gently brought it out to
see if there was a root zone that's
developed and then kind of i say oh no
not really want to be it slide it back
in so you can certainly do that if
you're a beginner and you're not really
sure if the root ball has developed or
not i've seen a lot of guys use uh
the clear solo cups and they'll put that
inside another solo cup so that then
they can just pull it out just to see
how the roots are that's a great great
call out right there yeah having that
clear cup within another cup uh it is
important to have the just not have a
clear cup because
light hitting the roots no bueno
not good at all um and also algae's a
thing that people can come across as
well right if light penetrates down
there and it's you know saturated medium
algae can certainly grow so yeah there's
two reasons why i kind of have a dark
container i know i was looking at thc
titans instagram page and this was
several months ago and some company made
white
fabric grow pots
and the thing was just loaded with algae
all around because the light was
piercing through that grill pot yeah you
know so that's that's a huge i don't
even know why the company made made a
white grill pot they weren't thinking or
something but but yeah that those are a
couple problems that happened with
transplanting that i've come across or
seen yeah that's a little weird to go
white
yeah
how about training plants a lot of
people do training whether it be you
know topping low stress training you
know super cropping what training do you
do and what problems have you kind of
come across
uh in the past i've mostly just just
gently bent them over
i used to call it super cropping but
somebody told me no that's not super
cropping so i wasn't super cropping
but i tried with the tie downs and uh
what else was i trying
i think that's all i tried before oh i
tried topping but i didn't do a lot of
topping i just topped a couple just grow
that i'm doing now now i've talked i
talked like almost everyone that came up
so this is the first time we're really
topping and i have canopy clips which
i'm using to spread out the plant which
they're great i recommend them for
anybody canopy clips are awesome
and that way you don't have to worry
about tying it down with wires and stuff
like that
i like those canopy clips problems that
i've come across while snapping branches
i think you know when you're low stress
training snapping that branch that's
usually a heartbreaker you know
manipulating that the top part of the
branch is one way to go about it usually
the top right branch is a little bit
softer i know if you bring your temps
real low you know real low the
60s degree fahrenheit in the 50s those
branches will kind of harden up less
chances of being able to manipulate
those plants you know bend those plants
without them snapping sure your
temperatures are in check it could be a
good solution when tying down i use the
wire ties and i have like a clip that
kind of clips the pot and then use the
wire ties i had there has been times
where i've actually you know tied it
down and the branch
grew
into the tie yeah i've seen that too
yeah yes i've had that happen before i
try to do just a loop around so i don't
actually like
tie like yeah it's just kind of like a
little hook yeah yeah kind of hook but
even if it's wrapped around twice it'll
kind of unwind you know what i mean
versus you know like a bread like when
you're doing like a bread tie
yeah you know twisting it together so i
avoid twisting it together at all costs
in order to prevent the branch from
growing into the tie
something else i've seen other guys
starting to use is i think they're
called
uh i can't remember now grass clips or
something like that they're about
three inches long and
that's all you do is you just push it
down into the soil with the branch in it
and it just pushes it down
instead of using the ties right okay
yeah yeah i've seen those i can't
remember what they're called yeah now do
you do any super cropping at all or no
i tried
like i said the guy one guy told me that
i was doing it wrong and
i guess i was because he was saying you
could do that big pinch and you got to
get at the bend over i wasn't doing that
i was just gently bending them over
but uh the tip that he did give me was
to water your plants 12 hours in advance
he said it helps loosen them up and that
way you can bend them a little bit
easier
yeah yeah that's a good one as well and
then silica as well will help with yes
kind of branch manipulation if you're
using silica definitely helps when
training plants yeah i got silica in
there right now
nice nice yeah i've been using it for
ibm how about controlling environment
you know easier said than done right i
mean remember the first time i ever set
up a grow tent you know i thought it was
going to be easy to get the temperature
stable i thought it was going to be easy
to get the humidity where i wanted it to
be then you add in the exhaust fan and
all of a sudden it sucks out all the
humidity out of the tent yeah exactly
out of the tent or you put your hps grow
light in there and
the temperature skyrockets you know what
do you do to control the environment to
kind of help stabilize your conditions
uh the biggest thing that i well i just
upgraded my exhaust van i ended up
buying an ac infinity uh
t6
so that thing's amazing
one punch of a button and you can
control your environment this is the
most control i've ever had over my
environment
but i'm pretty lucky where i am because
my relative humidity is roughly around
60 my house anyways so the only thing
i'm using right now is a humidifier i
don't use a dehumidifier i don't use a
heater i don't use ac i don't have to
use any of that stuff so just my natural
environment just is very ideal
for what i'm doing so
uh besides that
lots of fans i got all these different
fans that i use uh ipad stands so that
way i can put them at different levels
and you just put plop the fan on top of
it
so i got about four or five fans going
to keep the airflow and just i have one
blowing right on the lights to try and
reduce the the temperature
and yeah that's about it really oh and i
have a fan blowing air into my tent
through the through the bed okay yeah
it's definitely some good techniques in
order to help control the environment i
also have the ac infiniti fan
it's such a game changer isn't it it is
it is
it's awesome i have you know certain set
points so when the temperature reaches i
think i have one set to 82 degrees
fahrenheit
once it reaches that it'll start to you
know the fan will slowly turn on yeah
and then
exhaust some of that hot air you know
and exchange the air as well obviously
if it's removing some of the air and
then once the temperature drops down
because the air coming in from the
intake vent on my grotesque cooler it's
cooler so it does drop it humidity i
live in a very dry environment so i do
have humidifier i have in my fire in my
tent i have humidifier outside of my
tent in order to try to make sure that
the air coming into the tent is of the
proper humidity now back in the day i
used to struggle because
you know my natural humidity is
20 30 yeah you know so it's like
even if if i only have a humidifier
inside my grow tent well that's fine
it'll boost it up to where it needs to
be but once that
inline fan kicks on ac infinity well
it's bringing in
20 to 30 humidity you know so having
making sure that i have a humidifier
outside just in my grow room
yeah as well
is definitely helpful for sure
yeah yeah yeah to have one in your lung
room that helps out lung room yeah
that's what i mean by that yep how about
the seedling stage any problems in
particular we'll go through the
different stages we'll start with
seedling then we'll go into veg then
we'll go into flowering
well see if we can stage besides i kill
them
that's that's about it you know
it's just
i struggle with it i struggle at the
beginning i don't know why yet but i
guess because they're so fragile right
it doesn't take much to kill them so
i'm still learning so hopefully
i'll get that under control
yeah i've had problems with frying
seedlings you know particularly with hps
you know back in the day when i was
running hps i you know having that light
too close
yeah you know i used to think the more
light the better well uh no it'll die so
i fried ceilings before because i had
the light too close also on the flip
side having the temperature
of the medium too low has hindered
seedling growth right so particularly in
the winter time you know if you're
putting your solar cups for example if
you put them on the ground or actually
any container on the ground you could
come across where the medium is
too low in temperature it slows down
microbial growth slows down growth just
entirely right so that is definitely
hindered growth i know a lot of people
are basement growers
common mistake for basement growers is
they put it directly on the ground right
and it's just the cold coldness just
completely stunts the plant i mean it's
really bad
i'm in the basement so that's what i do
yeah it gets quite cold where i am like
i'm talking minus 30 minus 40 sometimes
so that basement floor is quite cold
so what do you do i raise them up a
little bit give them about an inch off
the ground
just so that they got airflow underneath
what do you what do you raise it up with
uh i have like crates and stuff like
that
whatever is handy that's whatever i can
use to get up off the ground yeah i've
used like two by fours before and yeah
two but yeah that works too yeah yeah
how about the vegetation stage any
problems come to mind for the vegetation
no not really that's been one of my
stages that i actually do well in
but you know because i
once i get to the vegetative stage i'm
able to start getting into a routine
when i'm watering when am i feeding uh
you know what am i training
and that's probably why i like it
because it's more of a routine rather
than the seasoning stage it's like oh
what do i do
so yeah besides that i have not too many
problems with my vegetative stage
the vegetation you know arguably is one
of the easier stages you know in my
opinion you know especially if you're
growing in a soil that is enriched with
nutrients already right fox motion for
soil i mean that's going to last you
you know roughly 30 40 days depending on
the size of your container so you know
once the plant's out of the seedling
stage it's still got plenty of nutrients
right so you know most people aren't
doing any sort of feeding oh until some
people go all the way 30 40 days and
then put the flowers they don't do any
feeding veg at all
so in my opinion the veg stage is one of
the easier stages one problem that i can
think of is
knowing when to flip to flower
because
you know just the fact that you don't
know how long how much it's going to
stretch
that's cultivar dependent obviously your
lighting is going to impact it your
nutrition all there's so many different
variables that can impact growth i've
had plants that were you know stretched
three times the amount once i flipped to
12 12. and so i ran out of height right
so that's the problem right it stretched
three times the amount i wasn't
expecting that much of a stretch
now my lights all the way up to the the
top what do i do you know then you're
bending branches down yeah that's a
common problem that people actually you
know reach out to me they're like oh
crap i ran out of space you know
what do i do now you know what what are
the options right you're either
you know pruning those branches off
sometimes right if you're like week one
into stretch
or you know you're gonna have a couple
more weeks of growth so literally
pruning branches off that are the top
branches off is an option at that point
without destroying your yield i don't
know you know a lot some people yield is
their goal some people don't but
certainly it could be an impact there
you know the general rule of thumb is
just expect the plant to stretch double
the amount
it is at the time of flip you know yeah
usually for the first three weeks right
but that's not always the case you know
you got you have cultivars that don't
stretch at all yeah i've had cultivars
which i expected them to stretch 2x
and they didn't barely even stretch at
all i'm like oh crap yeah stuck with
this small plant i was expecting it to
stretch so much more and then and then
you're stuck at that point
you know finish growing the plant yeah i
have the same problem i'm never quite
sure when to flip
i'm always kind of guessing
uh how about flowering problems in
flowering what do you got uh
i think my with the flowering
i'm never sure how much to feed that's
that's been my one of my main problems
and i don't know if i was supposed to
increase or
decrease uh yeah i wasn't sure but
besides that it's no different than the
vegetative stage
because you're still in your routine
right you're still you know you're not
doing is really training anymore and
unless like you said it's getting too
close to the light
so yeah for me it's just basically when
the flip and my feeding schedule i
wasn't sure about the feeding schedule
it can be tricky i mean i've had plans
yellow out too early and i think that's
a common problem right when plants start
to yellow you know week four or five and
you're like oh crap why is it starting
to yellow at this point right and that
kind of goes back to the fundamentals
you know if you're growing bottled
nutrients
you know what was the ph what's the ppm
are you in the proper ranges you know
that's right if you're organic growing
well maybe you didn't top dress enough
during that flip like you should have
maybe you're the the the medium is
drying out on the top where your top
dressing amendments are and the microbes
aren't breaking them down you know so
those are things you got to kind of look
at another problem in flowering is you
know when you get to the point where you
are at week five six seven and they
start flopping over right so having
support for plants yeah kind of planning
ahead on that avenue i mean i used to
use tomato cages
okay i don't know if you've ever tried
to put a tomato cage on a plant that's
in week six or seven and flowering like
trying to
to put it above it's just it's so
difficult so you know planning ahead
making sure you have like a trellis net
for example a lot of people use chelsea
for support not just to get a high yield
but using it as support stakes are good
to have on hand for support some people
use those yo-yos and they hang them from
above and they come down and help
support those branches above some people
use like those bamboo stakes and now
they'll kind of square them in similar
to how a tomato cage is so there's so
many different ways you can go
when it comes to supporting your plants
and make sure the branches stay upright
and also you know other things look at
calcium you know silica can help with
with the cell structure and keeping the
plants upright um but yeah i think
that's a common problem is plants
flopping all over the place towards the
end of flowering yeah yeah i had that
problem last time too it was uh they
were falling over so i was tying the
little strings from the corners to the
to the plants and trying to get them to
stay up and
they were stolen
i guess that's a good problem right and
these are getting heavy so
yeah i've had branches like snap too
yeah like really yeah snap completely
it's like what the heck so i had to
harvest at that time yeah it was a
pretty pretty clean snap too it's like
you know you could try to tape it up but
this one wasn't wasn't able to recover
at that point so um oh what about
lighting i know lighting's a huge one i
mean with these new grow lights people
are burning their plants people don't
know what the correct light distance is
with the dimmer and stuff have you come
across any problems with lighting and
like light distance and all that stuff
um just uh
trial and error was learning where to
put my light because like i said i'm
still rocking the cmh so i don't have a
dimmer on it okay so i'm just going by
measuring how far it is and just looking
at how there's the plants are responding
to it if they're looking a little bit
droopy or looking a little stressed it's
time to raise the light of it or just
either start the stretch well maybe it's
time to lower the light a bit i feel
like it's easier in that sense growing
with hid whether it be hps mh or cmh is
like distance because it's pretty pretty
standard in a sense right like was it 12
to 14 inches for flowering
18 to 20 inches
yeah you know 24 to 36 inches for
seedlings that's pretty standard you
know it's a led i mean you got to worry
about the dimmer if you want to use that
and then also the the distance on top of
that so i actually have a whole video on
kind of how to determine like distance
using the dimmer on your grill lights so
if you guys want to check that out on my
channel just search for it and you'll
you'll find it and gives you some
additional tips on what you can do to
dial in that light distance so nice yeah
no i was just going to say i i will be
having those kind of problems because i
am upgrading my lights
yep soon enough you'll face it yeah it's
coming
yeah light burning is like just the
number one thing i mean people are just
yeah they're putting their girl lights
too close too high of intensity
yeah it's just it looks like other it
looks like other issues too like it
looks like calcium deficiency a lot of
people mistake it for
really it's just
you're burning your plants you know
calcium deficiency you'll see the rust
spotting you know on the leaves
you'll kind of see that only kind of be
a different pattern with the light burn
but you'll notice it more on the top
part of the plant and you also you
notice like more yellow margins on the
leaves and like the leaves will you know
potentially start curling you know up up
or down like burnt
looking burnt in a sense that's kind of
how you know you have light burn versus
calcium deficiency
yeah i've seen that
yeah
how about pests any problems with pests
uh the only biggest problem i've had so
far knock on wood because
yeah i know it's it's gonna come it's
gonna happen so the only problem i've
had is with fungus gnats
and uh what i use for ipm is uh like i
said i use uh diatomaceous earth
what i like to do on whether just a top
dress
i've seen guys put it right all over
their flowers i don't know if that's the
right way to do it or not but when do
you apply the diatomaceous earth on that
medium
um usually i
amended it when i first
amended my soil when i was first
starting and then when i transplant it i
did it again
so probably when i top dress i might do
it again i'm not sure
okay yeah funky snacks is something i
battle with as well you know once in a
while
i feel like those are one of the easiest
pests to to get rid of i mean yeah
number one yellow sticky traps is what i
usually use and have those by the medium
so you can kind of see if you have the
problem
that's right you know and then letting
the medium dry out is another way to go
about it you know particularly with the
synthetic nutrients right you yes you
can have the medium kind of dry out and
then the fungus gnats go away in my
experience and sometimes you need to let
the medium dry out multiple times before
they truly go away because you've got
the eggs hatching down there and all
that stuff now when you're with or
organics you know people would argue
that you should never have the medium
dry out however if you're in a desperate
situation to where you've got an
infestation of fungus gnats and they're
destroying your plant well then you
might want to you know last yeah last
stitch effort you might want to let that
medium dry out or do that diatomaceous
earth like like you do which i i haven't
used myself my heart is extremely
effective
it is yes i recommend it for anybody any
other problems with pests at all i know
you've been growing for
he about three years
and no that's been about it uh there's
one time i thought i had spider mites
but i didn't i was just
being foolish
it was actually a mold from uh
you know mushroom mycelium sorry
mycelium it's like everybody's like no
no that's not fungus or it's not uh
spider mites it's just mycelium yeah yep
now how about harvesting
any problems with harvesting what do you
usually do for harvesting
uh harvesting i uh i usually chop my
plant down a hole i don't do individual
branches and i hang it up like that
and just this past grows when i first
start i started using um
hanging in my tent
so and i found that gave me a lot more
control over my environment that way
instead of hanging in a utility closet
with you know no fans no humidifier or
anything like that
so
i i got a good dry out of it the last
time i probably got about like 14 days a
good two weeks so i was quite pleased
with that but besides that it's just uh
after that then i do individual branches
of just trimming and
i trim with the scissors i don't have
any fancy machines
i do the old-fashioned trimming
and i i enjoy trim jail just like
everybody else
i think a common problem with harvesting
is
folks don't know when to harvest or they
harvest too early
you know i mean investing in that
microscope to see the color of the
tricoms is definitely a beneficial and
now most of the time a lot of folks have
good smartphones where you can
take a close-up picture of the plant of
the bud
and then zoom into that picture to see
the color of the trichomes so i can do
that on my phone i have the the pixel 5.
my roommate has a samsung is actually i
i think looks better than mine i'm sure
i have an iphone his stellar camera on
that one so a lot of people don't even
need the mic microscope anymore you know
yeah i got the same i got the samsung
and it has an incredible camera it's
unbelievable
yeah so microscopes are about to be
obsolete when it comes to thanks
checking the trichomes soon huh i think
so yep i've been knowing when to harvest
i mean you know the color of the
trichomes is something that people look
at
mostly cloudy is what i aim for
at that point there is some amber in
there some people look for a certain
percentage of amber
i don't really go by that i mean i think
when the trichomes are mostly cloudy
that might be you know ten percent amber
or something like that yeah but it
really comes down to personal preference
on when you want to harvest
for sure
for sure for sure and that's generally
what i look i look about for 80 to 20 80
to 20
roughly it's
whatever happens sometimes you just have
to like you said before sometimes you
just have to harvest it it doesn't
matter what the trichomes look like
now i know you touched a little bit on
drying dive a little bit deeper into
that so dry environment i know i use a
grow tent mostly i mean i've dried in
closets before i've drafted bathrooms
before driving regular bedrooms before
but uh being able to have that proper
temperature and humidity during drying
as well is arguably just as important if
not more important than the temperature
humidity when you're growing the plant
right
absolutely absolutely yeah what do you
aim for for temperature and humidity
when drying i i go with the 60 60 method
60 humidity 60
that's
that's why how i got it the last time
and it was uh
probably the best harvest i've had
more and more people go into the 60 60
route you know i generally do 55 to 60
rh and then i try to get down to 60. you
know room temperature around 70 degrees
fahrenheit is acceptable for sure one
could argue against 60 degrees versus 70
degrees now we know terpenes evaporate
at different temperatures so one could
argue that hey if you're drying at 70
degrees well then some of those terpenes
are evaporating versus you know 60
degrees you're having less terpenes
evaporate so i've been finding myself
trying to get the temp lower and lower
to achieve that 60 but i don't really
beat myself up you know from around 70.
it's i
start to panic a little bit when i'm at
like
over 75 you know then i'm like oh great
good now i really should be taking
actions in order to try to get that
temperature down because again terpenes
are evaporating at different
temperatures you're just losing it and
that that smell and the flavor as well
oh yeah for sure
and then making sure there's air
exchange in the environment right so
there should be exchange shouldn't be
stagnant i think you mentioned that you
have a fan in there to kind of make sure
air is blowing around
you can easily if you have stagnant air
in there you could easily get mold you
know
especially if you're running 60 rh you
know that plus stagnant air that's a
recipe of a disaster right
there now it's happened to me before you
know accidentally but making sure
there's a certain exchange now i usually
trying to grow tent and sometimes i'll
keep that grow tent cracked open so that
way you know there is some exchange i
make sure it's dark as well right light
shouldn't be shining on your plants
while they're drying because light uh
degrades those trichomes right yeah my
tent my 4x4 is kind of one of those
knock-off ones so i do have light leaks
so i i put a blanket over it to block it
because i only have one dollar entrance
so i put a blanket right over it to
block it where the zippers are so it
seemed to help last time how about
curing last but not least curing another
thing that i feel is overlooked often oh
have you had any problems with curing
uh again just only problems just from
learning right it's not because i had
any major issues
but
i do the cure i do the uh the burping to
twice a day for for a week and then down
to once a day for another week and then
after that
i might still burp once here and there
but then you kind of start just letting
them sit and be
just let them cure for as long as you
can without smoking it
i think it's very important to make sure
that just the humidity is not too much
in the container i mean i
highly recommend buying
spending the money to get hygrometers
right you can get a 12 pack of those
little hygrometers the digital i got
some of those that fit in the jars we
get i think they're like probably 20
bucks or something like that for a
12-pack
i highly recommend you you get that and
and monitor that because
if the humidity is too high in the
container mold mold occurs you know and
you've ruined your harvest at that point
that's right so spending the twenty
dollars on the hygrometers for your jars
i think is a must in my opinion
absolutely oh yeah i got them i use
those as well yeah so what other advice
do you have for growers who are
just getting started with growing
uh what i would say is first of all be
patient
you're gonna make a mistake you're gonna
make lots of them
and uh just don't freak out if things
aren't going right uh you know most
people start growing and they're
following somebody on youtube
some kind of content creator well reach
out to them the
most of them have discords or even just
on the videos themselves in the comments
like just reach out to them and ask them
the question
there's not too many that don't want to
help that's basically why we're all here
right is to help other people learn how
to grow so
uh yeah most definitely just be patient
and don't be afraid to ask for help and
yeah just research read
research watch
and
get a mentor if you can
that's always helpful
to have somebody to show you what to do
and how to do it
because
learning on your own it's fun but
you make a lot of mistakes
i think that's really great advice yeah
you touched on a lot of good good pieces
there for sure so wrapping things up how
can listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future well
everybody can find me obviously on
youtube as the rookie grower i'm on
instagram as uh the underscore rookie
grower all underscore or sorry all
lowercase letters and i'm also on
twitter
the rookie grower all capital
so uh besides that what do i have
currently i'm working on uh it's called
my chaotic run
and it's a uh i'm showcasing a breeder
i i've got a few of them coming up where
i'm
showcasing their cultivars on my channel
and i'm just doing i just have totally
dedicated to it to their cultivars
and so i got two more after this one and
then after that well
it's on to bigger and better things uh
mr grove exclusive i'm expanding my grow
room
nice
yeah awesome well i will provide a link
to the rookie growers channel down in
the description section below if you
enjoyed this video click that thumbs up
button also drop a comment let us know
what advice you have for beginners also
what problems you've come across and
what you've done to combat those
problems if you're tuning in on apple
podcast please leave a rating and review
and of course subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already i release a new
episode every single weekend garden talk
with mr grow at podcast i just want to
take this opportunity to thank you for
having me on the show it's a great honor
i've watched your stuff for quite a
while so it's
quite a pleasure to meet you no problem
thanks for coming on really appreciate
you coming on and
sharing your knowledge with the audience
here so
thanks again and i hope you enjoy the
rest of your day
right on thank you
you