Welcome to the Garden Talk podcast,
where we interview growers from all over
the world, both beginners and experts,
seeking to learn more about what they
know about gardening and how they do
things in their garden. What's up
everybody? For those of you who don't
know me, my name is Chris aka Mr. Growit
and you're tuned into the Garden Talk
podcast. This episode number 168. In
this episode, I interview Francisco
Sasso. He has been gardening for 15
years and works for Dutch Passion. He
gets deep into genetics here with a
focus on talking about some of the best
outdoor genetics. We also get a little
bit into how he grows his plants
outdoors. If you want to see short clips
of these podcast episodes, search garden
talk clips on YouTube. I also have a
gardening channel where I show the
plants that I grow. Both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below. One
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public. That being said, I'd
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who help make that goal
possible. Thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode. Check out their
cultivator kit, which is a complete grow
tank kit that features integrated AI
controls with precision equipment,
Athena simplified fertilizers, and a
voucher for Jungle Boy's genetics.
There's more to it, so click the link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about their cultivator kit,
and the discount code Mr. Growit 15
works on both Amazon and their website,
acinfiniti.com. Stash Blend. Several
additives in one blend, so you no longer
have to buy individual bottles. Check it
out at
stashblend.com. Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the
stash. And we are back and I'm joined
with Francisco Sasso from Dutch Passion.
How you doing today? Hi Chris, thank you
very much to invite us to your podcast.
We we follow you. Thanks for coming on.
This should be an exciting one today.
Today we're going to talk about some of
the best outdoor genetics. Let's get
into some that can give big harvests,
consistent yields, and high quality. We
also may get into some tips for growing
them outdoors. But first, can you tell
us a little bit about yourself and how
you got into gardening? Yeah, I'm you
I'm from Italy. You know, I work uh in
the for the company for dash patient
from 10 years already and uh I started
growing uh when I was more or less 16.
So I started quite early uh because
there uh where where I born you know
like when I grown up uh was difficult to
find a good products around you know to
to consume. So uh I come from from a
small village uh close to the mountains
in in the north of Italy. Uh so what we
did is that we start collecting seeds.
The first seats that were sell sold by
by by resellers in uh in Italy uh from
Amsterdam were the seeds. So actually my
my first plants my first sister that I
bought uh were were dash patient you
know then uh years later I I I start
working with the with the company and uh
and we were growing guerillas. So we
were growing in the mountains up to the
mountains uh outdoor and and from that
on you know I start to be really
passionate on growing because uh you you
never forget your first harvest you know
and your first plant and then you get
really really enthusiastic to uh to the
crop to the plant you know and that's uh
that's that's where where where
everything started for me. That's
awesome. Yeah. It's so exciting.
Exactly. And when you see the size the
size just the way it grows when the
flowers get on there it's just it's
incredible. Even to this day, I still
get excited growing out different
genetics cuz there's there's a variety
in these genetics and some grow better
in some areas than other areas, which
we're going to get into here in a
minute. So, overall your growth style,
are you 100% outdoors or do you do some
indoor growing as well? No, I started as
an outdoor grower, you know, like uh for
necessity, let's say. And and I keep for
me it's quite romantic, you know, like
to grow outdoor, you know, to see the
plants with the wind, you know, outside,
you know, kissed by the sun, you know,
like and and also growing like with a
huge sites, you know, like you can
really reach a big yielding outside uh
growing outdoor uh and it's also really
clean products. But uh uh then I started
you know to to to to do my my
experiments indoor uh and and and then I
I I became also really passionate about
indoor growing because you can really
control well uh the condition indoor.
You can really you can keep mothers you
can keep the genetics you know you can
uh you can you can start breeding you
know like you can start playing with the
genetics. So, uh I I I I I still grow
both uh you know like uh and more than
outdoor uh I became like more a
greenhouse uh glass house uh grower. Um
but uh yeah I'm I'm I'm both you know
like uh still uh still mainly growing
indoor uh lately you know like uh for
necessity and also because I moved to
Netherland to to Amsterdam where the
company is based uh and also here uh
there is not such a big space to grow
outside and uh and also the climate the
weather we can see later uh why also the
varieties are really really strong the
outdoor varieties breed in in in in in
uh in in Netherland uh the climate the
weather is not so easy uh to grow
outside in here around I can only
imagine how crazy it can be growing
outdoors in that environment are you
soil or cocoa and do you grow with
organic inputs or synthetic inputs yeah
that's um I mostly do cocoa like uh my
favorite mix is between 50% light mix
soil and 50% cocoa that's I really like
because I find benefit from both. So I
can find really nice development of the
roots uh fast development oxygen from
from the from the cocoa but still the
performing wise of the uh of the soil.
Then uh I became really a cocoa lover
you know like if I can say you know like
in indoor uh because also I can control
well my irrigation and watering. Uh but
um yeah, 50% mix. It's my it's my
favorite uh way to to grow. I see my
plants really healthy and um and I'm
more organic growers, you know. I start
with with more synthetics because I had
the feeling that was easier. But
actually then when you start testing and
trying you know you see also that
organic growing it's it's quite easy and
the beneficial from my point of view uh
from my harvest the quality that I got
from from organics uh it's really like a
uh top top notch you know like uh tarpin
wise especially I know a handful of
growers that do just about exactly what
you do where they mix up that soil like
that and getting more oxygen down in the
root zone being a little bit more area
of a medium they can get some really big
yields from it. Now, there's one
question I wanted to ask you up front
here. I want to get your input on. You
working for Dutch Passion, you I know
you have a lot of knowledge in regards
to what people are actually striving
for. It seems like more growers care
less about yield these days and are
really focusing more on quality. What's
your take on that? Yeah, that's that's
really true. depends uh you know like uh
also on the goal that the grower have
you know like uh there are many
commercial grower that sometimes care
more uh on the on the on the quantity
over the quality over the quality but
main you know like step by step the the
culture and the knowledge about if we
see the last 15 years you know grown up
a lot and really fast you know so uh uh
uh uh the the you know the the smoke the
users you know like medical users is not
uh uh is looking for quality you know
like if you do something do it well you
know like consume good products you know
like safe products clean products you
know like uh also because we we all came
from a black market you know so uh
people living in US or many many
countries or Canada where where now it's
in many countries is legalized you know
we come from black market and and and
you know we smoked and we consumed some
really bad bad quality with so people is
going more for the quality than for the
quantity. Then depends also in which
countries because uh in the countries
where is still illegal. So the
commercial grower take a risk to you
know to grow big quantities and then and
then sell uh uh normally they go more
for the for the quantity over the
quality. But the home grower the bical
home growers it's looking for mainly for
the quality than than for the quantity.
Lately we have knowledges and
technologies that can bring us uh to
produce quite high quantity with with
high quality you know so there is like a
good a good mix on on that. So uh but
definitely you know people are really uh
getting high culture on that and uh it's
looking for the top top quality top
quality and clean product. That's really
also like in organic way uh uh they they
look for for for really clean uh clean
products and that's really good. I'm the
same way where I really strive more for
quality versus yield. And back in the
day when I first started growing I was
striving for yield. one of the biggest
plants I can get and get the most yield
that I possibly can, right? But me being
a small home grower only growing for
myself and I can gift here legally, I
can gift to friends and family and stuff
like that. I don't need to grow pounds
and pounds and pounds per cycle. I can
get away with growing really less than a
pound per cycle and that's still enough
for me to consume between when I finish
growing and when I complete my next
grow. So yeah, I totally understand what
you mean how you saying that mostly home
growers are going for that quality side
of things because it's kind of easy to
get the yield in order to last to you.
Exactly. And that depends also on the
genetics you know like there are
genetics that are are are really well
known to be like low yielding but you
know high quality but also some genetics
can give you bigger yielding but still
good quality you know like top quality.
So it depends also on the selection on
how you grow it where you grow it. So
condition is almost really it's it's
really it's really really important on
that. But uh yeah quality quality over
quantity that's been the the the the
tantra in the last in the last years for
sure. Agreed. Now you working for Dutch
Passion one of the things you had
mentioned kind of behind the scenes as
we were exchanging emails is that their
genetics are bred in Holland. Can you
talk to us about kind of what the
climate is there? You know, what those
genetics really get put through? Yeah.
Yeah. We are um you know, Dash was just
to briefly introduce the company for who
uh don't know them. It's it's one of the
pioneer seed bank uh in one of the
oldest seed bankank in the world still
active on on producing seeds. Uh was
founded by Hank Vanalen, a biologist
from from Amsterdam in the 1987.
Uh so he started actually he start his
breathing project started before the
foundation of the of the company. So he
started to travel around in the in the
late '7s uh in places like Afghanistan
uh Colombia, Thailand collecting uh uh
original land race seeds from the land
race of of that countries and then
coming back to to Netherland and
starting you know his breeding project
you know the first experiment you know
because uh there were
already sold by the coffee shops in the
city centers and in the cities of of
Netherland but not so much produced in
Netherland. Main of the product that was
sold in the coffee shops around was
imported by Thailand. They were the
sticky tie. They were we call it like
that because because you know that the
the sides of the of the body were closed
in a in a iron in iron uh to transport
them in the boat like charas from India
uh you know like uh some some extraction
and also flowers from uh from
Afghanistan. So was in South Africa. Uh
uh so he started also with with a with
with with some friends with a group of
friends that are people some of them are
really well known in the in in the
international industry uh because they
they started their own project or
breeding or fertilizers. Anyway, they're
still uh many of them active in in the
industry. So he start to produce uh uh
uh uh uh flowers for the coffee shops.
He he founded a coffee shop that was
called Homegrown Fantasy. homegrown
because was one of the first coffee shop
in the city center selling only Dutch
flowers. So not imported uh uh flowers
and then you know like with with the
knowledge of the uh with the biologist
uh school you know like he started to to
do some testing and breeding and and he
he became like well known in the in the
first network of of Amsterdam. So the
other coffee shop started to ask to Hank
uh like if they can get some seeds
because there were many people in the
coffee shop asking for for the seeds. So
then he realized that could be exist in
a market about seeds you know like so
it's time to to produce seeds to
reproduce and to select the first the
first v and then I connect to uh to to
the main topic that is the the Dutch the
Dutch varieties. So that vis arrives
from old school land races crossed and
selected outdoor in Netherland. That
what it mean that generation after
generation that plants become stronger
to the uh to survive and flower in the
Dutch weather. The Dutch weather for who
don't know it's it's like a really cold
weather. It's a short summertime with a
lot of hours of of of lights during the
day. But in September, so normally when
you you in Europe, you know, in this
atmosphere, you you you harvest in the
late September, beginning of October,
you already have really low temperature,
so cold climate with wet uh wet climate.
So it's really hard to grow outdoor you
know up there you know and it's
Netherland it's all the Nordic country
of of you know also north of
Germany Danish you know like Sweden so
it's all these kind of Nordic countries
uh
so they special create a full family
call it the out the Dutch outdoor family
that are varieties are really vigorous
and strong for the for the extreme
outdoor
weathers as the Dutch the Dutch weather.
So they are more resistant to the mold
for the high temperature for the high
high humidity. Uh they can stand more
for the and they can flower really well
in the also in a cold climate. Of
course, there is some it's not it's not
going to go to to grow strong and well
below zero degrees for example, but they
can really stand on low low temperature
compared to the south of Europe or uh
other like tropical or subtropical uh uh
climates. uh inside of this family there
are some of of the legendary varieties
of dutial like as a durban poison one is
worldwide well known as a nice sativa
from South Africa from the Durban city
uh freezing dew that was at the time was
called in the 80s this v was called
purple star and that was back crossing
with a with a skunk number one so it's a
it's a purple star with um with with a
skunk number one so really old school
and strong uh plant like also with
strange color with nice color like
purple color in that pink purple then
the passion number one that have a cool
story because it's a really fast v
variety you can harvest it in six seven
weeks of flower time for outdoor it's
really suitable and at time was called
in our collection was called this variet
gold uh but then Amstel it's also like a
a brand of a beer the brand of the beer,
you know, like call it Hank say, "Hey,
you cannot call a variety like like our
beer." So he had to call the name,
change the name and he called it Passion
One because was the first variety
developed by Hank in the in the 80s and
still is still available in our in our
catalog. And then we have a Holland
soap. Uh, and a really cool variety that
I always mention is a freezing duck was
the first project of an outdoor variety.
Uh, but
camouflage. So, it's a variety that
until the the the middle of flower time
you don't see and you you don't
recognize the plant as as
as have this duck foot. So, the leaf
looks like a duck only only three point
and it's like a duck foot. uh uh leaf,
you know, like the the sides of the
leaf. And it's really cool. It's it's a
cross between freezing dew and a duck
foot duck foot var like a mutant was the
first project of mutant. So that
varieties can really stand well in the
outdoor growing uh in in good condition
you know like with nice weather and nice
climate condition can grow really
vigorous really strong with high
yielding but can really stand well and
and perform also in a kind of extreme
extreme weather extreme condition. Yeah,
those conditions that you mentioned
there seem like it's very taking the
place through a rigorous time there and
uh I'm sure they're going to be very
vigorous growth comes from being bred in
those type of conditions. Now I got to
imagine since it's being cold, wet, real
high humidity, you mentioned there's got
to be resistance to pathogens like mold,
britis, powdery mildew. That's got to be
what? like your number one thing that
you guys look at when it comes to
selecting genetics. Is that correct?
Exactly. also because outdoor growing
you know like we always say you know
like it's not a science you know like
it's there is many ways you know like we
always say like there's thousand rods to
go to Rome you know like uh there is
many many ways to to grow outdoor to
grow indoor like uh of course but there
are some some common fact you know some
some common conditions that make you uh
uh make you you know to give you the
possibility to harvest a nice quality
weed and and to harvest high quantity
also from from outdoor from outdoor
plant. And one of these is choose
properly the genetics. Not every genetic
is suitable for the for every climate
you know especially in the outdoor
because outdoor is not only growing you
are kind of depending a lot on the
weather and in your climate on the
condition that you are growing. So this
is affect a lot because in in the indoor
you can control your climate you can
control the the weeks of of vegetative
stage or or flower stage. you can
control almost everything in the outdoor
you can control till a point you're
depending a lot you know on on the
external conditions and that's uh uh
that's the challenge that's the
challenge outdoor growing is a whole
different battlefield compared to indoor
growing that is for sure I mean you
pests is another thing where it's like
you have completely different pest
prevention methods that you can take
indoors versus outdoors you kind of be a
little bit more hands-off indoors
versus outdoors. Yeah, it's a good
point, this one. It's a good point. Now,
you mentioned Holland's Hope, buddy of
mine, Pigeons 420. He raves about that
strain. He absolutely loves it. Nothing
but positive things to say about it. So,
eventually I think I'm going to get that
in my garden. Now, if people are growing
in the same climate or they have a
similar conditions to that and they are
striving after yield, for example, what
are some particular strains that you
recommend that they grow out in the
tropical environment? suitable the
mostly sativas we're talking about like
Mexico or the jungle in Colombia or
Thailand you know like close to the
Mechong Meong River for example you know
like all these all these uh uh varieties
uh are mostly sativas with long period
of flower time and not so compact PS you
know that's that's why it's because you
know there is normally high humidity so
it's really wet the air uh and and and
and you know like the mold get inside
easier if your your your your body of
flour is super super compact compact. Uh
then you have the the mostly let's say
indiga. So we bred some varieties like
mazar and master kush for example or
night queen uh that are all coming from
of agony. So we are talking about a
really high temperature so really warm
uh climate and normally especially
during the day dry climate. So these var
varieties are suitable for like more
warmer climate you know like but but
with low uh constantly low uh humidity.
That's also something that uh can help
to the grower you know to choose the
right the right the right variety. Uh
then we have really an interesting
family that it's called the high
altitude varieties that are actually in
our catalog are two it's pomeier gold
and snow bad. Both of them
are breed and and and and producing uh
up to 1,500 mters. So it's for the
mountains for the high altitude. We we
you know we selected that in the Alps of
Switzerland because Netherland doesn't
have um high mountains. Uh so we we did
a a project of breeding uh years ago in
in the Alps of Switzerland and uh we
produced these two var we stabilized
these two varieties really really strong
for the for the high altitude the
growing. So that's to say that I if you
are if if you grow in the mountain
really up to the mountain if if you
don't have certain condition like in
Himalaya or in Nepal you know that you
have some condition where the sativas
the Indian sativas can can grow really
well if you put a strong indica in the
mountain you you you can harvest that
but it's it's it's the hardest you know
like to to you to get a really nice
resin. So the palm gold is not but we're
bred for that. So that that's to to say
that it's not that you cannot give a
chance to this variety in in not in
their in in in in their comfort zone,
but it's always better to choose
something that it's select for for that,
especially for outdoor. And that's
something I don't think we talk about
enough is, hey, when you're selecting
genetics, select genetics that are good
for your climate that you live in. You
mentioned as an indoor grower, sure you
can control those conditions a little
bit more, but it's going to be super
beneficial to really do the research and
figure out what the background is of
those genetics and whether or not it's
applicable to where you're currently
living. Now, I personally live in Las
Vegas, I mentioned before we started
recording, and it's very hot, very dry,
and so you have genetics. Dutch passion
has some genetics that are good for this
particular climate, right? Can you name
off some genetics that are good for
those really warm dry climates? Yeah,
absolutely. Like uh banana blaze is one
of these. It's a banana kush cross with
mazar. The mazar it's our queen of the
indicas bar varieties. really strong
plant uh that the name it's also come
from a village in Afghanistan called
Mazari Sharif you know and that plant
was a land race there in that area that
now it's really hard to get there
because there is a riots there there's
like a fights between different tribus
you know like uh the different
oppositions uh so Hank was there in the
in the 80s collecting that seats and
this is a variety that really can stand
uh like like really in a in a desertic
almost dessert 30 let's say area. So
it's really nice uh it's a good plant
with with a toe leaf you know so really
really fat leaves you know that uh you
know so it can transform easily the
light in the CO2 so uh doing the
photosynthesis so it's it's a plant that
can stand really well on the on the high
temperature then of course as before
there is some there are some extreme
condition that the plants cannot stand
on that you know like if there is 60°
and the plants don't see water for for
for two weeks
plants is going to die for sure, you
know, like but on the category on the
families of this genetics that we offer
that once also the night queen it's
really nice and the master cush it's
it's another really nice plant that can
stand on this kind of uh of condition
course I want to say something that it's
also like uh it's it's a point that we I
think we have to touch because it's it's
the first phase of the plant you know so
it's the the germination and vegetative
stage is a a phase where the plant
uh uh can can suffer more because it's
quite weak at the beginning you know
when when when the roots system it's
already developed you know like and you
put it in the soil on the ground outside
you know then then the plants can can be
strong and can survive also to some uh
disease or or or bad bad condition in
the climate. But when the plant is
small, normally we always recommend to
start growing, germinate and growing,
you know, like indoor or in a in a in a
in a small greenhouse, you know, like
just to get more control in the first
phase of the plant of the vegetative
stage. Yeah, I'm glad you mentioned
that. I know a lot of folks, they start
growing indoors, they'll veg for a
certain period of time and then they'll
transition outdoors for the exact reason
that you mentioned. Now, how long
indoors do you recommend that people veg
for before transitioning those plants to
outdoors? Well, that's depends a little
bit of where and you're going to grow it
and and which residue you want to to
get, you know, like which sides of
plants you want to get. But normally one
month at least, you know, what we
recommend for a a boost the vegetative
stage and we saw co, you know, like
really consistent uh better results and
vigorous plants. It's uh uh uh to
transplant that. So you germinate you
know like in a small pot then after 3
weeks maximum you transplant the plant
in in a 3 lit 4 lit pot and then you
wait a little bit that the that the root
system start to develop a a bit more and
then you can start putting outside the
plants. That's something that really can
help you to have a a stronger plant when
you when when you put them outdoor. That
makes sense. Yeah. I feel like the
longer the plant has been growing, the
more chances it has of survival. Right?
If you're taking a plant and you're you
you have it growing, it sprouts and you
got seven days, it's a little seedling
and you transfer it to outside, it's
going to be a lot less chance that
that's going to survive, especially in
extreme conditions. Exactly. You depend
on the wind, you depend on the weather,
you know, they are like really really
weak at the beginning, you know, like
especially. So also we're not talking
just of course an LED indoor would be
the top notchotch you know like uh
starting point uh but also like a small
greenhouse with some control with some
extra light like simple light like quite
quite cold light like 6,000 Kelvin you
know like nothing special you know like
a without so many vats you know like you
don't need a super technology LED but
just to get the plants used and to be
covered you know to be safe you know to
start to start the process of of of
growing. That's a really good point. I'm
glad you brought that up. Now,
transitioning from the indoors to the
outdoors, some folks will do a hardening
off process, right? They either take
their plant indoors, bring it outdoors
for a certain period of time, then bring
it back indoors. So, they'll be going
back and forth, or some folks will take
it indoors, put it outdoors, but they'll
put it in the shade for a certain period
of time versus full sun. What's your
process for hardening off plants from
going from indoors to outdoors?
essentially our best res that we saw and
it's always I'm going to back that
depends on on on the conditions and the
climates but a temporary you know
like putting from indoor to outdoor and
then outdoor to indoor it's better
because then the plants get used
normally we recommend to put outside in
the middle of the morning till more or
less the middle of the afternoon and
then put it back in indoor you know to
take especially because we are normally
we are talking this phase it's in the
beginning of the springtime and at the
beginning of the springtime the sun is
not too strong you know there is like
some some condition that let you let you
put the plants outside to get used it a
little bit and then and then put inside
you know so it's not too too too strong
the sun to hide the temperature so it's
it's a medium climate you know like uh
and that's help a lot the plant to get
used then you can do that for 10 days
then the plants start to to get used and
you see that you Got it. That makes
sense. I think one of the big concerns
for folks that are growing outdoors, and
we kind of talked about it a little bit
earlier, at least mentioned it, was
pests. When you're taking these plants
from indoors to outdoors, one of the
things you're exposing to is potentially
a lot more pests invading that that area
that you're growing in and that
attacking that plant. What tips do you
have for preventing pests or any major
infestations if it happens? How do you
go about battling these pests? Well,
this is a good question because in
indoor you can as we spoke before, you
know, like can control better, you know,
like with your filters from outside, you
know, like you can you you have always
to be really clean where you work in
your station, you know, because mites
are are are there at the door, you know.
So and also if you for example if you
work with clones and you buy clones or
you take loans for friends to be sure to
to sterilize them you know like because
otherwise you can bring it inside
outside mostly you know we always say
it's better safe than sorry so it's
better to work in advance you know like
and uh first of all it's the companion
planting you know so what is it mean so
you know plant you know like put some
different kind of plants close to your
plants that attract
pests, you know, like a spider mites or
the whitefly uh or the the trips, you
know. So, first thing that that this
this this insect do its coin on that
plants before your attack your your
medical plants, you know. So, that's
that's a first nice prevent uh to
mention some of them like coriander.
That's really good that something that
also in in US you can find easily it's
like the uh uh the merry gold plant. I
don't know if you know that but it's
merry gold. It's really nice for the
white fly because attract the white fly.
Uh then the salvia uh uh the lemongrass
also it's really good to attract you
know like and that's already in this way
you you create like a kind of protection
you know around your plant. Okay. Then
uh something that we also use quite a
lot and it's uh uh it's it's considered
biologic in in the biological growing is
the neem oil. Then em oil sprayed in the
in the in the in the vegetative stage
create a little bit kind of a layer you
know on on the leaf to protect them you
know like it's it's really nice not too
much like we recommend once every two
weeks as maximum never in the flower
time but this is can can can help also
to to prevent uh and then you know
always talking about organic growing so
biological growing it's the predators
that uh this you you have to use the
predator in case. It's like not the late
the late move, but you you you don't
need the predators if you don't have the
problem because the predators survive
eating uh the spider mites or you know
like the the fly. So if if you start
seeing you know like a development on
this disease uh of this you know like a
problem. So you can you can use the the
predator. So it's like a biological
fight. Normally, it's like ladybugs. Uh
that you can find it in in packs of 500
uh 1,000, you know, and you start to
spread this this this bugs, you know,
like around and they start to to, you
know, as a predator to eat the, you
know, like the the the spiders or the
fly or or the trips in general. So, this
is the the this is the organic way,
let's say, the the biological way to to
to prevent that. and and or or or to
fight with that otherwise you know there
is always chemical solutions to to that
but we never recommend that you know
like it's for normally these products is
for user consumption so we always try to
push the people to to be as natural as
possible you know oh absolutely I'm the
same way now training plants I want to
get into that next this is something
that can be drastically differently if
you're growing indoors versus outdoors
narrowing it down to outdoors in
particular. What type of plant training
do you do? Depends on the resident who
you want to get because there are many
different types of out growers. You
know, there are out growers that they
don't have any problems on the sides of
the plants that they're going to grow or
others because many of our customers,
the growers that grow our seeds in the
cities inside the city centers, they use
balconies or they use teras to grow
outdoor. So, you know, for for for for a
a grower that it's in the countryside or
can grow big plants topping and feming,
it's always recommended, you know,
because you can boost drastically your
your your your your healthy, you know,
like your your harvest quantity of
flowers, you know, because topic and
female are really two nice techniques to
to get more to to to boost and power at
the the the beside
the beside the branches and then uh uh
have way more top colas than then don't
do that. So we really really recommend
that uh to do that uh especially the
feming with a really nice feming you can
get really many many many top callers
you know. So that's that's that's really
uh useful uh uh for who is growing like
in a in a in a in a in a in a balcony in
places where you don't want to attract
attention from outside that and show
that he's growing cannabis in the
balconies low stress training LST is
really good because you can train your
plant and keep it short keep it low so
under the radar let's say of of the
people uh uh it's also a a really good a
really good um uh training, you know,
training uh uh technique to to grow to
grow a door. The scrog also, you know,
in the balcony and and the LSD. That's
uh that's not that's not bad. Yeah, I
know some outdoor growers the only
training they'll do is they'll do I
think it's a 45 degree bend of that main
stem and then the rest is just those
side branches come up and it just grows
out to this one big ball of of a tree.
So that seems to be a common thing that
people do. Yeah. And the and the and the
first part of the plant you really see
the when when you turn when you turn at
40° you know the plant you really see
like a node you know like it's say wow
you know this plant it's really powerful
and on that I want to say that our
outdoor varieties are really you know
enjoyable on that you know because you
can
really try and test you know different
kind of of of techniques because you see
that if they have good good climates you
know you see them that are unstoppable
you know you can you know you can grab
them and and turn, you know, like a
little bit and everything, you know,
like uh 40 50° too and they keep on they
keep on growing, you know, they they
they don't stop, you know, like uh you
know, that's the that's really nice from
the outdoor. They recover quite quickly
from the from, you know, the the
techniques and the stress. Yeah. Like
from the cropping, too. I like the
cropping. So, one question that I wanted
to ask you, a little bit of controversy,
I guess you could say, it has to do with
flowering time and when you actually
start counting flowering time. So, as an
indoor grower, and a lot of my audience
are indoor growers, they count flowering
days in order to kind of get an idea of
when they need to harvest the plant,
right? Different varieties have
different flowering times. Typically,
when they flip that light cycle to
either a 1212 light cycle or 1113,
whatever flowering light cycle they're
flipping to, they'll start to count
flowering days from there. Now,
outdoors, when you're growing outdoors,
there is no grow light to turn on to
initiate flowering, right? It naturally
happens. When do outdoor growers
typically start to count flowering days?
Is it something that they look at the
plant and see flowers start to occur and
then they start to count flowering days
or do they actually look and see
sunlight how how much sunlight they're
getting per day? It's a really good
question like uh yeah as you as you just
mentioned like
uh when also we we we we write down the
characteristic of a genetic of a variety
or a new variety
um we you we test indoor outdoor
greenhouse we have different testing uh
uh spots but normally we we count the
flower time from the indoor the moment
that we turn
1212 that's what we do you know also to
uh put the characteristic you know and
and and then do analysis on our variety
on outdoor that change a bit because the
time of reaction of the plants on the
changing of the hours of lights depends
on the varieties. It's not all the same.
We have varieties that already like from
uh like I mentioned one like freezing as
an example or dura poison already with
14 hours and a half of lights they start
flowering and there are others like
destron that is a pure sativa across
between trillion races
sativas that start flowering in 2 weeks
from when the the time is 1212. So the
time when when when it start it's really
because and the plants already started
flowering actually we don't see the
pieces we don't see the pre flowers but
the plants it's in pre flowering so it's
really in the outdoor it's a little bit
more difficult normally personally I
count that from when the first you know
flower hairs uh so the first pisil uh go
you know are visible on on the plants
then I start counting from that you But
it's approximately because depends a lot
on the variety. That's uh that's for
sure. Got it. We got to ask that one.
We've got uh there's quite a few folks
that will debate particularly as
indoors. Some people don't actually
start counting the flowering days when
they flip the light cycle. They wait
till they start to see the plant
flowering. And then you got the outdoor
growers chiming in that say, "Hey, we
don't even have a light cycle to change
over." So, you know, we just start
counting flowering days once we see the
plant start flowering. So it seems like
there's an ongoing debate and a lot of
confusion on on who counts it when and
and so on and so forth. So just want to
throw that question at you and see how
you answer it. It's a nice question.
It's also true everybody because between
the vegetative stage and the flower time
there is a a short period where normally
the plants stretch a lot that it's
between 10 days that is pre flowering
you know. So you you we we should talk
about also pre flowering you know
because it's not really full flowering
but it's pre flowering. It's a middle
point between the vegetative stage and
and the plants. The plants start get
used uh to the change of of of of hours
of of lights, you know. So, they start
uh changing the hormones also and and
and put them, you know, like in in the
flower in the flower stage. So it's a
it's a good the bad but I think it's
it's a middle point you know everybody
can can see a different ways you know
like in this way but indoor for us it's
when we turn 1212 for our point and
outdoor you really depends on the on the
genetics and and the climate and and and
where you are too you know that makes
total sense so moving along here the
plant has been flowering let's just get
up towards harvest here now there are
different varieties that are going to
flower for different lengths like we
talked about, but determining when to
harvest. I think there's this is another
thing that some folks will have
different methods on. Yeah. Some will
look at the tricoms, some will look at
just the plant, looking at the the
pistols or stigmas that are there to
make sure they change colors. What do
you typically look for to determine when
to harvest the plant? Well, it's a good
um that there are many schools on that,
you know, like and there is many
different situations, you know. First of
all, in the outdoor growing, you depend
a lot on the weather. So, always look
the weather. Try to understand, you
know, like we say, okay, my plants is
full flower. I can keep her couple of
extra weeks, but it's going to get 10
days of
rain, you know, like then we always
recommend an early harvest. It's better
to harvest a bit earlier than keep the
plants for 10 15 days or a full week of
full rain or harvest under the rain
because we tried everything you know
like in Netherland happen you know like
uh you know like the days sometimes have
three different season from the morning
to the evening. So you have to get
prepared on everything and uh so first
of all like look the weather of course
you know like you have to see the bats
already structured you know like give it
time to flower but the the the wedding
the weather changing it's it's really
important so look at the weather and
then of course you know like depends a
little bit of the characteristic of of
the plant so the sativas the ibrid the
indicas um normally you know like the
first The second step on the weather is
to look this the pistols. So the color
uh there are and then also depend on the
variety there are genetics that become
100% on on on on like orange uh brown
pistols you know like orange bud. It's
famous to be like when you harvest it
it's 90% like really orange pistons on
that uh or you know like um you get like
60 70% on on the on the on the color red
pistons. And then we have to remember
also that when we cut it and when we
harvest it and then we lay you know we
put it down side in a in a black envir
you know in a dark environment uh the
plant still for a few days have liquids
inside so still to mature a little bit.
So the process doesn't doesn't end uh in
the in the in the day in the moment that
you cut the plants but it's still going
a little bit. So the the don't don't be
scared, you know, to uh to to to to to
harvest a little bit earlier than than
what you expect if the weather is not
great. And then the third the third
option, you know, the third wave is to
check uh uh the tricoms. So if are
transparent or milky or hamburger uh and
on that depends also what you want to to
get as as as as an effect from your
plants because if you if people look for
growers look for sativa's dominant
normally they look for an ephoric effect
uplifting energetic effect then normally
you get this effect with a little bit of
early harvest you know Like I don't want
to say like too early but a early
harvest get you a fresh fresh flowers
you know a little bit like freshy tasty
you know like that you don't get too
much tarpines that that you can get with
a a perfect or a little bit late harvest
but you're going to get a a really
uplifting many of the time uplifting and
energetic effect. So what you're looking
for a sativa, you know what I mean? Like
uh uh then you have also a late harvest,
you know, like a little bit late when
maybe already like 40 50% of your trions
are already hamburger. Maybe you're
looking for that because it's like more
a body stone, like more a couch, you
know, like couch situation where, you
know, talking, you know, like a more
more strong effect on on the on the body
too, you know, more relaxing, you know,
more more powerful, you know, like. So,
depends also what you're looking for.
And that's normally the effect that
you're looking for the indicas dominant
like the or the pure indicas, the
indicas dominant.
depends also a little bit what what you
want to get on that you know like uh
regarding the effect I want to mention
that because it's not a science on that
but it's quite quite clear from from the
test that we get and from the many
feedbacks and reports that we we have
you know like that uh that's that's
that's a principle point on on the
effort too I hear you yeah I think a lot
of people would say personal preference
I know some folks who well me in
particular I like mostly cloudy tricoms
with a little sprinkle of amber. I know
some people are like, "Oh, I'm looking
for about 50% amber cuz I want more of a
laidback coach lock effect." So, yeah,
personal preference. I'm glad you
mentioned that. I'm also glad you
mentioned that the weather as being an
indicator on when to harvest because
that's something we don't us indoor
growers, we don't really hear about. We
don't even consider because we're
indoors. We don't have to worry about
the weather. But yeah, when you're
outdoors, you have to pay attention to
that. I know there's so many growers who
have lost harvests because they had
rainy days towards the end and then they
had bud rot. So if they had harvested a
little bit early, they could have
avoided that bud rot from infiltrating
their their plants there. So yeah,
really glad you brought up weather as a
uh an indication of when to harvest.
Yeah, it's it's really a principle
point, you know, like also because if
you harvest under the rain, then you
have to get your products inside uh turn
down the humidity to to take off the
water and then you don't going to have
really good turpps on on that on that on
that flowers, you know, like uh you can
still have good products, but um it's
not going to be top top notch, you know,
like a product. Yeah. Sounds like a lot
more labor, too, in order to do that.
So, exactly. Okay. Okay. Well, I want to
get back into strains a little bit and I
want to know your personal preference.
Really? Can you name off the top three
strains that you've grown outdoors that
you really like? Yeah. Yeah. It's uh as
as a really fanatic out grow, I really
enjoy the the the the growing outside
and give me a lot of uh happiness at the
end of uh of of every circle because
it's also, you know, follow the the the
the season time, you know. So when you
know when you harvesting you get in
September, October you know Europe was
always autumn so more rainy you know
like and you have the the your new
flowers you know from the harvest. So I
really like that and as I mentioned I
started as gua grower so in in the
middle of the woods you know like
putting nets to protect them from the
animals and you know like it was really
like not not easy to to get to harvest
the plants. Uh I'm I'm really I really
love the Skywalker Dutch Pion. It's a
it's an old school variety that is a
cross between blueberry and mazar. It's
a monster plant. It's called like that
because the branch so that the the the
top butts, you know, like are really
like alpha meter size, you know, like
really huge yielding and super fruity uh
sweet smell come from blueberry. So it's
really like a nice combination with a
tough and strong effect like a indica
effect you like a really couch looking
for at least for me for the evening I
really enjoy more this kind of effect
when when I relax myself when I finish
my day. Um then I have the mazar that is
also one of the my top three for the
outdoor I enjoy that plant. It's it's
fresh fresh uh smell and and and you
know like it's really minty fresh. It's
a particular variety. It's it's really
strong to grow. So it's really like it
can suffer a lot but you you you get
something from that you know. So it's
always the rivery uh the the mazar it's
it's also a really nice a really nice
effect. And and the third one is a
freeze and new that actually I like it
and I still really enjoy that because
it's it's a beautiful plants with a
beautiful color, a fresh uh tasty, you
know, like
a incense uh uh uh uh taste and smell.
So, it's like a fruity incense, you
know, like it's a good mix of the old
school uh Dutch uh you know, like a
coffee shop smell, you know, like uh the
flowers. And I really enjoy also the
effect because it's a uplift in the
effect. It's not too strong. We're
talking about around 12 and 16% of THC.
So we put it in a medium low THC
average, you know, like and I really
enjoy for my daily smoke, you know, like
uh it's it's enjoyable because I can be
super functional with that, you know,
like motivate me, focus me when I have
to do something that maybe I don't want
to do that or you know like if I'm too
lazy at the moment, you know, like so
it's it's really like um uplifting for
me. So it's I would put on the top three
these three and then I may many others
you know to select only three it's
difficult but uh if I were to pick
without you all blind I would pick these
trees for sure. All three of those sound
incredible. Now you mentioned outdoors
the folks that are tuning in that grow
indoors would you recommend it to grow
indoors as well or would you only say
outdoors only for those three?
Skywalker and Mazar also indoor but
freezing dew is not really for indoor
you know you can grow it indoor but you
enjoy you can enjoy better indoor
varieties growing indoor you know what I
mean like it's really a typical outdoor
it's it's really a good outdoor variety
you know like that you enjoy the maximum
point that you enjoy this outdoor
greenhouse glass indoor I would pick
other other varieties yeah yeah but
skywalk and mazar you can really enjoy
that also indoor. Yeah, no doubt on
that. Good to know. I actually just got
my hands on, well, recently got my hands
on Skunk number one by Dutch Passion and
I haven't grown it out yet, but I got it
through Seedsmen. I know you guys have a
partnership with Seedsmen and uh yeah,
got skunk number one. Super excited for
that. I mean, that's a iconic legendary
strain there. And you will see the sides
of the B of of that plant. It's it's
unbelievable, you know. It's wow. You
know, lately we see like really nice
genetics as we said it before, but also
the size of the buds is decreasing, you
know, in general, you know, like you are
super frosty and really nice colors and
fantastic flavors and turns, but that
old school stuff like skunk number one
or the the the white widow, you know,
you see the size of the body and you
say, "Wow." Wow. You know, like it's
like a tin of Coca-Cola, you know, like
it's really like the old one. I had the
fat one, you know. I said, "Wow, it's a
like uh it's really really nice." Yeah,
I can't wait to grow that one out. I
when I first started growing, my buddy
had skunk number one and so I grew out
one of his cuts and u I'm curious to see
if it's going to be similar to what I
grew out back then cuz I know there are
a bunch of different skunk number ones.
Different breeders have their own
version of it and stuff like that. But
uh yeah, really looking forward to that.
probably get that hopefully get that in
the ground this year. Amazing. Now,
we're looking forward for your your
feedback too. You know, like uh we hope
you enjoy this legendary variety. So, we
are getting up towards the end of the
episode here and want to give you a
chance to tell the listeners how they
could find you and is there anything
upcoming in the future that you have
going on that you want to talk about?
Yeah, we've yeah, we're working you know
like yeah the genetics um you know like
environment and industry it's it's it's
growing fast and we are studying you
know like and and testing a lot of new
varieties we uh we breed and and and
stabilize one of the first variety uh
with eye contact of THCV it's called THC
victory uh it's really interesting
medical for medical users um we are also
testing and study something really
interesting that could another chapter,
you know, like that it's the triploid
varieties. Uh that it's still at the
beginning of the of the of the of the
development. Uh but we see quite a lot
of potential on the on the triploid uh
genetics uh uh you know talking about
turppins and quantity of of of
canabonoids and and as as a strong plant
you know like really stable stable
variety. So we are working we're working
really hard you know like uh uh with our
our our breeding team you know here in
Amsterdam and also with collaboration
around the world in different countries.
So uh we really love what's happening
with the plants because it's becoming
really like a huge international
community always been but with the
legalization and with the technology
that is coming in uh we are improving a
lot of aspect of source of our of our
job you know in general we improving the
quality uh the testing and that's uh
also because big you know like a
companies normally was always involved
in agricultural industry the normal one
the corn and all the rest now they're
get interesting and they're putting some
technology uh to us you know like to use
uh on on the plants uh uh um you know
testing and analyzing. So we are
discovering a lot of potential on on on
using these new technologies. Uh so yeah
you can can stay tuned you know like we
have a a web a website dedicated also
for for USA you know like uh where every
every week we share blogs information or
any kind of level growers you know like
from from the beginners till like the
pro you know like the breeding process
that we use. So uh you can you can stay
tuned on our web website and in our in
our uh channels you know like social
channels. So it's uh you know we're
going to be in Spanabis this year in the
in the biggest expo of Europe in
Barcelona then Mary Jane in Berlin. It's
it's really nice. It's a connection of
all the you know like like like
worldwide connection spanabis in
Barcelona. So it's always we always have
a really amazing week all together you
know like it's amazing to share a lot of
new come come you know on the desks or
on the table. So it's really like uh
it's motivating too you know like uh we
we we feel that we are in the right
direction you know like keep on working
hard you know like uh uh you know to
offer the best genetics you know like
that we can to the growers because of
course you know it's also a mutual trust
you know what I mean like when a grower
choose for your seed your genetic is not
just you know like a plant you know like
growing it's it's it's four months five
months it's you know it's time investing
money investing, you know, like uh so
it's really important for us keep the
quality first and it's what we always do
uh uh uh and and and and we are really
happy because you know we have many many
growers worldwide like uh really happy
and and giving great feedback. So that
that's for us the best motivation and
the expo for us is opportunities uh to
get face to face with with with that
people you know and and and then combine
the works you know like create
collaborations and uh it's uh it's it's
amazing what happened. Yeah the
networking can be so valuable. Dutch
passion Instagram I'll have that linked
in the description section below so the
folks tuning in on this can easily get
to your social page there. Also want to
give a big thanks to the folks that are
supporting on Patreon.
patreon.com/mrgrow. 100% of what gets
supported through Patreon goes right
back on the podcast. You keep this
podcast going. So, thank you so much.
The folks being scrolled on the screen
right now on the producer tier. Special
thanks to you, Francisco. Once again,
thank you so much for coming on that
podcast. This was awesome. We don't do
enough talk about genetics on this
podcast. That's something I want to do
more often. And so hearing about not
only outdoors, which is something we
don't talk about much, but outdoor
genetics, I think is going to add a lot
of value to the folks that are listening
into. So, thanks so much for your time
today and hope you enjoy the rest of
your day. Thank you very much. Chris,
thank you for having us and we hope you
we hope to to see you really soon in
Amsterdam. You know, you you are more
than welcome here in the Dash Special
Family. It's on my bucket list. I'll be
out there eventually. Thank you so much,
everyone. Peace out. Catch you in the
next episode.