well what's up everybody feel that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you're watching my extra channel
this is the grossed rs600 LED grow light
in this video I'm gonna unbox a unit and
also test the power output I've actually
had several requests of people wanting
to see more budget LEDs so I think this
light really fits into that category if
you want to see more budget LEDs on this
channel hit that thumbs up button and
let me know in the comment section below
I purchased this girl light off of
Amazon at a discount currently it looks
like there is a $10 off coupon not sure
how long this will last but I did want
to point that out when it arrived to my
house it of course came in an Amazon box
once I open up the Amazon box there was
the box with the LED grow light in it
upon opening the box the first thing
here is the instruction manual this
instruction manual has a ton of various
information such as safety information
specifications on the grill light it has
three additional models on top of that
which it talks about and compares it
lists what the power output is what the
spectrum looks like and what the
warranty terms are next out the box is
the power cord one ratchet hanger one
wire hanger and then of course the LED
grow light if you want to know the
specific features about this grow light
I will link it in the description
section below for the part test I'm
going to use the app og MQ 500 power
meter this measures from 389 nanometers
to 692 nanometers plus or minus 5
nanometers and measurements are in ppfd
this is just going to give you a general
idea of what the power output is it's
not meant to be a hundred percent
accurate I am taking measurements in a
grow tent which has reflective walls so
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the user manual says
this has a coverage area of nine feet by
eight feet and the Amazon listing says
as a core coverage area of 5.2 feet by
4.9 feet both of those must be in
correct lights this size are best suited
for a two foot by two foot grow space in
my opinion I've placed the light in a
two foot by four foot Croton and I have
the light on one side of the grow tent
and I'll be sure to keep the meter on
one side so measurements are taken in a
two foot by two foot space I'll be
taking measurements at three different
distances twelve inches away eighteen
inches away and then twenty four inches
away let's see what these measurements
look like
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
again I have left a link to this grow
light in the description section below
so you can find out more information
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]