welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody if you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Gard do podcast this episode number 116
in this episode I interview Walter from
dubes house he has been gardening for 12
years and grows a variety of plants such
as squash tomatoes cucumbers
strawberries broccoli medicinal
varieties and so much more he also has
worked in several commercial facilities
in this episode he talks about keeping
things efficient when growing multiple
plants at the same time if you want to
see highlights of these podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube that
channel is dedicated to short bite-sized
clips of these episodes I did a poll on
my YouTube channel the channel That this
podcast has posted on and asked how many
people are aware that I have another
channel 53% of the people said that they
weren't aware that it had another
Channel well I have another Channel and
I've been uploading for the past 7 years
there's actually 130 plus videos on that
channel where shows the plants that I
grow I'll have that channel linked down
in the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode their grow 10
kits are incredible you get their ion
board LED grow light their grow tent
which is currently the thickest on the
market their ventilation system clipon
fan and their controller 69 to control
it all you also get their fabric pots
trellis net plant ties and trimmers
definitely a good price for all that you
get in the kit I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow tank kits
and the discount code Mr Grow 15 works
on both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend I've been using
stash blend for over over a year now and
it's awesome one of the things that I
really like is that it saves me money
it's a whole bunch of different inputs
in one so I no longer have to go out
there and buy a silica bottle then a
separate seaweed bottle beneficial
bacteria then a separate one for microle
fungi all of that plus more is in this
one blend go to stash blend.com to learn
more about it and I also have a link
down in the YouTube description section
below and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with Walter Jones from Dub's house how
you doing today I'm doing good man how
you doing doing good thanks for asking
so you reached out to me on Instagram uh
I think it was several years ago now man
and you were like oh I'd be willing to
come on the podcast and to be completely
honest with you the list of potential
guests for this podcast is is over 200
you know so at the time I wasn't able to
do it finally I was able to get you on
here and I'm really happy I'm able to
get you on here I'm excited about
today's conversation because of your
background your experience
you have experience in commercial
facilities you have experience in larger
operations experience homeg growing as
well not just medicinal plants but
vegetables as well and I think you're
going to be able to bring a lot of value
to today's conversation because it has
to do with kind of making things more
efficient in the garden and when you're
working in a commercial operation and
you can correct me if I'm wrong I know
every commercial operation is kind of
different right but efficiency is kind
of a big point you know they don't want
to just pay workers for standing around
they want processes to be done in an
efficient manner and reduce the labor
hours the labor cost that they spend so
there are a lot of tips a lot of various
things that they do in commercial
facilities that I think save time and
also a lot of that stuff can be
translated to the hom grower as well and
a lot of the audience is hom Growers
here I do have quite a few folks
actually work commercial facilities
outdoor all aspects but for the most
part let's talk efficiency in the garden
and uh yeah let's get into the
introduction then we'll get into the
meat meat and potatoes of this so tell
us a little bit about yourself and how
you got into gardening yeah I'm my name
is Walter Jones um been doing some
gardening for about 12 years now a
little consulant on the side um but
before we get started I just want to
thank you for having me on the show um
it's it's a blessing to be here um I
know I want to thank you for all the
hard work you've done over the past six
years um youve created this awesome
platform here um shout out to all your
viewers and your subscribers and yeah
I'm just happy to be here man um know I
got into Garden in maybe about back in
2011 you know um my best friend came to
me and told me he was having a hard time
finding pops and Medicine um at the time
you know his pops was dealing with some
glaucoma and he needed to consume just
about every day to to be able to
function no normally and um of course I
was like yeah you I can help him out try
to find him some stuff and um once I
started doing that you know me and
really got to know each other a little
more even though I already knew him you
I would sit down with them for maybe
half an hour and then half an hour
turned into an hour then two hours you
know we we actually started hanging out
almost no three four times a week and um
one day he was like yeah man I just want
to um kind of showed me that um how the
glaucoma kind of affects him and um he
was like you know it's not really
painful or anything but it's just like
you know you get pressure like in the
eye like um some valve like attached to
the retina it kind of just builds up
pressure and it just causes them not be
able to see and um sometimes it just
made him cry a lot as well just for no
reason like just crying and um one day
he consumed in front of me and um he
showed me that you know once he consumed
like all that really came to a halt and
um that was the first time that I've
actually seen the power of the plant and
I it was pretty remarkable and um not
long after that um he asked me about
helping him do a garden in the backyard
and um of course I was like yes and um
he gave me a book I don't really
remember the name of the book but I know
in the book you know it told us
everything about gardening from U summer
crops the cold weather crops um how to
use the rotor taer to dig your plot uh
build a bed the rais bed build your soil
uh compost compost teas it was just
everything in there and um yeah we set
out know we set everything up did
everything that summer it was probably
like 2011 we did that and um we got some
really nice fruits and vegetables when
you see season was over and um the next
year um I'm up here in Massachusetts so
the next year was 2012 and they actually
um actually passed medical here so I
just had an idea like maybe we should
put some plants in the yard like I
wasn't really trying to like watch his
pockets but know I realized that he was
spending you know a significant amount
of money you know to get his medicine
and I just thought you know it would be
a great idea if we can just do it
ourselves and um when I asked him about
it I mean he lit up like a Christmas
tree and he was like so excited that
know I was interested in maybe doing
that and then he looked at me for like
maybe two minutes just not saying
anything he was like you know what you
know we cannot tell my wife about this
and I was like hey no no problem man and
then um you know I knew a guy who was
actually already kind of doing it at
home so um I went by to check out what
he was doing and he was actually uh
growing organically and he was telling
me like um he had everything already in
the soil so he was just feeding actually
just plain water through this whole
cycle
and um when he said that it just kind of
dawned on me like you know we just we
just built our own SoDo for garden and
vegetables I mean maybe I can just do
the same thing you know and um he
actually gave me my first two know set
of seeds uh it was some Cali Cali Kush
and um that's what I did you know I used
some of the garden soil and we put the
put the seeds in there and everything
was going real smooth and then all of a
sudden you know we ran into like the
malnutrition and like the efficiencies
kicked in and at the time we didn't
really know what any of that was we were
just like we don't know what's going on
so we just started doing some research
uh everyone was saying um you know you
got to go to your local local grow store
and you know get some stuff there so I
looked it up the local the the closest
store to me was in Rhode Island so that
was about 35 minutes away like you know
what I still went and when I went down
and in the store was the store was
phenomenal I've never seen the store
like that before so I was kind of like
wow and um actually found myself going
down there multiple times week sometimes
not even buying anything I just wanted
to go there and just pick the brain of
people who work there and um when I was
there the first time I noticed that some
of the the nutrients on the shelves was
uh some of the stuff that we had in the
garage already so I'm thinking okay well
I'm going go back to the garage and know
mix some stuff up so I'm in the garage
with a no five gallon bucket and I'm
throwing bone meal I'm throwing blood
mail in there and kelp alala I had a
little bottle of like seed weed juice
I'm squirting that in there and I just
Stir It Up mix it up and then I just
throw it on the p on the plants and I'm
just like all right I think we're going
to be in good shape now and man I'm
telling you like maybe 2 3 days later
that those plants look like fried
chicken they were so burnt up I didn't
know what was going on we were like did
did the sun do this we did we got some
past or something attacking it like we
didn't have no idea what was going on so
I'm back at the gr store asking the guys
you know know plants look a little weird
now and then they're like well did you
pH it uh did you get your EC right and
I'm like I don't know I don't know any
of that means
you know and then like yeah you got to
you know you got to make sure you're
doing the proper feedings and stuff and
I'm like ah okay so we eventually fixed
all that but um the end result was not
great um we were kind of bummed out and
um I was kind of like you know I think I
think I might want to try to do this you
know year round and um he was like you
know it's not a bad idea you know I can
help you invest in getting something and
so I went back to the store and I
actually picked up a uh was the hydro
Farm uh like fixture I picked up two uh
CFLs uh one for veg one for Bloom you
know took it home put it in the closet
you know I put the aluminum foil all
around the closet to get some reflection
going um made it real nice and then um
yeah I just started started growing
right in the closet at home and then um
I was reading looking at some videos on
YouTube people were saying you know more
lights better so you know I went back to
the store picked up some uh 4ot
t5s uh put put those in there and then
um I don't know if you remember this
light but there was a light back then um
it was called the castle kind of looked
like a a bigger version of a flashlight
it was like one of the one of like the
first LEDs they really marketed in the
in the grow magazines so I picked up one
of those and know I had all different
type of light spectrums going and know
that's pretty much how I got started you
know from the closet you know I felt
like it wasn't big enough ended up
copping a 4x4 and all the all the extras
that come with it and I kind of just
been doing it ever since man that's
awesome that's really really cool so you
started out with the vegetables I mean
before we started recording you listed
off a dozen vegetables that you've been
growing over the years then you went to
a closet grow now you're actually you
went actually into commercial facilities
too right I think you mentioned to me
behind the scenes that you there's a
couple different operations I'm looking
at your Instagram I see a greenhouse and
then I see an indoor operation how'd you
get into that oh that well well I'm up
here in Massachusetts so around 2015 you
know they really started to try to open
these places up and um I really wanted
to get a job doing it cuz I was doing it
at home you know people were saying that
you know you know I was doing a good job
you know I didn't know if I was doing a
good job but they said I was doing a
good job you know I always kept a
portfolio and I just kept going over to
the dispensary and I was like no can I
get a job can I get a job and they like
well the guy to talk to was never there
and then one day he was finally there
and um I showed him my portfolio he's
like oh you're the one that's been
coming around here for a job huh and I
was like yeah he said well your pictures
look nice so I think I'm going to hire
you and I was like oh nice you know so
that was actually my first gig um back
in
2015 and then um the greenhouse work
that came later on um that's actually
down in Oklahoma um I got some family
down there um around 2018 my brother
called me he was like you know I think
Oklahoma's about to get the green light
down here so he wanted to learn so I've
been so I was trying to teach him like
over over Skype over video know he
called me every day I sent him some
seeds try to get him going to show him
the ropes and um eventually you know he
took what he learned from me um and know
he showed his business partner and then
they got more partners and they ended up
opening quite a few things down here in
Oklahoma yeah I've heard Oklahoma is
pretty crazy there's a lot it's more
freedom than some of the other states
out there it's pretty wild west down
there pretty wild west but right now I
hear they're trying to clean it up a
little bit right now so that's a good
thing to be honest yeah and then kind of
to bring it to where you are now you had
mentioned behind the scenes that you're
doing consulting now so you've kind of
stepped away from the commercial
facilities still doing the hom grow and
stuff like that but you're doing
consulting how does that working out for
you it's been working out pretty good
you know um a lot of people like I
started this back in maybe
2016 um before I even did the before I
had dubis sou I actually called myself
natural remedy um because um back in
2012 when I was doing the closet grow
and stuff I actually
um his name's Clarence Clarence actually
became my I became Clarence caregiver
you know we got all licensed and
approved for it so I became his
caregiver I was doing everything for him
mainly and
um and then um later on down like 2015
um working in dispensaries and then like
just it just dawned on me that I wanted
to do something more like uh on my own
so um there was a lot of people at the
time that wanted to learn how to do this
because it was it was so new around here
everybody wanted to try to get the hands
in on the industry so I figured you know
I can start doing this helping people
out um start them off slow uh show them
how to do it from from beginning to end
and it worked out pretty well and a lot
of people really wanted to get into it
so I was willing to help them out
awesome so I imagine you have clients
that are kind of looking to get the
information that you're about to speak
today which is making things more
efficient growing a large number of
plants and being efficient with it and
uh let's transition to that right now
and I think I want to start with the
beginning really germinating planting
seeds and cutting clones right how do
you go about those things in an
efficient manner um I usually like to
start my seeds either in the Solo cup or
the paper towel method and um you I let
those sit in the cup until you know the
tab rout pops out uh paper towel method
um anywhere between 48 72 hours you
might get the tab rot popping out and
then uh shortly after that I kind of
just transition that into a maybe a a 4
in pot and that's going to be its home
for a several weeks I mean I don't
really uh move it out of that pot until
I get a really good root structure built
um maybe the plant get like six to seven
Ines tall um but before I even talk
about the the plants getting tall like
the way you go about it uh way I go
about it is like um before I even plant
the seed I like to um put the soil in um
I like to use like a like a Mis I don't
really go heavy with the water and I
like to mist the top of the soil you
know poke your hole you know put the tap
rout down um actually put plastic bags
over the cup or over the over the pot
just to keep the humidity up because you
know you need to get the seed to and
like at least 90% humidity to get the
get the seed to break the seed coat so
that's what I do with that and then I
usually let it stay in that pot for at
least probably three three and a half
weeks maybe four weeks before I
transplant to the final pot um my final
pots are usually um either one gallon or
two gall I just like those more cuz uh
like more control of your watering uh
that's uh it's kind of like um easy or
not to overw water your plants with a
smaller pot um I know a lot of people
have trouble starting off because they
usually know water too much and so I
think small parts are are way to go for
when you start off got it now you
mentioned the paper towel method and I
want to talk about that for a minute I
used to use the paper towel method quite
a bit and very common method I mean
that's one of the first things you learn
is to put the soak the seeds in the
paper towel then once you see it cracked
open you plant it from there there's a
lot of people who just go straight into
the soil and they say hey more efficient
easier skip the paper toile me just go
right into soil now when you're growing
hundreds of plants at once germinating
hundreds of seeds at once it's more
efficient to put into a paper towel see
which ones crack open and then plant
those ones versus planting a 100
different seeds into grow pots and then
finding out which ones pop and which
ones don't so like I thought that was a
a really good efficient tip that I heard
from somebody when uh talking about just
planting in the soil and saving time and
so on and so forth somebody replied and
they like no no not for me I plant 100
seeds at a time and paper towel is much
more efficient for me so thought that
was a great point to bring bring up
since we are talking about efficiency
here is uh yeah the paper towel method
can be more efficient if you're growing
a large number of seeds then you'll see
which ones are good which ones are not
you're not wasting time there so y now
how about mixing soil you talked about
you're growing organic what's in your
soil mix and how do you go about the
mixing process well I never really uh
never really grown an organic for like
uh for medicinal plants I mean I've
tried it once with um I heard a lot of
good things with um what's the name of
that company COA main Costa main is
supposed to have really good uh like
super soil and um the one time I really
wanted to try it I got a really bad bag
um so many bugs in it it was horrible
horrible experience with it but as far
as the garden goes um when we built the
bed for the garden uh we just used like
a bone meal blood Mill a fala male uh we
had Kel mail we actually used uh
European nightcrawlers instead of using
worm castings uh veralite perite uh you
know mix it all together you know you
throw it in the bed um let the bed cook
cuz you know all that stuff you put in
there is really hot so we let the bed
cook for like maybe 2 3 weeks before we
actually put plants in it and that's how
we went about building our soil and then
you said for container size you're
starting out in Solo cups have those in
there for about 3 weeks then you're
transitioning you're doing one
transplant correct me if I'm wrong to
your final container which is one or two
gallon containers then the question I
had was using organic in such a small
pot but you just corrected me that
you're actually using bottled nutrients
or are mineral based nutrients what
brand are you using man I mean I'm kind
of all over the place to be honest um
I've shed almost everything on the
market I'm just like everyone else when
you first start off you see so many
different things you like I got to try
all this I'm going to buy this one first
and buy this one next but um over the
past couple of years I've you know I've
dibbled and dabbled with like uh raw
salts I like the raw salts a little bit
um but my last score actually used Cana
I like Cana too Cana has really good
nutrients I used the the ter
the Terra blend the Terra it's called ve
Terra Vega Terra Vega blend it's pretty
good uh pretty good line and then how do
you go about the transplanting process I
mean you've got so many plants you can
really spend a lot of time transplanting
or there are things you can do to make
things more efficient how do you do the
transplanting process and keep things
efficient man I mean that that's a hard
one because uh I don't think there's any
really efficient way to get know 300
plants in a pot you mean other than just
lining them up dumping in the soil and
trying to transplant them as quick as
possible and get them under the lights
um that's how we usually did it you know
we just Lin them up uh dump it in uh we
would uh build the hole make the hole
for the for the new for the new uh
transplant uh we Ed some Michael rise
but you know put a little something in
there for the soil for the for the roots
to be happy other than just dirt and um
that was most that was like the most
efficient way I mean you're not doing it
by yourself of course but like you know
maybe two guys three guys and just kind
of have a nice chain going down the line
and getting them getting them all poted
up and putting into their new home
pretty straightforward there so you've
done your transplant you're in your
final container which is one or two
gallon when does your first feeding
happen and what does that consist of my
first feeding well it really depends on
what medium we're using or what medium
am I using I mean I've tried different
uh different styles of growing um I've
tried dwc you know I really like dwc um
very efficient uh super fast plant Grill
is probably twice the twice the rate in
the when it's just constantly eating
water all day and food all day um less
maintenance it's definitely less
maintenance when you grow uh dwc style
um cocoa core uh that's kind of time
consuming as well sometimes you got to
um charge the bricks if the bricks
aren't charged you got to charge them up
or you got to inflate them because
they'll come all like compressed
together so you got to get them
uncompressed U but on the larger scale
we kind of went toward the other ones
towards the mesh bag that already kind
of had the hole in it for your Rockwall
Cube and that kind of made things really
quicker and efficient cuz now you're not
know putting a bunch of stuff and put a
bunch of soil stuff in a pot the holees
there all we're doing is taking the
clone from the Clone Dome and dumping it
right into the new hole and that made
things really efficient for us when it's
time to transplant the Clones okay and
then as far as feedings were using raw
or we using Cana at that point um yeah
so when my first feeding is
probably well see so I use so it's tough
because I use Fox Farm sometimes and we
know um Fox Farm runs pretty hot so if
I'm using the ocean Forest I probably
won't feed for a couple of weeks but if
you use the Happy Frog um you know you
can probably start feeding your first
feed probably two weeks in two and a
half weeks in it'll be on the Lighter
Side um it probably do something like a
a 1.0 EC something that's really light
and uh pH it around uh 62 to 61 if I'm
in soil if I'm in Cocoa it might be more
around 59 60 okay and then for 300
plants I mean what size of container are
you mixing that in I mean are you in a a
large Reservoir do you have a automated
system drip system or like how does that
work out
yeah that would be on definitely
irrigation fertigation for all those
plants U steaking everything uh having
each each uh each pot probably get two
stakes each um set up the tables uh get
the emitters in drippers um that's how
we would go about that and then this is
hooked up to a reservoir and it's just
dripping down on there throughout the
grow cycle and what is it like once a
week or something you're changing up the
ratio of nutrients in the reservoir or
what yeah so we would uh we would change
up the recipe not the recipe we would
change up the feeding um so we like to
probably do like some micro feeding I
know micro feeding is pretty big in the
commercial field so they would do a lot
of micro feeding when I was there um we
probably water three to four times a day
um I think they we kind of like switched
up the the
EC um I think it would be heavier in in
the morning and then toward the end of
the day we kind of give it on the
Lighter Side just so get that balance in
the medium so we don't get any type of
like nutrient burn or anything got it
okay so switching things up a little bit
let's get into lighting now you've
worked in indoor operations I'm looking
at your Instagram right now and there's
just tons of Lights stacked down the
entire way do you have any tips for
lighting such as like grow light
distance or dimming par things like that
I've had my shareff plenty of Lights
there's like so many um I actually think
um I like t5s a lot in the beginning cuz
they're just so fluorescent a little
little less intensity for the plants and
they just love it like you can actually
have the plants like kissing the lights
and that will do no harm to them you
know the the power on those is usually
between two and 300 which is nothing um
of course in veg you want to be a little
stronger um because you want the in veg
you kind of want the blues so the blues
are anywhere between 400 and 500 micro
moles UM Vet and and flour you want to
be a little higher maybe in between six
and 700 and um and if you're having any
type of like um if your plants are
starting to stretch a little too much on
your tables and you're not liking the
stretch and you can always lower your
lights and that will help stop the
stretch and if your plants are too Squat
and you kind of want them to know
stretch a little more then you know
raise your lights up a little bit
probably between 18 and 20 Ines just to
get them to stretch up a little more and
um another big thing is uh environment
with the temperature I know that um if
you have a a huge swing difference uh
between your your daytime light and your
your nighttime temperatures I know that
also causes a little bit of stretch so
if you can really get your environment
dialed into to where the temperature
kind of stays the same it is during the
day when the lights on that would also
avoid your plants from stretching if
you're not looking to get them too tall
so what temperature do you typically aim
for I typically aim for um in between 80
and 84 uh like right now I run a LED and
the temperature kind of stays consistent
around
84 right now in the winter right now
it's winter time so in the winter time
here it's tough because there's really
no uh no humidity so the way I have it
set up right now on my tent is um I
actually leave the the back the back
vent open and I leave the one of the
side vents open and I kind of get I kind
of put a fan on the outside of the tent
that kind of blows air through through
the side vent and then um I have a fan
also clipped to the pole for circulation
and then um my temperature kind of stays
really steady between um
84 for temperature and my humidity is
always low because it's just so dry here
I mean in the winter time humidity here
is probably 20 lucky to be 25 or 30% so
I do use a humidifier in veg so I try to
know I try to get it up to at least 45
in veg mean it's real it's better in the
summer time here because the humidity is
a little high it might be at 45 or 50
during the day which is good and um but
um I have um also have central heat
where I live right now so it kind of
helps keep my temperature uh this is and
steady where it's at because I can use
the central heat but I don't have
central air so I use a AC unit for the
window and that really helps me keep my
temperatures down than having the AC in
there and um with the and when the
lights are on you know it's um 84 in the
winter but in the summertime when I have
the lights on it's probably in between
80 81 that's the tires that to get and
um as far as when the lights off my
temperature is usually drop like maybe 8
or n degrees on the swing yeah my
humidity in the in the summertime is um
stays kind of consistent around that 50
range just because because Outdoors it's
kind of hot but in the winter that's
when it gets real rough around here you
know you have to use a humidifier to
keep it up um my temperature stay in
between there I mean they're they're
never really higher than no 8 four with
the LED that I run right now okay and
then what about CO2 are you adding CO2
into the grow space in order to try to
get better growth I've actually tried
cl2 um when I first started I was
actually making my own cl2 just getting
a regular little like Coke bottle soda
bottle and then know using H yeast and
sugar and then letting it do its thing
letting it cook it thing in the in the
tent and then you know I started buying
the exhale bags um I tried the canisters
I tried the CO2 Pros
they all seem to do pretty well um but
right now I don't really use it because
um I have a monitor and usually the CO2
in my house already is around 600 PPM
which is not bad so I don't really try
to supplement more CO2 if I don't I
don't need to me I I get pretty good
yields right now so but I do I do dible
and Dabble with it if if necessary I've
tried it and um they work you know
they're very efficient I mean I could I
can see the difference and on the end
result when uh when it's all said and
done it can definitely be helpful you
know especially if you are running a
little bit higher of temps you know
which you kind of are with the 84 degree
Fahrenheit having that additional CO2
can help and of course having the high
lighting can also help with growth for
sure let's get into training plants man
I can only imagine 300 plants and having
a train all of them I've talked with
other folks that worked in cultiv
cultivation facilities in the past and
they have void some parts of training
because it takes so long talk to us
about how you do plant training when
you're working in these facilities or
when you worked in these facilities you
say was there certain type of training
you would do for all the plants were
were there training that you would avoid
to do because they's so timec consuming
or what would you typically do for that
yeah we typically try to avoid to do any
type of low stress training um it would
just take too long for the for the plant
to recover or get to where we want it to
be I mean when you're in the commercial
field everything's on a timeline
Everything Everything feels kind of
rushed so there's really no time to do
anything extra um so we didn't really do
too much uh uh training or trying to low
stress train anything um but we did do
we did a whole lot of fem topping and
that was like one of the main things we
did a lot we never really did any like
like like uh topping topping like
regular topping like cutting branches or
anything because uh we just didn't want
to do that unless we were taking clones
off the moms but um yeah we did a lot of
fem topping to get more tops and more
shoots and um when we put them in the
flower you know we we do uh we put the
trellis up we'll put them through the
trellis and then know we will actually
remove any branches that were kind of
crisscrossing across the table hitting
other plants stuff like that that's
about as far as we got with going with
training we just didn't want too much
stuff touching each other you know try
to avoid getting powdery Mill do want to
have good air flow we don't want to have
no thrip showing up so we would cut off
any branches that that were
crisscrossing with each other or just
didn't fit fit well in the in the
trellis on the bench now would you limit
the topping or fimming actually you
mentioned would you limit that to once
per grow cycle only in the veg or were
you fimming a plant multiple times in
veg and I assume you avoid doing that in
flow yeah we avoid it in flour we would
actually probably fem top twice we fem
Top early in veg maybe a couple of weeks
in and then we do it again right before
we send them over to the flower room
would do it again just to get some
additional topage going and um in the
end it worked out you know we wind up
know you go on there with just maybe
know eight tops you know we go we do a
film before go in there and then we'll
have 16 tops you know smart going after
the film in a commercial operation you
know not only does it help promote that
bottom growth those branches growing up
but you're getting more than just a
couple tops coming fimming it could be
three or four tops coming from that one
fim area so don't make sense that that's
used in a commercial operation and quite
frankly I feel like people should use it
more in homeg grow operations as well I
personally feel like I should use it
more uh in the filming is easier said
than done you know you got to get it in
the right spot I've tried to film so
many times and it just didn't work and
then I've topped the plant before and
accidentally turned into a film so it
definitely takes a little bit of
practice get in that perfect spot to
where it's actually going to fim and go
into a four different tops versus too
but yeah good tip for training there and
making things more efficient now pruning
plants you talked about how you you
would remove branches that were kind of
overlapping with other plants that's one
form of pruning what about like
lollipopping to where you're removing
the lower third or lower quarter growth
of the plant would you do that at all
also I want to Loop in defoliation so
we're moving leaves would you do that at
all yes that that's very important um so
when we do so actually when we put up
the trellis the first trellis that
actually goes up that's kind of like the
Baseline for the plant so wherever that
trellis lands on on the on the table
anything below that first trellis
Baseline is going to be stripped off so
we can transfer all that energy right to
the top of the plant you know get really
good coers and vigorous growth from the
from the top of the plant up and then um
once that started to take off you know
you put your second trellis on to
support that and um yeah that's what
that's what we that's how we did it we
would do it like that and um we would
defoliate um we defoliate all through
the whole plant cycle I mean always
always tell people you know always I
always ask people do you like haircuts
and they'll be like yes well like well
these plants love haircuts so it's
always good to give the plan a haircut
because you I know some folks get a
little worried about taking off so many
fan leaves they like oh no I can't do
that but they don't realize that you
know you're going to take all these
leaves off today and it's going to be
fully back to what it was 7 Days Later
like you did nothing and then they were
like oh no you was right you know I was
like yeah I mean these plants just love
haircuts I don't know they just love
them and um we would uh defoliate all
psycho um dur flower we would actually
defoliate and do the do the pruning or
the lollipop in before they go in and
then we would do it again maybe 20 25
days later we go in and do another heavy
strip and then just kind of let it ride
out from there until Harvest and and we
may take a little more fan leaves off
during before Harvest but we like to
keep as many leaves on as possible
toward the end of flower okay so that's
flower and then question for when you're
in veg you mentioned stripping things
down were you doing that every single
day or were you like limiting to every
three days every five days or whatever I
would say we were doing maybe every
every couple of weeks I mean sometimes
we would just pick off leaves just to
pick off leaves if we think it was no no
taking up too much light blocking the
lower we just pull it off pull off one
leaf but now we would we would wait you
know maybe a week or two then we go in
there hit it hard you know it'll grow
back plan to be much bigger we go in
there hit it again it'll get much bigger
and then sooner or later we're going to
have to move with the flower and that's
when we really give it know know the
full haircut that we want to give it
before it takes off and flower got it
any tips for the flowering stage to kind
of make things more efficient there
definitely use your trellis put your
trellis up um
keep the room clean when have a clean
environment make sure you have proper
air flow um I know a lot of people like
to chase uh VPD that's a really big
thing in the industry um I'm not really
a fan of it I think it's very dangerous
playing with that it's a dangerous game
but if you have it down pack no hats off
to you I just know um I mean that's one
of the things we did a lot there we did
Chase the VPD where I worked um it it
was okay I know it causes a little
problem you just got to be make sure you
have the proper air flow you don't want
to get powdery Mill do um you don't want
to get any pests showing up and that's
really the main reason um you got to be
really careful when you're playing with
the VPD I know a lot of people just will
ignore VPD because of that you know some
uh that's
me yeah running a higher humidity which
is what most of these VPD charts call
for and unfortunately there are several
different VPD charts on the internet
today and they contradict with each
other and that makes things so confusing
for people but generally speaking it
usually calls for higher humidity in the
flowering stage where if you're running
a higher humidity and you don't have
good air flow for example you get Bud
Rod I've had that I've come across that
before unfortunately not good at all to
be in flour and all of a sudden you spot
Bud Rod happening you got to chop off
colas and get rid of them or even
powdery mil do you know that's another
thing and of course one of the root
causes is stagnant air so having the
good air flow but yeah I know a lot of
people just ignore VPD because of that
though no matter what even though if it
calls for above 60% RH in flour they'll
still keep it lower than that because
they don't want to risk getting any sort
of Powter mildew or any sort of Bud Rod
so now let's move on to harvesting
another thing where it's like you know
when we're talking about large scale 300
plants harvesting that it's got to be
very timec consuming top chopping down
plants moving them around getting them
from the flower room to the dry room
talk about harvesting how you go about
making things efficient there oh you
just got to have a lot of people on
hands that day we got to have everybody
in the building all hands on deck for
that uh it's just a constant train of
chopping passing it down the line uh
tagging it uh putting it on the on the
dolly taking it down to the to the dry
room hanging it and you know we can take
down maybe a 300 plant room in probably
probably an hour hour and a half tops
you know get everything down and hung up
in the other room weighed get the get
the wet weight weigh it um I mean that's
the only way I think that you can really
be efficient is just have everybody all
hands on deck that day because it's
going to be a long day without having a
lot of hands and that's similar for a
lot of homerow operations as well I mean
when I was running 12 large plants and
I'm I'm maxed out here at 12 plants so
I'm a small hom grower that's all I can
grow in my state is 12 plants I can't go
above that legally uh but I usually have
call up all my friends hey come on over
we're harvesting or even trimming you
know all hands on deck for trimming
because that's very time-consuming
process now they have bull trimmer now
and a bunch of machine trimming now
which makes things a lot more efficient
but all Hands-On deck back in the day
when we were just using hand trimmers
the entire time so I can totally relate
to that on a homeg grow standpoint I'm
actually going to circle back because we
actually tried a couple of different
things when we Harvest them before me
one time we tried to actually harvesting
individual branches and that that was
just like o and um I mean it works but
that definitely takes up a lot of time
we kind of figured you know chopping
down the whole plant at the base make
things a lot easier hang the whole plant
uh space it out perfectly and you know
that that saved us a whole lot of time
just chopping the whole plant and then
rather than doing the individual
branches yeah great point I assume
you're taking all those into a specific
room for drying what's your drying
conditions temperature and humidity
um you know that I think that's really
preference for a lot of people I know
everyone has their preference where they
think The Sweet Spot is um on the
commercial side you know they used to
play around with it quite a bit you know
I've seen them run
60% uh temperature 45% humidity
sometimes they'll put it at
5550 um they like to kind of like uh
fluctuated a little bit I mean like
they'll go 3 days at 6060 then the next
three days they'll drop it down to like
55 45 just trying to uh like super dry
it but then give it then give it back
moisture a little bit but then take it
away again then give it back to it a
little bit but you really want to get
that real slow dry you know you don't
want to be chopping down too early and
Flash dry anything CU then you just
wasted the whole however long it took
you to grow that cycle you're going to
ruin it because you flash d it so they
played around with it quite a bit my
personal preference you know my last har
I just took down I actually ran um
6562 and it worked out pretty well for
me nice nice I was going to ask you what
your personal preference was so what
about like length of dry how long do you
like to dry for a number of days I like
to really slow dry I'm going 14 maybe 17
days if I can but if not then you know
know I'll pull it before it gets too too
dry like I know we're supposed to I know
you know the the the grow Bros always
say you know you want to wait till until
it gets to that point where you know the
branches are snapping I think that might
be a little too too too long of a drag
cuz now everything is going to be kind
of crunchy so um I kind of wait for the
the stems to be a little a little bendy
to where they might snap but they're not
going to snap and I think that's kind of
the perfect perfect time to I know take
it Down chop it and trim it understood
and then after drying comes curing how
do you go about that um I like I like
turkey bags man I don't know about
anybody else I mean I'm like old school
with I like turkey bags I know there's a
lot of things on the market these days
you know sea vaults my buddy just gave
me these new bags I don't even know what
they call he's like yeah man this thing
preserves everything and I'm just like
man just go get some turkey bags dude
you wasting your money on these bags I
mean turkey bags work well man you know
you get your turkey bag you get your um
your gometer um did I say that right I
think I did um you know the thing that
monitors what's going on inside the
outside the bag as far as humidity you
know I try to keep uh when my when my
Bud's actually Ching I try to keep it
between like 55 and 60 on the inside and
if it goes below that or above it you
know I kind of just crack it and off gas
it and kind of do a hard reset and
hopefully it goes back to where I want
it and um on the larger scale I mean
when I was in the commercial field they
didn't really do any of that turkey bag
stuff they just used uh they just line
up these totes with plastic you know put
them in there and then closed the
plastic lids and kind of just waited it
out and I just kept everything in the
dry room um yeah mean the dry room was
cold so they just kept everything in
there and keep everything uh in in a
dark cool uh cool environment that's
good storage conditions as well now were
they opening up the bins to burp them on
a daily basis or what was the process
for that yeah we would burping those at
least once a day you know smelted
amazing too but yeah we would burp them
once a day try to off gas and we do that
for
probably a week two weeks and then after
that we just kind of keep keep it shut
you know let let the Nuggets do its
thing you know we go in there and maybe
occasionally burp it and then after that
it goes off to packaging and then off to
the store and then people buy it right
yeah yeah nice nice so yeah we just went
from seed all the way through Harvest
drying and curing trimming we didn't
talk about that any uh tips for trimming
making that more efficient well the way
the way to make trim more efficient
honestly is make sure you don't have any
uh any popcorn buds make sure you have
all nice big colas know that makes
trimming a lot easier I mean I mean uh
trim machines are good know they do
knock off a lot of tric combs but some
of them are are pretty good um I know
people like the wet trim wet trim is not
bad I've done some wet trimming and then
we just hang it up in the net let it dry
but um yeah I would say just you know
try to avoid popcorn nugs um the bigger
the bigger the bigger you can get your
nuggets and your colas you know it' be
easier on the back end when it's time to
trim it you know and get it out to the
shelves seems to be pretty split between
people who prefer wet trim or dry trim
50/50 really I mean all with all the
people I talked over the years it's one
or the other and uh they're hardcore on
their stance there I personally like the
dry trim and U I do the same thing with
you we're talking about like ly buds or
the popcorn buds those actually nowadays
just end up in my trim pile to where I'm
using that for Edibles really for oil
butter and then making Edibles so yeah
I've gotten less and less picky about
trimming up lar or popcorn buds just
goes in my trim pile and then I just
keep the top nuggets so yeah so do you
have any other tips just overall for
making things more efficient throughout
any part of the growth cycle that we
didn't cover yet um just just be patient
man I mean gardening and growing in
general is just patience I know I know
when you're on the commercial side you
can feel kind of rushed or things feel
kind of rushed but just be patient I
mean everything's not going to be
perfect um take your time uh do what you
can do um yeah I
mean patience is key man I mean that's
Garden is supposed to be relaxing so
just be patient with everything you're
doing uh you're going to make mistakes
so nothing's going to be perfect yeah
I'm glad you brought that up I think
there's a big difference between being
efficient and cutting Corners you know
and cutting Corners that's what's going
to potentially get you into hot water
right if you're doing things where you
really shouldn't be doing it you're
doing it only to save time but you're
risking quality so yeah big difference
between being efficient and cutting
Corners all right so let's wrap things
up tell us how the listeners can find
you and do you have anything upcoming in
the future that you want to talk about
you can find me on our Instagram at dues
house um you know you got questions
about gardening or need help with
something feel free to reach out you
know I I respond and reply to everybody
always willing to help any and everybody
um as far as coming up you know I would
really like to know expand my know my
consultant Services a little better
maybe try to get in more more commercial
side of it um maybe start some
environmental monitoring as far as going
in with like P Tre dishes uh some
sponges and in ATP meter just trying to
help people out with the figure out if
they have any like mold or yeast and
mold and other bacteria flying around
their uh Grow rooms and stuff and know
scrubbing down surfaces uh checking the
trim machine and other Machinery they
might use that may carry yeast and mold
or other bacterias so I'm looking
forward to trying to know expand my um
my services into doing that um as far as
uh coming up that's about everything I
got coming up was that awesome I'll
definitely have a link to your Instagram
down in the YouTube description section
below at does host Walter thank you so
much for coming on today I appreciate it
this has been awesome to be able to
listen to how you do things in the
commercial facility as well as you also
gave us Insight on your home growing so
um it's great to have that vast amount
of experience and then hearing about the
efficiency side of things which is
something we really haven't covered much
on this podcast so thanks for giving us
your Insight and uh hope you enjoy the
rest of your day thank you man thank you
for having me peace out everyone catch
you in the next episode