what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're tuned into my extras channel here
I have the bloom + DP 1500 LED grow
light they sent me over this girl light
in order to do an unboxing and park test
video I'm also going to do a heat test
on it jumping right into it first thing
out the box is the user manual which
includes information on the BP 1000 the
BP 1500 and the BP 3000 it also includes
some Gro tips such as recommended
hanging Heights and assembly
instructions next out the box is the
fixture this fixture does come with the
power cord attached to it and last thing
in this bag they include some wire
hangers and two rope ratchets I'm not
gonna talk about all of the features in
this video but I will leave a link to
this grow light in the description
section below so you can learn more for
the part test I'm gonna use the apogee
mq 500 power meter this meter measures
from 389 animators to 692 nanometers and
the measurements are in ppfd if this
fixture is emitting any light outside of
that range it will not show on this
meter and this part test is really just
to give you a general idea of what the
power output is it's not meant to be
exact I'm taking measurements in a grow
tent which has reflective walls that
could increase the numbers so just keep
that in mind the flowering coverage area
is two foot by two foot and I'll be
taking measurements in a two foot by
four foot grow tent I'll do my best to
keep my par meter in a two foot by two
foot space I'll be taking measurements
at three different distances these are
the recommended distances shown in their
user manual twelve inches 18 inches and
24 inches ok I've plugged this light
into my kilowatt meter and it shows 1.17
amps pulling 143 watts
alright let's get into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
just a reminder that there is a link
down in the description section below so
you can click on that to learn more
about this light and I'll leave it at
that thank you so much for watching and
until next time
pace
[Music]