coming up on garden talk you put so many
materials so many ions in the root zone
that it creates a high pressure gradient
outside the roots which forces it into
the plant
anything that you're adding microbially
is going to create in its own
environment and it's going to create
some slimes and films and you're not
going to know what's going on so it's
kind of gross science just to be like oh
all microbes die whenever you put
synthetic fertilizers on there that's
not true it's very much of a gray area
yes some are super sensitive but some
are actually really resistant to these
chemicals they're putting down and
actually can help synthetic systems if
you brew compost tea do not adjust the
ph whatever it is put it inside your
medium and the buffering index inside
your soil will figure out where it wants
the proper ph to be
grow more plant matter carbon-based
systems are going to grow more
cannabinoids more alkaloids within the
plant
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 41. in this
episode i interview tim mccormick he is
the owner of cultured biologics which is
a company that formulates and
manufactures an organic product line tim
has an extensive background in
horticulture everything from chemistry
microbiology soil science plant
physiology epidemiology and plant
pathology in this episode he breaks down
bro science versus grow science we go
over a ton of different gardening
processes that many deem as bro science
tim reveals the actual science that
exists for them if any thanks to all of
you support this podcast or patreon if
you'd like to support you can do so by
going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible
big shout out to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast ac infiniti is
well known to produce high quality
products and provide excellent customer
service they have the thickest grow tent
on the market today
in-line vans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
grow it during checkout for a discount
on their products a big supporter of
this podcast is dutch pro they sponsor
this podcast and i use their nutrients i
have been using their base nutrients
formulated specifically for auro and
soft water i also have been using some
of their additives like calmag silica
and their root stimulator called take
root they have a few other additives on
top of those and ph regulators coupon
code mrgrowit10dp
will get you a discount on their
products and i'll leave a link to their
amazon store down in the description
section below
thanks to spider farmer for sponsoring
this podcast they have board style led
grow lights bar style led grow lights
grow tents
inline fans and carbon filters they also
have complete grow tank kits which
include lighting a ventilation system
grow pots a trellis net a timer and a
monitor for both temperature and
humidity coupon code mr growth 5 will
get you a discount on their products and
i'll leave a link to their amazon store
down in the description section below
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with tim
mccormick from cultured biologics how
you doing today good how you doing chris
i'm doing great excited for this episode
today we're going to be talking about
bro science versus grow science so
basically i have a whole bunch of highly
debated topics that many people swear
work
while others claim that it's just bro
science man so tim and i met at mjbizcon
and i thought tim would be the perfect
person to have on this since he has such
deep knowledge in several different
areas of horticulture you've actually
developed your own organic fertilizer as
well it's 100 water soluble we'll get
into that in more detail later on but
yeah this is going to be a great episode
first can you give the listeners an
introduction maybe tell us a little bit
about yourself and kind of how you got
into gardening yeah absolutely um so
my experience of gardening goes back to
my childhood pretty much my mother is a
has been a horticulturalist for like 35
years so take your kid to work today was
take tim to the greenhouse make them
water make them pick off leaves make
them go move pout and the boxes of
plants and stuff like that so i've been
i've been gardening since i was a little
kid but
my real career experience got started
when i got out of college um
you know didn't really know what i
wanted to do
got a degree in chemistry emphasis on
like compound pharmacy so it was you
know how to make medicine for people and
i didn't really like how the
pharmaceutical industry was kind of
how it's kind of geared
um to making pills for pills for pills
and it's not really where i wanted to
come from i really wanted to make
natural
natural medicine for people so i kind of
got out didn't really know what i want
and then by happenstance got to me a a
business owner trying to start up a
fertilizer company out of fort collins
um asked me and my best friend greg if
we wanted to move he's a marketer i
wanted to move to
colorado to start her career
and the fertilizer industry and being a
compound chemist i was like absolutely
like let's let's do it i can i have
experience of growing
[Music]
so at the time i was i was growing my
own uh medicinal plants inside my my
closet you know just trying to going to
school for chemistry kind of growing
plants hydroponically at the same time
um
then kind of got
thrown into this mix of of the
fertilizer company and from there i got
to travel the world um working with
acrochemicals and
latin america
domestic agriculture
so
my career background is in uh commercial
agriculture so i come from instead of
you know the the hydroponic entry being
where i started i started commercial
agriculture and uh you know got to do
some really cool stuff with uh the catie
it's a latin america university that
does
cacao
genetics to do bananas pineapples so a
lot of tropical fruits
then i came over to
working with the university of florida
extension program
um really got into
how to use these you know organic
chemicals on on our fertigation systems
our irrigation technologies so really my
background really stems from me
trying to take these or the organic
materials that we're making with our
fertilizer company and applying them to
our industrialized technology and trying
to find a hybrid
about four years ago my best friends and
i decided to break off and start culture
biologics
formulating our own
our own you know organic fertilizers
microbial inoculants bio pesticides and
so we've been doing this for about four
years now
pretty pretty steadily some
just
in the process of now releasing all of
my all my formulations that's awesome
yeah i mean you mentioned through dms
chemistry microbiology plant physiology
soil sciences plant pathologies a whole
bunch of different areas where you have
knowledge in which is which is awesome
that's really cool yeah it was actually
really cool i didn't you know a lot of
people go get the bachelors and masters
and phds and postdoc and whatnot um i
kind of got you know my
quote
pseudo masters working with the
university of florida extension program
because i got to work with
plant pathology professors entomology
professors soil scientists
at some point when i was working down in
latin america worked with the united
nations food and agriculture
organization
and they kind of taught me a
regenerative agriculture and what it
needs to what we need to do to kind of
repair uh the land throughout the world
um so and even it kind of merged into my
my own degree with pharmaceuticals where
you know the european commission we're
working with we're working with the
european commission on trying to figure
out how to reduce healthcare costs and
after all the the the
scientists and
hundreds of people at symposiums trying
to figure out how do we reduce
healthcare the number one thing it came
back to is growing nutritious food
so it's really cool like it was a real
full circle experience for me um
you know trying to trying to to figure
out how to grow food better and how to
make people healthier that's awesome
that's really cool all right first thing
let's dive into powdered nutrients
versus liquid fertilizer right so many
people claim that 99
of the liquid
in liquid fertilizer is water so you're
mostly paying for water
my question is how much liquid
fertilizer bottle is water and is all
that actually required right like i know
water needs to be in there so you know
chemicals don't bind together
you know unexpectedly and so forth but
is it true that 99 is water are
companies ripping off consumers by
giving excess water in their fertilizer
ah
you know that's
a hard that's not there's not exactly a
clear cut answer to that
so water suspends right water's a
solvent um you know there's only a
certain amount of salt you can put into
water until it starts falling out i mean
imagine you putting in sugar into a
glass of water it's going to dissolve
it's going to dissolve it's going to
dissolve till you put too much in there
and then it's going to start falling out
and it won't go into it
so
from a chemical point of view
you do you do need water you do need
other dissolution agents like weak acids
and things like that to kind of keep all
the salts broken down to keep everything
from binding together like you said
but commonly it's like
50 to 80 percent water usually
i try to keep down the low end for when
i make my liquid formulations but
there's a lot of i mean the hydroponic
industry is taking all these
concentrated salts and putting them in
the liquid form and diluting them
essentially
powdered salts being as the most
concentrated you know we do have
a smaller amount of salts going into the
hydroponics so most of the time it is
watered down salts
um and everybody sells the same
general formulations with the same
amount of water and it's it's it's
pretty wasteful especially when you get
to like the shipping end of things
um so quick answer 50 80
long answer doesn't always apply to that
gotcha okay
now let's talk about organic versus
synthetic so um you know when talking
about synthetic nutrients they're
already in a form that is available for
the plant to uptake they're in an
ionized form right right with
organic a lot of these amendments they
need to be broken down by microbes first
and then put into a form that the plant
can uptake you can easily over feed
using synthetic nutrients because the
plant is just going to continue to
uptake uptake uptake a lot of people
call this force feeding that's what they
refer to it as
when it comes to organic many people say
you you can't over fertilize when
growing organic because the plant is
only going to uptake what it needs when
it needs it via the exudates it releases
for the beneficial bacteria that's in
the rhizosphere and that exchange is
happening between the exudates being
released in exchange for the potential
nutrients so my question is can you over
fertilize when growing organic
um yes yes you can
um you can overdo the kelps you can
overdo the alfalfas you can definitely
overdo the guanos
just understand these these
materials still have nitrates and
phosphates in them
um blood muon has lots of nitrates guano
has lots of phosphates and nitrates
usually um so if you put too much down
and i've done this before on my outdoor
properties um
you know
you can
nuke a crop real easy um so some of it's
some of it takes time to break down some
is pretty available immediately um the
biggest difference between the synthetic
is is it you create osmotic pressure at
the root zone so you put so many
materials so many ions in the root zone
that it creates a high pressure gradient
outside the roots which forces it into
the plant and you can kind of train a
plant that's why you see people like
with athena and front row and they can
get up to like 5ec
and peak flower because they've been
training their plant to take that that
osmotic pressure and they work through
the plant up to it
whereas like the organic exactly
like we just said the exudates the
the mycorrhizae the beneficial bacteria
the network will slowly break down and
make compounds in a form that the plant
can just take up passively so it's
really hard to overdo or overfeeding
organics but you can't do it
so it's just it's like i said it's about
but it's in organics about finding an
equalization and harmonization between
um the life in the soil and the the
materials that are required to be broken
down for plant nutrition okay and then
diving deep into the micro microbes side
of things when using synthetic nutrients
like like mentioned before they're an
ionized form already available for plant
uptake are microbes useful when using
synthetic nutrients some people say it
is some people say that microbes are
going to be able to survive in a high
selenium environment and it's going to
be useful
when using synthetic nutrients other
people say that microbes are completely
pointless you should not be inoculating
your medium when using synthetic
nutrients what's the real deal with that
so
funny aspects i just had this
conversation with colin from crop king
um the other day
um
awesome consultant awesome awesome dude
for for you know all things plant
related but he had the conversation of
you know he doesn't believe microbes are
are needed in a hydroponic medium and so
my my answer is kind of
twofold um first you have to break down
hydroponics and like synthetic
fertilizers like are using just water
culture are using any substrates because
cocoa and p are still inert rockwool's
still inert and they're still
hydroponics right so when i go to water
culture i like to keep everything as
sterile as possible anything that you're
adding microbially is going to create in
its own environment and it's going to
create some slimes and films you're not
going to know what's going on
the only time i will say microbes are
are effective in the water culture
specifically so like your deep water
culture your aeroponics your sprinkle
irrigation all that fun stuff
the only time that you really are
i feel microorganisms are effective is
using them as as bio pesticides you know
trichoderma certain strains of bacillus
produce antifungal antibacterial
compounds that you can put like a root
shield or
um
bavaria rasciana with the
botanic gear right but to handguard
sorry
all those are really good for protecting
the root system killing any type of pest
that might be in the root system but i
wouldn't be using any type of nutrient
cycling bacteria or any type of
mycorrhizae in a water culture synthetic
system
my second part of this is like if you
use a substrate medium like cocoa
rockwool
peat and it's all inert still
hydroponics but you have a substrate for
them for the organisms to live within
and here is where you find
um the the usefulness of microorganisms
i feel
mycorrhizaes it it can it can it can be
helpful it can be handy um it you know
you
with mycorrhizae it requires an
insoluble phosphorus source
and then the mycorrhizae takes that
insulin like rock phosphate it takes
that insoluble
rock phosphate and it digests it and
breaks it down and then it's connected
intravenously within the plants and then
it just injects the phosphorus in there
when you're using synthetic phosphates
you're not giving the mycorrhizae any
food you know you're not giving it any
any any of its natural function to
actually survive inside the median so i
i don't really think mycorrhizae is a
good choice when you're using synthetic
hydroponics um and then when you have
the nutrient cycling bacteria plant
growth proposing promoting rhizobacteria
they release natural hormones around the
root system to increase root production
they can help stabilize the ph you don't
get ph fluctuations throughout your your
synthetic crop cycle you
you know it can also help break down
if salts do end up binding together and
locking you out or you know coming
together and
creating some precipitate
molecules in there you start to see the
white crust on the top of your substrate
the the natural the nutrient cycling
bacteria like the bacillus can help
break that down and alleviate lockout
and just keep ppm steady
so it really depends on what you're
trying to do
it's very much of a dynamic
answer i guess
but i mean using slf 100 enzymes always
good it just keeps everything clean it
keeps everything broken down
we have a product called flush um it's a
weak organic acid use those to keep
everything broken down um i don't really
suggest going really hardcore with the
microorganisms inside a synthetic system
okay so you mentioned hydroponic system
in our mediums you wouldn't necessarily
go towards using microbes but how about
soil you did mention some benefits that
really microbes can be useful in soil
when using synthetic nutrients is that
right
yeah i mean i i try to steer away from
using synthetics in any type of soil
just because you have a rhizosphere an
environment in the root zone where you
need to take care of certain
microorganisms and sometimes they can be
really sensitive to synthetic
fertilizers
most the time nutrient cycling bacteria
are okay with it
sometimes you can really impact a
mycorrhizal network by using high
phosphates
but you know if it comes to water
culture i stay away from everything
microorganisms related outside of bio
pesticides you know your trichodermas
your bacillus your antifungal
antibacterials
if you're in an inert medium like cocoa
like peat rockwool
i like to throw in nutrient cycling
bacteria for their ability to create
hormones around the root zone cycle
nutrients stabilize the ph
if i'm in soil i am a i go very very
heavy with microorganisms and try to
stay away from salts as much as i can
salts will can tank out the microbial
sphere that you've created
so you know keep it keep it organic soil
is supposed to be a slower uptake
anyways and that's why you rely on the
microorganisms to kind of be the
the fuel in the car the gas pedal you
know
the more microbes you usually put inside
in into an environment you know within
good means uh the better off your your
soils do because they can break down all
the amendments that are unavailable to
the plant that actually goes right into
my next question which is you know in a
lot of organic growing books and your
documentaries and stuff synthetic
nutrients kill killing off microbes and
then you got people on the opposing side
of things that say no synthetic
nutrients microbes actually consume
those so do synthetic nutrients really
kill microbes or is that bro science
ah it's gross science really
listen these microbes i think they can
you can put a microbial spore on like a
bacterial spore fungal spore on a
meteorite shoot that meteorite to pluto
and as long as pluto has an environment
that is conducive to microorganisms
being alive the proper oxygen proper co2
all the all the food sources and things
like that it'll come alive
i mean we use spore forming uh
bacteriums all the time our bacteria all
the time you know with uh with our our
teas and they can reason these spores
themselves can resist 2000 ppm of
synthetic fertilizer they can withstand
a ph swing of 4.0 to 9.0
um they can you know as long as they
have a conducive environment to
germinate
these microbes will come alive and
actually some of these nutrient cycling
strains and
subspecies of bacteria we were finding
actually solubilized some of these salts
a lot of soil remediations that we've
been that i've been doing throughout my
decade of experience in agriculture we
use microorganisms to remediate high
salinity soils so it's kind of gross
science just to be like oh all microbes
die whenever you put synthetic
fertilizers on there that's not true
it's very much of a gray area yes some
are super sensitive but some are
actually really resistant
resilient to these chemicals they're
putting down actually can help synthetic
systems
got it okay another thing that people
get caught up on is ph adjusters like
using ph up and ph down just for the
audience i've asked these questions to
other people as well
on the podcast i like to ask multiple
people this questions you know and see
if the see if the answers vary a little
bit so far they've been about the same
but ph adjusters you know so people
commonly use for ph down phosphoric acid
ph of people commonly use it's usually a
potassium hydroxide or a potassium
carbonate people swear that if you're
using those
to adjust your water or nutrient
solution
you know once you pour that into medium
you're killing off microbes
what are your thoughts on that uh so
no
um really it comes down to is it's so
funny how some of these
um isms as i call it kind of spun up a
couple different ways as the years go on
um but so
adjusting your ph up and down with
phosphoric acid strong acids strong
bases
isn't going to tank out your soil is it
the thing about soil is that you have
what we call a buffering index this
buffering index
is what counteracts the acidity or the
alkalinity inside your soil
that the organic matter inside your soil
the compost the worm castings all those
are buffering agents that are going to
help protect the living organisms inside
the soil now what i will say with that
when you're making compost teas like
brewed compost teas like you put your
your worm castings your compost with
your molasses in your water and you
aerate it for 24 hours you just create a
living network of like a called a
biofilm it's a long network of bacteria
layered on top of each other it creates
these long strands of filaments
when you start because it's already took
24 hours to condition itself it's at its
optimal ph it's consuming the
carbohydrates at an optimal level when
you take that and then you start upping
ph upping and ph downing the the the
colony the living colony of brood
bacteria and fungi that you just created
yes you will impact it
if you
just just general stance if you brew a
compost tea do not adjust the ph
i don't care if it's 5 5 i don't care if
it's 6-0 i don't care if it's 7.
whatever it is put it inside your medium
and the buffering index inside your soil
will figure out where it wants the
proper ph to be
um so if you're using a brood compost
tea yes it will
it will harm phosphoric acid will harm
the bacterial network
if you're using an instant tea like all
these instant microbials like our easy t
we use bacterial spores it's like i just
kind of just just went over like those
can withstand high ph swings so if you
need a ph in instant micro microbial
mix
um
you know
you'll be fine um
if you use a liquid inoculate like a
microbe life i would treat it like a
living like you just brewed a tea
because they are living organisms
um and the other thing is like i guess
the latter part of this conversation is
it's really really really really hard to
kill microorganisms with uh ph swings
they don't really die they go dormant
you know and i i feel like it's a lot of
things in our industries is
overly oversimplified
and um
and as we you know do these podcasts and
as we do watch youtube videos you have
people doing different gardening
segments the telephone game can kind of
happen so just just i guess uh just a
side note you know it doesn't bacterial
won't die because you put it in an
improper ph it's gonna go dormant and
it's gonna wait till the ph range gets
in a proper range that the bacteria can
come back alive and then it'll regain
function
okay that makes sense a lot of good
information there
one more follow-up on that so the people
that swear that you should be using an
organic method for ph up or ph down like
for example ph down they swear you
should use lemon juice or vinegar
instead of phosphoric acid or they swear
that you should be using baking soda for
ph up instead of the potassium hydroxide
or potassium carbonate would you agree
with that disagree with that
i you know it really depends on your
medium if
you're in a very sterile hydroponic
medium those strong strong acids are
strong bases the hydroxides the
phosphoric acid those are fine
they will work just fine um if you're in
this in a soil i do recommend and you
have like a if you have a living micro
micro organism
environment to be concerned about
go with the weak the weak acids the weak
bases so it's like citric acid like your
lemon juice your
acetic acid your vinegars those are all
weak acids that won't harm your skin
our flush is actually a weak organic
acid and you can put on your skin it's
actually a great
skin cleaner
but so it's so gentle
that it will it won't
harm your skin it won't harm any type of
the the organisms
if you're using any type of ph up like i
said hydroxides work in a sterile
environment i don't like introducing
hydroxides into my organic systems
it also goes with
the
kelp extracts the 1 0 18 kelp extracts
are
kelp is organic can be used in organic
systems but that 18 potassium is
strictly from potassium hydroxide
i would recommend putting that inside of
a organic system because hydroxides if
you're going to do it use carbonates
calcium carbonate potassium carbonate if
you're
you know
trying to ph up limestone
is liquid like calcium carbonate
potassium carbonate those are all good
alternatives to those really heavy
chemicals that you can use in like
synthetic hydroponic systems okay gotcha
i think that's a pretty good transition
into your product line so i forgot to
talk about some of the bro science first
growth science to start then we'll get
into your product line so some people
aren't like oh this is just an hour-long
infomercial his product line uh but you
know it really intrigues me you know you
have a you've developed an organic
fertilizer that's 100 water soluble yes
so you have a gross 360 a bloom 360. you
also have the pk blossom the calcium and
the flush you want to talk to us about
you know
what's in the grow 360 and bloom 360 how
those work sure
um so the is a true one part fertilizing
system it's a one part vegetative base
it's a one-part balloon base um first
and foremost what i want to do is get
away from the six to twenty bottles
people have to constantly mix and be a
cocktail mad chemist you know
um so i want to keep it as simple as
possible so if you just need to just
grow your plants as simple as possible
you can just take these two products and
it has all your macros all your
secondaries all your trace elements
one's just arranged for a the vegetative
stage and the other is for the blooming
and fruiting stage
um
with that i we use zero nitrates we only
use protein nitrogen uh we don't use any
laby phosphates it's all rock phosphate
so we talked about earlier about
mycorrhizae needing food source well
rock phosphate is the is the food source
from mycorrhizae rock phosphates in all
of our
indigenous
soils and on earth
um
then on top of that we use calcium
carbonate and magnesium sulfate both
those having uh attached to amino acids
so they're amino based and then our
trace elements i don't use any edta
chelated anything and that's where we
talk about being plants being force-fed
we're like these edta chelated molecules
they don't care what the plant wants at
any time they just go into the plant
guess what their job is
so a lot of the times you get that harsh
burning and it's because of lab made
phosphates being really harsh it's from
edta chelated micronutrients that you're
in the week seven a flower six of flower
and those are still being shoved into
the plant whether you want them to or
not so what i want to do and what i
searched out is i wanted to use amino
humic based trace elements so it's iron
sulfate manganese sulfate copper so all
the sulfate based molecules of the trace
elements but they're digested and and
chelated to amino acids and humic acids
so you get the the ionic uptake like
uptake like you do with like the edta
chelated trace elements but it's in a
form that's wrapped in carbon
the carbon molecules humic acids amino
acids and the the biggest thing i wanted
to do with this is most nutrient lines
are nitrate based
we wanted to be carbon based nitrates
elongate the plant cell nitrates to grow
plant matter
and which is good when you're trying to
vegetatively grow a plant but when
you're trying to
have the plant synthesize
other molecules like terpenes and
flavonoids and cannabinoids all of those
are carbon based so the limiting factor
for the plant to be able to produce
those is going to be the amount of
carbon you give a plant
so i wanted to make a nutrient line that
was that was carbon based where
everything is wrapped in a carbon ring
so one is microbial food source when
you're putting it into an organic system
it's it's a microbial food two i wanted
it to be bioavailable so if you put it
into a hydroponic system it's still 100
by bioavailable plant nutrients
so these two bases really encompassed
your amino acids your seaweed extracts
and your humic acids along with all of
your macro secondaries and trace
elements
um so that's our base fertilizing system
then you have the supplements
you have the calcium which is an organic
calmag uses calcium carbonate magnesium
sulfate that's digested into amino acids
so it's a protein sulfate based
calcium product so a lot of times we use
calmag inside um these synthetic systems
are all nitrate based so when you're
using them heavy in flour it causes a
bunch of fox tailing and your flowers
you get a lot of
airiness to them
with this you have proteins and proteins
and calcium all go to building strong
structure in your in your flowers strong
structure in your plant cells
the fact that there's a three percent
sulfate charge on there sulfur is in
every single terpene
so it's a it's a limiting factor for
your terpene production based on how
much sulfur you have going into the
plant so it's a it's a cow mag product
that's that's kind of designed to be
used heavily in flour when you need it
the most
but won't cause the fox tailing and
goes to really fortifying the plant
um
the last of the supplements is pk
blossom
this is an organic bloom booster
essentially
i wanted to
take micronized rock phosphate potassium
sulfate and calcium carbonate and put
them into a concentrated product so
you don't have to use
uh
mother of all blooms moab you don't have
to use cool bloom you don't have to use
all these synthetic
bloom boosters you get the the the
flowers to grow to get you know the
plant to really set in in um and enlarge
and ripen
throughout its flowering cycle
and last but certainly not least is our
flush product um probably one of my
favorite products uh uses a weak organic
acid called hydroxycarboxylic acid
um a lot of these flushing agents like
cleanse out there like drip clean
they're all forms of bleach so when you
put them into your system yes they might
remove
the the build the salt buildup it might
remove all these um excess materials
inside your substrate but it literally
sterilizes it nukes your entire
rhizosphere so all of your mycorrhizae
all the microbes you've been using
throughout your entire
um growth cycle it you put cleanse in
there any of these bleach flushing
agents and it completely nukes out any
and any microbes and you just end up
wasting your money so i want to do is
make a flushing agent that was one
carbon base to kind of go with this
whole carbon-based fertilizing system
but two make it safe for microorganisms
and it's probably one of the most
diverse products we have it's a water
conditioner so if you have hard water it
breaks apart the carbonates and
bicarbonates and makes it soft water
in the soil just it just acts as a soil
conditioner adds porosity to soil so it
prevents compaction so it's great for
those no-till guys
that over time how you get the the
compacted soils and we're dealing with
annual flowers we're not dealing with
perennials we're not dealing with
ornamentals these plants don't like a
hard compact soil they want the aeration
they want the porosity so this flushing
agent this flush allows porosity to
happen within the soil itself and the
the third part is that it also acts as a
nutrient key later so if you add it to
your reservoirs whether using salts or
whether you're using organics it helps
break everything down and chelate and
attach itself to
these these molecules so the plant
recognizes it as
since you know it's a car it's a
carbon-based acid so when it attaches
itself the plant can tell it has a
carbon has carbon attached to it so
plant goes oh i know carbon is and grabs
it in so it makes your nutrients more
bioavailable
when you use it with your with your
feeds i think he pretty much answered my
next question which is is this product
line usable with all water types so rain
water tap water ro it sounds like it is
and it sounds like even if you're using
tap water it's got chlorine in it it's
got chloramine in it that you can still
use that
yep and the cool thing about these base
fertilizers because they have humic
acids in them
they
they buffer out chlor
chlorine and chloramine so they can
actually help buffer some of the tap
water so when you're putting these
organic fertilizers into your tap water
and putting those into your soil system
you can actually help reduce the impact
of chlorine and chloramine just by using
the base fertilizers that's interesting
that's so cool
now ph is a big topic specifically one
talks about you know synthetic nutrients
you want them to be in a proper ph range
so the the plant can uptake you know
same thing with organics they need to be
in that certain range now
what is your overall thoughts on
monitoring ph when growing organic
there's so many people out there that
say completely ignore ph whatever water
you have
put in there the microbes are going to
adjust it then there are other people
that say no you still want to make sure
you're putting the proper ph into the
medium
in order for the plant to be able to
update the nutrients for the microbes to
be able to work properly
what's your thoughts on that so i
still like to keep everything in the
soil system between six five and seven
five and usually most of these these
agents that you're using or
products you're using are going to keep
it there
um but i mean
compost teas go down to five five
sometimes and i don't recommend ph those
you know the soil will figure everything
out the whole thing about an organic
system is that you're relying on your
soil the microorganisms the organic
matter
um the amendments you're relying on
those the limestone to like to buffer
and to keep everything stable so nectar
for the gods for example everything in
there is all fermented and everything in
there is extremely acidic
you know you still need to keep it up
and and
raise the ph and they have a liquid
limestone product that works great but
once it goes into the soil you're still
going to have the high amount of
hydrogen ions that's what creates
something acidic it's high hydrogen
high amounts of hydrogen ions and
what creates it alkaline is high amount
of hydroxide ions so you can buffer it
and you can get a stable ph and get an
equilibrium but you're still going to
put these these high amounts of hydrogen
ions that you just buffered up you're
still going to put them into your soil
and the soil is still going to react
with them so the biggest thing about all
these organic systems i wouldn't worry
too much about ph definitely don't do
anything crazy that's gonna like ph of
like 10 or 12 that's gonna you know
throws anything out of whack don't put
anything a ph of four or lower in there
um but if you can stay between
the
five five to seven five range the soil
will buffer and figure itself out you
know so you gotta rely you're creating a
ecosystem and you have to be able to
rely on that and not be
you know constantly at the wheel all the
time of trying to make sure everything's
perfect well said
let's flip it up let's talk about pgrs
so plant growth regulators
so some people hear about pgrs and they
automatically think bad
bad never use pgrs
everything about pgrs is bad yeah i have
trouble saying this word but plaquetrill
butrazole i i just struggle saying that
word for some reason that's the one pgr
that is really bad right that's uh
carciogenic related to cancer
talk to us there are good pgrs natural
pgrs within the plan talk to us a little
bit about pgrs the good and the bad
so
sure absolutely so uh paclo for example
is a bad pgr pgr for those who don't
know plant growth regulators it's
hormones whether it's
it's it's a hormones that that
control and direct a function within the
plant so a bush load has paclo in it
right so these you go to the ornaments
you find you go to ornamental nurturing
you see all these shrubs the same height
you see them all the same width you see
all these perfect shrubs
shrubs by themselves do not want to do
that they do the same thing as most
annuals plants do they have a pickle
dominant side and you'll see one branch
go way up and the rest of the shrub will
be like kind of lopsided we spray paclo
on it
and what happens is it regulates the
hormonal function of the plant so it
gets rid of the pickle dominance and the
pickle dominance is derived from auxins
the the one of the five plant hormones
uh naturally occurring within the plant
so paclo goes in there tells the plant
to stop doing that and to and to grow
more lateral
than to grow vertical
in
the old 90s hydroponic days you'd spray
your plants right before you go into
bloom all of them stay horizontal you
kick it you kick down the stretch
by
almost no you have almost zero stretch
you kick it down almost all the way and
you have these nice little
fat you know
bushes across the way
um the thing about this and what i don't
like about pgrs is most pgrs are
carcinogenic
so most they're cancer-causing and you
know when you're using ornamental plants
you're not
people use these chemicals on them and
you're not like you're not eating an
ornamental plant you're not smoking an
ornamental plant you know it's very much
one of these things of like it's it's
used for kind of like a
hands-off you're going to look at the
plant type of situation when we go into
consumable crops then we have an issue
with these pgrs becoming cancer-causing
because we're literally ingesting them
and these half-lifes are
sometimes six months six to 12 months at
a time so by the time you finish a cycle
it's still
existing within the plant um
you know it's really important to to
know that pgrs are
bad
but it's also important to understand
and this is where i kind of
afco is a overlying agency that we have
to work within they decide what your
heavy metals are
the government agency that dictates
what fertilizers what agents ingredients
we can use
in these in our inner fertilizer
products that we sell you
uh most these pg all these pgrs are
under the pesticide branch
so they're they're
very much um
restricted and they have a very strict
standard in which you have to use them
there's protocols to them however i i
argue with the government officials
about this i believe
that there are
plant growth promoters and plant growth
regulators
you have
for example you have the paclo the
synthetic hormones you also have
kelp extracts which has natural hormones
in them alfalfa has natural plant
hormones in them and this we have to get
into like the the the monotony of
what is regulating the growth of a plant
and what is just promoting the growth of
the plant because not all hormones that
are category categorized as pgrs are
what i consider pgrs so um
paclo is a growth regulator
plant growth promoters is why i call
them pgps and those are the natural
hormones you get from plant extracts
algae extracts seaweed extracts alfalfa
even amino acids have a plant growth
promoting effect
those are okay and those are safe to use
i recommend using those because those
don't control
and tell the plant to stop doing a
natural function and do this abnormal
thing like paclo or bushload does where
it just levels out the canopy and gets
rid of the pickle dominance they they
promote the stage at which the plants in
so when
i use seaweed extract when the plant is
vegetatively growing it's going to help
develop more nodes it's going to help
lateral branching it's not going to tell
the plant just to stop growing and just
to rearrange its entire hormonal
structure alfalfa as well they're plant
growth promoters they're going to
promote whatever stage the plant is in
and those what i want really the
delineation between the pgrs and pgps to
occur i want people to look for pgps
because those are actually what we can
use to increase crop production without
using any type of carcinogens to kind of
harm harm our bodies to harm the people
we are we're providing medicine to
lots of good info there thanks for
breaking that down for us let's move on
to light cycle particularly the 24 hour
light cycle so there's a lot of people
that say 24-hour light cycle is the best
light cycle for vegetative growth
because you're going to have that
photosynthesis going and going and going
and going people on the opposing side
says that the plant needs the period of
darkness now there have been studies
that particularly on the the period of
darkness toward things that happen down
below this you know in the soil microbes
you know exudates are being released
during the darkness period can you give
us your overall thoughts on the 24 hour
light cycle is it bad i'm not a fan of
it um
i like to give plant to rest period
because as soon as the lights turn off
you have a whole bunch of hormones being
rerouted down to the root zone um
abscisic acid so there's five plant
hormones there's
cytokinins there's
um auxins there's gibberellins there's
abscissic acid and ethylene
normally when you're seeing the top
growth in the canopy you're looking at
cellular elongation
oxygen you're looking at cellular
division cytokinins you're looking at
cellular bulking which is gibralans um
but what happens below the subsurface of
the soil yet the roots are releasing
abscisic acid and ethylene
back and forth to grow left to grow
right to go down to grow up so that that
darkness period i like to give it to
plants because the plant is allowed to
hormonally rearrange itself naturally
and actually use those those hormones in
the root zone um to to do its natural
function that it would do during in
nature you know naturally gotcha okay
and now kind of piggybacking off of that
some people do an extended darkness
period before flowering now this comes
down to phytochrome pr and the awake
state sleep state
pfr when pfr accumulates more than pr
the plant starts making fluorine
fluoride is the flowering hormone so
it's often said that giving your p your
plant a period of darkness an extended
period some people do 36 hours of
darkness between vegetative and
flowering that's going to help them
accumulate more pfr
make more flourigen transition to flower
faster was that all correct what i just
said there and and
you know is that true or not what are
your thoughts
so theoretically yes on on paper and
textbook that is how the plant
does its dark cycles and how it
rearranges itself
um
the problem the issue we get into
is and this goes across collegiate
uh studies this goes across third-party
laboratories it goes across the
government so it's so hard to quantify
this biochemical reaction to it that's
occurring and to know what levels are
where because the plant's constantly
going through a metabolic change
and this is where the the government
doesn't like the us to be able to list
like algae extracts or seaweed extracts
and say they have hormonal activity
because we spray it on there and then we
can't we don't know we can't quantify
like yeah we know the plant grows better
but we don't we are not able to quantify
how much of these hormones are going
into doing what and what the biochemical
cascade is doing
you know where we as as as humans are
still still figuring out what these
plants do and how to quantify them
properly in an effective manner so i
mean i personally and this is where the
scientist at me comes from i personally
do not know
how
much flooring is being produced in those
dark cycles i can't i can't tell you yes
for sure that is happening that's where
that's where i would call bro science
you know where we know that this process
happens so we can extrapolate and be
like hey
what if we do this to our plants and
then that theoretical thing would happen
to them
you know and so it's like i i like to be
able to quantify things so
growth rates uh
uh reproduction lateral branching uh
production weight
biomass weight usable medicine wait you
know what i mean i can i i can
quantifiably touch those things and i
know
that's happening but i can't
quantifiably say that yes i put my plant
in darkness for 36 hours and all of a
sudden i cut a week off my flower cycle
you know that's where bro science it's
like we extrapolate it and then we apply
it and we think it does stuff and then
we just keep doing it because that's
what everybody else does you know so bro
science until it can be confirmed as
actual science
exactly
yeah yeah totally and same thing with
the the dark cycle at the end of the
plant life i know that i'm sure you're
going to get into that conversation too
where it's like i
you know the the theory is that the
plant produces more
resin whenever the sun's about to come
up because anticipating being hit by uv
radiations and the resin glands is
spherical and perfectly spherical where
it diffracts the uv radiations before it
hits the plant tissue so if you leave a
plant at the end of its life cycle and
darkness you can increase resin
production but again bro science because
we don't have any quantifiable data and
in the research i've seen that people
you know take it to a lab and they get
their their flowers analyzed
afterwards
there's no consistent data that shows it
does increase
trichome production increases
cannabinoid levels increases alkalate
levels you know we have been able to see
that that drought stress in like peppers
increases capsaicin content
so you could extrapolate and cross apply
that to
the medicinal plants and be like well if
it happens here it'll happen there but
again we don't
we don't there's it's all bro science
they don't have any quantifiable data to
show yes or no
i'm glad you brought up the
darkness before harvesting typically do
people do 48 hours of darkness before
harvesting last-ditch effort to create
trichomes but then the opposing side
says
well even if you do are creating
trichomes they're not going to that
potent state right there's not enough
time for them to be in that potent state
so i'm glad you kind of clarified that
as of right now it's bro science until
we actually have studies done right and
can actually turn it into
actual science potentially now kind of
going into trichome development you know
when we talked to mj biz con you talked
a little bit about trichome development
you know in detail about
how
when trichomes develop can you explain
to us kind of just i guess the life
cycle of the trichome or just everything
you know about kind of trichome
development trichomes by themselves are
a defense mechanism that the
many many plants have to protect
themselves from bugs
creates a sticky surface so when the
bugs are walking the pests are walking
through they get caught and then they
they die from lack of water like a food
um etc
they are
a
they contain fragrance molecules that
attracts and deters certain certain
pests
trichomes themselves also usually
contain
the alkaloids that everybody uses to
partake in
it starts off as
you you have a a a stock a basin of it
and you have a gland on top uh those are
all silicon based
the the sock to the gland and over time
the plant starts filling those glands
with oils and starts filling it with
different alkaloids and whatnot which is
why you can see it go from clear to
cloudy to amber
because you're watching a biochemical
reaction happen throughout a period of
two months
um plants naturally haven't even in the
vegetative state same with with tomatoes
and same with the medical plants they
have
trichomes on them they don't have any
type of active material in them until
later on into the stages when the plants
can biochemically produce that because
it takes all the hormones and everything
and the flower cycle to actually
generate those active compounds in them
the plant starts off with
cbg and that's when you see the clear
trichome heads um the cbg's are
precursor to all the other cannabinoids
and then it goes into your active ones
um
cbd cpg cpc
all all those cannabinoids and then it
all terminates into cbn so when you
start to see the amber that's when you
start to see that the cbn
arrangements start to occur the the the
chemical reaction to turn all those
actives into
a more sedating compound
um
and then you start to see the glands
start to wither and start to to
wither away and that's usually you know
the pull during peak ripeness
so how long does it take i think you
mentioned two months
for that entire process to happen is
that true it takes two months for the to
go from clear to cloudy to amber do we
have like timeline for when it turns it
it really
that's a general broad stroke um
eight to nine weeks is our general
flower cycle uh for most of our
commercial cultivars
that's not how it necessarily works with
um
16 weeks sativas 18 weeks sativas you
know those will stay
cbg until
nine weeks and then after nine weeks
then it'll start to convert into the
active cannabinoids um and then from
there it goes
it takes another two weeks at the end of
it so it can be 16 weeks of a flower
cycle to get all those all those
cannabinoids to fully mature and fully
evolve into their peak potential
so it really depends on you know there's
sometimes there's a five week um
sorry not five weeks it's seven week uh
photo period sometimes you get
uh auto flowers which are five to seven
weeks throughout the entire thing you
know so it really depends on the
cultivar and the variety and where it's
from throughout the world because you
know you have equatorial sativas you
have things in the northern southern um
parts of the world that are going to
always mature differently so it really
depends on on your variety and that's
why i recommend everybody know your
variety
to the point where you know what that
biochemical cascade is doing at the time
that's doing it so you can pull at peak
ripeness and i have to go too far
um and start to have cannabinoids
degrade or go too early and have it be
premature where they didn't actually
develop into what they should be
developed into
gotcha now do you have any tips for
increasing track home development some
people you know talk about uv adding a
uv i think it's uvb if i'm not mistaken
towards the end of the light cycle just
for like an hour or so per day some
people say there are different nutrients
that you can feed the plant towards the
end of the light cycle that's going to
help with the resin production trichome
production do you have any tips for
increasing trichome development
well um
yes and that's kind of where i i got
into making my fertilizer line because
carbon-based everything about a trichome
is is carbon-based you know i think
the universities and all these the the
conventional way to grow crops kind of
miss the ball and one avenue of it where
they think they say that you need 17
essential elements to grow the plants
right you have carbon hydrogen and
oxygen which are freely supplied that
you don't have to provide yourself and
this is where i kind of stray away from
the collegiate teachings of
agrochemistry and agriculture where you
do need to provide carbon you do need
and
co2 is a form of carbon that you can
increase production with you know it
creates a faster photo
photosynthesis
it can increase
yields it can increase growth production
that the thing is though
you need to add
carbon
in a a form that goes through the root
system and the plants take that and
that's what the plants use to make
terpenes and flavonoids and cannabinoids
and in turn that's the material inside
these resin glands
you increase more resin gland you
increase more material inside these
resin glands you provide more precursors
for
production of resin glands like resin
glands are silicon based you know if you
don't have very much silicon in your
system the plant isn't going to be able
to assimilate that it is not going to
have materials to assimilate into a
resin gland
you know so i mean yes you can add the
lighting is is indicative of
of how much
trichomes are produced and that's
because trichomes are natural protection
protection from uv radiation so if you
increase radiation
your plants will naturally increase
tychum production which is the uvbs or
the plasmas at the end of the life cycle
you see cmhs have a higher blue and
higher blues are tighter wavelengths so
the plant needs to produce more
trichomes to protect itself
but first and foremost what i would say
is make sure your nutritional regimen is
geared to producing those active
compounds because that's what we're all
growing this for to have the medicinal
effects on our body
again nitrate-based
systems are gonna
grow more plant matter carbon-based
systems are going to grow
more cannabinoids more more more
alkaloids within the plant so really
it's making sure that you've got your
nutritional regimen dialed in and making
sure your lighting is is sufficient to
the needs of the plant to produce the
trichome coverage you're looking for
okay let's transition over to flushing
one of the more highly debatable topics
out there there has actually been
studies on flushing and when we talk
about flushing where
there's so many definitions now it's
crazy there's flushing as again running
a large amount of water through the
medium before harvest so you're trying
to reduce the ppm and the medium as much
as possible so that way that the plant
will start to fade you know the
chlorophyll will break down and advance
then there's leaching which is basically
just stopping feeding nutrients for the
last two weeks and some people call that
flushing but really the goal for
flushing i think a lot is to see a fade
or see a senescence in the plant in
order to i mean so many people say
different reasons for this
you know some people say that it's going
to reduce the amount of nutrients in the
actual plant and it's going to provide a
cleaner ash of smoke i mean i've heard
so many different things arc screen
technologies had a study on this i'm not
sure if you saw it or not but they came
to the conclusion that the length of the
flushing period did not impact yield
potency terpenes or taste
characteristics which tastes just
exactly subjective right right
but the the argument against that is
that number one there are nutrient
companies so they're going to tell you
to
feed nutrients all the way up till the
end because they make more money that
way
right so some people say that that's
biased but the thing that they didn't
measure which is what i'm interested in
is the amount of chlorophyll right we
know chlorophyll breaks down during
drying curing process right but
flushing or not feeding nutrients for
the last couple weeks having that fade
happen a lot of people say that the
chlorophyll is going to break down
during that period and it's going to
lead to a faster cure in a sense right
you're not going to taste that
chlorophyll
weeks or
over a month after you know you've dried
and you're in that curing stage
now there haven't been any studies you
need a what's called spectral
spectrometer spectrometer to measure
chlorophyll so that hasn't been happened
right long story short you know what's
your thought process on flushing do you
think it's beneficial do you think it's
not beneficial
so
you know um
uh where to start with this there's so
many different there's so many different
angles you're right there's so many
definitions for flushing so okay so i
like to look at this in two different
two different avenues like harvesting
flushing or or oh crap i messed up
flushing right
so
you look at the the oh crap
situation it's you fed too much you're
trying to do whatever else is doing
hitting a 5ec
peak flower you know you're trying to
crank out the weight in your commercial
facility yada yada yada you get lockout
everything starts tanking downhill
the plants taking in too many nutrients
versus water and the plants dehydrating
now now you see nutrient burn across the
board you see deficiencies left and
right
that flushing i would use some type of
agent to break to break the bonds of all
the salts inside your medium and release
them and flush them out and drain drain
them from the medium themselves that
flushing is is like a corrective
flushing you know i i'm all about
corrective flushes
um
synthetic mediums will be easier to
correct to flush than like in organic
systems because you have the organic
matter that ties everything up
um
but you know
that i i do agree is is a needed flush
that's really what i consider the
flushing mechanism
now when you go towards the harvesting
side of things i like to look at
harvesting more like a ripening
perspective than just a get rid of
everything there and let the plant fade
type of thing
naturally inside like organic systems
the plants just naturally you're going
to deplete the soil essentially the the
reservoir capacity you're going to
deplete it and the plant's going to take
up less and less nutrition which causes
cannibalism so there's anabolism and
cannibalism animalism of the plant takes
excess external materials and
synthesizes them into proteins and
synthesizes them into the plant
nutrition when the plant has a lack of
nutrition coming in a lack of elements
coming in the plant cannibalizes itself
and starts to
rearrange where the nutrients go to the
most important members of the plant
either the flowers of the fruits because
that's what you need to preserve in
order to allow the
genetic the genes to continue on
right
so
what i like to
do is is gradually
gradually reduce the amount of feed
towards the end of the life cycle and
let the plant cannibalize itself because
i believe that's where all the flavors
and that's where all the biological
molecules that end up being all these
smells and all these flavors and
breaking down the chlorophyll will
happen
um and that's that's mostly what what
that's for is is because when the plant
ripens at the end of its life when
senescence is happening the plant is it
takes the boron creates borosaccharolet
and boros acrylate or borosacchalos is a
sugar
that the plant takes from the leaves and
translocates the flowers and fruits so
you want that translocation to happen
and this is where like these nitrates
heavy nitrate diets you you really have
a have a really hard time getting that
fade without just stripping everything
out of the medium and letting the plant
have like literally just zero just water
for the last two weeks to cause that
type of translocation sentence to happen
i like to do that naturally and let the
plant naturally break itself down and
and and
with these carbon based ingredients like
i do with my products it allows the
plants not to be constantly fed nitrates
to get their elemental uptake they can
get all their elements without having to
excess nitrogen and i believe these
excess nitrates give too much nitrogen
so it causes an overabundance of
chlorophyll to stay inside
the the flower and that's why you get
that hay smell and that's why it's
harder to get you have to cure longer
and synthetic systems to get a good
flavor out of it because you're
constantly perpetuating chlorophyll to
be produced by constantly feeding it
nitrates all the way to week seven week
eight so rx solutions you know it was
correct in their studies where it's like
yeah it really doesn't
uh it doesn't affect
cannabinoid production it doesn't affect
terpene production but what i think it
comes down to exactly what you said it's
like how fast are you allowing
chlorophyll to break down and i think
that that
at the end of whether you flush at the
end or whether you're allowing the plant
naturally ripened through just a
naturally depleted medium i think that's
where we're all trying to get to is at
the end in the plant's life you want
that chlorophyll to break down so you
don't want providing it with a bunch of
nitrogen at the end of its of its life
cycle because that's what's going to
hold on to the that hay smell and not
allow the proper essence of the flowers
to come out post harvest well said it's
a tricky topic because like flushing is
just like this general broad
statement you know yep
have you heard of vice flushing
yeah
can we talk about that
absolutely
bro science 101
um
i i don't think the temperature of the
rhizosphere has anything to do with the
the senescence or the ripening process
of the plant the plant isn't like
sitting out in nature and just like oh
cold water is being sprinkled on me
right now i totally know to start
killing myself and to ripen really quick
you know i think cold water can lock out
some things so you get better colors
because you have
a different production you have a
different amount of elements going into
the plant you know the plants not able
to
properly take up certain things so then
you have a different biochemical
reaction happening but i don't really
think ice water flushing is as has been
quantified to do anything
other than make you feel good that
you're kind of emulating you're kind of
doing biomimicry and kind of emulating
nature which if that's what you're
trying to do
by all means dress up as a tree and
stand next to it you know what i mean
like
you know do whatever you feel like make
sure your heart was great and everything
but as a scientist quantifiably speaking
i don't see ice water doing anything
other than
adjusting the temperature of the root
zone which shocks the plant you brought
up bringing out the colors as well
colder temps towards the end of
flowering is another kind of old school
trick in order to bring out the colors
what's happening with the plant when you
kind of lower the temps and colors come
out lack of chlorophyll production is
what it is plants are green because
chlorophyll
you know so it's it
by the weather changing and doing all
these things is locking out the plant's
ability to produce green so then you
start to see the true colors of the
plant and same with like when the plant
starts to cannibalize itself and starts
to break down its own chlorophyll and
start to do that fade you're seeing the
actual true colors of the plant plants
well in green because of chlorophyll
because that's the color it takes to
absorb the sunlight to absorb the
photons
you know so i think with cold weather
happening it just changes how the plants
able to produce chlorophyll and the
plant actually knows towards the end of
its life cycle it doesn't need to
produce chlorophyll so when the weather
happens it triggers biochemical process
to allow the plants anthocyanins or all
these different colors to come out
interesting
okay how about stem splitting
you ever heard of stem splitting those
uh in favor of the technique argue that
it stresses the plant beneficial way
forcing it to uptake more nutrients and
produce bigger more potent buds what's
your thoughts on stem splitting uh
anytime
people are trying to do one little trick
to get
bigger
and
uh
more resin-coated buds i always kind of
like
my head to it because it's not one
way that it's just going to make your
buds be big you know and stem splitting
does stress and
the same thing it's like low stress and
those you have low stress and high
stress training
you know it it
can cause the plant to be a little more
vigorous because it has to fight through
the stress then once it heals the wound
the plants already has that much energy
going to it i don't necessarily enjoy
stressing my plant out more than i need
to and creating open wounds
i feel like it takes away energy from
other parts of the plant
um
stem splitting again i haven't seen any
data showing that it increases yields or
increases i mean i can see that it might
increase cannabinoid production only
because you stress the plant and the
plant produces metabolites when you
stress it
so i maybe see that but as far as like
vigor and growth that i prefer
if i could have a plant where i didn't
even have to top it and it could just
grow laterally and just like be a huge
bush i'll just do that and and
feed the crap out of it you know and
just
maintain a good
harmonic system within the root zone
into the plant make sure the ph is
stable make sure the ppm is right on
point where i needed to be and just
hit it with as many growth promoters and
microbes as i can
you know so i'd like that
i say stem swimming more um more of a
bro science
gotcha then i do actual any technical
and it's not really commercially viable
i mean if you look at it like if you
have a couple plants you can definitely
do that and you can baby them but if you
have 100 300 500 000 plants you're not
there's no way
you know you're gonna cause way more
problems and you're gonna get gain out
of it
gotcha okay
bud washing let's talk about that one
so washing your buds after harvesting i
love these questions
i saved the best questions for you yeah
yeah i love it thank you this is so bud
washing just a quick explanation of what
it is you know some people they'll dip
it in they'll have a couple different
buckets so they'll harvest their plant
and then they'll dip it first in
baking soda and lemon juice and then
they'll go into water and then they'll
have another one that's water so they're
washing off their buds any debris that's
on there supposedly there's a chemical
reaction happening with the baking soda
and lemon juice that's allowing some of
the debris to be broken down what are
your thoughts on blood washing what do
you know about blood washing
you know i have always been against it i
like the
the completely natural approach even
outdoor fly my favorite flower i've ever
grown and smoked has been outdoor
outdoor cali plants you know
um
but and that's no washing or anything
but i have seen um
there's a guy on instagram named heavy
icer his name's aaron um really has to
look out for his health
which i mean all of us do but he
especially and he's been really really
good at hands-on tutorial with like
blood washing and
making his own solvent list and whatnot
um and i he really gave me a change of
of perspective where
he had his three vats you know he dipped
dipped dipped and then um at the end of
it he had you know his plant outdoor
plants so he had
nice
couple pound plants it
did a
a bubble bag collection at the end of it
through like a 20 15 or 25 micron and
because everybody says like you dip and
it's going to take away all of your
trichomes and you know you're going to
lose all the material you grew doing
that and
he had
barely anything in that 25 micron screen
and he washed all he took all did like
50 it's like probably took 90 gallons of
water that he used to wash all those
plants with and did a collection at the
end of it and there's only like gunk
there's only stuff in there that you
probably don't wanna don't wanna consume
so after seeing that i was like
i actually understand this methodology
now because like yeah it's dirty outside
and there's with all the smoke and all
the ash
bugs
bird doo doo you know what i mean like
there's there's a bunch of excrements
from all these natural insects natural
animals out there that you probably
don't want to be consuming
so um
i actually now i think if it's as a
legitimate um
answer to dirty flower
mind you it's not going to get rid of
your pm it's not going to get rid of
grave it's not going to get really
spiderman so i mean you'll wash them off
but like
you should handle that before you can
get into flour or when you get in the
beginning of flour to make sure the last
four to seven weeks you don't get
anything on your plants but if you're
really concerned about your health and
you do need to you do want clean flour
then yeah absolutely wash it now i don't
know about residuals i haven't done any
residual analysis and that's the one
thing that i would be
concerned about because sit like lemon
juice is citric acid
sodium bicarbonate is
uh baking soda so i don't i don't know
about the residuals that would be my
question and what i would go to like
next in my
hierarchy of how i kind of discover
these things my discovery process
i'd see about the residuals after i go
okay that's a good process to make sure
my flower is clean now what are the
residuals on it because i still don't
have any data on if there is any
residual on it i personally have never
consumed materials that have been washed
so i mean i can't really say for sure if
it's like
qualitatively good or bad
but you know i can i can i guess i can i
guess what i'm trying to say is i can
see it as a method to clean flowers if
you know it's outdoor or you have dirty
flower
like actual dirt dirt dirty not like
dirty as in like oh it has
but loads of pm on it how do i remediate
this now you know gotcha that makes
sense
all right let's wrap things up
we went over a lot in this one
we have tell us how can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future
so you can find us on instagram i'm
very present on there um
i i run our instagram page so at
cul.tur.ed
we're on facebook culture biologics we
have our own group called cultured
growers where we do like exclusive
releases and discount codes and whatnot
um you can also find us if you're trying
to find our products go to your local
store say hi to them
uh go medicate with them you know go go
hang out like it's our old barber shops
how it used to be back in the day and go
ask for our products on our shelves uh
we like to work directly with with with
retailers you know we want to support
the stores that are supporting you so if
you have a question or you have a
problem that you don't know the answer
to and google's not helping you go into
the store those guys will probably help
you most of those guys back there are
really cool and they're probably gonna
be your best friends um the other
you know
easy way to contact us directly is uh
info at culturedbiologics.com
and that goes to all the executives and
so any question you ask us tracking or
anything like that just say hi
um feel free to just choose over an
email as far as what we have next you
know we just launched the eon fertilizer
line so we're trying to get into all the
stores and get samples out we're doing a
bunch of samples campaign we
launched samples about a month ago and
we already have close to 300 sample kits
being sent out
not on top of the sample kits we're
sending out the store so things are
going gangbusters right now for the
theon fertilizers so whether you're in
hydroponics soil whether you're doing
some type of medium between the two um
check out eon it's it's you know our
organic fertilizer system that's able to
be used in hydroponics all the way to
soil essentially i like to grow good
medicine i want everybody to grow good
medicine so what's what we're really
trying to do is is pump this really hard
and get this in as many people's hands
as possible because i really do feel
like this is the next evolution
in our how we how we grow plants
um so we're gonna be we're refocusing on
this pretty hard because i'm i'm dead
set on on doing things a little
differently so um
yeah we're just we're just cranking away
and then for all you new yorkers up in
the northeast uh we're gonna be at nyc
cantacon i think the first week of
january i think it is um so come check
us out come say hi you know come share
love cool well i will leave a link to
tim's instagram down in the description
section below if you enjoyed this video
click that thumbs up button try to get
as many thumbs up as possible share this
video with people you think would
benefit from this information subscribe
to the channel you know if you're on
youtube subscribe we're releasing these
podcast episodes every single week if
you're listening on one of the podcast
platforms particularly apple podcast
please leave a rating and review let us
know what you think of the podcast i
read every single piece of review that
is left thank you to all who have left
to review i think we're coming come
close to 200 ratings and reviews so
appreciate everyone who has taken the
time to leave a rating and review
tim thank you so much for coming on to
the podcast today this was awesome this
was fun you know there's a lot of myths
in this industry
you talking about what's actual growth
science versus bro science i think it's
going to bring a lot of value to a lot
of people so once again thank you for
coming on to the podcast
i appreciate it thank you for having me
all right have a good one
[Music]
you