what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watching my extra channel
I got another part test video for you
today sunrays sent me over there LED
grow light and in this video I will
unboxing it and also measure the power
output using my Apple gmq 5-under par
meter this mean your measures from 389
animators to 692 nanometers plus or
minus 5 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd
let's just get right into the unboxing
first thing out the box is this thank
you card after that there's a user
manual next up is one light ratchet
hanger one wire hanging kit and a 5 foot
power cord pulling out the light I was a
little bit surprised by the size of it
because the listing says it's for a 3
foot by 3 foot grow space that's a core
coverage area however it was the same
size light as some of the other lights I
have part tested for a 2 foot by 2 foot
area it's like the gross starlight and
the minger light that I did part tests
on both of those lights are the same
sizes this one but does say I'm not
listing that they're using 90 degree
lenses so we'll see how those lenses
reflect light onto a 3 foot by 3 foot
grow space I'm not going to talk about
all of the grow lights features in this
video but I will leave a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more this LED grill that has two
switches on it one for veg in one for
bloom I plugged the LED grow light into
my kilowatt meter and turned on the veg
switch and it is pulling 121 watts then
I turned off the veg switch and just
turned on the bloom switch and it is
pulling 50 watts then I flipped both the
veg and the bloom switches on and the
agent is pulling 164 watts I hung the
light in the 4 foot by 4 foot grow 10
but like I said the core coverage area
for this light is 3 foot by 3 foot so I
try to keep my par meter within a 3 foot
by 3 foot space this part test is just
really to give you a general idea of
what the power output is for this light
it's not going to be hundred percent
accurate the reflective walls could
increase the numbers so just keep that
in mind according to the user manual the
manufacturer recommends a distance of no
closer than 20 inches so that'll be the
first measurement that I take and then
also do measurements at 24 inches
36 inches all right let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
and I'll leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]