what's up everybody feel that don't
normally my name is Chris aka mr.
guerrard and you're watching extras
channel this is the minger 600 led grill
light I purchased this girl light off of
Amazon at a discount in this video I'm
going to unbox the unit I'll do a quick
walkthrough of the app that is used to
control the light and I'll test the
power output first thing out of the box
is the antenna according to the product
listing page the Bluetooth range is 15
meters which is about 49 feet next out
the box is a power cord this is 6 feet
long it comes with a set of wire hangers
and a user manual here is the LED grow
light I won't go over all the features
in this video but I will leave a link in
the description section below so you can
click on it and you can learn about all
the details on this girl light
I've hung the light on one side of a 2
foot by 4 foot Croton
unfortunately the wire hanging kit that
comes with this girl light is a single
style hanger
this results in difficulty in hanging
the grow lights straight so I highly
recommend picking up a pair of light
ratchet hangers and then you can do what
I've done here which is remove the hook
that comes with it and connect the wire
hangers directly to the light ratchets
this makes it much easier to hang the
grow light straight now let's do a quick
walkthrough of the app the name of the
app is gouf home and it is available on
Android and iOS once you get into the
app click the icon on the top right
corner and you can add in the device
I've actually already added in the
device as you can see here so I'll tap
on this device it takes a few seconds to
connect to the grow light and then this
is what you see you can actually set two
different timers and then you have the
option of three different spectrums in
order to enable the timers you would tap
the slider and then you would tap the
time spots and adjust the on and off
times for the spectrums they have three
different options for one six one and
eight one and the manufacturer
recommends these different spectrums for
different growing stages I plug the unit
into my kilowatt meter just to see what
the wattage draw is on this unit on the
for one setting it pulls about one
hundred six hundred seven watts on the
six one setting it pulls in ninety eight
watts
and on the eighth one setting it pulls
94 watts now let's jump into the power
measurements I'm using the apogee mq 500
power meter and then speed are measures
from 389 nanometers to 692 nanometers
plus or minus 5 nanometers so there's
any light being emitted outside of that
range it won't be shown on this meter
and this is just to give you a general
idea of what the power output is this
isn't meant to be exact
the reflective walls in this grow tent
could increase the numbers so just keep
that in mind
it doesn't say what the coverage area is
for this girl light however from my
experience this size grow light is best
for a 2 foot by 2 foot grow space like I
mentioned earlier I've hung this light
on one side of a 2 foot by 4 foot grow
tent and I'll try to keep my par meter
within a 2 foot by 2 foot grow space all
right I'll let the measurements do the
talking
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]