welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey everybody for those of you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into the garden
Talk podcast this episode number 141 in
this episode I interview Mike from 420
things he's been gardening for 15 years
and grows a variety of plants he's big
into gardening on a budget in this
episode he reveals many budget friendly
gardening ideas to help save you money
if you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Gard talk clips
on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow I'll link both of those channels
down in the YouTube description section
below one of my goals for this podcast
is to bring free information about
gardening to the general public that
being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their ion frame LED grill
lights which have the latest Samsung Evo
LEDs these grill lights include a
schedule controller that features 10
brightness levels dimming and a sunrise
sunset feature click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their ion frame LED
grow lights and the discount code Mr
Grow 15 works on both Amazon and their
website AC infinity.com stash blend
stash blend consists of several
ingredients in one so you no longer have
to buy individual bottles
it includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and Ed to
discount code the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with Mike from 420 things how you doing
today I'm not doing so bad how are you
doing pretty good man today we're going
to talk all about budget friendly
gardening ideas so You' like to do
things on the cheap you mentioned to me
so I'm like that's a great episode we
actually have a lot of people who do
things on the cheap just like you they
really have a budget that they need to
stay within with the gardening so that
would be an awesome topic and uh happy
to have you here today can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening sure sure thanks for
having me first because that's pretty
cool uh I'm excited to be here uh like I
said Mike you got that I live Ontario
Canada um I grew up in Florida though so
shout out to my 305
peeps um I have an amazing partner in
crime my wife uh and two great kids and
and I suffer from chronic uh back pain
that's really you know two kids that's
where my cheapness started um I started
uh you know helping my back with uh this
medicinal plant and I be I was a under
Health Canada program I was getting all
my medicine from the licensed
producers and man these government
approved areas is were they were
so expensive I decided to you know dip
my moderate green thumbs from previous
experiences into growing my own uh
medicine so I mean I I did I did work on
golf courses for many years I did
irrigation I did mechanics I did I was a
super you know assistant superintendent
so I I I I really liked the growing
season at a golf course you know you
would come out and it's like like
growing plants you'd have a start in the
you know in the spring you'd come out of
a harsh winter you'd have to like B the
course back you know Brown landscape and
then you know middle of summer
everything's vibrant and green and and
and such a lush you know player for the
thing so I I really feel like this is
where my my love for for growing came
from and and working on golf courses man
it's the same thing budget-based right
there's all even on big golf courses
nice expensive courses they're always
trying to cut your budget they're always
trying to get you to do it on the cheap
so you know macgyvering something and
and getting it to to to be that that
that sort of still get the job done and
do it on the cheap tip that's uh yeah
that's where it came from nice nice and
what would you say your overall grow
style is do you typically grow indoors
or Outdoors organic synthetic soil Coco
Hydro what's your style uh D all the
above I feel like changing it up from
time to time uh it gets me out of my
comfort zone and and it just leads to
like learning something new so right now
I grow both outdoor Dooors and indoors
and my wife my partner in crime she's
all she's she helps out so much and and
she's great um Outdoors I've done
synthetics before but I've got really
bad water here so I had to treat it and
I was really you know using my indoor
experience outdoors and it really was
expensive so I I've switched over and
now I'm doing organic outside it's great
I do a PR miix worm casting mix Gaia
green and man the cost of that versus
bottle nutrients running R water storing
it pumping it man it was expensive so
like and and that's what every start of
the year I don't know about your area
but for me I go pick up I go to like
garden stores in in the spring because
always have sales I mean I'm I'm always
potting and and I got to buy my
fertilizer then right so I get a you
know a big 20kg bag a 444 and 284 at a
spring sale 20 30% off it's like man I'm
saving money again and then it's so nice
to just you know top dress outside and
just water every you know couple of
weeks and and and or top dress a couple
of weeks and and and water just regular
old water out the to it it it works good
right so but my indoor stuff uh I'm
using synthetic nutrients um with ro and
uh right now for this today I'm I'm I'm
currently growing cocoa for the first
time and uh because like I said mostly
promix and and worm castings but it's uh
I I've got an automatic system my back
is pretty bad so I got you know an
automatic watering system I'm using that
both from Flor Flex and uh they have got
some pretty cool watering systems and
they're not they're not bad um but again
you know what I did I waited to 420 they
all every every company has got a April
20th has got a sale 20 30% off extra
free shipping blah blah blah so that's
the best time of year to to to if you're
if you're planning a grow and you want
to do something try to do it around 420
you know what I mean you you'll save a
ton of money shipping and stuff like
that so uh they do like a a water
soluble fertilizer so I guess it's it's
it's very simple it's just not a bunch
of bottles so it's a little bit cheaper
yeah 420 sales man I I do the same exact
thing where I try to get as many as
possible not just equipment but genetics
and also Black Friday is another area
where very deep discounts I feel like
Black Friday and 420 are the like the
deepest discounts that's where people
and companies really offer the most
percentage off so I'm just like you I
take advantage of that yeah you got to
be cheap man you got to stock up you got
to be and that's the best way my opinion
can we get deeper into your indoor
equipment setup and how you went about
it in a budget friendly manner so like
lighting for example do you go with
budget lights or are you kind of paying
a little bit more for a certain you know
amount of par or Spectrum also
ventilation system you know what are you
doing for that so on and so forth yeah
yeah first when so when I first started
I got the tent I got a setup uh I was
kind of new to it right so I'm like ah
look at these Cheapo beo blurple lights
I'm going to get one of those off of
Amazon right and um cuz they were cheap
I was like yeah you know after growing
with it I shook my head a little bit and
go no no no no this is not the way to go
so uh I started looking at some Quantum
boards and this I mean this is going
back probably four years from today so I
mean Quantum boards were where it was at
at the time and I found hlg and you know
an American company but man oh man they
lights I I was seeing great reviews I
was seeing a lot of people talking about
it but man wasn't able to spend that
kind of money I just I wasn't in the
place to spend that money and and again
being cheap I was like no I I not going
to happen so I went out and I started
looking for Alternatives and I found on
Alibaba uh uh a kingbrite it was a
Chinese company that shipped right from
China and it was like I'm going to look
into this you know and and and I started
Googling it and trying to look at videos
and I couldn't find any videos in
YouTube I go listen man even even if I'm
doing a break job on a car that I've
never done it before I go to YouTube
it's great it it's such a informative
gives you a little bit of info no
nothing on kingbrite so I go you know
what hey I'm going to do this I'm going
to start a YouTube channel and I'm going
to you know buy this light and do a
review and do the process of you know
how to get this light going through
customs and and and and doing it so it
it really broke down to like three
things right like first and foremost I
wanted to help other people because
there was no video right um then it was
a you know cheaper alternative to like a
hlg and and you know third I was like
you know what I'm going to start a
YouTube channel it's going to be small
and listen I might only have 10
followers 100 followers whatever it is
but I I you know what this is a business
opportunity and if this is a business
opportunity I can write this light off
so check another savings right so no
matter how big or how small you are
starting starting YouTube channel for me
was one of my biggest cheapness moves
that I've done in gardening why because
I can you know spend that money before I
get taxed on it and and and did but
listen I I'm I'm not an expert on this I
I I I hired a good accountant I I sat
down with him I paid him for an hour I
said let me pick your brain for an hour
I paid him best money I've ever spent he
helped me out he gave me guidance and
and and that was great so again that was
my start and then going into other
setups and other systems I I I decided
after the light I'm like you know what I
want to grow an rdwc
I see I see the Internet it's it's the
growth rate is insane I'm like I want to
try
this you know what TurnKey pre-built
systems are worth not budget friendly
when I was looking at them so I decided
you know what I'm going to I'm going to
do it all myself I'm going to do a d DIY
I'll do it I'll do another video write
it all off and then I was able you know
to buy parts off of Amazon um and and
locally and and you know with that
mechanical background I had an
irrigation I was able to do all the PIP
typing and stuff and and and again being
handy and like being able to DIY stuff
is another like godsent to being cheap
in the garden if if you can do stuff
it's great right right so I mean I just
just compar to the pre-built I was like
half or less than half in price so it
was like man when I talk to people and
I'm talking to them on on social media
and I see they're they're putting out
content they're doing videos I go you
writing this off you know are you are
you do you got like amaz links do you
have like Amazon affiliate or associate
marketing whatever like it's free to
sign up I go sign up get some links put
them in your video write all this stuff
off man
because that that that and again this is
listen this is Canada and every place is
different but hire that account and pay
that money and and and just and help
it'll it'll help offset gardening cost
big time yeah that's a really good idea
going back to the Alibaba kingbrite I'm
actually went to your channel and sorted
it by oldest videos been doing YouTube
videos now for 4 years 124 videos so
that's that's crazy man congrats on uh
all that there a lot of hard work is
kind of what I'm getting at and uh that
was a good idea for a video over 15,000
views on that now I've heard of some
people having bad experiences with
Alibaba uh in particular actually this
King brigh I'd like to know is this
still working today because I believe
they only offer a one-year warranty
where hlg for example I believe offers
three plus year warranty if I'm not
mistaken um is that light still working
good for you or what that light has
since been gone from the channel so
that's um it when I had it it was great
it was a little bit of a setup and
whatever and I did it in that video
because it was the instructions weren't
that good and and trying to deal with
people on Alibaba the time difference is
is is usually like you're in day and
they're night so it's hard to deal with
that so 100% warranty would have been if
I would have ever had an issue uh
warranty would have been a problem I
would have assumed just because of the
dealings but uh I sold it to a guy and
on like on Marketplace or whatever and
and he never got back to me so I'm
assuming it worked for him it it had
decent parts and yeah it would I I used
it for four grows probably and I never
had a problem with it that's awesome you
got some good usage out of there and you
able to resell it so you're able to get
some money back from it so that that's
awesome now would you recommend any
other equipment to get off of Alibaba or
just lighting so that is the only thing
I've ever done so I I really only speak
to what I know and listen the process
was a bit weird um and this was at the
time four years ago this Trump was in
office in the United States so there was
like extra duties and extra like tariffs
and and it was kind of
weird I I I at the time it was great it
was simple I I sent I sent my deposit or
my money by via credit card and I had
tracking in a couple of days I had to
spend a little bit extra when I got to
the door and in like uh brokerage fees
or whatever but still it was it was
pretty cheap so worth it worth a if
you're on a budget and you don't have
that money for that great best light
with the best service and the best
warranty it's an option I think yeah
absolutely and some of the other
equipment you can really find cheaper
options on you know Amazon or any other
website sometimes going directly to the
manufacturer's website it is beneficial
the company's website is beneficial a
little bit cheaper than going through
Amazon where Amazon charges companies
10% I think per sale or something like
that but as far as ventilation one thing
I wanted to mention was you don't have
to go and buy AC infiniti's automated
ventilation that comes with a controller
which is over $100 right you can get an
intake fan for under 50 bucks I believe
you know now it's going to come with the
the variable speed controller so you're
not really going to have the nice
options of going onto your phone and the
app and controlling everything there and
uh hit things automatically coming on
and off as needed but if you're on a
budget you need to keep things cheap you
can certainly get a inline fan for under
50 bucks 6 in 4 in you can find them for
sure so that's another option that I
think i' mentioned yeah yeah know that's
what I started with I just a basic
4-inch fan with like a a speed dial and
you're right it's cheap but cheap is not
always like like there's got to be a
point where you go is this worth it or
is it not worth it because like you said
I I you're right da infin is a little
bit more expensive but that control in
the app man I can be laying in bed and I
can be controlling my phone right I go
what did I M up or what did I do that's
worth something it it it is definitely
worth a little bit extra money to have
that you know that
interconnectivity yeah some things you
don't want to cheap on I completely
agree yeah it can be worth it to spend a
little bit more for better now what
about genetics would you spend a little
bit more for good genetics or do you
look for cheap
genetics and genetics isn't that one of
the most complex questions when it comes
to gardening for us again to me I go
where do you start like you know what I
mean like I listen I've Done Cheap
genetics like cheap cheapap real cheap
you know what I mean and then I've done
exp super expensive genetics um super
super expensive genetics and you know
what not always do you spend more do you
get more or does it equal you know more
money better genetics but listen let's
be honest great genetics are not going
to be super super cheap so where do you
draw that line and and and you know
balance between quality genetics you
know like like a brand that's putting
into work to make them good you know
getting getting to like that F3 or you
know doing the work and behind it and
then you know hey well listen this is
their third version of this like it's
got to be better you know what I mean
they're putting in the time and you know
and or companies that that you know
offer some sort of whether it's a
guarantee or a
warranty um and and again you can you
can you know spend a little bit less or
a little bit more and get that warranty
and then you get that ease of use where
you can you know pop a 10 pack hunt
through it try to find that unicorn
where you're going to go oh this is the
Holy Grail man I I got to reverse this
or I took clones and then you know still
fall back on some coverage for for you
know uh like like that warranty I guess
that's a word but again so you know
backing of their of this and you can
recoup some of your losses and then you
know it's kind of like a win-win you
didn't you didn't lose out and you
didn't spend a lot so that genetics man
it's a tough one I feel like this is
another area where you can Target Black
Friday and 420 deep deep discounts I had
the chillo G I think it was 40% off or
50% off for Black Friday same thing for
420 it's and there's so many breeders
out there quality breeders that are
given discounts so I would recommend
people look during sale times is really
to to pick them up right not really
offse when things aren't discounted yeah
yeah like like I don't like I don't I
don't know if you guys have anything
like Canadian Tire but in Canada it's a
place called Canadian Tire and it's like
uh it's got blah blah it's got
everything it's but if you buy something
from Canadian Tire and it's not on sale
you've messed up right so you're right
being on sale being that Frugal Shopper
is going to save you so much money year
to year here it's ridiculous so you're
right uhuh like yeah all those sales and
then you also kind of mentioned it
directly relates to genetics is cloning
right so sure you're going to buy seeds
to begin but you don't have to buy seeds
ever again if you don't want to you can
just clone clone clone clone clone so
another great way to save money yeah
yeah for sure and and again but it's
it's it's try to find that one that like
I know I know for me anyways I had one
and this was when I first started
growing that four years ago under that
King brigh and and I found a I called
that was great it was perfect it held my
back it was amazing and I didn't clone
it so I lost out and it's like I've been
chasing that strain I I've boughten uh
four different 10 packs of the same
strain and I've tried to get it and of
course well you know everybody knows
that's growing plants one seed to
another you're going to find something
different and it's like that's you're
right once you get it and you've got
that thing cloning it and and maybe
spending a little bit extra money money
on a second tent for a mother tent like
me I
have three tents now 2 by two for
mothers 5x5 for my main grow and a 2x4
for vegging and mothers too right so
that helps you keep that genetic alive
and and live and strong you know yeah
absolutely I also have a a cultivar that
I had a beautiful plant of and I didn't
clone it and I so much regret you know I
don't wish that upon anybody it's like
and I bought multiple packs trying to
find it just like you and didn't find it
so I uh I'm now like monster cropping if
I really find something special I'll
monster crop it right so cloning it in
flower and bringing it back to the veg
stage you know I'll definitely do that
because I don't want to miss out I don't
want to lose genetics anymore yeah and
that's and that's never again is that
ever going to happen to me while I'm
hunting that extra tent can can can save
you heartache I guess what it is 100%
let's get into some of the processes and
I kind of want to know how you do things
and then as we're going along and you're
explaining things maybe you can mention
how you're keeping a cheap going through
those processes so let's start with
germinating and planting seeds kind of
walk us through your process there yeah
so I'm pretty old school on this um now
the only problem with my place is I've
got I'm in a basement and I'm in Canada
and during the winter it's cold in the
basement during the summer I'm I'm I
don't like the heat so it's cold in my
basement so I'm always battling cold um
so the the the cheapest way I found to
do this is is just put you know get a
bunch of seeds put them in the Solo cups
put them on a heating mat put them in a
dome and you know control that in a very
small area not in the big tent where I'm
spending extra money on lights and extra
money on this and extra money on that
small based you know a clone Dome that's
you know maybe that can fit 10 Solo cups
and then I I just go right into right
into the soil and I just barely barely
below the top uh I don't go very deep I
I've had problems going deep um before
so I just I I pretty much go I mean
barely just enough soil to cover it
right and then while um and then and
then just just water very very you know
slow and use because again always
looking at overwatering right
so um it's it's it's cheap in the fact
that I have Solo cups all the time so I
mean I get that it's probably not
environmentally sound but again I I
Costco man I got I got 400 cups in my
pantry upstairs right so it's it's it's
one of those things that it's always
there um so I I to do that so again it's
it's it's is there a cheaper way maybe
going to do some smaller stuff but ah
again
Solo cups that stuff that's that's sort
of in the germinating stage um for once
it goes to seedling um I I I really that
that key for me is that not overwatering
so I I have a bunch of stuff from Amazon
these little 60 mil syringes that I find
are handy I use those you can get a
bunch of them for like 10 bucks or
something like that Amazon for sure uh
like I said Amazon and Amazon associate
links for somebody who's starting out
there's so many things you can use on
Amazon that are key so um just keeping
that soil moist you know in that sort of
like inch and a half circle around where
I put the seed in and and you know and
just and just water it daily so it's
it's labor intensive it's it's not I'm
not automating at this point um I'm just
doing it I want to be in there I want to
be touching it I want to be loving it
all you know right then in that part
right so yeah Solo cups reusing Solo
cups that's a big one right how to save
money should should be buying Solo cups
over and over and over again I've been
using the same ones for I don't even
know how many years plastic bags over
the cups instead of Domes instead of
going on buying the Dome I usually just
use plastic bags make that little uh
micro climate in the in there to begin
until the seeds until it sprouts from
The Medium I reuse the same bags for
year I think I've been reusing the same
bags for eight years now uh reusing soil
too that's another thing where you can
save money is if you're able to actually
reuse the soil over and over again I
spent so many years buying bags of soil
and using synthetic nutrients and
thinking that I wasn't able to reuse it
now a lot of people are just going to
throw that out in their backyard and
they say h that's reusing it right it's
still being used for plants that are
Outdoors okay but you can also reuse
soil indoors and a lot of people do it
with Organics you don't need to flush or
anything like that you just continue to
amend and you get soil tests and then
amend according to the soil test and
then reuse that soil over and over again
I have the same soil that I've been
using for six grows now so it's
definitely possible a lot of people do
it and if they're using synthetic
nutrients a lot of folks just flush that
soil they'll run water through it try to
get to a clean slate where there's
really bit I wouldn't say an inert
entirely but it's kind of drained of
most of the nutrition and then they kind
of reuse it from there and I've had
mixed results using that doing that
method but uh a lot of people do it with
success there so I figured I'd mention
that yeah yeah and and I'm that's so I
was reusing Mo soil I've got a bin like
you said I've got Solo cups I reuse them
I wash them I clean them I have a bin
full of stuff what's my worm castings
like one of those like Costco bins or
whatever it's like you know two two and
a half fet wide but I have a garden
outside and me and my wife we do a lot
of gardening outside we like we like to
um do jalapenos and and and peppers and
lettuce and cucumbers man cucumbers are
the greatest so yeah that's where all my
soil goes um out there and get get a
little the peed in there and all that
stuff in there it's great for that so
you're right it's reusing it but no you
you definitely can reuse it I'm a big
yeah yeah for sure but um I I found and
listen I I know you're very organic and
I'm not very organic I had I had an
organic grow that I was like I'm when I
did it outside and the taste that came
from it I'm like I got to like even my
peppers I put my peppers in organic
they're hotter they're sweeter they're
tastier I'm like I got to do this
indoors and man I went to indoors and I
had nothing but fungus snats and fungus
snats fungus snats I hate those little
things and uh I gone away from Organics
inside I wish I could do it better and I
wish I maybe I should do a little bit
more reading into it but the synthetic
man it's pretty decent for me yeah you
said I'm very organic I so disagree with
you I know I've got a book out on it and
stuff like that but I still do have
synthetic runs and Sanic too that's a
lot of people grow Sanic right using
both synthetic and organic inputs which
feel like it's kind of an underrated way
to go about it you know yeah yeah know
you're right you can suppl that's what I
found outside when I wasn't top dressing
enough I was like o these plants are
hurting little shot of little shot of
food boom boom they perked right up real
quick yeah you can definitely get away
with that for sure now how about like
environment conditions obviously
Outdoors you don't really have control
of the temperature humidity CO2 all that
stuff but uh indoors when you're growing
indoors what do you typically aim for
for temperature relative humidity and
CO2 so this is a good question so for me
I try listen you're right I can't do
anything outdoors but outdoors I do I I
do have um like a little again Cheapo
beo not cheap because if I were to try
to build a greenhouse it would be super
expensive so I got one of these green
houses in a boxes like um uh shelter
logic from from Home Depot great little
thing I put it up um and and here it's
always like I'm in the I'm on the East
Coast sort of mid East Coast I don't
even know it's super hot and humid is
what it boils down to
and I'm always on the lookout for that
white powdery mildew right like and this
is where that genetics you know can
really play play a role in it too and
and so this year I ran some plants out
last year from seed four seeds and three
of them perfect nice not a single and
then the fourth one white powdery Meo
from head to toe instantly like it was
so bad so guess what that one just we
just cut it down got rid of it cuz I
don't want to mess with that and those
three guess what I cloned them now
they're outside I'm going to be I'm
hoping not so much white powder and Me
Do Right but
um I then what what I do in my in my
Greenhouse is I I've got power out there
so I I defoliate like crazy and have fan
like just cheap Walmart oscillating fans
18 bucks like cheap like Canada I don't
know what they are in the States but
like just cheap cheap cheap ones put
them right beside the plant blowing
right on it keeps the air moving and and
that seems to you know be be pretty nice
so again defoliating is is great to help
that outside but
inside um I I I I I started on the cheap
route and and I really wasn't like I
said I had that fan with the with the
little the knob and and it was it was it
just I couldn't get to where I needed it
to be I wanted it to be a nice
temperature just you know under 27c I
don't know what that is a Fahrenheit my
H couldn't tell you um but anyways I I
try to keep it you know with that and
with that fan it was either too cold or
IJ it it was too hot so that's when I I
and I I found AC infinity and man their
controllers while not cheap worth every
nickel in my opinion um because it just
it makes it so much easier like and the
control so I I've I I've got everything
dialed in to my proper temps my proper
humidity I get that VPD in a nice good
zone for all my different areas and I
and I bump up the humidity and I do the
app is so I I don't even know how to use
the controller anymore I go I used to
know how to use the controller when
before the app came out now it's just
the app man it's it's it like I said
from bed from the couch from anything it
is so
again just a little bit more up front on
that unit can can help not get mildew
not get mold which again to me that's
saving money if I'm not throwing like
that one outside I had to throw it out I
put all that money into to to to Gaia
green I put all the effort into the soil
the bags everything so to to to spend
that little bit up front which is worth
the pennies and the Nickels it'll save
you on the end on loss so again um yeah
and and now I I've I just started we're
talking about environment I just started
CO2 um very new to it and and and I just
started Coco too I was telling you I was
doing Coco so I I'm I'm doing cocoa and
CO2 in a sealed tent and I'm doing it in
very small Solo cups for this Solo Cup
grow that I'm doing which is kind of a
silly thing but it's kind of fun it's
new it's outside of my comfort zone but
the CO2 man it it's kind of neat to to
deal with so um dialing that in it it's
a little bit hotter than I'm normally
and this one I'm doing in Fahrenheit
because all the stuff I'm reading is in
Fahrenheit so um I'm at about 85 86 and
I'm at about SE and then I'm in veg
right now and about 75 to 80 uh relative
humidity and that has my VPD just under
one I think it's like 0.9 or 08 or
something like that and um man it it's
it's insane the growth I I'm un I'm I
can't believe how much it is so it it's
probably rivaling the rdwc when I did
that it's so fast but because I've never
done CO2 before you know CO2 is
expensive I get to rent a tank and fill
it up but if I can get my plant to grow
twice as fast in the Ved stage I'm
really interested see during flowering
and see how this is going to turn out
because if I can spend that little bit
upfront on the CO2 but the end result is
I have more medicine well then I'm
saving money in theory I have to do that
calculation chees out on that one but H
you know it's again trying that new
thing so yeah yeah 100% I mean yeah do
the math figure out okay you're spending
this much on co2 you're getting this
much more yield well that much more more
yield would be this in the dispensary so
yeah I can imagine that did would be
beneficial from a cost standpoint to run
the CO2 and get the increased yield
let's move on to the veg stage so plant
training is done in the veg stage
watering feeding talk us through those
processes how you go about doing them
sure sure sure yeah so to me training so
fun so rewarding
so um good for like keeping you like me
I I'm in a 5x5 I wish I had more space
but I only have a 5x5 so I really have
to optimize it for that
tent and and training is that how I do
that to to optimize you know the every
square inch of the tent try to get every
square inch of tent doesn't always
happens but I used to use plant tie
downs and like uh paper clips or or or
like uh clothed pins my wife was always
giving me crap cuz she'd never have
cloes pins um and and just attach it to
the pot and like pull it down tie it
like twist tie kind of plant things but
now I've gone away from that I'm I'm
100% Bud Clips uh from Bud trainer
they're they're they're Clips man
they're they're the perfect angle in my
opinion they're not aggressive they're
aggressive enough but man their attack
on the angle is great so then then it's
like self-contained too right so I was
always a problem with the plant ties I
have I got big old man hands here my
hands are big right so to try to get in
there and mess with the plants and and
and and defoliate and stuff I was
hitting the hitting the plant ties
breaking the plant losing out on that so
and these are all reusable you can throw
them in dishwasher you clean them um and
again uh even when I was watering it'
get it get whatever so for in this veg
stage I use that on my outdoor plants my
indoor
plants and just just just make it a work
of art really and get it you know um get
it to where so and then um watering and
feeding um inside in veg I I like I said
I use that uh I have a a matrix system
from um Flor flex and again back savings
that's saving time and money sure saving
my back another one of my higher
priorities and this thing I've got it on
a table I've got it on a flood table
like an ebb and flow table but I don't
have anything cut out and I just put my
plants in there it's got a manifold I
can do up to eight 10 plants I I've done
two heads I've done it whatever and and
I can water it and it and it's great it
just runs off into the table shop vac I
don't have to pump it and drain it and
and I just again to me that was the
cheapest way to do it and and to not
have to bend over so that that's great
and and that's that that sort of it just
it just keeps the watering so much
easier yeah when it comes to training I
started using those Bud trainer Clips
they've been working out really good so
far for me although they are a little
bit pricey in my opinion I think I ended
up buying a 20 pack for 20 bucks or
something like that so I used to go the
cheap route there as well just with like
ties Garden ties you can buy them for
like two three bucks at your local Home
Depot or Lowe's in the gardening section
and then using those ties and bringing
the branches down and either piercing
your fabric pot with like uh safety pins
for example some people use paper paper
clips binder clips is what I use very
often actually Clos pins I've used those
in the past as well those are a little
bit more uh I say finicky but they don't
I don't really hold on to the pot as
much using those in the garden ties but
yeah anything kind of lying around the
house that's a good way to save money is
using those things when you're doing the
plant training now as far as watering
actually getting littleit deeper into
water you mentioned you use R water I do
too now there's a little bit of a
misconception about RO water that people
think that it's thousands of dollars to
get a home unit system that's actually
not the case I've got one that is I
believe it's 200 bucks I paid for it on
Amazon and it's a 1: one instead of a 1:
three and what do I mean by that I mean
for every one gallon of water some
systems will waste three gallons of
water but my 1: one system one gallon of
water will waste one gallon of water now
you can also take that waste line from
your AO system put into a bucket for
example 5 gallon bucket and use that on
your outdoor plants that's what I do
some people use that water they put it
into their toilet for
they save money there using that waste
water but again ways to keep kind of
keep things cheap filtered water I can't
use my tap water unfortunately but a lot
of people do use their tap water they're
able to well water but if you do go that
route you might want to get it tested
first to make sure that it is going to
be usable for your medicinal plants for
example because we all know now that if
there's an imbalance of nutrients in the
medium some nutrients can lock out
others prevent uptake from happening and
it could just be a rough battle trying
to get through a grow because you've got
what you think is the deficiency but it
actually could be an excess or vice
versa and uh yeah so fig I'd mention
those things about water yeah and you
know what listen my my ppm's coming out
of my well I have hard
water it's like 550 PPM like I have no
choice but to R it and you're right yeah
no R is not like when you look at 500 if
I was to start with 500 and add
nutrients
not I'm not I'm going to kill the plant
right so yeah it it it it isn't that bad
and getting back to the cheap I I I know
you were talking about the bud trainer
ones I bought some of the one off Amazon
that's how I started went away from the
ties I there was so many different
people whether they were 3D printing
them or whether they were there were so
many different sort of angles and
whatever I I felt I some of the cheaper
ones they didn't have like I don't know
what bud I don't know how they came up
with their their their method of their
their Bend because a lot of the other
ones the cheap ones they either cut into
the pl into the plant after you know
only a very short period of
time and and it it or it was too much of
a Bend so I found that that again but
you I buy I'm you have 20 Clips that's I
don't need to buy any more Clips like
that those ones are going to be around
for a long long time I find myself
putting them on and taking them off
pretty quickly versus the ties I would
tie them down on the side of the grow
pod they would stay on the plant for a
while the clips you can slide them on
and then literally within like a week or
so I'm sliding it off at that point it's
staying the branch is staying as the
angle that it was bent down to with the
clip so um yeah 20 might be enough I I
think I want to get a couple more packs
actually just cuz I grow a lot of plants
here but yeah you can certainly get away
with if you just go to a small number of
plants just one pack so might be worth
it to invest in that brand name one
Which is higher quality versus the
Cheapo ones I've seen the Cheapo ones on
Amazon and they can get pretty cheap but
a lot of people having problems with
them breaking as well so yeah yeah yeah
well and like you said you take it off a
week use on the same plant up higher or
keep and and again it it's it's it's
yeah it's good stuff now how about the
flower stage is there anything in the
flower stage that you can think of that
kind of you do that is a little bit on
the cheaper side versus uh you know kind
of spending more money towards doing
things and flower yeah okay yeah so what
I do is I I I do use trellis nets for
training and I I've started with the
cheap ones the plastic ones and and they
were you know they were I was throwing
them out I go this is wasteful I keep
having to buy them to me that's not
saving money because I have to spend
money on them all the time so I I went
with a uh reusable uh washable uh
trellis net and now that's how I use to
keep my my main colas separated and and
not overlapping each other and I have
two of them I have one one right on the
before the flip that I do because we're
going to see that stretch I put that one
down and I try to as it's stretching I I
I I try to manipulate the the the colas
into each one of the little squares and
then that goes up and then I and then
and then the second trellis net I put up
and that's pretty much just for you know
weight and stuff like that but keeping
those those those colas separated um
saves headaches at the end and throwing
it out cuz I I had some that were
overlapping and touching each other and
man at the start of my growing that was
like ooh and then sure enough I had some
moisture in there it wasn't good and and
it just was it was all bad so again um
flowering
stage that that was my biggest thing and
then
dehumidifying um the air right like
keeping it super dry also a must I mean
that environment control is a must and
again a nice cheap dehumidifier from
Canadian Tower Home Depot the the
cheapest one you can get on sale of
course like again that that that that
environmental control is is stable and
and and again to to to to keep it cheap
I I I try to I try to man it's so like a
balance between so many colas in that
5x5 area versus that sometimes I I cut
down Main shoots and just open it up
just to to have that that that area
where it's going to be nice and and Airy
and and nice and dry and I I I hate
throwing stuff out it makes me sad every
time so and cost like I just wasted all
that money and effort right and soil and
stuff so keeping your keeping it cheap
while keeping it clean and keeping it
that's again that's to me the best you
mentioned D humidifier and I'm the
opposite I'm always running a humidifier
because it's so dry here and there are
DIY humidifiers just search on YouTube
DIY humidifier you should find a result
there and there's one in particular that
I know of that uses that tub that you
mentioned that you use for like soil and
stuff the the 2T 2 and 1/2t long tub by
what is it like a foot and a half or
something like that maybe and somebody's
making a humidifier out of that so if
you want to keep things cheap and not go
and buy a a humidifier you can certainly
build your own and that could
potentially be a cheaper option so you
might want to look into that one yeah
and then another thing too I I I
struggle sometimes depending on what
equipment I'm running I I I run a res
reservoir for water and you know
freaking water chillers are not cheap
they are stupid expensive so what I
found and what I did was a swamp cooler
um for that and what all that really is
a swamp cooler it's a fan really it's
blowing on the reservoir and I couldn't
believe just by putting a fan another
little five or 6 inch fan from Home
Depot I used a little ratchet you know
those I hung it right above my reservoir
blew it on the water dropped the
temperature considerably um it did um
evaporate some of the water so I had to
keep checking the EC and stuff like that
but uh it it helped keep the water cool
so swamp cooler if you're looking for
something to help keep your Reservoir a
little cool on the cheap Reservoir
there's another area where you can make
things cheap right I was gifted one by
flexi tank and I pull it up right here
and these things are expensive I mean 50
plus dollars for Reservoir I keep it
cheap by using a trash barrel you know I
go to a Home Depot I bought a 14 gallon
trash barrel drill the hole in the side
and then put the uh I forget what it's
called the the piece that kind of screws
in there and and you can run a hose from
there yeah 10 15 bucks for that or even
a 5 gallon bucket I have a 5 gallon
bucket that's a reservoir that I use for
some plants and those are what $3 I
think roughly at Home Depot or or Lowe's
might be able to even find them even
cheaper but uh yeah I I would never pay
money to buy one of those expensive
Reservoir unless I was in like a larger
setup you know but me being a small home
grower I would just cheap out and and
use trash barrels and drill a hole in
the side yeah I have a 32 gallon rubber
made uh garbage can and it has wheels
it's great handle Wheels I can move it
around move it's I never even thought of
that as as part of it because you're
right those reservoirs I'm thick walled
heavy duty
they're expensive you're right so yeah
no garbage can for sure and wheels too
why not make it easy 100 100% how about
Harvest drying and curing those are
processes that need to be done after the
plant is done growing you've harvested
it and then you need to move on to dry
and cure what ways do you kind of keep
it cheap with those processes yeah so
listen if if I was listen I once helped
a friend this was many years ago he did
an outdoor grow and he had
11 lbs of medicine to trim and he was
like we're going to hand trim it I go
are you crazy that's a lot I said I'll
help you but I'm like man I'm going to
take shifts and I got to take breaks and
hand trimming is by far the cheapest way
but with a bad back hand trimming is not
always a thing so what I did uh I waited
obviously to 420 and I I got a sale on
many websites sell them but here in in
town at at many of the local like um
Grow shops they had uh trimming machines
they were either crazy expensive tumbler
cool thing like these barrels that would
turn and then they had some of these
tabletop ones and they had ones that
were like the the bowl trimmer um that
you you know that that your hand cranked
it's got fingers and it does it but
they're automated and I was looking at
those and I go man this sure would save
my back I go go whoa $1,400 for a
tabletop trimmer I go no way so I went
home I started
Googling and I found a a brand that was
um it was a Chinese brand that was not
like it had no name of the company it
was just this trimmer and it was $200
and some dollars on on sale at 420 so
I'm like I got to do this and that's
what I started doing just to save the
back
because I can't hand trim just not not
possible um so I bought these but now
listen these things are very poor
quality um at this very you know bargain
price um but being handy uh it was like
thin tin metal for the legs and sure
enough the welds broke on the like 6
hours in or whatever so it was like a
man but got a piece of metal put it in
there redid it and it it still works to
this day I got to pick it up and put it
on these little [__] but that handiness
came in in in handy so um and and and
again like what are you going to do when
it's that cheap like I got both trimmers
we I call them stage one and stage two
first one is a tabletop with um like
it's just fins and you just run it over
and take all the big fan leaves off and
then that sort of automatic bow 8 in or
10in tumble Weaver I don't even know
what to call it it's not a tumbler
because those ones are like the the
barrel tumblers and they're super
expensive but I got them both for under
the same price as locally a brand name
sort of trimmer so that not offbrand
sometimes is there but you're going to
have to deal with the quality so I did
that and uh and and and listen that was
that was the best deal that I do for for
that because hand trimming wasn't
possible
now I get into well then drying well
drying I I I I got these I I don't have
space so when you don't have space you
got to do what you got to do so you get
those accordion um accordion like uh
herb dryers off of Amazon is what they
call them and they're just like you know
10 inches wide they go down into a small
thing that was the cheapest way I could
store it and and still not have like
half my basement full of the plants from
the thing right so I did that and then
um curing again into into reusable jars
that I have and and sometimes I would we
use it for peppers and stuff in the
summer from our garden and I would reuse
those um those Mason Jess buddi he's
like it's going to taste like Peppers no
it didn't we cleaned it out it was fine
um and again just reuse the stuff that I
have but
recently I've switched my thinking on
this so this is
where it's going to people are going to
be on the fence where this is indeed
cheap or not and I can tell you to start
off it wasn't cheap so uh I got into
live rosin as my best way to consume my
medicine why it's cleanest the tastiest
it's whatever but to buy that from one
of the uh Ontario stores here and man it
was anywhere from $60 to $80 for one
little small you know gram of this stuff
so I decided you know what I'm going to
do the process myself so I invested some
money into a freeze dryer and this by
far is not cheap it's about 4,000 bucks
how can you say this is cheap well I
then talked to my wife I had to talk her
into letting me buy it first she didn't
kick me out of the house cuz that was
her first idea second idea was we're
going to start a we and I say her
because it was not we uh a freeze-dried
candy
business and I bought the the the the
freeze dryer it went to her business she
now is going to write off that freeze
dryer and um she has been selling
freeze-dried candies and making a ton of
money no it's worth it's effort it's
whatever but that subsidized the cost of
getting the freeze dryer so I can use it
for my medicine and still be able to to
to get it in there so again um write off
of the machine great could have written
off the machine as a as a as a process
and doing content here on on you know
the 420 things Channel but I couldn't
have started any sort of business with
it here in Canada so the the candy
business man it's it's multi-purpose
right you you get something for for one
thing and use it for two others and
you're saving money yes it's going to
cost you a little bit but man at $60 to
$80 per unit I'm going to save money in
the long run because I go through it
quite fast so guess what $80 uh you know
every couple times it it adds up so uh
at the first year of her business in the
freeze dryer she looks like she's going
to be able to make some money off of it
whether we get into the red or green who
knows but uh it's more than more than
what we had so again it it it it it is
that process but washing it with the ice
and the water it's clean it's I I know
what I'm getting so that's worth a
little bit extra to me so again while
it's not cheap sort of is cuz now it's
paying for itself with the candy yeah
I've been watching your stories on
Instagram showing your updates on the
freeze dried candy and that you went to
your local farmers market or whatever
and and selling them and stuff and it's
been really cool to kind of follow along
and see uh you know the progress you've
been making there and seeing how you
used it multi-purpose you know use it
not just for freeze drying your own
product but using it for candies as well
on the sell I thought that was so cool
yeah man it it is and we got into a
couple stores now like we're like we had
to get health inspected and all that
stuff right so it's up like there is
some process I had to pay for insurance
and so there was extra cost on top of it
where I go ah it's a little bit more but
these again my wife is going out meeting
people and talking to people and again
getting out in the community man it is
fun and again candy is is my kids love
it and we can use fruit veget like ve
like I'm going to uh all my all so we we
have probably three rows of jalapenos we
love jalapenos here so we always pickle
them at the end of the year uh freeze
dryer now I'm not I'm not only going to
pickle I'm going to now I'm going to try
to freeze dry jalapenos because
apparently they come out once you freeze
dry them bring them back out rehydrate
them they're just like new like right
off of the stock so again I'm like wow
that's kind of cool another thing didn't
know that so yeah again savings that's
really cool getting back to harvest dry
and cure one thing I want to mention is
if you are looking to save money keep
things cheap don't buy a
krol now I have one of those it's super
convenient it does automate things when
it comes to the drying and and storage
but uh they're very expensive you can
certainly get away with the drying
process just using a tent for example or
an open room some an open room a
bathroom although I don't know there the
germs floating around in the bathroom
not sure if you're using the bathroom as
as you're trying in there but uh that
might be a concern for some people but
you can certainly just use a DIY I guess
you can call it right little grow tent
setup to where you're you've got a grow
tent you've got your humidifier
dehumidifier whatever you need and some
air circulation and that's it you don't
need to spend $1,600 on a Canon control
now I have a unit myself I actually have
two units now because I do like it and
use it but if I were try to keep things
cheap I would I would not have one of
those I would not I would not buy one of
those so and then for curing glass jars
you mentioned it it's reuse them over
and over and over again well worth the
investment in my opinion because it uh
keeps things fresh some people are kind
of split when it comes to having
humidity packs in there or not but you
can certainly store things for longer if
you have those glass mason jars and
you're reusing them as well so yeah and
and you know what I I I don't know if
you ever used those those bags that that
they they came out not that long ago but
the I think they're The Grove bags Grove
bags yeah yeah yeah I've reused those a
few times like it's the same bag over I
don't I I didn't find it was as better
like it didn't it it seemed the my
medicine wasn't as good after the second
or third time and and I'm like uh if I'm
going to buy these I went back to the
jars when I was doing that right so but
uh I don't did you ever you ever try
them ever tried reusing them yeah I've
tried them they seem to work pretty good
but I still like the jars really just to
get things in and out of them you know
opening of the bags is just I know it's
not much of a difference in in removing
product from a bag versus a jar but like
it just feels more sturdy and things
aren't kind of compacting against the
buds as much and yes so I haven't been
using the Grove bags anymore but I have
used them in the past yeah no I didn't I
just you're right kind of glass jars if
you're curing that's that's whether
they're big mason jars too like you can
get some I I didn't when I first did it
I had all these little small mason jars
not small but I mean but there's some
big old mason jars like you can get some
big ones uh from different places seems
like time of year or two to get them
would be when they're on sale like right
before like a a jarring season right
like at at at Home Depot or Canadian
Tire or whatever these places they'll
they'll beat sales on those absolutely
what a conversation this was uh so good
and TI flew by for this one for me at
least it's uh I can't believe we're
already at the hour mark so that that's
wild let's wrap things up here though
can you tell listeners how they can find
you and what you have upcoming in the
future sure sure yeah yeah yeah so uh I
you you mentioned YouTube earlier
youtube.com sl420
things um that that's my channel um I
did have more videos on there you know
how YouTube is I got to a point where I
had too many videos that were age
restricted and I had a bigger um like I
had more videos of those so I had to cut
back on that I've been spending a lot of
time on Instagram doing that there so
I'm on Instagram it's 420 things grow
because somebody already else already
had 420 things so 420 things grow and
I'm planning on going to a couple shows
and events coming months here so I'm
going to in
September uh the Stony streamer session
in Michigan I'm going to go check that
out uh meet up with Rob and couple other
guys uh I'm going to Nan in Syracuse in
October and then heading back to your
neck of the woods in Las Vegas uh in
December for some MJ biscon so I'll be
in and about and I listen I love meeting
people I love talking to people I think
probably why I went by so fast here I
don't know for you I just I love getting
to know people getting to talk to people
I can I can talk to somebody in the
elevator that I don't even like what who
are you they look at me all funny but I
like I'll have a conversation with them
right so if if you're at any of these
events coming up and you see me come on
up say hello like let's just let's shoot
the [__] have a good time awesome I'll
definitely have a link to Mike's Channel
down in the YouTube description section
below and if listen on one of the
podcast platforms just search for him
420 things he will pop right up thanks
to all the patreons I actually recently
revised the patreon it's 100% for the
garden Talk podcast this podcast here
and all the money earned through patreon
goes right back into the podcast and I'm
going to scroll the members on the
screen right now thank you you are the
one that really keeps this podcast going
so once again thank you and I do have a
question for the audience what do you do
in your garden in order to keep things
cheap let us know I'd love to know we
probably just tackled a small batch of
things here there's got to be a lot more
out there so love to hear what you have
let us know in the comments Mike thanks
so much man for coming on this was great
appreciate your time and hope you enjoy
the rest of your day yeah appreciate you
man appreciate what you do keep on doing
it and thanks for having me on Brandon
peace out everyone catch you in the next
episode