what is up everybody feel that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and today I've got a part test video for
you this is the California light works a
solar system 1100 LED grow light it has
a coverage area of a 4 foot by 4 foot
and the 10th I am taking measurements in
is a 4 foot by 4 foot this LED grow
light is compatible with the controller
I do not have the controller so the
measurements I take will just be from
plugging in the light without adjusting
the spectrum at all I actually ran this
grow light for a couple grows and those
girls are actually documented on my
youtube channel so I've had a couple
grow series using this light so if you
want to see how those plants turned out
feel free to look back at those videos
I'll take measurements at 18 inches 24
inches and then 36 inches I'm using the
apogee
MQ 500 quantum sensor this takes par
measurements in ppfd and I'm just gonna
be doing the measurements in the video
I'm not gonna be talking about it in the
features or anything like that so if you
want to learn more about this LED grill
light I will link it in the description
section below
alright let's get into the measurements
just like the other videos I won't talk
over it I'll just let the measurements
do the talking
[Music]