what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you're watching my extra channel
here I've got the California light works
solar extreme 500 LED grow light in this
video I'm gonna measure the power output
I won't be talking about any of the
grill lights features in this video I
actually recently released a video where
I unbox the unit and talk about some of
the features I'll link that video in the
description section below so you can
check it out for the part tests I'll be
using the Apple gmq 500 power meter this
meter shows measurements and ppfd and it
measures from 389 nanometers to 692
nanometers plus or minus 5 nanometers if
this girl light is emitting any light
that's outside of that range it will not
show on this meter and this is really
just to give you a general idea of what
the power output is for this light it's
not going to be exact I do have this
grow light in a grow tent which has
reflective walls so that could increase
the numbers I also have the grow tent
door opened so we're not getting the
reflective on one side I have this light
in a 4 foot by 4 foot grow tent which is
actually the coverage area for this grow
light and I'll be doing two distances 18
inches away which is for flowering and
24 inches which is for vegetation both
of these distances are recommended by
the manufacturer just like all the other
part test videos that I create I will
let the measurements do the talking
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
I will leave a link to this grow light
in the description section below and I
will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
[Music]