coming up on garden talk if it keeps
raining and you're like damn i gotta
water in my liquid nutrients i got to
get nutrition in there that could be a
conundrum because your plant's wet
already and that's why it's good to
cover yourself with well it's been
raining but i did have some top dress
thinning outside thinning your plants
out when you're out there scouting for
pests you're not going crazy through
like you got to thin it out a little for
air movement and not creating
microclimates uh for pests microbes man
game changer for the grow you can do a
lot better and don't think it's a
misconception i used to think this as
well like oh i'm using synthetic
nutrients or salt-based nutrients or
this it's just it's not going to work
well the microbes they can work together
for sure in your grow media grow your
plants as happy and healthy as possible
and that helps a ton with pests a plant
that's ailing or showing signs like the
pests know they'll come to that they'll
have an easier chance of taking it out
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden dog
podcast this episode number 29. in this
episode i interview dude from the do
grow show he has been gardening for 18
years and he grows a variety of plants
such as peppers tomatoes arugula
strawberries and medicinal varieties he
also has a show which i'm sure many of
you are familiar with called the dude
grow show the show has been around since
2013 and so far there have been over
1200 episodes in this podcast episode we
talk about outdoor gardening dude talks
about his style of outdoor gardening and
some of the challenges that can be faced
when gardening outdoors thanks to all of
you who support this podcast through
patreon if you'd like to support you
could do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible a big supporter of this podcast
is ac infiniti they sponsor this podcast
and i use their products ac infinity now
has gardening tools and accessories such
as heavy duty fabric grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr growit during
checkout for a discount on their
products big shout out to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is a
plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products
thanks to spider farmer for sponsoring
this podcast they have board style led
grow lights bar style led grow lights
grow tents
in-line fans and carbon filters they
also have complete grow tank kits which
include lighting a ventilation system
grow pots a trellis net a timer
and a monitor for both temperature and
humidity coupon code mr growit5 will get
you a discount on their products and
i'll leave a link to their amazon store
down in the description section below
okay now let's get into the episode
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with dude from the dude grow show how
you doing today excellent man thank you
for having me on here always love a
little grow talk you know it's just uh
yeah it makes me feel irie inside happy
to have you i was just on your show a
great time a lot of positive feedback in
the comments section there people really
like to see these collabs happen it
seems like we get more and more c
positive feedback in the comments
section about collaborations going on
the community so i appreciate you coming
on and collab in here we're gonna get to
know about you and uh kind of your grow
style with outdoor growing we'll talk
about some challenges with outdoor
growing yeah it should be an
action-packed talk so to begin can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
kind of how you got into gardening hmm
gardening
i don't know first came to me is
i want to say challenges but sometimes i
thought i could do things better with
plants i mean the very way back in the
day would be my dad had tropical plants
in the house and when you have tropical
plants in the house so
my my first plant was a tropical plant
in my bedroom i'm like we got to get
some ambiance in here you know just a
little bit of uh make this nice and then
the lead from there
to really i've always liked hot stuff
hot sauce me and my brother would
challenge each other with who could eat
the hot jalapenos out of the jar
and then i was like dude i can probably
just grow some habaneros and that turned
into just messing with people right
drying them making hot powders habanero
pepper eating challenges
and then i guess finally just getting
into
yeah the value of medicinal plants um
was what really when i started to grow
indoors um and then recently not
recently but later in my growing career
had the opportunity in colorado to get
some grows under my belt outdoors i'm
just on the backyard level you know for
you know medicinal garden for myself but
that's it in a nutshell nice i have yet
to grow peppers i actually planted a
couple pepper seeds actually i have the
seeds right here they're uh bullnose
pepper from baker creek so um
i planted like four of them and they
didn't sprout so i gotta give another
shot one thing that was really cool
about peppers that i found out is like
you can grow them in small containers
and get like a decent personal yield out
of it like one gallon containers so i
thought that was cool you definitely can
i'll give you a quick tip i had some
seeds have been harder for me to start
for peppers and do it did you do like a
soak i did the paper towel soak with
them for probably at least
i was thinking it was two to maybe four
days keeping it soaked watching them
just just to start to get them to pop a
little and get their first little tail a
little root coming out and then i
planted them had much better success i
have to give that a try
yeah across the board for a bunch of
different seeds that actually can can
help out help get them excited to go
yeah i'm definitely gonna have to give
it another shot because peppers is
definitely something i want to grow um
you know not just those bull nose wands
or or bell style peppers or habaneros
it's endless
carolina reapers right that'd be cool to
grow one of those eventually
nice cool so do you typically grow
indoors outdoors or both both um so it
would be
indoors typically all the time except
for when it's summertime i have a
it's whether it's been a grow room
currently have a five by five grow tent
that i have out in my garage so
summertime i find it convenient wherever
your indoor grow i like to enjoy i call
it summer summer summertime and like i'm
usually so busy with the outdoor growing
going on in summer time that to have
to deal with both responsibilities as
well as the cleanliness you should be
doing when going between the two because
it's really easy to run around and just
go into your tent and go out so right
now outside for me
i only have two very small medicinal
plants because they're only in one
gallons right now i basically said i'm
going to quit growing my medicinal
plants outside where i'm at because of
the problems i've ran i'm in vancouver
british columbia here compared to
growing outside in colorado a whole
different animal
but i do keep busy with
like you said before i go peppers
outside every year strawberries actually
i've gotten into strawberry i've gone
strawberry basket crazy because i love
it keeps them one at head height for
when you're walking around to see what's
ready to pick and just
and then
two it can help keep a lot of different
pests away from them and then lastly a
bunch of tomatoes i don't eat tomatoes
my neighbor's like what you don't what
are you doing i'm like hey they're for
you they're for the wife they're for
gifting to the neighbors um but yeah
that'd be what's going on what's going
on as far as what i'm growing right now
uh but yeah no indoors not until fall
things got to cool off too sometimes
summer can just be too hot for the
indoor growers to have the proper
equipment
to maintain all that gotcha now on the
kind of medicinal plant side of things
are you the type of person that chases
after yield or did you kind of let the
plants do their thing and not really
worry about yield as much you're gonna
get yield typically outdoors i mean
we're talking like
these things love love to grow i'm not
ever usually chasing the old first it's
gonna know what you're starting with
what either you're starting with a
quality source seeds
or maybe some trusted cuts
so
chasing plant health first and foremost
but yield outside
people should remember when you're
thinking about grow medicinal plants
outside what what is your goal how much
is this just to try to see if you have a
green thumb and how which i believe
everybody has some sort of green it's
it's genetic it's in you um but
since you can get a lot of yield i mean
you could grow three five gallon plants
and depending on people's consumption
uh be good to go until the next season
around so and that being said upscaling
that you could grow two 20 gallon plants
you're like oh my god this is too much
too big
uh so no don't chase yield
but
yeah mainly know what i'm starting with
is super important what what potential
it has and that it's good genetics
gotcha
let's focus on growing outdoors really i
want to get into your style of growing i
want to start with with ipm and some of
my viewers are going to laugh at this
because usually ipm's at the very end
and i'm like hey we probably should have
started with ipm because it's just it's
so important and for those that don't
know ipm integrated pest management in
layman's terms it's really just things
that you do in order to prevent pests
right so um tell me what do you
typically do in order to prevent pests
well i like the last word in that it's
management right so
you're trying to prevent you're gonna
have pests outside
if you know your area if you have the
opportunity to talk to different growers
or even maybe some of the pests you'll
see on other garden plants you might get
an idea of what you're going to have to
deal with
so for me here i didn't talk to many
growers the area in vancouver especially
i'm in a little micro climate where i
live
tons of humidity and pests that kick my
butt are always new ones to me it's for
here it was called the corn ear worm on
my outdoor buds never dealt with that
before i had no clue
most important thing i'd say for ipm on
outdoors since we are in an environment
that we're not controlling as much as
the indoors is being there and scouting
also being able to thin out your plants
they can get so big and bushy so you
have air movement
depending on the size of them but
scouting and looking around because it
can be nice you could go by you can go
outdoors for two weeks maybe a month and
be walking around looking at your grow
and have no problems because nature's in
balance things are taking care of things
but then eventually what what happened
to me because i had a nice hops plant i
was growing some hops just to look cool
i'm not going to do anything with them
unfortunately i didn't have time to brew
as well
but
that brought in some aphids
which in turn they actually is this hops
plant was right next to medicinal plant
the aphids just preferred it for like a
few weeks they just stayed on it i'm
like okay if that was an indicator point
i'll call that then i'll leave them
alone to be there and eventually of
course they work their way over
um because i wanted to see what's
happened and then i i got a ton of
ladybugs ladybugs can be really good
outside for aphids especially since
they're big enough to watch them just go
on in and eat those suckers i'll just
stand out there with like hanging out
maybe with a pine or whatnot and just
watch them go to war and that was
refreshing when you can see the bugs are
big enough some of our predatory insects
aren't big enough to enjoy that but when
you can see them eating the bugs that
are going to bug your plant
that's really good i mean we can go as
deep as you want with ipm outdoors as
far as what to do when we we see pests
and whatnot but that's first off
scouting makes sense now are you also i
mean important pieces to check the
undersides of the leaves right i mean
yeah how do we do that for sure
underside of the leaves you're going to
want to be looking there a lot of bugs
i won't even say that i was going to say
a lot of bugs you can see by the naked
eye but you do need a loop i ran into
hemp rust that's outside one time
and you do need a magnification to see
those
spider mites like to start from my
notice on the lower parts of the plant
on the underside of the leaves
before you start to see a bunch of
damage going up the plant you can
usually catch them when you do run if we
want to do a preventative maintenance
let's let's say you notice maybe a few
aphids or a few spider mites so if we're
in veg we can the preventative spray i
know you like me i like neem as well i
actually don't mind the smell of neem at
all it's supernatural it's inexpensive
easy to apply
um but doing a type of spray program
once every week
isn't bad but i don't want to spray
anything that's going to hurt also if
things again i said are working like in
balance like nature the bugs are taking
care of each other i have a few i don't
want to hurt anything that's doing a
good job either
but predators outside
people that know okay this is my second
year and last year i got these predators
aren't cheap you got to get them quick
you got to get them viable if you know
you have a problem putting predators out
definitely are a good idea in the
outdoor environment um there's a lot of
good places uh to source those you can
go to local insectaries to search
beneficial insect insectaries on google
you'll pull up some options i don't know
if you've had anybody on or anything to
recommend but um yeah then there's
arbico organics i'll just throw that one
off the top i know they have a lot of
information on their site as far as
identifying predators which ones will
work good for you
and uh yeah
so that would be that would be it so
once a week spray is it just neem using
or using any other type of products um i
do like to use for me i use neem or for
whatever i'm spraying
typically i'll use a type of wetting
agent uh mine's optic foiler has a
product called trans transport
which i use
and that once a week spray i'm talking
about you know if i if i'm battling
something we got to break its cycle so
if we got spider mites and eggs are
hatching every three days and there's
variations there how hot is it out how
cold is it out is really going to affect
the cycle of some of these things but
you do have to spray if we're trying to
we've identified pests that want to take
care of them spraying every three days
for out i'm going to go for probably at
least 10 days to two weeks should break
their cycle
that being said you can choose both
methods though if you have a garden that
you're like you don't necessarily want
to spray and you have access to see what
the beneficials can do for you
i recommend going that route too i
usually will do a combination of both
when i add hemp brusset mites i'm doing
a spray i'm going to beat down the
population i'm going to assume which is
the number one downfall for people
spraying for pests it's really hard to
reach everywhere in your garden you have
to make contact
and that can be problematic so first
i'll do the spray cycle and then after
that i'll maybe do two releases of
beneficials just to hang out man maybe i
missed some eggs and things are gonna
hatch and that has always worked for me
just to take care of most pests and
pests for me
outside have been aphids those are
pretty easy they're sizable i haven't
gotten thrips outside i've seen some
spider mites hemp russet mites in
colorado they are just i don't know
they're popular for a little bit
but we can go into the other things too
where i talked about here
in british columbia bud rot
molds mildew oh my god nightmares
literally nightmares for me we'll save
that for the end we'll talk about some
of the other challenges that are going
on beyond pests uh yeah because that'll
be a real good conversation bud run in
particular because i've experienced that
as well so i can also speak about that
one forgot to mention um
this kind of ties into maybe you can
tell me if something else you're asking
me but healthy plants grow your plants
as happy and healthy as possible and
that helps a ton with pests
um you know a plant that's alien or
showing signs like the pets know they'll
come to that they'll have an easier
chance of taking it out so yeah i had
chad westport on my podcast a couple
weeks ago and he talked about bricks and
kind of how you can measure the sugar
content in the plant and if your brix
level is 12 or above then um pests don't
attack the plants which i thought was
pretty interesting so it's another way
to kind of
kind of see the health of your plant is
bricks
for those that don't know might want to
research a little bit more on that one
cool let's switch it up let's talk about
your media what are you using for uh
what's in your mix that can vary
definitely we're talking okay we're
outdoors
it's a lot of times can be what's
available to you and you look where you
live are you you live in colorado and
there's like 25 hydro store options
around you
that can be a variable for sure a base
for me would probably be uh the hp pro
mix bale of peat right that's because
it's just you can get a lot out of that
veil
it's compact and it's usually available
even at nurseries if you don't have
local grow stores and stuff
and then into pete i don't make a super
soil but i do like to put things in a
little bit warm cast just some basics
let's put some organics in our soil warm
castings are good to mix in
you could do a 20 mix of worm castings
you could do a 10 mix it's your call
there's a lot of recipes out there
which is going to give you some
nutrition it's going to give a diversity
in your bacteria and your living soil
other things i know you're a fan of when
we had you on insect frass it's just a
cool product i'm learning more about it
mixing that in your soil
also works really well i have been
cutting on and off playing with cutting
some cocoa into the peat it seems to
help with its like water inability peat
gets hydrophobic if you don't catch it
quick enough for your water on the top
or it sucks in a little from the side of
your containers
um and then you gotta the water kind of
beads off for a minute until absorbs in
uh different ratios of cocoa i've messed
with i've done like 25 cocoa to peat
ratio and it does help with that water
and inability which i've liked
so and that's it i don't usually mix in
a lot more organics i usually don't go
to i'm not a living soil grower although
i do like to put some things in my soil
and leave room in my containers to do
top dresses
um
and then after that
yeah that would be the base of my mix
i'm trying to think of anything i'm
forgetting that i like to put in there
because like again sometimes it it does
vary oh some compost if there is some
nice compost i don't mind mixing in
another 10 compost
as well and all this just helps the
overall mix i know some people do some
additional aeration due to anything like
uh
perlite
there's enough in uh at that specific
pete perlite
uh for sure and most if you don't
if you're getting a straight pete then
yeah i would be adding in perlite for
sure i would say
20 again there's a lot of good recipes
out there search around uh shout out to
build a soil they got some good recipes
they actually have if you want to get
that bale of heat you can just get a
nutrient to men kit it's like in the
instructions it makes it really easy so
you don't have to go out source all
these different nutrients if you're
trying to do somewhat of a living soil
and when i say living soil everybody
typically i shouldn't say everyone
typically knows it's a nose but a an
enriched soil that's going to be you're
relying on your soil more to feed your
plants than you putting liquid or other
nutrient inputs in great point now how
about container size what do you
typically
start in what do you typically end up in
i mean that's like what kind of car do
you like because there's so many
variables with container size
um we just talked about this again when
you're on our show shout out to coming
on the dude grow show but what
how are you going to feed your plant
i've noticed and i'm learning my peppers
that i have now which is i think almost
too small are in one gallon containers
right
you got to feed those a lot one gallon
isn't as we call it a big enough battery
like it's just not it can't hold enough
organic matter nutrition whatever that
gets fed liquid nutrients uh quite often
the bigger your container the bigger
battery
but if you could have an enriched mix
let's say but i'm going to tell people
man it's still relevant i was going to
tell people to do at least a 10 gallon
outside but you can see
somebody that just has maybe a small
apartment with a balcony and they do
three autoflowers
in a uh
in three gals
you know what i mean
so
but i guess we're here i'm talking about
my style i like to go at least
i'm gonna say 20 to 25 gallon if i can
outside you don't want to be chasing
after water on hot days depending on
your irrigation setup
so the smaller the container on hotter
days the more you have to water
you do have to keep on them more with
feeding
so
bigger is going to be better smaller
usually has a little bit more work on
your end a little bit more maintenance
uh and yeah and container type i like
i don't like the black nursery
containers man they just it's like i
wish they made them white which is
probably more expensive on hot days they
sit there you can touch the side of a
black nursery container and i just feel
like my roots and my rhizosphere and my
plants just going to be upset about that
and require more maintenance more water
so
fabric pots are great there's all kinds
of brands out there
uh there's different i use product
called radical bags it's kind of like a
mesh pvc fabric type thing
but yeah container size as well as is
import container type i've seen people
kill it in the five gallon home depot
buckets though you know or you see
people planting the 30 gallon rubber
made trash can i love it just the
monstrous tree
are you
just planting that seed directly into
that 20 gallon or are you starting in a
small
pot for sure
what's your transplanting
method or techniques like when do you
transplant uh so
you could go outside
pretty early or not it depends um where
i want to end up but i'll just say i go
into first typical for a lot of people a
one gallon nursery pot size container
i will start a plant in there you can
keep a plant in there for as long as you
want and watch it get angry and hold it
back or keep topping it but when i go i
go from that one gal which is gonna be
not fully root bound but like ready to
go whatever i put it in and i'm gonna
put that one gal probably into my
finishing container i know some people
so if i go from a one gal boom i'm gonna
go outside into my 25 gal you don't want
to over water that it could be easy to
do but i skip the one maybe people would
go to a five
and then to the bigger size container
because i just don't want to up pot and
do it's not that labor intensive for me
because i'm not doing that many plants
but i like to go from the one gal to my
finishing size whether that might be a
five mine is going to be at least a 20
to 25 gal and i know that's not as as uh
best nursery practices i think it's
caller scotty what is he called
something best management nursery
practices they're they're typically
they're going like
one three five or one they're like
they're keeping it all and that can keep
your plant chugging along a little bit
better uh but yeah this is my transplant
schedule i i think it comes down to
personal preference i mean some people
have space control constraints they're
going to start indoors and they're going
to stay in that small container they're
going to try to stay as a small
container as possible and then you know
transplant some folks don't want to like
you mentioned over watering would be a
thing that could happen if you have this
small plant in a large container so
it comes down to personal preference in
my opinion on transplanting what
container size to use so on and so forth
i don't like to deter anybody on i mean
this is talking about my girl style like
i said before
oh you're saying at least a 20 or 25 man
you can do a one gal if you want you
could try all kinds of stuff um that's
one thing about as far as these
medicinal plants they love to grow
outside when you have you know you're
not worried about having the the
expensive nice grow light you got the
best girl out on earth the sun kicking
butt for you um it's it's hard to kill
these things they love to grow and
there's a lot of ways to do it so do it
my way is not always
there's a lot of different styles i want
to throw in there well said
now how about nutrients what do you
typically use for base nutrients and
additives
all right so base nutrients and
so my base nutrients so my mix initially
it's not that enriched right it's the
the base peat some cocoa we're going to
get a little nutrition from the worm
castings not much a little nutrition
from the insect frass
and that could last me maybe a few
waterings or whatever but i have to get
water in this thing with some nutrients
right away
i usually use a set of bottles lacing
recently um actually for like the past
three or four years i've been using uh
ramos nutrients nutrient line and just
it's a basic i can follow the feed chart
it's eight or five mils of all the
product that's light though like i'm not
going to a high
ppm the highest parts per million so ppm
and ec is how you guys measure your what
how much nutrient is in your your
solution if you don't have that pen
you're looking at a feed chart you're
like well i put in x you know you're
probably going to be within the range um
that they want you to be in
but that's that's not my only nutrition
and some people will be like that's
pretty low 700 parts per million
well then i'm also going to take a break
with some of my as we say the fish
brings the dank maybe i'm going to add
in so there's a bunch of different fish
fertilizers out there a little bit of
fish because i like to diversify what
inputs i'm putting in and i believe you
know i like some of the thicker funkier
products at times
or top dressing i know you like the top
dress
um i used to before i start stopped
using bat guano i do need to do more
research into
i think i saw an uh like a scary
documentary on netflix where i'm like
this is how they get the sea bird like i
don't know man and how the people in
their camps it just didn't seem cool to
me i'll look into it a little more but
when i had back guano it's a good um
bone actually i think i have fish bone
meal now which is a byproduct of the
fishing industry which is a high
phosphorus i'll take these products and
i'll do a top dress at different points
in the grow maybe it's blooms really
coming on
just to feed the plant in all different
ways i feel like i'm giving it's that
the word synganic uh or you're feeding
synthetically or salt-based nutrients
and organically or just you know
nutrients and i do stay away from meals
i get a little freaked out of uh big ag
bone meal blood meal just i don't know
i i need to learn more about what
possibly might be in those byproducts i
don't know if any of the antibiotics or
funkiness from that industry comes over
but i don't i have other things i can
use in my garden where i don't need to
use those so
i'm trying to think what else i do have
some favorite like i don't know if you
do like do you water in with any bottles
at all yeah sometimes yeah yeah do you
have any favorite bloom additives or
something like that's the typical
additive or that you would use i used to
use back in the days to use
a pk booster used to use beastie blooms
by fox farm when i was using the fox
farm lineup and that that helped
and it was always when i worked
hydroponic retail it would be one of the
most hottest like people be like all
right i'm a month into flower what kind
of boost does he got like let's what
kind of boost oh this is a zero 60 you
know like they just get pumped but it's
not all about that i do really like it's
kind of a unique one
massive from green planet is a
like a trichantinol type and there's
more in it than that i don't even know
if they can market it as that
but it's one i really dig on i'm trying
to think what other bloom boost is
typically if you have your base
nutrition really rocked though it's not
about doing a big on booster you can
mess up things in your isosphere you can
kind of i think affect what's going on
with the microbes if you go too high in
with phosphorus
so watch that but yeah that would be one
of my my many main additives and of
course i haven't said it in any of this
i use re i know you like recharge i use
recharge across throughout the grow
that's one of the things that in a
roundabout way for me ties into ipm
recharge guys is just a
microbial inoculant if you aren't using
microbes you want to be adding microbes
we only have so much time with this
plant right to get it right uh and kick
out a good a good crop are there any
other microbial nockins you use beyond
recharge and do you use any sugars like
some people use molasses honey brown
sugar did you do any of that or
um recharge has enough molasses in it
where i don't need to add another sugar
sugar guys it's going to feed the
microbes i like to diversify my sugars
because i think if i'm a microbe maybe i
want to eat something different than
molasses today that's where i get into
god i don't know the name fox farm has
uh they have a lion something like a
bembe or bimbe line maybe it's actually
called bimbe it's like a sugar
uh from i believe from beets
i was like interesting okay i can
picture maybe some maybe some of the
microbes and this is kind of bro science
or just me making myself a microbe will
be more turned on by eating some of this
beet sugar today and do some type of
different attribute in my my terpene
profile you know
um so other than that what other sugars
have i used
just those two mainly as far as a sugar
to feed them microbes
yeah another micro product sorry you
asked um i did i haven't since just
availability up here microbes in canada
are really good it's just goofy
regulation thing hard to get their hands
on some um
oh mammoth p damn i don't know i'm
stumbling on that mammoth p i've used on
and off uh as well
and i have it in a while but i would
still recommend
at transplant there are some cool i
don't know if you know any but um
mycorrhizae products that are
specifically one strain i think the
intradices that it's nice at transplant
to get that
on i think mycos when you can get that
on the root zone when you're actually
transplanting you can put some
mycorrhizae in the hole make sure you
get that connection that's one good time
to use another type of that's actually a
fungi mycorrhizae i pretty much use the
same products i think the the mammoth p
and recharge combination is incredible i
mean they both just work so well
together you know i remember using
recharging mammoth p several grows ago
and
taking it out of the one gallon
container uh the roots were just
so amazingly pearly white like beautiful
and just
i i never got that before you know using
recharge you know
so uh in mammoth p together so i highly
recommend that combination for anybody
who is interested in
you know using trying out some new micro
products learn about microbes too if you
guys you don't have to learn a ton but
um that wasn't like i don't know my top
three i don't know if it was led
lighting co2 and microbes off the top my
head but microbes man game changer for
the grow you're gonna do a lot better
and don't think it's a misconception um
i used to think this as well like oh
well i'm using synthetic nutrients or
salt-based nutrients or this it's just
it's not going to work well with the
microbes they can work together for sure
in your grow media
so yeah look into that if you're not
it'll it'll help you grow great point
now you mentioned one other thing on
feeding i know you mentioned ramo
nutrients and you measure mention these
other things you're doing some top
feeding fish so on and so forth are you
following the feeding schedule for remo
nutrients at all or are you doing a
reduced dose or are you not looking at
that feeding schedule i try to just have
a plan i mean i feel the feeding
schedule as a basis their line
specifically
um it's super easy because it's always
the same amount
across the board doesn't matter what
bottle you're using until
you know if you you can start off at
five mils and that gives you this ppm
and then you can go up to eight mils or
you can go up to ten mils so it depends
on what you're doing
so i don't follow a feeding schedule
particularly um as far as a new grower
sometimes it's nice to say okay here's a
nutrient line let me hand you their
feeding schedule you follow this and you
should be good and that's right you
should be good
know your quality your quality your
water starting points if you can if
you're on a well or whatever you're on
it is nice to know to get either a water
test
know your starting pp or a ph my
starting ph is seven i'm on a well here
in british columbia my ppms off the tap
are i think one it's like the water's so
good here
there's nothing in it but to know that
starting point is good
for sure and then after that you should
succeed the only thing that'll mess up a
feeding chart
is if you have hiccups in the grow and
you you need to slow down on something
or you need to not feed
um and then outside speaking of all this
i don't know if this ties into something
you got coming up
if your plants aren't protected from
weather and rain
rain alone is going to
adjust like if it keeps raining and
you're like damn i gotta water in my
liquid nutrients i gotta get nutrition
in there
that can be a conundrum because your
plants wet already
and that's why it's good to cover
yourself with well it's been raining but
i did have some top dress so that's kind
of like a tip there if you know you got
some weather coming because it could
rain for like a week straight happen to
be in colorado plants are always wet i
can't add any nutrition
nor are they probably going crazy at
that point it's cloudy out it's been
raining on them but if you can't add
nutrition and no weather's coming you
can always top dress some nutrition as
well and that doesn't even have to be
organic amendments they have vegetable
granular fertilizer out there or it's
just like osmocote type stuff we just
sprinkle a little on there and you know
if you you water through with plain
water you're going to get nutrition if
that answered your question with the
feeding chart
yeah i'm not rambling i got my cold brew
kicking in here a little caffeine going
so just if you cut me off at all i don't
know no that's all good you're actually
ahead of the game a little bit my next
question was going to be about water and
you touched on well water uh you know
your water source is clean going in
which is good my next question was going
to be talking about ph
now as your ph good like what does it
come in at to begin and are you doing
any sort of adjustments are you
monitoring it all or
okay i got that just quick with the well
water if you guys got hard well like if
you got high ppm in your well water
let's say you get a little pen and it's
like holy it's like at 400 500 600
it's good to know what's in there i
think i haven't had to deal with it i'm
no expert a lot of times i think it
could be calcium there are different
liquid nutrients that um you can adjust
your nutrients to that ppm so you're not
giving too much of one thing or the
other but if you do have that high of
ppm i would like to know what's in there
i would consider a water test if that's
going to be your main source or after
that if you don't you got to look at a
water filtration system such as ro which
gives you a zero starting point that's
why uh when
commercial facilities when they got to
replicate their feeding plan across
multiple facilities or anything
everybody has the same ro system so when
the lead grower over here is looking
over here he knows everybody's starting
at the same point at least with
nutrients so if you do have or even city
water not just well water check that man
i've heard of some people say they're i
don't know what's your do you know what
your ppm is where you're at is it high
my tap is like 485
yeah do you know what now what what's in
there or what does that uh i mean i have
the water report that i get from the
from the city but i don't i
don't know i know what i can't always
trust that either so many it seems like
variables with what's in the pipes
between here and there and the other
thing
but anyway check that guys know your
water report then you asked about ph my
starting ph is seven
um i don't know most nutrients i don't
know about most rainbow nutrients buffer
down typically i think they anticipate
a seven-ish starting point because i
always brings me down within range which
is going to be upper fives five point
nine to six point i'll order in 5.9 to
6.45
or even high excuse me even higher if
you have a lot of microbes active
they're going to help buffer out and
take care of this if you're a little out
of range okay and then you touched on
ppm and ec earlier a little bit you
threw out a couple values i knew
throughout 700 ppm can you tell me like
what values you aim for like some people
will start with a low ppm during
seedling stage then they'll kind of work
their way up can you tell me kind of
your strategy for ppm or ec
yeah i think uh it's been overdone a lot
with the people like to push medicinal
plants super hard to get the most they
can out of it and then
maybe you should
come on back and try to go lower mine
would be okay early veg i'm around
you know three four hundred prime time
veg meaning man these things are going
everything's happy i could go you can go
up to
i'm still staying probably around though
five to six hundred and i'm not saying
if you went higher it might
this can be strain dependent as well
depending on your plants
um
but
750 to 800 is what i max out out at and
i don't see
i see not diminish i guess diminishing
returns might be the right phrase when i
go higher i'm not seeing more come out
of the plant
you can mess with it of course if you're
growing the same type of plant season
after season but if you change up the
strain or the plant type then you just
how do you track that but less seems to
be more typically i'll say not all of
them nutrient companies want to put down
like what they're not going to put down
the least amount you could use i mean
they i'm not saying they're there to rip
you off
um but they're going to go a little bit
on the higher end sometimes the nutrient
charts offer three different levels i've
seen like it's funny some will be like
are you at the master level are you at
the pro level are you at the beginner
level which i don't know why they work
like that
but less is more see what your plant
don't overdo it under doing it's a
little better i mean if you want to try
and bump up at different times go for it
but again using microbes i keep going
there
that helps with nutrition across the
board and i have not needed high ppm at
all since doing that i'm always lower
than the feed chart and if you don't
want to mess with all that you're
intimidated by that you don't have to
you put a plant out in a container with
some enriched soil some compost
water in some microbes and you know
there's also just
bagged soil out there that uh ocean
forest is the most commonly available
across the nation or i've heard
different growers granted uh it's not
going to work for all strains but man
all they did is water in with some ocean
forest which is enriched soil and i
gotta harvest uh you probably can do
better you're probably gonna run out of
nutrition getting towards middle towards
the end but this it can be real easy or
easier than worrying about ppm ph but i
grow synganic so both values i'm taking
care of all of it gotcha let's flip up
and talk about plant training so what
plant training techniques do you
typically do in outdoors on it outside
when these things want to grow like
beasts i mean
you can do a lot of different training
tactics i mean if it's uh
first would be
you're going to want to top a bit uh
because these plants you're going to
when you're going to go to bloom
in colorado it was around mid-august i'd
start to see flowers come in i'd assume
i was two weeks in um i wouldn't i would
want my plants to be and this is
relevant to uh you know how big of
plants you can grow but i would top them
back like three or four times top in
your plant you're taking off x amount of
the top of your plant down to a node um
and you can you know google that out and
see exactly it's pretty easy to do
the only time you you don't want to do
this if you know like oh man i'm going
to be going to bloom probably in about
10 days for me i set that date at august
15th so the last time i do some topping
would be maybe august 1st so i have a
little bit of recovery time for new
shoots to come out
and everything to be good but keep in
mind you're going to gain at least i'm
going to say across the board two feet
if not three feet maybe four feet when
you get into bloom and that's when
training can come in too
where you're doing you're bending over
you can literally
make sure your plants properly watered
and healthy bending over your stems some
people will just bend to not get a break
sometimes i even bend to get a little
bit of a break in the stem because i
know how quick these are going to
recover
you can do tie down method where you're
taking part of a plant and you're
bending it way over here maybe because
it needs to stay below a fence
and also thinning outside thinning your
plants out to get rid of those micro
climates when you're out there scouting
for pests
you're not going crazy through like you
gotta thin it out a little for air
movement and not creating micro climates
uh for pests and speaking about the
fence uh the having the plant not grow
over the fence i think you got i got
some some good comments on whatever
outdoor security your neighbors that
kind of thing as well i think you have a
question on here i know some people who
swear by the 45 degree angle method they
just do this one outdoors particular
they just do a one bend of that bean
chute at 45 degrees that's going to
allow the lowers to come up which i
thought was pretty interesting it really
helps create more shoots coming up so
it's not just like a christmas tree
style that you typically see
so that's one basic easy thing that you
can do for for training um you know when
growing outdoors you can do it indoors
too sure but um we're you know we're
focusing on outdoors on this video now
what about uh more more so pruning
defoliation lollipopping do you do any
of that stuff growing outdoors yeah for
sure defoliation i mean that was tying
into kind of where i'm talking about
thinning out your canopy thinning out
your mid lollipopping like you said
definitely that's bringing up your lower
branches
so again that can be an area where if
you have that all thick down there where
you might get a problem at the soil i
like to see my soil level
i was about to say i like to put sticky
traps out at soil level but that's more
for indoors for me sticky traps outside
i feel like i'm catching some good guys
too and it hurts my feelings but
um yeah pruning your plant up
lollipopping it up uh definitely
important you'll get even more of those
shoots it was hard for me as a new
grower to cut off a lot of the lower
ones because it's like oh there's going
to be some good flour on here or here
but really
taking those off and i don't like to
fully like pop it up two or three feet
but taking a lot of those off
to enable to send that energy and to
send all that to the upper parts of the
plant uh works great let's get into
challenges growing outdoors so
indoors outdoors totally different
battlefield i mean we already talked
about pests that's one challenge you
gotta face
i just i was just scrolling my notes i
didn't want to mention one other thing
before i forget about ipm uh we don't
have this option as much on the indoors
and outside if it doesn't i mean
depending my plants are usually always
covered outside which we can get into
but spraying your plant taking the hose
and just
giving your plants a really good wash i
mean it's a sim plus you're gonna get
naturally outside you'll get some type
of dust or pollen or you'd be actually
for me here now in british columbia
smoke particles some fires going on
somewhere washing your plants is a good
idea and same it'll wash off potential
negative egg sacs or pests that are
bothering stuff and it's super easy to
do even if it was once every other day
and just just clean off your outside
garden it's a good a good tip
sorry no all good so you just blast them
with plain water now when you say wash
your plants are you also talking about
bud washing at the end after harvesting
i haven't done bud washing and when you
wash your plants it'll show your weak
points and where you might not have them
staked up properly as well because
sometimes they'll just bend way over
whatever but
get that those plants staked up with
bamboo
bud washing i mean it's it's not the end
of the world if your buds get wet um if
they get rained on but i don't
intentionally try to wash buds at any
point with the yeah pressurized
pressurized water okay now some of the
other challenges that you've faced uh
growing outdoors um like i was
mentioning is this there's so many
different things beyond pests one of the
things that you had mentioned earlier
was bud rod you want to talk about bud
rod a little bit
sure because that was one that just came
i mean there's a few different types
like bud rot
can be
just some rot in the bud that you get
from a type of
like bacteria or mold i believe
sometimes just buds that are really big
and dense i grew big bud crossed with
white widow outside and the buds were so
big and beautiful looking and i didn't
know i had the rod um and this was in
colorado until i started trimming and i
was like oh that's when it's really
disappointing because i wasn't even
anticipating it
and
for me it came from corn ear worms corn
ear worms
if i understand right i'm trying to
recall is i believe a moth that lay like
an egg or something and then this thing
comes it's a caterpillar and the
caterpillar looking thing just goes
around throughout your bud and when it
does it shits
and then we have
the feces from the caterpillar in there
which creates the rot
um well it's so that was kind of
interesting it wasn't actually this
caterpillar would be like a half inch
long
it going around causing it was actually
it's
taking a dump my flowers that caused the
problem i did not have my flowers
protected there's different ways you
could try and handle it um bti bacillus
terengensis subspecies israeli insist is
a product
interesting enough though these things
have become resistant to it on and off
because everybody uses it and the corn
earworm usually
affects corn crops but it's found in the
medicinal plants some of the flower
structure i don't know if it thinks
maybe the moths like that looks like a
corn stalk or not but it messes with it
and the only way for this one that i
have found maybe when i try to set up a
grow next season a little bit smaller is
putting out the fine bug netting that
you can buy for agricultural purposes
and therefore these moss and things
cannot fly into your plants
because it's just such a bummer i mean i
and then i did get a little pm
and there's not a lot you can do i mean
you can grow plants actually i could
take that back there are plants there
are
breeders for different areas
that you might be able to get a strain
that is less susceptible to that type of
issue i always cite an instance on the
indoor
indoor grow tent back in the day i had
four plants in it
three of them
completely got pm like it was horrible
and one of them same tent leave share in
space and never got it i was like this
is interesting these are all the same
type of plant but different strains and
this one just won't get it so there's an
example of
pm really powdery mildew when i say pm
these other plants
so it's hard to
control that a lot there's different
sprays and things you can do for pm you
got to be on it but man depending on the
size of your garden
can really up your labor
a lot trying to deal with these things
um outside so kind of going back to bud
rod i had bud rot before indoors and
i'll briefly talk about this yes i uh
had plants where i decided to do no
training because i usually do training
and topping and low stress string and
all that stuff and i was like you know
what my audience wants to see something
different let me do no training for the
beginners who who don't want to train so
i had all these plants and they had nice
real big colas coming up um and
unfortunately my fan died overnight the
oscillating family i had died overnight
and i only had one fan in there so
that's a mistake that's one thing going
back always have two fans in your
environment in case one dies uh that's
something i'm doing moving forward
um but really it
you know i noticed it
that my fan had to have just been uh
dead for like 24 hours so there's no air
movement whatsoever right and the
humidity skyrocketed uh overnight you
know i don't i don't remember if i like
just watered the plants that the
previous night or not but
um what i'm trying to say is that the
bud rod happened like pretty much
overnight now
once you get bud rod it starts to form
it starts to form like on the stem and
then kind of works its way out i'm
talking about botrytis scenario in
particular
it'll uh
it'll continue to grow so although i
fixed that fan issue i still like two
more weeks left in the grow
the fans were going i had air movement
but that botritis that's still there it
doesn't just magically stop growing it
doesn't matter you just disappear
so like i got all the way to harvest and
then i noticed actually that i had
botrytis i was like what the what the
hell this is terrible it's complete now
luckily it was only that top main cola
right the fattest one the lower buds
were fine so like that's typical too
yeah so in that case i just threw away
those colas as had as it was they were
beautiful and it sucks to take that cola
and just throw it in the trash but you
gotta do what you gotta do right you
don't wanna be smoking that crap but
yeah the lower buds were fine in there
but it was uh
it's not fun it's not fun that air
movement is important and one other
thing to mention is you can identify if
bud drops happening if
the leaves coming from the cola if it
starts to yellow from the bottom of the
leaf
that's an indicator that you could
potentially have bud rocks you can um
you notice you'll see some of the little
leaves coming out of developed flowers
because this last grow i forgot to
mention we've been talking outdoor i've
been thinking but indoor my last harvest
i probably lost about not bad maybe 10
percent from the flowers but you would
see i could you just be looking around
in the canopy and this unhappy family
for not family but leaf sticking out of
the flower
and so a test is to just grab that and
then if it pulls right out super easy
and then you can see it potentially a
little bit of dust or whatever you know
like that area is contaminated and what
i did for that is i just immediately
take
a
just a plastic garbage bag or whatever
over it and then snip below it because
i'm worried about you don't want and
turn off all your fans and hope none of
that little dust spreads around anywhere
but assume you're already gonna be
dealing with it and you're gonna when
you get the final processing of your
plants you're gonna run into more of it
and just be pleasantly surprised if not
yeah it's not fun at all i and now i
also another tip is i
make sure i set up alerts so i use a
sensor push alert i know some people use
like the pulse
but i have alerts come to my smartphone
if my humidity is too high well i get an
alert on my smartphone i know i need to
go take action so i can see now if the
fan does die out well i should be
getting alert yeah but yeah it's not not
fun at all getting bud rod all right no
challenges yeah i've got a few other
good ones here some fun ones here timer
mail function okay so
in uh colorado had four four outdoor
four or five outdoor grows um and the
first thing i realized i'm gonna need to
eventually because uh the first season i
put no protection over my plants i lived
in an area where every once in a while i
was almost guaranteed we're gonna get
some hail that comes through um so and i
could see i was like addicted to i'd sit
at the computer when i'd see it look at
uh the weather underground or whatever
and i'd have the enhanced radar i'd be
like man it's common and i'd be like i
gotta stay home this afternoon no
mountain biking not having umbrellas
ready
after that season i set up uh what i
call my tiki grow where i use you can
get the corrugated uh greenhouse panels
from home depot they're not that
expensive
and then i'm not a handy carpenter but i
can rig stuff up and a grow tip here is
you can get
two foot long pieces of rebar that are
already pre-cut at home depot and easily
pound that one foot into the ground and
then they sell all kinds of different
sizes of bamboo but there's bamboo poles
that were eight foot or maybe ten foot
tall that the bottom diameter of them
were big enough just to slide over that
rebar and i was like boom now that and
some green zip ties i'm starting to grow
plus i want my outdoor grow to look kind
of cool and i thought having a bamboo
like grow shack over it with some
corrugated plastic panels works great
and it did it stayed up for like seven
years so if you can protect your plants
from even if it's just rain
and weather and figure out how to rig
something up or even into the structure
that temporarily goes over them you're a
huge advantage there but i'd run into
weather
as far as the challenge here that man
the sun's going away or was going to get
too cold and i had spare grow lights
sitting around so i put out two 600
watts and a thousand watt hps out over
my outdoor grow
and then had a timer mail function
coming home at night it's dark out and
in between my house and the neighbor's
house it looks like a ufo's landing like
luckily at that point i lived on a court
i knew all the neighbors at that i
wasn't doing uh at that point in time my
garden was allowed i didn't have
anything to worry about or to get in
trouble for uh but that was just rather
interesting to be like whoa uh
talking about lighting if you if you go
outside light pollution
uh does your neighbor have a light that
might shine toward your garden to affect
its photo period
i had a
street light in front of my house
so i was like oh what am i getting to do
about this because you don't want to
have light pollution coming in they can
handle some don't get me wrong think
about how bright it is when a full
moon's out but for this particular
situation
it's like okay we can't do anything to
the light that we can't we can't
vandalize the light or do anything to
the lights
so i set up a ladder and actually i took
a piece of foil and spray painted it
primer gray
it looked kind of gray like the light
and just wrapped the back side of it
that pointed towards my house
and just used some uh some type of zip
ties i believe that lasted like five
years as well and my neighbors actually
like thank you that light used to shine
into our window
so be careful of light pollution out
there anticipate where you're going to
put your garden are you going to get any
light pollution from your neighbor's
security light or outside lights
and then it ties into smell man you can
have some smell from medicinal plants
and
different you know different strains
different strengths of smells uh
my neighbors were cool but also
sensitive to it at times like that's
getting kind of strong dude
but you know keep that in mind and you
can do a little research into that into
what which plants might give you more
smell than others at prime times and
flowering
um so those would be i don't know it's i
don't know did you want a little
security talk at all or i know that's
good i was going to mention you remind
me of uh when you talk about the smell
one time it would mean three of my
buddies were trimming
and uh
fedex guy came rang the doorbell and so
i opened up the door and he had to have
smelled something really strong because
i needed a smile
yeah well no he saw my shirt i had a
gross shirt on he's like oh that's what
that smell was
and
so
so yeah i mean kind of that wraps into
security right if you don't want people
to um you know know what you're doing
you want to hide the smell with you know
carpet filters or air
filtration systems yeah i mean if you
want to talk about security a little bit
sure
for you as the fedex guy you said for me
it was the my mail lady she's at the
mailbox and she was like huh and and
then the next time she's at the mailbox
i'm like are you garden at all and she's
like talked a little like here's some
free recharge you know just make sure
she's happy so but it was all good yeah
i mean keeping your garden um
out of sight if need be uh
keeping it to where there's not a lot
you can do about smell if the wind's
going the right direction and you have
neighbors close by sometimes that's
going to happen you can blame blame
skunks if need be
but yeah keeping it you know out of
sight and uh secure as possible
things are changing all the time with
how secure you need to keep it grow and
and it really it's nice to share your
grow if you can
but
the less people that know the better
it's easy to put things you know out to
notify you know this day and age with
technology and the affordability of
different cameras or things that can let
you know hey somebody's in your garden
or maybe even you're catching that can
tie into animals or pests you know if
you want to know that something's there
that shouldn't be deer we'll really love
to eat your plants
you can get other types of pests that
might come in and really like to eat
your plants but having a notification if
somebody's been there somebody's there
is good and just be around man be around
your plants like it be around your grow
as much as you can it's good for you
it's healthy for you it's free therapy
if you will i don't know about free we
do we do invest in our growth but yeah
be around to check things out that's
definitely some really really good
advice
all right so wrapping things up how can
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future dude rose as uh
scouting my co-host says yell dude grows
at your phone dude grow show man i think
we've been doing this almost eight years
now
we do shows every day of the week if you
want to listen to some grow talk make
sure you check out the growtalk episodes
we have a show called wake and bake
which is news culture and entertainment
and whatever else we might come out of
our mouths hang out on that show and
just get down
what's coming up
more dude grow show we come up with
ideas to change things up or do
something a little different content
collaboration with people such as
yourself thank you always like to do
that i'll be keeping the shows coming
out every day of the week is really uh
not the challenge but the joy it keeps
us pretty busy find us dudegrows.com as
our webpage we're over on youtube or
podcast any podcast player we should be
on
stitcher apple spotify just yell dude
grows at your phone and you'll see what
we've got going on awesome if you
enjoyed this video click that thumbs up
button also if you haven't already
please subscribe to the channel i
release these podcast episodes every
single weekend typically it's on
saturdays
if you're on apple podcast or spotify
actually apple podcast in particular
leave a rating or review that definitely
helps the ranking i'm just about to pass
100 ratings and reviews so thank you
everyone who has left that share this
podcast if you haven't already if you
know somebody who would benefit from
this information
please share it dude thank you so much
for coming on to this podcast today this
has been a great talk definitely
provides some value to those that are
growing outdoors
so i appreciate your time and i hope you
enjoy the rest of your day
back at you peace out guys
[Music]
you