what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching my extras channel
chilled led sent me over their new grow
light the x1
and in this video i am going to unbox
the unit so you can see what comes in
the box
i'm going to do a par test on it and i'm
going to do a heat test on it
i'm not gonna go over all the specs that
this grow light has but i will leave a
link down in the description section
below
so you can click on that to learn more
about it okay first thing i'm taking out
the box
is this t-shirt the t-shirt actually
does not come with the grow light
it is an additional purchase in this bag
there is a power cord and also an
extension cord
this bag includes a dimmer as well as a
set of rope ratchet hangers
in this box is the meanwhile driver
and lastly is the fixture chilled led is
actually doing a giveaway on one of
these lights
they're also doing a giveaway on the x1
mini they're giving away a t-shirt and
hat
and some chilled led sunglasses i will
leave a link to their giveaway
in the description section below for the
part test i'm going to use the apogee
mq620 extended range par meter this
meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd
and this part test is really just to
give you a general idea of what the par
output is
it's not going to be 100 accurate i take
measurements in grow tents which have
reflective walls
that could increase in numbers this led
grow light is recommended for
side lighting they do list a coverage
area of two feet by four feet on their
website
so in this video i'm going to take par
measurements in a two foot by four foot
grow tent
like i showed you during the unboxing it
does come with a dimmer
i did not plug in the dimmer for this
part test so the light is operating at
full power
i'm gonna take measurements at three
different distances 12 inches
18 inches and 24 inches i've plugged the
x1 into my kilowatt meter and it shows
1.36 amps pulling 163 watts from the
wall
all right let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
do
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
the giveaway down in the description
section below feel free to click on that
to learn more about the giveaway
and to join it and i'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching
and until next time peace
[Music]
you