hey everybody welcome back to my channel
for those of you that don't know me my
name is Chris aka Mr Grow it and you're
tuned into one of my q a videos I film
these q a videos live on Twitch every
single month follow me on Twitch if you
want to ask questions and potentially be
featured in a future episode twitch.tv
Mr Grow It that'll get you there make
sure you follow and turn on
notifications so that way you'll be
notified when I go live next that being
said let's get into today's q a
I'm using a 284 dry Amendment for mid to
late flower in an organic grow is there
anything you would suggest adding silica
I always recommend people add in silica
Bryce holes is just a fantastic way to
get silica in your plant you know the
organic side of things many many
benefits with silica so if you're not
using so I think everybody should be
having silica in their grow if you're
not using like micro resolution fungi or
a microbial inoculant you can do that
worm castings are fantastic to use I
think that should be in every organic
Grill in my opinion yeah I would go with
those ones are there any good grow light
sales going on right now yes there is
the sponsor of this episode Mars Hydro
has a sale on the FC and fce series of
grow lights going on right now both are
bar style so an even light spread across
the footprint some have removable bars
so you can adjust them if you'd like and
all of them connect to their smart
growth system the fce series of grow
lights uses Bridge lock diodes it comes
in at a bit lower of a price point the
FC series of Lights uses Samsung 301b
and the ppf comes in a little bit higher
than the fce series both are good for
home growing and if you're on the
commercial side of things reach out to
info Mars hydro.com to get the best
price possible more information on that
sale is on their website Mars hydro.com
link is in the description section below
and you can use discount code Mr Grow it
and you'll get a bit higher percentage
off what does your feeding process look
like I.E mixing nutrients in a specific
order I like this question it really
depends on if I'm using you know
synthetic bottled nutrients or if I'm
growing organic I'll break down both of
them start with the organic a little bit
easier in my opinion typically I like to
run organic Blends build a soil craft
blend it's a great organic fertilizer
I've been using it for many many years
also kiss Organics their nutrient pack
I'm using it for the first time this run
it's working freaking awesome I love it
and um both of them are very similar
feeding technique where you literally
just doing doing one cup per plant every
30 days so and I do a top dressing style
for that the past several girls I've
actually been doing a nutrient well I
spoke about that a little bit of my last
q a I believe also my main Channel video
I talked about that just dig down a
little bit of a hole in there put the
nutrients in that one spot bury it and
then that's an additional way instead of
just doing the spreading out the top
dressing All Along The Grill pot and
then some people will kind of mix it in
with that top layer other people will
put an additional layer of soil on top
of that top dressing and then kind of
water in I've done it all those ways
before just this past couple girls have
been doing that nutrient well now the
downside about the nutrient well
technique is a lot of people complain
that you're disturbing the root zone
right you're kind of digging down into
the soil making space for the Amendments
and then there's also the theory
downside people say oh well you're
concentrating nutrients in one part of
the grow pot how does that impact the
plant plan I've never had really an
issue where I saw any deficiencies
happening because the plant wasn't able
to get that nutrition so so nutrient
well is kind of the way and then yeah
organic feeding just one cup per plant
every 30 days for those ones in
particular I've done individual
amendments before organic amendments but
I'm not a soil scientist so I don't
really recommend people try to go in
there and fumble around themselves okay
those oyster shell flour put some of
this in alfalfa meal that's good for
this dump this in you know you might be
able to get away with doing that without
issues but in the long term you can have
can definitely have bad consequences on
the soil it can just be kind of an
imbalance of nutrition nutrients can
lock out of the nutrients so on and so
forth so I don't recommend that one so
that's organic when it comes to the
synthetic side of things I will always
follow the feeding chart as far as the
ratios do the different bottles but I
always just about always start with the
half dose sometimes even a quarter dose
of nutrition to begin so I'll mix out up
to usually put into a five gallon bucket
however much water I need then I'll put
the nutrients in the older I put them in
start with silica mix that in real well
then Cal Mag then the grow fertilizer or
Bloom fertilizer whatever stage I'm in
then after that I will pH adjust then
after that microbes so I'll mix that up
and then give it to my plants and
typically it'll be like every other week
typically is what it comes out to I
usually do the water feed water feed
technique so I water the grill pot then
when the medium dries out I have a dry
back in between waterings or feedings
after the water would be a feed dries
out water dries out feed so on and so
forth so very long-winded answer on that
one but uh there's plenty of details for
you how I do my feeding is there a
difference in the amount of ppfd for
autos and photos due to the extra time
under the light I think that's a good
question I think for many many years a
lot of us kind of neglected that fact
that Autos continue to stay on a higher
light cycle and it's just been kind of
generalized to this much ppfd and
seedling this much ppfd and veg this
plus ppfd and flowering and really kind
of neglected the photos versus Autos I
will um look at DLI is really what it
comes down to for that so yes if you're
if I'm have my plants in the flowering
stage for Autos I can still aim for that
600 to 900 ppfd but I might want to go
more towards the 600 ppfd for a lower
DLI of course CO2 is going to impact
that as well as far as uh you know how
much light the plant can intake but yeah
I would kind of Notch it down a little
bit particularly in flowering you know
you can definitely get away with six 700
800 ppfd particularly in the flowering
stage but you can still do the 200 400
ppfd for seedling 400 to 600 ppfd for
veg I think it's a good question because
I think a lot of people do it
differently let me know how you do it in
the comments section below what's the
best type of soil you use
easy question question for me I feel
like I talk about the soil just so much
as Foxwell motion forest soil it's just
kind of what I've been born and raised
using I started growing back in 2010 and
that's the soil that I started with and
my buddy actually who taught me how to
grow he was using that along with the
fox farm Trio so I've just kind of stuck
with that I have it at my local Nursery
it's a pretty good price and um it's got
enough nutrients to last me you know the
first 20 to 40 days of the plant's life
depending on what size container we're
talking about that's got to be my
favorite do you have you made compost
teas and if so how often did you apply
it to your plants yeah I've done compost
teas before I think I have some content
on compost teas but not enough content
but I've been using them I haven't used
them in several grows actually I used to
use them just in flowering really and
typically it was more so using them when
I was growing organic and maybe I did
that top dressing before or right at
flower and then after the first three
four weeks or so maybe I'm do I'm
hitting them with a t then and then
every couple weeks after that is usually
when I would hit it with the tea it's
just up until Harvest that's primarily
when I use teas and I feel like if I
don't need to use them why use them and
actually the past probably three four
Groves now I haven't had a need to use
them you know my plants have been
healthy throughout the entire Bloom
phase from using build a soil craft
blend and then other ones was Kiss
Organics nutrient-packed I spoke about a
little while ago I'm using that this
Crow plants look great you know I'm uh
mid flowering coming up towards the
final weeks of flowering for some plants
several different cultivars that I'm
growing this round so I'll be out really
compost teas as needed basis for me
flour Progressive light schedule or
higher in the beginning tapering off to
mimic nature I like this question I've
always just kind of been slowly
increasing the ppfd up until Harvest
that's always the way I've been doing it
actually I have done grills like years
ago six plus years ago where I would
lower the wattage this was with hid
lower it down for the final one to two
weeks in order to do exactly what you
had mentioned I've never done testing to
kind of see if there was a difference or
not so these past six plus years I've
just been doing uh just been doing full
last all the way up until Harvest it'd
be cool if somebody did do testing on
that though right that'd be really cool
to see if there was a difference growing
from seeds or clones currently currently
I am growing from seed so I've got four
different cultivars going on right now
we've got runs by homegrown Co I've got
curb stomper that is why prism Labs see
what else do I have American Pie if I
grow more fire that one I think has hop
Lane thyroid I'm actually recording
footage about the plant showing the
plant why I think it has hot blade and
thyroid testing so I've actually taken
samples and sent off for testing waiting
to hear back results on that but the hot
blade and thyroid man it's got me so
interested because uh it's something
that I'm sure a lot of us have
experienced and not known it the
symptoms on it are like really like kind
of some of the symptoms are similar to
other deficiencies and so on and so
forth but like one of the ones that I'm
experiencing right now is the um the
overlapping leaves so for example like
you know five finger leaves if the lead
if the leaves kind of overlapping kind
of curl in like that that's a identifier
of a viroid hot plate and viroid I think
there's other ones it could be as well
so I wouldn't say that that's definitely
that but from my understanding that
indicates a problem right so I actually
had that for the first time I think ever
because I haven't noticed any plants
maybe it's not really a trait I've been
looking for but like that overlapping on
every single leave it's just it's weird
to see so anyways I sent it off for
testing and uh we'll see what it comes
back and see if it's positive or
negative but yeah just seeds as of right
now and everything's looking pretty good
oh and I'm also growing uh Hades Throne
by Zaza genetics so this is the four
that I got going on right now I actually
had to kill off a Hermie yeah that one
ended up flipping on me unfortunately it
looked freaking fantastic beautiful
plant in week three or I think it was
three a flower two or three a flower
flower development looking amazing and
all of a sudden ball sacks show up so no
bueno had to kill that one off I'm still
really sad about that to be honest with
you any record recommendations
techniques for older seeds yeah so the
technique that I read in Jorge
cervante's book so shout out to him he's
uh oh gee his Grower's Bible if you read
that you'll see that he has like an
interesting technique to where he's
taken the seeds and have like a piece of
sandpaper to kind of rough up the seed a
little bit or the side of like a
matchbox or whatever it's just a rough
area to kind of rough up the side of the
seed and then it claims that it helps a
germination rate
I do that at your own risk I think I
actually tried that before and it didn't
work for me but uh your question reminds
me of that but now just kind of dropping
them in water paper towel method those
are kind of the best ways I think of
checking to see whether or not your
seeds are good I think some people have
done special solutions that they dip
their seeds in or soak the seeds in I'm
not really familiar with some of those
those remedies that people have comment
below if you have any little home
remedies of uh getting seeds to
germinate kind of increasing those those
chances there would you ever try
carbonated water for a watering no
probably not to be honest with you I
just been using all real water and that
works for me so I don't really feel the
need to do it me personally I don't
think I'm ever going to try that one but
I think it's interesting for the folks
that do do things like that I'd love to
hear of your results if you do do that
opinions on a new vipa Spectra 1500 Pro
LED grow light I like them I have I'm
running two of them right now I had them
in my 2x4 grow tent for veg real even
light spread on them and then I switch
them over to my 4x4 I have them on half
my four by four then I have the new AC
Infinity Light the EVO 3 on the other
side of my 4x4 and
um I like running two lights for like a
two by four grow space because you have
that flexibility to kind of make light
distance kind of adjust you know some
plants growing bigger than others you
can have them on one side of the tent
and raise them raise up that light and
then keep the yellow light down now
oftentimes I will actually just uh you
know if I do have one light that kind of
goes across that old two by four I'll
just put it diagonal you know I know
some people are against doing that but
I've always been doing that and it's
been it's been help making that even
light spread and I have a power meter so
I gotta check to make sure that things
are kind of dialed into the ppft that I
want on the plants at the time but that
grow light is is great I don't have any
complaints on it at all actually I think
one thing that could be improved on that
is like the dimmer switch I don't like
the dimmer switches how they go from
like you know 25 50 75 it's just those
particular set points you can't adjust
it like from zero to a hundred to any
percentage so that's one thing I don't
like about is some grow lights have that
but it's fine it's it's no big deal I'm
uh yeah it's not small con I'd say back
in the day I always said estrogen would
make your plants female so people are
crushing up birth control into the sea
uh that made me laugh that's a good one
foreign
[Music]