coming up on garden talk as soon as a
root busts out
and exposed to the air it's getting
colonized by bacteria so whether it's
negative bad bacteria like pythium root
rots
or it's positive bacteria like bacillus
that are actually going to feed the
plant
you've got to give some kind of place
for those guys to grow
60 cocoa 20 percent pearlite 20
castings and then i will put a little
bit of rock dust in there like that
azomite or just glacial rock dust
there's very specific mycorrhizaes that
work for very specific
plants you know so like you'll see
ectomycorrhizae on some labels
unless you're growing pine trees
ectomycorrhizae ain't going to help you
i want people to have success you can
grow the biggest
damn tree you want but if it wilts on
you know
five days before harvest because you
forgot to water it guess what
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 24.
in this episode i interview scotty real
from the dude grow show
he has been gardening for 30 years and
he grows a variety of plants
such as bamboo palm trees medicinal
and hot peppers i'm sure many of you
know him from his show the dude grow
show which is on youtube
and on podcast platforms in this episode
he talks about growing in coco coir
specifically his style of growing a
cocoa and how he likes to keep things
simple
big thanks to all of you who support
this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into the episode
i'd like to give a quick
shout out to our sponsors dutch pro is a
sponsor of the podcast
coupon code mr grow 10dp will get you a
discount on their products
they are a plant fertilizer company that
has been around for over 30 years
they originated in amsterdam and their
nutrients are available in several
countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition
from base nutrients to additives and ph
regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below
and don't forget to use coupon code mr
growit 10dp
for a discount on their products thanks
to spider farmer for sponsoring this
podcast
they have ford style led grow lights bar
style led grow lights
grow tents in-line fans and carbon
filters
they also have complete growth tank kits
which include lighting
a ventilation system grow pots a trellis
net
a timer and a monitor for both
temperature
and humidity coupon code mr grow growit5
will get you a discount on their
products
and i'll leave a link to their amazon
store down in the description section
below
alright now let's get into the episode
and we
are back welcome to the garden talk
podcast
today i am joined with scotty real from
the dude grows
show how are you doing today hey i'm
psyched man i'm really psyched to be
here hanging out with another content
creator
i dig your style dude i dig your style
thanks man it's an honor to have you on
here i mean you're somebody who i've
looked up to i mean you guys have been
around i think i first started
watching dude grow show back in like
2014. i believe you guys started in
2013.
so um and that was when you guys said
audio only
remember those days yeah i ran into dude
at a party and he says i'm starting my
own growers podcast and then i was like
no
i'm doing that i saw joe rogan first it
was like the
you know a couple couple months after
rogan came out he's telling everybody to
do it
and sure enough it was so much fun it
was honestly
the dude and i with all this stuff was i
don't know maybe was in 2013
everything's blowing up here in colorado
and we're talking about it on the phone
for an hour hour and a half a night
we're like this is the show
this is it right here so we put mics in
front of us what audacity and
it's funny that was when like the early
few hundred versions of that or shows of
that is
like us alone doing what we can with uh
with you know with the computer then uh
sean showed up grow guru showed up about
three four hundred episodes in
and we actually got to where we could do
video you know it's actually was a huge
upgrade for us but what a joy
yeah the progression has been awesome
over the years just to kind of see you
guys get better and better and the
continuous improvement
and the show it is today is just it's
incredible so
um definitely appreciate you guys doing
that for us
in the community here because it's
definitely entertaining and it brings a
lot of
education to the community as well so
thank you for that i'll be right back at
you i was hanging out last night i
watched vader and the painted lady with
yes
man there's not that much great content
to absorb at least
not if you turn on the tv so youtube is
that double-edged sword you've got to
watch yourself on there but i'll be
damned that there isn't
a ton of great information to consume or
just people to hang out with the idea
with our show
is to have people to hang out with
hopefully you got some like-minded folks
that are hanging out half the time we're
talking growing
and half the time we're just talking
culture you know having someone to hang
out with whether you're in your grow or
in the greenhouse or
in your car exactly
so before we get to our topic today
we're going to talk about kind of the
easiest way
to grow simplify growing can you tell us
a little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
i got into gardening by trying to make a
better product
i saw you the medicine that i that was
out there
just it didn't even remind me of a plant
it reminded me of a product and i
thought to myself how can i
uh it comes with seeds you know how can
i
do a better job with this how can i make
better medicine for me
and to share with my friends it really
is medicine to me
it always has been so uh yeah that
brought me to a heck of a long journey i
started in 1991
basically learning you know going to the
the grocery store buying the hyphen
you know potting mix what you could find
at kmart or walmart whatever it was back
then
and uh you know literally just just
starting from scratch
like that and it took uh
it was actually a journey i started with
putting a seed in uh
you know in some soil and then i started
getting enamored with the technology
hey there's you know is this uh is this
there's a machine that will grow this
for you and it'll grow these you know
beautiful beautiful quality flowers and
that
uh you can't really treat
flowers or something living like a
machine you know
it took me 20 20 years to figure that
out
you know that i would grow in deep water
culture
i would grow in all these different uh
unnatural systems i treated a plant like
a machine
and i would grow decent quality but it
just wouldn't uh
it was just missing something and uh
yeah when i learned how to treat
uh plants like plants like something
living you know whether it's more like a
pet than a machine
i was really able to to get better
that's when i really hit my stride of
growing
and uh yeah i've been doing it was 30
years
jeez 30 years man it's a long time for
sure
yeah and it's been an evolution i mean i
am i was originally
growing medicinal herbs and then i kind
of got enamored by
i went to i bought my first house and i
went to go buy a
privacy fence and somebody says you know
what if you actually put bamboo up
it's natural and it's a natural privacy
fence and i was like bamboo who the hell
heard of that
you know i heard of palm trees i'm from
south florida but a bamboo was a niche
and i ended up buying 20 acres taking
the very simple
uh lessons that i knew about growing
from
uh you know from growing medicinal herbs
and bringing them into bamboo
and it was kind of funny i really
actually got my butt handed to me
because i would go like first thing i
wanted to do is put 20 acres on liquid
feed
you know just like we do we go buy
bottled nutrients where they were like
you're going to go broke buddy you know
what do you want you know
a thousand liters of of three containers
of liquid feed
so very quickly you kind of learn how
how things scale up and what works and
what doesn't work in those situations so
it was a heck of an education man
that's pretty cool i didn't know that
about you so let me ask you
uh you know a lot of people want
different things out of growing right
like some people
i think a lot of people jump to the
assumption that everything's about yield
everybody just wants the biggest
possible flowers
it's not really the case for everybody
though i know some people that chase
after
taste smell there's some people i know i
mentioned in a past podcast
one of the things i strive for is
efficiency having a deficient grow
for you what's the goal with growing to
get the harvest
i say that really it's a tie between to
get clean medicine
for me and my friends to enjoy but when
i'm talking to other people about
growing
even when i'm thinking about myself it
is to get to
harvest it is not that easy to
uh provide your plants with 100
110 115 days worth of very consistent
uh environment food watering
uh ipm all that stuff to go for
you know you know three months three and
a half months it's not easy
i mean if you're just hand watering and
you miss uh
what two days you know [ __ ] i wasn't
feeling so well a couple days ago
and i just didn't have the energy to get
up and water my plants
and i was like if i don't get up and
water my plants it's 11 50
you know it's 11 35 my uh lights go off
at midnight
and i better go out there and water them
or they're gonna all die you know
it's like uh it's not that easy to have
120 days of success
so that is what i really tried the whole
growing simplified thing
i want people to have success you can
grow the biggest damn tree you want
but if it wilts on you know five days
before harvest because you forgot the
water
guess what you know that really is the
goal
growing big plants and growing all that
stuff is really a matter of strain
now what you pick if you want to pick i
don't think they still make big bud
you know a blue dream or gorilla glue
one of those giant ones you can grow
you can pick what you want um but
there's
all sorts of things some people want to
do that some people just want
what i want which is to share great
medicine with
our friends our family those in need
it's it happens here in colorado and it
is a joy
and it is such a different experience
than it is
in commercial markets i'll say that
makes sense
all right now let's get into indoor
gardening and your style of
keeping things easy let's start with the
medium what
medium do you like to grow in when
you're keeping things simple
excellent and cocoa i love telling
people about cocoa
cocoa core first of all it is well it's
renewable
i was in costa rica recently and between
there and florida
you'll never see so many coconuts
coconut palm very easy to grow it
doesn't take a ton of resources
grows the coconut the world's biggest
seed first of all i think that's a trip
but when you peel that thing all that
pith and all that stuff that comes off
it
is great growing media i mean if you
think about it that just came out of the
earth
you know that was just growing your
growing media was just grown
as opposed to pete where i used to live
uh uh
have a place in florida when i would
drive by there was a peat bog
and they would actually be mining the
peat they would actually have a
bulldozer going and they were tearing
out the earth that pete takes
you know i don't know millions of years
to become pete
and it kind of if i got my choice of a
year to get coconut husks you know
out of uh off of coconut or you know
millions of years of peat that they're
mining from the earth i'd rather do the
coconut but that's just
that's just honestly ethically i guess
the performance is
way better man coco core holds moisture
and air way better than pete does
peat will compact and it's really hard
to get a lot of air into pete or at
least you better aerate it well
as to where cocoa you can take just
cocoa with no
aeration no perlite anything like that
and use it as a media
and it works awesome and so it uh it
holds a lot of
air but the best thing about it is even
when you let it dry
it re-wets very easily i don't know if
you've ever used
i'm sure you've used peeps but for the
listeners peter's one of those things if
you screw up and let it get a little bit
too dry as to where you can kind of see
the
you know it's pulled away from the side
of the container you are going to have a
difficult time or it's going to take you
a very long time of just dropping a tiny
bit of water on there letting it absorb
until that peat re-wets and they call
hydrophobic it becomes
scared of water man it's just so much
easier to re-wet cocoa and uh
yeah i love cocoa when i first came to
colorado i was fairly intimidated i came
here in 2009
i was the backpack days and you really
had to have your act together
and uh when i came here i looked for
anything i could i talked to my buddy
corey over a way to grow
is the owner there i said come on give
me any advantage i can
and he said can a coco can a and b
and uh 10 gallon smart pots pretty damn
easy system
and you pour equal parts a and b in
there you know you test it to a thousand
ppm you make sure your
ph is okay you pour that water on there
a couple times a week
and uh you get the harvest it's pretty
damn cool
so you're using the bagged cocoa instead
of the
bricked cocoa and then and then
hydrating or what yeah we can talk about
that i've tried
all sorts of ways i have definitely
ordered the brick cocoa off amazon i've
been like
yeah come on let's see how cheap i'm
telling you i want to see how
inexpensive simple we can make growing
for people so that somebody can say dude
i've got a balcony or i've got a porch
and i've always wanted to grow something
i tell you what this looks so damn easy
you know you water it you know for some
of these bottom feeding buckets you
water them once a week or you water it
every 10 days
i can leave it outside on my patio i
didn't know that and i'll actually grow
something that i can use that's kind of
what
that is the the message that i want to
put out there
you know if i can get if i can inspire
someone me and uh my buddy soup the
gardener shout out to growerslove.com
he's a really smart guy really great
with organics
we want everyone to have a two by two
tent whether it's a two by two or four
by four but you just have
one plant even if it's just to
experience what it's like to care for a
plant
so you know i don't know if it's as
intense as caring for a dog or
maybe similar to a cat i would say you
know
but man to care for something like that
it really does uh
it really does something to you
absolutely
now with the cocoa are you amending
anything in it to begin
or are you just taking it straight out
of the bag and then putting into the
container
you know in the beginning i was just
taking it straight out of the bag i was
relying on
it becomes really nutrient dependent i
think when you do that when i bought
canna
nutrients i definitely bought can of
cocoa i do believe there's something i'm
not a chemist i've never i've never even
made it to chemistry class
but uh from a guru grow guru is uh
uh my co-host on the do grow show he's
the guy that that went to college for
all this stuff
there are different buffering agents and
coach
cocoa has a bunch of potassium in it so
they they buffer it
and so it works with the nutrients
that's why when you get a nutrient line
they usually have a cocoa
i that's where i started with of course
when you when you're baking a cake you
start out with a recipe right and then
you start saying hey let me put a little
more sugar in it let me put some
purple food color no i'm just kidding
but uh you start with a recipe so after
like i like cocoa
it didn't remind me of soil though when
i would look at it i
started learning about soil microbes i
started learning that
nature fills a vacuum so i would have
problems i tried all sorts of stuff
deep water culture straight up cocoa
which is
which is hydroponics and what i find is
when i didn't have a real media in there
when i didn't have something that at
least resembled soil
i left myself open to pathogens i left
myself open to
pythium just different root rots i
didn't even know what they were i just
know i'd show up one day
and one of my plants was just dead dead
from the inside you know so
i was just trying to figure that out and
what i learned was
like i said nature fills a vacuum if i
cut my finger
and i sterilize you know sterilize the
cut and then i sterilize some soil like
i just bake it bring you know
bring it out of the of the oven where
it's baked and sterilized
if i stick my finger in there my fingers
not gonna stay sterile it's gonna
there's gonna be infection pathogens
that come
where do they come from i don't know
bacteria is everywhere
so my point is it's difficult it's
impossible to keep something completely
sterile i mean it takes a lot of
of uh equipment to do that you know it's
like a scientific thing as soon as you
bring things out as soon as a root
you know busts out and exposed to the
air it's getting uh colonized by
bacteria
so whether it's negative bad bacteria
like pythium root rots
or it's positive bacteria like bacillus
that are actually going to feed the
plant
you've got to give some kind of place
for those guys to grow
you know those microbes those living
soil microbes to grow
rockwool pretty difficult rockwell's
like spun stone so it doesn't want to do
it you can maybe
get mycorrhizae on there but it really
doesn't want to
colonize on rockwool on the expanded
coco the expanded pellets the clay
pellets it's really difficult to grow
any kind of beneficial bacteria on there
so
the only things that will grow on there
or what loves to grow on there and
colonize is the bad stuff the root
eating stuff the pythium and
the rots and what's not so i really
started learning that the key to
whatever you're growing is to add some
kind of to emulate soil to add some kind
of
organic material to it so for me it was
earthworm casting so earthworm castings
loaded with microbes it's either loaded
with microbes it's dead microbes it's a
home for microbes
and even when those microbes die they
just turn into soil organic
matter just just more organic that's
what you want that's what soil makes
is it makes organic matter it breaks
down
you know leaf tissue and whatnot and it
takes that organic matter but turns it
into soil organic matter
food from the microbes home for the
microbes
uh so that that's what i learned i
started adding more and more castings in
i'm to about 20 castings uh to about
trying to think i want to say it's about
about 60 i don't really measure that
hard you know i might forget as i'm
i'm dumping the bucket but about 60
castings 20
perlite uh shoot i'm forgetting
something i know i'll put a little bit
of biochar in there hang on i wrote this
down
60 cocoa 20 pearl leg 20
castings and then i will put a little
bit of rock dust in there like that
azomite
or just glacial rock dust and all that
is it's just a little bit of
micronutrients in there that the plant
can't access or the microbes can access
uh just a tiny bit of that works you
need literally parts per billion or some
of some of those things
uh and then one thing i've been playing
with is biochar
you've been messing with biochar lately
yeah i've had uh i had my hands on
biochar i mixed it in
on a couple different grows i love that
stuff yeah i've been getting a shout out
to biochar now which is a colorado
company that actually makes a really
good biochar you can kind of sometimes
it looks like charcoal
or you know something that came out of
the bottom of the fire
but there's a beautiful little
pelletized activated biochar and
what that does it's just got a bunch of
little holes just like the carbon
filters
excuse me the carbon filters have a
bunch of
they're very porous the carbon is in
there so as the
uh odors go through it they're captured
there's just a whole bunch of air in
there well all those air spaces can also
be used as homes for microbes
so by just adding a little bit of
biochar in there a it air rates but bike
is such a great
great home for microbes so yeah that's
that's kind of what i've been playing
with lately and just been having
great results man awesome yeah i looked
at one of you i watched one of your
recent videos
and uh man you grow some massive plants
indoors i was looking at i don't know
how tall you are
but these plants were had to have been
just as tall as you if not
taller than you uh i'm only four foot
tall so i mean there i knew that
no i'm just kidding but you got some big
plants i was wondering what what size
containers are those plants in
those are in five gallon hempy buckets
and uh i'll get into that in a second
the reason i grow
uh plants is just because of of how the
laws work and the reason i grow very
large plants
is how the laws work you know um i want
to show people that you can take a two
by two or a two
by four tent and it's going to take you
you know 100 120 days whatever it is
three four months
uh to get through to that harvest but
that
that is a worthy investment that you can
make that worth your while that you
can uh create a make your own
very clean medicinal or medicine uh
without going to a store without
uh you know having to you know venture
in the unknown i mean we're talking
medicine here i mean you can wink about
it all you want people might and
you know might make them feel good but
this is real medicine for people and
especially for sick people
uh if they're inhaling you know somebody
wanted to
make sure that they got the harvest so
they sprayed eagle 20 on there which is
a
pesticide that's for ornamental use only
or they
had spider mites and they didn't do the
right thing or you know didn't you know
maybe they needed to cull their crop and
they didn't and he just sprayed some
poison and middle claw bridge
poison on it none of those things have
been tested for us to
ate eat i mean maybe they haven't tested
for us to eat
but they have not been tested for us to
smoke you know so that's a
really uh frightening thing and that's
what makes me want to
uh want to control my own supply chain i
guess you know in the supply chain for
other people who i help
gotcha so five gallon heavy buckets
we'll talk about the empty buckets
in detail in a little bit but i i know
you do start in the small
solo cups and then you kind of you must
transplant up eventually into those
containers can you talk about your
you know when you transplant yeah um i
have a kind of unique system i'll try it
i hope it's not too complicated i'll try
to share
it but it's a it's a 12 plant system it
basically has four
stages so the idea is to harvest three
nice plants a month
i have a little six by twelve so it's
something that i think people could
accomplish with a couple tents or
something like that
i have a two foot by i'm sorry i have a
six foot
by two foot veg so just a length of
the width of a closet and then two foot
is my veg
and in there i grow solo cups i have a
couple mothers i actually use a shelving
unit
and i grow a couple mothers on the
bottom uh i will
propagate those into cups just into the
cup and cup method
i'll let them grow for about it's all
predicated on a month so
i'll take the clone let it grow in the
cup for a month
uh then i'll transplant that to a three
gallon keep it in veg for another month
then after that i transplant it to a
five gallon which is called a a hempy
bucket or a sip bucket it's basically a
bottom feeding bucket just a little bit
more forgiving with the water
i'll transplant it to a five gallon and
i move it into flowering
very shortly afterwards the idea is
every month
i'm harvesting three plants and moving
three new plants into flowering
and it's uh for a 6 by 12 it is
a yielder i mean that that system will
really push it
i keep on forgetting the original
question it was transplant
[Laughter]
solo and usually i try to do month
interval solo to a three gallon to a
five gallon out to flowering
uh 60 days and they're gone and and
every month i'm continuing to do that
and it's a perpetual harvest gotcha that
makes sense that's a pretty cool system
that you got in place there
i'm trying man i'm trying to do this to
where i use slow release fertilizers
where i incorporate just a simple slow
release fertilizer in there
i mean it is it's gonna say it's so easy
that my friends can take care of it
while i'm on vacation but
i guess it's not that easy
and that's what we're going to talk
about next you know we talked about your
mix your initial mix
kind of getting going what containers to
use transplanting now
nutrients let's talk about what are you
using for nutrients space nutrients
additives microbial inoculants can you
talk to us about that
yeah i mean i've been growing since 1991
so i've been through the mix
and i don't know if a ton has changed uh
three-part
general hydroponics i heard you and i
think was painted lady laughing about
back in the day like that was that was
the only option you went to the grocery
store you got three part general
hydroponics
it worked it left you wide open for
pathogens it was the kind of thing that
it wasn't
kind of addressing the roots or any soil
organic matter or that kind of stuff it
was basically either
a rockwool it was designed for a
rockwool slab system or hydroponics but
it worked you know worked it was fairly
no frills
uh but then i started going to a little
bit more boutique stuff i've tried i'll
skip fast forward to
when i went to uh colorado started doing
a little bit more boutique stuff i think
that was the
canna a and b which i think i would
consider that a boutique brand though
sure yes it's certainly not
uh you know bargain basement price but
went to that
uh play hung out there for a few years
as far as a very simple system goes i
mean they're by no means a sponsor or
anything like that but just
canon is clean product you put equal
parts a and b
in there you used to match it up with
their cocoa and it's pretty easy to have
success
you know as long as you water them and
have good watering practices which
i don't know if you ever talk about that
it's so damn easy to teach people how to
water
you pick the plant up when it's
saturated and then you go back and you
water when it's about half
that weight i mean i love being able to
because over water and underwater
that's those are things that keep people
from getting the harvest and then they
end up throwing the equipment
in the uh you know in the closet and
there's their growing career down the
tubes
yeah that's a that's a good way to put
it i don't think i've heard it that way
before to to saturate it and then to
would you say let it go to halfway and
then water it's about halfway you won't
get in trouble you can't play with
it there but yeah i mean that's a just a
simple rule of thumb i like that i like
to talk to people about
and that's specifically in cocoa in your
method right so if soil you'd probably
do something different right
it's a rule of thumb you know it's meant
to be it put it this way it'll probably
keep you
keep you from grossly over watering
whatever you're growing
that is the biggest problem i think is
people want to love things to death
you know for me i would do you know i
had the general hydroponics three part
and then i would uh get root rot and i'd
be like oh my gosh what can i do for
that man i better go get some hydro
guard and put that on there
i better go get this product and put it
on man they're still not looking good
let me put some more on more on and
you're more on for putting more on okay
you need to listen to the plant man the
planet you can't just keep what's like
if i'm
just so stuffed i just got back from the
buffet and i feel terrible and i'm like
i feel terrible guys and you go
eat more here here's a steak
[Laughter]
it's not going to help man so actually
that's where it comes back to understand
that plants are alive
and understanding that they need balance
they need the right proportions
of air water carbon dioxide
in that air which really is the
macronutrient
uh but air water and just a little bit
of nutrients
i mean just that just they don't need
when i say a little bit
a thousand eight hundred nine hundred
parts per million but compared to how
much
carbon it's taking in and it's not that
much you know an air and water it's
using
the nutrients are just a little a little
bit there
so you following their feeding schedule
for that just doing like a reduced dose
and then
are you doing any additives or just the
the base nutrients
you know this was a bit ago i will tell
you i'm kind of
i forgot my last year or so i did want
to get some content
so i was doing pretty good with whether
it was kind of a and b that kind of
stuff i was doing pretty good with
it commercially no complaints was i
going to win any competitions with it
no and when i started talking and i
started talking to really great growers
i was like hey man
how can i step it up a bit more and you
know one guy his name is jaron from new
millennium you should actually see if
you can have him on the show is a wealth
of knowledge
but he would come over and he would just
show me
that he was at the next level and i
asked him he said how do i get there i
actually ask a lot of growers when they
show up and they're at that
9 10 to where i'm just salivating i'm
like what's going on there what are you
doing
and so jaren gave me a unique answer he
says it's the nutrients he's got
new millennium is quite a bit different
than what i'm used to i'm used to a
slow release fertilizer that you you
know incorporate in
and kind of get a couple additives from
there
just just to kind of tweak it his is i
want to say it's nine or ten bottles
there are some interesting things there
but you control the cow mag you control
uh you can add more p and k if you want
there's
fulvix there's uh that winter frost
product which is an actually interesting
thing actually that's a good tip it's
winter frost even if you don't use new
millennium
that product will make your uh plants
all finished different strains finish at
the same time it's really valuable for
someone like me that's doing perpetual
harvest things got to be out of there in
a month
so i was playing with that but for me
i'm i'm not trying to i had to make a
decision am i really trying to
uh grow top-notch you know 10 flower
that's going to win competitions and
going to have people beating my door
down
no i'm really not i don't have a lot of
ego in it i just want good medicine i
want people to grow good medicine
that they can enjoy that their friends
can enjoy the more the better the more
people that enjoy
good medicine the better this world is
going to be
so it doesn't have to be nine or ten you
can grow a plant that's a six or a seven
and that's and that's great you know for
you and your friends it's great for me
that's great for the world man so yeah i
was just thinking that uh
it's a little bit complicated for me it
was nine bottles and so
i went back to just my uh slow release
fertilizer controlled release
fertilizers
gotcha gotcha and then one of the
products which i assume
is in your garden is something i got
right here so uh
recharge these are microbes and you are
the owner of this company right can you
talk to us a little bit about recharge
and kind of how you incorporate in your
garden
yeah absolutely it brings such a smile
on my face that product does that was
something i i formulated with uh
i was in the bamboo and learning at the
bamboo nursery there's 20
i have 20 acres tens of thousands of
plants and the fertilizer costs on there
are unbelievable i mean you're talking
you know
six digits in fertilizer to keep
everything really pumping out of there
a year and i started hearing about red
tide i'm from florida red tide the fish
were dying it
has a lot to do with the sugar
corporations releasing their fertilizer
into the oceans
and it made me not i'm a farmer i have
20 acres i'm spending 100 plus thousand
dollars on fertilizer every year
i am part of that problem so i started
figuring out i don't have the organ i've
got like two percent organic matter in
my soil there's no
way that i could have a could do what i
do uh just using
organics it would take me 20 years to
build that soil and there's no way i
could have
have production on it like that so i'm
kind of locked in i'm in sand
so with my bamboo nursery i'm locked
into
using synthetic nutrients so if i'm
locked into that at least let me keep
them
in my field at least let me keep them at
the root zone
and that's where i really started
studying first you know the first
microbe that everybody learns about or
that i learned about was mycorrhizae
which is that
that funny sounding word it's
essentially a root fungus though and i
don't have anything but
gross analogies but if you get a fungus
on your finger now
and your fingernail grows does the
fungus just magically go away
no it keeps on you know keeps on growing
on the fingernail as it grows
well that's a pathogenic fungus now
let's talk about a beneficial fungus
let's talk about something that
mycorrhizae
is a fungus that's actually a coating i
think of a bare wire and i think how
dangerous a bare wire is
and then i think about a coating if you
just put a coating on that wire
and that's what it does it coats the
roots except it's like a fuzzy coating
and it had all the the mycorrhizae has
this fuzz it has these root hairs that
come out
and that's where the nutrient is
absorbed and the nutrient is absorbed on
those root hairs
so not only do you create much massive
thousands a thousand times more
absorption points for the nutrient
but you've also increased the whole
surface area of that root
so it's huge man so finding the only
thing is that mycorrhizae
like llamas and eradices there's very
specific
mycorrhizaes that work for very specific
uh
uh plants you know so like you'll see uh
ectomycorrhizae on some labels
unless you're growing pine trees ectomy
ectomycorrhizae ain't gonna help you you
can see 60 different
species of mycorrhizae if you're growing
you know
specific plants you know specific
medicinal plants you need iteratives
that's the one that that
forms that bond so there is a lot of a
lot of fluff
on a lot of labels and whatnot but
that's the one you want to look for
uh what i really learned about what
keeps the nutrient in the soil though is
the bacteria
another gross analogy that i got i don't
know i need someone to clean up my
analogies but
when you wake up in the morning you got
stuff stuck on your teeth that's
bacteria stuck on your teeth
you can't just wash them out with water
you can't just take a glass of water and
be like all right i'm all good i'm ready
to go to
to my day you'll have a lot of bacteria
still stuck on your breath
you have to brush them off you have to
actually take something you know a brush
and
you know with some toothpaste some you
know aggregate
and brush those things off because
that's the glomulin the bacteria make
this glommula and they stick
so they stick to your teeth guess what
else the bacteria will stick to roots
soil particles specifically in the soil
if you've got these sticky bacteria
things can get absorbed which you know
it goes inside or
adsorbed which it just sticks adsorbs
just a d instead of a band it means it
just sticks to the outside here instead
of being on on the inside here
these bacteria get these uh
these nutrient particles even these
synthetic neutral particles they stick
to them
even if they die in the soil whether
they move to the root zone or they just
die in the soil
these basically it's like a sink it's
like your soil is the battery my buddy
soup the gardener invented that
your soil is the battery and the the
more nutrient you can
hold in it whether it's through usually
through bacteria is the way you
uh or soil organic matter is the way
you're gonna hold it
but the the stronger your soil is you
know the more nutrient dense your soil
is
and uh i also the last analogy i got is
if you're thinking think about coco core
or something like that
or you're thinking about whatever soil
it's when we use these synthetic
nutrients they're salts
right they're that's what they are the
hydro
ionic form of nutrients whether it's
general hydroponics or any of the brands
they're all salt based
uh when you go to the beach and you have
salt all over you and you wash off on
those showers
it's complete the opposite experience of
brushing your teeth right you don't to
brush stuff out all you got to do is let
that water touch you the salt runs right
off that's why it's so
easy to leech soils that's why when you
deal with soils without microbes they
tell you to
water till 10 runoff and all that stuff
because they're trying to just very
easily all takes 10
extra water to wash all those salts out
and where they go and they go down the
drain if you're in a commercial
you know facility 20 acres or whatever
it is they go down and they become
somebody else's problem
and if you're buying those for 30 40 50
a gallon why not keep them in the root
zone and keep them where the plants can
use them
that makes sense for sure yeah a lot of
good information there there's some
definitely some things i didn't know
so definitely appreciate you dropping
those knowledge bombs there for us
but recharge great product i am i've
been using this since 2016 in my garden
off and on
um i need to use you know if i use the
same thing over and over again in my
videos my people just get bored so
i've been using this kind of off and on
in videos this is something that i
really get a lot of value out of in my
garden i mean it has everything from
beneficials uh you know bacteria
mycorrhizae kelp molasses
humic and fulfilling acids and even
amino acids so it's really loaded
with a bunch of good stuff in there
definitely recommend it for sure
man you mind if i say something about
that good
sure okay see i even asked before i
started again
[Laughter]
when i got into the industry everything
was separate there are separate bottles
you know for a
and b and fovic and humic i remember
when
i hope it's it's okay to say this no
begrudging to anyone that comes in
marketing products but
when advanced nutrients came in there
was 30 bottles i want to say
maybe it was 20 bottles and it was
everything was priced 30 40
i don't even think it was a gallon she
was expensive and i just started
thinking to myself this
starting to smell [ __ ] here man i
have a 20 acre bamboo nursery and
not even the world i know some
world-class growers of some very
hard to grow ornamentals nobody's using
20 bottles
so i just started thinking about it and
i said what can you combine you know i
started
can you combine mycorrhizae with
bacteria yeah you actually can
uh can you instead of growing them uh on
whatever
on clay can you grow them on kelp yeah
yeah you actually can man
can you provide a food for them a
molasses yeah
okay cool uh you know it was all these
extra things okay hey well amino acids
if we add add an amino acid uh k complex
in there will it
will it uh affect anything or will give
us any beneficial
results yeah it actually will we test it
and it will all these things to be able
to
you know make a product that actually
adds some value that actually separates
you from going and buying
uh four or five different bottles it was
kind of my
homage to making this industry a little
bit more honest man a little bit more
you know following what growers do in
commercial growth settings
it did bother me man they when they
separate you know when it's humic
and you're buying that for forty dollars
a bottle and then fulvic you're buying
for forty dollars a bottle
and they don't bother telling you that
phovix is just a lighter fraction of
humic
it's uh you know it's i don't like when
when people promote
ignorance for for profit that's what i'm
hoping we can change in this industry
and by the way it is changing
it absolutely is yeah i've seen it as
well it definitely is changing for the
better
absolutely cool i want to ask you about
a couple other things when growing in
cocoa so
some folks they'll monitor the ph
ppm or ec are you monitoring those
values and if so
what do you aim for when i use liquid
nutrients i do
right now i'm using these it's fairly
new for me i'm taking
some of the lessons i've used over at
the bamboo nursery
which is liquid feed for dessert and
then your steak and potatoes just comes
from
a uh for me it's a controlled release
granular
but uh when i'm doing liquid feed
pretty easy rule of thumb uh just in
containers
about a thousand ppm when i'm doing a
bottom feeding or a hempy bucket
that they're sitting in that nutrient
water so i'll go down to
seven to eight hundred ppm down there
because they're constantly just being
bathed in it
uh but yeah uh ppm pretty easy i have
one of those blue lab truncheon meters
it's easy enough to measure
ppm if you're doing liquid feed i will
say ph a little bit more of a pain in
the butt
uh do you have a ph meter sir oh yeah of
course
the blue lab with uh i have one where
it's
which one you got i got the uh a para
okay i'm going to take a look at it i
had for years and years i'd have these
blue lab meters
i want and they're like laboratory
equipment i'm sitting there in my grow
and this is legit laboratory equipment
there's calibration solution that you
have to put in there there's storage
solution
there's all this stuff that made it a
pain in the butt and a guy like me
was buying new probes every six months
150 dollar probe i'm buying because i
the water ran out in mine or whatever
you know the solution ran out
so i have been able to get away from
that thankfully
thankfully when i started learning about
microbes and started using recharge
i kind of noticed that the plants were
less sensitive
to ph and i started using my ph meter
less and less and then i was just like
everything's going fine there's a
problem i'll pull it out
and what i learned was that microbes
remember they're lining the roots
and they're buffering the nutrient in
the soil so they can
absorb or adsorb nutrients at a much
wider range of phs
than just the roots the roots those bare
roots
was it like a five five to six eight ph
range and there's
there's nutrient-specific nutrients that
are absorbed as those ph
fluctuate a little bit so it was uh
really a joy for me to be able to throw
out the ph
pen and i'll say that and granted you
need to know what you're starting with
everybody you know i make it sound too
easy throw out your ph pen and use
microbes
if you're starting with water that's
nine or you're starting with water
that's super acidic of course you need
to address that
but for us in here over here in the
rockies man it's
some great water here so it comes in
about neutral right about seven
and uh yeah i'm able to just actually
the new millennium nutrients that i'm
using and i think you were talking about
this
painted lady there's something they get
the nutrient guys got it down to where
when you
mix it to a thousand ppm usually your ph
is is pretty stable or at least it's
formulated for you know somewhere around
neutral
so i don't use a ph pen anymore i let
the microbes
you know kind of be the fudge factor
buffer them for me
and i've had good results and it has
been that's been a challenge for me is
to look people in the face and say
man you don't have to use your ph pen
anymore yeah they're full
yeah both i don't know about that scotty
but it's true yeah
i've used blue planet nutrients and then
a mixture on that
comes out to be 5.8 ph and that's what i
like for cocoa
so that it was kind of hands off really
didn't have to use a
a ph pen at all when growing in cocoa
specifically because
my water came in at whatever it was but
when i added the nutrients it would drop
it down to 5.8 ph is the perfect
and i would just do 5.8 ph going in
every time
and just completely ignore the runoff ph
and that worked great for me
so um yeah it can definitely be
simplified on that avenue for sure
you talk about that real quick the
runoff ph people always talk about
collecting your runoff and testing the
parts per million and ph on it
um that can be particularly with parts
per million that can be
very deceiving you know it's like we
talked about the shower washing the salt
right off you
i mean if you're i've had runoff before
where the plants are just because i
hadn't uh
water till runoff for a while where
they're off the chart you know it's
over 2000 ppm but the plants are still
looking good and it's just it really is
a
that's a deceptive one i think yeah i
mean we can get into real deep on this
right so it's not going to really the
nutrients aren't going to show up unless
they're in an ionic form
right so right if people are putting in
top dressing nutrients for example those
aren't in
a ionic form just yet the microbes have
to break it down so
some people will get a runoff number and
they'll realize it's way higher than
what they put in well there's nutrients
in there they're breaking down in the
meantime
and then there's folks that are out
there they're like oh i have a 2000 ppm
or 2 500 ppm but my plants look fine or
i need to flush well how big is your
plant how big is that root system right
i mean because you're you're measuring
the runoff
but if you're real small plant in there
with the small root system that hasn't
reached everything
well then you probably are going to be
fine so yeah i totally get what you mean
by it can be deceiving i know the runoff
ppm values it kind of just
get a guesstimate of what could be in
your medium
and there are general ranges that people
can follow
to kind of help ensure that they're not
over feeding or underfeeding so you can
break it down to kind of like a
a beginner to simplify things but yeah
certainly can go outside of those ranges
and
genetics are going to be able to take it
some will be uh be able to take
higher than other you know what i mean
so there's there's a lot to do with that
but um as far as ph um you know checking
the runoff of
that again it gives you a general idea
of the ph in the future you could do a
runoff test or you could do a slurry
test
some people will take off some of the
top layer of soil put it into
a cup or something add in some distilled
water
let it sit there for however long and
then take a test that way
so there's two different ways to kind of
to measure it but it's really just to
give you a general idea of what's
in the medium you know i mean to make
sure you're in those proper ranges
because
i think you and i both know if your ph
is off it
inhibits uh some of the nutrients from
being up taking right if it's too low
it inhibits some nutrients too high it
inhibits some nutrients so so
yeah that's why i was just kind of
curious on your avenue if you did
monitor the ph
or ppmec in any value in any way i mean
so it's interesting to hear how you go
about it yeah i've gotten quite lazy
about the ph maybe i just have you know
i've been here for 12 years now as far
as in this town
i'm familiar with the water and uh yeah
i'm just able to dial it in i guess but
i don't use a ph meter anymore and i
will say for i've been growing since
1991 i definitely wasn't growing to the
point where i had 300
to sink in a ph meter for a long time i
would use those little you can get them
it's like a little five dollar ph test
kit it's got the little bottle of
of droppers and you drop a couple drops
in there and it gives you
essentially just a color whether it's
red for a super acid
almost blue for uh super basic
believe it or not if you're on a budget
you can certainly test your ph and get
it within
you know a half of a point a quarter of
a point
within uh you know with something really
simple like that like
i'm trying to make gardening really
accessible to anyone
you know under 100 bucks you should be
able to put together a little system for
your balcony anyhow
yeah i completely agree you can
definitely get away with those those
small
test kits i actually have the same thing
for my pool my swimming pool i use that
to test the ph and make sure that's
balanced the same
same stuff as being done there i'm from
florida i definitely managed my family's
pool for uh
since i was eight years old it's fun it
can be fun
but anyways let's get back on topic of
uh hempy buckets i know you wanted to
talk about those can you talk about
uh can you like explain in detail of
what hempy buckets
are and how you grow in them it's just
super simple concept i learned
about it i think there is a guy named
tempe or at least there was
and it's just a sip bucket i don't know
if you ever go when you go to walmart or
home depot most of the buckets
they don't they have like a little they
have like a little lip on the bottom
that you can actually
water there and then the idea you water
from the bottom
there's maybe a couple inch reservoir
that holds that water and then it slowly
wicks up
and it uses capillary action of the soil
to wick up and feed the roots and it
always
keeps those roots at an even once once
you dial it in
keeps those roots at an even moisture
it's the perfect moisture i'll dig down
into a hempy bucket
i'll grab some soil that's in there or
some cocoa i'll squeeze it
just a little bit of water will come out
it's just that perfect moisture and
likes that plants need
air they need air for those roots to
breathe for those microbes to live
they need water and they need nutrients
so uh yeah
giving them giving them plenty of air is
uh definitely definitely a big deal
definitely cool um a hempy bucket is
just
so we'll say this is the size of a
container right here let's say it's a
normal container just go
two inches up two inches up and you just
put a little hole in there you can use a
drill
if you don't have a drill you can use a
damn steak knife don't sue me
but you're just basically taking i take
a five gallon bucket and just one of
those home depot buckets if you find a
black one from the the grow store
it's better just because it uh you know
it protects the roots a little bit you
don't want light getting to your roots
but two inches up you just drill a
little hole in there maybe a
3 8 inch hole the idea is you're gonna
fill
right to the hole two inches you're
going to fill it with perlite just
i like the chunky pearlite but just
pearlite right to two inches
and then you just fill the rest with
soil that's the simply heavy simple
hempy bucket i use cocoa modified cocoa
and then the idea is you just water it
until water comes out that little
hole basically what that means when you
water the water comes out that little
hole
you've filled up that little two inch
layer of perlite on the bottom
you've given yourself a little two inch
reservoir you go
you know you go back and your soil is
perfectly
moist until that reservoir goes and then
you just want to water it again and
maybe gives you an extra couple days or
something
but the most important thing is it keeps
that the soil
evenly moist almost it it doesn't take
very long for it to balance out
and it's just such a simple way to grow
just a five gallon bucket
it gives you a little you can go away
for the weekend and
uh it just affords you sports a little
bit of extra
extra time between waterings and it
keeps that soil at a nice evenly moist
level which is really important when
you're
don't know and you're trying maybe over
watering underwatering
it's pretty cool that is pretty cool i
remember reading about empty buckets way
back when i first started in like
2010-ish um i think
i've seen people doing a hundred percent
perlite in theirs
have you done 100 perlite or you just do
the the bottom bit
perlite and then above that cocoa i just
do the cocoa i have been experimenting
honestly it's pretty cool we actually
started this thing
my newest project is called 420 grow lab
it's an open source challenge basically
to the growers community
we've got a great community called the
dgc that hangs out and
shares all their growth tips with us but
it's just an open source project to come
up with the
simplest system for growing good quality
medicine
and it's it's you know the goal is to
just
i put my basic hempy system up there and
everybody's coming up with mods we
it's so much of my emails busting open
you know it's uh overloading my email so
we're making this site but the idea is
that you can spend
whether it's you know you go buy one of
those monster garden kits or five or six
hundred dollars for kind of
everything you need to get started but
just to be able to go
or whether you go to your hopefully go
to your local grow store and support
them and spend a few hundred bucks get
you know a two by four
light and fan you spend what seven eight
hundred bucks and you're
able to start growing i mean that's
that's the idea behind it so
i have the simple hempy bucket system
there's all sorts of mods there's
uh folks that are cutting 55 gallon
drums out
and instead of using uh perlite as a
media
they're using geez one guy's using sand
shout out to ray with the hemp buckets
man he's using
sand as a wick and then there's a
difference in a hempy bucket between
what you use in the bottom
and then what you use as far as the
cocoa media you know the
the media up top so the wick is really
seems to be what coco
where a lot of the innovation is coming
whether you're using perlite whether
you're using
sand there's all sorts of people trying
to little expanded clay balls
but people are kind of playing with that
uh the best media up top though is coco
as far as i'm concerned some kind of
amended cocoa
that's cool sounds like it makes things
a lot easier off to try out heavy
buckets sometime in the future i think
that would be
really fun you know do something new
plants haven't been
growing in perlite for millions of years
you know billions of years they've been
growing in soil right
yep yeah so the symbiotic relationships
you know the relationship like i said if
you
think about what perlite is we like it
because it lets so much air in
what we talk about bacteria you know
bacteria is
it's it finds a way you know nature
fills a vacuum like we said
so you're leaving those roots with a lot
of
of you know places to get pathogens from
the air
so it's a bit more dangerous than if
you're surrounding them
a with a mycorrhizae coating but still
we put cocoa in there
and then we put a bunch of organic
material to at least simulate soil with
the castings
yeah that makes sense it's a good point
it's a really good point all right
scotty so
kind of wrapping things up we've covered
a lot of easy things to do when growing
in cocoa in particular
a lot of good information here how can
those students find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future dude grows dude grow show
if you like hearing me run my mouth
which i'm sorry i feel like i ran my
mouth a little too much today but
i like i love your show i listen to it
all the time i watch it
and uh i was just really excited to be
here man thank you so much for that i
really do appreciate
the offer sir dudegrows.com real easy
way to find me
realgrowers.com is where i sell recharge
but uh
better to just type recharge your yell
real growers recharge into your phone if
you want to learn anything about that
and i will tell you i'm kind of psyched
me and my buddy banner over here
are we are we have this goal
of simplifying growing i got banner
growing i traded him for a website about
five
six years ago got him started growing
and it's so much fun to see the
evolution
of him into a great grower it's like i
want to spread that that's what the dude
grow show is about
and that's what hopefully i'm doing this
420 grow lab 420 grow lab.com but
like i said it's just an open source
project to make the simplest growing
system we can we're going to crowdsource
it
we're going to share these mods like i
said i'm going to put up a uh
my basic system and let people mod it
from there i'm actually actively working
on some mods right now
so that's actually what got me mostly
excited right now
awesome sounds good that's really
exciting so i will leave a link
to scotty's channel down in the
description section below
if you enjoyed this video click that
like button try to get as many likes as
possible that's going to help get more
people to view this video or show up and
recommended subscribe to the channel if
you haven't already
if you're on apple podcasts please leave
a rating and review
i think we're about to hit 100 or we
just passed 100 ratings and reviews so
thank you to everyone who have
left a rating and review on there share
it sharing is caring
good places you can share it is reddit
facebook groups there's a lot of
different places that you can share this
and thank you to everyone who shares
this podcast scotty thank you once again
for coming on to this podcast it has
really been an honor
um you're an inspirational person in
this field so thank you so much for
coming on and
and spreading the knowledge about what
you do when keeping it simple growing
cocoa so thank you once again ah this is
it is such a joy to do this and to be
able to
connect with everybody you know connect
with the community
keep some people company in the grow
have an impact maybe have some
folks learn a couple things it is an
absolute joy
absolutely thank you so much peace
[Music]
do
you