welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
guard Talk podcast this episode number
135 in this episode I interview Bryant
Mason also known as the soil doctor he
was on the podcast once before episode
26 back in 2021 we talked all about soil
testing he did a soil audit walk through
and also talked about some of the
elements of a plant growth and got into
heavy metals this time around he talks
about water testing I got my local water
tested here and he breaks down the
results I also got the soil in my
backyard tested and he goes over those
results as well and gives me suggestions
for improvement these episodes are
broken down into small Clips if you want
to see those subscribe to the Garden
talk Clips Channel on YouTube I also
have a gardening Channel where I show
the plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their all-in-one
pH pen which measures pH EC TDS and
temperature the sensor probe is
replacable and it comes with sword
solution and calibration Solutions click
the link in the description section
below so you can learn more about their
all-in-one pH pen and the discount code
Mr Grow 15 works on both Amazon and
their website AC infinity.com stash
blend stash blend consists of several
ingredients in one so you no longer have
to buy individual bottles it includes
corn steep liquor seaweed extract humic
acid beneficial bacteria silica and
micro risal fungi it can be used in
addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with the soil doctor Bryant Mason how
you doing today doing well how are you
Chris pretty good man thanks for coming
back on to the podcast you were here I
had to look it up August 7th 2021 was
when the last episode dropped wow and
another thing I like to look at and talk
about is the number of views it got so
30 th000 views on that episode which is
pretty crazy it always surprises me that
there are so many people out there that
are tuning into these and it just shows
that there are a lot of people
interested in gardening and and better
their Garden excited to have you back on
here and talk about soil science
absolutely and it was fun to meet you
even for just a short moment this year
that was that was a special thing yeah
we able to meet in person at the solo
Summit I was there for the the first day
and um yeah I know you had a good talk
there and everything everything and
really a lot of value that you add in to
the whole Community really so appreciate
what you do yeah thank you so the last
episode we when we got together we went
over a soil test but it was a soil test
from soil that I had Outdoors but it was
originally bag soil so it was like
reused soil and I was growing medicinal
plants in there we also did a soil audit
walkthrough so you actually walked
through the entire soil report talked
about some of the different elements for
growth and we got into heavy m
this time around we're going to go over
another soil report but we're also going
to go over a Water Analysis report too
so I'm kind of laughing a little bit
because the water report is my tap water
I live in Las Vegas and we're known to
have very hard water I measure it at 485
PPM which is like very high uh I think
EPA guidelines is like no more than 500
or else it's considered unsafe or
something like that but so it's very
high uh as far as PPM and then the
report we're going to go over is from my
backyard and I live in Las Vegas and
it's just a lot of rock and desert and
so I'm looking to revive that soil and
uh grow some vegetables I've got some
trees out there that I'm going to be
growing and um so looking to see how you
know your analysis of it and just
suggestions for proving it great fun and
I I glanced at your water report before
and it's going to be a fun one awesome
well before we get too deep into it can
you introduce your yourself for the
folks that didn't catch the first
episode we did together yeah sure I'm
Bryant Mason um I'm a certified crop
adviser and I focus on organic nutrient
management so I work in various crop
types helping Growers improve their soil
fertility with Precision nutrient
applications so the process typically
looks um like you know with a with a
grower it's pretty simple Growers test
their soil and then I do the agronomic
math and write organic um Amendment
recommendations I also analyze water
tests and tissue tests quite extensively
um and then I also have an online course
for people who really want to deepen
their understanding of nutrient
management and spend you know 15 hours
just becoming more self-sufficient so if
anyone's interested in that they can
find that everything I offer on my
website um but mostly as a as a crop
adviser I'm just focusing on nutrient
management not necessarily
IPM um or environmental controls or
anything like that so um yeah that's
that's the brief introduction I also
have a a farm of my own in western
Colorado um I have I grow vegetables and
medicinal plants like you um but my cash
crop I have a th000 peach trees so I'm
an orchardist um and so I'm I'm really
interested in Fruit production as well
so this this year is going to be my
first Peach crop um I planted the trees
three seasons ago three summers ago and
they're like thriving and huge and
there's a bunch of peaches on the trees
so that'll be fun that's exciting and
and some folks might recognize your name
from my book my second book that I just
released January 1st this year I gave
you a mention I talked about kind of
soil testing how you get to soil tested
and then you can also link up with
somebody like you who's going to be able
to give you advice on what you can do
for the soil and really this episode
you're going to kind of get a glimpse of
that so where would you like to start
would you want to start with the water
yeah let's start with the water I know
that was your your primary your your
main priority so let's start with that
the water report I just want to say
before we dive into this I think this is
the most underutilized underrated single
test that people can do and the reason
for that is is sort of twofold the first
is that if you think about inputs to
your to your system to your soil water
is the biggest input so over multiple
irrigation Cycles over multiple years
whatever's in your water is going to
influence the soil solution more than
anything else and the soil solution is
essentially the the water that's
available for roots in the pore space of
the soil and so whatever the chemistry
of your water is that's really what's
going to define the chemistry of your
soil solution over the long term so it's
your biggest input from a heavy metal
standpoint from a salt standpoint from a
nutrient standpoint often times um and
then the other thing is water does
change obviously um you know like Wells
for example can fluctuate a little bit
from Fall to Spring but by and large
water uh a single water test will tell
you exactly what your water is going to
look like or the pattern that it's going
to
um exhibit over the long term so really
in my opinion you only need to get one
water test and then you know your water
forever more or less um if you really
want to double check things you can but
if you get three water tests they're all
going to look pretty similar so the
reason I like that is you only have to
pay for one water test um it's very
inexpensive and you get a really good
sense of the chemistry of your of your
water so let's dive into it so the first
thing that people often look at and it's
the first metric on the soil test is pH
um most Growers are familiar with phing
their water up or down generally it's
going to be down
um and pH is important but it doesn't
tell the full story of whether or not
you should acidify your water and we'll
get to why that is with a second metric
a little bit further down the Water
Report the next metric on the soil
report is hardness you mentioned this
hardness is really just a summation or
an or an aggregate uh calculation of the
calcium and the Magnesium content in the
water so it's really just telling you
the mineralization of calcium and
magnesium it's a pretty simple equation
you can look up online um and in your
case you have 338 parts per million of
hardness which is a lot like you
mentioned that's a lot of hardness um so
you have a lot of calcium and or
magnesium in your water and we'll get to
that and just to back up I didn't
actually mention what your water PH was
for listeners it's
7.7
so right away you think oh that's pretty
high maybe you should PH down well let's
wait on that conclusion until we see uh
another reading closer to the bottom of
the report called alkalinity so your pH
is 77 your hardness is
338 and again that probably fluctuates
depending on um you know the Las Vegas
Supply and things like that but it
doesn't really matter the hardness is
always going to be high
um I'm going to jump down to there's
there's another three things hardness
grains which is just another way to
measure hardness conductivity which is a
salt reading it's an EC reading and then
sodium absorption ratio which matters in
agronomic Top Soil field production but
for the purposes of this conversation we
can skip it um because it's really just
a computed calculated number um that's
getting at how much sodium there is in
your water do you have any initial
thoughts or questions before we keep
going yeah couple just to back up a
little bit you mentioned one water test
should be fine they're really not going
to change I heard it may be Chang like
over the years like shouldn't it be you
know maybe this year get a test next
year you could see a different result or
are you saying no that wouldn't be the
case I mean you'll always see
fluctuations even if you took a test
tomorrow you would see the numbers just
slightly different but my
believe
is the pattern of what we're going to
see here on this report isn't going to
change so yeah the pH might fluctuate a
couple tenths of a you know point the
hardness may go up or down even 20 or 50
parts per million the but the but the
underlying pattern of the water is going
to be the same which is that you have
hard water with you know high pH high
sodium low Etc so as a consultant I
think there are tests that you should
take frequently but I'm constantly aware
that you're trying to save money as a
grower so I don't think the loow hanging
fruit is to continually water test
because you're pretty much going to come
to the same conclusion even though it
will fluctuate a little bit now of
course there's going to be parts of the
country where the water fluctuates a lot
so that's not a universal statement but
by and large you only need to take one
water test in my opinion okay I do have
a few more questions but I'll I'll
gather some more questions and ask them
when we're done with the water section
okay sure so so the the what's always
most interesting to me when I see a high
pH is the next five or six things I'm
going to talk about so calcium magnesium
potassium and sodium those are cations I
um they're the dominant cations in soil
and they are the dominant cations in
water too and they're going to really
Define the cation balance in your soil
solution so all of three out of the four
of these are nutrients to the plant
sodium is not a nutrient but calcium
magnesium and pottassium are extremely
important beneficial nutrients so the
balance of those three really matters um
so calcium is 107 parts per million
that's a lot so that's what's creating
all that hardness in your water you're
in this Aid environment in the Western
United States that doesn't get tons of
rainfall and so it's very natural for
there to be really high calcium levels
uh in the parent material and in the
rock formations in the geology and so
when the water moves across the surface
of the the land or or underground it
picks up those calcium ions um and
that's why your calcium is high now
luckily calcium is a nutrient for plants
and it's a very important maybe
underrated nutrient and so it's
fantastic in certain ways that the
calcium is so high however it's the
calcium is coming with other things that
usually aren't as beneficial so hardness
in and of itself is not a problem that
high calcium is in my opinion a good
thing the Magnesium is 17 parts per
million um
which is slightly elevated but compared
to the calcium is not very high so that
calcium to magnesium ratio in your water
is just fine
um the potassium is three parts per
million it's very rare to see high
potassium in in natural sources of water
um and by the way is this Municipal
Water from from Las Vegas yep okay okay
so here's the kicker I'm going to jump
to sodium this is in my opinion the
greatest weakness of this water it's not
pH it's not salts it's not hardness it's
sodium your sodium is a whopping 48
parts per million
and um there there could be a number of
reasons why this is It's hard to know
the first is uh the the city of Las
Vegas could be trying to soften the
water and when you when you soften water
you essentially there's a number of
different ways to to soften water but
one of the most cost-effective ways is
to uh exchange sodium and so you're
essentially removing the calcium and the
magnesium and in doing so you're sort of
replacing it with sodium salts um so
it's possible that just through water
softening they're increasing the sodium
content of the water trying to get below
the you know the EPA limits or whatever
regulations they're trying to follow
maybe trying to take make it taste
better um I know hard water can be tough
on plumbing and so they they could be
essentially creating elevated sodium the
other possibility is again there's just
high sodium in in the source of the
water um and as it runs across the
surface of the desert or
underground uh maybe it's coming from
Lake Powell maybe it's just
grabbing uh sodium from the environment
from the aid
environment so in any case uh
unfortunately these are these are the
cards you've been dealt but it's really
not optimal and the this will be
something that you'll need to manage
over time is this high
sodium um I'll okay I I guess I'll pause
and get your reaction or your thoughts
or questions about about the sodium or
about any of these cations yeah high
sodium I mean you mentioned they appear
to be softening the water kind of
unrelated question does that mean I I
don't need a water softener I was
looking at potentially getting one of
those when it comes to your drinking
water your shower not you know like
shower glass not showing stains water
softeners work but when it comes to
plant production I am not a fan of water
softeners I think they're a horrible
idea because they're removing calcium
and magnesium which are plant nutrients
and and they're adding sodium which is a
not a plant nutrient and in fact is very
antagonistic and problematic in plant
production so I have never recommended a
water softener and in fact I'm
frequently
recommending to scrap the water softener
when it comes to irrigation yeah I was I
was kind of leaning towards the whole uh
you know dishwashing and uh cleaning
clothes and stuff like that unrelated
like I mentioned because the the fiance
wants a water softener and if I can come
to her and say hey you know what we
already got sodium in there it's not
going to you know we don't need one you
might you might for your dishwasher and
for clean dishes you may want to soften
it further got it okay but your plants
won't appreciate it I mean there other
way there's other salts that can be used
in water softeners like potassium salts
but still I wouldn't want to crank my
potassium up necessarily um there might
be a balance there but I would never use
a sodium salt in water softeners and
usually you don't have control you just
plug them in and you kind of buy what
the what's manufactured so okay and then
I'm assuming that at the end recommend
some sort of filtration so I was going
to ask what options are there to filter
this and I'm not sure if I'm getting
ahead of the conversation here or not
well so no let's talk about that so when
it comes to
sodium um really the only solution is to
filter it out because you don't have
control over that if there is a water
softening process from the city of Las
Vegas you don't have control over that
um you get what comes out of the tap so
so there's really only one filter that I
know of that removes sodium effectively
and it's Ro filtration which is really
uh unfortunate for small scale Growers
because of the economics just how much
they cost um and you know Aro really is
unfortunate because it produces a lot of
waste water and if you think about it
that waste water that produces is even
higher in concentration than uh the
Water going in so you have to do
something with that waste waterer and so
it's a it's it's not a
very you you you have to think about
what to do with the Wastewater before
you install Ro filtration there are
other filters out there um Growers all
the time when I analyze water tests say
oh I'm using a hydrologic filter I think
they're called tall boys or something
I've seen dozens of tests and these just
they don't they don't work that you know
we've taken tests of the water before
and the water after and so inexpensive
filters just don't tend to remove they
might remove like five parts per million
or something of sodium but they really
don't clean the water like they need to
so there's the one option is you know
you filter the the second option is um
you actually can manage without
filtration and essentially what that
looks like is you irrigate and you
balance the other cat ions with nutrient
applications and you water with your
high sodium water and then every once in
a while you flush so what what will
happen is you you irrigate with high
sodium water and over time that sodium
accumulates in your soil um because the
plants well let's just say a lot of that
water evaporates into the air
but the sodium doesn't evaporate with
the water the sodium stays so the water
comes in with the Sodium the the H2O
evaporates but the sodium stays so over
time it starts to accumulate in the soil
and that's where you really start to see
issues with nutrient antagonisms or what
people call lockouts um maybe even salt
stress on your plants because your
sodium's getting too high and so you can
flush that sodium out so you can
irrigate with your high sodium water and
then when it accumulates you just do a
big flushing or leeching event and you
kind of um just run tons of water
through your so soil profile and that
all that excess sodium will essentially
get flushed out now if you add gypsum in
during that that leeching event it'll
actually be more effective in reducing
sodium and and so you're never getting
the sodium to zero you're just reverting
your soil back to that 48 parts per
million because that's what your is in
your water but what's going to happen
over time is it's going to go from 48 to
you know 75 to 100 to you know as high
as who who knows how high and so if you
leech it it kind of brings it back to
50 does that make sense yeah even if
you're planting in ground you would do a
flush like that yeah so it's very common
ergonomically in what's called sodic
soils which are high sodium soils to to
leech the the sodium out now that
assumes that your soil drains well and
that you have enough water to do this
kind of flush you're not like water
scarce um and it's not perfectly
effective by any means but it's this is
how like people in Arizona grow all the
time in Top Soil so now if you had like
a really poor draining soil a really
clay soil like for whatever reason you
just couldn't do that then it's not
going to be as good of an option you
really want your soil to to to drain
well um and it takes a lot of water you
really got to just like leave the
sprinklers on for a couple days type
thing and it's it's also something you
don't have to worry about yet so you can
sort of ignore this problem for a while
um in a high precipitation Place places
that get more than about 30 Ines of
rainfall per year which isn't Nevada
unfortunately but for listeners who have
maybe high sodium water um but live in a
place where it rains a lot that process
happens naturally so you're never seeing
elevated sodium because the water the
rainfall just keeps moving through the
soil profile and sodium luckily is very
Mobile in the soil so it moves through
the soil profile and out of the root
Zone pretty easily okay and then the
sodium listed here you 48 parts per
million he said it it competes with the
other cat ions potassium magnesium
calcium and calcium's higher at
107 magnesium's at 17 and then
potassium's at 3.4 so is that enough
calcium I guess another enough of the
other cat I to kind of compete with the
Sodium that's a good question so yeah I
mean to to the there's two issues with
sodium one is that it competes with the
uptake of other cat ions and the other
is that it increases the the um osmotic
stress or let's just call it salt stress
on the plants so at high levels it it
just adds more salt stress um and so it
makes it's harder for the plant to
uptake water and at these levels it um
technically what the plant is seeing is
Milla equivalence which is a it's not
it's a little bit more accurate way to
look at cations is like mill equivalence
looks at the the size of the ions in
addition to the quantity um and so yeah
I wouldn't worry about it I I would
worry about it antagonizing potassium
first and then
magnesium um it will reduce the uptake
of calcium but but the the what's going
to really hold your plants back is going
to be potassium and magnesium and we're
g we can see that on the the saturated
paste report which is a soil report um
if you look at
percentages we we let's let's wait on
jumping over there for now but that
would be the place to see if it's going
to really create like nutrient
deficiencies of other cant would be on
the paste
analysis but you got it I mean it's
mostly potassium
where there's going to be issues
understood okay what else do we need to
know about this okay so so I mentioned
high pH so you might think oh well can
you can you acidify the water well you
could you could drop the pH of your
water with acid um
but
there's you know some some
Waters have a pH of 7.7 and they just
need a tiny tiny bit of acid to drop the
ph and there's other Waters with a pH of
7.7 where you need quite a bit maybe a
whole handful um in a drum of water or
something so why is it that a water one
water with the same pH as another water
might need a little versus a lot of acid
to drop the ph and it's something called
alkalinity which is the the water's
resistance to pH change and with water
that has low alkalinity what that means
is that the the soil is going to buffer
the pH very easily so if you have low
alkalinity in your water uh your soil
it'll just very quickly reflect the soil
PH um or another way to say is it's not
going to change the soil PH very easily
now a water with a lot of alkalinity
means there's a lot of minerals that are
all putting upward pressure on the pH
that is a water that should be acidified
because it will influence the soil
solution pH quite significantly so
luckily even though your pH is 7.7 your
alkal alinity is relatively low and so
the the kind of arbitrary number I use
for alkalinity when to acidify versus
when to not is 120 parts per million and
you're at 70 so um yeah you know the
high pH isn't ideal it's not optimal but
it it shouldn't dramatically affect your
soil PH and just giving a little
foreshadowing to your soil your soil is
a very mineral Rich calcarius high
calcium very high PH soil so this water
is not going to affect the soil PH your
soil pH is like it's like an ocean liner
you're not going to be able to move it
very easily
um so I would not acidify this water I
don't think that's the right use of time
money effort energy and then there's
some other stuff on this test that we
can just Breeze through bicarbonate
bicarbonate is the most common ion that
that creates high pH in high alkalinity
and you're at 85 parts per million um so
essentially what you're doing when you
add acid is you're neutralizing that
bicarbonate and that drops the
alkalinity in the pH so you're probably
you know there's probably sodium
bicarbonate in your water essentially
baking soda so that's just another uh
mineral that's in your water and then
chloride and sulfate so chloride at 94
parts per million is slightly elevated
but the best way to manage chloride is
not to freak out about how much is in
your water but rather to just keep an
eye on chloride levels on the saturated
paste report and when that starts
getting elevated then you know you
should do a leeching event um similar to
what I discuss with
sodium um and then sulfate so sulfur is
a beneficial plant nutrient it's very
high in the Aid West in soil often times
and oftentimes in water and sure enough
you have high sulfate so a lot of the
salt concentration of your water is
coming from the calcium some of it's
coming from the sodium but you have a
whopping 235 parts per million of of
sulfate in the water so not only do you
have sodium bicarbonate but you also
probably have gypsum which is calcium
sulfate in your water so not a bad thing
but um you know that's that's also
adding to the the salinity of your water
the good news there is you know you you
may not need to apply as much Gypsum to
your soil because you're just getting
free calcium and sulfur now
unfortunately it's coming with sodium
and chloride and things like that as
well so that so the reading on this you
know this salt concentration is showing
618 PPM so it's high like you mentioned
you're you're reading 400 something like
that point is it's it's elevated you
have salty water some of those salts are
good some of them are bad um but the the
limitation really on this test is is
sodium and then the final four things
that you added this isn't included on
all Logan tests I usually don't get them
tested is nitrate um
phosphorus and uh so nitrate is 1.8 PPM
honestly a little more than I'd want but
it's not a problem I wouldn't worry
about it it's fine for drinking
um and then no phosphorus essentially
which is really good that would be very
strange if you saw phosphorus in your
drinking water um and then there's two
other metrics phc which just says like
is the water going to be depositing
minerals stripping minerals from your
soil and yours is 7.6 so that's a
resounding deposition water it's going
to be providing minerals to the soil
because it's so high in salts um if you
AR filtered it it would drop to like
below one and that would be a water
that's that's essentially um you know
water is polar so it wants to like
consume it wants to pull minerals into
solution so when it's less than like one
it'll be pulling minerals I don't like
the word stripping that sort of has a
negative connotation even though that is
sort of what's Happening um and then the
adjusted SAR sodium absorption ratio
that just means you have kind of that
that's a that's a very relevant
measurement agronomically for your soil
because it's speaking to the sodium um
but it's more of a it's not really
helpful for for Growers it's more it's
helpful for people like me to determine
when to suggest leeching soil in this
case I would so that's kind of that's a
lot so that's everything on the Water
Report there I do have a few questions
in regards to it you talked about
adjusting the pH you wouldn't really
have to adjust the pH in my particular
case but just for the folks listening
what are some general recommendations as
far as how to adjust the pH now you
mentioned for down it would be some sort
of acid right you're talking phosphoric
acid or you're talking something else
and then also what would you generally
use to adjust the pH upward
it really depends on if you're an
organic grower or not in organic
production the only two products that
are allowed to lower water PH are citric
acid or I'm sorry organic acids but
generally that's citric acid so any
organic acid could reduce water PH and
that's allowed um organic acids have you
know
Carbon and the most common and the least
expensive is citric
acid um
and the other option that's more even
more economic and really the only viable
option for Growers that are growing at
scale is sulfuric acid um sulfuric acid
is pretty uh CTIC you got to be careful
working with it you just be careful with
the PPE and um if you're you know for
Growers like around me who are reducing
their water PH they use sulfur burners
which is a tech think that used to be
used in indoor um
cultivation often times you're like
essentially sterilizing a room with a
sulfur burner this is different you're
you're burning sulfur and injecting it
into your irrigation water and it
reduces the pH but for small Growers
Organic acids are generally the best
option
um so yeah that's that's I guess what I
could say there you know some people get
creative with like different
ferments um you know really acidic
ferments or you know Theory you could do
it with a with like a humic substance
but it doesn't make sense because you're
you're really trying to do this in on an
ongoing basis so to continually reduce
water PH with the humic acid would be
overdoing it
um and then ph up I rarely am increasing
pH because generally an easier way to do
it is just put just push your soil PH up
a little bit and then when you water
with an acidic water in a and you water
a high pH soil they combine and create a
really good optimal pH so in my opinion
you just want to lime your soil up um
and it's okay to use a slightly acidic
water now sometimes occasionally if I
like over pH you know if I'm if I'm
reducing the pH of my water and I overdo
it I'll just throw in a little bit of
powdered lime calcium carbonate um the
bottled products that are are more
common would be like potassium
bicarbonate and things like that but
again I can't there's just not many
instances when I'm recommending an
increase in the water PH um usually I'm
decreasing pH and really I'm just
personally I decrease pH most often when
I'm doing foler sprays I like to
decrease my foler spray solution um it
improves the efficiency of the foler and
I always just use citric acid got it
okay a couple more questions here on the
Water Report there's a couple things
here that this report doesn't show that
are big concerns for Growers which is
chlorine and chloramine can you talk to
us a little bit about those two things
yeah that's a good question um I'm
curious how the lab tests chloride and
if chlorine and chloramine are included
in the chloride number um I should know
but I would need to think about the
chemistry there and have to look look at
the molecules and
things but no even if it was included in
the chloride number you don't
necessarily know the difference
between uh chloride chloramine and
chlorine the if I had to sort
of my my guess is those two are are
concerns of Growers not necessarily from
a chemistry standpoint but from a
biological standpoint yes because
they're natural sterilizing agents in
our water um to clean up our water and
so nobody gets you know lethally
ill but you
know yeah it's I guess it's a it's a
question of what weather we should be
drinking it too so those numbers aren't
reported I guess is the short answer
personally my general view of biology is
that there's not enough of those two
chemicals in the water to like smoke the
biology in your soil the concentrations
are low soil biology is very resilient
um and so I've never seen or heard of a
reduction in biological activity
abundance or diversity because someone's
using a water treated with chlorine or
chloramine of course if you went high
enough with those you could absolutely
kill everything but generally speaking I
don't think municipalities are are
pushing them um high enough to to Really
you know kill everything now are they
killing some things I don't know it's a
good it's it's I guess that's an open
question um no one's ever presented
evidence to me that reducing crop
quality or production or yield or even
biological numbers but that's not to say
it's not I would just question that
assumption a little bit and just I'd
love to see like someone who um I mean I
guess the the best way to to to answer
that question would be there's something
called DNA sequencing where you can
actually sequence the entire Genome of
the soil every single organism in the
soil it'd be interesting to see to
sequence a soil before and then after
like a season of chlorine and chloramine
application to see if um
the the total numbers of of organisms
decreases that would be really
interesting to see yeah because
generally you know for chloramine for
example it's generally said that there's
nothing that can be done in order to
eliminate chloramine but for chlorine a
lot of Growers they're doing a couple
things they're either letting their
water sit out for a period of 24 hours
some say that if you if you have light
on it that helps reduce the amount of
chlorine and then also some people
saying that it sticks to your skin so
some people actually stick their hand in
the bucket of water swirl it around and
they're saying that's reducing the
amount of chlorine is there any truth to
either one of those things well I can
definitely speak to the first thing and
say yes if you leave it out it
volatilizes off
um the sunlight I don't know I I just
don't know it might it might degrade the
molecule or something um the
arm don't I don't know but my tells me
no my gut tells me you just smell it on
your it's you know you're just smelling
the water on your arm but I don't know
um it could be there could be some kind
of
like light electrical charge that you
know grabs the molecules a little bit
that's possible
um in any case I wouldn't be too worried
about it unless you're using like a
really strong like you know it was pool
water I'd be worried about it but yeah I
mean everyone has a different style I
would say that that's generally not the
low hanging fruit in in you know yield
and crop quality as for in my experience
but it's not to say you shouldn't be
thinking about it okay and then last
question on the water side from me is I
want to get your overall thoughts on
kind of some of the water treatment
options out there that neutralize
contaminants for example there's the
product out there I won't name the
product but it says it neutralizes and
assists in reduction over 250
contaminants it reduces lead chlorine
fluoride
and uh 99% of industrial chemicals and
99% of pharmaceuticals it also
remineralizes those adds in like calcium
phosphorus potassium so I think there
are numerous products out there that do
something like this generally are these
products something that you recommend or
recommend that you avoid that people
avoid or what yeah so there's sort of
two categories of products I can think
of there's filtration products and then
there's like additives generally with
any kind of
filtration my my recommendation is take
a water test before the filter install
the filter take a water test after the
filter obviously it's not showing
everything definitely not
Pharmaceuticals and hormones and
chloramine and stuff like that but if
you see the numbers decrease of the
things you are testing for then you know
the filter is working and if these
things don't decrease well I could bet
you they're not taking anything else out
either so there's a lot of filters that
don't work and there's a really simple
solution you just test before and after
um and determine if your filters working
I do think filters work I think some of
them are extremely effective and some of
them are not very effective and there's
a whole spectrum and usually that's
correlated with the price of the filter
um so in general I believe in fil
filters I don't believe in additives
like things you add to the water that
tie up because here's what happens um
similar to what I was explaining with
sodium that water goes into the soil and
it may tie up things so it's not plant
available or it's you you know sort of
enclosed in a molecule and so the
microbes and the soil and the plants
can't access that thing but over time
those degrade and biology you know
there's a whole cycling process that
happens in the soil so if you put an ion
of lead in The Soil well it may be you
know complexed or chelated somehow but
over time eventually that's going to
become available because it's going to
cycle into availability and out of
availability a thousand times and so
when it comes to heavy metals and really
anything in my opinion tying it up is a
short-term solution but longterm you're
not solving anything um and so you
really just want to
avoid the addition of heavy metals to
begin with um because they're going to
they're going to just like sodium
they're going to accumulate as the water
evaporates and they stay and just
because they're tied up now doesn't mean
they're going to be tied up later
nothing is permanent okay yeah the
product I was mentioning is in your
definition an additive it's a a liquid
bottle that you would add to your yeah
that seems fishy to me I mean it's
probably like a carbon based thing and
then if it's not carbon based it's like
definitely not organic and you might be
creating other contamination issues you
know like keates aren't the the kindest
thing either synthetic key lades so um I
don't like those I would not recommend
that there's a lot unfortunately in the
world of water there's sort of like a
lot of snake oil um and there's a lot of
things that I don't even want to call
them snake oil I just want to say like
they're unproven or they're sort of
questionable and for some reason this I
mean all the way from like structured
water to mag magnified and electrified
water there's just like this whole
Rabbit Hole of water I've gone down it
unfortunately and gotten like you know
sold on things and then had to sort of
come back out and realize like wait what
am I doing like I should stop obsessing
about the quality of water I haven't
seen and I haven't seen any improvements
in crop health and yield um if you are
going to invest in something that's
you're not sure about or that you think
could be you know kind of bogus what I
always recommend is do a split test so
like if possible break your farm your
garden your grow into into in half and
do no treatment on half and do the
treatment on the other half and just
observe if you see a difference like
make the result speak for themselves I
think every product should have to prove
itself so that's often difficult with
water because you're installing
something and that's the source of your
water so how are you going to like you
know go back and forth but in general
that's the concept I think All Growers
should always be thinking about is like
if you're going to invest money try to
figure out a way to like prove it to
yourself that it's going to work okay
good to know should we move on to the so
test now sure let's do it what do we
need to know about the soil test there's
two different ones from Logan Labs there
one that's labeled soil report and then
there's one labeled as saturated paste
report yeah so in general my
recommendation to Growers is to get a
complete soil test from Logan um Logan's
my go-to lab it's the only lab I use
I've calibrated I've seen you know tens
of thousands of these tests so I can't
really switch Labs because all labs are
a little bit different um and I really
recommend Logan Labs partially because
they do what's called a saturated Pace
test as part of their complete analysis
and so a standard soil tast test
generally uses a strong acid and they
extract all these theoretically
available nutrients with a acid with a
pH of
2.5 and it's supposed to show you what's
your bank account of nutrients looks
like and so that's what you see on kind
of like any normal soil report and they
have different acid extractions and
different techniques but what Logan does
is they then take your soil and they
combine it with your irrigation water
and they do a water extract it's called
a saturated paste test T so on the one
hand you see the standard soil test
that's like all the nutrients that may
be available over decades in your soil
and then you see the saturated past test
which is okay what are the nutrients
that are available today that are
soluble that
are available to your roots right now
and the reality is not one or the other
but it's really helpful to see both of
those tests to be able to to sort of see
what's happening real time as well as
the general chemical pattern of your
soil and so that's why I recommend
getting both of these
um so I guess like the first thing just
kind of like I'm just instead of going
through it all in in great detail which
you know I cover in my course and it
takes hours let me just point let me
just kind of point out a couple things
about your soil that I feel like are
relevant the first thing on the standard
test that I see is you have a organic
matter of
1% um which is is unfortunately quite
low and what this means is yeah you
probably have a grally rocky sandy soil
that just doesn't um hold organic matter
like a clay soil would and that's just
so it's partially just a function of the
soil texture um but it also is a
function of where you live in the
country you know generally organic
matter levels aren't super high in Aid
environments because there hasn't been
eons of tropical jungles and plant
growth and forests and things like that
you're in the desert there's just not a
lot of vegetation that's gone into that
soil over the long term so the best
solution for you in my opinion for your
nutrient management
is is simply large amounts of biomass of
composts
manure uh
mulch um small amounts of wood chips and
biochar I mean anything any carbon based
input and specifically just compost I
mean large applications of compost I
think
will um work wonders in combination with
uh just Garden it cover cropping I mean
whether it's your vegetables and your
trees or if it's a cover crop like a
living cover crop over time that will
really start to raise organic matter and
just start pushing carbon into the soil
it's a longterm process but the
combination of carbon based inputs and
and actually like cover cropping is the
best solution for the soil and you know
mineralization through organic
amendments will help but at the end of
the day over the long term you just want
to get more organic matter in the soil
that's sort of your like your insurance
policy against all nutrients so that's
the first thing would worm castings be
in that category totally I forgot worm
castings worm castings are great um you
know the problem with being in Nevada or
Arizona or Colorado is the same problems
with the water that we're looking at and
the same problems with the soil that you
have are also going to be seen in the
comp post that you buy commercially
around you it's probably going to be
high in sodium it's probably going to be
high in you know calcium and sulfur and
so it's
like there's not a perfect antidote from
a compost standpoint generally because
it's it's going to have the same sort of
underlying pattern as these other things
in the environment um but still castings
if you can make them um just carbon of
all kinds I mean like heavy mulch leaves
just
and I would personally in an AED
environment with low organic matter I
actually like tillage only because I'm
able to
incorporate this these carbon sources
easier you can get them deep I mean you
can like just broad fork or double dig
organic matter is you know as deep as
you can go and then over time you can
back off on the disturbance on the
tillage um but for right now I would
just try to get tons of organic matter
in that so okay yeah it's Rocky out here
I have to use a jackhammer order to get
down low oh man so yeah it's uh it's
pretty brutal I mean so yeah so that's
the other thing that soil test won't
show you is rocks I mean rocks are like
obviously everyone knows rocks are not
good for for plants but so sometimes the
best investment you can make in a field
or a garden is is Rock picking which is
extraordinarily time and energy
intensive but like the the you know
there's these old farms around here
where the entire edge of the farm is
like a giant pile of Rock rocks so some
Oldtimer some Pioneer literally like
picked the rocks out and and that was
the best in that was the best long-term
investment they could have made in that
field because to this day like people
can grow in it and they're not you know
and I know you're in a garden scale but
there's implements on tractors that can
like they're called Rock Pickers that
can remove rocks from Fields so anyway
that's
interesting yeah get the rocks out Jack
hammeron go as deep as you can go and in
the process is you're disturbing it
getting the rocks out try to get
castings organic matter mulch anything
in there will do um so the other things
I'm seeing on here is like your
phosphorus is particularly low so I like
to look at phosphorus on this serer test
you have 28 pound per acre of phosphate
which is
p205 um for really heavy feeding
vegetables let's just say Tomatoes I
like that to be a thousand so heavy
applications of bone meal I think would
serve you very well um and bone meal or
fish bone meal whatever your preference
is also brings in uh 3 to 4% nitrogen 3%
on bone meal 4% on fishbone meal so uh I
would be thinking about like in year one
and two like my primary nitrogen Source
in addition to the compost would be
would be some kind of bone meal um and
that'll just really push your phosphorus
levels way up and provide quite a bit of
available nitrogen as well fishbone meal
also has nice micronutrients in it the
downside of fishbone meal is it's from
the ocean so it also has high sodium and
chloride which you already have an
excess of so personally I'd go with bone
meal and so between the the bone meals
and the heavy compost SL castings
application I think that will probably
get you the nitrogen that you need your
nitrogen your available nitrogen which
is tested on that soil test as in
inorganic forms um of ammonium and
nitrate are both like less than one PPM
depending on the crop and depending on
the production system you want that
quite a bit higher like 25 to 125 parts
per million of nitrate depending on what
you're growing how long it's in the
ground uh top soil versus you know pee
based engineered media there's a number
of variables but for your for you
perennial trees and vegetables I would
want that at 30 to 50 parts per million
of nitrate so heavy compost and bone
meal should get you there but the best
thing to do is incorporate those things
and then retest and see where see where
things fall because compost is highly
variable um so there's it's it's hard to
be precise with compost the best thing
to do is just get it in there and then
retest and see where you're at um but in
general I mean uh just to give you a
rate on compost uh or castings let's
just say it's a 1% nitrogen compost
which is pretty typical like a rich
compost uh castings yeah let's just say
1% I would apply
20 tons per acre which
is like 440 lb per th square feet but
quite a bit um when you spread that
though it spreads out pretty quick I
mean that's like probably only a quarter
inch or something but you could easily
go with like a half an inch deep and
then and then work it in um and people
with a with a more mellow compost you go
way heavier than that you could do two
inches and just really work it in heavy
I never recommend applying more than two
inches of compost in a single
application and I would want that to be
like a a mellow yard waist sort of
compost not a manure based
compost castings tend to be rich
depending on how they're made um do you
make them yourself yeah I do have a worm
bin so I do have but it's real small
scale it's a small bin in my garage
actually so yeah so in your case you're
just applying everything you can make
yeah exactly yeah I would just make it
as much as you can as fast as you can
and just get it out there I do have a
local source that has worm castings but
they also add in kelp and rock dust
which I thought was kind of interesting
yeah both great products for trace
minerals non- essential but highly
beneficial and bios stimulating trace
minerals I use I've always used rock
dust and kelp I've backed off recently
if you're getting tested for arsenic in
your you know cash crop I would not use
those but um or heavy metals just in
general but I've always used them in my
vegetable garden because I'm trying to
sort of increase the mineralization of
my food
um yeah so a a a well-made compost just
apply it liberally as as much as you can
afford up to 2 in um and if you
overshoot and it's a little too rich and
your your nutrients get a little too
high that's generally okay when it's a
compost-based nutrient if you're using
synthetic nutrients it's a lot more
risky um but over a flying compost is in
your case probably not the end of the
world let's see let me just jump to a
couple other things um your your soil
has a pach of
8.6 which
is probably shockingly high for a lot of
listeners um and it is quite High way
above optimal and um yet I'll make the
point that an excessively high pH is not
nearly as much of a problem as an
excessively low ph pH so if you put a
plant in a pH of 8 versus a plant in a
pH of
4.5 the plant that goes into the the
soil with a pH of 4.5 is going to be
much worse off much much worse off my
soil pH is 8.2 and you should see the
explosive growth on my peach
trees so um in the west again the Arid
West that hasn't had you know thousands
of inches tens of thousands millions of
inches of rainfall over the last several
thousand th years those minerals levels
are just so high that it pushes the the
ph up and it's we can't unfortunately
adjust the pH of our soil very easily
because there's just huge amounts of
Free lime in the so in the parent
material of the soil so I would not
recommend trying to reduce your soil PH
I would simply um try to balance the
nutrients as well as possible and let
the the plant RIS asphere acidify just
that tiny little area next to the root
to make nutrients available in instead
of trying to acidify the bulk soil that
makes sense and and I noticed you
mentioned the pH on the soil report
versus it also shows a pH on the
saturated paste report yeah so this is
okay let There great great point so like
I said the soil pH is 8.6 but then when
you combine the soil with your
irrigation water which is what the lab
you submitted some irrigation water
obviously for the water tests but then
the lab used your irrigation water for
the pace test so they're trying to
replicate what the soil solution looks
like after you irrigate and so even
though your your water pH is high it
actually dropped the soil solution pH
because the soil is 8.6 the water was
7.7 and the combination of the two is
7.9 so believe it or not your water your
high pH water is actually slightly
acidifying the soil solution which is a
good thing it's bringing that down so
the the plant roots don't actually see
8.6 they see 7.9
um so I guess I said I wouldn't
recommend acidifying your water I still
wouldn't but if you did it would help
theoretically um if you were really
trying to optimize if you were like if
you had like 100 acres of Premium Fruit
or medicinal plants or something and you
were really trying to optimize your your
growth I would say you yeah
acidification with a sulfur burner would
totally help but on a small scale I
don't think there would be much of a
difference and I think it would be a
huge pain in the
butt um so yeah your plant roots are
swimming in 7.9 otherwise the TR the
because you're they combine the the
irrigation water with your soil the
other thing that's high on the pace
report is sodium unfortunately because
again you're the it's it's sort of
reflecting that high sodium in the in
the water so your sodium in the SL in on
the past report is 56 parts per million
and unfortunately your potassium is only
six parts per million so I would expect
if you didn't amend your soil your plant
your plants would show pretty acute
potassium deficiency and potentially
magnesium deficiency magnesium is
actually I think magnesium is okay it's
30 parts per million and the reason I
say that is because if you jump down on
the pce report to the percentages
calcium is 43% of the soil solution
pretty good I like 40 to 60% generally
higher is better but um I don't think
your plants are going to have calcium
accute Calcium
deficiency the Magnesium is 28% that's
actually pretty high I like magnesium to
be like 20% of the soil solution and
you're at 28% so the magnesium in the
soil and the Magnesium from the water
from a balance standpoint is sufficient
but then the next two are where the
problem lies potassium is 1.7 % on the
pace test so 1.7% of the solil solution
is potassium and 27% is sodium medicinal
plants that we've talked about before I
generally see potassium but Growers call
lock out but what I call
antagonisms essentially potassium
nutrient deficiency visually manifests
when that percentage of sodium goes
above the perc potassium so in this case
you're not even close like that sodium
is so much higher than the potass that I
could I would bet money that those
plants would struggle and you would see
weird symptoms that maybe look like
potassium deficiency but often times
just look hard to identify visually and
that's that sodium blocking the uptake
of potassium so in your case I think
this a large compost application will
really push potassium up because there's
a lot of potassium in compost but I
would
also um be ready to feed potassium and I
like uh organically there's a product
called pottassium sulfate it's not
carbon based but it is allowed in
organic production and that'll really
push up soluble potassium it'll move
that percentage toward potassium and
away from sodium so you're not removing
sodium you're just adding more potassium
to try to U kind of balance the scale so
yeah I mean I guess the takeaway here is
just apply huge amounts of compost and
retest because it's hard to be precise
and then I think what you need to be
aware of is having a an additional
nitrogen Source on hand if that compost
doesn't provide the nitrogen you need
and your plants are hungry or you retest
and it's still low I think having any
kind of nitrogen meal so aala meal
soybean meal um blood meal feather meal
and just whatever you want to use
whatever your preference is um or you
could use like a liquid nitrogen like uh
liquid fish hydrate or
um you know any kind of powdered soluble
nitrogen
so that's I would I would just have that
ready I think that's an important tool
in the toolbox for you and I would also
have a small amount of potassium sulfate
ready um because if that compost doesn't
provide enough potassium or the sodium
keeps keeps accumulating over time you
might need to keep chasing balance by
applying
potassium um and otherwise I I wouldn't
necessarily oh and the bone meals that's
right that's
pre-plant and otherwise I'd say like see
with the compost a large comp compost
application does for you I mean zinc and
copper are both low iron's low manganese
is low a balanced micronutrient blend
might really benefit you um but I think
those again you might get that through
the compost so I would wait and see okay
one of the things on here that we didn't
talk about is silicon and you know
silica is non-essential element for
medicinal plants I know it's essential
in some plants I believe it's horse
tailes if I remember correctly it is an
essential element but generally for a
lot of plants I believe it's a
non-essential element now this percent
here say well it says 29.3 on the report
is that a high number is that a low
number yeah so silica is interesting
it's yes technically it's nonessential
but it's so
beneficial
that it should be thought of as an
essential nutrient um from for all the
plants we're talking about because it
just it increases abiotic stress
resistance um it strengthens cell walls
it just has like a weird almost
biostimulating effect on yield and plant
growth and
health so
uh generally speaking silica
applications are always going to be
beneficial the the reason I don't love
the Silicon number on a standard soil
test is I'm not sure that silicon is
plants available so essentially that
that acidic uh soil extractant is just
kind of dissolving some of the soil and
the silica I mean rocks are made out of
silica so a lot of a lot of that's just
kind of like it's hard to know if it's
actually plant available or not but to
answer your question 29 PPM is a quite
High number um so you have really good
silica in your soil whether or not it's
plant available hard to know uh
especially at your high pH level if the
pH was a little lower um I do think a
lot of it a lot more of it would be
available I also think that in theory
biology over time um soil micro should
be mineralizing that into availability
so personally I wouldn't apply any more
silica cuz it's there and I think it's
important for commercial cultivators to
think about and I think the best way I
guess I'll add one more thing Chris in
your
soil like my soil the numbers are kind
of crazy I mean extremely high pH the
total exchange capacity is like false
because what it's doing is it's just
looking at all that Free lime in the
soil profile so you have this h huge
amount of calcium in the soil tons in
the water large amounts of sodium really
low micronutrients everything is just
like wonky so the best thing you can do
in my opinion is you're never going to
get a balanced soil you're never going
to like have the picture perfect soil
report which is okay because that's not
the goal the goal is healthy plants so
the best thing you can do is tissue test
a plant whatever your highest value
plant is maybe you're like you're going
to focus on tomatoes this year I would
send a tissue test of the leaves of the
tomato plant to the lab you can order
these on my website and see what the
plant is actually
uptaking and see if it's getting enough
calcium and enough magnesium and um
nitrogen and so and just I would I would
manage your nutrients more based on what
you're seeing on tissue tests rather
than soil tests so I always think it's
good to pre do pre-plant amendments
based on a soil test but then it's often
helpful to just ask the plant what it
needs more of and sort of guide your
your amendments your top dressing your
feeds based on on tissue testing um and
that's you know soil tests and tissue
tests are generally pretty well
correlated in let me just say normal
soils but in our soils that you and I
are growing in it gets weird um like for
example last year my plants didn't have
enough calcium even though like your
soil test has showed enormous amounts of
calcium in the soil and that's just cuz
we're dealing with these very strange
desert soils so I I don't want to negate
the the the power of soil testing and I
don't want to Discount the the
usefulness of this test in particular
but at the same time um when things get
weird test the plant good advice I have
one more question here now I know some
people will actually add in when they're
trying to revive their soil they add in
like a Pete or cocoa some people add in
like
Iration uh and then other folks will
actually also inoculate with micro Gres
I notic we didn't talk about any of that
here in this particular case so you
would you advise against adding in Pete
for example or some form of variation
whether it be perite or or any of the
other ariation points and then inocula
with microbes I know she didn't talk
about that at all yeah great so um those
are two other yeah so I mean the reason
we haven't talked about it is because
we're looking at uh a soil nutrients
analysis and none of those things will
change the nutrients or balance the
nutrients um but that's not to say that
they're not important or recommended I
would let me let's talk about Pete and
Aggregates first those change the
physical properties of the soil not that
they're they're inert so chemically they
they have very little influence on the
soil chemistry especially when you're
applying on to Top Soil um they're not
providing nutrients and um Pete might
have a light downward pressure on the pH
but in your soil won't do anything um
the purpose of them is to improve the
the structure the ation capabilities of
the soil and the drainage capacity and
things like that so in certain instances
in your case this may it may be one like
just getting a better physical tilth may
be
very nice and it may benefit the plants
tremendously I mean Pete Moss uh it's
kind of a a double-edged sword because
on the one hand we don't Pete bogs are a
big impact so when we use use Pete Moss
we just need to be aware that like
that's a resource in someone else's
backyard that we're Mining and it has an
impact but it performs extremely well so
I I love Pete Moss I think it's great um
it's going to loosen the soil Pete Moss
has this interesting characteristic
where it both kind of loosens and arates
the soil but it also holds water well so
that's why Pete Moss works so well so
incorporating things like that in a in a
top soil um really in a small
environment can work once you get larger
than even a few hundred square feet it
gets very expensive for the benefit you
get I don't generally recommend adding
aggregate to a top soil I would say
carbon based Iration sources so cocoa
and Pete are much better the only time
I'm ever thinking about Iration is in an
engineered media like a Peete based
potting soil um for indoor production or
you know when you're growing in pots or
raised beds I think that's fine when it
comes to microbes so microbes what
they're the role of microbes is to cycle
nutrients that are already in the soil
so personally I have a philosophy that
if you use carbon based
inputs and
you grow living roots and you irrigate
really well you keeps consistent soil
moisture and you feed you have a
consistent flow of carbon through your
soil system in all different forms from
molasses to wood chips and everything in
between over time the microbial
Community can get very healthy and so I
inoculate at planting I every plant I
put in the the ground I do a dry
pelleted micro isal inoculant and a root
dip in a full spectrum bacterial
inoculant and that's and then I just
like you know let the indigenous
microorganism sort of run their course
and I just try to feed cover crop I
irrigate I do all the things I can to
just feed the microbes and that's my
only inoculation but people do it
different people Brew teas um people
will create ferments which is really
sort of you're getting the microbial
byproducts more than the microbes
themselves um so yeah I mean you can
kind of be pushing microbes through the
season and that's that's definitely
going to help but long term I think the
best thing you can do is just treat your
soil well and and constantly be feeding
carbon ources into your soil okay
awesome good advice I appreciate you
taking the time today to go over the
water test and soil test and can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and is there anything upcoming in the
future that you want to talk about yeah
sure so people can find me first and
foremost on my website which is soyd
consulting.com
um everything I offer is on there
testing online courses things like that
uh I'm on and off of Instagram so
Instagram handle is soil doctor where I
put out short nerdy videos about soil
and different farming practices and
things um during the busy growing season
I don't really produce much but in the
winter I generally put out a lot of my
learnings for the year on Instagram and
I would just recommend no matter the
size uh if anyone's interested in
getting a soil test it's like get your
soil tested or get a single tissue test
or a water test after this conversation
you can order them all on my website and
I work with Growers of all sizes
so um I'd recommend it I mean it's it's
a pretty low investment to really
understand the the most important thing
about your your production in your
garden so um I would just push people to
my website to check out the offerings
and and if they're interested reach out
awesome all right well I'll definitely
have a link down in the description
section below so you can easily get to
his website and uh if you haven't tuned
into that previous episode we did
together definitely tune into that I'll
have that link down in the YouTube
description section below as well or you
can just search for it on YouTube just
type in soil doctor and Mr Grow it and
it should pop right up should be the
first result or so Brian thanks so much
once again for coming on here this has
been very insightful I've learned so
much from this and have a feeling a lot
of my audience has learned from this as
well so appreciate you taking the time
today yeah Chris thanks for inviting me
on um I appreciate it and it's it's fun
to look your soil and your water over in
Nevada awesome all right peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode