welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 123 in this episode I interview
Mr Nice Guy he's been gardening for 5
years and is big into DIY gardening he
has created his own DIY hydroponic setup
at home he talks all about the
hydroponic setup and how he grows in it
he also talks about some common problems
and solutions and he reveals a lot of
great advice when it comes to Growing
hydroponically if you want to see short
bite-sized clips of these episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube I
also have a gardening Channel where I
have over 130 videos showing the plants
that I've grown I'll have both of those
channels linked down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
General Public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to aec Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their ion frame
LED grill lights which have the latest
Samsung Evo LEDs these grill lights
include a schedule controller that
features 10 brightness levels dimming
and a sunrise sunset feature click the
link in the description section below so
you can learn more about their ion frame
LED grow lights and the discount code Mr
Grow 15 works on both Amazon and their
their website AC infinity.com happy
Hydro they have some of the best
complete beginner grow kits on the
market today their kits include a grow
tent grow light ventilation system grow
pots soil nutrients and more they have
36 different kits in their beginner
category and also have advanced kits
cheap kits and kits that include an auto
watering system go to happy hydro.com
Link in the description and use the
discount code Mr grow during checkout to
save on your order stash blend stash
plant is a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and microle fungi check it out at
stash blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash and we are back welcome to the
Gard Talk podcast today I am joined with
Mr Nice Guy how you doing today hey
how's it going Chris good good thanks
for coming on did you happen to get your
name from that 1997 Jackie Chan movie Mr
Nice Guy where the Chinese Chef
accidentally gets involved with the news
reporter who filmed a drug bus that went
Airy is now being chased by gangs who
are trying to get the videotape um read
that plot right then and there pretty
pretty close on the genre at least I
mean it was in the 90s but I don't know
if you've seen Half Half Baked maybe but
uh the delivery service was Mr next
deliveries kind of stole it off them oh
that's funny that's where you got it
from well thanks for coming on to the
podcast today we're going to talk all
about Hydroponics which is really your
bread and butter DIY let's get into all
that you have a lot of experience there
can you first tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening um yeah most definitely if
anything um uh my background isn't too
like uh let me say focused on on like qu
culture or or growing or anything like
that um rather of it is DIY I learn and
do a lot of research between what I know
and how I can apply it so a lot of
experience from work not to mention I I
grew up you know at a young age working
like know construction asphal framing
did a lot of lot of different like
physical kind of jobs uh growing up so
I've used that to apply it to you know
now I'm gardening and uh fixing my
house um I I grew up here in cali
southern California so you can imagine
um the weather is not not too crazy but
it does kind of shift Up Up and Down I
mean like I mentioned um uh a lot of my
DIY goes into my my experience through
life and uh I mean i' I've been working
on cars computers Electronics ever since
I was a little kid kind of mentioning
and applying that where I need it where
can be uh used most
efficiently um I I look up to Growers
like yourself on YouTube uh ever since I
started um Mr kanuck I don't know if you
watch debacco or I mean we love Mr bugby
if anything kind of on my feet on a
daily um so I I'm an everyday learner so
if I could apply it to what I you know
love as a hobby or you know as a grower
or Gardener that I I try to you know be
the best I can I when it comes to
gardening I guess I really started
gardening when I first purchased my home
that was a few years ago I mean with my
wife and we have a lot of you know
backyard space to do so uh we have
avocados we we can try going watermelons
potatoes assortment of tomatoes if you
want to call that a kids love doing that
my my daughter loves picking those and
growing them herself I have a Mand tree
I'm trying to grow a lemon tree so I can
have the necessity you know every
everyone's backyard kind of dream for
that same reason and then I have my my
seasonal medicinal plan that's outside
for the most part it's kind of
derivative of my indoor stuff that I
have and I push it out there when
season's right and now what would you
say is your overall style of gardening
are you indoor outdoor Organics
synthetics soil cocoa what's your style
uh well I would imagine my my style of
gardening would pertain mostly to endoor
Hydroponics um where I use different
methods of growing for different growth
stages uh you I use Co I use cocoa Rock
W hydren I also use synthetic Blends um
especially since you're it's a
hydroponic system it needs to be clean
you can't have too many builds up algae
or film and you know causing the flow to
stop one way or the other um I I work a
lot with uh recirculating system so I I
need the flow to be constant and
consistent uh let me see here um I'm I'm
trying to maintain a Perpetual grow so I
have two different tents IND doors that
I have like my seedlings my my cuts my
fresh cuts I have on one side and when
they're rooted enough and big enough to
move to the to my bigger 10 or my my
next 10 over and I have my end stages of
like vegetation and and flowering at the
end of in there at least and repeat the
process of the take cuts that I need and
get tired of the the C ofari kind of go
on the search for another mother you
know so mostly Hydroponics indoors
perfect that's exactly what we're
talking about today and I know you like
to get into the DIY side of things you
built your own dwc system let's break it
down a little bit for the beginners
first some people not might not know
what dwc is or also are DW can you
explain what both of those things are
well um dwc or you know deep water
culture more or less a form of
hydroponic similar to like I don't know
if you're I know you're familiar with
the crackie method the you know simple
thing is like having a jar and you know
roots are hanging into the water and it
kind of depletes the nutrients as it
grows um I think water culture is more
passive uh or less passive for that same
reason it requires that you you
implicate oxygen so we can add uh add to
the roots for that same reason and you
know that's kind of the difference
between overwatering your plants and
underwatering them it's definitely
capable of doing so within water culture
as well um in a nutshell the plant is
suspended in a neutral like medium with
its roots mostly hanging out the
container uh to take the nutrient water
up and at the same time you have like I
mentioned some oxygen um being air rated
up from maybe
a like a AirStone or depending on how
big you have setup it's to drill some
micro bubbles up there and and keep the
keep the auction going keeping the plant
healthy and keeping it some some air to
breathe and theni to maybe a uh rdwc of
recycling the water culture um in my
let's say uh situation I have like a
kind of three three plant uh setup where
I have all the buckets kind of
interconnected with uh PVC tubing
that'll give it a nice flow between all
all the same water flowing between the
three plants it'll make it so I don't
have to refill or maintain individually
those plants those same plants um and to
be honest like you know when you're
doing like a deep water culture or like
you know something that's all connected
you want to kind of keep to the same
kind of like plant or
cultivar just so it doesn't get too
you're not too too different uh in grow
growth rate or like things you have to
kind of like uh like let's say maybe
manipulate the the different nutrients
that you have for plant so some some
plants like uh they're they're very
temperamental you know this and
depending on where they come from they
have different uh let's say means to
uptake nutrients I mean for the most
part the two biggest differences between
the deep water culture and you know
recycling is is the the passing of the
water between the tubes and it can be
anywhere from you know simple like uh
vinyl tubing or you can go PVC tubing I
mean nice and setups where they
anywhere from in inch stick to uh pipes
to like 3 in so um you can go anywhere
from there to be honest it's not the
biggest difference if you have a smaller
setup but the the higher flow would be
kind of will circulate a lot of the
nutrients and keep it like not idle it
won't be sitting there and kind of like
building up film or anything of the sort
and that's us the case with like deep
water culture usually the water is like
fluctuating a lot got it and so arguably
our dwc is a little bit easier for the
regions you mentioned uh there's a you
know Reservoir and things are
recirculating through multiple plants
and you really just have that one
control versus dwc kind of like
individual buckets right and you got to
fill up individual buckets and and
manage the nutrients for each individual
plant but like you mentioned has a
downsize for recirculating system if
you've got all different cultivars in
there and they have kind of different
nutrient uptake it can be finicky right
you can have some plants that are
perfectly healthy and others that are
deficient so yeah there's definitely
some pros and cons to both of those
methods and that's pretty cool that you
do the rdwc method and know that you
actually built your own setup can you
talk to us about the DIY hydroponic
recirculating system that you set up
well for my setups for the most part I I
like to have a basis and you know before
I build so I can have some expectations
at the end um a lot of it does pertain
to budget and the space to have to work
with and more or less trying to maximize
the the usage as of what I have already
and what I need to get with my 2x4
design um I designed
a like I mentioned a three plan rdwc
system um I I also kind of implicated a
waterfall to get like top roots with top
with some some moisture as well uh those
are kind of like
a like the idea of a bubble bubble ponic
kind of a system where we have a
waterfall and then give some new to the
top route so they can expand through the
oxygen gap between the the bubbles
coming from the bottom of the water so
you don't essentially don't want to feel
like your the water too high I have a
four like a a 4 gallon bucket I I merely
fill it up like a third and then it kind
of all the moisture hits the roots
anyways and there's very little dry back
the basics to some some deep water
cultures require a reservoir depending
on how you go about adding your
nutrients I personally deleted my
reservoir and even my chiller for for
more space within my
room um but depending on your situation
I know it's kind of humid where you stay
water temperatures might be like you
know kind of kind of up there uh so I
can imagine using your Chiller would be
more optimal for you guys um
unfortunately I didn't need that so I
kind of pulled it saved some electricity
and the extra you know computer tower
that to sit on the outside of my tents
but here in Cali we're I'm pretty good
with my water temps at Mid 60 sometimes
I mean the colder the better not too
cold but colder Roots the the better the
uptake from for the most part like I was
mentioned earlier about Space Management
so I I do a lot of measurements I make
sure everything does fit um especially
with the buckets uh they're not easy to
find for like let's
say um aside from commercial use you got
to go far why trying to find these
buckets with their proper Lids if they
don't already come with them I use Uline
um they do sell a lot of commercial
materials for like you know job sites
and this and that but you know anybody
can purchase it regardless of your
setatus of wholesaler or being in
business um to be honest I I found my
buckets at Home
Depot they were uh they were sitting on
a stack I guess they were um putting
flowers in them and like they were there
to take so I'm like oh can I have these
I'm going to use them for a project I'm
like yeah I take a few if you want
they're essentially trash but there's
some nice black buckets that I found
Lids on UL line for and I drilled off
some holes um added a a netting pot on
there to hold my uh my rock wool my
essentially the plant that's going to be
growing in there for the rest of it Life
by the way my my netting pods are
anywhere from like 8 in pretty big ones
that sit halfway through the bucket and
I mean great expansion for my roots and
The Rock will opens up pretty well I
feel the gaps with um with um hydr and
and it does pretty well with the
drainage for that same reason and as for
like the uh the flow I I've gone from
tubing vinyl tubing to PVC piping I
found different um Outlets to on on
Uline and even Amazon for that same
reason too kind of build it properly
make sure everything fits and for the
same reason you you don't want to make
build something like this and not be
sure that's not going to fail the worst
thing in the world is a water leak
Midway through your you're grow and you
have to like flush and then redo it all
over again dismantle it and find your
leak seal it and go for it that's that's
kind of the nightmare of a of
Hydroponics or or deep water cultur it's
like filling the bottom of your your
tent with with uh with
water getting that vacuum out you
mentioned 4 gallon buckets why 4 gallon
would it be better with a larger bucket
or smaller why why four um it really
really depends on like again the spacing
that you have um the taller the bucket
uh I probably wouldn't mind too much but
the the 4 gallon bucket um height and
anywhere from like a a foot and a/4 up
and then they're like maybe 10 in wide
so it's a great fit um for giving the
space for the pent to grow upwards and
it doesn't take too much space around it
so I can have piping and um other things
like different fans and uh maybe a pump
for my water within the tent more as a
cleaner area and now you have a
concerned of the roots kind of filling
up that space how do you know like I
guess plant size to bucket size that's
kind of like a blessing in um you
know uh in in a situational in itself
because like the more Roots definitely
you want to get everyone wants Roots you
want to fill your even in so you want to
fill your bucket your your pot over
Roots as much as you can at the same
time we I have my my water flowing
through one another and U these roots
can get clogged within those pipes and
at the same time that's why people have
bigger pipes so the roots don't kind of
like clog up and and affect the next the
next pot over um but yeah that's that's
ble all in itself so like you want the
big Roots but at the same time you don't
want clogs either because you need that
water to flow in not overflow at the
same time my um my drip it's taken out
of the um one of the same buckets that's
connected so it's taking water from the
bottom and throwing it on top of each of
the of the other Bott buckets so it's
this is going to overflow if I have one
of them cloged at the same time so
maintaining them is definitely a good
idea keeping an eye on them got it that
makes sense and then what size tubing or
or PVC and how do you kind of determine
that I know you said you're using a for
gal like what size tubing for the for
gal and then is it Go by number of
plants to the size tubing does that
relate at all or no with this my most uh
recent um build it it was availability
um and I would have definitely went
bigger tubing I personally have it at an
inch and a half um almost 2 inch so um I
would definitely have gone to two or
three but the second part that's needed
wasn't always available so the knuckle
that I I I thread the PVC into I didn't
have the other part to go go bigger than
what I had so it's I'm dealt those cars
so I kind of make the best of it if
anything but I hope they have a 3in like
threaded knuckle I can add to my next
setup I definitely would go bigger for
that same reason with the roots and and
the clogging issues um ABS maybe um it's
it's black versus white it's it'll Tak
in less less lighting and no buildup of
like Aly between the tubes it's thick
enough I believe so I I personally
haven't come across it with this tube
but you will with vinyl all day okay
good to know and then Reservoir if I
know you said you're not running a
reservoir but for those that are looking
to run a reservoir how do they determine
what size to use Reservoir space um
personally I have or when I did have my
reservoir it it was great to have it um
to the left of my or what whichever side
of my tent um with that Reservoir out
there you're going to have to find the
means to uh run a line and you can't run
lines um horizontally or or you know at
an angle or anything like that for that
same reason you need to have it level to
the ground so the water can flow and a
lot of these tents aren't made with like
you know outlets at the bottom of of the
tent they're usually like you know have
fo it up for like you know ducks or or
or cables so you're going to have to
punch some holes to the bottle of your T
and you know kind of modify uh an outlet
so you can find a side for your
Reservoir and as for the size of it it
really depends on and how much you want
to like uh suspend for your tanks to use
so it's a reservoir and then like like a
an automatic fill so when your Reservoir
starts losing water it starts refilling
from the top bucket um and those go
anywhere from like 10 15 Gallons uh
they're they're convenient as hell
really you don't have to go inside your
tent um you your your refills are are
much easier um I want to say maybe your
flushing it probably be more of a pain
in kind of clearing out you know an
extra bucket um especially if your your
grow is more
compact but um again I I I always look
for you know more efficiency for my turn
and you know how much more easier it
would be you it's the same same idea or
outcome um I'm probably going to go for
the the ladder in and then can you talk
to us about like pump size like if
somebody's building their own system and
you know whether it be a four plant
system or eight plant system like how do
they determine what pump size and how
many airstones to kind of put in each
bucket I'm to be honest I've always find
myself always going bigger the better
for for some things or um the better
quality and and brand for that same
reason but there's definitely a minimum
of like let's say um free air pump I I
have a a three plant system with 6 in uh
flat airstones and I have one commercial
pump with Outlets running for all of
them um there's there's definitely
smaller versions of them less loud or
more loud for that um really depending
your situation um General General
Hydroponics they they make some simple
puns with like pre- Outlets Amazon has
several pumps that um they're really
affordable and and they come with
Outlets too and and not you know to be
honest they're not as bad they're just a
name really they're all PR remade in the
same place um but I I I personally use a
commercial one it's it's yay big and
it's very quiet has some rubber like
like feet so it kind of vibrations go
off the
floor um it runs 24 hours I've been
running it for several years now didn't
spend too much on it um again it's one
of those things I I was able to purchase
like um I think someone had it used
fall out on someone on Instagram or not
Instagram on offer up you know um
Growers fall out all the time and they
kind of give up on a hobby and I come up
on some of these products um here in
California we have shops that close down
on on on the regular and turn around and
have the sell their their materials and
and like uh you know parts and that's me
picking it up on the other end if I
could find it you know so you mentioned
8 in net pots is what you have within
the buckets you use rock wall and
hydroton surrounding it can you talk to
us about kind of using the Rockwell from
start to finish do you start Cuts in it
and then kind of have it in your
seedling area and then switch it over to
the bucket or how do you go about that
um I I believe Rockwell has gone a long
way especially with tech um there's a
brand grodan um they're they're kind of
big on on their products but they they
make different versions I mean everyone
makes rock wool but they actually use
their their plugs and their 4 in cubes
I've big used bigger ones for it to to
kind of experiment but it's not really
necessary unless you're going to do like
a drip to drain kind of like set up but
um I start with plugs um they're
see or you know small little cubes um
and these are I insert them into another
4in Cube as I go so my seedlings and my
uh my FR cut clones I I I drop them in
there and kind of uh
[Music]
nutrients what do you use for a nutrient
lineup currently um for actually last
couple years I've been using um
Athena uh they've been pretty
consistent not Rocky at all really from
from day one I i' I've been pretty uh
haven't really dropped the ball like
everything that I put in there it works
pretty to to its word um follow the
instructions the guidelines and and if I
really wanted to I've tried
experimenting like bumping up ratios see
if it kind of you know messes with the
plan or if they like it a little bit
more but I got to different ppms
between flower stages and they can go
pretty high um if you harden your plants
well enough they can take they can
they'll take a lot of salt um for that
same reason um like I I go by PPM I
really don't go by um EC I I I'm a
numbers guy so I like seeing the numbers
that break down pretty the detail and EC
is like two points and I can't really
break that down or vit themin to my
nutrients that I mixed into it most
recently but um I I love it you know if
anything I'm thinking of moving over to
their um their salt mix if I ever expand
my op and and you know need more liquid
for that same same part of it um but I
it come from other nutrients like
psycho um even like psycho is good it's
not it's now really to be honest a lot
of these nutrients aren't bad at all
none of them aren it's it's just really
their ratio and how they formulate um to
for these plants to work and you know
everybody knows these plants are
different so they're going to take up
these nutrients differently and then
that's up to the to the grower The
Gardener to kind of like fine-tune that
their ratios and and give the plant what
they like so you know a lot of these
companies are not mentioning like here
this is yours you do with it what you
will or and you figure it out but you
know they want to make it easy I mean
they have their charts and to to a to a
base it works but to make it better it's
it's really up to the grower um and that
goes with a lot of variables you know
conditions lighting and and exactly what
the plant may
prefer but I run Athena and hopefully I
can keep on doing it I've heard a lot of
good things about Athena a lot of people
seem to be jumping over to Athena and
using them just because of the results
that you see people getting out of them
and um I heard a lot of good things
about e of use they make it really easy
to use
now you mentioned PPM are you talking
500 scale or 700 scale and also are you
adjusting the PPM that you have that
you're giving to your plants throughout
the growth cycle so it gets higher as
you go from fegge to flour or how do you
go about that I go 500 um for the scale
if anything and um yeah by stage I I try
to pay pay attention to to what the plan
is like and how they react they're if
they're praying at the time of with with
enough heat um really it does fluctuate
from vegetation to to flowering um when
I find that within flowering you know
they're they're lacking a little bit I
kick down some things so so they can
pick up but if if they're really liking
it I do add I add and I add until until
I see a lacking um if if they start
showing some some bad signs I definitely
take away but um I haven't actually so
I've heard other girls go um you know
several thousand um in PPM like you know
3,000 PPM to to a point of like you know
you don't even imagine that for your
plants and how they can really uptake it
but if you have the right setup and your
and your roots are really clean if if
they're big enough and they're able to
uptake they will um and you know finding
that plant finding that mother that you
know is suitable for such conditions is
is the you know part of the journey
definitely between my growth Cycles I
try to up as much so they can take as
much nutrients um for that same reason
more or less towards the end I try to be
real more critical and kind of sensitive
to seedlings and even teens at some
points because they're not they're not
I'm not giving them the full love back
until they really s step into the
flowering
stage um especially with their lacking
root expansion okay and then are you
changing nutrient is it every week where
there's kind of like a new ratio that
you're kind of increasing week by week
and when you do that change are you
doing any type of like is cleaning of
the buckets or anything with any
cleaning solution or you just rinsing
them all with water and then putting in
the next week's nutrient mix in with
with my water at least I use purified
water like everyone should um
unfortunately I don't I have like a
purifying system um which I should
actually every Hydroponics person should
have a filtration system especially if
you're growing uh clean water is is
necessary especially if you're drinking
or consuming anything from it um my
water is uh between my buckets and and
more or less flushing between the Cycles
I definitely do that so going from
vegetation to clearly to to you know a
flowering or fooding stage all that
water is going out being dumped into my
outdoor grows and reused one way or the
other the the buckets are then like
rinsed out with that same water again
thrown into the the outside grow stuff
um I don't do full flushes um if that's
one of the questions I'm sorry um
towards the end um with with what
research I've learned I mean even Bruce
bugby was like I mean there's no results
after the fact you're kind of
deteriorating doing the even the the the
3 days after uh after um that flush um a
lot of those bro signs is kind of going
out the door and um initially when I
started growing I I try to like throw
that use do all the stuff that I can
imagine that you know would make my
plant um bigger or or more or go more
vigorously a lot of it wasn't consistent
enough for me to continue to keep on
doing it so really I'm just following
directions into what my nutrient line
ask for and um if it does requir that I
I flush uh it hasn't really but there
there definitely things to do so there
that there's definitely means to flush
aside from pulling out you know uh
excess nutrients from your plants um if
you're changing up from different Cycles
like I mentioned you definitely want to
have a clean a clean start and not have
anything behind that can mix into what
you're putting in
new um if you if I find that there's
something lacking within my my mix I'll
I'll get runoff test the runoff and see
how that how that is how it looks on my
uh my tester um opposed to how it's
running within the system um this may
kind of confuse a lot of people when
when they're testing water that's inside
the system because the AirStone kind of
makes pH levels fluctuate so you know
pull your water out test it test a
runoff
don't test don't test your stuff in
motion because a lot of it running
around is is going to mess with your
testers and it'll it'll kind of mess you
up on
paper um but yeah from the last question
I I raised up my my nutrient levels my
my PPN between Cycles with that being
said I I don't want to mess mess up my
numbers that I already put down and kind
of add to another one I I will top off
my levels with the same nutrients as
they're growing um and but I I don't mix
uh different nutrients to uh to fill it
up it's definitely fleshed out and we
start fresh when we go to new cycle got
it now you mentioned you use that
nutrient solution on your outdoor plants
now how do you get it from uh pretty
basic question here but what do you use
to get it from your grow tent that are
in the buckets on the floor of the grow
tent how do you get that out into your
yard using a a shopvac or using a sub
pump like how do you remove the water
from the buckets uh that I mean ENT
initially that was a big uh you know a
big question in my head to kind of
transfer a lot of liquid um I I've got
myself some some bigger like um
containers blue containers um to to fill
the liquid with but at the same time yes
I I do use a shop back a wet wet dry
back and I I pull out all the water and
then it's another another breakdown
between the system and having to pull it
out and rs out really quickly the
rinsing is is a good thing and I I I
really promote the the whole rinsing
part of it because you don't want any
clogs you don't want any leaks you want
to make sure that your system is still
consistent to to work the next cycle and
and and you know longer my drip system
it clogs a lot the the sedative the the
sediment from the the salt buildup um I
mean the only way to clear that stuff
the lines is is is another solution to
add to your to your um your wire which
you don't want to do you don't want to
add a a solution to clear your lines
that's going to also go into your plants
um I mean take it out and do it in
another another time and you know keep
it running as you can and as my plants
are suspended out out of the water while
I'm cleaning I mean they're they're
going to dry back and they're still wet
nothing happens to them they're still in
their
light but maintaining is a big deal
especially with you know anything
hydroponic any any system that you want
to run consistently like a car you want
to make sure that car has gas and oil
you want make sure your system is clean
and and and clear
salts um the buildup does happen and
everything is dirty you wash your dishes
for a reason you don't want to wash your
your your pots or your buckets from the
same things you're going to eat off that
makes sense so we talked about PPM but
we didn't talk about pH yet can you talk
about pH a little bit like what you
typically aim for on a week to we basis
I'm always trying to sit between a 6 and
1/2 and at seven um when it comes to my
my my hydro water flowing um I always
started a z um a zero like PPM when when
I have fresh water and it's always
tested and and mixed in before I drop it
all in there um I buffer my pH with a um
with athenus balance so so anything that
has a silica in it it kind of raise your
pH and you can work it out from there so
you're always adding your silic first um
and then building out from there and
then kind of fine tuning between where
you want to be at on on your pH and your
PPM um I mean I go pretty light with my
uh my ceilings and and anything in
vegetation um more I just want to keep
keep my my veg stuff like
consistent and and and expand on root
zones and then move it over so when it
comes to like my pH it does definitely
need to be consistent because um in my
my veg everything is um is pure rock
wool it's all like uh uh feed feed the
drain so they're sitting in trays so I
got to pay attention I see those guys
every day I want to make sure that
dryback is not too long and and are able
to like open up their roots and uh for
the same part like lighting isn't
building too much algae on anything so
maintaining maintaining that is is kind
of revolves around the pH because
something else goes bad it may fluctuate
the ph and then I have to flush that and
it's even more difficult when you're
working with rock you can't really flush
the rock uh unless you sit it over water
for times and and that's a big headache
you almost want to start over again and
just you know pull it out drop it in
another quebe but you know it it's
definitely not as easy as you think got
it now on the topic of DIY you also
created a DIY double trellis net can you
talk to us how you went about doing that
net yeah um that actually expanded from
one of my one of my first couple grows I
had a bigger 10 um it was a 5x5 instead
of my 2x4s I broke it down too I I kind
of saw saw um an example from like Mr
kanuck when I was watching his videos a
lot of he gets really really tall plants
um but they're always flopping
around um even if he has a single trist
and it they just flop around so I mean I
imagine like why not have a double chal
run one and then when it surpasses that
one run the second one I mean you're
always going to have stragglers at the
bottom that you're going to want to like
kind of move over to the corner or to a
point where you have lighting I know
nowadays there's a lot of like side
lights or stuff you can add to the
bottom of your tent to to add um add
some sun but not everyone has that same
thing so you got you want to train I'm
I'm big on training and it comes to like
um putting positioning your plants or or
even like kind of like bony them to a
point where they they they lay down lay
down on you you know my first grow I had
one plant that was you know filled the
whole 5x5 uh tent and I was running that
Tris where I can get them lay
sideways um toward the end of the the
other end of the plan and it grew out
big it was it was my first grow and I I
put like slightly little than 500 or and
I had I mean I still have a little bit
left over from years ago if anything but
uh the the t is definitely it's
definitely a big help um PVC piping it's
lightweight it's it's really like
flexible you can put it and you move
around as you please
um just be good with your measurements
uh you know materials aren't too costly
when it comes to things like that uh the
reason I built my own I mean not
stacking two on top of one another it's
another cost effective kind of thing I
mean if you notice how much these things
cost a line they're you're mostly paying
for the shipping I I for instance I I
love gorilla go tent and clearly they
they sell everything nowadays it's like
um AC Infinity they they're a kind of
One-Stop shop I I Gorilla Grow Tent is
here inia
I want I wanted to buy a $20 trellis net
and it was another like you know 25 or
$30 to ship it over to me I'm like can I
pick it up it's right here in Los
Angeles like unfortunately no we can't
so that was my turn around to go to Home
Depot was like another less five miles
and you know go build my own with some
string um or you can go go on Amazon
pick up the trellis net and and run over
some a frame of your own uh it's it's
pretty basic but I mean it goes without
was saying like you really just have to
put yourself forward and have to you
know want to make these things and not
have to wait for shipping or you know
paying someone else to make it for you
and I I kind of pushed that you know
across across the board we've seen a lot
of things I do whether it's growing or
fixing a car if I can't fix it if I
don't know 100% sure I'm not going to do
it but if I can I'm going to attempt but
you know without any loss for the most
part you can certainly save a bunch of
money doing a DIY and I think that's
more one of the reasons why a lot of
people go go for it you know not just
because they're good with their hands
but because it's going to save them
money as well so for these the PVC
double trellis what size PVC and then
when you're connecting them and they
have what's it called the elbow pieces
are you putting any is there any like
glue or any sealant or anything that
connects the two to make sure everything
locks in place or what it really depends
on you um if you wanted to have like a
permanent fixture yeah there there is a
PVC adhesive that specifically for for
PVC so the plastic can stick to one
another um and then they also have um
like threaded joints so you can get
where you can just you know screw them
in there and then reuse them again later
I I prefer more the threaded joints so
if you ever wanted to break down that
same uh trellis you can um and I did
that same thing um I had a big 5x5
trellis I I broke down and I I made a
3X3 trellis to fit a shower grow um and
I just moved it around I try to reuse as
much as I can and I mean I may not have
a 5x5 in but you know now I have another
opportunity to use it for my a small
3x3 um but yeah it it's it's uh for
putting it together it's really to your
spec so if you plan on reusing it don't
go the permanent route shoot for a
threaded so you can screw it in and
unscrew it if you find that you're it's
something going to be a staple within
that same 10 that's not going to change
go ahe and get an adhesive um it smells
at first but it's nontoxic it's not
going to bother your plants um um it's
it'll set it and you can forget it for
the most part good to know and then for
the actual thread that is run the ones
I've seen online with people doing it
they're basically just taking screws and
then putting it into the side of the PVC
at a certain spacing and then they're
using the the twine string and running
it up and down up and down to make
squares is that pretty much how you do
it or like what's your method of of that
part I want to say my my mark one my my
first prototype I definitely did the
whole eyelid screws into the into the
PVC it definitely is um more tedious of
work you also have to make sure your
measurements are on point with how how
big you want the squares so when I my
double trellis I I did like a a 4in
square to a 6in square so it can kind of
like open up between you know how L
expands um with the eyelid screws that
you're going to put in there you're
you're kind of GNA have to play
Spider-Man and go and the end and if you
know one line kind of is loosened then
you're going to have like a floppy area
for that same reason um I found that
getting the the nylon ones on Amazon are
just as good and you're going to find
that zip tis are going to be your best
friend and that goes across the board
too between your whole grow zip ties are
are are a savior get that zip tie and
just ratchet it on there um between the
the right the right net and you can
modify the net as big it is and cut it
it's no big deal those things are like
seven bucks on Amazon um people also use
like you know wood they for their
framing like 2x4s I mean they have to
scre it more properly it's not
lightweight but I like hanging my my
trus from from the top of my 10 so I can
kind of like adjust it as I please that
makes sense yeah it sounds like it's a
lot easier to just buy the the nylon net
and then zip tie it to the PVC piping
save a bunch of time there I'm sure yeah
and headaches yeah so for all these DIY
projects whether it be the hydroponic
setup you have or the DIY double trellis
what are some of the problems that
you've come across and how did you
resolve them you've already kind of come
talked a little bit about the water leak
and and clogged pipes not sure if you
can expand on that at all or if there's
anything else that comes to mind and to
be honest those are kind of the biggest
nightmares the the leaks and not being
around when the leak happens um I mean
there are several things that could
happen between a hydro product setup
because um you get to a point where you
want a lot of things to be automated so
if if you want to set in forget it walk
out of the room and make sure
everything's still running it's you want
to make sure everything's confirmed
working um to walk out of the room and
then get a power outage and now all of a
sudden you know half your pumps aren't
going your your your roofs are sitting
in water uh for this amount of time and
it it's so idle and it just built a
bacteria that you don't one um I mean
that that's that's a crucial you know
hold down for you when you come back to
a room that's not on anymore and you
have to run a breaker in the back to
turn it back on some people aren't Keen
to those things they're like then
they're freaking out like they're
calling all their friends and like sh my
power is off how you turn it back on um
I mean there's there's several things um
Power running out a weather conditions
California is pretty pretty upset and
weather it kind of changes every day I'm
look at have the Sun out today but like
the last few days it was just raining um
we're in
February um uh I could say that anything
that kind of affects the household or
the room kind of affects the environment
on the
inside um with things turning off on you
or things not working when you're away
from it I mean for that same reason
that's why I have cameras within my
tents I keep an eye on
them 24/7 it's almost like I wish I had
a camera on my kid for that same reason
put cam on top of her head so I know
what she's doing this whole time I
wouldn't have to worry so much but the
these are other kids that can't fend for
themselves and and and get sick if
something touches them wrong so um it's
definitely a hobby and put yourself in
the position to be more caring or more
observant to things that that you want
to you know love and pay attention to
especially you get to you know you get
to have your cake and eat it too at the
end um and it goes across the board with
opland
who who doesn't like an apple from their
own
tree uh you see here but you know with
these uh these ideas of things walking
into the problems the the things that
you want to you know most worry about
things are things that are out of your
heads if you have things running out
automatically then you can have like you
know a slight you know slight weight
lifted off your shoulder because you
know it's working the cameras help a lot
because I can pay attention from from a
distance
um especially if I can hear things
running like okay that's a good sign but
all of a sudden as I get a notification
that my camera is off or it's not
working either somebody's robbing me or
or or my stuff all turned off and I'm
going to come back to a quiet room and
then you I'll have to figure it out and
and when you're away it's probably
because you're out like doing something
or you know it's at night so when you
come home it's like it's at the end of
the day and you have to deal with a
whole bunch of stuff so that that's kind
of the the nightmare you don't want to
walk into or expect when when having an
automated system you know that's
supposed to work on its own but uh you
can you can keep away from all that
stuff by foreseeing it imagine it before
you're doing your build like uh I'm
definitely going to not going to have
any leaks ever because I I triple double
check my my my water sources and and
make sure that it flows in the right
places I put high pressure on it on on
the tubes with a hose to make sure sure
nothing comes out um the triple
double-checking your stuff will
definitely keep you out of the realm of
having to worry about it but always that
thing in the back of your head like it's
going to
happen no one is is uh come uh safe from
you know mishaps it's it's like the law
of
life we're I mean even if you're running
through soil there's there's always
something that that could you know
surprise you through pest or or you know
lacking
management weather conditions things
that not you're not sure that can expect
when you come back from you know
whatever you're doing but
personally I maybe have like a water
phobia but of it being everywhere um
just the fact that there's a lot of
electronics around it it's it's like
playing with fire eventually I can see
how that could be scary for some people
for sure but the camera thing that you
mentioned is pretty good idea of you
know listening to the camera to see your
equipment still kind of sounds like it's
still on you know I don't have cameras
in my grow yet I'm looking to actually
put cameras in my grow what cam what
brand do you use actually um I I use
these blink Cabas um they're not too
expensive I'm pretty sure you can find
like 25 bucks a pop and then you can get
some mounts um from Amazon where you can
kind of angle them as you please and
within my two 2x4s I I have them pointed
down and I have a full coverage where I
can kind of Zoom in and out has two-way
sound so you can hear the sound coming
back out and you can imagine if there
was somebody else in your room you can
talk to them and they can talk back as
well um it's it's great on surveillance
I mean to be honest when I first
purchased my house surveillance was a
big deal so I covered my house and like
ring cams and I found these bling
cameras on the way over I'm like hey
these are inexpensive pop them to my
tents and you know I can watch
everything I mean eyes on eyes on me
vice versa that's awesome yeah going
have to get cameras going in my tent
soon well we talked about quite a bit
here in this talk today in regards to
DIY and hydroponics let's wrap things up
tell the listeners how they can find you
and is there anything upcoming in the
future that you have going on that you
want to talk about you can always kind
of catch me on um Instagram or or even
YouTube I go by highly motivated highly
motivated hydronics um Mr Nice Guy if
anything uh YouTube and Instagram uh if
anything my I have girls coming up
trying to find a new mother to uh move
over into the next tent um you know this
this Hunt is always the biggest thing
between any kind of like a gardener
between whatever Cult of art but trying
to find the best uh best one and and
keep them moving is is kind of the idea
right now not much Tech update to be
honest I'm I'm kind of uh I'm kind of
settled where I'm at but if anything you
comes out I'm definitely going to be on
top of it um for the most part I I like
a lot of the the brands that I'm using
AC Infiniti Cavita I mean they're
they're pretty great and
consistent can't say they're there's
there anything to matter with them but
you know watch out for my my videos and
my posts and see some updates and where
I'm going out with it and hopefully it
expands and kind of enjoy the videos or
the content you know awesome I'll
definitely have a link to Mr Nice Guys
Channel down in the YouTube description
section below so you guys can easily
navigate to that and if you're listening
on one of the podcast platforms just
search from highly motivated Hydro his
channel should pop right up and then
you'll be able to tune into his content
Mr ni Sky thanks so much for coming on
today and talking about Hydroponics and
DIY I definitely learned a few things
myself I'm just getting into dwc so uh
there's definitely some things here in
this talk that I'm going takeaways for
me and I might actually hit you up with
some additional questions behind the
scenes if if I have any so thanks so
much and hope you enjoy the rest of your
day no thank you man I'm glad to be here
Hing I'll talk to you back then thanks a
lot man peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode