are you using some synthetic line of
nutrients and what's the EC or PPM that
you aim for for the different stages of
growth oh yeah I'm running uh all
salt-based nutrients right now recently
I've been running um Athena and I've
been liking it a lot it's my first run
with Athena and I've also recently been
running autof flowers which I'm not used
to so usually I might be and a lot of
times I'm just testing this in like a
PPM so a lot of times in veg I might be
getting up to 700 or 800 ppms in the
peak of veg and then maybe even over a
th000 ppms in the peak of flow but I
found that these autof flowers have been
running it's just a few but they seem to
like a lot or need a lot less nutrients
so I've been running about half of that
strength with the autof flowers I've
pretty much been taking the feeding
chart that Athena recommends and just
cutting it straight in half and it's
been working really well yeah that's a
common question that people ask is about
autof flowers and their feeding it's
often here that there it requires less
nutrition and there's some people that
say no it requires the same amount so I
think that's one of like the debated
topics amongst the community is whether
or not Autos should be treating
differently when it comes to feedings so
it's interesting to hear that your
experience that yeah you've had to cut
the dose in half there I heard the same
thing and so I tried I went with the
full
strength and I could just you could see
the normal signs it it just wasn't happy
you could see the leaf tip burn
starting and then I just backed off I
was like I let it go for maybe a whole
week before I was like I got to change
this Reservoir it's just too much cuz it
felt like too much because I think what
it was recommending even early in vegge
was 1100 PPM and it said that this
formulation is made to run at a higher
EC and I was like all right let's let's
try it never tried these nutrients
before I'll go with what they recommend
and I think it was just this particular
cultivar because the whole plant I mean
finished is only this big and so it
makes sense that it doesn't need that
much salt true yeah I know some aut
flowers can grow massive and then some
just stay squat really comes down to
genetics obviously it comes down to
other things lighting environment
nutrition all that stuff but yeah some
could be real small so it makes sense
for those smaller plants to need lesser
nutrition right yeah it does to me now
mixing up those nutrients in water what
is your water source are you just using
tap water or are you filtering the water
in some way like reverse osmosis or
what's your water source I have a uh 75
gallon per day Ro filter in the house
it's just hooked up underneath my
kitchen sink and it's off 90% of the
time but I know like every time I'm
about to have to say I have to fill my
reservoir tomorrow I'm going to change
it I'll go ahead and turn on the filter
tonight fill me up a few five gallon
buckets and get ready so I always have
uh the RO water at the house I don't
have to worry about going and trying to
get distilled water worrying about
what's in my water supply because I know
just a few years ago here in Denver go
to the full episode by clicking the
outro card here or click the link in the
description section below catch in next
video