what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. Griffith and
I just mixed up a batch of nutrients
here this is Blue Planet nutrient - Blue
Max two-part feed schedule so I have it
all mixed up stir it up and checking the
pH at the moment and the pH was at 5.8
that's willing I actually like about
Blue Planet nutrients as the ph ends up
being 5.8 with that if it's a half dose
which is the ph level I like to give my
plants growing in Cocoa but I am growing
in soil this round so I do have to
increase the pH using pH up alright now
I got up to 6.2 and I decided to film
this video so we're gonna get it up a
little bit more than that the pH I'm
using is by blue playing nutrients their
pH up I also have a small cup some RO
water here this is a jug that washed out
it needs to be melted and I have one of
these what are these called again so
what you're not supposed to do is you're
not supposed to take this P up pH up and
put it directly into there I'm going to
show you I'm gonna do it here for
example purposes I want to show you what
happens
see that gray cloud a little bit more
hopefully the camera can pick it up it's
a great cloud swirling around there um
so it's actually a chemical reaction
happening I actually learned this from
Everest Fernandes he has a YouTube
channel oh I'm gonna actually link the
video below where I learned this from
basically this chemical erection is bad
this is not useful for plants if you
want that full description on why that's
the case I will link his video in the
description section below but instead of
doing that what you are supposed to do
is actually dilute it first a lot of
people aren't doing this I noticed so I
figured I'd make a quick video on how to
dilute it so really just all you need is
a small cup of water you know this is
the size that I use which is fine
pour a decent amount up because you
really want to when you're diluting it
you don't want to have like a too small
of a glass like a small shot glass isn't
really gonna be enough to dilute it down
put a little bit more in there and I
kind of just kind of guesstimate on how
much I'm going to need it's really
adjusts depending on how much you're
trying to bring your pH up or down what
are you supposed to dilute it here like
I'm doing here and then from there well
actually let me get rid of this other
cloud first mix that end what did this
go up to so that went from six point to
up to six point four and now let's say
if this small container that just mixed
up is going to increase it up to about
six point five is fine if it goes up a
little bit more than that I'm okay with
that but you don't see the gray cloud oh
crap I stirred it before to show you
there was no great cloud because it was
diluted and now I am up to about six
point four six point five we'll see if
that goes up any more but it got me up
to where I need to be but more of the
story just want to make a quick video
today urge you guys to dilute your pH up
pH down before mixing it with your
nutrient solution because the chemical
reaction happens and that is about it's
pretty much it for this video guys if
you enjoyed it please click that thumbs
up and that will leave it that thank you
so much for watching and until next time
space
[Music]
you