coming up on garden talk when they get
switched to flower the day of flower
no matter when they got switched no
matter how long ago they got vegetative
nutrients i give them two tablespoons
per gallon of 484 period nematodes work
really well too
but you have to be uh diligent with them
as well
and keep dosing them because they still
come back and functions that's
their fungus knives come back so easily
i get very equal results from topping
the low search training
the difference is is that low stress is
less stressful and i've noticed that
even topping the plant can't stress it
out and it can be droopy
otherwise all these videos this dude
told me it was the best way like
everybody say that way is the best way
too
the only way you gonna know is just to
go ahead and do it and
figure out what's comfortable for
yourself
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 19.
in this episode i talk with mr good buds
he is a fellow youtuber with over 19 000
subscribers on his channel
and his videos have over 1.3 million
views combined
he does like to keep it simple in the
garden and in this video we'll learn
about
his style of gardening and some of the
easy gardening techniques that he does
if you're listening to this podcast on
apple podcasts please leave a rating or
review
if you're on youtube that thumbs up
button helps out a bunch
and also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already and of course feel free
to share this podcast with others
and if you want to support this podcast
even more you can do that through
patreon
the link is patreon.com mr growit and
i'll provide a link down in the youtube
description section below before we get
to the episode i'd like to give a shout
out to our sponsor
dutch pro nutrients as i mentioned in a
previous episode
dutch pro is now a long-term sponsor of
the podcast and they sent me over their
nutrients to try out
i'll be using their base nutrients
additives and ph regulators
they are a plant fertilizer company that
was established in amsterdam 30 years
ago
and the nutrients are available in
several countries across the world
i'll leave a link to their amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use coupon code
mrgrowit10dp for a discount on their
products
all right now let's get into the episode
okay
we are back garden talk podcast and we
are here with mr good
buds welcome to the podcast how you
doing today i'm good man what's going on
mr gross
good good i'm glad thanks for joining me
today you know i i think
the audience ought to know how long
we've been trying to do this
i was gonna say when we when we finally
did it i was you could go ahead and talk
about it because this it's been a long
road trying to get
trying to go from doing what i normally
do to doing this type of uh
this type of content so i had to get my
stuff together so
yeah it took us a minute yeah i had like
four or five people request you
and i've been telling people i'm like
we're trying to get it done we're trying
to get it done so finally we get to sit
down get it done
and uh we'll get it out there for the
people that uh that want it so
cool that's cool i'm cool to hear that
people request me on your platform
because you gotta you've been out doing
it a lot longer than me so that makes me
feel real good so
so i'll make sure i'm everything is up
to par i'm looking good on you
on your platform too well you have a
real large following right you got like
almost
you're about to have 20 000 people
following you on youtube which is huge
so you know there's got to be some
people in my audience that don't know
who you are
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself kind of how you got into
gardening
getting into gardening was a long
journey for me i i started wanting to
grow
probably about eight years before i
actually started
and during that time i was living in a
house where the basement was all screwed
up i live in in detroit
in my old house a lot of detroit has had
problems with flooding basements and
stuff so
i tried to start then and i literally
built an entire growth
like out of out of two by fours and uh
black plastic and stuff
then the basement flooded destroyed all
of it had plants
it destroyed the plants and it was all
bad
and that was my first attempt and so
from that point on
i literally was so obsessed with growing
that i
researched it nonstop for like five
years straight after that
until i finally moved into the house i
was in
and i kind of forgot about it it's funny
because i once i moved i forgot
and it was one day i was over my boy
house and i still had these same sheets
the same packaging so ak-47 seeds the
first seeds i grew
on my first grow my first season i had
those seeds literally eight years i had
those seeds for eight
almost five years oh no i had them for
like six years i had them for five years
and then i stopped so when i moved
i forgot about it so i went over my boy
house who had been grown and uh and it
was about the time to start growing
right when
my first ak-47 season had started my
first
youtube season and uh he asked me he was
like uh how come you ain't
started trying to grow yet it's the time
it's like it's that season nah
and i was like you know what i do still
got those seeds and so i'm like i'm
gonna go ahead and i'm gonna go ahead
and drop him
and he had he was growing outside so i
tried to grow outside that time that
particular time
and if you uh watch my whole season you
can actually follow everything i'm
saying because i started it outside
and uh and then i got like a super crazy
rain and it just like i came home one
day and
all the plants was tilted over and it
was all laying down and
the dirt was falling out the cups and
stuff so i moved it all inside
and i just started going from there and
then one day my the he
the same guy told me he was like how
come you don't record
everything and then make videos for
youtube for it because i've been doing
it
and i'm like i've been recording it for
myself and i'm like you know what i
should do that
literally in my first video i took every
clip i recorded
not making it for youtube but i just
took the clips i recorded for myself and
made my first video out of it
and i just been doing it ever since then
so it's been a pretty cool journey since
then
that's awesome that's really cool so you
just had that one outdoor season or
one outdoor period and then you brought
indoors and you've been indoor is
everything yes sir
yeah it was like a week outside and then
i didn't make it i'm trying to do
outdoor grow right now
but yeah i was like a week outside it
scared me too much and i just brought it
inside and
got a tent started from there gotcha are
you mostly growing
autoflowers or photo periods or what
um at first i was growing both it took
me a while to figure out what i really
liked the most
and at this point i could say for sure
that i like i prefer photo periods
but i do grow autoflowers and i had a
lot of recommendations for autoflowers
that people
like and i've had i've grown a lot of
great autoflowers too
so i do i do like them both but for me
personally in the amount of space that i
have
i prefer doing photo periods so i've
been sticking to that mostly
um but if i had more more space i would
grow everything i like
the photo periods i want to get into
breeding and stuff too and
i want to start making some feminized
seeds so yeah
nice nice yeah i know that um you know
i've seen some of your your indoor grows
on youtube and one thing i know what you
really like to do is you like to keep
things simple you like to make things
easy uh you have kind of a more
laid-back hands-off approach that's
really what i want to get into
here in this podcast is ways to make
things easy
simple techniques that you do so on and
so forth so we're going to get into the
questions that
i sent you several weeks ago
we first tried to plan this out and
we'll go through your gross style and
we'll talk about some of the things you
do so for indoors
what size growth space are you in oh so
i have three tents i work in a two four
by fours and a three by three
um i like the i like the 4x4 the most
um for my photo period plants it's
perfect for what i like to do
i like to keep four or seven gallon pots
flowering
like towards the end one of my 10's is
just the veg 10 which is well i don't
know if you can see this is the
flower temple right next to it is the
vegetation and so i various plants out
in there and then flipping the flower
right away
and i've been doing that with my other
tent too but my other tent was mainly
the autoflower tent
mostly but um yep 4x4
mainly is my favorite space so far but
again i'm in a very tight space as well
so
i like to get in bigger bigger spaces i
hear you i'm similar to you i've got
a small area to work with myself i've
just got right now i just got one four
by four and one two by four
so i'm actually running smaller than
what you got there
um no what are you using for for
lighting for the three tenths
oh so i got all mars harder lighting i
got a um
right now i got in the three by three i
have an fc 4800
uh i don't run it at full power i rented
about i ran at about 400 watts
during the peak of flower um it's pretty
it's pretty uh
it's built for a 4x4 but i like to go by
i got this i got this from mr canucks
too that you that you go off for 35
watts per uh
per square foot and i've had great
success with it since i started so i've
been sticking with that ever since i
started
so i go strictly off of that and in the
other 4x4 i have a ts3000
uh man i like to have like around 600
watts per
uh 600 watts uh true watch from the wall
in there
uh and then i also have a uh the other
4x4 i have two sp
3000s currently right now and they're
all running at 300 watts
so 600 watts so i like to keep them
around the same thing at 35 watts per
square foot
the science behind it i'm not completely
sure about but i've had
wonderful success with it and i've done
less than that and i've had i've had
less success so i'm thinking that's the
sweet spot for
what we're trying to go for here i've
had my hands on the
sp 3000 two of them in a fallback before
i did a part test on it and it looks
like it rocks
so um yeah that's cool to see
you running that because when i was
doing the part test i'm like man
who's running two of those it's gonna be
working real good for them so
that's cool to see i had my hands on the
ts 3002
i thought that was pretty good and then
the fc 4800 that's one of the newer ones
right that they released
is that the bar style one how do you
like that the fc 4800
is awesome actually with the with the
bar
the bar style lights that it has i had
really good light penetration and the
first time i used it
was with some very small clones that
turned out
really really great um the buzz
the i grew og kush a lot of times
already and the one time i grew it
was starting with very small clone
underneath the 4800
i had a really nice size buzz really
dense buzz and
it was really good so i'm thinking i'm i
actually really like that that i like
like that like um for that first run
so i'm going to be using it i'm going to
stick with it for a while i have the uh
the detachable ones too uh so i'm
actually gonna be putting the 6500 in
the other 4x4
i'm liking the i'm liking the bar style
lights i'm thinking that that allows a
greater penetration so i'm going to
experiment more with it to see how the
results we get from
yeah it definitely helps with like the
light spread across the footprint right
having that even light spread that's one
thing i personally like about those
bar style lights i like with the bar
style light six when you can dim them um
you know when you're not running co2 you
don't need to have these things at full
power right unless you're frying with
plants
are you running co2 or now no i don't i
actually have
i'm sorry about that i actually have a
million kids so
that's one of my things about trying to
keep everything simple because they
keep me really busy and my i got a wife
and like they keep me really busy you
know there's a lot of stuff that goes on
so
like i live in a world where i want to
grow but i'm going to make mistakes
and so like i try to like i try to keep
things as simple as possible so that i
can maintain and get a
get good results while still being
distracted by
everything else in the world and because
of that i don't use co2 because i have
so many people in the house
that there's plenty of carbon dioxide
flowing around here so
the kid is always up here this is
and then i got millions of nephews and i
got cats and
so i got plenty of carbon dioxide in the
house i actually don't supplement it
um i tried it once and i didn't notice
anything different
and i'm thinking now it's because i'm
already i already got a decent amount of
co2
in the house already yeah that's a good
point uh if you have people living in
the same house we're growing in i mean
that is gonna be enough co2 for the
plant
uh but i assume you do some sort of like
um like air exchange
in the tent do you have like inline fans
that you're kind of exhausting out of
there how
is that set up yeah that's all i have is
just the exhaust fan
uh i run an exhaust fan in each tent um
i haven't been uh
i don't use the carbon filters i don't
have to worry about the smell as much
actually i just realized that i probably
should because the
dry nutrients smell really bad when you
water so i just realized
recently that i should use carbon
filters but i only got three uh exhaust
fan each one i don't have any intake
fans i allow
my vents to stay open and i leave like a
vent or two on the side the bigger tents
i leave
two vents open and then my three by
three i just leave one open
and i take care of the intake of the air
and the exhaust says the air has to be
replaced as the
air is being exhausted out of the tent
so it works pretty good
and i exhausted air right into my room
i've been doing that ever since i know a
lot of people like to
like to exhaust it out of the room
completely
uh i wasn't able to do that in the
situation that i'm in
uh because my room is in the attic and
it's a weird room um so i just exhaust
everything right into the room and i
haven't had no problems with it so
that's all i do one exhaust fan then one
uh
air to circulate the air inside the tent
and that's it
must smell amazing in there oh man
when the plants are flowering this
is wonderful i love to leave the house
and then come home
and they'd be like oh my god oh i smell
the water
they get used to it right here all day
right right
yeah i actually don't i haven't been
running carbon filters either
and that's a good thing to bring up
right is that's an optional piece of
equipment if you don't need to smell you
don't need that
piece of equipment so yeah another way
to kind of keep it simple if you don't
need that smell don't even buy the
equipment exactly
there you know exactly but yeah i think
my neighbor is probably
can smell it like late flowering you
know how it is like even when you're
like drying
like it they can even smell it you know
it's dry and be something different too
that's when they transform and they get
a lot more a lot a lot a little
danger i've had so many like fedex
drivers and ups drivers like
just like smells good in there
that's funny let's uh let's continue to
talk about environment a little bit
temperature
what do you usually aim for when it
comes to attempts
um so this is a this is another thing
when it comes to keeping everything
simple
uh ideally ideally like when i get into
a facility i would like to keep
everything
i would like to have different temps and
ranges for
vegetative and flower plants
um but being all in one room and not
being able to do that
and having to have everything up here to
keep it safe for my family
everything pretty much runs at the same
temperature and the same humidity all
the time so
the only thing i can control and i can
keep a difference in is the
drying tent which i like to keep is 65
rh but inside the room i'm pretty much
at the mercy of whatever the season is
so
if it's winter time outside then the
humidity in here is nothing
like there is no humidity in the air in
here because it gets
extremely dry in the winter time and uh
and there's no way i can it's i've tried
i've tried
um i've tried raising the humidity in my
veg tents and stuff and
it just it's just impossible in this
room in this room this room is
horribly insulated and it's just it's
just a
pain and then vice versa in the
summertime the humidity is super high so
it's kind of different in the summer
because the air conditioner helps lower
the humidity so i keep the humidity
around 40 50 ish
and that's about as low as i can get it
but it doesn't bother the plants and
flower
and i've had really any problem um
at first at first my best
plans that were used because i did use
the runner i had a humidifier that i ran
into veg 10 for a while
but i was literally refilling it every
few hours which drove me crazy and i
just was like you know what
i'm like y'all just not gonna have no
humidity because i can't do this
i can't keep up with it and they ended
up they had during that growth of that
particular growth they adjusted to it
which i learned and the plants will
adjust
and they'll go for they'll do fine even
my clones
i don't have a dome over my clones
either and they don't have a problem
with that either so
they're pretty uh relentless relentless
guys there so they
they they adjust and i pre ended oh i
didn't answer the temperature
the temperature i do have great control
over
i always keep the temperature around 75
in the room period
with the air conditioning during the
summer and the winter i'm
able to keep it around 75 70 i had a few
times that has gotten super
super high being in the attic um it is a
fight to keep it there that's why i
asked the lowest i could ever get it
but yeah humidity though either
i can't control humidity at all you
bring up a great point is
you don't really have to have the
optimal humidity right that
that is widely said online is
you need to be in this range for veg
this range for flowers so on and so
forth
you can get away with lower than that
you can get a little higher than that
right
it's not going to be growth but the
plant will still grow the planter is
resilient like you said so
if you are trying to keep it simple if
you're on a budget or whatever you can
probably get away with not
having some of this equipment and not
regulating humidity and stuff like that
so now people could probably argue about
the overall final
quality of the product i mean i think
that's a fair use on that but
you can still the plant will still grow
still usable
it's not going to be detrimental to you
grow until you have nothing
to harvest you know man i think with
people i think
people get hung up on a lot and which is
something for me
starting off is getting into learning
about growing
everybody makes it like an extremely big
deal like
like everything has to be perfect um
this has to be there this has to be that
way
if you're not doing this then your stuff
is trash and a lot of people get
discouraged by that
but we we we growing we're running for
ourselves
and like that's why i tell myself and
like like when i when i was done
i was happy with like even though i
wasn't the greatest like my first time
when i got done with my first growth
like it wasn't the greatest i ever had
but i was happy
and it was satisfying to me and that's
why i did realize like man i
just like it may not be the best of the
best but i'm not trying to like
sell this stuff like i'm just trying to
appease my
own my own pastimes and and
and i think that i think that people
need to think about what's good for them
and and and just do it and see
how you like it like don't get hung up
on it being the best ever or you know
it's just somebody tell you like this
but
that's not the biggest or it doesn't
smell like just do it and see how you
like it for yourself man you're gonna be
satisfied
for yourself and you're gonna you're
gonna go you're gonna
do as much or work as hard as you need
to work so that you can get what you
want
well i think that's really important
that people remember that they're doing
it for themselves
absolutely for sure i mean you even had
a
grow i saw on your youtube channel where
10th went up to 106.
and uh that would you still got a final
product out of it right you want to talk
a little bit about that
i did that that was amazing too and i
was that was another thing that showed
me like
just listening for everybody else when
things like that happen i started
panicking
i panicked like i came home i opened the
door let me tell you how hot it was i
opened the door to my room
and it was like a sauna like and like i
italy started sweating i'm like
what the heck like and not only that
the aroma from the room was so strong it
was like it cooked them like
it was like they got cooked in the heat
and i literally panicked like i lost my
mind and
i went through here opened the window
fan and
i opened the tents all the way all took
them all the bars and
left them open all night and like the
plants was all
droopy and they were hurt from it but
and i panicked and i i really thought
that that
that harvest was gonna be for nothing
man it wasn't
it was wonderful like you would have
never knew you never knew that that
happened to it
that's awesome that's funny good
recovery i'm glad you were able to to
get stuff out of that that's it yeah
that's good
that's one of my scariest scariest uh
time since i've been doing it
let's switch it up let's talk about what
medium you grow in so
are you in soil coco i know you don't do
like dwc or anything like that i use
roots organic soil
which is which is mostly cocoa and peat
moss so it's not actually soil
peat moss parsley soil but it's mostly
cocoa and pima
and perlite it's a lot of perlite too
but it's been
i use it i use it once and i had great
results with it and the plants
all love it and so i've been using it
ever since
i don't really know much about dirt
either so
i recently went to the store was was uh
there was a lot of guys walking down
with bells of um
pro mix and i was asking the guy about
the pro mix and
he confused the crap out of me like
that'd be the kid like if you complicate
stuff so much i was like
he said like you got to do this and then
mix this down and then put some of this
in and i'm like oh my god oh like never
mind
like i just i just gotta get through
this again because
i'm not about to do that
is basically making his own amendments
which i know a lot of people do but it
was just like
i just bought uh i'll just get the rules
organized i didn't even know
i thought y'all were just growing in the
pro mix
are you uh does the roots organic i've
heard of it i'm not i haven't grown it
before does it have nutrients already in
it
yes yeah it's real uh real heavy and
vegetative nutrients
and it's not it's not too bad too that
it'll burn the plants because when
sometimes when i
go right in the flour and i use that
i'll mix flour nutrients directly in it
and it has no issues with that either so
this is
it's like the perfect mix and i've had i
have used uh
fox farm soil the very very first time i
tried to grow
and it actually was burning my plants my
uh all of the plants all my uh
all my seedlings they all they all came
all kind of burnt
they were fine they were still growing
but they came out looking kind of weird
and
i didn't know why then but now i'm
thinking it was because the soil was too
hot
oh interesting yeah interesting yeah i
primarily use the fox farm soil i think
out of the you know sometimes you know
you leave the soil up
yeah yeah yeah that could be more
breakdown and stuff like that but uh
yeah i've had i've had a few problems
but very very few problems very rare
to have problems with the fox that's
just maybe i have heard of people not
having
good experiences with that soil but no
the fact that the roots organic has
nutrients in it so you're probably not
doing any sort of feeding for
what the first 30 40 days depending on
how much you're transplanting and stuff
or
yeah that's pretty good keeps it kind of
easy huh so do you start off in like a
small container and then work your way
up to that seven gallon that you spoke
about
yeah exactly so especially with the
photos i i
always start off in like a solo cup
coming from out the cloner
going to a solo cup and they literally
stay in the solar car forever
like i got plants that'd be like three
feet tall and it's low
like and i literally put nutrients in
the solo cup and just put it right on
top of this water
because i'd be so busy but yeah i put in
the solo cup and uh
i try to keep it i try to uh go into one
gallon
i like to go in between a one gallon
before i go into the seven
so i go from like the solo to one gallon
uh after it just
looks like it's dying off then i keep it
in one gallon to death
like you said i just i just really meant
every 30 days but if i'm not
if i'm not flipping the flower or
anything like that i'll just i'll remain
with some dry nutrients but every 30
days
with the with the soil um they i don't
i'm not feeding at all
just i try to keep the water around 6.5
to 6.8
uh and i just plant ph water the first
30 days
after that 30 days if they're going into
flower or they're going into another pot
if they're getting transplanted they
don't get fed so that's what i love too
that's why i try to
try to keep everything around those same
time periods too so
like if it's around that time ready to
transplant then i'll
i'll wait it all the way out and then
when i transplant they can go another
they can go another 30 days and
and then i try and keep it right around
so if i had to go in the flower which i
still have the
i said i'd defeat them but if they're
going to flower i still try to keep it
right at that 30 day limit so i know
that they ate all those vegetative
nutrients
and they was ready for new nutrients and
stuff like that i really ever only have
to feed
mostly flour nutrients i barely ever use
my
my vegetative dry nutrients so which
nutrients are you using
i use down to earth dry nutrients so i
only use a few of
the four four four the four
eight rosen flower that's why i use the
flower
i use boneville as a halfway through
flower boost um it has 3 and 15
phosphorus and zero potassium
and then i use i use their dolomite lime
every once in a while too so just those
just those four
so you're fully organic then right yes
now that's something i'm really big on i
don't i i don't agree with chemicals
um and mainly because my hair too
like and like the things i do with my
body i a lot of things i do in my body i
don't use any type of chemicals in my
hair
i don't eat chemicals i don't use things
with petroleum
uh things like that so i i carry that
over into
it to growing the plants as well i i
like to stay away from chemicals
and just try and keep it completely
organic things that you can get from the
ground
because i believe i like i'm a real
heavy on
i'm gonna also have you in like
apocalyptic situations too
and i know i want to still be able to do
this like i have to like have their
apocalypses so you want to be able to
i like to look up a lot of ways to like
get natural nitrogen natural phosphorus
and potassium and stuff like that
and just keep everything organic gotcha
i know a lot of people
down to earth is very very popular and
actually not a lot of people that are
kind of looking
for instructions on how to use it they
don't give very good clear instructions
on how to use it can you just
mention one a little bit more like how
you apply that
down to it when you apply it so yeah
like i said with the dirt
every 30 days now if i do need to
if they're going to get the vegetative
nutrients then i'll do two tablespoons
per gallon
of the vegetable nutrients per gallon
pot that they're in so if they're in the
5 gallon pot then they'll get 10
tablespoons
mean they had to be every 30 days if
they're going to stay in that pot
uh when they get flip when they get
switched to flour the day of flour no
matter
when they got switched no matter how
long ago they got vegetative nutrients i
give them two tablespoons
per gallon of 484 period
and and then halfway through flower like
maybe late week for
early week five i'll give them
75 484 and then i'll give them 25
bone meal and so basically they're still
getting the two tablespoons per gallon
no matter what
but i'll add that up and then i'll break
it down 75 percent
of the 484 and then 25 bone meal so like
if it was a five gallon pot
and i was doing two tablespoons per
gallon they would get seven and a half
uh tablespoons of the 484 and then they
would get two and a half tablespoons
of the bone meal so they still got the
exact same well
i just like to give him a little boost
at the end of the second half of the
flower period
that makes sense and i know you also do
microbes too right you inoculate with
microbes yeah you're using a recharge
yes anything other than recharge or just
recharge and what's your what how do you
apply the recharge
i started off using ruth's organic
organism xl
and then i started to recharge the only
reason i they both exactly the same for
me
they both recharged didn't do any better
than organism exhale
the only difference was that was very
important is that that organism exhale
clumps and it gets really hard
and it like turns into like these like
rocks
and then it's like basically it takes
you half the time trying to break it
down so that you can feed it to the
plant
and the recharge doesn't do that it
stays in that powdery farm the whole
time
but the the microbes are extremely
important i found that
having having a good micro micro uh
life in the soil however you put it
microbiology
living with the soil living with those
microbes in it is very important for
breaking down the
the um organic having the organic
nutrients that i use
it works hand in hand with the dry
nutrients though
that those are that's that's my uh
that's the only thing i do those dry
nutrients and
the recharge micros once a week a pa is
water
and that's it nothing that's probably
more than enough
yeah not too bad and talking about
microbes it's
you know we're talking about making
things easy maybe saving some money
things like that
microbes you know when you're growing
the organic side like you mentioned
they're so important so that might not
be something that you kind of want to
skimp out on right so
yeah you're going to get a lot better
results if you do have those microbes
breaking down right
so yeah that's a good call out so
recharge using
just in flowering or using throughout
the whole group
i use the whole time it's most important
for me in flower
i make sure i never miss a feeding of
recharging flower but i do use it the
whole time
but sometimes i'm a little more relaxed
about using it in vids
just because it's not the best plans
kind of growth like
veggies that advance time is time for
them to heal they're able to heal
themselves
they're able to recover and like like
it's it's
more of a much more relaxing time like
there's
it's like once you get into flowers like
a race so like like then during that
time
they i make sure they get recharged
every week on on the dot like there's no
missing no recharges
and it's crazy because i like it works
really well because you can see
it says it on the back like noticeably
you'll notice the difference in your
plants you do
you do they'd be really happy like the
next day
yeah absolutely and not having the
microbes and veg i mean
if you're working with a quality bag of
soil
right it already has those microbes in
there to start it's gonna be enough for
the first
30 40 days or whatever so yeah keeping
it easy just just inoculating the flour
i like it how about plant
training let's switch it up to that
let's talk about what do you typically
do for
plant training throughout the grow plant
training so
yeah um with the plants plant training
depending on what i'm doing
so i found that with the photo periods
well this is all in keeping it easy so
for me topping and low stress training i
get very equal results from topping the
low search training
the difference is is that low stress is
less stressful and i've noticed that
eating topping the plant can stress it
out and it can be droopy
especially if you got more than one
topping you type in all the tops
it can't stress plan on getting droopy
and so i
i don't i don't like to um i don't like
to top
autoflowers a lot of people say
autoflowers they don't want to stress
them out too much
so i strictly train them and this is
because i've noticed
stress from from top of the plant at the
same time i've broken the entire top off
of an autoflower
and it still is my second highest
yielding plant from that growth
so i don't always know but i i try to
stay away from
from stretching out the all the flowers
as much as possible um
but topping is way easier it's really
easy just the top of a plant
then having to pull out all these plant
ties and bending the plant over trying
not to break it
tying it down like that that could be a
lot more work than just pinching off the
top and being done with it
so with the photos i i just strictly top
the photos
i don't really do too much anything else
unless one of them starts to grow
too much farther too much taller than
the rest then i'll do some super
cropping
just to bend it down and bring it back
down to the same level
but i strictly just top my photo period
plans i top them like three or four
times too like
i top it once at the top once it gets
the two tops i top both of those
and then i let it grow all the four
times and i top off four of those times
and that's it
after that it bushes out that i usually
get it it's usually about time to get it
under the scrog net
for the photo period plan so that's
about all i do for the photo periods and
once they get big enough
in the 4x4 i do use a scrog now i will
utilize this crossnet
because it does help with light
penetration and maximizing the yield
i found that when you spread those
plants out
they will replace tops like if you've
been in top now it will replace it with
two more tiles even if you're not
pinching them
like if you remove the top out the way
it'll allow another top to get to grow
to where that is so i love to put the
i love to take that strong then and bend
on all those main tops
and then you and then there's always a
bunch of small leaves
like small tops that's right at the top
of the straw
and and in a couple of weeks when those
other tops are bent over as those grow
back up those small tops grew up as well
and then now you got a whole bunch more
tops and i like to use the three inch
the three inch uh scrog net for that and
then after that
once i fill that up and i try to
strategically sometimes though i have
gotten away i have uh
recently gotten away from trying to fill
up every single square
that was a big deal for me at first but
i found that's another thing it's not
that serious
i don't filling up every single square
versus not
every square but getting most of them
and i haven't really
suffered my yield too much so all right
let's just try to keep the work easy uh
after that i put a six inch uh
square scroggin on just to hold them up
that's it
you know all the last thing i love
stretch training all those but that is
so
low stress training is is so
is so much work because they they grow
out of it so fast
and like you load stairs training and
then come back the next day and they've
all grown up
and i've even had plans like rip out of
the tires and
like you literally have to keep tying
them down every single day and they just
keep growing and
it's an everyday thing so i tried to
stay away from those frustrating
this is why i tried to stay away from
all the fire i got my autoflowers kind
of hard
like this just in those things just
talking like that like
it makes it a little bit harder right i
totally get what you mean
i do a similar technique for topping you
know i'll do the main top then i'll top
those tops and then i'll top again so
eight main colors or 16
colas depending on how many times you
top but you know one thing i've
challenged myself to do when it comes to
low stress training because i like to do
the topping
and then do low stress training along
with it to try to keep the canopy even
at that point
you gotta fly after going after you
right now
but uh you know as i'm bending them down
doing low stress training i'm
challenging myself more and more to just
bend with my hands and then use no ties
and i've actually been getting away with
it and just bending it now
yes it's gonna be beneficial to get in
there twice a day and do the hand
bending
you can get away with once a day you
might not have as much good of a
canopy just doing it once a day but it's
definitely possible to get away with low
straight chaining without ties
for sure yeah definitely it definitely
is i did i've done that a few times
and then i know you do some defoliation
too right so
uh you [__] up some of these every now
and then when you usually do that
oh now defoliation the foliage is very
important too uh
i forgot about that so like well all
those with all of the info up here i
defoliate all of them
in the beginning i used to i used to not
defoliate the autoflowers barely at all
but one of my girls i particularly
did it on purpose and i i did it in my
normal defoliation
because i don't do too much defoliation
period like i'm still
always with photos or auto i'm still
very selective about it just to keep the
the top sides uncovered but one of my
all those girls i actually particularly
just went ahead and just was like i'm
just gonna
defoliate like i normally would and i
had no issues out of it oh so i
defoliate all my plans
i try to keep the big families all the
families get really big
i take them off um i like the uh
you know like when they they start
getting the granddaddy families like
like those huge families that's been
there for those families i take those
offers
the ones i've been there from the
beginning and i just try to keep the
huge ones going
and like the the regular sized families
that they grow
like they like they grow new families
and stuff like as they grow
tops then they grow new families and
like i like the new tops to keep those
they families and so like
as the plan gets older i take the old
families and i just let it
develop new families and as it gets
bigger and bushes out
as those older families that's super
huge and those times got really long
i'll take all of those families again
and just keep
i just keep doing that same routine and
i do that to the autoflowers too and i
have no issues out of
yeah that makes sense uh i do it's
similar you know i am defoliating
particularly within the first three
weeks of flowers when i'll pluck off the
leaves and then
after the stretching period once they're
done stretching you know the buds fatten
up
i don't like to pluck off leaves during
that time period that's just me
i know people do it all the time they
get away with it so on and so forth but
that's just me and then sometimes like
towards the very end of flowering like
day 45 of flowering right like a week
before two weeks before harvest
i'll get in there and i'll do
defoliation kind of on the middle of the
canopy
um so like you get down in and that
helps with the finishing in my opinion
so
that's kind of what i do there how about
let's switch it up and talk about
pests what do you do do you do anything
at all to prevent
pests from i know you get a house fly
running around there
and you've got your grow tent right
behind you
what do you do to uh prevent pests if
anything
well the uh now i try to i like the
nematodes
oh i went through a lot of different
things with the pests i tried uh
neem neem oil and the neem oil works
really great
but it smells horrible and it just then
it has a really strong smell
and so like it works really good but it
filled your entire house your whole
house would smell like nemo and you
can't use the door flower
so then i got away from nemo i started
using mosquito bits
mosquito bits work pretty well um
but not great for spider mites i've
tried i've had fungus a million times
and i've had i've only had spider mites
once
so the neem oil spray worked okay
um it worked great for the spider mites
and the they weren't great for in the
[__] snacks while i was in veg
but it wasn't really much i could do for
them uh once it was in flower and they
still came back
um so after i got away from doing that
then i said i started using the mosquito
ducts
the skilled dogs didn't do anything at
all obviously for spider mites but they
were
good for a little bit for uh fungus nuts
um but they still kept coming back from
that's all relentless
um so then i started getting into uh
using nematodes
and nematodes work really well too um
but you have to be
uh diligent with them as well and keep
dosing them because they still come back
and fungus that's
that fungus knives come back so easily
and
and then these then flies too i like to
keep uh
i like to keep fly traps up in an easy
grow tent too
uh i don't know i don't know where all
these flies just came from
just today because they all came today
to bother me
so i actually went and got some more uh
sticky chops i love to keep the sticky
chops up too just a little just so that
it alerts you to what you got going on
uh because you don't really you don't
really notice the fungus that's real
unless until you come to water the
plants and you water them and then the
fungus gets flying around
um but i love to come in every day and
just take a look at the sticky chops and
see what's on them
and then you'll know that you got other
things i haven't had spiderman
spider mites again since then though
um so i've been pretty good i haven't
i've been pretty
pretty blessed with the um with the uh
pests except for the fungus i haven't
had anything else
yeah i was gonna mention the yellow
stickies because i've seen those in your
videos
and you know trying to keep things
simple sticky put just sticky traps up
is kind of an easy thing that you can do
in order to
help catch the fungus gnats so you can
kind of see and then take action from
there
now you're growing organically the
medium needs to be moist at all times
it's no surprise that fungus gnats will
will come at you
a lot right they thrive in that wet
medium on that top layer there so having
those sticky traps there
they're so key and like you said i mean
they could just invade
so quickly and then before you know it
you get the fungus damage on
the leaves like the yellowing and the
leaves and like those circle
uh spots the rust spots just all the
leaves and you know you have fungus
gnats and
it gets really bad really out of control
and those yellow sticky traps are an
easy way to at least catch to identify
and also helps remove some of them right
because they're getting trapped into
dying there so
cool yeah that's awesome i know what
kind of flipping things around here kind
of getting all over the place one other
thing i wanted to talk about was
i think that i saw in your video it's
not on the list of questions that i gave
you but i figured it would be good to
bring up here
because i thought it was pretty
interesting was the after you harvest
right
you do your trimming or whatever and
you're putting it into actually a vacuum
seal
can you talk to me a little bit about
that you said you had a lot of success
doing that right
so that's something that that's
something that i discovered
recently it wasn't funny i can't explain
exactly how i discovered it
but basically basically i needed to
figure out
how the product was going to be after
being vacuumed still for like a week
so it's all i don't normally do i just
i just happened to just do it this one
time and uh
and so before i did what i did i just
wanted to make sure
that it wasn't gonna be destroyed
afterwards so i just wanted to check so
i uh
so as i did what i did i took some more
implants and i put them i vacuum sealed
them
and then i left it in there until
the other thing that i was doing was
ready and
and then i came back to check to see how
i was see how it turned out
i actually took i actually experimented
with two ways i took them
i took a bud and put it inside of like a
regular mylar bag and sealed it and then
i
actually vacuum sealed some of it in
inside of a vacuum seal and sucked all
the air out
and then sealed it that way now in
detroit
in detroit we got this stuff that we got
this stuff that a lot of people like to
call his eyes
or exotics and basically
basically the way that they do it is
more so
it's more so chemicals and stuff
that they uh they give it this really
tight look
and it's really this really strong smell
so after after this week was up and i
opened this pack
i was completely blown away because like
i was like oh my god like i like it turn
to exactly
like like it literally like got really
tight
and then it smells like extremely strong
and i opened it up and i was just like
why what did i what did i just do like
and
i did it again then i harvested another
plant i did it again
and so are you letting them dry you're
harvesting and then letting them dry
then trimming or are you just
trimming and then going well i actually
uh so i trim it
and then i put it in a jar i leave it in
the jar for a week i'll let it cure
normally before a week uh just cause
it'll still be kind of soft still
and like i feel like i'll be scared to
do it right in there like i feel like
it's gonna
let's crush it completely so i'll let it
i let it cure like
regularly for a week and then i go to
the vacuum seal and
and i just squish to make sure it's and
you got to have it you got to start like
a good material so your material need to
be
a decently dense material already uh
like and like because i've had i've
tried to do it with
like i've had like an auto that didn't
grow as great and it was it was kind of
fluffy
and i tried that and it did not work it
just crushed it and
even after letting it cure for a week
it's still crushed so
like it still has to be decent a decent
uh plant
that's a that's a decent decent distance
that can withstand the strength
of it being squashed like that but yeah
after a week regular cure in the jar put
in a vacuum seal and i only do it for
one week literally only one week
and it's just it's just to compact it
like that and then it just
it does something to the smell like like
i it's
it's almost like it just like it's
almost like it traps
everything inside and like once you open
it up it never loses it like
like and i and i take it out after that
week i break it all down like i was and
then i put it back in the jar and i just
i continue curing just like normal and
just like normal and it continues to
carry normally
but it just i just do it for the look
and and that smell it just boosts the
smell
like i can't t i can't i'm not gonna lie
i sit here and say that it makes it
smoke any better
uh because it doesn't and like like it
smells this is great either way
but like but for the appeal
it definitely does it definitely does
something for the appeal especially with
in my city a lot of people are looking
for and like it does that
i'm not even sure if that's how they do
it or not because it seems like that's
how they've been doing it
because it literally did that it was
pretty cool so i've been doing that
ever since just one week vacuum still a
week and then back to the jar man
i've been doing that with everything is
it the recipe i like it
yeah i can imagine the video that you
showed it looked like it was tightening
up those buds
quite a bit so yeah as far as peggy i
mean it makes total sense so i thought
that was interesting fair bring that up
on here in case anybody
either wanted to know that as a tip or
if maybe some people were already doing
that
and they know about that but it's not
something we normally see
yeah and i couldn't find no information
on it myself either
it was one of those things that i had to
like i had to come up with that little
routine myself because i researched it
hard
like i thought i did that that one time
i did a lot of research like
how should i do it should i go straight
from the plant should i trim
like how long should i dry how long
should i leave it
i couldn't find no information on it so
it was something i just had to
experiment with
and so like you said if anybody wants to
do what i did
uh i explained one more time i trimmed
cured regularly in the jar for a week
vacuum still leave it back yourself for
a week
and go back to a jar for the remainder
of the curious cycle huh that's it
all right well i know that most you're
following those a lot of followers of
yours that are beginners and they're
following you do a great job with kind
of explaining things
you know step by step on your channel by
the way
that being said you probably get a ton
of questions from beginners
so on and so forth what advice do you
have
for people who are just starting out
advice i have for people that just
starting out
is go for it uh jump into it and get
your first girl started
i spent a lot of time a lot of time
confusing myself and harping over
how i should do it what should i do am i
doing it right
like which sees like p like
getting into growing is so frustrating
like like it is so
hard and so frustrating to get the
information to get
some type of solid information that you
need
to make you comfortable enough to pull
the trigger on what you want to do
it's so hard like like you'll never be
comfortable enough with the information
that you get
and what i learned from that is just to
do it and
and learn from doing it and
and that's the best way i've learned and
it and a lot of a lot of stuff about the
way that my channel is is because
it was it's because a lot of that stuff
was hard for me
to come across like a lot of information
that was hard to come across from me
and and a lot about like
me being simple and so mine a lot about
that too
is is uh is
it was really hard for me like like when
i first started i was trying to build an
ebb and flow table
they had me trying to build an ebb and
flow table for flower
they had me trying to build a a draining
field
uh um it was crazy it was like one of
them was going to be at ebbing flow
where they flood the whole table
and then drain and the other one was
like a dripper the veg system was like a
dripper system
and like it had all these leaves it is
water pumping all this stuff that the
guy was making good otherwise all these
videos
this dude told me it was the best way
like everybody say their weight is the
best way too
the only way you gonna know is just to
go ahead and do it and
figure out what's comfortable for
yourself there's nobody that's going to
be able to tell you
what's comfortable and what's the best
way they're going to say it's the best
way but it may not be the best for you
and so don't don't don't get too uh
too caught up on everything just do it i
i live my life that way i just jump into
it and do it and i learn from there
that's really good advice yeah there are
so many different ways to grow
and it can become so overwhelming it's
like just do it try it
do what you think best adjust every part
every single part of growing there's a
different million different ways to do
it
but you'll never you'll never be
satisfied
all right so wrapping things up where
can the listeners find you and what do
you got upcoming in the future
well y'all already know i'm trying to uh
we still trying to open this uh
this dispensary so um detroit right now
is being sued
uh which is a whole another story but
they're being sued for basically
trying to have this program for a
low-income people
um for people who aren't low-income that
don't qualify for over being sued for it
so
the especially may not end up in detroit
but there will be a good buzz wellness
center uh we're not gonna give up on
that
it may not be in detroit but it will be
uh
if you want to holla at me you already
know to follow me on youtube mr good
buzz
uh you can keep up with me on the
instagram um and see what's going on
uh on mr goodbyes on instagram
um and i'm on facebook and twitter as
well
i'm all mr goodbye so you can just type
in mr goodbyes on anything you can look
me up
i might even start a uh i might start a
tic toc uh girl channel too
and just do some like some quick little
growth growth things on tick tock i've
been seeing some uh
stuff like that lately too so i might
get on there as well i already have a
tic toc page mr goodbye is there as well
so
i'm gonna highlight me there as well
awesome well for those on youtube i will
link his youtube
channel down in the description section
below so you can go down there and click
on it to get to his channel real quick
give him a sub show him some love over
there in the comments
and yeah thanks so much for coming on mr
goodbyes i'm glad we got to
finally do this i think it was a great
talk i appreciate you being patient with
me too man
yeah and we went through hell talking
man y'all don't even know
i i didn't i i was waiting one of these
i was like man you know what i forget it
oh i don't want to do it norma at that
point i was gonna beg you like man
please man please
appreciate that we got it done yeah we
got it done for sure but uh
all right i will let you go and uh yeah
have a good one
all right man appreciate your time man
we out peace
[Music]
you