coming up on garden talk
if you can get those stomatas to open up
and to intake co2 it'll increase your
growth and your performance of your
plants like so much it got me nervous
wanting to venture into the organics but
as soon as i did and as soon as i found
out how simple it was it was like why
didn't i do this from the start
let's all add another layer of living
soil sea soil on top of the top dressing
so that that top inch is only the living
soil that's kind of drying out once i
see tap roots or some sort of root
formation i'll transplant them into
little half gallon square pots
it becomes super simple
when you want it to be simple just dive
into it get into the living soil and
just start
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 35. in
this episode i interview jeff from mad
hatter organics he has been gardening
for five years and he grows plants such
as cucumbers peppers corn medicinal
varieties sunflowers marigolds and more
in this episode he talks about his style
of organic gardening he likes to keep
things easy in the garden and he talks a
lot about the easy gardening techniques
that he does thanks to all of you
support this podcast for patreon if
you'd like to support you can do so by
going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible
thanks to aec infiniti for sponsoring
this podcast they sent me over their
grow tent which has a canvas density of
2000 d making them the thickest grow
tent on the market today it has an
aluminum plate that mounts your
controller to the grow tent with a light
proof pass-through for cable routing the
frame has fifty percent thicker steel
poles and carries two times more weight
than the standard grow tents
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their website down in
the description section below dutch pro
is a sponsor of the podcast coupon code
mrgrow 10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pro's amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit10dp for a discount on
their products a big supporter of this
podcast is spider farmer they sponsored
this podcast and i use their led grow
lights spider farmer now has a bar style
series of led grow lights they have the
se 3000 a four bar fixture for a three
foot by three foot grow space the se
5000 a six bar fixture for a four foot
by four foot grow space and the sc 7000
a six bar fixture for a five foot by
five foot grow space i will leave a link
to spider farmer down in the description
section below and you can use discount
code mr grow at five during checkout for
discount on their products
all right we are back
welcome to the garden talk podcast today
i am joined with jeff from mad hatter
organics how you doing today
good man good how are you
doing great thanks for joining me today
we're going to talk all about organic
gardening you have a pretty easy
techniques you do a lot of easy
techniques when it comes to organics and
we're going to get into that today i
know there's a lot of people out there
that watch my channel tune into this
podcast that they are they grow with
synthetic bottle nutrients and they want
to make that transition over to organics
and i think kind of this conversation
here with you will kind of unravel
how easy organics can actually be so i'm
super excited for this one one thing
that we usually start out with is could
you just kind of tell us a little bit
about yourself and kind of how you got
into gardening
yeah for sure um
i've kind of always been into gardening
from a young age
my dad had a huge
vegetable garden out back of our
property and
um
he kind of just
made me get my hands dirty in it so uh
i started
started when i was probably four or five
doing that and then uh
as time grew i you know became a late
teens i i started
i started actually
going into hydroponics i grabbed
general hydroponics
grow bucket with some
general organics uh
bottle nutrients and master allies and
tomato plants and they were the
most delicious hydroponic tomatoes i've
ever tasted in my life
so it was kind of just intriguing with
with organics and and growing stuff and
[Music]
so yeah i kind of dabbled into the
medical market and
in the legacy side of things and
we uh
we had quite a few plants in uh
current culture hydroponics
and
so i did a few years of that and then i
moved i moved
a thousand kilometers away from from
where that was and uh
and then the legal market came alive in
canada here and i uh
i started
growing medical stuff and um
i actually
just started using synthetics like most
people you know uh
pro mix hp
just bottle nutrients
normal you know calm egg stuff like that
and uh and then i got into fox farm
ocean forest so it's you know mostly
organic mix and
um
i seen how
i see how easy it was
it seemed just you know add water and
the plants just grew and they grew like
beautiful beautiful plants
um
and i kind of did that whole synganic
side of things so i started off organic
and then i went
after the nutrients kind of drained out
of the soil i went back into the bottles
again and that's kind of when i started
to see my problems
you know the calmag issues and
ph uh
toxicities and stuff like that and
and i was just like man why am i doing
this to myself why can't i
why can't i just
add water the entire time like so
i kind of looked up a bunch of soil
mixtures um
my local
my local hydro store has uh
has guy green nutrients so i just
i threw a bunch of that in there and it
started messing around and now i'm like
full blown organics and it's it's just
amazingly simple it can be real easy for
sure once you kind of figure things out
you know it might take a little bit of
research to begin with and some people
might complain
that you're not able to kind of look at
a one-page thing and follow a chart a
feeding chart like you can with bottled
nutrients right once you figure out the
basics and you kind of have a general
understanding of things it really can be
as simple as just
watering
and top dressing you know what i mean
and we'll get into that a little bit
deeper here in a few so now you actually
have a youtube channel too so you're
actually showing off your garden to an
audience now i know you have i have your
youtube channel up right here 182
subscribers looks like you probably have
a couple dozen videos
yeah it's fairly new it's it's maybe
about six months old or so so it's
fairly new i'm just trying to get in to
get into it i'll definitely link it down
in the youtube description section below
so if you are on youtube you can easily
navigate to his channel and check it out
and then if you are on one of the
podcast platforms
search mad hatter organics and that'll
take you to his channel
so are you just an indoor grower or do
you do outdoor growing or what
yeah um
i've dabbled into
outdoor growing but where i am it's
it's a very weird climate um
we have
a later i guess
yeah late spring so it goes into
about may 20th is the last frost um so
like you know i can't get my plants out
until may 20th and then first frost is
september 14th
so
i have a very short period i can really
only grow autoflowers
um
i have dabbled into photo periods but
they just take way too long they go far
into october and
uh
they just end up getting
you know the humidity spikes because the
temps drop so much um so i just end up
getting bad bud rods and
and this year we had horrible horrible
thrips um
and then we also have a bunch of hemp
farms around
that uh that just
the aphids the aphids are absolutely
insane
uh i've
i've done everything i can and i'm just
i've kind of given up on the
outdoor stuff but i do grow lots of
vegetables outdoor um
corn
[Music]
tomatoes
cucumbers peppers you know all the all
the general stuff
uh but i think next year i'll probably
be dabbling into a little bit more
vegetables so you're mostly indoors now
can you talk about what your current
indoor grow room setup kind of looks
like you know what size grow room are
you in lighting ventilation so on and so
forth
yeah uh so
[Music]
i have a little desktop vivosun tent
uh
it's got
it's actually for
propagation so seedlings and clones um
it has a little spider farmer sf 300
it's a little 35 watt unit perfect for
cloning and seedling for for myself at
least
i've got a little four inch fan in there
to circulate air
and then a little
a little nightstand or a humidifier so
it takes a little water bottle you pop
it on top and it just has this little
cool mist that comes out and it
keeps humidity perfect in there
so yeah i i run that for a few weeks and
then
i have it set up so it's perpetual
it goes into my 2x4
vivosun tent that i have a spider farmer
sf4000 in that i've dimmed down to about
40 50 percent uh if i crank it up it
just the heat just becomes too much in
there
uh so i have a little
four inch fan exhaust fan that kicks out
of there i've got my vents open in there
i use that as my veg tent so the lights
are staying on from 18 to 6
18 and six um
i also use auto pots
[Music]
so once they're done in the seedlings i
transplant them into the auto pots i
start the veg off for about a month in
the auto pods and then
they get kicked over to my 5x5 that's
right behind me here um i've got an 8
bar
led
just an alibaba one um 650 watt
it produces some some light for sure uh
so i've got that set up with
a six inch exhaust fan
um
and then
another auto pots with the aqua five
valves so i just basically take them out
of the tube or two by four ten
the pots and i just transplant them over
into the the trays into the 5x5 so it's
super simple
i also have everything set up
on
ink bird controllers so i have
the seedling tent has inkberg
controllers and a heat mat the 2x4 has
both the humidifier or humidity and temp
controllers they're non-wi-fi
and then i have the 5x5
with the humidity and temp controller
they're both wi-fi so i can check them
on my phone to make sure that all my
temps and humidity are
are set perfect
and
[Music]
and yeah so they
my temp controller is set up on
with a exhaust van to pull out hot air
if it gets way too hot in there uh and
then it's
and i also have a little roll around oil
fed heater that
kicks on because i'm i'm in my basement
and i'm in southern alberta where it
gets minus 30 so it in my basement it
gets pretty cold
so i have my
heater there just in case the temps do
dip down too far
it'll kick on and heat up the tent
and then i have my dehumidifier set up
on my inkberg controller or humidity
humidity controller
so once the
humidity is
too high it kicks on the d-hum and
sucks all the video
and i also have the humidifier that's
you know if it gets too high or it gets
too low then it kicks on so you got
multiple tents for the different stages
of growth and one way you keep it easy
you just bench is you have automation
right so you're able to control the
environment's conditions
through automation the input controller
the heater so on and so forth so
definitely a way to keep it easy is to
invest in the equipment in order to
make it easy so your hands off quite a
bit there yeah absolutely in regards to
controlling the environment
now are you starting from seed or do you
usually do clone
uh it really depends on what i do um
obviously i start autoflowers from seed
if i do do autoflowers um i'm kind of
leaning away from it i did a few years
of it so i'm just
kind of interested in photo periods now
um
but i mostly start from seed with photo
periods and right now i'm doing a fetal
hunt uh 20 seed feed on
that uh that have started from seed and
i will be transplanting everything over
to the 2x4 soon um
finding the females calling off the
males
and uh and then i'll be taking clones
and cloning the planets out so i do a
little bit of both okay cool
now what are you a soil grower coco
what's in your mix
it's a kind of a little bit of
everything it's a super cocoa i like to
call it uh
it's a coco cocoa pearl
from psycho
psychonutrients i don't know if you're
familiar with them they're from
australia
but uh yeah some coca-cola with uh with
perlite in it
uh and then i add some either guy green
living soil or sea soil
and then
i'll add worm castings and guy green
dry amendments
so it's a little bit of a
super cocoa mix
what are you adding in can you give us a
little bit details about like kind of
your ratio and kind of what you're
adding in so what your initial mix kind
of consists of in detail
yeah um so it's my the auto pots are
3.9 gallons
so i'll add uh about two and a half
gallons of
coco coir uh half gallon of worm
castings
and then
a half gallon
of
the living soil or sea soil and then
i'll mix in the dry amendments on top of
all that
okay and then you're just following the
instructions for the dry amendments
according to what is gaia green what is
it you know whatever tablespoon per
gallon it mentions on the packaging
yeah i think uh
what did i have it set for i think it
was three tablespoons per gallon yeah
two it was i mixed in the four four four
and the two eight four the whole purpose
and the power bloom
got it so three tablespoons per gallon
for each of those yeah yeah cool all
right so that's their initial mix and
then you're starting out in smaller
containers as you mentioned coming from
ron let me make sure i'm visualizing
this right you're starting off in the
smaller containers in your ceiling tent
and then you're transplanting into
directly into that autopoc container
that three point whatever a four gallon
container will say for easy it's just
under four gallons i believe it is auto
pot xl i believe it is yeah when do you
actually do that transplanting
so yeah like
i start off my seedlings in rockwell
cubes and then
once i see taproots or some sort of root
formation um i'll transplant them into
little half gallon square pots
um
or solo cups uh and i'll just i'll i'll
basically just transplant those right
into like a living soil or sea salt just
so they're not getting too much
nutrients so they sort of so they're not
getting
burnt right away typically i'll leave
them in those solar cups or half gallons
for about two weeks and then i'll
transplant them into those pots
um into the auto pots four gallons
and i'll leave them in veg in the auto
pods for about four weeks
so then they'll deplete
kind of their veg nutrients out of that
mixture and then once i
throw them over into the 5x5 flower tent
so i'll veg
i'll start my seeds and veg for total
one and a half months
um and then i'll kick them over into the
flower tent and
as soon as i do that i'll top dress i'll
tea
and i'll mic you know add microbial
inoculants okay we'll get into more
detail on what nutrients you're feeding
when and the teas
a little bit later
first what is the water source using are
you using reverse osmosis distilled
tapped are you collecting rain water and
bringing that in so what do you do for
for water well for all my outdoor stuff
i i use rain water i've got a barrel
barrel collection system with that
um
i was starting to kind of think about
kind of introducing it into into the
tents as well but
uh
we'll see we'll see
um but i was also using ro uh i was
running to the store every week or so
collecting four big five
or i guess they're five gallon jugs of
water
you know they're costing me two bucks a
jug so it was just getting a little
costly and a little time consuming doing
that
so i actually bought um
one of those boogie filters i think the
they're like rv filters for for camping
trailers
you hook them up to your hose and they
get rid of contaminants that are in the
water out of your tap
they dechlorinate it they
get rid of a lot of the chloramine
they just reduce overall minerals in the
water so it's more of an acceptable
level like
like yourself i have kind of a hard
water situation here i'm running about
315 ppm
um
so i
kind of want to pull as much as i can
without spending five six hundred
dollars on the naro system for my house
so as of right now i've switched to just
using a filter on the end of a hose and
pulling all the minerals out of it yeah
it's a good thing to
remove the chlorine and chloramine in
particular because that's what's known
to kill off the microbes in the medium
right and that's what's the microbes you
want in a
organic system because that's they're
there working to break down those
amendments
and turn them into usable nutrients for
the plants
so it's good that you're you're
filtering that out there now you
mentioned the ro system being very
expensive i think you said about three
four hundred dollars i know you live in
a completely different area than than me
i have a five stage one that i have
underneath my sink
and that one ran me about 200 u.s so i
don't know i think canada probably about
three hundred years a little bit more
in there but i did the math on it and it
does turn out to be good for me i know
everybody's different number of plants
you're growing blah blah blah blah blah
but it can be worth the investment and
this is particularly talking about to
the people who
did what you did which was go to an ro
station
you know what i mean and spend that
money i mean my ro station that's right
down the street it's like a dollar 75
for five gallons so it can be very it
can add up very quickly especially if
you're not only putting that water into
your medium but if you're also filling
up humidifiers that's another thing to
kind of calculate as well so ro system
is something i definitely recommend but
i have you know use tap water
as long as you're filtering out that
chlorine chlorine the things that are
going to kill off the microbes which is
what you're doing right now so that's
good
yeah i was
i'm not against going ro whatsoever i i
love it i just
it's too time consuming too
costly for me right now so eventually i
will get one in the house
makes sense and then one last thing to
talk about ro i know some people are
going to call this out as
it's wasteful right so for every gallon
of ro what do you get
roughly three gallons is going to go at
the drain so recommendation and i got to
give a shout out to dog of the hut for
this one take your drain line put it
into a bucket and then use that for your
outdoor plants right so you're not
really wasting that it's not just going
right back into your local water
municipal system you know what i mean
it's if you're actually using that water
so just a tip there now are you ph
adjusting your water at all or is it
coming out within the range you want it
to be in
it's it's coming out a lit like a little
bit more than i'd like it's not too bad
uh but i also don't adjust it
um
i rely on the microbes to balance
balance that out for me
uh
i i trust it and
have trusted it so far uh it's been
working and i haven't seen any sort of
ph issues in my planet so is there a
specific ph range that you aim for or
you just like hands off as far as don't
even monitor it all just kind of water
it in and kind of let the microbes do
that thing
um
my tap comes out at 7.9 so it's it's not
horrible
uh i like to see it at seven
um and i'm sure the microbes will
will balance those out to seven
okay that makes sense
now talk to us about your watering
strategy i know you're using the auto
pod system you mentioned that i've used
the auto pod system in the past as well
we actually had a conversation offline
about using the auto pot system and
organics can you just talk to us about
the auto pod system kind of how it works
in your organic system yeah uh
the auto pawn system is an automated
watering system
it
doesn't require any electricity or any
sort of motors or anything to pump with
[Music]
it it works off of capillary action so
you have a reservoir a 15 gallon
reservoir that will
feed into the trays
the
trays or your your soil mixture will
then
soak it up from the bottom
and you know use that capillary action
to
water your water your plants water your
soil
when
when my nutrients kind of fade out of
the soil
i'll top dress
but when i do that i'll also
uh top water so i'll add
i'll add
a half a gallon or so water just so i
can i can get the nutrients kind of
soaking down into the soil instead of
getting pulled up from the bottom
uh
and then yeah i add teas i top dress the
teas as well um
i top dress microbes
every about every two weeks i'll shut
the system right off
i'll turn yeah i'll turn the system
right off and i'll i'll let the soil dry
out for a day or two and then that way i
can i can top water without having that
soil absolutely saturated
and drowning the roots out that's what i
was doing too you know auto pot system
like you mentioned it's hooked up to a
reservoir and it's coming down and it's
it's basically dumping out water or
nutrient mix whatever you have in the
res
to the bottom of the pot and then it's
like you said capillary action which
people that don't know that it's
basically just wicking up
the pot right but in my experience i
found that that top inch or so is still
still dries out so the problem that i
ran into in the past particularly with
top dressing organics
is it just it didn't maintain that
moisture level and the moisture level
needs to be there in order for the
microbes to be active and break down
those nutrients that are in that that
top layer so i struggled i had like
yellowing like
mid flowering week five or so you know
four or five for flowering on some
plants but i did the same exact method
that you did which is turn off that
valve and just let the thing dry out for
a couple days and then top water and i
also went in there like daily and i was
spraying
the top of the medium in order to keep
it moist like on a daily basis one
sometimes two times a day just that top
layer not soaking it so it goes all the
way down but just doing what i can to
try to keep that top layer moist
yeah because it is important when you
have an auto watering system there and
there are other so many different auto
watering systems out there some of them
are up top and kind of work their way
down which might be better arguably
better for organics i know i run the the
blue mat system that's one that drips
down from the top and i've had no issues
with that top layer drying out but yeah
something i thought that was definitely
good that you brought that up and talked
about the auto pot system and organics
because of the fact that it can be a
little tricky right it can be a little
tricky but
in the long run it is easier it is more
hands-off you know yeah cool yeah it
kind of like how you were doing it
spraying the top layer it kind of just
defeats the whole purpose of auto
watering it's you know like you want
that ease and and
reliability of it uh
but when you're having to talk top water
everything it's like
what's the point but uh kind of the way
i kind of got around that as well with
the top dressing
is i'll add another layer of living soil
sea soil
[Music]
some sort of of
media on top of the top dressing so that
that top inch is only the
the living soil that's kind of drying
out so you have that layer of top
dressing that will actually
be able to get
the water absorption
gotcha yeah i usually use a mulch layer
so barley straw is what i what i use
that helps keep that layer below the
straw below the mulch layer moist do you
use a mulch layer at all or just kind of
what you mentioned there i yeah i know i
don't it's just uh
yeah the living soil kind of layer uh i
recently just got in contact with a
brewing company to get some rice hauls
so i'll be i'll probably be adding that
in for
for more aeration and more silica um and
then that top mulch layer like you said
to try to
keep things a little moisture up top
cool how about cover crops do you do
anything for cover crops at all
i don't uh i don't reuse my soil in wall
i don't i do reuse my soil i don't reuse
them in my tents uh i i add them to the
gardens in my yard uh i will
add them to the compost i'll add them to
the
the the big garden bed for
more out of like autoflower plants
in the greenhouse
um
[Music]
but yeah i don't i don't use any
hey cover crop i i'm kind of looking at
getting into
if i can find someone with a two by two
um
fabric bed
i'd like to add it to my 2x4 and then
if i do end up going that route i will
start doing cover crops that way because
then that soil will just
be there and i won't have to replace it
how about beneficial like insects do you
have any like
spring trails road beetles isopods to
use worms in your garden anything like
that at all or
uh outdoor stuff i use worms um in the
beds and that for for the veggies
uh
in my tents i'll use beneficial uh
swerve skis and
californicus
um
just to protect for ipm measures for uh
spider mites and
thrips
but
no i i keep i try to keep everything as
clean as possible so i don't need
the rove beetles and whatnot to
for beneficials
and that's one thing i think a lot of
people get tripped up on you know
especially when they're starting to
learn organics they think it's a
requirement you know they think it's a
requirement to have cover crops they
think it's a requirement to have
emotionally they think it's a
requirement to have worms
beneficial insects when really it's not
you know there's there's that is one way
to go about it and you could argue that
that's the better way to go about it the
more natural way to go about it for
nutrient cycling and so on and so forth
but you can certainly get away with
using organic inputs without using any
of those beneficials mulch layer cover
crops all that stuff really you're just
relying on the microbes to break down
those amendments which is what you're
doing on this
on that avenue so
i think again i think a lot of people
get tripped up on that they think they
must do that in order to be considered a
living organic system or an organic
system whatever you want to call it but
you can get away without it for sure
that's uh that's one of the biggest
things that
when i was starting to get into organics
that really
kind of got me nervous about it was
was the
soul like this
so much information there's so many
different ways to go about it right i
mean yeah you know you can do the top
dressing way with the organic blends
that you're doing or you can do the
living soil and have individual
amendments that you put on once in a
while i mean rely on worms to create
worm castings rely on cover crops to do
nitrogen fixation so there's just
there's so many different ways to go
about it so yeah i think that's kind of
it got me nervous wanting to venture
into the organics but as soon as i did
and as soon as i found out how simple it
was
it was like why didn't i do this from
the start i hear you i was the same way
information overload and then finally i
found out about organic blends and then
kind of went that route so let's get
into organic blends in particular you
know the organic inputs the organic
nutrients that you're using curricular
firm are using gaia green
is that right yeah okay
you also use worm castings as well right
yeah
so when do you first apply i know you
you mentioned your initial amending of
that soil now eventually those nutrients
are going to be depleted
from the soil so at what point you have
applied that first top dressing and what
does it consist of so
yeah my first initial
amendment mix is when i go to transplant
them from sealing into the veg tent um
and then as soon as they're done in the
veg tent about week four so uh
week six from c but week four from
transplant
uh
i'll throw them over into the five by
five flower tent and
i will
top dress i'll mix up a mixture of of
living soil
um
guy green 444 and guy green 284
and also
add in some worm castings a couple uh
probably about two cups over castings
and then i will scratch the surface up
uh get those feeder roots kind of
exposed and
then i'll top dress all the dry
amendments on top of that and then
on top of that top dressing like i said
before i'll add a layer of living soil
just so that it has that dry layer kind
of thing
but yeah that's
that's as soon as i start as soon as i
flip them to 12 12 i top dress that's
traditional i feel like a lot of people
will do that they'll do it either on at
the flip or right before flipping that
light cycle you know so they have a
solid 30 40 days in veg and then they'll
kind of flip over some people even
longer than that but there's so many
different ways to go about it now
let me ask you this the gaia green that
you mentioned two eight four and four
four four
you're doing three tablespoons per
gallon for each of those is that correct
yeah yeah okay all right and then
do you apply a second top dressing at
all throughout the grill and then what
does that consist of if you do
yeah i will do the exact same
mixture uh
about four weeks into flour uh top
dressing that as well okay and then are
there any other feedings that you do
after that or is that it so
between the top dressing so i'll go
as soon as i put the flower top dress
two weeks after that
i will add a tea a
brewed compost tea
and then
about a week after that i'll
i'll introduce more microbes so i use
this product called microbial mass yeah
it has the microbes for that focus on
phosphorus breakdown similar to like a
mammoth p is another microbial inoculant
that's well known for to have the
microbes in there that focus on
phosphorus breakdown it increases the
bioavailability of phosphorus that's
that's what i'm looking for
so then yeah so i'll add
microbial mass and i'll also add uh
um it's uh it's another product from
microbial mass
where
it's derived from crustaceans like crab
shells and stuff so i'll add both
microbial mass and ketosol at the same
time
um and then
that's at week three and then week four
all top dressed again and then
i'll repeat that process until
pretty much
the fly you know the end of flower so
usually typically it's about eight to
nine weeks and
you know
i'll let the all that the flowers
deplete the soil
after that eight eighth week there so
the microbes that you're using
when do you start them and when do you
stop them are you also just doing the
dosage on the bottle for that so i'll
actually add them right from seedling uh
as soon as i
yeah as soon as i i drop seeds in the
into the rockwell cubes all
at a couple drops of microbial mass just
not not too powerful
but uh
it's increased a little bit of uh
success rate on on the seats and clones
um
so yeah i'll run that all through it's
every pretty much every two to three
weeks i'll run that uh with
with adding them into the auto pots i
will
i will double the amount that i that's
on the bottle just because
i i top dress in
so i'll top dress in sorry i'll top
water in a liter water with the solution
and then
i'll double the amount and add in
the water from the below
um
[Music]
so it kind of balances each other out
so it's
back to that bottle recommendation okay
that makes sense and then do you
incorporate any sugars into your garden
i think one of the ones that i believe
i've seen you use in one of your
channels before is liquid weight by
green planet nutrients
yeah yeah um
yeah so i'll add that in
when i'm doing my compost teas
just to actually feed the microbes i
don't
like to give them too much sugar
um i'd like
them to get the plant or to get the
sugars that are derived from the plants
um
so yeah i do add a little bit of that
liquid weight it's it's a three
three part sugar solution so it's mostly
molasses really
uh
and i'll add that in with my compost
teas as well just to feed the microbes
from the compost let's get deeper into
the compost teas because i know you said
you use throughout the grow or at least
in flowering can you talk to us about
the compotes you do
they're just the aerated compost teas
can you kind of tell us like how much
compost you use to how much water and
what else you're adding in
yeah uh so i have these little little
mesh bags
they're for produce from the
grocery stores
uh
they
they just have little tiny holes in them
just enough so that
the the compost and everything doesn't
fall out of them
um
[Music]
but i'll take a five gallon bucket i'll
add i compost i have my own compost bin
so i i
add worms to my compost bin as well so
it helps break down everything in there
um
it's just mainly food scraps from
from dinners and
you know whatever's left over in the in
the
vegetable bins in the bottom of the
fridge i will add about two cups of that
compost to those bags and then i'll also
add a cup of worm castings
and
a couple teaspoons or tablespoons of of
the
guy green power bloom
i'm not really 100 sure if the power
bloom's really doing much if i'm brewing
that as well
but i just do it just
just because
uh
so yeah brew i'll brew those with
with an oxygen or a
air pump for about 24 to 48 hours just
kind of typically what everyone does
and then yeah i shut off the auto pod
systems for two days and let everything
dry out and then i'll
all top water all my compost season and
was that for a five gallon container
five gallon home depot bucket okay
and then
you're doing that how often once a week
or once every other week or what uh
once every two weeks two and a half
weeks and if i feel like i'm kind of
over watering them with the compost teas
i'll um i'll just take them upstairs and
give them to the house fonts instead
good point gotta put it put it to good
use i mean you could even sprinkle out
in your backyard right your vegetables
i'm sure they'd love it as well oh yeah
yeah
yeah i brew all my approved compost teas
for my lawn and for my vegetables out
back and
yeah put it put it to good use
one thing i forgot to ask about was
temperature and humidity i don't think
we covered that what do you typically
aim for for temperature in your
environment so for seedlings i like to
keep it around 78
um
fahrenheit uh and then
65 to 70
relative humidity
uh just to try to i
i'm a big believer in vpd um
[Music]
the vapor pressure deficit it's just
it's proven it's it's a massive benefit
to your garden uh
if you can get those stomatas to open up
and to intake co2
it's
it'll increase your
your growth and your performance and
your plants like so much so it's it's a
it's a huge thing so i try to
get everything in that perfect range the
perfect vpd range and uh there's a few
charts that are online that you that i
follow
um to to get them in there to for the
right humidity and temperature at the
same time
so then
seedlings will stay at 65 to 70.
once i go over into the veg tent i will
stay around
78 to 80
fahrenheit um
and i'll
typically sit around 60 to 65 percent in
veg for a few weeks
once i hit flower tent
i'll start off at uh
that's
60 humidity and i'll drop to about 52
into in 52
until the flowers are done
uh temps right now
they're a little high they're sitting at
85 not too bad but uh
i typically like that 80 80 degree mark
uh
it's kind of fall right now so it's not
too hot it's not too cold so my house my
my central air my house isn't gone
and it's not cooling everything down and
uh
getting to that point and i don't want
to add my my little roll around ac unit
because it's just
it's more power more noise it's
it's it's too much so
i'll let her ride for now i'm almost
finished flowering so
uh
and then yeah it'll be winter time so
the the basement will
cool everything down for me that way
nice nice
let's flip it up let's talk about ipm
so do you do anything at all in order to
prevent pests from invading your garden
yeah like i said before i use a little
sachets that i hang off of my plants
by culper
culprit i'm not sure how you pronounce
it but uh
covert biological systems
uh
they hang off your plants and they
introduce swift skis and
californicus to fight off thrips and
spider mites
so i got hit by spider mites if
probably a year ago really sucked
they came
what week four of flower week three of
flower
there was nothing i could do i couldn't
spray anymore i couldn't really
couldn't really do anything other than
introduces the
sachets so they helped a lot uh
they got everything under control
manageable
where they weren't you know completely
webbing up all my butts but
uh
but right from seedlings i i use
essential oil sprays
uh there's a company called
um
culture
and they they have a bottle of it's
called mercenary and it's just essential
oils so there's peppermint and sesame
seed oil and
rosemary so all the all the beneficial
oils that we'll use as suffocants and
deterrence for
for the bugs i start that right from
pretty much
as soon as they start showing their true
leaves
all the way up until about
a week to a flower so so as soon as they
start getting those little pom-pom hairs
on them that's
what i cut them out
and then i keep everything i try to keep
everything as clean as possible as soon
as i'm done with the tent everything
gets
bleach spray i sewed everything like
i tried to keep
clean clean and clean yeah that helps so
much i always do a uh
just kind of a wipe down of all the
equipment grow tents everything before i
start growing also i try to do one
between when i flip the flower you know
i mean i try to do another cleaning of
that if i am able to remove the tents
remove the plants out of the tent i will
you know what i mean i think it's worth
it in my opinion and of course one of
the basic things to do is to avoid going
directly from your outdoor garden to
your indoor garden right because you
could be little those little critters
could be stuck on your clothing and
could definitely invade your your indoor
plants so yeah like i said this
this year it was horrible thrips and
horrible aphids so it was like
i was freaking out for a bit i you know
i didn't even want to go outside
okay so what advice do you have for
growers who are just getting started
with organic gardening
uh
you know it's not as hard as you as you
try to make it make it seem you know
like it
you read so much into it and you're just
overwhelmed with the amount of
information and the amount of like oh do
i need worms and do i need this and do i
need that well no you don't really you
know just
have a quick search on on build a soil
build it you know fill the soil has
amazing soil that
that's already pre amendment amended and
pre-built for you so it's like
they have these little mixtures that you
can do they have
there's little
there's little packets of
of already pre-mixed uh
brewed tea stuff
so it's just you know it's it
it becomes super simple
when you want it to be simple
um
[Music]
just dive into it
get into the living soil and just start
you you don't need to go crazy on
[Music]
on rice halls and cover crops and this
and that you can just
start off simple um
there's lots of of mixes that you can
mix up yourself too like the coots mix
and
uh
yeah like this build the soil stuff that
you can just do all yourself
it's uh
it becomes simple
don't get too uh
don't get too nervous about it
i think that's great advice for sure so
wrapping things up how can listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future
you can find me on instagram mad
underscore hatter underscore organics
and
uh youtube same thing
uh mad hatter
organics what i have in the future uh
i've just started a discussions kind of
topic on my youtube channel i just take
a you know two to five minute kind of
thing
just the basics uh i just did one on vpd
um
i'm just gonna
start with the basics of things like
if someone wants to learn the basics of
microbes i'll
i'll touch on that and do a two to five
minute thing on that and uh if you know
the basics of things
you don't have to dive too deep into it
if you want to you can but don't get
overwhelmed awesome well i will link
your channel down in the description
section below and again if you're
listening on one of the podcast
platforms you can just search mad hatter
organics and this channel will pop up if
you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up button also drop a comment
down below let us know your style of
organic gardening so many different ways
to do it i would love to hear what you
do down in the comment section below if
you haven't subscribed to the channel
yet please do i release these podcast
episodes every single week typically
it's on saturdays sometimes on sundays
and if you're tuning in on one of the
podcast platforms particularly apple
podcasts please leave a rating and
review
creeping up towards 200 ratings and
reviews so i think we can get there so
with your help i believe we can get
there so thank you to everyone who has
left a rating and review so far jeff
thank you so much for coming on to this
podcast today we definitely broke things
down in an easy manner i know there are
people going to be tuning into this epic
it's not easy as i think it is you know
what i mean if you're new you may be
thinking that it's not that easy by
listening to this but
i think once you continue to push
yourself to learn more and more about it
you'll find out that the organic blends
top dressing method
is the more easier way to go about it
you know when it comes to organics so
again thank you for spilling spilling
your knowledge here dropping some
knowledge bombs
and i hope you enjoy the rest of your
day yes thank you very much for having
me on i'm i'm humbled and blessed and
and yeah
can't be uh can't be any more happier
thank you very much
you're welcome take care
[Music]
you