what's up everybody feed that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watch a mattress channel got a
part test video for you today this is
the es 300 version to buy the green side
check company it's also called the
electric sky 300 they actually sent this
grow light over to me and in this video
I'm going to test the power output I did
do a part test for the es 300 v1 if
you're looking for that video I will put
a card in the top right corner of the
screen right now and also posted in the
outro card of this video they've also
provided me a discount code for my
viewers so you can get a percentage off
a plus free shipping depending on what
country you live in
I will provide a link to this girl light
in the description section below along
with the discount code for the power
test I'm gonna use the apogee MQ 500
power meter this meter measures from 389
nanometers to 692 nanometers plus or
minus 5 nanometers and measurements are
in ppfd
and really this video is just to give
you a general idea of what the power
output is it's not going to be hundred
percent accurate I do have this girl
light and they grow 10 which has a
reflective walls that could increase the
numbers so just keep that in mind the
coverage area for this grow light is 2
foot by 4 foot they say that you can
extend it to two and a half feet by five
feet but I do have this in a two foot by
four foot grow tent and that's what I'll
be taking measurements in for this video
just like all the other part test videos
that I do I'll let the measurements do
the talking
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed please click that
thumbs up and that will leave that that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]