what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr grudd and welcome to my talk
channel got another discussion video for
you today
for this one i brought in chris from
happy hydro we talk about
environment particularly indoor grow
environment
we talk about the temperature humidity
co2
and air circulation you all have made it
very clear that you want to see
more of these type of discussion videos
the video i did with pigeons
on plant training has over 105 000 views
right now
the video i did with rob from cl tv
talking about plant nutrients
that has over 175 000 views as of right
now so you all have made it clear that
you want to see
more of these discussion videos and uh
got one for you today
the audio on this video is actually
recorded onto one channel so chris's
voice
on it is slightly lower than mine in the
future i'll make sure to record on
two channels so that way the audio will
be better in the future
but still pretty good you can still
listen to it so don't click away just
yet
let's get into the video all right we're
here what's up chris how you doing
good man how are you good good ready to
talk about
awesome ready to talk about environment
or what let's do it
all right so we'll cover uh let's cover
temperature
humidity let's get into co2
and then air circulation so basically
covers everything
has to do with uh plant's environment
how's that sound
sounds great man um you're located on
the west coast i'm on the east coast
we're dealing with different natural
outside
environments which um affects you know
inside environments and also correct me
if i'm wrong
there's not people don't really have
basements on the west coast right
yeah i don't have a basement now it's
just yeah on the east coast you guys
almost every house has a basement right
yeah like every house in buffalo pretty
much has a basement and
it's really a good spot to grow in terms
of like trying to keep things private
maybe like from
family friends visitors you know it's a
it's a good way to keep things separated
but there's
when i say it's a good place to grow
it's not an
easy place to grow in terms of like
you know humidity temperature and
controlling things
so i take it you grow in basements
i've grown in basements in the past the
biggest issues that you have
is a lot of basements aren't completely
waterproof
or sealed you know you get like a
basement that has cracks in the walls
and stuff and you can easily find
yourself dealing with
mold mildew and just like things like
that that can really screw up and grow
it's not the optimal place to grow
but when you you know if you have a
two-bedroom house and
a roommate and there's nowhere to grow
and you got a basement it's like well
obviously we're gonna utilize that space
if possible so
we have to look out for cold concrete
floors you know it's
you don't want to just set your plants
on the cold concrete floors in a
basement
um and also
just in the summertime dealing with
humidity dealing with the extreme cold
in the winter
those are some of the challenges but it
is a common area that people do grow in
and i
i think that people could
get some value out of some tips on how
to grow down there if you're on the east
coast
absolutely absolutely so we could
definitely talk about that so let's
start off with
temperature so me living on the west
coast
i actually live in a very dry climate a
very hot climate i live in a desert
region
you're in a more humid climate since
you're on the east coast
you have bodies of water around you
it's a lot more humid it's a lot more
colder
so i think our discussion i'm pretty
excited to have you on here in
particular because you live in such an
opposite climate
that i do and so there are different
pieces of equipment that we use in order
to control temperature
humidity and so on and so forth so kind
of starting with temperature
so the ideal temperature that i usually
aim for when i'm growing my plants
is anywhere between um 70 degrees
and about 82 degrees fahrenheit roughly
that's kind of ideal
now how some people may be watching this
they have may have read my book and saw
it was slightly different than that
what's in my book is kind of a general
guideline for that i'm kind of narrowing
that down
to be a little bit more ideal leaf
surface temperature of 82 is what i've
heard to be
ideal so i kind of aim for that if that
means that the canopy temperature is a
little bit higher than that to achieve
that
leaf surface temperature of 82 that's
okay
now as far as how low it goes i had
mentioned 70. it's okay
you know if it goes into the 60s that's
fine i actually do like to drop my temp
in the 60s towards the end of flowering
that way
it tends to bring out some of the colors
in some of the phenotypes
that i've grown um so going down to the
60s
is is fine for me like the plant will
still grow just fine
in that range but having a swing greater
than um
you know 10 15 once you get to upwards
of a 20 degree swing between day and
night time temperatures that's when
you know you might want to cause for
alarm it might be stressing out the
plants too much
so i would um i would agree with you and
i think that i would do
pretty much the same thing but one thing
on the east coast that we have to look
out for is if
if we drop the temperature down to 60
degrees in
late bloom and we are not aware of our
humidity levels
and we have like high humidity
low temperatures um you know it's a
prime time opportunity for powdery
mildew to start growing in your plants
like
um i've dealt with it in the past having
like too cool
of a of a bloom at night with too high
of a humidity
um from you know growing in the summer
or growing in
a basement that doesn't have a knock
a basement that's not completely dry or
um or even growing in an
upstairs like bedroom or something that
you just can't
if you don't do a good job of keeping
your humidity uh
low you can definitely have issues with
powdery mildew with cool
uh temperatures in late bloom so i would
warn people watch out for that
and then um another thing i wanted to
well what percent is high rh do you
consider high
that you're at risk for powering mildew
i mean if you're in late bloom and
you're and you're over 60
humidity i think you're starting to
creep into dangerous um
territories i mean i'm sure it's
debatable um
yeah i agree with you on that one i've
had bud rot uh in late bloom yeah
big large dense buds higher humidity not
enough air circulation that that
is involved in this as well and with
pottery mildew and it happens
yeah and it's so depressing when it
happens
yeah yeah cause it's like you've just
spent three
months maybe four months doing all this
work and you're
you know about to trim or you're about
to be cutting down soon and you find
that powdery mildew and stuff and it's
like
oh man like what do we do do we
now we have to throw a lot of this out
like wow
um it's terrible but to rewind a little
bit you mentioned
the uh plant canopy and leaf temperature
surface
and one thing i wanted to mention is
that um
if you're using like a grow room monitor
such as like the pulse sensor or sensor
push or any really temperature it could
be like a 12
you know walmart uh temperature thing
with the probe or whatever
that probe you're going to want to have
in your
canopy the temperature at your canopy on
top of your canopy
could be different than the temperature
uh you know in the
in the side of your room or whatever so
i think it's important for you to know
that they want to take their temperature
levels at the canopy
where the plants are because it can be
different throughout the room
yeah i agree with that i know some
people have a room temperature
they also have that canopy temperature i
know some people actually put it down by
the soil so they can get kind of get an
idea of what the soil level temperature
is now
of course if you have that humidity
monitor just resting on top of your soil
it could kind of be inflated as far as
the humidity number
for example um you know if you have a
wet medium moist medium yeah
and that's not going to give you a real
accurate representation of what your
temperature is
in the soil right it's kind of like
above the soil but it kind of gives you
a general
um general idea of what uh you know your
temperature and humidity is at the soil
level so
yeah canopy level great call out is to
get measurements there for sure
um and then you know you mentioned bud
rot and and uh
you're cooling your temperatures down in
late bloom and stuff
a one thing that you can do or that
growers can do
to avoid that issue even if the humidity
does get
get high in the room is to have good air
circulation
so i know this was on your list of
things to talk about
when you have good air circulation it
makes it hard for
mold and mildew to grow so having
you know the leaves on your plants just
like
you know moving a little bit signifying
that there is good flow coming through
the canopy
is going to prevent um the possibility
of a lot of like
mold and mildew and butter out and stuff
like that
i do want to take a step back and talk
about temperature just a little bit more
so if the temperature is one thing that
i use to regulate the temperature
in my grow environment is an inline fan
i use the ac infiniti inline fan which i
know that you are
familiar with i use the t6 model
for my 4x4 grow tent and i have
for those of you who don't know about
the ac infinity fan there's a controller
on it
and this fan is is pretty advanced
compared to other fans you can actually
have set points on it as a probe and set
points
so you can actually hang that probe and
canopy level and you can have the set
points
for certain temperature and humidity so
what i have it set for is the
temperature at 82
so once the temperature actually goes up
and reaches 82
it will my ac infinity fan will turn on
and it will start to exhaust
some of that hot air and then of course
my lung room or the room that
my grow tent is in has
air that is around room temperature it's
usually around 70
72 degrees so that air is coming into
the grow temp passive intake
and then again once that hot air is
being exhausted the fan will
automatically
turn off so it's intermittently coming
on
controlling and kind of keeping that
temperature around 80 82 degrees
when the lights are on now when the
temperature is
too low so say it goes down
below my ideal temperature like i
mentioned
you know 70 roughly if it goes into the
60s that's okay but
i have a heater in my lung room so lung
room the room that
my grow tent is in i have a heater so i
try to stabilize
the temperature at around 70 degrees 72
degrees
for example now on my heater there is a
feature on there which is going to you
can put that you can set the temperature
so if the temperature drops below that
set point it's going to kick on
so my lung room is stable at all time
due to the heater
and then as my grow light is on and it's
exhausting with that hot air that stable
um
air coming in about 70 degrees is coming
into my grow tent so
my fan is coming off and on so that's
how i
regulate temperature in my grow space
and then one other thing to mention was
the sensor push
sensor push pulse those are monitors
that you can use
within your growth space i personally
use the sensorpush one i actually just
got
the pulse one thanks to you i haven't
used it yet though
but but um
having that canopy level as well and
getting alerts through your smartphone
because there's an app that you connect
and tells you what the temperature is
what the humidity is you can just see it
on your app you don't actually have to
go into your grow room
um so using those pieces of automation
uh
what do you mean records like it records
the data over time so you can go back
and you can look at your graphs and be
like oh on
i notice that every november this
happens
you know what i mean on the graph it
gets too cold in my room so i know i
need to have a heater in november like
you can go back and analyze the data
or like i know that like i'm noticing
that in the middle of the night it gets
too cold or it gets too hot in the day
or you know whatever
exactly exactly you can analyze yep and
you can also do the set points as well
on sensor push where you get
notifications on your phone right so if
the temperature drops yeah so the
temperature drops too low
i'll get alert then i can go into my
room figure out hey why is this
heater's not working do i need to
increase the temperature so on and so
forth
or if it gets too high right maybe maybe
uh
you know something went wrong to where
my lung room the temperature is too high
um so the air coming into the grow tent
is too high so that i need to make
adjustments maybe add an air conditioner
for example
so how does it work with you you're
you're talking about this um
the sensor pushing how it can give you
alarms to your phone this
technology of like those types of alarms
greenhouses have been using for
forever um so my wife her grandfather
owns or owned a greenhouse he's passed
away and the business was
closed but um in his greenhouse
they had alarms so it didn't go to your
smartphone
they had a wire ran so there was an
alarm
in their bedroom in the house like in
front of the greenhouse
so if it was too cold or too hot um
you know the alarm would go off at three
in the morning and they'd have to wake
up wake up and go out there you know
they've got
a ten thousand dollar crop they gotta uh
make sure it doesn't die
so i just think it's funny how the
technology
is still kind of the same but like now
it's like oh right on my phone like
i don't have to have an alarm like
in my bedroom yeah so
when the temperature reaches too low i'm
using a heater you know my lung room
temperature's too high i have actually
have a central air conditioning is what
i've used i've used those
portable air conditioners before very
inefficient
didn't have good luck i mean temperature
was super stable don't get me wrong but
as far as energy consumption it was
super expensive
so i i've avoided using that i use my
central ac now
that's just in my area like i mentioned
my climate that i live in
i live in the desert region so i'm able
to kind of get away with that what do
you do do you do you have to run a
heater and you have to
run any sort of air conditioning too
so um on the east coast if you're if
you're growing
in like your house where you have you
know central air
or um heat it's going to be very similar
to what you're dealing with it's not
going to be a whole lot different
um but you know if you're growing in a
space where you don't
have like for example a friend of mine
is growing in his basement and
um what he does in the wintertime
is he runs a couple of the growers
choice 500 watt
cmh lights instead of running led lights
because he actually uses the heat from
the lights to keep the grow space warm
and then when they shut off he's got um
you know a heater down there and i i
think he actually
uh vented his like heater for his house
to like
be able to uh produce heat into the
basement grow room as well but um
yeah that's something that people in
cold environments can do you know leds
are
efficient and they save on heat but if
you need heat use an hps or a cmh
yep yeah it's going to generate a lot
more heat and
heat up your grow space i know growers
who that's what they run in
the winter time is hps so they can warm
up their grow space
and in the summer time they go to led
yep yep that's um it's pretty common on
the east coast
at least uh for the people i know and
the growers that i've met in the local
grow shops and stuff when i worked there
let's talk about humidity shift gears
over to humidity so humidity
uh you know there's a lot to be said
about humidity
what the ideal range is i know a lot of
people go again go
for vpd a vpd vapor pressure deficit
we won't get into too much detail about
what that is feel free to google if you
want to learn more but basically
your humidity level goes by the
temperature
leaf surface temperature to be more
exact some people just use the the
temperature in the grow room to kind of
chase after vpd but it does call for
higher higher humidity than
normal right and you do come across
risks for things such as bud rot
uh pottery mildew mold things like that
for uh what calls for higher humidity
than normal
vpd oh okay yeah yeah
yeah so if you're running like 80
degrees i mean we can bring up the chart
right now
let me see if i can summarize vpd for
for those who might not know
basically like your plant is going to
release
moisture from its leaves
based on how humid it is in the room
yeah transpiration yep okay so it
transpires
it releases humidity transplant out of
the leaves into the room and if the room
is very humid it will transpire at a
lower rate if the room is really dry
it's going to transpire at a faster rate
which is going to affect
how often you have to water the plant
and the the health of the plant and how
it's
producing cells and um growing
yeah i mean that's one thing i run into
is a very low humidity uh
transpiration increases if i'm running
synthetic nutrients for example bottle
nutrients of feeding the plant
it could run into very very very well
run into a toxicity issue
it's happened before to where you have
too much yeah because your plants drying
out
uh the medium a lot quicker it's up
taking nutrients quicker there's a plant
available nutrients
you can't run into toxicity issues with
low humidity so
kind of bringing up that humidity but
getting back to the vpd
i'm looking at the chart right now so
for example if you're running
a temperature of 84 degrees
it's calling in the green area for about
74 to 78
humidity so let's just give you an idea
that's you know some people hearing them
like oh wait that's
that's way higher than what i'm running
right now some people might
hear that number and they might be like
oh i hear pottery mildew
pottery mildew knocking at the door you
know so um
it's risky i think chasing after vpd i
think is definitely risky
the general range that i usually aim for
is between 40 and 60 percent
um so i can avoid pottery mildew you
know bud rot when it comes into
flowering
so on and so forth what um what percent
humidity do you usually aim for
well let's um i'd like to just talk
about early veg for a minute
um well seedling clone and early veg
because i feel like
that is a point in time where humidity
is extremely important
and um a lot of people have
issues with their plants during these
periods that they think are due to ph
nitrogen toxicity or not enough
nutrients
whatever like it's hard to sometimes
pinpoint if you're not tracking your
humidity well
uh the the general consensus really is
that you have to have
high humidity in early veg and for your
seedlings and clones
or they just they they don't grow well
yeah you bring up a great point i should
have said that
it's crazy the difference that it makes
like i've i've seen
a girl maybe i was even involved in it
that had you know just
vegging plants that just look like
and you're like
why is this happening like what do we do
we you know we go through the list we
try to narrow it down
you know what let's introduce a ton of
humanity uh
to the room and get it up to you know 70
percent three days later all of the
plants are just
i call it praying for light when the
leaves are just like
they just look so happy like um
so i think like early veg one of the
biggest problems that people
have that they overlook or don't put
enough kind of like
uh effort or whatever into is is
figuring out or is getting their
humidity up so
uh one thing i saw which is really cool
from seed to stone
he has these little plastic domes that
he puts
oh so he transplants his seedlings or
his clones into
the pot and then he has these like
plastic domes that he puts
over them which acts as like a little
humidity it only keeps the humidity up
as the plant transitions into its new
vegetative state and uh new pot
and i've seen you do it with like
plastic bags plastic bags over the cups
yeah that helps with seedlings for sure
which is cool too yeah but one of the
biggest changes that i made like as an
early grower was introducing more
humidity and a veg and just
it's just it's a it's a big um big
difference
yeah you bring up a great point i should
have said it earlier when i mentioned
that the 40 to 60
the 40 60 40 to 60 that i mentioned
earlier is really for
for veg and flower those are safe routes
now when you're in seedlings
clones um i run higher than 60
i aim for like 65 to 85 percent
is typically what i aim for on that
avenue and then when they're in veg
you know mid veg is when uh you know i
get below
60 and that goes against vpd you know
some people are going to say that this
isn't ideal and we're just kind of
talking general range that the plant
will grow in here
um so i think that's the kind of a
general range so like i mentioned before
i live in a very dry climate
so i have to actually run a humidifier
at all times 24 7. two humidifiers
actually have two humidifiers in my lung
realm
in my veg 10 i have a humidifier too and
my flower 10 i don't need to
run a humidifier most of the time
we also run we also run a humidifier in
a vegetation in this climate
oh you do without jerry in this diamond
yeah okay i've heard a lot of most of
the time
i've heard a lot of people i know my
friend lives in boston
and uh he's i mean he's right on the
water so humidity is just naturally high
i mean
sixty percent plus uh it's just
naturally i know in florida too
it's crazy so people have to run a
dehumidifier all the time
or else powdery mildew
you're both on deck just in case just in
case because you know the
with the season's changing i mean winter
you know if you have forced air in your
house
in the in the wintertime it's getting
dry and the winter just gets drier in
general over here
it's honestly a pain in the ass because
if you're not
really caught if you're not paying
attention to the seasons
especially if you're a new grower like
you know you go you have this
amazing grow because you did it in the
perfect time of season and then you go
to do your next girl
and you're like you know why why what's
happening why why aren't things healthy
the seasons change and the humidity is
different so we keep both to keep the
humidifier on deck and the dehumidifier
i mean just try to
really pay attention to the season
changes
so you have them on at all times in the
room even if you don't need it or do you
only bust out the dehumidifier like on
certain seasons
we bust out the dehumidifier for usually
uh mid to late veg and then
into the drying phase like we don't we
don't crank it during the drying phase
because if you dry
your stuff too fast it's just not good
it'll smell like hay and
not good so we don't crank it but we run
it
in the summer we usually don't run it in
the veg we usually don't have to at all
even in like mid-late veg
um yeah we run in the summer in the
winter we just run it basically in late
late late bloom uh and in the drying
phase
uh the humidifier we run in the winter
we're running it in veg
actually mostly year round
um like i said i just find that the veg
up
like the veg plants grow so much faster
with good humidity so
we don't really use the humidifier in
bloom
ever i don't think yeah i don't really
think we do
and if if we do it's only for like the
beginning for
you know a little wild first couple
weeks or something
but yeah that's a good example of how
it's comp it's different for me like i'd
never
run a dehumidifier need to winter time
like you mentioned the heat forced hot
air
you know i have a gas forced hot air
heating system
it does lower that humidity actually
it was 18 the other day 18
that's crazy crazy low so i'm constantly
battling that low humidity and that's
why i have to run multiple humidifiers
in the climate i live in and it's just a
perfect example how two different
climates two different setups you just
gotta
you know uh figure it out there's so
much balancing
i get so many growers asking me
questions about what they need to do
and they live in a different climate so
it's like uh they
it's like different than what i would do
and so it's just a matter of uh
tinkering with your equipment and
figuring it out i think
i think this is a good segue into
discussing co2
yeah oh yeah yeah um using co2
the most ideal way and efficient way to
do it is in a sealed room right because
if you're not
if you're just exhausting all your co2
out the window
it's you know what i mean you're gonna
go through tons of tanks or
you know propane if you're using a co2
burner or
it's just not extremely effective to
run co2 and then just like exhaust
outside so the long room
is a fantastic way to uh to have like a
a good co2 system where you know the co2
gets
goes into the grow tent and then it gets
pumped out into the lung room
you know that lung room is going to have
a higher co2 content like the
the co2 is going to stay in there that
the plant isn't
the plants aren't consuming um it's
going to sink to the floor
because it's heavier than air and the
passive
intake on your grow tent i assume is at
the bottom
so the co2 is just going to get sucked
you know back into the tent
naturally and uh kind of just keep going
into the tent
into the long run into the tent in the
long run and um
and you're so you're using tmb naturals
um co2 canisters correct
yes and you you shake those up like once
a day
and they um do you do you like hang it
above your plants or do you just set it
on the ground
so guidance from tmb naturals we you can
do a couple things
number one is you can hang it above your
plants because co2 is a heavy gas it's
going to sink down so your co2 will sink
down there
or if you have an oscillating fan within
your environment they had mentioned it's
fine to place it like
around that either in front of the
oscillating fan or behind the
oscillating fan so that way
it's blowing the co2 around i've just
been putting it on the ground i've hung
it above my plants before
i actually think my co2 tank is uh the
canister is actually oh right now i need
to refill it
um i haven't been monitoring the co2 uh
recently i have gone grows where i've
monitored the co2 very closely
with those tnb naturals it kind of
varies especially since i'm living in
the house
that i grow in human respiration
my i'm exhaling co2 i have a roommate i
have pets
that is actually sufficient so when i go
in my room my lung room alone
it's like 600 800 ppm of co2
and when i'm out yeah without the
without
tmp naturals now with them when i got
tme naturals in there
plus my human respiration i'm up over a
thousand oftentimes
a thousand 1200 i know a lot of growers
uh ideally they had mentioned a thousand
to fifteen hundred when you're using
like a co2
tank for example which i know you have
experience on
and there's a regulator and so on and so
forth is that typically what you aim for
or what do you what do you
aim for when it comes to co2 and how do
you manage it i think
i think if people are are using
supplemental co2 they're they're
you know ideally trying to hit a
thousand twelve hundred at the very
least
before i get into the tanks so i wanted
to ask you is there a specific reason
that you decided to go with the co2
canisters from tmb rather than like the
mushroom bags
or tanks or
um they sent it or whatever sent them to
me for free
try it out that's a that's a good answer
that's that's the reason why yeah
i've seen those bags and those bags i've
heard a lot of people say they're much
more effective
there's some i think last with 365 days
or something like that i think
the exhale bags but i haven't used those
so we use this i used to sell them in
the grow store i worked at here we don't
sell them on happy hydro
yet but um you know we had one set up in
the store
and we and we had a monitor on it and it
kept the tent you know 900 to a thousand
and i'm pretty sure as
long as the the mushrooms are or the
mycelium is growing
as long as it's growing it's producing
co2 constantly so basically i
you know someone can correct me in the
comments if i'm wrong but as long as
that bag
is is alive and producing more co2 and
growing
it can last as long as you keep it alive
but
they are you know it is introducing
another living thing into your room
that you kind of have to keep an eye on
it
and kind of keep alive i mean if you
just throw that mushroom bag
two feet away from a thousand watt hps
light or something i'm pretty sure that
light will
dry it out or kill it or and there are
cheaper methods to the bags and the
canisters
uh there's actually home remedy methods
it seems like every time
every time i release a video where i
show the tma naturals or talk about co2
in some sense
there's always somebody in the comment
section who lists off
a super cheap way to do their own co2
and their own their own method of doing
it
i don't have it memorized i've never
tried it but there's super cheap ways in
order to
create co2 on your own without buying
canisters
bags tanks uh so on and so forth but you
you run the tanks sometimes right you
used to run the tanks
i have i have co2 tanks so
the biggest thing like if anyone's using
co2 tanks right now
and they're getting them from their
local hydro store and they're swapping
them out at the local hydro store
um it needs to be known that those
tanks were inside of other grow rooms
and if
other people aren't clean and they have
bugs
those bugs get on the tank they come
back to the
to the grow store they go to the co2 you
know factory wherever they fill them
long story short they come back to the
grow store and they go to your room
so i would tell everybody who walked
into the grow shop
here in buffalo that i worked at bleach
your tank
before you put it in your room take a
take a washcloth with some bleach water
and just bleach it down because
properly diluted properly diluted yeah
it would just really suck to swap your
co2 tanks out and then have
spider mites because the guy before you
wasn't a clean grower or
or maybe your growth store isn't the
cleanest grow store you know who knows
but yeah if anything that you're
bringing into your room and swapping out
regularly like co2 tanks i definitely
recommend cleaning
um how much does it cost for a co2 tank
and regulator and all that stuff oh it
depends
um i i remember uh
tank refills were like 20 bucks uh to
buy the tank
full for the first time i think is
probably 80 to 100 bucks depending on
where you go um and if you're in a
sealed room it lasts
what two weeks or something roughly it
depends on how big the room is you know
like
if you're and how efficient you are like
sealed
room is a very loose term
uh because i a lot of people may think
their rooms are sealed but they're not
um it's hard to get a
perfectly sealed room like i'm sure
there's plenty of people who have done
it but
uh there's always gonna be little spots
for
stuff to leak out and um
but the tanks you know you can get three
four weeks out of the tank in a smaller
area if you're
um efficiently sealed and
and everything and you know the cool
thing about it is if you hook it up to
the monitor and the controller and
everything you can keep that co2 level
exactly where you want it and you can
take
uh they make this perforated hose that
comes off the end of the tank
and then you hang the perforated hose
right above your canopy
so it's just you know raining co2 right
over your canopy
and since we're talking about canopies
in co2
something that we should be aware of is
that
the the plant leaves are absorbing co2
as the co2 approaches uh
the edges of the leaf like it's only
consuming co2 right by the leaf
so if you don't have good circulation or
like constant flow of co2
co2 is heavier than air so it's it's
going to the ground at all times
if you don't have circulation pushing
that co2 around and back up
keeping your plant leaves kind of moving
a little bit
um the plant is going to consume the co2
around the leaf
and then you know if it's just stagnant
air it's not going to get more
co2 you have to have circulation or
or some sort of you know distribution
distribution system uh dropping the co2
onto the leaves
ideally constantly to really get the
most out of it
yeah and then it always kind of worried
me with the seedlings with the
the bag over the cup we talked about
that earlier it's like there's no air
circulation going on there how is that
seedling still growing so like it
when it's small when the plants are
small like that you can kind of get away
with having
the bag over for 24 48 hours 72 hours
whatever
or like you said seeds of stone has this
whole dome that he puts over
i think those domes actually have a
ventilation um
sloths so you can you can open it up um
but yeah for a short period of time and
when the plant is small you can kind of
get away with it but uh but yeah you
bring up a very valid point is that air
circulation is definitely needed
uh in order to maximize you know co2
intake
and so you were saying that like just
you and your
cat and your roommate and everything
like produce enough co2 in the house and
in that room like if you're spending
time in there
to where you don't need a whole lot of
supplemental co2 so
based on that we can say that talking to
your plants makes them healthier right
yeah somebody commented on my one of my
videos and they're like oh you just
put your gym in there right you just
what
put your gym in there then you'd be
constantly
start working out and then do push-ups
jumping jacks don't wear a mask in your
grow room
so speaking of ambient co2 if you don't
have a sealed room and you're
and you're exhausting um you know out
the window or
like whatever the ambient co2 in the
in the world is between 250 and 400 i
think it's closer to 400 and varies
on on where you live um it is rising
um but there's tons of like big
greenhouse growers and stuff that
just can't afford and don't have sealed
environments to
to uh implement uh external co2 so they
just use the ambient co2 and
in order to do that you just really have
to have good
airflow and circulation you know keeping
those like i said earlier keeping those
leaves moving
you can still achieve good yields with
ambient co2
but these new led lights that are coming
out um such as the roi e720
they produce so much light that i'm
pretty sure that in order
to get the most out of the light to get
the plant to be able to keep up
and photosynthesize the amount of light
that's being produced
by those uh they they need
co2 yeah absolutely right i mean
commercial facilities are the commercial
grow lights right these
there's a reason why the they're labeled
commercial grow lights is because in
commercial facilities they regulate co2
and they're able to have the
additional par hit their plants there
are so many home growers who just
fry their plants with these new grow
lights it's becoming more and more
common
even at the proper light distance it's
still they just don't have the co2
they have low levels of co2 so their
plants just aren't able to handle it
you bring up a really great point with
that one so yeah increasing the co2
in your grow space will allow you to
intake more of that par
and also it allows you to deal with
higher temperatures
your plant can handle more extremities
when it has
more co2 i'm pretty sure it can handle
more nutrients too
seems like it just kind of like
turbocharges the the photosynthesis
process so the plant can just handle
more it definitely helps
uh but you know it's definitely not a
requirement so i know something i could
have a lot of new growers on this
channel
and uh some of them might be thinking
that they need to start implementing co2
you don't have to the natural levels
that are there is going to allow your
plant to grow just fine
i think the amount of yield that it
increased as far as like a
roi return on investment adding co2
versus
not having co2 i think that's a bit
debatable i think it depends on the
uh the method of co2 how much you're
actually spending right if you're
spending a bunch of
money on canisters versus
bags yeah if you're sealed so there's
too many variables
to really talk about that one but um
dude when i was a new grower i freaking
walked into a hydroponics store and
like i don't even know how to describe
it like
i just it was like my brain
shut off and i i
i'm no longer just growing a plant they
made it seem like
i needed the world to to grow this plant
right like
oh man it was i i didn't know what i
needed and what i didn't need right
because they just wanted to sell me
everything
oh yeah you're starting to grow co2
definitely
i'm like okay well i have three hundred
dollars and uh the bill is one thousand
so how do we
what do i what do i really need to just
get going
truth is you don't need co2 to get going
uh you don't need a million bottles of
nutrients
really you're just growing a plant like
any other plant and
and uh keeping it simple as a beginner i
wish i would have done that
i did not dude i got i over complicated
things so
much that it was just it was a disaster
the moral of the story is about that is
like as a new grower
like it's it's really hard to navigate
and figure out like what you actually
need and what you don't
and at the end of the day you need a
little nutrients you need a little light
you need a little dirt and a little bit
of water and some good temperatures
right like you know environment is key
yep absolutely
and i think one other thing that we do
need is air circulation right
let's let's start talking about that and
we'll wrap up with that one
is air circulation is just so key for
for so many different reasons
um co2 we already talked about how it is
important for co2 if you have stagnant
air
your plants aren't getting the optimal
one on co2 because
it's directly right by the leaf is is
really what matters for for them in
taking co2 so air circulation is very
important
you had mentioned that you like those
plants to be dancing at all times
i agree with that just a little bit yeah
yep i agree with that
um i also aim for that what i do is i'll
have an oscillating fan
above the canopy or right yeah right
above the canopy
so my plants are able to sway from that
so there's air circulation there
and i also have a oscillating fan on the
lower part
of my canopy you know it's usually on
the ground and it's blowing i actually
have those clip-on fans now
that clip directly under the grow tent
so this is super easy i can just adjust
the height
on the grow tent but above the canopy
below the canopy
those are two things i usually aim for
and that's usually gives good air
circulation that plus
my inline fan popping on and off
for air exchange that's usually a pretty
simple method
that's usually what i aim for now i've
run one
oscillating fan in the past and it died
overnight
and uh when i found it there's some part
there was some bud rod that already
started
and once it starts even if you fix that
issue
it still can continue to grow within the
buds and unfortunately two weeks later i
harvested and then uh drying came and
i opened it up to some some bud rods so
that wasn't good but so now
i'm running two oscillating fans of my
grow tent at all times
what do you usually do for air
circulation it's just a kind of rewind
to talk about oscillating fans
you know that i've been doing tons of
research into oscillating fans because
i'm trying to find a high quality one to
bring
onto the happy hydro website and
what i've found is that most of these
oscillating fans the smaller six
inch ones suck like they die on you like
you said you had one die
um and so i mean i think it's worth
mentioning that if any cust if anyone
out there is doing
is looking to get an oscillating fan to
do your research i'm not going to call
out brands specifically
in the video but do your research and
make sure the brand
that you're purchasing from you know has
a high quality
fan a high quality uh oscillating fan
because like you said they do
if it's a low quality quality fan they
do eventually die out
and um when they do
three months worth of work can can be
out the out the window so
you know is saving ten dollars on your
oscillating fan
worth risking a failure i don't think it
is i have no problem mentioning brands
if they have defective products
the one that you're i think you're
talking about is the the vivo sun or
some people call vivoson i think it's i
don't know which way it's pronounced
i've been saying vivo sun and they
haven't corrected me on it so
i'm gonna run with that but um i've been
talking with them
about that in particular because i did
have a fan that died from them
and if you look on their reviews it was
just flooded with people who have
that fan uh that would die on them and
what they had mentioned is that they
have revised that fan
so that issue no longer happens what was
happening the root cause for that
is as the fan was oscillating the wiring
inside was
constantly rubbing up against the side
and then there was basically kind of a
short circuit i don't think that's the
right term for it but the wiring would
just get
yeah the wiring would just get um
annihilated from moving back and forth
it would wear out and then it would no
longer
have the electricity to the fan they
said that they fixed that problem we'll
see if that new generation of fans
if that problem is fixed or not but yeah
you bring up a group i'm not willing to
be a guinea pig for it
neither neither will i uh put my
customers up to that um
if they do fix it and uh you know they
put out a good product and
you know i'd be happy to distribute uh a
quality product but
um until that's you know verified um we
probably won't have a vivosun fan on
happy hydro site right now
i'll be the guinea pig perfect i'll be
the guinea pig if the new one they send
me
is legit then hey i'll let you know
if you get if you get bud rod i think
you should send them a bill for your
long
harvest it'll be nice if i could do that
that would be really nice
but what do you usually do for air
circulation
so a cheap thing that people can do
that's pretty reliable
is to just buy a cheap box fan
take to a grow light hangers hang it
from the ceiling
and have it blowing air right between
the top of the canopy
and uh the light fixture
okay so vertical it's vertical it's not
you know i'm talking about horizontal on
the top of the
grow tower vertical right vertical okay
so like the side of the grow temperature
yeah um so that's like just like a cheap
way to
to really move a lot of air i mean a box
the box fan will move a ton of air
um how did you how do you fix it up
just like hang it from grow light
hangers grow light hangers
okay yeah and then it can just blow you
know it's not ideal for like a 4x4 grow
tent
but if you're growing in like a bedroom
or something
um and you need to move a lot of air
like you know
hang up hanging a big box fan it's like
a budget
way to get the job done got it um
obviously it's not as great as like
having oscillating fans like mounted to
the walls and stuff but
um you know that's that's the way i was
a budget grower
like when i did my growing you know i
was
between the ages of 14. i don't tell my
mom
and uh 22 i wasn't just
i didn't have a lot of money to to to
invest so i found
you know cheap ways to do things that
worked really well uh
and you mentioned that you put your
oscillating fan
you know over the canopy in between the
light
another huge benefit there is those
lights are putting off heat
and if you can just pull that heat right
off uh before it hits the canopy
that allows you to push those lights a
little bit closer
up up to a certain extent the closer
that you can get the light
usually means that the deeper that the
light will reach and you know the denser
the buds you could produce
up to a certain extent
[Music]
but yeah that's a trick that i use
hanging the box fan cheap trick
um if you have the space then you have
like an oscillating just standing
pedestal
fan laying around your house that you
can just use
you know grabbing that throwing in there
is a good way to
to just to have a budget option um
in the grow tent i think that
if this oscillating fan thing is dealt
with and like they have high quality
oscillating fans that can clip on to
the um the grow tent pole
you know that's perfect but if they
don't there's there
there are um i think the monkey fan
uh there are fans that clip on to the
grow tent pole that don't oscillate
but but still you know are small combat
compact uh and can push a decent amount
of air into your
you know four by four tent or whatever
um one thing to mention about that
though
is you just gotta be careful to avoid
wind burn right wind burn is a real
thing
if you're constantly blowing air onto
the plant consistently
the plant can have a stunt growth that
dries out the leaves the outer part of
the leaves and you'll see the edges
start to
to brown and curl down and things like
that happens it may i've happened to me
multiple times and also even with the
oscillating fans uh
if it's blowing directly onto the buds
those white pistols
they turn brown and start to recede a
lot faster
due to the amount of air that's hitting
them so
um you'll notice that i know there's
some girls who have come across that
in the past so explain that to me again
quickly it's so like in uh in what part
of bloom do
is this a concern i mean really any part
of bloom i mean i've been an early
flower
and i had an oscillating fan and every
time it went to one side
in blue it was hitting a bud and the bud
on that branch the hairs the pistols
went from white to brown and
started to recede and then you look at
the other parts of the plant
and that wasn't the case now how much
that's going to actually impact growth
i don't know um but it certainly had
stressed out the the plant to the point
where
the pistols had turned color and receded
it's really interesting i never thought
about that or
i guess i just never noticed that but it
makes sense i mean obviously the
oscillating air is going to affect your
vpd
in the way that the plant is transpiring
and you know drinking water
damn i had something to say but i'm
losing it
oh okay so if you
if you just have a carbon filter sitting
on the ground
and you have a fan on top of it like an
inline fan
and you're just you know scrubbing air
in the room
and you're sucking in air through the
carbon filter and then pushing that air
straight up um it's a good way to get
the co2
that sinks to the floor
back up and above your plant canopy so
that's like you know if you're not
worried about
if you're in a sealed environment and
you have an extra carbon filter and a
fan just like
laying around and you're looking for a
way to get like some circulation going
in your room you could just set that on
the ground with the fan on top of it
blowing that air up uh you know 24 7
you know another way to just get some
circulation going in there and it'll
also you know that filter will catch
some pathogens and things other than
odors that
you probably don't want floating around
in the room
that's interesting and i've never done
that scrubbing method
before so i've never heard of that i
think it's a great great tip for sure
um when you're scrubbing so uh the only
problem is
if you're worried about odors right so
if you're just scrubbing in the room
you're not creating negative pressure so
negative pressure for those that who
aren't aware
it's basically so if you have a carbon
filter and a fan inside of your grow
tent and you're exhausting air out of it
you may notice that the sides of your
grow tent start to suck in a little bit
what that means is that no no air
inside of that grow tent is just gonna
leak out of like the zipper
or a hole or whatever as long as you
have negative pressure in the grow tent
all of the air that leaves the grow tent
goes through the filter first
now if you remove that negative pressure
so you're
i'm no longer exhausting the air out of
my tent
i'm just you know scrubbing the air
inside of the tent i've got the filter
on the ground i've got the fan on the
filter
it's just scrubbing the air inside um
air is going to
smelly air is going to leak out through
your zipper through your ports through
through whatever hospitals
actually use negative pressure rooms for
patients and basically anybody who who
may have some sort of
uh airborne illness or something
you know they put them in a they put
them in a
negative pressure room that way the
virus doesn't you know accidentally
creep out of the bottom of the door of
that room
the airflow is constantly creating a
vacuum in the room
you know so i think it's kind of cool
how negative pressure is used
in uh you know a hospital environment to
to protect from
uh you know pathogens and stuff
infecting humans
and it's also used in the growing world
to prevent
odors from just leaking out wherever
they feel like
so it's a lesson in negative pressure
interesting that's good stuff okay so i
think it pretty much wraps
everything up our in talk about
environment we talked about temperature
humidity co2 air circulation this isn't
everything you need to know about those
things these are just kind of a
discussion that we're having uh
you know what we do for those different
things to control those those pieces of
the environment
and uh i think it's beneficial since you
know we live in different climates
so talking about these things definitely
there's some things that i didn't know
that you do which is
this is awesome and i'm not sure if you
knew that everything that i had talked
about as far as controlling environment
in in the desert region so it depends on
which inv
which climate you live in always you
know feel free to make adjustments as
necessary in order to
get your environment's conditions into
the ideal ranges yeah and uh if anyone
really if anyone has any different you
know way that they deal with humidity
temperature
everything tell us in the comments um
you know this isn't the be
all end-all these aren't the be-all
end-all ways to uh
control your environment and i'm sure
there's things that we miss and stuff so
please comment in the description let us
know like if we're wrong or if there's a
better way or a different way to do
something
um definitely want to hear it and um
you know don't forget to subscribe to my
man mr girl's page too
his channel here yeah that's what i was
just gonna say is i would love to know
how you control
uh your environment conditions everyone
who's watching this let me know down in
the comment section below let us know
i love reading through that and just
seeing that various ways
that what people do in order to make
things easier as far as controlling
their environments so
um slap that down in the comments
section below hit the thumbs up if you
haven't already
chris how do they find you on social
media
and your website and so on and so forth
so our website's happyhydro.com
uh we're on instagram at official happy
hydro
we're posting on there you know a couple
times a week and
we sell all sorts of different products
on the site
if you do go to our site through the
link in the description and buy
something
mr growit gets a commission um so you're
helping support him
um and you're helping us uh
we are you know our goal is to just try
to
build a company that can get you your
products for a good price quickly
accurately
and you know give you an enjoyable
experience along the way
i've dealt personally with a ton of
companies that
are drop shipping and you order it and
you don't know
when it's coming and uh
i don't know we're trying to do things
different differently and make
people's you know shopping experience
better and
stuff like that so come check us out
make sense i'll have links down in the
description section below
chris thank you so much for coming on
today and talking about environment
thanks for having me man you know i'm
always nervous to do public speaking
things usually because i'm too lit but
i appreciate you bringing me on and we
should definitely do this again
awesome all right have a good one
youtube brother
thank you so much for watching this
video click the video on the left
to hear about grow room setup with baby
j from the grill 420 diaries
and the video on the right is
automatically generated by the youtube
algorithm
until next time peace