at what week of flower do you pollinate
your females for best seed results so I
learned from sub cool around day 28 is
what he had mentioned and I've just been
doing that really anywhere between day
20 to 35 is a rough range where people
like to another thing that people say is
that only ate the plant when it looks
horny when you see those uh those
pistols stigmas they're really bursting
up from all directions that's when you
hit it with the pollination so but
usually it's around day 28 is when I'm
going in there and pollinating the
female plants and then of course I'm
just letting that plant grow and grow
and grow all the way up as far as I can
because uh really I'm not harvesting for
flour so oftentimes they're going past
the Harvest window so I can get more
seed development out of it there have
been some plants where it just looks
cannibalized towards the end there
because I'm just pushing it to try to
get more seeds out of it and seeds will
be dropping for sure you know when you
push them plate that long that's been
pollinated seeds start dropping off of
the evil diode man I really like the Evo
diode I mean it's Samsung's newest
release right for diode so the lm301h
Evo diode 3.14 micro moles per Joule so
that's awesome I know there's some
companies that have included them in
their fixtures I did want to mention
that Mars Hydro actually is including
them now in their FC series big shout
out to Mars how to they're actually
sponsoring this q a video so the FC 3000
Evo they've got the FC 8000
fc1000w FC 6500 and fc4800 all have the
Evo diodes from Samsung in there and
they're actually doing a sale right now
14 off all of the items on their website
so um actually use coupon code Mr row it
use my coupon code Mr Grow it helps me
gives me some some credit there and the
sale is running from the 14th to the
27th so I want to jump on it now and uh
save some moolah I'll have a link in the
description section below what do you do
when you get clawing and toxicity and
organic living soil grow I think that's
a really good question what I normally
do is just continue to water in I don't
do any type of flushing I haven't been
in a situation where I needed to but I
felt like I needed to flush an organic
soil right soil with just organic
amendments in there I've just been kind
of doing watering and then letting the
plant kind of work itself out of it you
know if I need to keep a plant in the
vegetation stage a little bit longer
then that's what I do before flipping
the flour but yeah I have got come
across that where you get some a little
bit darker of leaves shiny clawing clear
sign of nitrogen toxicity and uh yeah I
just continue to kind of just feed plain
water only and then eventually that
plant kind of bounces out of it right it
depletes the nutrients within the medium
the Amendments have you know broken down
plants of uptaking those nutrients and
you start to see it kind of bounce back
and be fine from there so that's what
I've done I know there are other Rose
out there who just they flush they go
right to Flushing they go and run a ton
of water through the medium in order to
flush out and kind of start back from
scratch but I personally haven't done
that what are your thoughts on 1212 from
C never heard much about it I've done it
so I've done it a couple different times
I've done it in a Solo Cup and uh one
thing to know about 12 12 that I think a
lot of people have misconceptions on is
if you are planting a seed seed Sprouts
on the medium right day one it's getting
12 12 light cycle it's still gonna spend
some time in the vegetation stage it's
not going to go right to shooting on
pistols and start flowering and have
barely any growth right it's gonna spend
the first 20-ish days in the veg stage
before you start seeing pistol I believe
it was 21 days is when I first started
seeing pistols on a plant that I just
gave 12 12 right off the bat so you get
some veg period then of course it starts
to flower so yeah you can totally do
that some people do that in order to
save on energy consumption and so people
do that on the sog technique sea of
green so if they're just doing that one
Cola coming up but a bunch of different
plants they'll just hit it with a FL 12
12 right off the bat it'll grow up you
know 8 10 12 inches so just keep that
one Cola and then it'll start flowering
and then they'll have a whole bunch of
just single Cola SOG technique so
there's a couple different reasons for
why you would potentially do it I've
just been sticking with the 18 6 for the
veg and then 12 12 for flour because I
do like to have that control over the
veg period I mean veg the plants for as
long as I want to get the plant shaped
the way I want to then kind of flip it
to flower but uh yeah 12 12. that is
definitely a thing that people do for a
couple different reasons can you please
explain what power should be run at seed
veg and flour and the height this is all
dependent on what grow light you're
using so grow lights are all not created
equal there's some folks that have a
grow light where they're dimming it down
and they're getting super close to their
plants other folks are putting on a full
blast having the light all the way up at
the top of the tent and then just
keeping on that setting the entire time
and then the plant kind of grow into it
a couple different ways you can go about
it some people are going to say that hey
if you're keeping a full blast all the
time especially with just seedlings
you're wasting energy so Some people
prefer to kind of bring it down and then
dim it down but it's really impossible
to give you an a blanket answer on what
power should be run at the seed veg and
flower cycle a different way to go about
it would be DLI a lot of people go after
in between 40 and 60 DLI so if you're
tracking DLI that is said to be kind of
one of the more accurate ways in
determining how much light your plant
should get on a daily basis the other
thing would be par let people look at
the ppfd numbers they have a par meter
and they'll look if you do have a
parameter although they are very
expensive it can be useful I have one
I'm looking at giving 200 to 400 ppfd in
seedling or clones even mother plants
I'm just going to keep them growing slow
400 to 600 ppfd for plants on the
vegetation stage and then 600 to 900
ppfd in the flowering stage if
supplementing CO2 a lot of people going
a little bit higher than that so um so
yeah that's kind of the best answer I
can give you for for that question it's
really dependent on what grow light
you're using on what power you can put
it at what height you can put it at for
the different stages of growth it's my
first harvest I've dried some larf and
then some of it comes out smelling
really good and some of it smells like a
plant or in 65 temp 60 humidity so my
actual question is when you hang dry how
long does it take for the plant to smell
to go away it's it'll take a little bit
right yeah that fresh plant Harvest
smell that you get certainly you can
have that in the drying phase for sure
once you get into curing so once you've
you've dried for in between four and ten
days some people are longer than that
actually uh I'm planning a video talking
about drying and curing with some a
bunch of studies that have been come out
pretty recently here but ideal drying
time according to latest studies is
anywhere between four and I think it's
12 days of drying if you go longer if
you do an extended dry micro growth is a
concern but uh 6560 that should be fine
and you'll see once you get into curing
and you start burping those jars and
having that off gas thing happen within
the matter of weeks you'll see the true
smell start to come out from there I
have taken cuts for the first time 14
days ago on Wednesday I have some that
rooted bothers that have not in your
opinion how long should I let the ones
that have not rooted ride in the dome
and what should I do about the ones that
don't take thanks good question I am
assuming that you're going straight into
the medium so maybe you're cutting a
clone and putting directly into soil or
directly into cocoa and then assume
that's kind of what you're using since
you didn't mention any other type of
method I've been through that same exact
bang to where I've got cloned put them
in the soil and then they didn't take
root one of the things that for me I
found is the actual temperature of the
soil so I made the mistake a long time
ago of having kind of I suppose winter
time number one so a little bit strong a
little bit harder to keep the root Zone
temperature up but utilizing a heat map
so I'm not sure if you use utilizing a
heat mat or not but that might be what
is causing it not to root either that or
lack of oxygen in the root Zone maybe
the roots don't maybe the soil is too
moist it's just not getting that oxygen
that needs maybe drainage on the
containers I don't know if you're using
like Solo cups for example I used to
just slice the Solo cups I wish I had a
picture here to kind of show you but
just kind of slices versus taking out a
big amount of the bottom of the Solo
cups drastic difference you know now
that there's better drainage better air
getting down in there so those are the
things that I would check out if I were
you because those are kind of the main
reasons I've come across for things not
rooting when uh cloning and just putting
it directly into soil or cocoa have you
tried curing in Grove bags yes I have I
put them in the Grove bags eat sealed
them and put them into a wine fridge
okay so that's what I used for curing I
actually put a little hygrometer on
there I did Hold Steady at the 62
percent that's kind of what I was aiming
for it held steady there didn't have any
mold but I was just using a really for
curing I know some people are using it
for drying as well I think I haven't
used it for drying though the problem
with where I live is it's very hot here
right now it's uh well geez in here it's
about 78 degrees usually anywhere
between 75 78 degrees Fahrenheit that's
not great for storage and I spent many
many years just storing in room
temperature and uh month two months
later buds just planned you know the
flavors uh depleted it's uh volatized
it's it's gone so so I've storage
temperature has kind of been something
that I've been more focusing on between
the Canada troll using that for storage
that's good to get the temperature down
and also the wine fridge some people put
in refrigerators I've had to put in
refrigerators as well that's down to
about 40 degrees Fahrenheit so all those
are things that I've tried to kind of
stored temperature for curing curing
slash storage but the grill bags worked
pretty good you know I don't have any
complaints on them use them for a very
short period of time I will tell you
that though you just keep in the fridge
what temperature are you storing at on
the regular usually about 60 60 degrees
Fahrenheit is what I have my wine fridge
set to I have the uh I had the Canon
troll set to it and then I bumped I've
been playing around with a little bit
between 60 and 65 and to be honest with
you I haven't noticed a whole lot of uh
difference between 60 and 65 as far as
storage temperature fridge yeah like I
mentioned goes down to about 40 degrees
it actually varies between
um for me for the way I have my fresh
sat at everybody you know there's a dial
where you can adjust it but my range is
between I think 34 and 40 degrees
Fahrenheit just kind of what that range
is but uh yeah sometimes when I have to
when I when I'm drying in my canister I
got to put it elsewhere some of it fits
in the wine fridge Last Resort is the
actual regular bridge better than room
temperature that's for sure have you
tried the bottled organic nutrients
having some success with the bio and
outline yes I have I use Bloom yellow
bottles oh and by the way in regards to
answering questions about products yeah
if people ask them I will answer them I
know at least a q a video on my channel
and there was a lot of the questions had
to do with products and somebody in the
comment section it was a couple people I
think comment section like hey why are
you just talking about products all the
time what is this an infomercial it's
like I'm just answering questions here
if you got questions about products I'll
answer them you know so but this episode
actually has been a lot of plant
questions so those people won't be as
much of keyboard Warriors as I'm sure
but Bloom yellow bottles yeah I use them
that line I had some good results in but
there's just so many bottles in that
line that was just a major turn off for
me it was just the amount of bottles
there and it's very expensive although
it's a very concentrated line so you
don't have to use much there's just
there's a lot of bottles and it adds up
very quickly so yeah I had pretty good
luck with that I haven't used any other
bottle organic nutrients what can I use
for silica other than rice holes and
Bottles good question I mean
diatomaceous earth is some silicon they
have I don't know how many people use it
as an amendment for silica stash blend
this got it right Shameless plug stash
blinds got some silica in there so you
could pick up a bag of stash blend and
then it's powdered form so longer shelf
life than liquid mix it up into water
and then soil drench and yeah and get
silica that way but yeah rice Halls kind
of bottled forms or seemed to be the
most popular forms of silica trying to
think of other amendments off top my
head let me know in the comments what am
I missing I'm missing something on air
what kind of pots do you use I've been
using the 10 gallon fabric pots I used a
living soil fabric pots by Grassroots
fabric pots they actually have a
discount code Mr Grow it if you get
anything off of them but they're the
fabric Parts with the liner in the
middle there so living soil you know
when you're growing organically out in
nature the soil doesn't dry out from all
angles like it does with the normal
fabric pot right so they have the liner
in their fabric pots so it just really
dries out from the top down there is
some fabric on the bottom part where you
can get some drying up from the bottom
there as well a little bit but that
actually adds aeration in there so I've
been using the 10 gallon pots from them
and I like them for that I was using
seven gallon plastic I mean I'm using so
much over the years five gallon three
gallon but over the past three four
years ish pots have been getting bigger
and I've been growing organic what is
the best way to lower PPM when you using
GH well you could just do a lower dosage
so when you're mixing up your nutrients
in water you can instead of doing a full
dose according to the feeding schedule
some people do a half dose quarter dose
so on and so forth if you gotten to the
point where you've actually added in the
nutrients already mixed them up and then
put the TDS tester in there to see the
PPM or our EC meter cdec we realize it
was too high and you're like oh no I
don't want this to be this strong a lot
of people just dilute they'll just add
in water dilute that mix down to their
desired EC or PPM before watering in so
not sure if you thought of that but uh I
think it was worth mentioning you feel
like you water more in fabric yes yeah
absolutely for me I mean I'm just
straight fabric pots not talking about
the Grassroots living soil pots that I
mentioned earlier for sure it definitely
dries out at all angles and I'm watering
more often there's more aeration you
know so it's it's normal I live in a
very dry climate it's 35 percent RH here
right now in this room and so I'm always
adding in humidity with the humidifier
for example but yeah definitely watering
more in fabric that's one of the reasons
why I've opted if you've seen a lot of
my videos over the recent years it's
using a lot of plastic using plastic
pots I like to be able to wash them out
and reuse them too you know I mean I
know you can do that with the fabric you
can wash those out and reuse them and
stuff but uh plastic pots of I'm working
fine for me so I kind of I haven't
really been using fabric pots besides
the living soil pots that I mentioned
best way to lower PPM week three of veg
runoff at 1800. how does the plants look
plants look okay just water for a while
water only for a little while until you
get the PPM where you want it but 1800
isn't too crazy so people go upwards of
2000 PPM assuming you're talking about
the 500 scale TDS tester when you talk
about the PPM that's more common unless
you're in Europe I know a lot of folks
do the 700 scale but just water you know
water for the future times the medium
needs it and then you'll see that it'll
eventually lower or down now if your
plants are struggling that's a different
story right A lot of people that blame
they'll flush you know so I'm not sure
if using synthetic organic inputs that
would uh make a difference there as well
[Music]
foreign