coming up on garden talk
a lot of people they talk about and i'm
one of those people is the harvest
tastes green right it just doesn't taste
natural why is that when you're pumping
your plant with the wrong nitrogen and
it's producing excess leaf or growing
too fast and your harvest comes out bad
well it's because what the plant is
doing right is producing more amino
acids for growth and not the proper
amino acids or peptides or proteins for
flowering or flavor manganese what it's
like how much manganese do we use and
why why is it responsible for over 300
enzyme coenzyme reactions why are we not
making it more significant right if
people are on well water well water for
some reason always has a lot of sodium
throwing sulfur in your soil it's going
to help regulate your ph i'm just blown
away by that right just one molecule
it turns the ether into reality where
you can touch it and i i'm fascinated
with that
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden dog
podcast this episode number 28. in this
episode i interview mark bellwell mark
is the owner of perfect gardens which is
an online hydroponics store that has
been in operation since 2009. he also
has a youtube channel where he uploads
science-based horticultural videos to
his audience of over 25 000 subscribers
in this episode he talks about some of
the essential nutrients for plants he
also touches upon what deficiencies and
toxicities look like for those nutrients
and he created a full presentation with
pictures for you to follow along a link
to the presentation is in the youtube
description section so if you're tuning
in on one of the podcast platforms i
recommend heading on for the youtube so
you can access the presentation link big
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast or patreon if you'd like to
support you could do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's podcast to help make that goal
possible thanks to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro
products are now available in several
countries across the world for those of
you that don't know dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that has base
nutrients additives and ph regulators
they have different formulas of base
nutrients for if you're in soil or if
you're in hydro or cocoa they also
formulate their base nutrients for if
you're using hard water or if using ro
or soft water i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products spider farmer
is a sponsor of the podcast coupon code
mr growit5 will get you a discount on
their products they're most known for
their led grow lights but they also have
other products such as grow tents inline
fans and carbon filters i've used their
sf 1000 sf 2000 and sf 4000 led grill
lights in the past and i got some great
results with them i will leave a link to
spider farmers amazon store down in the
description section below and don't
forget to use coupon code mr grow at 5
for discount on their products
big shout out to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast ac infiniti is
well known to produce high quality
products and provide excellent customer
service they have the thickest grow tent
on the market today
in line fans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
growit during checkout for a discount on
their products
alright now let's get into the episode
and we are back
welcome to the garden talk podcast today
i'm joined with mark baltwell from
perfect gardens how are you today hey
brother how are you doing today i just
want to say thank you so much for
letting me on the channel i love all
your content and i appreciate this
opportunity yeah thanks for coming on
man you have been requested by multiple
people
and uh you know when i went to your
channel like i knew about your channel
probably about probably about six months
ago i think or something like that is
when i first found out about your
channel you've been on uh youtube for a
long time longer than that and you have
some really detailed videos with
you get into like a lot of science so
i thought you'd be a great person to
have on the podcast and uh we're going
to go over the essential elements for
plants today not all of them you know
there's a lot of them so we'll touch on
a good amount of them today and then
maybe maybe if the audience requests it
we can do a part two with the remaining
elements mark did a full presentation
it's basically there's 41 slides
41 slides and that's what we're going
over right now if you're on youtube just
go to the description section it's it'll
be the second link down i'll put mark's
channel link first then i'll put the
link to the presentation if you're on
apple podcasts spotify
any of the podcast platforms i highly
recommend that you go to youtube and
click on this presentation and kind of
follow along with us because one of the
things in here as we get deeper into it
start talking about some of the elements
there are pictures pictures of what
deficiencies look like toxicities
and so on and so forth so but first can
you introduce yourself kind of let us
know a little bit about you and how you
got into gardening
sure absolutely just before i start i
just want to encourage people to go down
to the description and grab the link i i
just like how just like how chris said i
created a presentation with tons of
pictures tons of things that you could
follow along with and in the future i
will expand this presentation to
other other plants so you'll be able to
do craft cross references with lots of
other plants
and not just be specific to one
okay so just want to get into family
history because in some level i think
it's super important
anyways to okay so georges bowell
created the irs our family hired the
first four thousand employees and worked
with abraham lincoln himself
we created the tracking system to
track the debt to pay
to pay back the centralized baking
system with the greenbacks so
moving on with that
my mother and father marquinida bowell
they were migrant farm workers they
developed the systems and processes for
harvesting packaging and distribution of
lettuce in monterey county from
1977 to 1989 production went from 1400
pounds an hour to over 65 000 pounds an
hour in only 12 years
the significant thing about that is the
farmers prior to this point couldn't get
past 1400 pounds and we're talking like
a 70 to 100 year span and they were
maxed out and their thought process was
why why try to grow more if they can't
harvest it and sell it
so
in addition to that a lot of the reason
why we use chlorine on food to extend
shelf life is because my father
um it's also the reason why our family
through many conversations we've
acknowledged
mineral deficiencies and people overall
because of what chlorine does through
the microbiology on plants so i think a
lot of this presentation is going to go
into the depth around
science because it talks a lot about how
all these things connect
after the uh during the 40-year family
span we also
at one point wore 35 million dollars
through construction flipping
fixing and flipping long-term rentals
from 89 to 2007.
uh we opened up a family loan office and
wrote over three billion dollars in
loans to home homeowners from 2003 to
2007.
at this point i joined the military to
12th para rescue in 2005 after dropping
out of college and this is where it
ended up really taking a twist and and
us
you know going heavy deep into uh the
other types of industries we actually
lost 34.75 million dollars in the real
estate crash in 2007-2008
we used the last bit of wealth to open
up perfect gardens in 2009
at the same time we started operated and
got busted the largest indoor grow
facility in the state of california from
2009 to 2012.
total operation expanded to a thousand
plus lights
the mushroom farm is what we called it
plus we rotate it through between 35 and
70 miner operations averaging six to 20
lights per operation
and a grow coach each and every one of
these people until stands were met
consistently
after that i started a
half acre grow from december 2013 to
harvested approximately five thousand
pounds before being shut down
then went on to develop a new industrial
water extraction method for large-scale
large-scale
extraction thousand-plus acres
i only went into the research and
prototype phase got shut from
2014-2018 and then we completed the
largest uh hemp biomass transaction in
the united states in 2018 that was 800
000 pounds from oregon to colorado it
was 39 million deal followed up by a
two-year lawsuit for unpaid commissions
so as you can
as you can tell we've had successes and
failures what i can say is our failures
have led to other successes so don't
give up want to get into perfect garnish
real quick our vision is can a farmer i
think canada farmers are going to solve
our world's ag problems our mission here
at perfect gardens is we help you grow
our values as integrity putting the
shopping cart back every time
sustainability doing our due diligence
and
being present one problem one solution
at a time just for food for thought for
everyone think about who's growing and
who's farming right now we have grandmas
grandpas community gardens can of
farmers and then large-scale
corporations
they grow 98 of the food and they they
encompass only two percent of the
population those average farmers that
own all that land is
their ages between 60 and 70 and their
one heart attack away from dying
i think the most unique thing about the
county industry is that we have created
a very inexpensive way of testing the
quality of these plants through testing
the terpene profiles and i think by
cross referencing these
terpene profiles we'll be able to
examine our
ad growing practices and hopefully scale
up healthier growing practices as the
canada farmers take over the land in the
next 10 to 15 years as obviously the
industry collapses so you have a real
long family history here
real extensive and it goes way way back
i mean you started 1862 and there's a
lot of successes in there some major
numbers and even included some loss you
know that that tragic loss you had
with the real estate crash but again you
had mentioned that you know you had
successes and failures you just got to
keep on going right and after that big
failure that you had in 2007-2008 i mean
it looks like it even
you had even a greater success right so
taking a step one step back two steps
forward type scenarios so that's really
cool it's really interesting and um you
know congrats on all your success so far
with that and and perfect gardens right
i went to that website there it's a nice
website you get a lot going on there so
yeah thanks for that introduction um
let's continue on i know the next thing
up that you want to kind of talk about
here that's on your presentation is the
law of minimum so you want to get into
that a little bit absolutely so there's
two laws that i think are being
overlooked dramatically and a big ag all
the way down is the law of minimum first
one law minimum states that the growth
is dictated not by the total resources
available but by the scarcest resource
and i'll give you an example let's say
you have all the minerals the best
lights best sun but you're not watering
your plants
well at that point that's the scarcest
resource in your plants die
that goes along the same with trace
minerals macro minerals light
temperature humidity everything so
that being said
mark twain said whiskey is for drinking
water is for fighting just to give
another example if i may um please you
know
co2 is one of those things you could
have your environment dialed in
proper temperature humidity everything
could be you know properly watered it
could have the proper nutrition the
lighting could be dialed in right but if
your co2 level is low your plant's just
going to operate at that level and
that's really the law minimum right and
again another example would be you could
have everything dialed in with
the co2 but say you you don't have vpd
dialed in for example right the
temperature humidity the the leaf
surface temperature it'll operate at
that that lower level so
yeah that's uh that's something that we
don't talk about a lot much at all
really so i'm glad you covered that how
about the larv tolerance absolutely so
the law of tolerance and just to talk
exactly what you're saying too i think
it's because everyone's trying to sell
something right and so they're trying to
market their thing as being the best
thing versus encompassing everything as
a whole and as an ecosystem so let's get
into a lot of tolerance exactly what
you're saying so the law of tolerance
states that the laws
a law stating that the abundance and or
distribution of an organism can be
controlled by certain factors where
levels of these exceed the maximum or
minimum limits of tolerance of that
organism
so
in the extremes
absolute minimum or too much you have
zones of intolerance then because these
plants are so all plants are amazing
they they want to grow they'll do
everything in their power to produce i
mean i mean just don't water a plant for
a week and then come back and water it
you'll have it it'll probably come back
believe it or not
then you have your your zone of
your tolerance range right where you're
you know you might just be kind of
paying attention watering every so often
and then you have your optimum range
where you're you're carrying about
everything drip irrigation your
microbiology you're caring about your
lights everything you're saying and
that's your optimum range the visual
that you have here is is is perfect it
provides a
great visual ph i think is one that i
kind of want to highlight and talk about
for a second i mean it shows like an
optimum range
for ph so you know generally speaking i
think a lot of people what they go by
for soil ph for example for the plant
that we all know and love is for soil ph
you're often said in between 6.0 and 7.0
ph now that might be the optimum range
right but
oftentimes they'll get growers that say
oh my ph is i'm in soil in my ph is 5.8
or my ph is 5.7 i'm like well how does
your plant look plant looks fine well
that just goes into your tolerance range
right so that lower ph maybe 5.5 for
example down as low as 5.5 is in your
tolerance range now you probably won't
get optimum nutrient uptake there could
be some issues with slow growth
potentially and so on and so forth
but having an optimum range and then
that tolerance range
um yeah i think this this paints a great
picture for a lot of folks and i see
temperatures in there as well it's the
same thing so yeah i'm glad you put this
in here as well i think you gave great
examples actually i mean so thank you on
that i appreciate it how about the next
yeah
sorry sorry
okay so the next slide the next slide i
think is absolutely incredible it it if
you and just to describe it it's a it's
a circle and it has tons of minerals and
not all of them it's just another a few
of them and then what i'm doing is i'm
showing how all these different minerals
correlate right and so
this is the first time where i want to
use some terminology where i think this
many industries are throwing things out
trying to confuse people from marketing
and to just capitalize on the roi and
that's fine but i i want to you know
bring you behind the veil in the sense
so every single time different minerals
work together that becomes a coenzyme
production situation i'm going to show
you that in science so i just every
single time when i say bacterias make
coenzymes
so so when i say that
or i say aids in activating coenzymes
think of this chart because it's gonna
it's gonna explain oh wow okay so
you know these minerals all these
minerals work together you know so i'm
only when you flip your bottle back you
know be in the back and you look at it
you know you only have mpk or you only
have a couple macro minerals think about
this chart because what are you missing
going into what you're just saying um
mobile and immobile nutrients so at this
point this next chart if if you didn't
want to listen to the rest of this this
this podcast which i highly recommend do
so to geek out on it but if you if you
don't want to this chart this next one
is going to really just break it down
for you and make it super simple simple
to identify your problems or narrow it
down to what it most likely is so
there's three things i want you to
absolutely remember
immobile
mobile and semi-mobile so immobile
nutrients will if there's a deficiency
or excess it's going to appear in the
newer leaves and so why is that right so
immobile nutrients is when the plant
needs nutrients at one specific time and
won't need it anymore so if it doesn't
have it while it's growing or producing
it's going to show up as immobile
nutrient because it doesn't have what it
needs at that one point
to grow properly mobile nutrient shows
up in the
in the older leaves
first why because the plant can rob that
nutrients from the older leaves and take
it to the newer leaves to do its newer
function growing flowering producing
whatever that looks like semi-mobile is
nutrients can actually show up in the
older or newer and sometimes it's
finicky sometimes it's going to
matter on the ph it's going and it's
going to adjust so just know that
semi-mobile nutrients can show up in the
older or newer and as we go further down
through the pictures i'm going to show
you very
clear like once i show you the picture
you're gonna be like oh okay i've seen
this you know just because we've all
seen it it just you you have to
you and there's so many so many
deficiencies that look similar because
there's secondary deficiencies
underlying it that you it's difficult to
really identify and when you when you
see over a million plants and a number
of different different plants from just
just one you see a whole bunch of them
you see this deficiency it becomes oh
it's really clear okay this is what it
looks like so
let's go ahead and get into it well one
thing i want to mention before we move
on is
this chart right here i mean it breaks
it down between primary nutrients
secondary nutrients macronutrients it
has the
symbol there and then i assume that
third column correct me if i'm wrong
mobile or immobile so for nitrogen yes
as mobile right or is mobile yes or no
right yes so yeah for example
and i'm sure we're going to go on this
uh on once we talk about nitrogen but
nitrogen is a good example i think a lot
of beginners would
would
come across a nitrogen deficiency and
realize that the bottom part of the
plant the leaves are going to start to
turn yellow from the tips moving up and
what's happening is it's a mobile
nutrient that's being relocated to the
new growth but yeah i won't jump too
ahead i'll let you keep on going on
there
no you're perfect exactly how you're
describing i don't want to like you said
if if we stop at a certain point we'll
come back to a part two and you know i
think the most important thing is just
coming into that awareness part of
yourself where you're exactly what
you're feeling you're like okay it's
starting in the in the old growth and
it's turning yellow so the and and look
at where it's starting at the leave and
you're starting to really realize oh wow
you know it's it's robby and you're
taking it you're starting to identify
how it's showing up whether it's showing
up on the tip or it's showing up right
where the the stem meets the the leaf
because all these things will show small
characteristics of what's what's
happening within the plant and like they
say it's like like an animal whisperer
right but you become a plant whisperer
and it's just because you're you're
seeing these commonalities so thank you
for actually pointing that out
that's very helpful actually so next
slide two ways to fix uh fix most of
problems okay so we're gonna keep it
simple again rest again most of the
slide is about geeking out this the how
to solve my problem is that's what most
people are concerned about two ways
flush a plant ph it and restart or which
most people don't talk about is balance
the minerals and that goes into play at
the law minimum and the law of tolerance
okay so let's dive into the first one
nitrogen
and i want to talk about the nitrogen
cycle because i and this one it breaks
down the chemistry really well but i
want you to use this as a as a mental
template as we talk about calcium
magnesium phosphorus and all these other
ones because
there are many different chemical
manufacturers out there that
make other types of chemicals
and and then they mark it as nitrogen or
phosphorus or whatever so i'm going to
show you right here by science how
science uses nitrogen how how it changes
the molecular structure and then i'm
going to show you how there are other
nitrogens that come up in this industry
or other big ag industries
and why are they putting that nitrogen
in there when there's when there's the
natural nitrogens that are fertilizer
that they can synthesize and sell
that are just as available and
relatively close to the same price
and i don't know why they do it but it
is what it is
all right so the nitrogen cycle
so there are five parts of the nitrogen
cycle there's a nitrogen fixation a
stimulation a modification nitrification
and denitrification so nitrogen fixation
is basically when the nitrogen gas and
let's say electricity bulge or
electricity fires off ends up
a turning um ends up electrifying
nitrogen and turns it into nitrogen
dioxide so it goes from in n2 to no2
okay so then when that's electrified it
combines to water and then becomes a
nitric acid so nho3
and so that entire process is nitrogen
nitrogen fixation so then when it comes
down to the ground the plants can
actually take up the nitric acid that's
why things uh things turn green right
after if you're and and all that stuff
people know what i'm talking about when
i when if they watch the
mountains or the fields after a rain so
that nitrogen acid though when the
bacterias get ahold of it the bacterias
will begin to convert it over into
ammonia and so ammonia is in h3
okay and then as it gets assimilated
into the plant and the bacteria can
continue to keep converting it turns
into ammonia ammonium was which is nh4
plus
and then as the plants take take it up
and die or animals die
the fungi actually hold on to the
ammonia and convert it into nitrites and
nitrates and
slowly release it back into the
environment so as the plants take it up
it's assimilation as the plants die
it's a modification and as the fungi
hold on to it and and slowly release it
back into the environment it's
nitrification and then as
the
force is burned down or or evaporation
happens then that is denitrification so
these things go back up into the
environment so that's the complete cycle
and so correct me if i'm wrong but you
pretty much explain to here is that the
the plant can uptake multiple forms of
nitrogen and that's one thing that's
kind of unique about nitrogen from my
understanding so the the nh4 plus
i think you explain that they're able to
uptake and then the no3 minus the
nitrate is what they're able to uptake
is that correct to my understanding
they're actually able to take up three
of them
and this
this is what the this is what the
fertilizer industry tries to replace
uh for this process so it replaces tries
to replace the fungi and bacteria
because the fungi bacteria do the
conversion the enzyme the coenzyme um
reaction process or cation or
anions and we're going to get into that
later the the terminology of this stuff
but basically the fungi and bacteria do
these conversions and so what science
does is it removes the fungi and
bacteria
conversion it does it does it for us and
you you'll actually see right over here
and i'll go into the next slide before i
go into these the other nitrogens that
this the industry uses so let's just go
real quick into nitrogen what is
nitrogen because i think it's described
isn't described properly so nitrogen is
the building blocks of amino acids
peptides and proteins so amino acids
peptides and proteins are mainly i mean
are made of organic compounds so what
are organic compounds right organic
compounds are carbon hydrogen oxygen
nitrogen and sulfur
those things are i think become really
interesting for me at this point because
because in science in science for human
beings and plants there's actually a
disconnection of what are what are when
when amino acids become peptides and
when peptides become proteins and so for
for me i've had to do
to um create my own terminology or my
own definition basically and so amino
acids
are basically within one to ten you know
individual acids and when they when they
come together they
more they will become peptides
and so those those are
creations of again
carbon hydrogen oxygen nitrogen and
sulfur but then when they be combined to
a mineral that's when they become a
protein and so that's my definition
that's something that reading all these
different things and all that all that
stuff i i feel like when it be binds to
the minerals that's when it actually
becomes a protein
so in the nitrogen cycle there are seven
chemical structures uh structures
nitrogen goes through and we talked
about that n2 no2 in h03
in h3
in h4 plus in
o3 negative and
nh2 negative my question is why does the
ag industry use four plus nitrogens
outside of the natural
natural nitrogen cycle you know so they
they're putting stuff like ammonium
nitrate
ammonia nitrogen and urea and there and
a number of other different nitrogens in
other videos i show you a whole bunch of
different nitrogens and those are in h4
in
o3
in h3 negative n and co
in h32 to the second power so i'm not
going to do that every time but i'm what
i'm really just trying to show you guys
is that there are all these different
types of chemical structures and there's
natural chemical structures that nature
goes goes through that that the these
chemical companies can actually use
these or you can just go to the store
look in the back of the bottle and see
what the chemical structure is and if
they're not using the natural net
chemical structures put the bottle back
because it's only going to destroy the
microbiology let's so nitrogen nitrogen
is a mobile nutrient we already talked
about that so we won't get too heavily
into
the
into it but i do kind of want to explain
a little bit around excess right so if
you're giving too much nitrogen why is
that because they're using urea and so
what does nitrogen do it it's amino
acids peptides and and what it what does
amino acids and peptides are are meant
for they're meant for the growing part
of of these things so why so that's why
the stem will elongate and that's why
the stems will become weak and it's
actually the reason in many cases why we
sell this industry sell so much bamboo
and support equipment is because of the
chemical it's actually it's like solving
the problem because not being thoughtful
where the problem got started right and
so we start to create other solutions to
to minimize uh minimize that problem in
a sense we're talking about too much
nitrogen the plants get really dark
green i mean to the point where it's
fake and you you can tell i mean it just
doesn't look good and then a lot of
people they talk about and out and i'm
one of those people is the harvest
tastes green right it just doesn't taste
natural why is that is because those uh
in in the beginning they're using a
whole bunch of nitrogen and i'll show
you in the chemical structure the whole
bunch of nitrogen in initial amino acid
coenzyme process with the bacterias
where to to grow right but then when you
when you do when those nitrogens in
those organic compounds combine to the
trace minerals the smaller minerals
later they're used later in the plant
and so and they're using totally
different ratios so that's why when
you're pumping your plant with the wrong
nitrogen and it's producing excess leaf
or out growing too fast and your harvest
comes out bad well it's because
what the plant is doing right is
producing more amino acids for growth
and not for the proper amino acids or
peptides or proteins for flowering or
flavor and that's why a lot of people
are
they say they flush at the end of the
cycle and i don't know if i'm jumping
ahead here but like um
it kind of opens up a can of worms
because there's gonna be so many people
that say oh flushing is pointless and
then there's gonna be people that say
flushing is a must you know and i think
you hit the nail on the head here the
excess nitrogen and i did i know there's
been studies that came out and actually
did a video on a study that came out on
flushing and one of the things that i
had said as kind of my thoughts is that
i like to see that fade in the leaves i
like to i like to see that senescence um
you know because i i also felt like i've
had plants where it had excess nitrogen
and i did have that taste so i
personally do look for that fade to
happen now whether or not i have to
flush the plant it you know it depends
on if i'm seeing that fade or not but
yeah i'm glad you brought that up as far
as the harvesting tasting green to the
excess nitrogen because i personally
felt like i i've encountered that before
i actually love you brought the the
whole fleshing topic up for just a
second because
it's really funny right you have you
have a polar complex going in the
industry from flower to extracts right
so
and this is everything it's it's it
doesn't matter you know whether you're
in the sugar industry or whatever you
know it's about harvesting and then
packaging up as tight as possible to
sell it to the end consumer to be
reinfused into other products and and
sold even again
the the point to this is that
the flushing process
and i really loved what you what you do
with that because it actually helps me
even think a little bit more about it
and when and i and i don't know if you
thought about this part right so when
when you take the end product and take
it to the extraction team what what was
their issue with it right too much
chlorophyll in the extraction process
which made the extraction process much
more intensive to get to that end
product as well so when you are using
when you're flushing you're actually
starting the degradation process of the
plant earlier and and in addition that
the plant needs nitrogen up to the point
uh to the end of flower to keep doing
the amino acid reactions to to produce
terpenes so they're there and the damage
that was created through using the wrong
nitrogens in the beginning it's already
been done you know it's like the
relatively the product is going to i
want to say the products are going to be
bad it's just the product the the plants
didn't
have the right nitrogens to produce the
right coams and reactions with the other
trace minerals and and not enough time
was there to produce those other terpene
profiles right so you're kind of hitting
on both sides you're hitting it on the
on the on the nitrogen forcing it to
grow which you're getting more
starches and more of that and then
you're also hitting it where the the
plant doesn't have the other trace
mineral coenzyme reaction time to to get
to the point where it's capable of
producing the higher terpene profiles
super interesting for sure so we'll go
into the next one so a lot of people go
right into the npk mpk no i'm going into
the the building blocks of the plant so
the next one is the benefits of sulfur
sulfur is another organic compound a lot
of people are just going to say this
stuff you'll see the stuff on the
intersect and right here we're going to
explain it so the amino acid uh format
it helps with amino acid formation so
we're talking about those five organic
compounds needed for
amino acids and for peptides and then
when do they become a protein is when
it attaches itself to the other minerals
and i'll show you this a little bit
later
so enzyme and vitamin development we
already talked about that law minimum
law of tolerance so i think this is also
a big marketing thing everyone's saying
fulvic acid folic acid human gas and
human acid well fulvic and humidity acid
are normally composed of amino acids
bonded to sulfur
so that is getting behind the veil you
know so don't go don't get caught up and
and and where where this plays a part is
where
they
ex where where they got their raw
materials and when they where they did
their extraction that's where it makes a
good humanic or fulvic acid product is
where their their initial raw material
is is starting and their extraction
process so
sulfur helps complete incomplete in
incomplete chemical reactions uh whether
by nature so using meals like bone meal
blood meal or a synthetic chemical so if
you are
this this is where again if you have
growing outdoors and you amend your your
soil with a little bit of sulfur and
you're using a man-made
nitrate that sulfur is actually going to
help with the chemical reaction to
revert it back to a natural natural
nitrogen it just takes time and and time
is with short crops is is not good
sulfur lowers the ph and so uh
in soil so tip here if people are on
well water and well water for some
reason always has a lot of sodium or
anyone that is tapping into water with
high amounts of sodium throwing sulfur
in your soil it's going to help regulate
your ph sulfur is needed in seed
production and photosynthesis a
photosynthesis for the nitrogen fixation
right so this is now where it's getting
a little more complicated or complex in
the whole chemical reaction part this
comes into play when you balance the
sulfur and nitric acid equation
you end up needing a lot of nitric acid
to balance one molecule of sulfur
during this balancing the bacteria have
time to convert it from ammonia in h3 to
ammonium nitrogen in h4 plus
so
the amount of time it takes for
the nitric acid to become stable is the
same amount of time it takes for
your
bacteria to con to convert it so
a tip here this is where mycorrhizae
fungi are beneficial in soil to increase
sulfur sulfur content because fungi
holds onto sulfur waiting for rain that
is why you will see mushrooms right
after rain and is why your fungi colony
is so important it's a semi-mobile
nutrient so we'll look to the newer
later older growth
again go to the go to the presentation
you're going to see pictures that it's
almost impossible for me to describe uh
although you're the it's it's the lime
green is just so clear when you see it
um
that it's it's just going to pop out at
you so go to the slide
and check out the pictures it's one of
the best ways i can recommend to do so
what do you think about it yeah and and
you guys can thank susan for not
allowing us to post the pictures on
youtube she uh susan's the ceo of
youtube
it would get flagged and blah blah blah
so yeah these pictures you have on the
slide i mean pretty straightforward you
see it on the newer growth there the
yellowing it looks like it's coming from
kind of like the the stem there
upwards
to the tips
so you can clearly see yellow and then
the green on the tips one more
additional tall tale is
there there are three deficiencies that
have purple characteristics and sulfur
is one of those purple character one of
those deficiencies which creates a
purple characteristic in the stems
veining and the stems a lot of people
don't notice it
but it's one of those things where a lot
of people like hey do i get a purple
strain going yeah when they're actually
running into a deficiency purple stems i
mean that's that's a whole can of worms
there i know there's so many different
reasons why i heard nutrient balances
was another reason for that um but i
haven't heard that sulfur in particular
which that that's pretty interesting
well you just said it right there a
nutrient imbalance right and sulfur is a
does
compound uh organic compounds
amino acids and peptides to create uh
proteins which are later used
also cold temps is another thing if
i know when i
pull temps or if you like water the
plant with cold water like under i want
to say like roughly 65 degrees
fahrenheit or lower than that like
overnight like the next day you can see
like it's not just like a straight up
purple stem the entire stem but it's
kind of like streaks you'll see streaks
of purple so if you see the streaking at
all you can probably contribute to the
low temps or low water temp giving you
to it so figure that's worth mentioning
they're actually causing a plant
deficiency in that moment and um and
i'll explain that in one of the other
deficiency slides okay yeah it's really
funny you know when you i i was caught
up in the same thing right it's like oh
throw on the ice and i'm and then i'm
thinking like well we're growing way too
big i cannot recommend all my growers do
to to get all this ice and put on the
plants this is does not make sense and
then you start digging into the thought
process behind it and you're like oh
actually i'm creating a plant deficiency
right here and it goes into in
we'll go into another few minutes um
benefits of phosphorus so phosphorus
root growth flowering and seeds seeding
why
so photosynthesis collects the sun and
carbon dioxide to produce atp right so
adenosine triphosphate
plus oxygen atp will attach itself to
three phosphate groups to become a sugar
so right now we're talking about amino
acids peptides proteins and this is when
it becomes in my viewpoint a protein
so that science is a c10h16n5o13p3
and this is a coenzyme reaction people
might argue with me
on when i'm using this terminology
properly again i didn't go i didn't read
the books
i've
at all
i just i get curious and i start reading
lots of different people's perspectives
and then after you read thousands of
words you kind of formulate your own
thought process to it in a sense so
plants release the o2 and store
the energy in the form of sugars glucose
in the root system which later be
combined with amino acids to become aka
exodites so that's another
um terminology in the industry that i
think a lot of people use
although
it's not really understood the
connection right between photosynthesis
and when it becomes exciting that when
it becomes exadite is when that sugar
attach yourselves to other amino acids
which again become an exodite which
stimulates root growth and bacteria and
fungi development and it stores the
energy in the roots for night uh for
nighttime growth obviously nighttime
growth is optimal for plants to grow and
and roots are the storage the battery
for them in my my how i look at it
photosynthesis gets shut down
dramatically without phosphorus and we
explained why why atp and the
triphosphate groups and all that so
deficiencies phosphorus is actually
another one
that has purple characteristics
different from magnesium and sulfur so
those are the other three phosphorus
magnesium and sulfur have purple
characteristics and deficiencies
purple pigments in the leaves mixed with
with the green any time prior to the two
weeks of harvest this is like everything
is obviously i'm saying is not like
keystone these are these things where in
in my years of growing and grow coaching
i had to be able to go into a room very
quickly and identify the problem and get
out because i had to go to the next
operation to identify their problems and
go on and on so
i had to be able to see certain things
and and this was one thing so whenever i
see purple pigmentation two weeks from
harvest i was like this is too early for
autumn autumn situation to happened so i
would i would start to be like okay this
is this is kind of a
a towel that lets me
depict what type of a deficiency i'm
having this is caused by accumulation of
sugars that produce
anthocyanin uh followed by necro
necrosis of the leaves similar to
calcium deficiency although five times
worse it's a mobile nutrient so where do
you want to look for a mobile nutrient
bottom of the plant right older older of
the leaves older the leaves exactly
great job i'm trying i'm trying to you
know and if as i go through this i
encourage you to pause the video and
before i answer it put your answer in be
like i think it's this you know and and
and just go along with it just just who
cares if you're wrong
so phosphorus go ahead i was gonna say i
know with phosphorus deficiency i've
come across this multiple times it would
use the fox farm nutrient line up for
example and
and their lineup i know there's some
nutrient lineups that they come with
excess phosphorus and there's soil
scientists that say hey some of these
bottled lines they have excess
phosphorus in it and it's going to lock
it out in reality that nutrient formula
probably should just be changed so it
has less phosphorus so it doesn't lock
out for example or maybe maybe i'm wrong
maybe it wasn't an excess of phosphorus
that locked it out but maybe it was not
enough phosphorus and also i know that
there's some nutrients i don't have them
memorized but there's some nutrients
that lock out other nutrients
if there's an excess of them i'm not
sure if you cover that in this
presentation i don't have them memorized
i have a couple of them memorized but
not a lot of them but i know phosphorus
can get locked out due to excess of
other nutrients as well well we're going
back to that
the first two laws law minimum and law
of tolerance right there yeah i don't i
straight up guys i don't know all this
stuff i have to go back to my references
this is why i make notes like this so i
don't have to remember i nowadays don't
have the best memory probably because of
the medicine whatever but
but that's why i take really diligent
notes so i can go back share it with
someone else and they can they and we
have the confidence together that
that we're solving the problem together
and we we we can reference it in in
other ways because that's that's the the
situation with growing right is you have
a certain amount of time to do your best
to bring in that crop so it doesn't
matter about being the guy it matters
about some of the problem and bringing
in the harvest because some farms they
have a lot of micro micro economics
around them with with employees and
taxes and all that other stuff so it's
important that that crop comes in on
time and in line with your values great
point the
so this is the purple pigmentation right
and
that everyone's seen it it's it's so
clear and it looks like autumn it looks
like on but it's not and you and you
you'll notice it benefits a potassium
so aids in photosynthesis and food
formation
helps convert sugars into starches so
this is also another big thing so we we
talked about nitric acid plant takes it
up a little bit there then we talked
about the amino acids and we talked
about it converting into atp and sugar
but the plant actually only can use a
little bit of that sugar it actually has
to convert it into starches for later
use and we're talking about the
batteries in a sense so the starches are
stored in the root system for long-term
use
increases root growth and improves
drought tolerance by building cellulose
and reducing weak stem so when you put
your hands on the on the plant that's
cellulose okay and so so just like
anything
think about going over to the beach with
a really thin cooler
right you have a very thin cooler well
all the ice is going to melt fairly
quickly but you have a really nice
cooler that has a great insulation layer
well your ice is going to be in there
just about all day long
and you'll be able to feel you know
refreshed throughout the whole day and
that's the same thing with this plant by
building that dirt uh by the building
that building up the cellulose the
plant's able to
not evaporate as much as much water away
on hot days it maintains turbo pressure
reduces water loss and wilting so
trigger pressure is the pressure of the
water within the cells and
yeah so more water pressure and you know
it's going to fill up it's going to stay
in there versus once again being
evaporated away it increases protein
content of plants which are
organic compounds amino acids bonded
with minerals in water okay so with more
turgor pressure and and less uh water
being evaporated away the plants are the
the plants are going to have more time
for other coenzyme reactions right but
the plants constantly having to refill
up its tank
well it doesn't have enough it doesn't
have enough time to do more coherence
and reactions so this is that that that
process where that's what photos nasa
helps do this is why water the water
system is the blood transportation
system for more coenzyme production and
it's how potassium aids in activating at
least 60 other coenzymes being produced
so we go back to the law of minimum law
of tolerance that chart where you see
all the minerals working together right
well when you have water and time you
have time for that co-amazon reaction to
happen with more chromosome reactions
happening
the plant's able to achieve its true
potential helps stop the spread of crop
disease and nematodes while nematodes
come because of stagnated water right so
if you have more water retention and you
have more minerals in the water the
water is going to stay healthy and just
going to be able to fight off disease
potassium is a mobile nutrient so where
are you going to look for the mobile
nutrient
older leaves all right i love it okay so
i won't keep doing that to you i just
paused for a minute so the audience
could think about it oh okay i'll keep
doing it then i'll keep doing it then um
okay so the next one potassium oh this
is just so clear again we've seen this
so often it
kerosis starts on the upper half of the
leaf i it it is it happens over and over
and over and and all i want to do is
just take that one leaf off yeah like
get rid of that like i don't even want
to see that def i don't even want to see
that why is that one leaf dying right
but it's it's showing me signs of what
the rest of the crops going to grow
through and if i pay attention to that
one leaf i'm going to be saving myself
through deficiencies later through a
crop everyone's seen it go to the
presentation and see it once you see it
you're going to be like oh wow i have
probably have a potassium deficiency in
my in my grow room right now one thing i
do want to mention that relates to
potassium is it's
potassium one thing i do know is is we
talked about the relationship of
nutrients potassium and calcium are
antagonistic
and basically what that means in
simplified terms is they kind of work
against each other in a way i guess
that's the easiest way i can i can
explain it
and a scenario happens somebody post on
my forum mr growth.com forum if you
wanna ever wanna post pictures you grow
you have questions or whatever you can
head over there they had a calcium
deficiency
and one thing i had mentioned is hey
what part of he was in late flowering
and he started getting calcium
deficiency and i asked him what his
nutrient regimen was and he was loading
and he was pumping in a pk booster right
so phosphorus potassium so he actually
had an excess of potassium that caused
calcium deficiency
so that was super because he was he was
feeding calmag normally like he would
he's like why do i have a why do i have
a calcium deficiency if i'm feeding it
in it was because he had excess of
potassium so i thought that was worth
mentioning at this point
and write what you just said there too i
won't dive too much into it but that is
a question and something that brings is
brought up in the topics is like a lot
of people like oh should i not use
calcium magnesium uh toward the end of
flowering
right and so
to each is their own and mpk and that's
what we're discussing right the k and
the k is known for flowering and so
right there you're just saying the
potassium and the calcium are contradict
contraindicated in a sense at times so
and when is calcium used right calcium
is used what is calcium out we have we
didn't get into it but calcium is an
immobile nutrient so it's used in the
initial construction of the plant so as
you get into the flowering process why
do you need to construct more of the
plant at that point you need to allow
that that the other coenzymes to to take
place because at this point the immobile
nutrients you need other immobile
nutrients to start to start um doing
their job in the plant not the calcium
in a sense i was gonna say i wasn't
gonna get into it but then we got into
it so
um magnesium i think magnesium is i love
this topic i think this is one is where
it was when i when i finally got my head
around i was like
right it was just like okay i get it i
understand um so chlorophyll reduction
in the green blood okay so chlorophyll
production is the green blood of the
plant i always like to use certain
terminology that hopefully creates a a
connection to your soul in a sense right
so you have red red blood and then you
have green blood and that's the
chlorophyll so hopefully you you you
have a deeper connection in a sense
magnesium gives the green color
so the the center of the chlorophyll
molecule is magnesium
so let's jump over to the
uh to the magnesium molecule so we have
55 carbons so that's an organic compound
72 hydrogens another garnet compound
four nitrogens another organic compound
five oxygens and then one magnesium i'm
just blown away by that right just one
one molecule
it turns the ether into reality where
you can touch it and i i'm fascinated
with that okay and and
uh so anyways so so phosphorus mobility
so it talks about phosphorus mobility we
already talked about atp so this is also
where
an iron utilization we're going to get
into that seconds but
phosphorus mobility and iron utilization
goes into the law of minimum law of
tolerance again right where
when magnesium is able to do its job
with the chlorophyll the atp is able to
do is its function and then again we'll
get into iron a second fruiting and
maturing so
if you want to use a rock-based
magnesium supplement uh look for ling
lingtonite it's uh potassium sulfur and
magnesium
and look right this is how this is how
these minerals are combined together in
nature naturally that's where again i'm
fascinated with that right you have
these things in the in nature's like
okay this is what you need use it and
this is everything you need for this
stage
or you can use epsom salt which is
magnesium sulfate both of these will
actually still help uh help and
they will not interfere with your
microbiology okay if you get out and
we're talking about the different
chemical structures there's other
chemical structures the magnesium that
the chemical suppliers try to sell you
so again look to the back of the bottle
and look uh look at what type of epson
salt or magnesium is in there now and
look at magnesium edta that's that's a
new that's another chemical structure
for an example so magnesium is a mobile
nutrient so where are you going to look
for the the deficiency
older leaves i love it all right so it's
pretty magnesium actually shows up in
uh as a secondary deficiency quite often
i and times it it was actually difficult
to find a really great magnesium only
deficiency but i was able to find one
picture
you know it normally will show up with a
calcium deficiency or something and
that's or a sulfur deficiency and that's
why you'll have different products where
it's a mag sulfur magnesium calcium
product fused together the magnesium
sulfate can be used as a foliar i don't
think a lot of people know that so
it'll kind of hit your plant faster in a
sense if needed so if you are coming
across a mag deficiency consider
magnesium sulfate as a foliar feed
absolutely i love that any
you know that's where you get the we
were talking about
we were talking about earlier right what
is the most unique thing about the
canada industry right is the
is that we have developed an inexpensive
testing process to test the quality of
this product and we
are are
take time to actually go back to the
growers that are getting four percent
terpenes on the plant and ask them what
they did we're going to be able to
identify you know their growing
practices and how we should probably
start to implement those growing
practices into large-scale agriculture
because the chirping profiles
you only get to and i hate to use the
word only but i'm going to and you can
unsubscribe to my channel because i used
it whatever but
the only way you're going to get to the
highest four percent terpenes and above
that on the planet went through the
testing is with all your microbiology
going plain and simple that's my
viewpoint i
all the all the growers i've known that
i've gotten into the top 10 on the on
the on the testing on the
on the different types of competitions
out there when i've got an opportunity
to talk to them they were all in the
microbiology direction they weren't just
in the chemist so okay so let's go ahead
and get into iron iron is
for chlorophyll formation because of
ferrotoxins and fair toxins are iron
sulfate protein
a found or peptide whatever well this is
iron right so we're now talking about it
connected to a mineral and an organic
compound so we want to call it a protein
so iron sulfate protein found in the
chloroplast the site of photosynthesis
and you can look at the picture where
i'm showing
were is in the presentation ferrodoxins
also play a role when balancing the
nitrogen and the and reducing the sulfur
so then in the nitrogen fixation and
assimilation process is when iron and
sulfur uh sulfur come together so we're
a minimum law of tolerance again
when balancing the equation and
when balancing the equation it increases
oxygen because when you balance the
equation with sulfur and nitric acid the
final math it and i won't get into the
math but basically what it means is you
have one sulfur six hydrogen six
nitrogen and 18 oxygen molecules and
that's why your oxygen content will
increase when adding in iron so we're
talking about a trace mineral so if
you're making if you're making your your
if you're using like the vortex uh
thought process and you're agitating
your wa or just putting a bubbler there
and agitating your process well we're
talking about the oxygen carrying
capability of your water even and so uh
by having the proper trace minerals in
your water which i'm always talking
about a product called drops of balance
it's an alk it's it has 34 plus trace
minerals and it's the foundation of
sulfur of how all the minerals are
placed and makes it water soluble but
going back to
the slide cell division and growth is
because of chlorophyll and this is why i
consider iron the father and sulfur the
mother is because you have cell division
which is you know production and then
you have growth which is the nurturing
process this is how i'm able i try to
remember the minerals and how i create a
a healthier relationship with my plants
and the you know the minerals that i'm
using to feed my plants and then one day
feed my body tip bone meal is a great
source of nitrogen and iron for soil
growing because the bone because the
blood cells are the exact same chemical
makeup of chlorophyll except the center
molecule is iron so it's 55 carbons 72
hydrogens four nitrogens five oxygens
and one iron molecule and that's why
bone meal
has has iron supplement iron it comes up
and shows up as a at times as a sulfur
deficiency and it looks at it other how
i would encourage you to look uh look is
at the tips of the leaves you'll at
times you'll see green in between the
yellowing as well and once again go to
the powerpoint presentation you're going
to see a really great example and you're
going to see
within the leaf there's spottiness right
you're going to see some really nice
green and then you're going to see the
yellowing and it's not going to be like
a nice flow of lime green um once again
go to the go to it you'll see what i
mean you see it you'll be able to
identify it from that point on one thing
to mention that i want to add
particularly for new growers that don't
know this is new growth is gonna start
as yellow and it's gonna turn to green
so oftentimes and i get this a lot with
beginners
they will their lights will just come on
for the day and then they'll open up
their tent and they'll look and they'll
see oh i got a iron deficiency or i have
a sulfur deficiency because it looks
kind of similar to where there's
yellowing starting at the base and then
going up towards the tip so they think
that they have some sort of deficiency
when really like an hour or two hours
later all of a sudden the leaf is green
there so new growth like overnight for
example when your lights are off it's
not producing that chlorophyll to make
the the leaves green and it just takes a
couple hours for that to happen but if
you just turn on your lights and you see
what looks to be an iron deficiency just
remember that new growth is starts out
as yellow and it should turn to green
within a couple hours or so and again we
go we
i love that you said that right it's
because
the plants growing faster than what
than than what it can produce on other
coenzyme production
right so that's and because iron is a
semi-mobile nutrient it's able to keep
moving and keep to the newer growth as
as as it grows and that's exactly what
you're describing right here so i love
it calcium
calcium
okay so benefits of calcium formation of
cell wall and and cell membrane build
soil structure when you use
bill it builds soil structure when you
use sea shells or bone meal uh see and
just to elude uh give more
marketing it's either sea shell you if
you're using sea shells uh limestone
diotination earth those are all the same
exact thing okay chalk there's just
different marketing names to settlement
under different industries and yes
there's some binders and different look
to the process the how they're
processing their their material that's
that's the key to getting a great a
great source of material of anything
this feeds the microbes which holds the
soil together
calcium nitrate is a
is a synthesized chemical that i
actually would be fine using it's nho3
and if you go back to the nitrogen um if
you go back to and you see where it's
dry from it is limestone derived from
nitric acid okay so limestone i'm good
with nitric acid is the is the acid in
the
natural nitrogen cycle so i would use
calcium nitrate and there's actually a
brands i'm going to recommend in this
into this
video that have been very thoughtful
around this they even if they're using
synthetic fertilizer they're actually
using fertilizer only in the natural
um pathway that microbiology converts
their stuff into so give you another
example calcium gluconate
is a synthetized chemical will not feed
microbes and in fact we'll shut them
down
so that calcium if you that type of
calcium is actually in a number of
bottles and that you that you buy on
your shelf and i'm not going to slander
slander some of the brands right now but
um i want to so uh
critical for activating certain enzymes
law minimum law of tolerance tip use
dolomite lime for soil to help prevent
calcium deficiency
calcium is an immobile nutrient so look
to the
newer leaves and to identify
deficiencies in excess calcium we've all
seen it it's it's yellow uh yellowish
brown irregular spots uh and you're
you're going to see it as a like again
as the plant is growing you're right is
because it's immobile nutrient it needs
that as
the plant is growing and
it needs it dramatically less later into
flowering it's like what we talked about
earlier the thing with the calcium is it
again it goes back to strong cell walls
right
if you come across calcium deficiency
and flowering you're gonna get some
floppage right you're gonna the plant's
gonna be flopping over especially if
it's got those big flowers on there uh i
it's happened to me before and it's not
fun oh excuse me it's not fun to uh try
to get them up for support so calcium is
super important uh just going along with
what you're saying like i i grow coach
clients literally all over the world
that they this is all they got this is
all they you know it's for some reason
this is what they buy and i don't want
them to go buy more stuff and i and when
i look to the back of the balls and look
at the the nitrogen they're using
whether it's your urea or whatever this
is when i would highly encourage them to
make sure to be adding in the calcium
because that plant is going to be
growing quickly and they need the other
fertilizers to to do those other
functions that they're growing or like
we said they're going to get weak stems
or whatever so as i'm as in grow
coaching people it doesn't matter really
what they're how they're growing i
always encourage them to go to the
microbiology direction but they don't
i'm also tailoring them on their base
nutrients how they're growing and other
additives to use at certain times for
very specific reasons on on because of
the chemicals they're using great point
so benefits of magnesium and this this
is where i i get incredibly fascinated
right so as i go through these slides
you're going to see that the enzyme
coenzyme reactions start increasing more
and more and more but
it's
manganese what it's like how much
manganese do we use and why why is it
responsible for over 300 enzyme coenzyme
reactions
why are we not making it more
significant right and this is again how
we get to the the higher health or
potential of these plants is because as
we get more into the trace minerals like
all the foundation of the plant if you
notice it is is created for is to
transport the trace minerals so why are
we not putting more energy into what the
plant is actually asking for almost the
entire time so magnesium manganese aids
in more than 300 enzymes
that regulate the human body and plants
law minimum of tolerance without
manganese chlorophyll cannot capture
sun energy for photosynthesis
capturing light
what is light light is harmonic
frequencies so magnesium is the receiver
so plants are listening to music all day
long proof plants like music just a
correction manganese you said manganese
oh thank you i i do that all the time i
always switch these stupid yeah
if i do that again we are on manganese
not magnesium
plants uh interpret the music they are
listening to by the trace minerals
activated with co-enzymes designed with
the dna rna code that are stored in the
leaves
now i'm going to repeat this one more
time because i think this is so
incredibly important you know light
light when light hits the leaves it
creates a prism right and and when it
reflects off what is that harmonic
frequency and and and minerals are
minerals are gemstones they are they are
they are the prism that the light
reflects through and if your plant
doesn't have
all the trace minerals that are you're
capable of providing to the plant that
prism is going to be isn't isn't going
to be a full spectrum in my viewpoint
and the ana and and the
the light intensity and all the
different types of light that come off
the sun is crazy intense like we only
see this like tiny tiny little little
speck of spectrum of that that we can
see when blight when when the sun is
actually like
uh let me go back it's like that big you
know what i mean and
and we only see this little about a
little mount and so i'm always thinking
you know with all these trace minerals
is the is is the plant capable of
capturing all these other a number of
other light spectrums that
that the sun emits because the sun
wouldn't emit those those spectrums onto
our earth
if it wasn't for a purpose you know i'm
not trying to get in religion or in that
stuff but i do
in some level think that we're in this
divine
system that is created for us and
everything has a purpose and every
single time someone tries to to dismiss
us or dismiss our our reason for being
as just being random i don't even want
to talk to that person
so
whatever
um not whatever but you know my point
moving on
i i wonder what phosphorus and this is
my point to this right is i wonder what
phosphorus and calcium sound like to
microbes trace minerals actually play a
larger role when uh when we are
than what we are led to believe
i don't know if you've ever talked about
a moto's work on water and holding
energy no i haven't the modus work on
water is all about capturing the energy
that that we emit off of our bodies when
we're saying love or we're saying hate
and the energy and the water actually
has the ability to capture that energy
and what he does is he he he says this
words or he plays certain music right
when the water is going to the freezing
point and then he looks at the water
underneath the microscope and he's shown
over the last two decades all the the
different uh crystalline structures that
the water forms through different energy
we emit off of it and not to go too far
into his uh to our ancient history
um but you know the waterways in india
all throughout the world actually uh in
the strong structures where they're
having water going through all these
pathways a lot of these angel structures
actually have words like love or
appreciation going through their
waterways which
is very interesting to me
so
minerals are electrons protons and
neutrons can we admit that can we agree
to that yep
okay so buddha said we can experience
108 human characteristics
characteristics being emotions
emotions are energy my hypothesis is
that there is one mineral associated
with every human emotion we're capable
of interpreting on this human plane so
my theory is that there is a 108 total
or organic compound slash minerals
and our
and as our technology gets more
sensitive we'll be able to discover them
and right now we're roughly around the
90 range
so going back to manganese so manganese
is an immobile nutrient so look to the
newer leaves for deficiencies in excess
and manganese one of the best ways i
think it is it very often i think people
will be like oh i'm dealing with the
calcium deficiency but the
the it's different like the spots appear
different on the leaf than a calcium
deficiency in my viewpoint it's just
it's just a slight
i don't know it's just slightly
different and when you look at the
picture you're gonna see exactly what i
mean and you're like oh yeah i noticed
that i know exactly what it is it's
definitely mistaken a lot for calcium
deficiency that is for sure i've come
across manganese deficiency just a small
handful of times to be honest
one time in particular that i can
remember as being cocoa and my ph was a
little bit too high and you know we have
those ph ranges where nutrients are
uptaken at different ph ranges and it
was just out of that range and so i saw
a manganese deficiency so yeah this
picture i think is pretty good you can
definitely looking at this you can kind
of see that there is a clear difference
between this and calcium deficiency
because uh yeah there's like a little
bit of yellowing in there as well right
mm-hmm and in just what you're saying
also i've actually noticed my uh this
deficiently come up more when using the
fox farmland i don't mean to slander it
but
again i grow coach i this this line is
around the world i've made at least 30
videos on fox farm and you can read all
the all the threads i got a couple
growers that wanted to use up their
nutrients ran into this issue so um that
being said let's move on all right
moving on to the next one which is
copper
benefits of copper so copper is a
metabolic catalyst and so it actually
helps speed things up because that's all
a catalyst is so it helps the catalyst
of photosynthesis and the respiratory
and that is why it increases sugars
i think this is where a lot of the
industry thinks that sugars
is in part it is part of it but they
think that they they they want to
provide sugars to increase the taste and
that's actually
not how you increase the taste when you
and when you add in more cane sugar and
other stuff you you're you're jacking up
your your your bacterias and you're
showing your down your your fungi and
that's also goes back into the lawn
mower tolerance this is actually how i
actually know if the nutrient line knows
what they're doing is when they're
increa when that when i see them saying
higher higher terps or something like
that and i turn to back a ball and they
have copper in there i'm like okay this
nutrient line kind of knows what they're
talking about because copper aids in in
enzyme production all bacterias are
capable of producing different coenzymes
for every mineral that exists in the
soil so you have billions of bacterias
millions of fungi and all those
bacterias can produce different
coenzymes what do copper enzymes do they
intensify color why because with more
minerals that become bioavailable more
of the music can be interpreted by the
plant involves improves flavor flavor
equals terpenes because with these
these specific cone designs your plant
can now produce a higher terpene profile
copper is a semi mobile nutrient so it's
going to appear in the newer before the
older and it's very distinguishable look
at the picture
i mean
you'll know you'll know what i mean and
this and this picture you they're even
going through a nitrogen deficiency with
it in my opinion because of how fake the
green is and even when you look at the
the flower development it is
underdeveloped and
and when and i'm probably looking at a
seven weaker right there yeah probably
nitrogen toxicity nitrogen toxicity
thank you okay
nitrogen deficiency yeah nitrogen
toxicity like you mentioned before the
dark green leaves i see that as well and
then you can see the outer edges
yellowing to the chlorosis there so yeah
exactly so we didn't cover all of the
essential nutrients here in this video i
definitely want to save it for a part
two
if the audience demands it if you demand
a part two audience uh we'd love to have
you comment in the
comment section below let us know you
want a part two because we've i think a
little bit less than half the amount of
the sensory nutrients we covered today
so we have we could really do a part two
and cover potentially the remaining
amount of essential nutrients so if you
want to want to part two let us know
down in the comment section below yeah
let's move on to uh what do you got next
okay just the solution to the problem
and this is the
one product i would actually
say it will be is a game changer i can
almost guarantee you will not find
another product like this in industry i
know you've heard that before yeah yeah
yeah
but i'm guarantee you you will probably
not find this this product out there
five thousand dollars have went into
verifying the science of what this
product does and it's called drops of
balance and so we'll go back to the law
minimum real quick it states that the
growth is dictated not by the total
resources available but by the scarcest
resource and we already gave the example
right you have all the minerals but you
don't have water your plants die
same thing goes with the trace minerals
of course we have the basics water light
all those other things so what is going
to create more coenzyme reactions even
if you're not using microbiology it goes
into the trace minerals the things that
people are not discussing because the
science isn't there really to to and the
technology isn't there i do to create
sensitive enough
technology to actually identify the
minerals and
and their compositions it's really
interesting the science actually is
we japan is 15 years 20 years ahead of
us on water science so drop the balance
drop balance is 34 plus negative ionic
trace minerals sulfated trace minerals
it cleans over 2500 plus man-made
chemicals so it reverts them back to man
sulfated minerals
and that's at at a four ml rate for
drinking water um i'm going to talk to
you guys clearly if you're gonna use
this for growing it's at a rate of one
ml per gallon so let me say it again for
growing is at a rate of one ml per
gallon so the 8 ounce bottle will be
good for 240 gallons of water
the 16 is for 480 and 32 ounces is good
for a thousand you need more than more
than that hit me up and yeah let's go
into the next one law of tolerance the
law stating that the abundance or
distribution of an orgasm can be
controlled by certain factors where if
levels of these exceed the maximum or
minimum limits of tolerance of that
organism once again going back over into
the the chart i circled the some just a
couple of the ones we covered today look
at all the the other ones we didn't and
and this is just a very small list of
the minerals that we could so we can
actually create a part two three four
this is where i want to put put a lot of
my energy next year into the proof
brands by perfect gardens is gaia green
i love their brand i love their
processing how they extract they're
thoughtful around what they do i like
their brand earth dust nectar of the
gods down to earth drops of balance npk
nutrients raw if you're in hydroponics
recharge extreme gardening they make a
great product on extreme gardening for
the azos and the mycos they're simple to
use throw it in and i've always got
great products off of them
anyways there's a few other lines that i
do like but for now
i think that's about everything awesome
well mark you were
really the first person in this podcast
to put together a presentation like this
this is phenomenal this is great a lot
of details we touched on so much i think
this is going to be a viewer favorite
for sure thank you for your efforts
there tell us where can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future well you can find me
definitely at youtube at
perfectgardens.com i really my goal is
to get to one grower at a time and see
their thoughts with see their mind with
healthy thoughts on growing practices so
i'm i'm really not putting my attention
to large scale anymore i think it's the
wrong direction of this industry and
where it's going and i think because of
the collapse and all the land that's
going to become available i think the
best place where i could put my time is
with a one-on-one basis
you can also find me on
perfectgardens.com uh where you can buy
some of the materials you don't have to
not necessary and also hit me up at
admin.com if you if you do want
consulting on a larger scale i do offer
it i just am very selective with the
corporations and where i put my energy
and time to also please
like share and subscribe that's super
helpful guys i have made 400 videos up
and a fourth of them
know even more than that are demonetized
but
i i genuinely enjoy giving away the free
information because i don't have to get
caught up on on on trying to sell stuff
to survive took the words out of my
mouth as far as liking it subscribing if
you haven't already i will leave a link
to mark's youtube channel down in the
description section below
and yeah if you're on apple podcast
spotify leave a rating or review we're
coming up to 100 ratings a review or
actually i think we just passed 100
ratings and reviews so thank you to
everyone who has left a rating in review
and don't forget to share this podcast
if you know somebody who would benefit
from this information
share it there has been a lot of people
are sharing on reddit lately thank you
for that facebook groups the forums
there's just so many places we can share
it and thank you to everyone who shares
this podcast mark once again thank you
for coming onto this podcast uh this is
something i'm going to be watching over
and over again
because the information here there's
just there's so much of it so
thanks and uh yeah hope you enjoy the
rest of your day thank you chris
appreciate you and have a great grow
everyone
[Music]
you