coming up on garden talk it has been
well documented that there are 92 maybe
more naturally occurring elements on
earth wherein 82 of which have been
found in plants
and then the plant says okay guys
if you just give me a tiny bit of nickel
and a little bit of biology i can turn
your trash that you're giving me into
something usable and we always try to
say it's it's twenty percent silt and
it's and it's ten percent clay and
that's all these things
all those things creates a magnetic
charge and if you have biology we talk
about your ec increasing because your
biology and your magnetic charge and
your magnet gets stronger and stronger
you'll even start to see the atherosin
as the purple starting to appear in the
leaves but what you're not going to see
is you'll see a huge reduction in in
essential oils
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 78. in this
episode i interview mark beltwell from
perfect gardens he has been on the
podcast once before episode number 28
and a countless number of you have
requested for him to come back for a
part two this time around he picks up
right where he left off talking about
some of the essential nutrients for
plants he also touches upon what
deficiencies and toxicities look like
for those nutrients thanks to all of you
who support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible ac infinity is sponsoring
this episode my entire ventilation
system is ac infiniti i have their
inline fan ducting and carbon filter i
love the controller with the temperature
and humidity programming and having
control of different fan speeds this
makes it so much easier to control my
grow environment and i can't wait for
the controller 69 wi-fi version which
also controls their oscillating fans and
grow lights you can use discount code mr
growit for any of their products on
their website ac acinfinity.com
or use discount code mr grow at 15 if
you're buying off amazon spider farmer
is sponsoring this episode coupon code
mr grow at 5 will get you a discount on
their products check out their se series
which are bar style led grow lights they
have the sc3000 a full bar fixture for a
three by three grow space the sc 5000 a
six bar fixture for a 4x4 grow space the
sc7000 an 8 bar fixture for a 5x5 grow
space in the sc 1000w a 10 bar fixture
for a 5x5 grow space check out the
website at spider-farmer.com
or search for them on amazon and don't
forget to use the discount code mr
growit5 for a discount on their products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with mark
from perfect gardens how you doing today
doing good brother thank you so much for
letting me come back on the channel for
part two and i just also wanted to say
thank you so much to your community for
for asking for part two
thanks for coming on uh this is your
second time on the podcast first time
was a big success you know lots of
people in the comment section demanding
for that part too so here we are part
two in the first episode we did together
you talked about some of the essential
nutrients for plants
and you also touch upon what
deficiencies and toxicities look like
for those nutrients we covered so many
of these elements nitrogen sulfur
phosphorus potassium magnesium iron
calcium manganese and copper so we got a
whole bunch done still a lot more to go
mark actually created a presentation for
this so if you'd like to follow along
i'll put a link to the presentation in
the description section below and if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
find this episode on youtube in order to
access the link to the presentation i'll
show what i can on the screen this time
but if there are any slides that youtube
might not like i'll leave those ones out
so let's continue where we left off
essential elements for plants part two
and i think you've snuck some
non-essential elements in there too so
i'm excited to see what you got in there
but yeah i'll let you roll on with the
presentation i know there's a little bit
of an introduction in there and stuff
which will help for those that didn't
catch the first episode we did together
so take it away
chris thank you so much and just like
you said if you haven't checked out the
part one highly recommend to do so on
this presentation we are going to talk
about a couple things we talked about in
part one the only reason why we're
talking about again though is because i
don't i didn't think i did a good enough
job um really going through it and
explain the significance so this time
around
we're going to do a much better job so
the title this is deficiencies
toxicities minerals and biology
presented by mr growit and perfect
gardens
like uh chris said if you're not
following along the description is down
below if you put your email in you're
going to get three things you're going
to get the presentation you're going to
get a free visual plant guide so
something you can actually um a lot of
times you you don't know the deficiency
name but you know what you're looking at
so what we did is we created a visual
plant guide so you can actually what
you're seeing you can reference it
scroll over and then see whether it's a
deficiency of toxicity and most likely
what it is in addition you're going to
receive a free audio book all about
minerals for plants and for the human
body
i want to do a special thanks to the
army of growers that helped make this
presentation what it is special thanks
to dave hansen ken
hayes mike emily emily actually helped
create the visual plant guide such as
special thanks to him as well av sai and
the rest of the team
so perfect gardens culture you've heard
me say this before our vision can of
farmers solving the world act problems
our mission is we are we are here to
help you grow our values our integrity
putting the shopping cart back every
time sustainability doing our due
diligence and being present one problem
one solution at a time we are an army of
growers
so what is perfect gardens perfect
gardens is an online retail store and a
growing community our mission is to help
you grow
one of those ways is by using testing
and teaching you about products that
will help create long-term regenerative
practices
we think that ninety percent of the
products sold in most guardian stores
are just there to have you repurchase it
the following year
throughout this presentation we'll be
talking about a few brands we support we
are not saying that you should purchase
these products we are saying that you
should look at the raw materials of what
these products are created from and then
start there
we hope that by guiding you to purchase
high quality products it will in one
part help fulfill our mission here at
perfect gardens which is to help you
grow
okay so we're going to talk about the
law minimum real quick one more time and
we're going to give some examples around
the law of minimum because i think by
giving these examples
in the beginning this presentation it
will make the rest of the minerals as we
go through them a lot more efficient and
easier to understand so the law minimum
states that growth is dictated not by
the total resources available but by the
scarcest resource today we'll be talking
about the five most limiting factors
that support enzyme production
eighty percent of the deficiencies
toxicities bugs mold low yield and
crappy quality are because of a lack of
enzymes
those five most limiting factors are one
carbon slash humic layer two
clean and consistent watering practices
three ionic sulfated minerals
four biology and five co2
okay so you've heard me say this before
the most unique thing about the canon
industry is the testing of our terpene
profiles
the reason why is because more terps
means higher overall plant health
we are talking about nutrient density
not just the weight of the yield in this
presentation we are going to be going
from academics to application
knowledge is not power it is the
application of knowledge that's power
and through this presentation i'm going
to be encouraging you to take more
action
the brands below are supported by us
because they help fix the five most
limiting factors
pit moss pit moss is a little fibrous
paper and it's your carbon is your
consistent watering is your water
conservation and it's the future home
for your microbes and minerals to
complete their enzyme production cycle
which is 24 hours we recommend to don't
don't start over five percent i start
with five percent of pit moss in your
total media and then slowly add in over
time drops of balance drop balance is 64
plus negative ionic sulfated minerals
plus it cleans over 400 separate
man-made chemicals out of your water
terraganix tarragon is specifically em-1
more than 80 separate bacteria colonies
we always recommend at indo fungi
there's lots of brands out there that
have endo fungi's we recommend either
recharge or or micos from extreme
gardening and then last but not least is
organic shield organic shield is a
complete ipm product that will take care
of any of your bikes in addition to this
though when it breaks down it breaks
down into water
co2 and sugar that being the fifth most
limiting factor
okay so you have seen this picture if
you have downloaded the presentation
before in this situation though i
actually added a few more things to help
give the visual representation between
the relationship between bacteria
minerals and enzymes so let's explain
this real fast
enzymes are responsible for breaking
apart and rewelding dna
rna
amino acids peptides and protein bonds
every enzyme needs enzyme cofactors
bacteria make enzyme cofactors
all enzyme cofactors are dependent upon
the amount of trace minerals in the
environment these enzymes can perform
their tasks hundreds of times before
degrading in the plant it has been well
documented that there are 92 maybe more
naturally occurring elements on earth
wherein the 82 of which have been found
in plants
so just you got to think about that for
a second
if plants took up those 82 separate
minerals then that means bacteria at
some point made them water soluble so
that the plant could take them up
and the plant wouldn't take it up if
there wasn't a purpose for them the next
slide real quick also talks a little bit
around visual around your dna rna
proteins amino acids and we're going to
explain real fast what this is your dna
is responsible for storing and
transferring genetic information
rna directly codes the amino acids and
acts as a messenger between dna and the
ribosomes which are large and complex
enzymes
to make proteins all interactions need
bacteria and cofactors
amino acids plus enzymes bond together
in two or three to make peptides
peptides plus enzymes bond together to
become complete proteins
all of this happens in a 24-hour cycle
and so the most important thing to
understand about this is that the
bacteria and the minerals need to stay
in the same spot with a consistent water
source for that enzyme reaction to
complete its job in that 24-hour cycle
and if one of these things goes out of
whack that production cycle has to
restart or it's incomplete okay so let's
talk about the law of tolerance let's
give a quick definition of what this is
a law stating that the abundance or
distribution of organism can be
controlled by certain factors where
levels of these exceed the maximum or
minimum limit of tolerance of that of
that orgasm so what does that mean
exactly well just like have we talked
about before there are zones of
intolerance and then there are the
tolerance range and then there's the
optimum range and so let's give some
examples so example is like ph if you
have a ph of 3 or a ph of 9 there's
probably in the zones of intolerance and
your plants are going to die fairly
quickly but if you have let's say a ph
of 5.6 and 7.3 that's more the zone the
tolerance range the plant's still going
to grow it's still going to do its job
but it's probably probably not going to
see the full potential
and if you are in that optimum range of
5.8 to let's say 6.6 where the majority
of the minerals are available well
that's going to be your optimum range
and you're probably going to see a
better potential of what that plant
could do
other examples are temperature if it's
too hot or it's too cold you can imagine
what happens starts to happen
deficiencies if your light intensity
your photons your dli your daily light
integral is too much so if you're giving
too little of light what's going to
happen to the plant right and if you
give too much light what it what's going
to happen the plant and the the plant
has has different expressions uh
throughout this so if the plants doesn't
have a lot of photosynthesis going we're
going to see it in a deficiency but if
it's too much light we're probably going
to see
a tacoing or or
the plant's going to say hey
listen it's a little too much light for
me
the last one i want to bring up is the
magnetic charge or the parts per million
or the ec
all these are really important to
understand around minerals and that's
what pretty much the rest of the
presentation is going to be about i
think one that i'd like to throw in
there relates to the temperature and
actually relative humidity would be vpd
a lot of people chase after vpd if you
don't know what that is google it check
out the vpd charts there's different
charts for
ceiling stage vegetative stage flowering
stage for example but it's basically at
a certain temperature what is the ideal
humidity that you should be at and on
the chart there's a dark green range
there's a lighter green range and then
there's a yellow or red range so i
thought that was a good example i
figured i'd throw out there i i love
that chris actually the reason why i
love that is because your your brain
headed to exactly where i was hoping it
would go uh right into vpd as being the
next example of how these all play out
so that was phenomenal i know that the
presentation's working
uh so
so magnets um and let's give an example
around the law of tolerance around
magnets and we're gonna play into right
right exactly what chris is talking
about temperature and bpd
so your magnets phosphorus is your
dominant macro negative
ion magnet calcium is your dominant
macronutrient positive cation magnet
when you balance your phosphorus all the
other negative ions can be balanced so
that means all the other trace minerals
that have a negative charge can be
balanced is phosphorus is balanced if if
calcium is balanced that means all the
other minerals that have a positive
charge that are smaller than calcium can
be balanced but when one of those that
is off remember we're talking about the
law of tolerance too much phosphorus too
much calcium all the rest starts to get
thrown off so now let's go into how how
does the magnets play into the
relationship around temperature and vpd
so as calcium gets warmer it gets
heavier and its positive charge gets
starts to get neutralized because of
additional negative electrons it
collects
when the leaf temperature is above 86
degrees fahrenheit plants will go from
photosynthesis to a respirative state
at this point calcium stops being taken
up by the xylem and the calcium already
taken up starts to settle into the
oldest growth of the plant until calcium
can gain back its full positive cation
charge
in addition it gets lighter calcium will
get lighter in density as it cools by
the losing of the electrons and new
calcium is able to flow all the way back
up the xylem attracting the negative
ions back up with it in addition you may
also see leaves deform in new growth
because your vpd is off so this is where
i'm trying to now relate to the language
of the of of where all of us are talking
about but i'm also connecting it with
the science right here
you may also see purple leaves purple
pedials and the fading from the bottom
up due to a lack of flow of calcium and
boron and this relationship to the speed
of atp production and the robbing of
phosphorus because it is a mobile
nutrient so what does that all mean
example right so when it gets too warm
the calcium stops flowing up the xylem
and it settles back down the plant but
the plant is still
doing atp production right atp is
adenosine
phosphate so how does it get neufon a
new phosphorus it robs it from the
bottom of the plant and takes it up so
that way if it gets too hot you may
start to see phosphorus deficiencies for
this reason because it's starting to
cannibalize itself to continue to keep
doing its job
calcium and phosphorus flow together
like a positive and negative magnet
until phosphorus and other
micronutrients are released and taken up
in the sap of the plant called the
phloem
so the xylem is the xylem is the
transportation of water minerals the
phloem is the sap where the chemical
reactions the enzymes do their job so in
between it and we've done a number of
videos showing on on that
that when you see the xylem and the
phloem the bacteria are traveling in
between them constantly and the reason
why is because they're they're the
intermediate between the xylem and the
phloem
all magnets minerals need to be present
in a 24-hour period to complete their
enzyme reaction in the cellular
construction temperature to optimize and
enzymatic activity is between
76 and 83 degrees fahrenheit
so all of you guys have seen this slide
the biggest thing to pull from here is
the question you need to ask yourself
when you see a deficiency and the
toxicity is the deficiency or toxicity
appearing in the older or newer growth
immobile nutrients shows their
deficiencies or excess in the newer
leaves mobile deficiencies show up as a
deficiency or excess in the older leaves
semi-semi-mobile
can show up in
in the older or newer leaves so just
understand that question if you
understand the question is where am i
seeing it you are able to eliminate
literally half your problems almost
immediately
okay
so now let's get into the first mineral
or really the continuation of the
minerals from part uh part one the the
reason why is once again is because when
you understand
the what i explained up top it's going
to make the language and everything i
read here it's going to be able to flow
in like you're just reading a the best
book you've ever read or the watch the
best movie you've ever seen
okay so zinc
aids in enzyme production that are
responsible for driving many metabolic
reactions in all crops growth and
development would stop if specific
enzymes were not present in plant tissue
carbohydrates proteins and chlorophyll
formation is reduced in enzyme deficient
plants
the significance of zinc stems from its
property as a divalent positive cation
magnet
which means that zinc ions can form two
chemical bonds with a with an ion
at ions are molecules that have a
negative magnetic charge
more trace minerals being present helps
the release of other minerals at a ion
exchange site when zinc is present it
helps release and hold two other
negative minerals so you kind of have to
think about this when you have a big
mineral it doesn't do a really good job
at holding on to those smaller tiny
minerals you actually need as you go
farther and farther down the smaller the
mineral you it needs to go
actually be able to hold on to those
smaller magnets
that's why
it's it it's important to understand
that this the bigger ones can't really
hold on to the smaller ones very well
so zinc is the zinc they you can also
call these things chelating agents right
they they there's another word that that
works in this in this expression of
trying to understand what i'm what i'm
trying to say here
zinc helps soil structure because it
increases the magnetic charge in the
attracting and the releasing of other
minerals
when smaller magnets are present it
creates a stronger magnet that is called
our humic layer it is why we have to
return what we take
and i hope that makes sense your humic
layer is just a composition of all these
magnets and we always try to say it's
it's 20 silt and it's and it's 10 clay
and it's all these things
all those things creates a magnetic
charge and if you have biology
we talk about your ec increasing because
your biology and your magnetic charge
and your magnet gets stronger and
stronger
zinc is an immobile nutrient so look to
the newer leaves first to identify a
deficiency in toxicity if you're
wondering zinc is found in drops of
balance and if you're over there on
drops of balance.com make sure to type
in mr growit
for additional discounts because all the
products that we're talking about today
are available on dropsbalance.com
also on perfect gardens as well okay so
the zinc
zinc i i tried to find a pitcher that
really represents a zinc deficiency
because um these these deficiency and
toxicities are going to appear in your
plant
specifically during certain times
because of the of the enzyme enzymatic
production that these minerals
specifically do during vegetative state
or flowering right
so i tried to find a picture that would
is actually going to you'll actually
most likely see
versus
providing too many pictures and the one
that really is going to pop out and you
see it you're going to be like okay
that's a zinc deficiency you're also
you're often going to see the stem tips
fail to elongate and grow and grow shoot
tips they become bunched up and you and
you'll you'll know what i mean it just
goes like
it goes like this and it's just it's
really the only mineral deficiency that
does that okay so the next one the
benefits of malignant
important in microbial nitrogen
assimilation part of the nitrogen
fixation cycle so due to the presence of
nitrogens the enzyme that performs the
into fixation to the nh3 ammonia
and the nitrate reductus the enzyme that
performs the first step in the nitrate
no3 negative so it turns the nitrate no3
negative to a nitrite no
two negative
so
just to kind of understand this right so
just malignant itself it helps use the
the gas
that's abundant in our air
to make it more available
for the plant okay so i find that to be
incredibly incredibly important
and then we talked about right these two
enzymes there are these two bacterias
create these enzymes
that allowed
malignant to to be utilized to its full
potential
so remember we're talking about what's
that most limiting factor is enzyme
production is also important to
potassium absorption because the same
bacteria that does the nitrogen fixation
also breaks down the potassium mineral
and makes them water soluble through the
cation exchange
so really understand the point here
right so if you have a couple bacteria
these few bacterias can soluble soluble
eyes make these minerals water soluble
and just and if you have one bacteria is
capable of producing
five ten hundreds of enzymes hundreds of
enzymes if you if there you just have
the right mineral in that environment
and we as we go into the the next few
slides i'll explain more about that
you normally will see a zinc deficiency
with mo because of the role they both
play in photosynthesis why should you
care about mo
well australia went from a wheat
importer to a wheat exporter in one year
just by adding malignant okay and if
you're wondering million yes is in drops
balance so so you got to understand this
okay malignant is used in
very very very tiny amounts if you use
too much it can get
your plants won't do well it will become
very toxic for the plants but just by
adding this very small amount an entire
country that had to import wheat the
very next year went to being able to
sell weight so if you're wondering
whether this trace mineral can increase
your return on investment
yes it can it can boost your internal
return investment because it's gonna it
can help boost your yield
malignant is a mobile nutrient so look
to the older lease first for your
deficiencies and toxicities
and so remember malignant
um
it's a mobile nutrient and the picture
once again i try to find it is it
represents
the plant when you see it a malignant
deficiency it'll look like the plant is
aging
but it's not maturing and what i mean by
that is when you see the plant you're
going to see the the like our plants
you'll see the pistols coming out you're
going to you're going to you're going to
think like the plants maturing like it's
getting ready to be harvested you'll
even start to see the atheroscine it's
the purple starting to appear in the in
the leaves but what you're not going to
see is you'll see a huge reduction in in
essential oils and that's what i mean
right the plants maturing or the plants
aging but it's not maturing
and that's and that's what i mean by the
difference so it's very distinguishable
when you see the malignant deficiency
you'll know exactly what i what i mean
me when i when you see this picture and
youtube isn't going to allow me to post
this picture so this is going to be one
that you're going to want to download
the presentation for just click on the
link to access the presentation for so
you can see it's very interesting
picture here one of the rarer ones is
this type of deficiency so once you see
it you might have come across it in the
past but it's it's very rare so there's
a good chance that you didn't come
across this chris is 100 right in our
group we we are have clients now
worldwide all in our membership group
and we must have seen a linkedin
deficiency maybe twice out of
i don't know four or five hundred uh
gross throughout the whole year so if
you think about that that was like
they probably grew two or three times in
the same spot so out of 1200 separate
grows we must have seen them electron
deficiently two two times so it's so
it's really just you're not going to
you you might you might not see it but
just understand that that trace mineral
if it's applied appropriately with the
right bacterias it can increase your
your yield and that's what's going to
happen with a lot of the rest of these
minerals that we talked about on this
presentation they're not going to appear
in your plant
whether it makes it green or
makes it tall or produces the flowers
it's
they appear in the plants differently
through the taste
the
the overall quality the terpene profiles
you you you see them
they they represent themselves in a in a
different level in a different
expression not just in the yield they
they represent themselves in another way
so benefits of manganese
magazine aids in more than 300 enzymes
that regulates the human body and plants
so we were talking about you have a
bacteria and you have manganese
it can produce 300 enzymes for you just
just
these two things that's that's huge and
those enzymes go on to do the function
hundreds of times before the plant
degrades it i find that to be incredibly
fascinating without manganese
chlorophyll cannot capture sun energy
for photosynthesis
we covered this in part presentation one
but i i wanted to bring it back up
because we're talking about enzymes and
this is what i'm what we're talking
about the most limiting factor in most
gardens is enzyme production
and what why is this so significant for
me and i always love to re re-say this
is
capturing light what is light light is
harmonic frequencies so magnesium is the
receiver so plants are are listening to
music all day long this is proof in my
opinion that plants do like music plants
interpret the music they are listened to
by the trace minerals and the microbes
that are present
when you have bacteria and manganese
they are capable of creating once again
over 300 enzymes
absolutely amazing
manganese is an immobile nutrient so
look to the newer leaves first to
identify deficiencies and toxicities in
trace amounts that's all we need
remember trace amounts so manganese so
we've seen this deficiency
probably no more than 10 times this year
so again this is not something you're
going to see a lot
and a lot of people
are going to see this uh and they might
think it's a calcium deficiency and
calcium and and manganese are actually
both immobile
nutrients so they're going to be being
used as the plants growing so they'll
actually appear
in at the same time if it's deficient so
it's so the big difference though is
calcium
deficiencies you could see holes in your
leaves or you could see a like um
like roses in the leaves like spots but
in this one you're gonna see more like
brown spots and it's different and if
you're if you download the presentation
you're going to be able to see
exactly what i'm describing once you see
it you'll be able to distinguish it 100
from calcium deficiency i've actually
come across this a handful of times and
i can't even count the number of times
somebody has commented on my forum for
example posted a picture like this and
thought it was calcium so they just
upped the cal mag and they're doing more
harm than good right because they're not
actually fixing the problem there so
this gets mixed up with calcium
deficiency so much and you know you
already said that but the yellowing that
kind of goes along in
with
like the the spotting
i think that's a major indicator that
it's actually manganese and not calcium
that is actually a great observation
chris and it's something it's so funny
it's it's not until someone points it
out but that you begin to notice it
yourself right i i fixated on that brown
for so so long that if
i think if i would have
presented it the way you just described
exactly the the yellowing that follows
along with it uh manganese 100 that's a
great way and it's like a random
yellowing it's not your typical yelling
that you'd see off of
magnesium deficiency where it's like the
intervenal corrosis it's like just
scattered and random on the leaf it's
super interesting
and when you go back to that the slide
right before it what does manganese do
right chlorophyll uh and we're we're
talking about that we're describing
the what the megan oil is doing if it's
deficient within the plant and we're
seeing it too and i love that that's
beautiful chris thanks for pointing that
out okay so benefits of boron this is i
love boron boron is the throttle to
sugar transportation and is responsible
for moving the energy into growing parts
of the plant plays a key role in
integrated pest management
boron also plays a key role in cell wall
formation and the functional integrity
of biological membranes
specifically helps move the energy in
the last three weeks of the plant's life
cycle so it moves that sugar
into the fruiting and pollination and
seed setting so
again if you want
really strong
long
lasting flavorful food nutritional dense
food where the where the flavor actually
lingers in your mouth and you your mouth
kind of waters
that's because there's boron because
it's shifting the the sugars it plays a
role in membrane metabolism and function
thereby being involved in enzyme
reaction as well as the transportation
for ions metabolites and hormones boron
is required in very small amounts it is
an immobile nutrient so look to the new
release to identify deficiencies and
toxicities
so with this picture i pre i presented
and chris just uh this
obviously this picture isn't going to be
available as well because we're showing
a can of picture make sure to download
the presentation but just to kind of
highlight what we were talking about a
little bit before do you when you see
this picture you're seeing the the rust
and the brown happening
in in the in the leaves but when you
look at the flower the flowers like
almost near maturity and you could tell
like you'll see the deficiency happen
almost when this
at the near end of flowering and why is
that right well it's because boron is
responsible for transferring those
sugars especially in those last three
weeks so you're going to see the the
expression of a deficiency more often
than a toxicity with boron and it's in
it's going to show up
when when the majority of the enzymatic
production is happening for that plant
for boron
i've actually never come across this
before it's
so rare a great picture by the way
really good picture there once i've seen
it like once personally in my in my
whole life too it's it's a very you
don't see it very much and it's because
these
these other minerals some of a lot of
these minerals
they they they like we were talking
about before there is essential minerals
and beneficial minerals right and these
beneficial minerals and i'll explain a
little bit more on the next slide as
well but beneficial minerals they can be
replaced by other minerals so they don't
they don't think they're absolutely
essential so if you have like the enough
of the right chemistry it these these
minerals can be interchangeable with
other with other ones and so that's why
they don't really appear as they don't
really appear much just because there's
enough chemistry to to do the function
it and but it's not the same thing but
it
it does what needs to do
okay so cobalt the cobalt is a
beneficial nutrient for single cell
organisms human beings and other mammals
but it has not been considered as the
essential micronutrient for plants does
that make any sense
instead this element along with other
elements like aluminum selenium
silicon titanium
has been considered as a beneficial
element for plants a beneficial element
can improve plant health status at low
concentrations
for the element to be considered an
essential
it it must be required by plants to
complete
its life cycle
must not be replaceable by other
elements and must
directly participate in plant metabolism
when you look at a definition it that
does make sense right when you when you
think about it like that it's like do
do i need this to produce leaves and
stem and the the seed or the fruit i'm
looking for
although
when you explain what they do it it you
begin to wonder why isn't it considered
a beneficial mineral so
cobalt inhibits the formation of
ethylene and delays
send essence uh senescence it basically
is slows aging so cobalt is a is an anti
anti-aging mineral basically
aging and maturing are different things
you you can still mature without aging
so aging is being brittle slow and weak
maturing is reaching your highest
potential and
all of us have seen it when you have
like this amazing grow
like
you at the very end even when the
athleticism is happening the purple and
the leaves are happening the plant still
looks like it can keep going
the that's because it's matured it
hasn't it hasn't really aged cobalt and
rhizosphere bacteria are responsible in
growing root tips and synthesizing
cytokines we pay a lot of money for
insect frass mushroom compost and kelp
why because of cytokines
cytokinins are plant hormones that
regulate plant growth and so much more
rhizobia and other nitrogen fixation
bacteria require
cobalt for fixing atmospheric
denitrification into ammonia
providing plants with a essential
macronutrient nitrogen
so i'm not a consumer conspiracy
theorist but this is starting to sound
like a conspiracy now listen to what i
just said a second ago cobalt is
required it is the one of the required
elements to to turn
the gas in the atmosphere into usable
nitrogen
so but they don't say it's an essential
mineral
like
but the chemists know this you know if
you really think about that if you could
add a trace mineral in so that you
wouldn't have to use another something
you have to purchase to keep more money
in your pocket but they call this a
beneficial mineral versus an essential
mineral
this is where i begin to think about
things differently
cobalt plays a vital role in the
integration with iron nickel and zinc
and maintaining cellular homeostasis
similar to other micronutrients plants
respond to cobalt concentrations in soil
at low concentrations it promotes plant
growth
but it causes photos toxicity at higher
concentrations so let's talk about
nickel another beneficial nutrient
nickel is used 10 times less than
malignant
nickel is a component for some plant
enzymes most notably
urease which metabolizes urea nitrogen
into usable ammonia within the plant
without nickel toxic levels of urea can
accumulate within the tissue forming
necrotic lesions in the leaves
so
again think about that for a second
right
there they sell
farmers urea perfectly knowing that the
plant can't take it up can't utilize it
and then the plant says okay guys
if you just give me a tiny bit of nickel
and a little bit of biology i can turn
your trash that you're giving me into
something usable
i find that to be incredibly interesting
i i realized that at that point bacteria
is capable of
of evolving in its current environment
even even though urea is a synthetic
fertilizer it's still capable of
processing it recent studies have shown
that nickel degrades a potent cytotoxin
compound naturally produced by cellular
metabolism which is produced during
stress and that would make sense right
you give it a urea what happens plants
stretch well
the nickel helps detox that as the the
plants going through rapid cellular
metal metabolism so if you are using
urea i would highly recommend to
use some type of foliar spray or
implement it in nickel and if you're
wondering nickels and drops of balance
it is
examining this role of nickel in the
relationship to stress suggests
that nickel may have a key participation
in plant antioxidant metabolism
so nickel basically helps detox a plant
and the picture i found here really just
shows it very well right if you are
giving too much nitrogen what happens
with the leaves it is dark green and
that's all these free radicals flowing
into the leaf well nick will helps detox
that into a healthier green
nickel is important for seed germination
so chris you you do your own chin eggs
right
nickel would be
so important for you if you do see
germination
nickel is also important for bacteria
and fungi nickel behaves a largely like
zinc in the soil plant system but it
forms strong chelates with with soil
organic matter thereby showing closeness
to copper
all because it has a divalent
and a trivalent property so remember
we're talking about a divalent can hold
on to two other smaller minerals or two
other minerals that have the opposite
charge well nickel doesn't just have a
divalent
property it also has a trivalent
property so it can hold on to three
other minerals but it's used ten times
less than malignant yet it can hold on
to three other things
i find that to be once again absolutely
fascinating
excess nickel also affects nutrient
absorption by roots impairs plant
metabolism inhibits photosynthesis and
transportation and may also show signs
of sucroses and or necrosis but that's
not always the case
flowers are often deformed under these
conditions
and for nickel deficiency seeds uh seeds
that i don't have nickel
normally won't pop they they're just
inviable and if they do pop the more
than likely you're not going to be able
to bring in a yield and again this is
just by a nickel deficiency
that's not a beneficial element it they
call it it's not an essential element
it's a beneficial element actually i
think it was
20 years ago or something was enacted as
an essential element
so it's the newest one yeah there's 17
essential elements nickel is the most
recent one which around 20 years ago i
believe it was added as an essential
element so i appreciate that thank you i
thank you so much for correcting me on
that i love i love it when people point
things out and i love learning so thanks
again regrets for that so
silicon it's a it's a beneficial element
right not essential now you got me going
non-chicken correct yeah yeah just
beneficial non-essential cool okay so
silicon and if i say
uh silicone
i don't i mean silicon i have like 20
years of construction behind me so
sometimes i say silicon
or silicone i mean anyways so silicon is
a beneficial non-mobile nutrient
microorganisms like burke holia or
batillus and other bacterias solidifies
different types of silica silicates
silicon benefits plants when under
stress
it improves drought tolerance and delays
wilting in crops enhances the ability to
resist micronutrients and other metal
toxicities like aluminum copper iron
manganese and zinc and etc so just kind
of point this out right there's a
mineral
within all the other minerals
because how do you how do you regulate
the trace minerals that they're so small
right well silicon if it's in an
environment will will hold on to the
excess trace minerals so they don't
become toxic to your environment
once again find that to be absolutely
amazing how perfect the world we live in
if we don't mess with it too much
silicon enhances growth and yield of all
annual vegetable crops promotes upright
growth stronger and thicker stems and
shorter internodes
provides resistance to bacterial and
fungal diseases
decreases some ana antibiotic stresses
as temperature
silica
which is different than silicon and
silicon is silica silica's processed
silicon
is often alkaline by nature because of
the pro of what it does to make it
soluble therefore naturally it's going
to increase the ph and so what you're
going to want to do if you're using a
liquid silica you're going to want to
add that first ph your your water and
then then add in your trace minerals
like drops of balance and then the rest
if you're wondering if silicon is in
drops balance it is and it's in an
acidic form not an alkaline form
silicon promotes light exposure and of
leaves and makes an enormous difference
in trichome production
trichomes are mostly silicon
trichomes play a role as a light wave
guide for the far infrared silicon
particles helps far infrared light
efficiently propagate inside the
trichomes and leaves
these properties are useful for
efficiently warming the plant since
absorption of far infrared lights is
converted to heat
this is due to the photonic bandage and
which the velocity of light slows
in other words silicon gives structure
to light as it enters and enhances the
reflection and absorption of light
therefore plants to form trichomes in
order to efficiently
capture far infrared light
which would be useful for for the
enhancement of photosynthesis
and if i didn't explain that well enough
just to kind of recap on this
light is fast and it's coming through
your your plant really fast if you have
silicon it will actually slow the light
down
capture it better and efficiently guide
it to where it needs to go
that's what silicon does and so i for me
i don't would i don't understand that
how you could ever be efficient with all
the lights that you're using with the in
repaint that reoccurring build like
wouldn't it be cooler if you captured
more of that light in your plant that's
it's that's what i think at least you
could do that with silicon i think
silicon is one of the most undervalued
nutrients
out there i mean you covered so many
benefits
one of the main ones is trichome
production if you look at i believe it's
an electron microscope and you look at a
trichome on a plant that wasn't
fed silica versus what was fed silica
you see a massive difference in just the
structure of the trichome alone a lot of
people don't know that and if you are
going to supplement silica a couple
things to know you want silicic acid or
orthosilicic acid those are the
bioavailable forms
silicon dioxide is not a bioavailable
form so let's forget to add those few
things in
all right i love that you brought that
up chris because if you want long-term
bag appeal with a great nose
you're going to use silicon right it's
being like what we talked about more
those trichomes are made mostly of
silicon so if they had more of that
structure when they're finished off do
you think they'll be able to retain
those terpenes and those oils a little
better versus breaking off or or
floating away this this so this is like
we all know this right it's like you
look at your buddies herb and you're
like how old is that and you're like a
year last year was a crop and like damn
how did it looks amazing right that's
because they're using the right
essential minerals to so that the plant
can do with the bacteria so that they
can produce the enzymes needed to do its
full potential and like i was saying
right they they call these essential
minerals versus beneficial but we're not
because we eat our food quickly and
because though things get thrown away
quickly and a lot of herbs we a lot of
people don't see the preservation of
herbs long term right and if you if we
if if you're taking care of of a crop
from one year versus the of let's say
you have two different crops and you see
you use one with bacteria that has the
right enzymes the versus the other one
that doesn't the one that the one the
the where you see the difference is a
year later where you're still able to
sell your crop versus the other one it's
already started to degrade and that and
you don't we don't acknowledge it
because it's not now
but if we but we are capable of seeing
it long term we do see the benefit and
these are because of different enzymatic
production different enzymes being
produced at different times
selenium
selenium is considered a beneficial
element for higher plants enhancing
antioxidant metabolism photosynthesis
secondary metabolites and carbohydrates
in plant leaves
at low concentration selenium enhances
photosynthesis in plants due to
increasing protection of light
harvesting proteins and photosynthesis
pigments called antani complex right and
we're talking about enzymes and proteins
right
you need all these things bacteria and
selenium are closely interlinked as the
element serves both essential nutrient
requirements and energy generation
functions
however selenium at high levels can be
toxic for bacterial homeostasis selenium
and nickel
help detox plant inflammation and that's
what we're talking about before free
radicals dark green is going to bring it
back to being a healthy grain
titanium titanium is a semi-mobile
beneficial element titanium applied via
roots or leaves at low concentrations
have been documented to improve crop
performance through stimulating the
activity of certain enzymes enhancing
chlorophyll content and photosynthesis
promoting nutrient uptake strengthening
stress tolerance and improving crop
yield and quality
it is considered a biostimulant for
improving crop production titanium's
role in plants lies in its interaction
with other trace nutrient elements
primarily iron iron and titanium have a
synergistic and antigonistic
relationship when plants experience
iron deficiencies titanium helps induce
the expression of genes related to iron
thereby enhancing iron's uptake and
utilization and improving plant growth
so let me explain this a little better
let's say we uh we have a tank of gas
and we hold 10 gallons we use up nine we
have one left and imagine you were
capable of pushing a button to make your
engine engine more sensitive so that one
gallon actually acted like 10 gallons of
gasoline
that's what titanium does it makes
everything more hypersensitive so if
there's a deficiency or there's not
enough in the environment it will make
it enough
i find that to be once again for soil
that's incredibly depleted i find
titanium should be a an essential
mineral versus a beneficial titanium if
you're wondering is also in drops of
balance the big question
how do i start applying this knowledge
today
we have to go from academics to
application i just shared all this
knowledge right
we have to we have to go we have to
remember that knowledge is not power it
is the application of knowledge that's
power so we go back to the five most
limiting factors that support enzyme
production
one your carbon and your humic layer in
your soil and so your carbon and your
humic layer is pit moss like i was
telling you it's these fibrous little
paper that acts as as a net that keeps
things in places because if you're using
cocoa or
or sphagnum peat moss all these things
the way they're processed kind of hold
differently and so when you put your
when you put in the the your nutrients a
lot of these nutrients was if using dry
metals will actually fall to the bottom
because they're not being captured very
well in the media so once again pip moss
is your carbon and it's your future home
for your microbes and minerals and why
is because the microbes and the minerals
need a full 24 hours for those those
minerals and those bacteria staying
undisturbed in that environment for 24
hours to do to create those enzymes
two you need clean and consistent
watering practices
so clean is what drops balance drops
balance cleans over 400 separate
separate man-made chemicals
in your consistent watering practices
well because of the pit moss remember no
more than five percent in your media to
start it's paper so it acts as a wicking
system throughout your entire media
helping to rebuild your humic layer so
once you get your compost compost going
and and reinmenting your soil
it it just helps start that process and
keeps things together
three ionic sulfate trace minerals
that's drops balance 64 plus ionic
sulfate trace minerals four your biology
tear organics it has 80 separate
bacteria colonies endo fungi we
recommend and support recharge or
extreme gardening they're mycos and then
last but not least is your co2 which is
organic shield obviously if you have a
bug problem you need something that's
going to kill the bugs immediately the
organic shield does that but when it
breaks down
into into having no residual it has
breaks down to water co2 and sugar which
is your fifth most limiting factor
okay so let's wrap this up in and
understand why is this significant right
well photosynthesis what do you actually
need
for photosynthesis to do their job to do
its job you need co2
water magnesium iron
manganese nitrogen zinc titanium silicon
nickel cobalt malignant sulfur and
bacteria
you have that your photosynthesis is
going to do its job and it's going to do
it to the best of its ability if you're
missing one of these things
i promise you you're not going to see
the full potential of the plants and how
you measure that is in the terpene
profiles at the end of your grow
let's go to the next most the next one
that you should really pay attention to
the first one was capturing the light
right the next one is your ipm your
integrated pest management because bugs
can really do damage and wouldn't it be
nice if you you have the ability to add
in the right things
bugs wouldn't be attracted to to your
plants because
the the leading reason why they think
bugs are actually attracted to plants is
because of excess enzymes
on those plants and why is that
well it's because bugs actually don't
have a
the ability to
produce enzymes they don't have their
own digestive enzymes so they actually
have to go rob them from another place
to do their job and that would make
sense right nature is trying to create a
situation for
to clean up its own mess
so how do you fix this well you fix this
by by giving the plant what it needs so
it can complete its 24 hour cycle of
their enzyme production so what do you
actually need
so your plants are less attractive well
you need magnesium you need sulfur you
need malignant you need boron you need
sugar
selenium and nickel and bacteria
all staying in the same spot for 24
hours
and if you did that there's a very good
chance you're probably never going to
have
a bug breakout you'll probably still
have some bugs
but for the most part they're they're
not going to be attracted to your crop
they'll be attracted to your buddies
scientists try to replace bacteria and
say they are creating the same amount of
enzymes
what do you think i'm confused no i'm
just kidding
a lot of good information there some of
these essential elements some
non-essential elements but are
beneficial elements you definitely did a
great job with this presentation and i'm
super thankful that you uh that you came
on here and uh and spilled this
knowledge for us for a second time
around tell us where can people find you
you can find me over at perfect gardens
tv uh obviously
i work with perfect gardens
and also i highly asked to subscribe to
the perfect gardens youtube channel
always helps and if you guys ever want a
part three
uh just let me know i could definitely i
love this subject about gardening and i
could definitely make a
part three about something new and
interesting if you're interested just
leave a comment down below
yeah i think between the part one and
part two we covered all of the essential
elements except for chlorine carbon
hydrogen and oxygen so i might have to
drag you back for a part three so we
could we could finish up the essential
elements i know there's a lot more
non-essential elements that we could
potentially cover in the future as well
so if you want a part three comment down
below right part three and uh maybe we
get mark back for part three mark thank
you so much for coming on to the podcast
once again this has been awesome i've
learned so much this is one that i'm
gonna look back at and continue to learn
more and more and more every time i
watch it because it's a lot of
information
really tough to absorb it all in one run
basically impossible to absorb all in
one run unless you're one of those
people who have a sponge for a brain
it can't absorb it all in one run
but uh this is something that is
definitely going to be on the rerun i i
agree with you man this this this is an
incredibly
uh confusing and complex topic and
that's why
i really tried to break it down to say
hey listen guys the most limited liberty
law minimum your most limiting factor in
your garden for especially a
biologically alive garden is enzyme
production and instead of trying to get
complex in the knowledge i tried to say
hey listen these are the products out
there that are going to solve 80 of your
problems
immediately and help you get to this
goal so once again thank you so much for
allowing me to come to this channel and
share a little bit hit that thumbs up if
you haven't already subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend i'm releasing a new
garden talk podcast episode and i'd love
for you to tune in to future episodes
also we're on all podcast platforms so
if you didn't know we're not just on
youtube we are on all podcast platforms
apple podcast spotify amazon so on and
so forth so check us out there if you
haven't already and apple podcast in
particular if you can leave a rating and
review that would be super helpful
because uh the more those the better
that'll help with ranking help more
people tune into the podcast so thank
you to everyone who leaves a review mark
once again thanks so much we'll leave it
at that peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode