welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr growt and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 125 in this episode I
interview Tad hussy he's been on the
podcast once before episode number 103
we talked all about how to reuse your
old potting soil for another grow there
was a ton of knowledge dropped in that
episode with many of you commenting on
how helpful it's been for you well Ted
is back for another episode this time
he's talking about various organic
amendments that you can add to your soil
with many of them not being very well
known if you want to see short
bite-sized clips of these episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube I
also have a gardening Channel where I
have over 130 videos showing the plants
that I've grown I'll have both of those
channels linked down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who help make that goal possible thanks
to AC Infinity for sponsoring this
episode check out their electric
sprayers with a 2 L capacity and an
adjustable nozzle that can go from a
strong jet to a fine mist spray their
sprayers are battery powered and can be
used for 3 hours on a full charge no
pumping required and it's a one button
operation click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their sprayers and the
discount code Mr grow5 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend consists of
several ingredients in one so you no
longer have to buy individual bottles it
includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
what are your plans with it you can get
it at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and Ed to
discount code the stash Mars Hydro the
Mars Hydro 420 sale is active now you
can get some amazing deals with
discounts up to 30% on a wide range of
their products LED grow lights UV IR
deep red supplemental lights grow tents
inline fans clip fans dwc systems and
more some deep discounts include FC 6500
is $100 off fc8000 is $120 off and there
are many more go to the website
mars-hydro
docomo it for a discount on any of their
products and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
once again with Tad hussy from Kiss
Organics how you doing today I'm doing
great how are you doing pretty good man
appreciate you coming on once again we
had such a great conversation the first
time around the audience really really
liked it it was on how to reuse your
soil and really went into deep real deep
on how to do that and a lot of people
are now saving a lot of money because
they're not throwing away their soil
they're actually able to reuse it so
appreciate you dropping some knowledge
bombs there uh and we got a great topic
for today really just going over a bunch
of different amendments that can be
added into your garden whether it be
organic all natural but ways to add
these organic inputs into your garden
and U have a successful grow from so a
lot of these inputs I'm actually um some
of them I'm familiar with a lot of them
I'm actually not familiar with are
really too deep of knowledge into
regards to what the benefits are how to
use them and so on and so forth so we
have a whole long list here before we
get into the list can you introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together yeah
absolutely so my name is Tad hussy I am
the owner of Kiss Organics kiss stands
for keep it simple and that's really
been the goal of our company from the
start we started out uh in the nursery
and landscaping business my parents
owned a Nursery and Landscaping company
for oh 30 years I think so I've been
around plants my whole life but I
recently well not recently anymore 20
years ago got into uh specifically
medicinal plant cultivation and um
created for our company we have um
living soils specifically for medicinal
plants and we really work to take a
science-based Approach at how to grow
these plants to their optimal genetic
potential that's awesome yeah I have uh
been using your nutrient mix that you
have nutrient pack using that for
several grows now and it's so good so
awesome just so easy to use just one
scoop per plant and then uh do it a
couple times throughout the grow water
only from there on out and plants are
healthy and you get to a good harvest
from it so I've definitely used kiss
Organics products in the past and I've
got a few my list here that I want to
purchase coming up here soon so but yeah
we met in person we were able to meet at
the SW Summit over in pump Nevada and
such a great time that was a great event
I only got to make it to the first day
unfortunately I have a five-month old
that I to care for but I was able to
sneak out there for the first day it was
awesome you had a great speech on there
you and a couple guys from kiss and it
was really good to sit down and talk
with you I think I talked to your ear
off for like 45 minutes or an hour or
something like that
we had a good conversation though no I
really enjoyed it it's it's so nice to
meet these people uh in person that
you've had you know conversations with
and and really talk to so no it was a
lot of fun I hope we get to meet up
again at future events Absolutely I'll
definitely go to the Sol sumone next
year if there is one that'd be great all
right let's start getting into some of
these amendments so we have a long list
here like I mentioned let's just go one
by one uh start with Organic whole grain
molted barley talk to us about that baby
what the benefits are how to use them
your overall thoughts on them so on and
so forth yeah before we dive into multi
barley I just want to back up really
quick and say uh the the to to me the
best way to amend your garden is through
a soil test so if you have the ability
to get a soil test and then get a
specific recommendation we can add back
in the exact fertility that was removed
when you harvested your plant um and
that that's what I just did in my garden
that's sort of what the whole idea with
a nutrient pack is if you can't soil
test then the idea is then you can we
can get you we can give you get you
close based on adding a general amount
of fertility overall back into the soil
but then there's all these specific
amendments and they all do different
things and have different benefits and
that's really what I think we're going
to talk about today and and to start
with with uh organic maled barley so
this this actually dates back to
Clackamus cot and it's something that he
came up with uh with the idea being
borrowed from the beer industry that
malting bar
freezes barley sort of at its highest
enzymatic levels and because of the
enzymes in the seed itself these enzymes
are things that enzymes are just things
that speed up uh chemical reactions and
so um what the idea was by adding malted
barley is you're speeding up a lot of
the uh natural plant processes and
reactions and so you would take the
malti barley you would grind it up um
apply it to your soil and then water it
it and that was part of uh something C
came up with as a way of um getting
better health and growth now I've done
this a couple times I've done I did a
trial in my tomato garden uh when I had
the farm and I didn't see an a
statistical difference on my plants
there so it's not something that I
utilize on a regular basis but we do
offer it a lot of people love it I've
heard many people say their plants just
exploded after trying it so in some way
it must have been addressing some
limiting a factor of growth in those in
those scenarios so I'm I'm not here to
say it doesn't work I'm just saying for
me it didn't I didn't get the results I
wanted but I think it's um it's
definitely worth trying in your garden
that's an input that I haven't tried yet
myself I've heard a lot about it it is
one of those things that are really
optional right like you don't have to
add it in order to get through the grow
but it is something that could certainly
add have some benefits at least it is
said to have some benefits so I'll have
to give it a try in the future these
next few that we have on the list here
are kind of similar so we probably talk
about at the same time which is a a
compost it's a fungal compost and then
there's also fish compost I thought it'd
be a good opportunity to kind of talk
about compost overall and the
differences between the two yeah so
compost is a is a whole podcast in of
itself uh making the compost determining
the quality of the compost it can vary
dramatically depending on what the
original feed stocks were how the
material was actually compost was it was
it thermophilically compost meaning I
killed all the weed seeds and all the
pathogens uh was it processed long
enough that the nitrogen cycled there
there's a lot of things that go into
this so uh just be aware I guess the big
takeaway is that not all composts are
created equal you want to Source a high
quality one in general composts tend to
be lower in fungi than bacteria and so
you know we call ours a fungal compost
um for one of the ones on our on our
website because we're adding food
sources to feed F fungi to get a more
balanced ratio there that being said
um really just make sure that your
source of compost is clean because
compost is going to be your your biggest
contaminant in your grow in terms of um
heavy metals and in terms of pests and
pathogens so pretty much all Pest and
pathogens can be avoided in compost if
it's properly thermophilically composted
with the exception of fungus Nats uh
anytime you bring organic matter like
compost into your grow space you're
potentially adding fungus snats so it's
always a good idea to have a plan for
that like bti or um I SF nematodes
something something along those lines so
when a consumer is looking to purchase
some compost you said look for a high
quality one is there something like in
the product listing that they can like
look at look for I should say to
identify whether or not it is a quality
compost yeah it's a little bit
complicated there are you every compost
manufacturer should be able to provide
you with a chemical analysis of their
product which um they're required by a
lot of have just to sell as a commercial
compost and that'll tell you some key
information like C to n ratio that
carbon to nitrogen ratio uh to show you
that that material is fully composted
that it's free of pathogens uh they'll
have that testing what they don't really
have for you which I think is also
important is sort of what are the
physical properties of that compost so
how much large particulate is in it how
well screened is it because that can
affect the physical properties of your
soil when you add it and then the other
thing is the biological properties of
that compost this is this is a time when
I like to break out the microscope and
uh throw the compost under there and
just make sure that I'm seeing all sets
of functional microorganisms in decent
quantities and that's really the best
way to do it is sort of all three of
those things um and then do a
germination test as well uh if you're
not going to do all that then you really
have to rely on the manufacturer or the
supplier to be giving you accurate
information or that you trust that what
they're providing is going to be good um
or maybe a buddies or things that have
tried it but but keep in mind with every
compost that you add or even compost
extract or compost tea you're adding uh
some fertility usually nitrogen and
potassium and you want to account for
that in your re amending process so you
don't overdo it you mentioned a
germination test can you kind of go into
a little bit of detail what you mean by
that yeah you can just throw some seeds
in there uh you know radishes are a good
option A lot of times um because I think
they're fairly sensitive to herbicides
so just some some cheap seeds is a way
to see if the if the plants are able to
grow in it um usually the compost
manufacturer will have germination tests
on their
um on their analysis that they can send
you so that it'll show you know we had
96% germination in this that so you know
that there's no um residual herbicides
or anything else from that compost
Source cuz some composts are made from
different manur or commercially um
collected yard waste and so there are
sources of contaminants that could be
potentially an issue in your garden
depending on where you're sourcing it
from that makes sense and you said not
all compost is created equal would you
also say that as far as the application
rates you know how much to apply how
often to apply is there any general
guidance amongst all composts or do you
have to kind of look at the packaging
and get the manufacturer's
recommendation so if we're talking about
making a soil from
scratch uh one of the most
popular formulations is this Cornell mix
which is a third a third a third so
that's a third Pete Moss a third Iration
like perter pmus and then a third
compost now I personally like to use
less compost than that I'll use compost
in most of my commercial mixes around
15% of my total media um and then once
that soil is established and I go to
reimen I will rarely add compost mostly
because I don't want additional
contamination specifically I don't want
to have to deal with with fungus Nets
and I also want to risk bringing any
more heavy metals into the scene so I
tend to not add compost every cycle but
a lot of folks do and get really good
results too so I'm not here to say that
doesn't work um but you just need to be
thoughtful about your application rates
um once that soil is in place you know
and you and you're running I wouldn't
add more than a cubic foot per yard of
of total compost every cycle that would
be the max I would I would want to add
okay that's good to know moving on down
the list we've got biochar next can you
talk to us about biochar yeah biochar is
amazing I I became a Believer when I
visited a facility and the only
difference between the two soils um they
were using our water only soil and then
we made a a formulation adding in 8%
biochar by volume they were getting
about 8 or 9% better growth and yield
with the addition of biochar and like
compost not all biochar is created equal
um there's a big difference between
biochar and charcoal so you do have to
do a little research but um by using
biochar you're getting uh the the
nutrients are going to be better
retained heavy metals are going to be
less available you're going to get
better water retention uh and just we
see better overall health and growth
with the plants um I'm not sure that I
fully understand it at this point either
at least why we're getting such a
dramatic response for it from it uh you
do need to charge the biochar but if
you're mixing your soil you can just add
raw biochar at that point in time
there's enough nitrogen and other
nutrients in there that is not an issue
but I definitely recommend if you have a
soil mix that does not have biochar and
adding it in at a rate of five to 8% of
your total volume uh can really make a
big difference in your overall plant
health biochar is something I've added
into my soil here and there haven't
really been calculated approach to be
honest with you but I need to kind of
circle back around to it and make sure
I'm using it correctly you know what I
mean because I don't want to use too
much don't want to use too little I feel
like uh it's got to kind of be the right
amount in order to kind of see an impact
from it right yeah it's a pretty safe
amendment to add the one thing to be
aware of is it can alter your pH it
tends to be alkaline so you just want to
make sure that your pH isn't creeping up
too high to pull you out of it effective
nutrient uptake range okay something to
keep an eye on next on list I have worm
castings now in particular African
Nightcrawler worm casting which is on
your website and it really made me think
of there are different types of worm
castings and we don't really talk about
that much right so worm castings I think
a lot of my audience is familiar with
the benefits of It kind of how to use it
but if you can break that down for us
and also kind of the differences between
like you know African Nightcrawler worm
casting versus other types Yeah so
basically the African is just the type
of worm that is used in this system It's
a larger worm larger poop uh so it looks
really nice and um I really like the
African one that we carry but there's
nothing I'm not here to say that like
African worm castings are going to be
superior to um red wigler worm castings
for example it's really the the most
important factors with worm castings are
the feed stock so what the worms are fed
the quality of that how long the worm
work that material so when you look at
worm castings and it's easier with
African because they make bigger poop
but what you should see is a bunch of
tiny balls if you're seeing a bunch of
other stuff in there that means that the
worms haven't worked that material fully
so that's the biggest factor in terms of
uh getting pure castings and getting
your money's worth we used to sell a red
wiggler casting but what we found over
time was this particular Source was um
higher chlorides in and sodium in the in
the final product that we want because
we're always testing these things and so
we stopped selling that one but uh prior
to that from a biological perspective
the the African looked just as good as
the red wigler but the chlorides and
sodium were much higher than the red
wiggler so we dropped it so just be sure
to you know look into your sources and
make sure you're adding things because
when when you get too high of sodium or
chlorides in your soil both of those
things can cause issues with your EC and
limit available nutrient uptake for your
plant yeah too much sodium can certainly
inhibit some of the other nutrient being
upt and that's a problem I ran into I
have high sodium I water high sodium
bicarbonates and so when I tried using
tap water here it just it was a terrible
result I had deficiencies unfortunately
a whole bunch of crap was going on in
the medium there it was uh not a good
result at all so that's interesting that
that was in the worm castings though
yeah yeah water is the most important
thing I Wherever Whenever I move to a
new location the first thing I do is
test my water and make sure that it's
suitable for irrigation because what you
can drink is not necessarily what you
want to put put into your soil or put on
your plants so that's a really good
point I'm sorry you're dealing with that
and in regards to application rate now
is this more generalized versus the
different types of wor I'm castings like
typically what I'll do is uh you know
either cup or I'll do like an inch
across the top layer of the soil is
there certain application rate or
General application rate that you advise
folks to use for warm castings no so the
way I approach worm castings is really
because they're so expensive it and we
don't have we usually have limited
access to them because of the cost um I
tend to use them specifically for
biology so I will use them like you said
with a light top dressing or I'll make a
compost extract or compost tea out of
them and irated compost tea is a way of
extracting and replicating those
microorganisms so uh I think those are
the best ways to get the most Bang from
your buck from earthworm castings good
to know next on the list is kiss
Organics microbe Catalyst talk to us
about that sure yeah so
this this product specifically was
something that uh we discovered worked
really well as a as a diversified food
source for making compost tea so we
called it a microb catalyst because it
it speeds up the microbial reproduction
in your tea and it's easier to use than
uh sticky liquid like um unsulfured
blackstrap molasses for example so yeah
we have rates and recommend for people
to use that as a sort of a a compost te
food source and that's that's primarily
what we sell to folks for that's awesome
I wasn't familiar with that product at
all I'm going to have to pick some up it
seems uh seemed interesting to use that
so you basically use it in replacement
to like a molasses that you would the
same dosage that you would with a tea or
what yeah so in a five gallon Brew for
example you would add a half a cup of
the micro Catalyst and a tablespoon of
the alphalpha of organic alphalpha meal
and that would be all the food that your
microbes would need for that 24hour to
36-hour brew cycle um in addition to the
compost that you're adding um and that's
that's really all you need it makes it
really easy and it's just uh it's it's
it's affordable and clean the Molasses
works great too it's just kind of sticky
and messy and um that's the only reason
that we uh we form it's hard to ship
molasses too so we we thought adding a
more Diversified food source we see we
tend to see really really good results
under the microscope using that as a as
a feed stock that's awesome I'm
definitely going to have to try that out
let's uh we're on a roll here let's just
keep on going we got that neem cake
pellets next on the list yeah so
neem the neem cake comes from the neem
tree it's a the neem uh it's also called
neem seed meal essentially what it is
it's the Pressed version of the seeds
it's what's left after they extract the
oil so it's still going to have some as
a dra in percentage it's going to vary
depending on your source and how well
that material was pressed and um it it's
got an NPK value that's fairly good I
tend to not use neem as much anymore
when I first started out with Clackamus
cot uh NE was one of his must must use
amendments and so we we added it to our
mixes and I was using it in CO's mix at
the time and and we still offer it but
I've I've dialed it back for a couple
reasons one is sort of the ecological
impact of shipping a product all the way
from India to here because it's they're
not grown here it's grown in India so we
have to get that fertilizer here I just
think there's sources that offer us
similar nutrient values that can be
sourced more locally or
sustainably second and this is more of
an issue with the oils but we did uh one
of the a good friends of mine was
working with a farm in Oregon and they
actually failed for a chemistry of
pesticide that hasn't been used in the
United States since since the 70s it's
been banned and essentially what
happened was that pesticide had been
sprayed on the neem tree and then
pressed into the concentrated into the
oil and then when the when the farmer
here used that oil he ended up failing
uh when he submitted his final flower
for testing and so this this is this is
a rare occurrence I don't think this is
this is something to necessarily be
afraid of but it is a a potential source
of contamination and we try to limit
those as much as possible so um I I just
think there's other options that we can
turn to that are a little safer um that
work just as well wow since the70s it
was a a long time ago that's uh that's
very surprising very surprising result
well yeah so it was obvious that the the
farmer the medicinal plant farmer hadn't
been spraying this product cuz they
wouldn't even able to Source it but the
fact that it was there in Trace Amounts
on their plant they traced it back to
this oil and then the oil got traced all
the way back to India where they they
figured it out essentially and
realistically the person who was selling
the neem oil didn't realize that the
product had been contaminated either um
because they thought they were sourcing
a clean source as well so when we're
getting things internationally there's a
certain level of trust that uh we're
having to put in terms of how that
product is produced I mean it's it's
worse for our food frankly but it's just
something to be aware of great Point
next up we've got humic acid powder talk
to us about that yeah so humic acids are
uh derived typically from leonardite
it's a minded product it's very good at
chelation um this humic acid powder is
going to have uh some level of fulvic
the humic and fulvic it just relates to
the size of the molecule itself um so
it's a great carbon-based input that you
can use when you are doing a folar
application or even a light soil drench
when you're applying other products so
it's sort of like U uh it's I put in the
category of things like surfactants that
you would add to a to a product when you
go to apply it just to get a little
better efficacy out of the product
itself you mentioned the word cation and
I do have a mixed audience here some are
beginners intermediate some are Advanced
some know what cation is some don't do
you mind taking a second here to explain
what cation is yeah cation is just a
fancy word for bonds width so
essentially what it does is bonds with
and makes these uh minerals or your
fertilizer application a little easier
for the plant to um to access the
nutrients in your application and is it
is it heavy metals usually that kind of
bind to that keyate easier I'm speaking
a little bit above my head here I'm not
crazy into chemistry here but from my
understanding something like iron for
example is uh can be chelated and kept
in that form so the plant can be uptaken
when the ballpark there or what yeah
Iron's a tricky one because uh it
oxidizes so rapidly when exposed to
oxygen it um it changes form but um I I
so I feel like a broker record bringing
up heavy metals what my my thought was
in relation to humic acid is just
realize it can be another potential
source of heavy metals because it is a
mined product and I have seen uh it come
back with higher levels of lead you're
using such a tiny amount of it it's
probably not a large risk I mean you're
we're talking like an eighth of a
teaspoon per gallon of water but still
it's just something heavy metals has
been a bigger topic for a lot of Growers
because of uh regulations around around
growing and so we just try to limit as
much as possible and for our own
personal health too even if I'm growing
plants medically I want to make sure
that I'm I'm growing the cleanest
possible product that I can you really
bring up a great point with the heavy
metals I think that's off of a lot of
people's radar you know they're not even
looking at that but it is a concern and
it it can be a concern with all natural
inputs as well uh some people think oh
it's just just a synthetic stuff that
you got to worry about heavy metals no
no there's all natural inputs can
absolutely have he heavy metals included
in there as well and we actually had uh
we covered it quite a bit in our last
talk so I want to reference people over
to that last talk that we had because
you went on for several minutes just
talking about heavy metals how to check
for them things to look out for so on
and so forth so check that last episode
we did together if you want to learn
more about heavy metals next on the list
we have coconut water powder yeah so
this is another one that has to get
credited back to Clackamus cot back in
the day the the idea there is that a
seed has all the nutrients that it needs
to grow you don't need to add fertilizer
to get a seed to germinate uh so those
initial stages everything it needs is
inside the seed itself and so coconuts
are the largest seed seeds that you can
get so by taking the water out of the
coconut what we're getting is all of
those enzymes and nutrients that a plant
needs to start its life and so what
folks have done is essentially taken
that coconut water uh or the coconut
water powder which is just a dehydrated
form of that's more concentrated so it's
more affordable and then um applying
that to their plants is a way of getting
plants some more essential enzymes and
and
nutrients uh again it's not something
that I recommend on the regular uh but
we do offer it and a lot of people
really like to use it I don't think it
makes sense
commercially just due to the cost
associated with it um we really try to
limit inputs on a commercial scale uh
because it's all revenue driven and
we're trying to create the simplest you
know least number of touches to get the
maximal result that we can but for a hom
grower I think things like the Mal
malted barley and the coconut water
powder are absolutely worth
experimenting with and see what kind of
results you get in your grow and and if
it's worth using on a regular basis or
if you just don't really see a benefit
that's an input I haven't used just yet
but it was on my list of things to try
in the future so I'll probably be one of
the ones that to experiment with it in
the future awesome next up we have
karanja seed meal let's get into that
yeah karanja seed very similar to neem
and that it's uh it's sourced from India
it's got a little different NPK value
than the neem does
um I don't have a ton more to add about
it other than when I I did some
microscope work work with it I found
when I so I take compost distilled water
I add a little bit of NE cake for
example to it and I let the microbes um
work it for a while and then see what
happens and with the neem cake we found
the microbes actually increased in
biomass uh specifically bacteria seem to
really like it would the cran seed it
actually kind of had an opposite effect
I didn't see a lot of growth microbial
growth from adding it which I I thought
was really interesting I don't know what
that means in terms of the properties of
the product itself uh we primarily use
it just for a little bit of NPK and I
know it's something that Clackamus cot
used in his original mixes pretty
straightforward there next up on the
list I have maganese sulfate now I know
a lot of people are familiar with
magnesium sulfate but maganese
sulfate a little bit different talk to
us about that yes so very important you
don't confuse the two let's start there
because uh mang manganese is very
different than magnesium um if you if
you were to apply manganese sulfate at
the rates you apply magnesium sulfate
you would get in a lot of trouble so
manganese is a uh Trace element that all
plants need it performs a bunch of
different specific plant functions but
you need parts per million of it so you
don't need very much and what we found
more recently with our soil testing is
that by that plants are utilizing a fair
amount of Manganese and so we're
applying it like I just reeded my my
grow base and I applied um two two
teaspoons per yard of soil to give you
an idea on a rate and that because I
can't sprinkle that in evenly I add it
to water I dissolve it and then I water
that in and that's going to be all the
manganes requirement I'll need for a
whole cycle just to give you guys idea
of how little we're using but um yeah
based on the tissue testing and the soil
testing we are seeing some
manganese uh deficiencies or hunger to
that we want to address by just adding a
tiny bit more okay and technically this
is a salt right you got two elements
that are bound together the maganese
sulfate it's salt and a lot of people
just ass associate salts with synthetic
however there are all natural salts and
this is one of them right do you know
the source of this magnesium sulfate or
I said it wrong there magnes sulfate
yeah so a lot of these products are
mined um and then refined and it's that
refining process that technically uh
people have issue with in terms of the
the fact that it is a A sulfate but keep
in mind that gypsum is also a sulfate
it's calcium sulfate um magnesium
sulfate Epsom salt is also some A
sulfate so all of these things are mind
products um they are approved for use in
organic production if you can show a
deficiency on your soil test um so it's
not something that I necessarily shy
away from because it's the easiest way
to get targeted available manganese for
my plant but there are other ways you
will get some manganese potentially from
VAR compost sources uh Rock dusts kelp
meal um you're just you're bringing in
other sources other nutrients at the
same time and you're also bringing in
more contamination and heavy metals so
uh it's you got to make a choice there
as to what you're comfortable with as a
grower using using in your grow and
honestly if you didn't use manganese you
probably wouldn't see a visible
difference in your plant but we are
seeing it in the tissue testing that um
the plant is taking it up and is
utilizing it that's interesting it's
good to know next up we have aisel 16h
which is a potassium silicate talk to us
all about that what are the benefits
application rate so on and so forth yeah
so many people are familiar with uh a
lot of the silica products on the market
like uh Silica Blast or din gr protect
things like that the Exel 16h is just a
dried powder that allows you to make
your own liquid silica by adding your
own water so you're not paying for them
to ship water so you end up with about a
gallon a pound will equivalate to about
a gallon of uh din gr protect in terms
of the ratios and similar to you know
these other products that we've talked
about it is uh approved for use in
organic production as a foler
application for IPM but it's not allowed
for uh soil drenches and other uses for
fertility so it is not uh fully organic
but it is allowed for use in organic
production so people do your research
depending on how you feel about that but
silica is amazing it helps with uh uh
stem strength it helps with drought
resistance heat resistance uh pretty
much all forms of abiotic stress it
mitigates microt toxicities of uh
micronutrients in your Leaf by spreading
that out more evenly so you don't end up
with um toxicity issues it's uh it it
has so many benefits I did a whole
podcast with Dr Wendy zelner just
talking about silica and I learned a ton
it it's it really should be an essential
mineral and if the soil if your soil is
deficient in silica you will actually
see higher uptake of heavy metals so
getting that silica in there actually
helps mitigate heavy metal issues too so
it really is a wondrous Amendment and
there are other sources of silicon that
you can get they um they they just are
may not be quite as available but some
other options for folks are dious Earth
is another one um there's biogenic
sources which just means it's plant
derived from things like bamboo or rice
um and then lastly the least available
form uh is is quartz or things like
silica sand those I tend to shy away
from just because they may not be
available within a reasonable time frame
for your grow so adding them you know
you may not get a result for months to
years in terms of availability
but yeah I I think people should do a
deep dive on silica and really consider
utilizing it in your grow next up on the
list we have borax this is something I
haven't really heard of people using
talk to us what is it and how do you go
about using this in your garden yeah so
borax is is a source of boron you want
to be really careful with it it's a a
trace mineral like manganese but you're
we're talking you know just a few parts
per million and so uh I would only
suggest that Growers use Boron or Borax
if you are uh if you have a soil test
and you are low on that test and you can
to add just a tiny amount you would mix
it with water and water it in to your
soil but if you don't have a soil test I
would not even mess with it um
interestingly enough you can pick it up
at your locally local grocery store
because it's the same stuff people used
to wash their clothes uh so it's kind of
that's kind of fun but uh just be
careful very very careful with it
because you can absolutely make your
soil uh toxic and cause a lot of issues
for your plants that's where I heard her
from it's a grocery store but I had no
idea that it was actually able to be
used in the garden that's interesting
yeah yeah kind of fun there's a few
things like that is the next thing
something like that corn gluten
meal so corn corn gluten meal it's a
byproduct of uh
corn the egg industry and essentially
what they found you'll see it in a lot
of products as a weed preventor so it's
a pre-emergent so you can use it to
deter germination in something like your
lawn if applied at the right time in the
spring other than that it's primarily
just a nitrogen Source it's not
something that we uh use a lot of with
our medicinal plants specifically but it
is something that we we do offer for
folks folks but we don't we don't use a
lot of it got it and so everything that
we had just talked about is available on
your website correct me from wrong there
kiss organics.com one of the things I
wanted to bring up I don't know if you
want to talk about it you sent me a
usual suspects chart and I thought this
was pretty interesting here it kind of
breaks down some of the soil amendments
and what you get out of it as far as the
nutrition are you able to talk about
that at all yeah one of uh one of the
guys that
Brandon Hudson actually kind of came up
with coting the frame the phrase Usual
Suspects with the idea that these are
the these are the amendments or
fertilizers that we tend to recommend
over and over again uh either because
they they bring in the specific nutrient
that we want uh they're very clean
they're very affordable they're easily
accessible uh so that list is that's
where that list came from and you can
get it actually downloaded from our
website on the soil testing information
page U or if you go to our website you
can also select uh amendments based on
what you're looking for by mineral like
are you looking for nitrogen you can you
can click on that and see all the things
that are going to give you nitrogen or
potassium or phosphorus or if you're
dealing with a Target pest same kind of
thing you can click you know Target
aphids target white flies Target
spidermites so we tried to make it as
simple as possible for folks to find
what the information that they're
looking for um on the various pages so
yeah feel free to share that link list
or I'm happy to talk about any of those
amendments uh at any point too yeah
we'll definitely get that list shared
and if you want to find out more
information you can contact kiss and uh
they'll be able to send you this chart
as well and some additional information
in regards to it so taking all these
inputs that we just talked about what
advice would you have for Growers using
these inputs for the first time so some
of the best advice that was ever shared
with me is
to if you're just going to go
go for it as in no soil testing and you
want to start experimenting with these
things couple couple piece of advice
would be sort of a half cup to a cup per
cubic foot is a good rate if it has a
higher mpk value go with that lower rate
if it has a lower one like alfalfa meal
for example you can go with a little bit
higher rate of like a cup per cubic foot
and generally you can stay out of
trouble with something like that if if
you want a product that's already done
that for you that you can just mix in
you can get there's commercial products
like our nutrient pack for example where
we've already kind of done that
formulation for you it's going to give
you a wide variety of amendments and you
can just mix it into your soil you don't
have to go through that process um the
the last piece of advice I have would be
if you do have the ability to do a soil
test uh I absolutely recommend it
because that's going to tell us exactly
what is going on with your soil and we
can then really dial things in specific
for what your plants are going to need
so if we know the crop and we know the
water quality and we know the the
fertility of the soil we can get we can
hit whatever targets we're looking for
um for your particular crop um but
whatever you do have fun with it I mean
I I think experimentation is a lot of
fun and I'm always doing experimenting
with my plants the one thing I think
that's important when you do experiment
is to just do change one variable at a
time so add biochar to half your garden
don't do anything else differently cuz
when you start when you start experiment
add five different things it's really
hard to know what actually made a
difference and what you're wasting money
on or what made or maybe one of those
things actually was antagonistic because
it added too much potassium or too much
nitrogen so just change one thing see
what the results look like and then make
another decision your next round and and
go from there I think that's some really
good advice and one more thing I'd like
to add to that is you know get some
viewers tune into this or listen to this
and they think that they need to go and
buy every single one of these inputs and
add it to the Garden they absolutely do
not need all of these inputs in order to
be successful in the grow actually this
particular list here you could probably
get away with not using any of it and
still be successful in the grow there's
other inputs that you can add such as a
kiss org against nutrient pack for
example you can use just that and get
through the grow what we've talked about
today are just additional inputs that
you can add to potentially get a better
result in your G better growth higher
yield quality so on and so forth and so
I thought that would be um Worthy of
mentioning here right now because I do
have some folks that think they need to
buy everything go out and buy everything
right now and uh another thing is people
think that we're just trying to promote
products the whole time and the fact of
the matter is we don't care what the
heck you buy go ahead and do it yourself
we're just here to talk shop reveal some
information here and uh just have fun
with it you know enjoy the conversation
I think some people watch my episode
sometimes and they're like oh you're
just trying to push products and it's
like I don't care what you buy go buy
what you want I'm just talking products
and it kind of goes back to the um the
fact that we're always in social media
there's always advertisements in front
of us and those advertisements are
always products so our brain is just
kind of hardwired to think product
advertisement you know what I mean so
just want to clarify that thing that we
don't care what you buy we just talking
about the products talking about inputs
getting Tad's advice on these different
inputs what he uses how he uses them and
so on and so forth so appreciate you
sitting down with us today Tad great
talk I will definitely have a link to
Ted's Channel down in the YouTube
description section below if you didn't
know he has an excellent podcast as well
more advanced podcast similar to this
Garden Talk podcast but kind of more
advanced folks so if you are on the
advanced side of things and happen to
not know about his podcast 100%
recommendation for you to tune into his
podcast because I tune into it and I
learn so much from your guests there so
appreciate you doing that podcast
appreciate you coming on here today I a
link to your Channel and to your website
in the description section below and I
hope you enjoy the rest of your day Todd
thanks Chris really appreciate it you
have a wonderful day too thanks peace
out everyone catch you in the next
episode