welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey what's up everybody for those
of you that don't know me my name is
Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into
to the Garden Talk podcast this episode
number 148 in this episode I interview
Luna Wickham she has been on the podcast
once before episode 111 where she talked
all about things that you can do in
order to increase plant taste and smell
one of the things that she mentioned in
that episode is that she uses ferments
which prompted some of you to comment on
that video requesting more details she
has a ton of knowledge on this so in
this episode we get into it she talks
about the different types of
fermentation and how you can Implement
in your garden if you want to see short
clips of these podcast episodes search
Garden talk clips on YouTube I also have
a gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who help me think all possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their Advanced grow kits which
include nearly everything you need to
start growing indoors they have several
different size kits and they all come
with a grow tent grow light ventilation
system oscillating clip fan a controller
69 Pro and so much more click the link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about their grow kits and
the discount code Mr Grow at 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend is
a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro fungi check it out at
stash blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash and we're back and I'm joined
with Luna wickom how you doing today
good how are you thank you for having me
back yeah Second Time Around first time
was awesome we got real deep into things
you're one of the more advanced Growers
I'd say of just Advanced knowledge and
we had a lot of folks here that tuned in
and they were just blown away by all the
knowledge that you dropped that time
around and they wanted you back for a
second time so here we are for part two
I'm happy to be here let's uh let's go a
little bit deeper let's give to the
people what they want absolutely So
today we're going to talk all about
fermentation for plants and when I think
of fermentation I think a lot of people
think of like k&amp;f they think of the
fermented plant juice fermented fruit
juice but there's a lot more to it than
just those things and that's what we're
going to get deep into today there's so
many different ways to go about it I
know you have certain ferments that you
do so finding out what you do when you
apply them how you make them all that
stuff uh we'll cram that to this episode
we'll see how far we can get and then uh
should be a very knowledgeable packed
episode could you just introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together yeah yeah
sure my name is Luna Wickham um I am a
uh educator in the kind of living soil
field um I do soil mineral balancing
Consulting um on my Instagram I I share
a lot of different recipes um like the
ones we're going to talking about today
and like different approaches to things
and how you can like up your game and up
your soil Health uh your plants volatile
organic compound profile which is like
this just the smell make things smell
better um get your yields up stuff like
that you know I have like a patreon I'm
a breeder um I breed you know different
types of uh seeds and stuff um and
genetics that I that I like to work on
I've been doing that for about 10 years
I've been cultivating for about 16 years
and this is my passion soil and plants
are my passion
awesome and like I mentioned we did do
one episode together in the past I'll
definitely have that Linked In the
description section below so you can uh
after this episode you can click on that
one and go tune in to that one okay
fermentation let's get uh let's get into
it there's so much to know about
fermentation and so you mentioned a
couple like k&amp;f inputs fpj you know
fermented plant juice fermented fruit
juice and stuff like that which is like
a mixture of a um uh sugar but they it's
just any kind of high osmotic pressure
pressure input that will pull the juices
out of plant matter um and then they
they leave it open you leave it open
like a coffee filter and it'll collect
you know microbes specific to that
profile of compounds inside of the
organic matter and that juice so like
different enzymes and amino acids and
carbohydrates will attract specific
microbes that you know want to live in
that environment so you'll collect you
know microbes specific to that plant
matter and will help break it down make
it available um that's what makes it a
fermentation cuz fation is just a
biological breakdown um or changing from
one compound to another through biology
um in plant matter so there's a whole
bunch of different types of
fermentations out there like you
mentioned the fpj the ffj and stuff like
that that's an osmotic fermentation okay
but we also have um solid state
fermentation which is like bkash where
you take a dry brand and you add lactus
to it we can get into the details of how
to make that stuff um there's also an
iic fermentation which is usually used
with um lact bacillus lactic acid
bacteria serum um and then that's also
added to to plant matter and you can add
different inputs like calcium and amino
acids um and then there's you know an
aerobic fermentation which people often
call um compost teas and I think compost
te is kind of a um it's it's the very
widespread term used for or making them
but they're they're just like aerobic
fermentations um and and I think that
that's a more accurate way of describing
it so yeah I'd love to break down each
different category and like how to make
them and how I like to approach it where
would you like to start which one should
we kind of begin with so the foundation
for a lot of them is going to be making
lactic cast of bacteria serum and this
is a practice taught in the Korean
natural farming world but it's actually
goes back way before that way way
earlier than Korea goes back to Japan
and even you know and Greece and this is
a practice that was used all over the
world almost simultaneously it's like
everyone everyone did it um in different
areas I wouldn't say that it really came
from one specific place you know um but
it's essentially when milk uh will be
inoculated with lact pillus and it
separates and you get a cheese curd and
then you're left with the serum beneath
it and that Serum is a potent probiotic
um source of lactobacillus a whole bunch
different types of lactobacillus um
this was then used to add to crops to
boost Health um prevent pathogens it has
a property that's called competitive
exclusion it's it's very good at
competitive exclusion which means that
it will multiply very viciously and
exclude out compete different pathogens
and other microbes that might be
pathogenic or infect your plant and so
it was very commonly used and this is
this is like how cheese is made too um
you know so anywhere that they were
making chees cheese they were making
lactic acid bacteria serum and then that
byproduct was used um as a fertilizer to
fertilize crops and and to promote
nutrient cycling to prevent pathogenic
growth in the crops um it was used all
over the world it's just an ancient
practice lactic acid bacteria for short
people call it lab break down the steps
on how to make it yeah yeah for sure um
so how it's taught in Korean natural
farming is you collect rice wash which
is just starch that comes off of rice
but really you can use any kind of
carbohydrate source that will attract
microbes from the air I'm going to just
go through the Korean natural farming
process because it's the standard way to
do it but if you're in an area where you
really insist on not going out and
purchasing stuff you can use any
carbohydrate you know that might be
growing in your field or that's just
local to your area because that's what
you prefer so you take rice you take
rice okay um what I like to do is I like
to soak it over night to really get all
that starch softened off of it and shake
it real good inside of a jar probably
like 50% volume of your jar and then the
rest um
water and you shake it up real good
after about 24 hours and it'll get all
that starch off of it and then you
filter the rice out and you're left with
the rice wash and then with that rice
wash you set it out in an area people
can do it in their house they can do it
you know in a Cupboard I don't recommend
that I suggest you find a place outside
underneath like a covered like with like
a little canopy like bushes or whatever
cover it with um like a coffee filter or
a paper towel put a rubber brand over it
hope you don't have any any um Wildlife
or rodents that get into it but put it
in an area where local microbes are
going to be existing you know where you
see that there's healthy plant life
right set it out there usually it takes
only about 24 hours but you wait until
you see a thin film that collects on the
surface of the water and that is
microbes those are microbes it's just a
whole bunch of bacteria that starts to
grow on the top and you know that now it
it's a source of bacteria um and it's
not going to be just lactobacillus it's
going to be everything in your
environment that's attracted to that
carbohydrate in that profile of of
enzymes and
carbohydrates but it's it's enough lact
bacillus and what we do is we introduce
it to a lactic acid environment to
promote only lactic acid bacteria to
multiply and for you know this example
is is um milk so people use milk I like
to get you know if you're really bougie
and you want to make like the best the
best stuff find some like local cream
top um which will usually separate on
its own but adding more microbes to it
just makes it that much better um you
can definitely use any kind of milk um
that you get from the grocery store you
know 2% you know whole milk um whatever
you can use whatever you have on hand
getting something local is going to be
super ideal
so you take one part your rice wash and
you add it to 10 parts milk I like to
use a 5 gallon bucket if you're making a
whole bunch you can use like a 30 gallon
barrel and that's enough for a whole
field so you mix it up you're also going
to cover that um with like a paper towel
or some kind of mesh whatever um often
times I just put the lid of the bucket
on top of it but I don't seal it because
it's going to off gas CO2 and we don't
want to create a bunch of pressure
inside the bucket and have it
explode so I don't see but I just keep
it kind of breathing and then after
about 2 to 3 days you'll see it separate
and you'll have a cheese cart on top
that's nice and thick I just cut it into
pieces pour it into like a paint
strainer bag or something like put a
paint strainer bag in another you know 5
gallon bucket whatever and pour
everything in there and then you just
lift that cheese Curt out and that's
cheese and you can eat it you can press
it you can make cheese with it and
flavor it um and then we're left the
Lac we're left with the lactic acid
bacteria serum and um you know that's
that's the staple for the rest of the
processes that we're going to be talking
about you can use it raw people use it
at 3.5 m per gallon or a ratio of 1 to
1,000 um you can consume it it's a
little stinky but you can do it it's
really good for your gut health
um and that allows us to make fermented
plant extracts it allows us to make
solid state fermentations and then we
can add it to things like compost or
aerobic fermentations as well okay so
you mentioned the delution ray one to
1,000 or 3.5 m per gallon so you're
going to dilute it down is that going to
you know some people using it as a fer I
believe I mean soil drench is that
happening oh yeah you can definitely use
it as a foler spray um and do introduce
native biology native lacilla species
onto the leaf surface of your plants and
that would be the correct ution for that
too um the proper you know dose would be
like 3.875 or something like that but
3.5 is just fine um you can use it a f
your spray application you can use it as
a soil drench um I recommend doing both
it's really good for your plants and
just having it added to your fol your
spray routine is really great and just
adding it to your your soil drench soil
drench regimen is also really
good I suggest using it about once a
week though I wouldn't push it to every
time you water because it can be very um
voracious like I mentioned it's
opportunistic we want to like maintain
maximum diversity biology in our soil so
we don't want to overuse lactic acid
bacteria serum okay and I heard that you
can even drink this straight don't even
need to dilute it you just drink it is
that true or no you can do that you can
I
wouldn't um you can you can definitely
do it you know if you if you're like you
know you're really into that kind of
stuff and you want to you know you don't
mind the the very pungent smell and
taste your you can absolutely do it you
can also delete it down too um you
know humans we secrete lactic acid and
so often times on our bodies we collect
lactobacillus and so the smell is very
similar to body
odor oh you could put that in your mouth
if you
want you know but you can you definitely
can oh that's funny so that's lactic
acid bacteria I'd like to get into you
mentioned Bashi composting next or
bokashi that as being a fermentation
this is something that I'm actually in
the process of getting into and so I'm
super intrigued by this one break that
down for me so bukh is a solid state
fermentation of any grain carbohydrate
and what that means is it's not
suspended in water you know we add a
little bit of water to make it moist
spread the lactobacillus throughout the
substrate throughout the the media like
whatever grain carbohydrate we choose
which can be wheat it can be oats it can
be
um whole bunch of different things right
it could be rice itself and essentially
what it does is it is an introduction of
mour but it's also an introduction of
lactus and it helps break down and
compost things on the surface of your
soil so when you add bkash to the top of
your soil most of the nutrient cycling
that's happening in soil is happening in
like the first 6 to 8 in of the soil and
so when you add a very very potent ulent
like bkash it really helps with the
nutrient cycling in that area and then
that that there's like a filamentous
high that comes out um there's been a
lot of debate about what it is um but
there has been confirmation through
different doctors recently that it is
mukar and this is something that I've
talked in the talked about in the past
it's in the The Rise ofus
family and so what mour does is it's in
every single soil and it plays a very
crucial role in decomposition of
nutrients it also has the potential to
create symbiotic relationships with
micro so microa kind of attaches to the
root Zone it spreads out you know it
expands the surface area allowing for
more of the soil to be accessed by the
plant therefore more nutrients to be
uptaken the muor will will form a
symbiotic relationship with that microa
also and just extend that reach and that
surface area even further so it like
multiplies the potential for nutrient to
be absorbed by the plant so let's get
into the process of like how to make it
right so you'll take your green
carbohydrate you'll take your
lactus you'll dilute your lactus I
usually like to do 15 m per
gallon of the raw
lactobacillus but if you're using
activated lactobacillus which we can get
into in a little bit would be about 30
and this is like what your FP would be
or your a your activated effective
microorganisms delude it to about 15 per
gallon and then you if you want it to be
just super simple you can take your
grain you can mix it just like that you
mix it to what's called Field capacity
to where it's moist but it's not
dripping and that's like the maximum
amount of water it can hold without
runoff
okay take that you mix it very
thoroughly you remove all the oxygen
from it so people I like to just put it
in a trash bag I think that that's the
simplest approach you just throw it all
in a trash bag you collapse all the air
out of it and you tie it and then it's
going to fill up with air um with carbon
dioxide because it's off gassing a lot
of CO2 and then after 3 weeks it's
finished you dry it and then you use it
it's very simple to make and it's very
effective in the garden this is
something that I have been looking into
and there's recipes all over online and
you know one of the ones I actually
pulled up here it has you start with 10
pounds of brand and one thing I to
research where do you get it we can get
at local feed stores you can get it
pretty cheap too so you get like huge
like 50 lb bags for pretty cheap so
that's usually where people start out
with I fig I mentioned that one and then
you also mention Us in lab a lot of the
recipes call for EM1 which would kind of
be a replacement would you say you could
use either or in that case or what so
EM1 is a product made by ter penics um
and it is a lact bacillus ferment got it
so EM1 it has other it's a Consortium
right so it has mostly Lac bacillis in
it but it has other things like purple
non for bacteria um it has some yeast in
it it has some other stuff too you can
definitely use EM1 that's going to be a
little bit more expensive route you can
make your own and it's significantly
cheaper or if You' like to go that route
and you don't want to bother with the
risk of you know maybe messing something
up or the frustration of of not having a
successful culture you can absolutely go
out and get EM1 okay and then uh there's
also some other things listed here how
you've got like add in molasses and then
water and yes you can use molasses so
that's just like a sugar Source you can
also add different fermentations so
let's say you had some fpj some
fermented plant juice um that you wanted
to use you could add some of that as a
food source also you could use an FP
that you've used this laop culture to
break down um different organic
matter you can use different
polysaccharide sources so these
polysaccharides are just complex
carbohydrates so what I like to do um is
add Labs I'll add red beet juice which
is has a very you know potent
polysaccharide called inin in it which
is really like lactobacillus loves it
it's really great for lactobacillus so I
like to add red be as my input you can
add different food sources you don't
have to the grain itself is a food
source but if you want to like really
play with with you know getting
different cultures of biology and like
having different Expressions kind of
inside this bkash you can definitely
play with different food sources you can
use fruit juice vegetable juice you know
people use carrot beet aloe
vera and those are kind of just
different things that you can play with
and those ratios are going to be
different depending on what you're going
to be using so I don't want to get too
much into the specifics of that because
I don't want to like lead anyone astray
because if you use multiple inputs those
ratios are all going to change as well
so using a food source like that is a
good practice you don't have to do it
but just the simplest form is just AI
lab um and letting it ferment for 3
weeks in an anerobic environment with
without oxygen okay and then the end
product you kind of end up with like a
dry brand right right when it's yeah so
you have to like after 3 weeks you want
to spread it out on like a flat bathable
surface some people have like mesh
screens like um like window screens and
stuff that they use um and that's not
much surface area so you might want to
get creative often times people just put
it on a tarp um that works just fine
also you just spread it real thin
ideally in a shaded area because the
sunlight can damage the the
biology and you just let it dry out if
you're going to be using all of it right
away you don't have to let it dry out
you can just kind of like powder it up
real good and just toss it right on the
surface of the the Garden or the the
soil um you don't want it to be too
thick you know just like dusting it you
just want it to be spread kind of evenly
you don't want like a layer of it if
you've applied it to the point that it's
like a cake you've added too much um and
also what I like to do if I do add a
bunch is I'll scratch it into the soil
surface to kind of break it up because
it can create a thick layer that can dry
and then prevent um oxygen going back
into your soil you don't want to apply
too much um because then it can create
other problems also don't add it to the
stems like around the stems of the
plants sometimes if the plant is younger
and it hasn't kind of developed its
strength you can add this strong
microbial inoculant intended to break
down organic matter to your stem and
it'll just break down the stem so so
don't add it to the base of the plant
they keep like three four to 5 in you
know like a little doughnut around the
base of the plant ideally and then how
often would you apply would you only
apply it during a certain stage of the
plant's growth for example flowering
versus veg or is it good throughout the
whole life cycle um I personally like to
do it through vet
keep in mind this is a this is a
potent microb Source right so if you
have any kind of testing that you need
to keep your microbial counts down if
you add this blooming you know
filamentous um kind of like fungi um to
your surface you're creating all these
spores each little head has all these
spores inside of it and they'll fly
around they'll get everywhere so if
that's a concern to you I definitely
wouldn't do it um I like to keep it in
like my vegetative grow stages or early
flowering and then cut it out but some
people wouldn't agree with me that's my
Approach yeah I can imagine some
commercial facilities I mean they they
test for microbials so it's like like
you mentioned if you're using in flower
it could potentially they send out that
for testing and they could potentially
fail and then they have to throw away
their batch so definely totally get your
reasoning for that and some people are
allergic to it
they're very sensitive to the spores
being in the air um so if you're one of
those people who's sensitive to spores
being in the air it's probably a
practice that good to know and so the
bokashi brand after you make it you can
take that and not just apply it to the
soil like you mentioned but do a process
called bokashi composting and that's I'd
like to get into that if you got
knowledge on that cool yeah yeah for
sure I don't know if you want to start
with kind of maybe how you make a Bashi
bin and then kind of using the bokashi
brand on the food scraps yeah yeah we
can talk about that for sure okay this
is definitely like a non-traditional way
of composting um and it won't actually
break the plant matter down like into a
mush or into like a black substance like
you would usually see um doing like
thermophilic
composting it almost like pickles it
right like kind of keeps it in this like
pickled stage but once it's taken out of
the the bin and you throw it in like a
regular compost bin or on your um soil
surface it'll break down very quickly
but in this this controlled state in the
bkash bin it won't actually break down
and that's normal and sometimes people
see that and they get so your bin is
essentially um a bucket or any vessel
that has like a spout on the bottom and
the technique is you put down a layer of
bkash at the bottom of it you add a
layer of your organic matter usually
like chicken scraps kitchen kitchen
scraps um and then you cover that again
with bicash
and what it does is it'll it'll create
what's called lechet which it'll kind of
break it down it'll create this juice
and that juice is very very potent
nutrient source that you can then add to
your water and feed to your plants you
can add it to compost it has it's rich
in biology it's rich in nutrients and
you essentially repeat that process of
adding a layer of organic matter of
plant matter adding a layer of Bashi and
doing it over and over and over and over
again until you fill your vessel um and
you let it break down you know i' let it
kind of sit for like 3 weeks or so until
you get all that Leed out you can even
press it down to get more and then what
you're left with um is plant matter
that's still rich in organic matter
still rich in nutrient content um and
you would break that up and top driess
with it and it'll break down very
quickly it's really great for your
plants you also don't want to make that
too thick because it can create too
thick of a layer that'll prevent oxygen
from penetrating into the soil or you
can add it to regular compost Min and
compost it and it'll compost very
quickly also okay yeah like I mentioned
I'm just kind of getting into it so I
have the 5 gallon bucket and I also
bought it's actually used for car wash
bucket it's to get like a dirt trap
basically you put it in the bottom of
the bucket but it adds in the space so
that way the liquid can kind of be down
on that bottom part and spout on the
side like you mentioned and then uh food
scraps I mean you can put bones in there
you can put meat in there right all
sorts of food you can put within there
as long as you're putting the brand on
there at least that's my understanding
of it that's what I plan to do you can I
would personally avoid animal products
really yeah was it is there a specific
reason I'm not a fan of fles in compost
um there's just you're playing with when
you start playing with breaking down
flesh and like cell and like animal
tissue and stuff like that you're
attracting biology that's going to be
breaking down flesh um and that's not
often times a good thing to have around
us as animals um it can it can bring in
passages and stuff like that and while
act bacilus by nature is very
competitive like it can out compete
things um and the potential is much
lower the possibility is still there
especially if you make a mistake um and
so I don't recommend using Flesh and
Bones and stuff like that because God
forbid you get something that makes you
very sick makes sense so what would you
recommend for somebody who is looking to
like reuse food scraps or whatever what
type of things would you add in there
safely food waste um your you know
lettuce tomato you know
your plant matter whatever if you're
trimming things off of your plants if
you have you know plant matter that
you've you've defoliated or that you've
you know pruned the bottoms off of that
stuff is perfect um or like the butts of
whatever vegetables that you're not
using vegetables fruits and vegetable
scraps is what I recommend using would
about like bread bread or um you can add
bread french fries or things like that
so I would stay away from anything
that's been like really heavily treated
with pesticides and stuff like that um
just because it's going to limit the
microbial activity you can definitely
add carbohydrates for sure um but I
think most ideally is going to be fruits
and vegetable scraps um if you really
want the bang for your buck I would go
that way and then that liquid that you
mentioned that you would eventually go
down and then you've got the spout there
so you're you're draining it from the
bucket occasionally does that need to be
diluted before doing the application to
the plants m 1 o per gallon is is
perfect 1 ooun per gallon okay yeah I
wouldn't go any higher than that
honestly it's pretty potent stuff you
can go lower than that though um and if
you do want to use things
more decrease the dosage so if you want
to increase the frequency decrease the
dosage increased frequency decreased
dosage um um so if you do want to use it
every watering you can drop it down to
like 3 m um and go like that because it
is it's it's decent and it's not going
to be as potent as a lactobacillus
source as straight lactic acid bacteria
serum so that's kind of an okay practice
if you want to do about once a week once
every two weeks you can go up to about
30 um but if you want to use it more you
have like a deficiency you really want
to correct quickly I recommend smaller
dosages and would that be for a foler as
well or would you only recommend a soil
drench with that you could use it as a
fol application I would I would
definitely drop the foler application
down a little bit lower too to about
three to five and then like you
mentioned that food isn't going to break
down entirely right so you you'll press
it down get all liquid out and then
you'll empty out with that bucket
eventually and I know a lot of people
are you know put it in their backyard
and then bury it down in a hole in their
yard for example so that's a way to go
about it that's kind of the way I I plan
to use it here I live in the desert
I have 1% organic matter in my backyard
and so I need to I need to uh I'm I'm
trying to reuse my scraps and I have a
regular compost pile I have a Verma
compost but I want to continue to do new
things here so Bashi really sparked my
interest there are things that you can't
put in the worm that you can actually do
through bokashi composting so I think
that's what interested me the most is uh
instead of just putting in the garbage
for example I can put it into bokashi
composting and then uh eventually try to
build up the organic matter that's in my
backyard and be growing some fruits and
veggies out there yeah 100% And if you
do feed it to your your worm bends the
worms will eat it much faster too and
it's really good for the worm like gut
health ah okay that's good to know
that's good to know so you take it from
bokashi composting big clumps put it
into your worm bin it breaks it down
even more you got the worm castings in
there so and that would create a very
high quality earthworm casting awesome
yeah cool so you you said um you know
bkash can do some things that
traditional composting can't we and you
had mentioned like using meat and stuff
I kind of wanted to just take a little
detour and kind of discuss ways of like
composting meat cuz I know that that's
like a big thing for people okay so
black soldierly larvae and like beetles
are a great way to break down flesh um
and so if you have a lot of food waste
let's say you're on a farm and you have
you know animals you're a hunter and you
have you know a lot of Flesh whatever
that would just kind of you know that
you're not going to be using whatever
you can create a black soldierly larva
bin um which are just like a species of
fly and they consume the flesh very very
quickly same with beetles will consume
the flesh very very quickly and then
their excrement is used as a nutrient
source and biological inoculant good tip
yeah I appreciate you throwing that out
there okay so next up you had mentioned
an aerobic form would be compost teas
can you get into that a little a little
bit Yeah so now we're going to tie
everything back
together um we can use all the inputs
that we discussed um you know the
osmotic fermentation the anerobic
fermentation um actually you know what I
think we should back up a little bit
okay yeah let's go to FP um because we
can talk about using um labs and like
molasses and food sources to then
ferment into an FP and then we can use
that as like an input and kind of wrap
it all together all right let's get into
FP so we talked about lact bacillus um
fermentation um as biological inoculant
right um but we can also use it just
like when we do Bashi buckets to break
down organic matter to create available
nutrients um this is also considered a
solid state
fermentation but we can also do an
anerobic fermentation in water with
lactobacillus to create what's called a
fermented plant extract and so so what
this is is we collect plant matter
typically typically you know people will
go out and they'll collect like Fallen
fruit this is what I like to do I like
to go collect Fallen fruit peaches and
apples I also like to use kind of like
um um gourds you know I'll use like
pumpkin and squash and and melons and
stuff like that which have a lot of
sugar inside of them they also have a
wide diversity you know between all the
things that I mentioned including beets
they have a wide diversity of
polysaccharides which are different food
sources different complex carbohydrates
which will contribute um different
organic acids and each organic acid you
know found in all of this diversity of
plant matter we have diversity of
polysaccharides we have diversity of
organic uh organic acids these organic
acids will act as um like plant
stimulants they're they act as phyto
hormones okay and each organic acid will
stimulate different processes in the
plant which can which is a whole other
Wormhole and we have things like
jasmonic acid which is the stress
response hormone we have oxin we have
gibberellins we have cinin um which will
all trigger different physiological
effects inside of plants so we add a
whole different array of plant matter to
water and we let it soak it'll pull
those organic acids out and adding the
lactobacillus will keep pathogens from
multiplying it'll also help break down
that organic matter and release those
organic acids as well as release the
nutrients inside of it so what we do is
we take the plants and the waste that we
have around us and we introduce it into
water and lactus and let it ferment
either with just the sugar sources that
exist inside of the plant matter or we
can add a little bit of masses also if
we don't think we have enough sugar
sources and this gives us a very potent
fertilizer that we can then dilute and
add to our garden regimen and it also is
a source of phyto hormones that we can
then used to stimulate growth processes
and we can tailor the plant inputs used
to have specific organic acid profiles
to stimulate different growth processes
in the plant during the time that it's
needed so these different phyto hormones
will have benefits for different plant
growth processes um like gibberellin is
good for um
germination cyanin um is going to be
good for like that transition stage um
the Ethylene
is going to be good for like finishing
and stuff like that it's going to be
good for your ripening stage and so we
can use resources um online to look up
different organic acid profiles a good
one is called Dr Duke's phytochemical
database you can punch that into Google
and you enter your plant into the search
bar and it'll give you a full breakdown
of your uh phytochemicals exist that
exist inside of that plant matter and
then we can determine what we have in
the plant that will stimulate which
growth process um in the garden that
we're that we're looking
for this can be kind of arous because
it's going to give you a list of like
these organic acids that you may not
know what they are um but you can like
filter it by PPM and then you can look
up you know the most potent sources in
that plant to know like when I give this
to my plant when I harness these organic
acids it can promote certain growth
processes in my garden so that's what I
really really like to play with when
when making fermented plant
extracts is like
creating certain Brews that are going to
accomplish certain tasks and have
specific profiles of nutrients that will
complement certain growth processes in
our garden as well let's say we have a
plant that needs a particular amount of
potassium at a certain growth stage or
phosphorus at another one we can tailor
our fermentations for vegetative early
flowering mid-flowering late flowering
um to help facilitate that growth
process in our garden
and ultimately replacing a lot of
products that you know are out there on
the
Shelf probably not all of them though
okay so fermented plant extracts correct
me if I'm wrong here but what falls
under that is fermented plant juice
fermented fruit juice so no it it
doesn't actually it doesn't okay no it
doesn't so um fermented plant juice is a
osmotic extraction um with like a sugar
store something that has a high osmotic
pressure that does not use lact bacillus
this is plant matter I like to blend it
to you know keep the surface area like
as much surface area as possible plant
matter fill
like I like to make 55 gallon barrels
with this okay you fill it a third to a
half if you're bold and you're really
patient you have a lot you can do like
3/4 um but I think like a third to a
half is pretty solid and then you add
your lactic acid bacteria serum um
the ratio is 1: 1 to 20 so you add one
part lactic acid bacteria serum one part
your food source and then 20 Parts water
so if you have a lot of sugar in your
plant matter you might want to tone down
like how much molasses that you're using
if you have a lot of sugar you can skip
it completely which is what I typically
do is I'll fill it with a whole bunch of
plant matter I like using aloe vera I
like using beet you know uh um
cantaloupe squash pumpkin premature
apples you know stuff that I mentioned
earlier um blend it all up add it to
this this vessel which I actually have a
video on this on my Instagram um talking
about making a fermented PL extract you
add your one part lact pillus to your
one part food source to your 20 Parts
water so let's say you have a 55g barrel
right we're just going to do it right so
we have a 55g barrel that's uh 200
13,125 M right so if we divide that by
we have 22 Parts total we know we need
um about 3 gallons of lactic acid
bacteria serum a little bit less about
two two and two and 2/3 we would add 2
and 2/3 2 and half gallons of lactic
acid bacteria serum and if we have the
volume equal to that in plant matter
probably a little bit more CU you know
it's not all going to be sugar you maybe
twice that amount in
volume we would then just add water to
fill it all up but if we're skipping the
plant matter completely you would just
add molasses and fill it up with water
and this creates a fermented um a
activated effective microorganisms but
with the plant matter it is a fermented
plant extract you fill it up to the top
you know you mix it nice and good you
cap it you keep it anerobic
you have to have a little um valve one
of those little water valves like U
bubble ones like that are used in
fermentation people use them in beer
wine and stuff like that to off gas CO2
this also prevents oxygen from getting
into the culture because it is an
anerobic
fermentation lactus is technically
called faculative which means it can
survive in anerobic anerobic conditions
but in this s this situation we want to
keep it anerobic as possible so we cap
it we seal it we add um one of those
little air off gasing bubble valve
things and we'll let that sit for 3
weeks and we watch it don't open it um
let it sit for 3 weeks test it with a pH
pen see what the pH is if it's between
3.2 and 3.7 it's done um this will help
us give an idea of how much lactic acid
is is inside of the culture and when
that lactic acid concentration reaches a
certain level it'll be with within that
range and so we know that the b or the
bacteria the lactus has released enough
lactic acid to reach a particular
concentration that we know that it's
done so 3.5 it's done anywhere between
3.2 3.7 it's good you can't get it down
that low it's a failure um it usually
never gets lower than that though I've
never seen that
happen um you have to be careful when
using plant inputs that are
alkaline um if you don't get your
culture low enough the lact billus isn't
going to thrive so this is a problem
when people are using um when people are
using the leaves of plants that they
might defoliate the underp part of um a
common one that people do that with is
often very alkaline
um and so to kind of accommodate for
that we can use things like um apple
cider vinegar to drop that pH to about
the 4.5 to 4 range and it'll help
facilitate the multiplication of the
lact pillus quicker um so it is good to
check the um the pH before you start
your culture and before you seal it
because if you're using plant matter
that is very alkaline it's going to
interrupt the functionality the of the
fermentation if you open it up after 3
weeks pH is good take a little shock
blast of it you know there shouldn't be
a pelic which is like a collection of um
lactobacillus that's going to protect
the rest of the culture from oxygen um
it's just like a thin film um if there
isn't aicle that's good it means that
your your Barrel was completely sealed
and there was no air that got inside if
there is a pelic it's not horrible it's
not really a bad thing it isn't doesn't
represent a fail um but there was oxygen
that got in your barrel and that's is
something to note take a little shot
glass collect it set it out for a couple
days see how quickly that pellicle forms
if the pelic doesn't form it was a fail
um you didn't multiply lactobacillus um
if it does then that's a strong um
that's a strong culture this is a way of
determining the strength and like U
microbial density of lactobacillus based
products as well a lot of people sell
fpes a lot of people sell laop bacillus
cultures and if you don't have a
microscope and you want to see if this
thing is actually viable and Alive take
a shot glass of it and leave it out if
it doesn't form a pelicin a day or two
it's weak um if you get one the quicker
the better um eventually it'll probably
form something but if you're at like 7
days that product is inferior to
something that you can make at home um
that's a good thing to to know
about um if you had a successful one you
you got your pelic you got it within the
PH range um this is something that you
would use between 15 to 60 m per gallon
I typically use it just at 30 um you can
use it as a f your fol your spray
application um if you really want to get
fancy with it you can get a
refractometer and see how much sugar
content is in it if you have a lot of
sugar left in your culture after those 3
weeks um you overfed it and it's not
like a huge big deal you know it's not
going to create problems but it will if
you're going to start fure spraying it
if you full your spray sugar onto your
Leaf surface you're going to start
getting things like white flies or
different pests that are attracted to
sugars so it's important to not overly
inputs that have a lot of sugar in them
and and if you do you need to have a
microbial Source along with it to help
consume that Sugar um but if you add too
much sugar and you fully spray it on
your plants you're going to have some
big issues just to be mindful it's
better to underfeed your your cultures
than overfeed them I can't take notes
fast enough there so much good
information so much new information for
me like I mentioned I I don't really do
ferment right now but it is something
that I hope to eventually get into in
the future so I'm learning and I'm
definitely going to be watching this
episode back and taking notes Here in
the future that's for sure so you said
it's different than fpj and ffj do you
think now's a good time to get into
those things here sure we can yeah we
can discuss the differences I kind of
covered it a little bit um were there
any like specific questions or things
that you know you'd like to know about
regarding them well with fpj fermented
plant juice you're really only using
plants with the fermented fruit juice
using fruits can you use a combination
of things was a question also brown
sugar I know is an often a thing that's
often used would you recommend that to
use for fpj and ffj yeah brown sugar is
like the that's like what the standard
okay yeah it's a standard but it's
anything with like high osmotic pressure
I was chatting with some of my my nerd
friends we were talking about using
dextrous because it's the highest
osmotic pressure um like simple simple
sugar out there um and it might pull out
more I've never actually done it but
anyway yes I would use brown sugar um
and so you you do a one: one ratio by
volume mix it up kind of chop it like
masticate it a little bit um and then
mix it with your brown sugar at a 1 to
one ratio and um some people have
changed the ratio k&amp;f k&amp;f kind of is
known for changing their their recipes
over time but one to one was what I was
originally taught and what I have been
using and it works just fine um
and then they let that sit for about 7
days and then collect the juices that
have separated and they'll be sitting on
the bottom um and that's something that
you use at a 1 to 1,000 um application
rate
also you need to have a microbial Source
when you're using it um cuz like I said
it's pretty much just sugar it's like
syrup um and you can you can use it like
syrup you can eat it um you might want
to seal it up um with like a
fermentation lid if you're going to be
making it for consumption
um but it's like sugar and so when in
knf people are using those um those
inputs with lactobacillus but they're
also using what's called indigenous
microorganisms which is just the name of
the input which is um it's rice that has
been undercooked and left out in the
forest to collect microbes
um this it'll it'll form that that
filamentous H layer like bkash bkash
will like mour
um the claims are that it's collecting
indigenous microorganisms and
multiplying them this is not a practice
that I use um it seems to me that it's a
method of introducing a mour and biology
throughout your soil um I just like to
use Bashi instead um I think it's
simpler it doesn't take a lot of time
anyway point being you have to add a
microbial source to your um your
fermented plant juices you don't want to
add um sugars to it so what they'll do
is they'll add IMO they'll add fpj
they'll add brown rice vinegar as your
enzyme Source um they add water soluble
calcium they have like a whole range of
things that they use and they use them
together um and it's important that you
have that Consortium of stuff you have
your inoculant you have your enzyme
Source you have your nutrient Source um
you have your your you know your
protectors they call them like the micro
police which the lactic acid bacteria
um and they introduce it all together as
this complete picture and you know they
recommend you know not using one alone
um and I recommend that also if you're
going to be using something high in
sugar you have to have mic microbes and
enzymes that go along with it not going
to be brown rice vinegar that can be a
little bit of apple cider vinegar there
are a lot of different enzyme sources
out there you can also use things like
sprouted seed teas which are seeds that
have been sprouted full of enzymes you
blend them they're a very potent enzyme
source um you can add you know that too
but it's important that you have biology
the enzymes the lactobacillus and then
your fermented plant juice your sugar
Source because it's just like straight
sugar and that can be problematic if
used alone Yeah you mentioned several
different k&amp;f processes and that's a
topic in itself or episode in itself I
should say I had a couple people on in
the past that were talking knf and it's
so fascinating the way everything works
together on that Avenue and yeah we get
super deep into into that into a future
episode yeah there's a lot to talk about
around around knf but maybe we should
stick to the fermentation one thing uh I
would like to get into if I think we
have time here is the compost teas so I
know a lot of people use compost teas
there's right ways to go about it
there's wrong ways to go about it
there's some people that say that you
shouldn't use them at all so maybe
that's the question I ask you to begin
is this broad question you have folks
who say they use compost te's frequently
and they gain a lot of value out of it
you've got other people that say just
use compost just top dress of compost
and water it in doing a tea isn't going
to have any additional benefits what's
your take on that
so it depends
um yeah adding compost top drifting
compost is going to be a much if the
compost is quality is going to be a much
safer way of introducing biology and and
nutrients
um it's in its original form you add the
water the microbes get introduced um the
nutrients are there it makes it very
simple where the problem comes in is if
you have a lot of soil you need a lot of
compost to cover it so if you're growing
in a field you're growing any
significant amount of food and you don't
have enough compost to do that compost
tees are a great way to stretch that
biology um and often times you know
people don't take into consideration
that when we're making compost tees
we're also we can also add other things
to the compost te um that wouldn't be
present inside of a thermophilically
composted compost um or even a
mesophilic composted like um insect
frass or um earthworm
castings a little bit earlier I had
mentioned diversities of organic acids
used um as like phyto hormones to
promote plant processes um we can add
inputs that introduce those organic acid
profiles to our compost EAS and make
them more effective and more readily
available to our soil um we can also use
different inputs in our compost teas to
encourage microbial multiplication all
cells require amino acids all proteins
you know are formed through amino acids
so what I like to do in my compost is
I'll add an amino acid Source um I'll
add different diversities of complex
carbohydrates of polysaccharides to
encourage diversity of
biology compost teas are not the native
environment for soil biology um sure
soil gets wet but it does not water
right so when you make compost teas
you're taking you're taking biology out
of its native environment and you're
putting it in water and you're going to
limit the diversity that it can multiply
it still is very effective um but you're
not going to have the microbial
diversity that you would get if you were
to just top dress it but top dressing an
acre is is a huge task top tressing you
know half or quar or whatever if you're
trying to b remediate a piece of land
it's going to be very difficult and take
many many years to do um composting um
traditionally and adding compost to to
the soil surface compost are a great way
to just help kind of bridge that Gap to
add biology to help cycling cycle
nutrients earlier
so I think that it's they're just tools
and I think to be like oh this tool is
just better than this tool I think that
this tool has an application
specifically um that's going to be ideal
and then this tool has another and all
of these things that we're talking about
today they're all just tools and some of
them are going to have strengths and
some of them are going to have
weaknesses and some are you know not
going to be ideal in certain situations
um compost is just another one of them
so you can play when making a compost te
you know people use
compost obviously you can use
thermophilic which is going to be your
traditional turned compost you use
mesophilic which is going to be your
earthworm castings or your insect prass
they're going to have different profiles
because they are made through different
processes one is through the turning and
um heating up of microbes that break
down the Plant matter into compost the
other is being consumed by insects and
going through their gut biome um and
using their excrement I prefer
um mesophilic breakdown mesophilic
composting um because when it doesn't
get to that higher temperature isn't
going to cook off other biological
species that can't survive in those
temperatures um you know microbes they
some of them prefer um acidic
environment some you know more basic
some you know colder some hotter and as
we heat them up we're creating an
environment that those you know those
microbes that want that warmer
temperature are going to exist in while
in mesophilic we going to leave a larger
profile of
biology so in my compost I like to use
Earth room casting specifically um and
if and it reduces the potential for
pathogens if whoever made it didn't turn
it properly um making compos is an art
and if you mess it up you can introduce
pathogens I've seen people introduce
septoria um and you know ferium
different pathogens through thermophilic
uh thermophilic compost um very
regularly especially with mushroom
compost that people use
um so I like to use Earth castings um as
my biological inoculant and my like
compost source so I'll take earthor
castings I'll throw them in a vat of
water um your Brewing vessel people will
like to add um bubble snakes which is
just like a a tube that wraps around the
bottom that has holes in the bottom and
they blow bubbles down and it agitates
the the water and you have a brew bag
and you put all your your inputs in it
and it kind of agitates it um and it
like Scrubs the biology off of your
inputs and it soaks into the water and
then while it's in the water it has your
food source which people usually like to
use molasses um I like to play run and
add some different things I like to add
um oat flour which is something that Dr
Lane Ingam talks about um it has more
lipids in it and there's more like you
know fats in there for you and for the
biology and has a lot of starch and
stuff and has um you know
polysaccharides that are good different
complex carbohydrates that'll more
diversity of biology and then I like to
use beet juice um which you can see
which I've talked about which is inin
you know it's a very strong Prebiotic
these polysaccharides they're prebiotics
right and that's what I make my teas
with oat flour and be juice with
earthworm castings and then before the
like long fermentation process which is
usually about 24 to 36 hours um I like
to add things are going to promote
cellular development things are going to
promote microbial multiplication like I
said before all proteins require amino
acids to be built so I like to add amino
acids um you can get products that have
amino acids in them there's like soy
based amino acid products there's
fish-based amino acid products um you
can use um aloe vera which I also like
to use however I prefer to use it at the
end and I'll get to that in a second um
so I add an amino acid Source but then
I'll also add a calcium Source there is
a Korean natural farming input called
called water soluble calcium um and it's
essentially exactly what it says it is
but it's um calcium
carbonate that has had apple cider
vinegar added to it and it breaks down
and it makes it an available calcium
form it makes calcium acetate um because
apple cider vinegar has acetic acid in
it and it creates chemical reaction
calcium acetate is one of the most
available forms of calcium that we can
find in nature and I'll add that to my
compost as well so I'm creating the
foundation for microbial multiplication
and diversity of biology in my compost
with a biological input earthworm
castings which has a very wide range of
biology um compost tees can be as
creative or simple as you want them to
be you could literally throw Earth
castings in a bucket with molasses and
let it sit and then dilute it and water
it in and it would work um you can get
very creative with what you're using you
can go find different you know plant
inputs that have different sugar
profiles um that feed different profiles
of
biology um which is what I like to do
which is what
I which is what I'm kind of known for um
is kind of creating these more
concoction potion based uh compost to
use in my garden and then there will be
some inputs after you brew that you
would want to add um that you don't want
to add
beforehand for me that's like your
inputs that are going to have
Rich profiles of organic acids or um
amino acids that you don't necessarily
want to be broken down so I like to add
my like aloe vera which has you know 19
of the 20 different amino acids it has a
whole bunch of enzymes it has a
polysaccharide called aaminin um which
has tons of soil benefits um and will
elicit plant responses just that
compound itself it also has oxin in it
um which is a plant growth hormone C
cause like explosive growth in the plant
I don't want any of those compounds to
be broken down by biology so I'll add
them at the end so if you have a plant
input or just input in general that you
want to use to stimulate specific growth
processes add it to the end of your
compost because biology changes
compounds from one thing to another
um and so when you're using an aerobic
fermentation that's much more likely to
happen than in like an anerobic one
um also lact pillus lactic acid bacteria
serum since I talked about how vicious
and opportunistic it is if you add it to
your compos T pre Brew it can multiply
and dominate the rest of the biology in
the in the Brew leaving you with less
diversity um so I like to add that to
the end also good to know about the
inputs added after the Brew I don't
think a lot of people add inputs after
the Brew to be honest now you mentioned
a brew time of 24 to 36 hours and
there's a lot of information some people
say it should be shorter some people say
it should be longer can you just give us
high level what are the risks of brewing
for too long and then what are the
downsides of brewing for not long enough
so here's the
deal the time period thing is just to
make it easy for people
um it's going to depend on a lot of
different factors how much you fed how
much inoculant you used um what the
temperatures are outside what the
temperature of your water is does your
water have um any kind of contaminant
you know what's the calcium amount you
know what's the sodium amount what's the
um do you have chlorine in your water
which always you should not have
chlorine in your water by the way a good
point um these are all going to affect
how quickly the biolog is going to be
multiplying in your in your Brew so when
people are like do a short Brew it's
because like yeah if you mess it up and
you know it multiplies too much you can
have an imbalance in your your
biological profiles things like protool
will start to take over which can be
potentially pathogenic they're also an
important part of nutrient cycling
they're like our predators
um I know that's complicated but there's
many different species of them um
so in like soil food web Sciences right
we use microscopy to identify the
profile of biology existent in our
compos we have a particular microbial
density of lower lower bacteria you know
like um and then we have our our
protozoa we have our amibas you know we
have you know different types of
protozoa we have our ciliates we have
our felet we have our um rotifers and
stuff like that and there's things that
we do and that we don't want um and
given a certain amount of time we're
going to see our protozoa show up in
numbers which will consume a lot of our
lower bacteria which is what we need um
but we also need a certain count of
protozoa so it's one protozoa usually a
ciliate for 10 field views and so when
people are like how long should I brew
my tea it's like well it depends on how
many protozoa have multiplied inside of
your compost te um so it it's it's not
a simple answer the simplest safest way
would be just like do it for 24 hours do
it for 6 hours do it for just mix it and
water it in you know like um cuz we're
playing with Biology you know we're
playing with bacteria you know there's a
reason why why why people
are cautious when playing with bacteria
and multiplying bacteria because it you
could you can mess it up you know you
can make mistakes you can make people
sick you make yourself sick um that's
one of the reasons why people say don't
do it um this is one of the reasons why
I only use earthor castings um you know
I had a buddy who was turning mushroom
compost he got um um some like fungal
infection in his in his blood you know
like it's just you know we're we're
Farmers you know we we play with plants
and stuff we play with Biology but like
I just had someone yesterday tell me how
he got something from from turning
compost um you can have like asper
Gillis you know like you inhale asper
Gillis like you're GNA you're gonna make
yourself sick so to answer your question
is there isn't a very simple answer um I
usually do 24 to 36 hours 24 you want it
more bacterial dominated and 36 if you
want it more more
protozoa and to determine which one you
would want you would need to get a
microscope and examine the profile of
biology in your soil and so if you have
low microbial density you want to add a
compost tea that's going to have a lot
of lower bacteria in it going to have
like a lot of simple bacteria and then
if you see in your soil that there um
Aren't Enough protozoa you're going to
let your you're going to want your
compost te to run a little bit longer to
introduce protozoa into your soil um and
that's only determined by by what the
microscope through microscopy um so that
I do 24 to 36 hours understood well
there has been so much good information
in this episode as well thank you so
much for coming on to the podcast again
let's wrap things up here can you tell
the listeners how they can find you and
if you have anything upcoming in the
future now would be the time to spill it
yeah for sure um so you can find me on
Instagram um Luna all day l u n a l l d
a y um I am a breeder I have stuff that
I've read specifically for large yields
you know unique Expressions unique
Aromas and stuff like that um uh I have
a patreon if you go to my Instagram you
can check out my patreon where I have
whole different recipes like the ones I
was talking about I had go really into
depth into the Sciences behind this
stuff I have tons of research papers um
discussions about you know all the
different things I have like a 100
different channels covering different
topics like we did today um and breaking
them down in detail and you can interact
with me and stuff
too um I do podcasts um with the FCP I
took a break for a while but I'm getting
back on it um and I should have I'll be
doing episodes every Friday at 5:00 um
and you find that on
YouTube uh I've been working with skun
magazine I'm publishing skun magazine um
we just had a new skunk seed line drop
um our website is up skunk Global
genetics.com awesome I'll definitely
have a link I believe to your link tree
that's I think what we used last time so
we can probably do the same thing this
time around that'll get all the links to
what she just mentioned got to give a
shout out to all the patreon folks that
support this podcast patreon.com grow
100% % of what is donated there goes
right back on the podcast so thank you
so much I'm going to put on the screen
right now the folks that are in the
producer tier special thanks to you Luna
once again this has been just an awesome
talk I would like to invite you back on
for a part three but I think I would
like to talk about breeding you know you
said you had 10 years of breeding
experience there's so many different
ways to go about breeding I would love
to sit down with you at some point in
the future and talk breeding if you're
down I'm absolutely down
awesome all right well we will leave it
at that once again thank you so much and
hope you enjoy the rest of your day
thank you have a great day peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode