welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr growt and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 150 in this episode I
interview George Murray he went to
college at Purdue where he studied plant
physiology and plant metabolomics and he
now works in the fer izer industry he is
the formulation chemist for both Ventana
plant science and stash blend in this
episode he talks about several organic
inputs their benefits sourcing bacteria
fungi and more if you want to see short
clips of these podcast episodes search
Gard talk clips on YouTube I also have a
gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said i' like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their cloudray S9
oscillating fan this 9-in fan features a
redesign build with carbon steel gears
and ip44 rating it has 10 precise levels
of fan speeds and dynamic wind modes
which allow you to recreate the natural
flow of air so your plants feel as if
they're outside there's more to it so
click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about their Cloud Ray S9 oscillating fan
and the discount code Mr Gro 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend stash blend is
a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottle nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with George Murray how you doing today
hey doing great how are you good man
thanks for coming out the podcast today
you're on the road I appreciate I know
you're a busy busy guy and uh the only
time you could do it was on the road
which is fine with me as long as I still
get to pick your brain and uh extract
some of that good information from you
absolutely my friend no appreciate your
flexibility appreciate making the time
I'm excited to have the discussion today
and you've been on the from the stash
podcast I think it was twice if I
remember correctly you were on there and
each time man just dropping major major
knowledge bombs I mean I've been looking
through the comment section it's just
people just thanking you left and right
from all the information that you've
been providing so really happy to get
you on this podcast so I can pick your
brain individually without Rob and
pigeons you know asking some questions
I've got you done myself this time so
really excited for this so we're going
to talk about a whole bunch of different
things today you for me formated vitana
plant science that whole nutrient line
you formulated stash blend which is uh
my audience is very familiar with that
so I'm excited to get into those things
but before we get too deep into things
could you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
yeah it's a really good question I mean
it it's it was kind of one piece at a
time right I mean you you you grow up
and uh you know I did a lot of upick um
fruit picking with my mother and that
would go into kind of making jams and
pies and other types of baked goods he's
kind of had this I had this Fascination
I think with this connection of you know
being able to see something from start
to finish and growing something and then
making that into a product and then
sharing that you know throughout the
seasons and and all the emotions that
went with that and as I got older I got
to be a lot more curious about the about
the science side so I went way to Purdue
I studed a lot of plant physiology plant
metabolomics right and then you know I
got into the agrochemical industry and
the fertilizer industry and and really
do more research and figure out you know
how can we effectuate changes in in crop
physiology and maximize our yields and
just it kind of like all the emotions
and and and everything kind of came
together and did my scientific interest
overlapped and you know here we are
today um it's been a journey let's put
it that way awesome and then when did
you kind of link up and get Ventana of
plant science going there was a few
seasons back now um oddly enough it's
funny how time worked works right um
kind time fing having fun been a few
years now and you know Nate was an
introduction uh Nate Lipton who heads up
bana um he he was an introduction of
mutual friend and we just hit it off I
mean Nate's Nate's moving to Shaker man
he uh n is excited about Innovation and
there was just this kind of immediate
connection and we kind of sat down at
the table and said hey you know with
everything that you know and all the
people that you know and everything that
know I think there's some creative work
that can get done here and it's just
been it's been a blast working with him
and his team innovating and and putting
stuff out like stash you know is
obviously you a great example of that
yeah stash Bland I mean I was thinking
back that you formulated that two and a
half years ago now if I remember
correctly and then obviously we did a
year of testing before even releasing
and stuff like that so man time does fly
for sure it does man the gray hair and
the beard is no longer accidental it uh
you know I I wake up one day and I'm
like am I an old man yet and if not how
much longer I got to go because I feel
like it you
know so getting into I want to get into
stash blend first a little bit and I
know some people might be like oh well
this is just going to be an infomercial
for stash blend it's there going to be
more to it than just stash BL don't
worry but I do want to dive into some of
the ingredients because we do get a lot
of questions some really good questions
from folks that are using stash Bland or
interested in using stash Bland and one
of the main questions that we get is
about one of the ingredients which is
corn steep liquor can you tell us all
about corn steep liquor everything from
what it is its benefits how it's sourced
so on and so forth yeah absolutely and
so so corn seed liquer is a byproduct of
of wet corn Milling right so when you
take the corn typically there's
something you want to produce from that
corn right it's a lot here in the US we
do we produce a lot of ethanol from corn
right that goes into fuels but we also
we also produce a lot of starches uh
which you know will go down and create
modified starches and a lot of things
like that
um and we also produce a lot of high
fructose corn syrup from there right and
so the byproduct um from that process is
corn steep liquor right so when you go
through and you go through that wet
Milling process all the amino acids all
the proteins all the vitamins all the
minerals AKA not the starches not the uh
the uh the sugars right that that all
used to get just pitched down the drain
it was a waste product and then someone
at some point in time said now hold on a
minute we've got all these great
proteins peptides amino acids all these
great vitamins and minerals there's
something we should be able to do with
this and it didn't take the plant
Community along to figure out that it
was really an excellent source of of
nutrition at the end of the day and you
know I think for me when you look at the
way corn steep liquor is used right now
it's used as a food source for a lot of
fermentation uh large scale uh
fermentation work that that that goes on
because it's such an excellent uh
fermentation product for biology too and
food source and so when you look at a
lot of the other ingredients in stash
and you look at the overlaps and the
synergies that were creating corn steep
lier as a foundation was a really great
fit um it's a upcycle product would have
gone into a waist Stream So that checks
the box from environmental perspective
great nutritional mineral amino acid
protein profile and uh yeah it's a
little sticky to work with so there's
some things we spray dry it into a
powder and things along those lines but
um that's that's really you know the
foundation of stash and why it's a
foundation of stash it's a it's a great
great foundational product yeah I know
that's listed as one of the top
ingredients for it and contributes to
the the NPK yes one of the questions
that people have asked about the corn
steep liquor is would you happen to know
if the corn was GMO or non-GMO does that
matter uh yeah you know it really
doesn't matter at that point in time
right um you know because you're all
you're talking about extra in and so the
proteins that come out of that you know
are really not going to make a
difference at the end of the day we do
use an organic corn steep liquer so that
would be
non-GMO um and that's that's a lot of
where you know the corn steep liquor
ends up is more in organic applications
so that's kind of the um that that's
kind of the niche that it fills you can
have a non-organic I suppose GMO corn
steep liquor but the iteration that we
use is is organic compliant good to know
and talking about organic compliance I
think it's appropriate to talk a little
bit about omry certification I know we
did touch upon this in a conversation on
from the stash but I think it warrants
on here as well since there's a bit of a
different audience on here but omry
certification we get this question a lot
is like why isn't stash blend omry
certified and this is a conversation
that we had behind the scenes I know you
you probably remember this and it was
kind of generally advised not to go the
omry certification route can you just
break it down for us like omry
certification what is it and what are
like the pros and cons of being omry
certified well I think any certification
any third party certification that you
have it it's you know it helps it helps
Market the product right I mean it's
something that people can recognize
there are other theoretically other
organic certifying agencies that are out
there right um California's got theirs
Washington's got theirs as an example so
just because you don't go to rout of
omry doesn't mean you could do an
Organic certification through another
organic certifier but um you know omry
charges per per size of skew I mean last
I checked anyway it's me it's been a
little while but uh so if we wanted to
sell a one pound bag and a half pound
bag or 50 Grand bag we'd have to pay
different uh prices you know for each
one of those SKS Armory is you know the
organic materials review Institute it's
it's valuable in my estimation it's it's
run by people so it's not a perfect not
a perfect organization by any stretch
imagination
um I would say philosophically some of
the stuff that's on there from an armor
perspective can be a head scratcher for
me um and some of the stuff that's not
on there can be a head scratcher for me
I mean for instance the uh the
polyaspartic acid that we have in there
which I'm sure we'll talk about here in
a bit that that's from sugars that have
been fermented into fic acid and then
aspartic acid and then um you know
that's uh we use heat to polymerize the
aspartic acid and omry says well since
you're using heat to do that it's not
organic anymore and it's like well you
know why not but it's it's just you know
their their philosophies their take on
things versus you know ours and um you
know we have some ingredients in there
that omry says they they don't want to
certify and that's that's fine but we
want to have the best products possible
out to the out to the consumer and
that's the route that we went yeah and I
think also the fees were a big turn off
I mean the amount of money that you got
to pay just to get the omry
certification is pretty extensive and
what do you get out of it you get to use
the logo on the product well big whoop
you know some people are going to care
about it but I think a lot of consumers
these days they don't really care as
much about it you know so yeah we chose
not to go the omry certification route
for for those reasons really yeah I mean
we we want to do right by the
environment want to do right by our
customer right and if It just fits to
where hey we can also get a third party
certification that people see and
understand and recognize and appreciate
that's great but you know if we have the
right ingredients in there and they've
got the right pedigree and they're doing
the right thing for the plants and the
right thing for the
planet I that's that's the most
important piece of the puzzle to me
completely agree and that's where I
think we were all aligned you know when
we sat down and we had these meetings on
it we were just we were completely all
on the same page on that we want to do
what's best for the environment and best
for the customer as well having this
all-in-one blend uh was a huge win for
the customers just less bottles they
have to you know there are less
individual bottles that they have to buy
his additives so having this all inone
blend so it's really really been good on
that Avenue as well seaweed extract I
like to get into that next now this is a
pretty common input a lot of people use
seaweed but break it down for us what is
seaweed extract what are the benefits
how is it sourced so on and so forth
yeah so seaweed grows all the way around
the world right the first thing you have
to answer is what kind of seaweed do you
play with right because there are some
species of seaweed that's been their
entire life life and water right think
of the Kel Forest sou California as an
example right but you know what we're
interested in is those you know
intertitle Zone species right an asphy
andad doam is probably the uh the most
obvious example one and that's the one
that we use and and what happens that
those seaweeds you know end up spending
half their life outside of water as the
water recedes and when you do that you
create incredibly stressful environment
for the plant and that's why the plant's
producing all these secondary
metabolites to survive in those
conditions and it's those secondary
metabolizes from seaweed that we really
like now you can take and harvest that
seaweed which is absolutely sustainable
the seaweed that we uh actually get is
from the uh coast of Ireland um
completely sustainably Harvest and
harvested and uh you can take that
seaweed and you can Mill it wet Mill it
into a seaweed dispersion right and you
get all the cell walls and all the detis
and all the lake
and all the hemicellulose and everything
that's ins soluble in that product along
with that uh but what we've taken to do
is we take that and we Mill the seaweed
and then we extract that with pottassium
hydroxide to create a soluble extraction
of all those little goodies that we like
and that does two things one it cuts out
all the ligin and the hemicellulose and
all the cell wall stuff that you don't
need and that's not soluble in water and
and and two it it increases your
concentration all those beautiful
secondary metabolize those plant defense
mechanisms uh compounds and and the
rooting hormones and things along those
lines that are in uh seaweeds that that
we like and that's um that's the route
that we went so ask found doome arid off
Ireland extract from potassium hydroxide
and that gives you the cleanest product
with the highest concentration of all
the all the goodies that we like in
there yeah I was going to ask you about
the pottassium hydroxide next because
that is listed on the label but I
remember in a past conversation you
mentioned it's not really in there
anymore but you have to put it on there
from a regulatory standpoint fertilizer
laws require you to put that on there
yes but you did cckm for wrong you
mentioned that some pottassium is
available on there right because there's
a reaction that happen can you get into
that yeah exactly potassium hydroxide is
Koh right you've got your potassium ion
you have your hydroxide ion your
potassium is positive your hydroxide is
negative and what happens is that when
you react that with usually to lower pH
secondary plant metabolites the
potassium remains and the hydroxide ions
actually react with the hydrogen ions
that come off the other compounds
creating water so you end up with
potassium salts of all the other goodies
that you like and water as your reaction
product so there's no potassium
hydroxide that actually remains as
potassium hydroxide anymore so you end
up water and potassium and all your
secondary metabolites but the labeling
laws uh and under AFCO and state byst
state require that if you use a
pottassium if you use a um a seaweed
extracted product you have to list the
potassium hydroxide in there with it's
just kind of goofy and again you know I
think like that's probably another thing
that you look at with the labeling laws
you know I think that they always come
from like a point of of good intentions
but I think sometimes they actually
create a lot more confusion than they
actually resolve and uh but that's you
know there another podcast conversation
you know for another
day yeah I'm sure we could get it super
deep about that but uh yeah we'll avoid
that conversation for now yeah but one
thing I did want to mention that when we
talk about labeling there is something
that is in stash blend that's not on the
label and that is the amino acid polymer
and I forget the reason why you
mentioned why it can't be on the label
maybe you can expand on that a little
bit can you talk to us about amino acid
polymer just in general everything about
yeah absolutely so you know there's
there's there's a number of different
amino acid polymers that you know are
out there and obviously you know amino
acids hook together to create peptides
and then from peptides they grow into
proteins right and you know what we try
to do though with our amino acid
polymers it's it's we take a singular
amino acid which is a spartic acid right
and then we take that as spartic acid
and we use exceptionally high heat right
500° F and we fused those aspartic acid
monomers together to form an aspartic
acid polymer and from there we'll react
it with potassium hydroxide where we
heard this before to make it a soluble
polymer instead of an insoluble polymer
and um there the story behind how this
concept came about actually uh
originates from the late 80s they had
discovered that mollusks in the ocean
build their shells out by taking calcium
from the Water by using an aspartic acid
polymer and it's a completely a lot of
our polymers out there have that a
synthetic man-made polymers that we use
like polyacrylates and things along
those lines uh they're not biodegradable
right so they don't break down in the
environment and so someone said hey look
you know we've got mollusks that are
creating this amino acid polymer to grab
on the nutrients to help build out their
shells wouldn't this work in agriculture
and if so how could we diagram a way to
produce this in mass and predictably and
get this out in agriculture because we
we can use this to grab nutrients out of
the soil and increased nutrient uptake
and oh by the way the process to make it
you only your byproduct is water vapor
and your polymer is fully
biodegradable and actually the polymer
that we make is food great it actually
there's probably another conversation
with another day but it actually goes
into uh beverages all over the world uh
certain very specific beverages but um
again it's another story for another day
but um that's you know that's the whole
story so but again there's labeling laws
and there's requirements there's all
sorts of stuff and so we wanted to have
the best possible product we wanted to
to have something was going to increase
nutritional uptake in Plants right which
is really you know the the whole secret
story behind that has blend and uh you
know we do that with Biology we're doing
that with seaweeds we're doing that with
corn steep Liquors that's feeding the
biology in the plant and then we have
this this beautiful uh aspartic acid
polymer that's in that mix that's uh
chemically helping grab onto the
nutrients and also acting as a terrific
food source for the bacteria and biology
on the back end so um but it's not on
the label because again you know
labeling requirements and and things
like that and you know we've got Decades
of research on this stuff but it it
never seems to be in the exact right
format that each state want some states
have no problem some states and
predictably you're going to know
probably which states those are um I
think they just like putting their ores
in the water you know what I mean and uh
so that's you know that's a little bit
behind so we kind of go back to that
labeling law stuff and then the tents
are good but it actually ends up harming
consumers in some ways because you know
we're not able to put everything we want
to put on there but we want to build out
the best products possible exactly I
appreciate you expanding on that one I
do want to get into humic acid next can
you talk to us about what is humic acid
what are the benefits reasoning why it
was uh added into stash blend and all
that stuff I mean humic acid has had a
big following for a long time right and
I think there's some serious synergies
when you add humix in with seaweeds and
with our polyamino and we we've done
other types of work and and released
other products of that that same sort of
synergy and hemic acid is that you know
if you if you look at at um its age it
was you know usually produced in the
Carboniferous era millions and millions
of years ago had we left it in the
ground it would have eventually turned
into coal but it hadn't gotten there yet
and you know it was produced in a time
period in our Earth with the carbon
content the carbon dioxide content was
exceptionally high so you have a lot of
carbon and you've got a lot of really
great really great complex carbon
sources that are part of humic acid so
you mine the human right and then you're
going to take the soluble low molecular
fraction off that that's fulvic acid
that will come off in the process and
then what's left is that higher
molecular weight
organic uh or carbon containing
compounds and a lot of times you'll
again you'll hear this again you're
using potassium hydroxide to create
soluble compounds from that mass right
and hemic acid we is actually mined down
in Florida it's produced here in the US
it's a really clean really beautiful
product but the thing I like about humic
acids is again it's a very complex High
molecular weight source of organic
carbon which is really great for biology
because the more complex you get in your
organic matter the more difficult it is
for the biology that we don't want to
feed to use it right uh you know the
harmful pathogenic biology that is so
we've got a great food source there very
complex but we've also got a really lot
of interesting secondary metabolite
compounds that come in with that humic
acid suit and I think it's hard for
people to put their fingers on exactly
what those compounds are aren't if you
run it through like high pressure liquid
chromatography and uh or mass
spectrometry right you can start to kind
of pick apart you know exactly what's in
there what's not some of them are kind
of unidentifiable some of them are but
what happens and what usually happens is
that good food source of bacteria and
biology but all so there's some nice
secondary metabolites that it sounds
wild to say this but have survived for
millions of years chemically intact and
you know have a response on plant growth
as well yeah hemic acid was something
that uh I didn't really even think of to
potentially add to stash blend but I
know that's something you you wanted to
put in there and I thought it was a
fantastic idea and yeah it definitely
works well in that mix I want to get
into silica next on the label you have
soluble silicon
silica I know it's a highly purified
silicon dioxide in there some parts are
soluble some parts are insoluble but
break it down for us all the details on
silica yeah it's it's that's a that's a
double duty mix right uh ingredient we
have it there functionally for the blend
itself because there's a lot of what we
call hygroscopic elements in there and
hygroscopic elements mean elements that
want compounds that want to pull in
water right so corn seep liquor is
really hygroscopic the polyaspartate
polymer is really hygroscopic right and
so the silica will actually do a really
great job of holding water as well and
so we wanted to try to kind of mitigate
some of the clumping issues that
consumers would have uh as much as we
could these really sensitive compounds
obviously we're not going to eliminate
everything but we wanted to include
silica in there as a mechanism that
would help absorb water a lot like you
would find in like silica packets right
and and food stuffs or things like that
where you're trying to absorb the water
and prevent uh your food from spoiling
or whatnot but beyond that you know we
said look this is going to work from a
functional perspective for the product
that's kind of an anti-clumping aid but
can this also be a silica source for
plants right because you know plants you
know you look at calcium deposition and
building walls and obviously it cross
links with Boron you know so you can't
have calci calcium deposition if you
don't have boron but you know silica
actually plays a really really big part
in in building out the scaffolding of
cells as well more of an exterior rather
than an interior component and I read an
article the other day where they were
actually considering making uh silicon
essential nutrient right that says hey
you need silica right which I thought
was really interesting because there's
always this debate of do you need silica
do you not need silica in my opinion you
know having silica is always always
going to help
now you know there's a lot of silica out
there in the world right and really what
it comes down to is available silica
right so that's why when you put it on
the label you can only put in what the
acid soluble silic fraction is because
that's what's available to the plant
because if we really wanted to put in a
bunch of silicon we could have put in
sand which is silicon dioxide right but
we all know Sand's not available to
plants you look at the particle size you
look at how that's going to break down
how it's going to react so what we do is
we start with a nanop particle silicon
dioxide it's been build down
exceptionally small when you say Nano
particle you're talking about nanometers
right uh exceptionally small size and so
that makes it a lot easier to react with
the biology react with the water sources
and create that acid soluble silica
that's then available to plant and
that's usually in a form of monic acid
or orthosilicic acid right and so it's
it's it's double duty you've got kind of
an anti-clumping a that's in the product
but you've also got the right form of
silicon the right size that's going to
be readily available to the plant as
well so that was that was a pretty cool
pretty cool thing we built in there and
correct me if I'm wrong the plant will
release acids microbes will release
acids that produce hydrogen ions they're
going to react and turn it into the
monosilicic and orisic acid is that
right there you go it's exactly right so
you've got a really small particle Nano
particle silicon dioxide you hook a
hydrogen or a couple hydrogens up to
that
and uh introduce some water and Bobs
your uncle there you go and the pH is
totally impacted in the medium and I'd
like to kind of derail a little bit and
talk about pH in the medium because I
think a lot of folks are confused about
pH they think like okay the water source
that they mix in on the nutrients that
they mix up and adjust the pH on when
they water it in they're expecting that
that's what it is in the medium as well
and you know you've got a pH on the
medium then you also look at the risos
spere where it could be different uh but
the plant releases acids and microbes
release acids that change the pH can you
expand on that at all yeah I mean pH is
just that concentration between hydrogen
ions which are acidic and hydroxide ions
which are basic right and so you know
you've got inputs like your water source
you've got inputs like your fertilizer
sources and that are absolutely going to
play a bit of a role when it comes to
the pH of the soil right but really you
have that Bal bance of minerals that are
in the soil that are going to be the
ultimate dictators there and and and to
go A Step Beyond that a lot of what
happens is that it's really the plant
that's able to kind of help modify and
and its rizosphere and some plants are a
lot better at this in other plants right
just depends on genetics where they've
grown up naturally what kind of genetics
they're carrying if they've had to
modify their environment a lot of
tropical a lot of tropical plants grow
in very acidic soils they're very old
soils very weathered soils and so you
know those plants are Adept at releasing
hydroxide ions to buffer their ph up and
then you have other plants that uh you
know can grow in more alkaline
environments knowing that the soil needs
to be a little more acidic for them to
take up essential micronutrients like
iron or manganese or zinc for an example
and they're a lot better at releasing
hydroxide ions right that's going to
acidify that that rizosphere and acidify
that soil surface so uh a at the at the
roots and in the ball media but you know
really you know a lot of what happens in
this exchange between the roots and the
soil is that when a plant takes up uh
let's say a positively charged nutrient
like ammonium as an example it will
release a hydrogen to balance that right
because otherwise it' be acidifying
itself and that's why something like
ammonium sulfate as a nitrogen source
will reduce the pH in your soil right um
you know a lot of people use Elemental
sulfur to drop pH in soil and what
happens there is actually a chemical
reaction between the elemental sulfur
turning into sulfuric acid from a
biological reaction right so those are
some kind of examples but you know what
we did with with the stash blend it's a
very neutral blend very low use rate um
you know you're not going to see a lot
of pH differences when you use this
product right I mean it's it's a very
neutral product both in terms of its pH
of itself but also in and how it works
with the plant and taking up nutrients
it's there to assist the plant take up
nutrients in general you're going to
move the pH of the soil by adding in
things like calcium carbonate in bulk or
ammonium sulfate or Elemental sulfur in
bulk depending on you know what you're
growing and what you want to do great
points and I know I hear a lot of
organic Growers that uh often say they
don't pH their soil and they're like oh
yeah the biology in the medium is going
to take care of it and this is a perfect
example you explained in detail how that
can happen that plus the plants
releasing acids so really good info
there yeah now you have a lot of
knowledge on bacteria as well so
bacteria there's a Consortium of
bacteria in stash blend there's a billus
Lin formis billus pelli billus subtilus
and then a Pam basilis Asos fixen which
I probably butchered all of those names
you know it came close right yeah you
can't really close break it down for us
all about bacteria you know what those
particular species do for plant Health
yeah I think when you look at that mix
right and simple Google searches will
tell you you know specifically what each
one of those do and I think In fairness
of time without going too far down a
rabbit hole I don't think I'll address
you know each one of them and it's in
this particular but you have that genus
and species that identifies what what
you have right
but it's not quite that simple because
then you have different
strains of those genus and species right
and so each different strain of a basil
a subtilus example um is going to work a
little bit differently from one strain
to the next and so what we've identified
over a course of time and and through a
fermentative process is a strain of
Select individuals that will do
primarily two things is what we're
trying to accomplish one is just overall
plan Health right and guarding that
risos spere and uh and giving those
molecular signals to the plant and out
competing the pathogenic bacteria that
might be in a soil and then the other is
nutrient uptake and usually what we're
looking at there is just kind of overall
from an enzymatic perspective but also
uh in in particular from a nitrogen
uptake perspective as well and you know
if you look at the stash BL I know we've
talked about you know individual
ingredients right and and kind of on
their own I think every one of the
ingredients on their own has real Merit
right I think it's going to absolutely
help you in your growth but I think in
the format that we have them the
specific species that we built out in
our biology the amino acid polymer the
humic of seaweeds a food source in form
of corn steep liquor that Synergy of
ingredients that we've tied in you know
across multiple continents of raw
materials and brought into one bag you
know I think that's that's where that
special performance really comes into
when you use those things and synergies
um and so the biology is you know
obviously a big part of that that it is
lyophilized it's freeze dried onto a
sugar based substrate and uh when it
gets into water that uh the signal to
the biolog is hey we've got water again
uh let's rock and roll and and the
reason we use a sugar- based substrate
so the the the there's a hency with
those sugars right so the cells don't
dry out when you're going through that
lyophilization process and
lyophilization is freeze drying by the
way so you can spray dry with heat or
you can freeze dry uh using cold
temperatures and uh at that point in
time it's more kind of an evaporation
sulation if you go from a freezing to a
gas um but it's a lot more gentle when
it comes to the survival of the species
and using those
Hants um those osmolytes or are how we
how we preserve the uh the bacteria I
think the species that intrigues me the
most is the Pam basilis azos fictions
because it's nitrogen fixing bacteria
just it blows my mind that they're able
to grab nitrogen from the air and
convert into a form that the plant can
uptake I thought that was so cool yeah
it is really neat and there's more of
that coming right I mean I think even in
R crop if you look at some of the
companies that are out there some of the
startup companies um there's gaining
traction where they're they're putting
these specific species and strains of
biology down to help bring in nitrogen
and they're they they know predictably
that you can reduce your your synthetic
nitrogen inputs by X number of pounds
per acre when they do that and that's
that's neat and we need we need more of
that by the way because there's an
incredible amount of emissions uh that
are that are offut during that
manufacturing of fertilizer as you know
and and the industry is not resting on
its Laurels I think people are actively
trying to figure out
a a Hab Bosch process where you can fix
nitren from the air you know using
sustainable uh electricity and and and
with reduced pressures and reduced heat
and um we're not there yet obviously but
you know that's that's a process that's
you know 100 years old and uh it needs
some updating but attacking it from the
biological side you know to me yeah yes
please let let's see more of that yeah
if it can be sustainable and not cause
harm to the environment that would be
fantastic yeah now next to really on any
micro product you should see a
cfu SLG which stands for Colony forming
units per gram can you kind of talk to
us a little bit about it like what does
that actually mean what are some
reasonable amounts uh yeah I mean
reasonable amounts are going to be you
know depending on use rates right at the
end of the day and depending on the
species themselves how well do they
colonize you know how are they going to
out compete other
organisms um you know the colony forming
units per gram is just a way to to
recognize what's the what's the density
of viable uh viable living organisms if
you put it in in one gram it's just it's
just a way to measure how many viable
living organisms you actually have and
that's third party certified by the way
I mean we've got to send out to the
third party lab they've got to they've
got to grow uh the species on the pet
tree dish and be able to measure that
for us and give us a number for to be
able to put that on on the bag and
that's also why the bag has an
expiration date even though since it's
completely dry you know the expiration
dat is kind of something that's legally
we have to put on there but I think you
know it's U not something that I think
goes bad in the insiration date but um
yeah it's just a way to be able to
express at the end of the day how many
living viable units you have and mean
you'll see 10 to six 10 to seven 10 to
eight that's a million you know two
million 100 million billion you know
when you get a 10 to the nth right um
you know anything around those numbers
10 to fifth even depending on the
species you know you get into really low
counts you know you wonder sometimes if
there's more you know Sizzle than steak
but um I think to me it's just
trusting uh what you see with a plant
right if you're going to use the
biological product you know what do you
see from it do do you see benefits do
you not are you putting it in um you
know a uh media that is is fairly
sterile you know because you're going to
see probably different things from that
are you putting it out there in a in a
composted outdoor environment that's
teeming with Biology right I think
there's some you know are you going into
an into a situation where there was
steam sterilization in the soil and
you're
rebuilding um you know let let your eye
and let your yield indicators tell you
uh whether a biological product or
biologically based product or prodct
contains biology is doing what you want
it to do rather than how many Colony
forming units is printed on the bag got
it and I see next to the bacteria it's
col Colony forming units but next to the
endom micro it's prop SLG what does that
mean yeah it's just propagules right so
that's that's just another way to
measure you're dealing with a different
organism obviously um you know when you
when you go from bacteria to fungi so
it's how those are measured and you know
micro isy are difficult because I don't
think there is as much consensus out
there in the laboratory methods to
measure those I think they're a lot
harder to measure uh at the end of the
day and I think for me it's about taking
reputable Partners when it comes to uh
mic rizy and um you know but that's
that's the same sort that's analogous to
cfus is uh you know how much how much
can you can you propagate and uh from
that from that uh input there okay so
Endo microz that's in stash blend
there's four different species of glomus
in here I won't try to butcher the four
different ones
there it well inter interes is the most
important one no doubt I mean you look
at endom micro and what and what it does
the the vast majority of research that
that you'll find out there is on
intereses and it's it's a heavy lifter
but the Endo uh package that we use was
was specifically built out to be water
soluble um to be able to be run through
irrigation to be used in in large scale
you know Greenhouse grows as an example
and um all the micro isal packages out
there micro isal suppliers we could work
with um that that to me was and it was
fairly new iteration too a fairly new
new launch um and that's why we we built
that one into there and mic risel fungi
has so many benefits can you just give
you want to give us a quick rundown
well I think you know I think it's it's
one of the more classic examples of you
know an excellent symbiotic relationship
where you have you know the endom
microid that they're actually moving
into the vascular system of the plant
and extending out a Ty into the soil and
you're magnifying the plant's going to
give up a little energy to do that so
it's it's a tradeoff uh but what you're
doing is you're magnifying the the root
system of the plant basically when you
do that so the plants you your your
nutrient uptake is is is to find root
hairs not your structural larger roots
that have been lignified but it's the
root hairs that um that do that and so
those root hairs will Slough off and die
and and continue to reproduce and and
grow and so you know you have the plant
taking up nutrients to its root hairs
but then you have also uh these micro
rizy these endom micro rizy that are
growing into the vascular system of the
plant and tying in directly and they're
growing out their High Fe and so in
parallel kind of there root hair uptake
now you have the ability to take up
nutrients through the micro rizy as well
and uh it's a it's a great great
symbiotic relationship awesome yeah I
know you hear a lot of it uh has with
phosphorus how it really helps like
unlock phosphorus make it more available
and and be able to transport it and all
that stuff so yeah and you hear that
because phosphorus is you fairly Mobile
in the soil right so it's all about
route interception and so when you're
able to expand you know your either real
rot system or your borrow root system
from micro rizy your odds of stumbling
across uh nutrients uh improves greatly
you know at the end of the day and then
you build in your poly aspirate in there
which helps with phosphorus you build in
your bacteria you the micro rizy and and
if you think about it it it's a um it's
it's more of a longer term play right
the bacteria can move in the soil and
can start working the other elements
that we have in the stash blend can move
into soil and start working right away
right but the micro Riza you know
they've got to infiltrate into the roots
they've got to grow out their root
system so that's more of a a a longer
term play and while you're having this
turnover all your wonderful you know uh
uh biological compounds and and bacteria
that's in that so unfortunately at this
point George's connection dropped being
on the road it's just me here now and I
wanted to close out this episode so
first off big thanks to George for
coming on to the podcast like I
mentioned in the beginning of the
episode George is the formulation
chemist for both Ventana PL science and
stash blend so I have links to those
products down in the YouTube description
section below also link the from the
stash episode that we did with him
awesome awesome episode there I
recommend all of you go to that episode
after this one as far as social media
George isn't really on social media and
he likes his personal time so there'll
be no social media links for him or ways
for you to contact him but if you
comment down below and mention part two
if we get enough of them maybe I can
have him come on again in the future
also list any questions that you may
have for George down in the comment
section below and if I'm able to get him
back on for another episode maybe I'll
ask some of those questions also want to
give a big thank you to the patreon
supporters
patreon.com grow on the screen right now
the folks in the producer tier 100% of
the money that is donated through
patreon goes right back into the podcast
so big thank you to the supporters over
there who keep this podcast going that's
it for this episode thank you so much
for tuning in and I'll catch catch you
in the next episode peace out everyone