Welcome to the Garden Talk podcast,
where we interview growers from all over
the world, both beginners and experts
seeking to learn more about what they
know about gardening and how they do
things in their garden. What's up
everybody? For those of you that don't
know me, my name is Chris aka Mr. Growit
and you're tuned into the Garden Talk
podcast. This episode number 171. In
this episode, I interview Mile High
Dave. He has been gardening for 25 years
and has won multiple grow competitions.
And that's what we're going to get into
in today's episode. We'll learn a little
bit about him, what competitions he's
entered and won, and specific gardening
strategies that he does in order to win.
If you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes, search garden talk
clips on YouTube. I also have a
gardening channel where I show the
plants that I grow. Both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below. One
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public. That being said, I'd
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make the goal
possible. Thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode. Check out their
controller 69, which can help automate
your environment's conditions. It'll
automatically turn on and off equipment
to help control the temperature,
humidity, BPD, light schedule, and even
the oscillating fans. Click the link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about the controller 69. And
the discount code Mr. Grow 15 works on
both Amazon and their website
acfinity.com. Stash Blend, several
additives in one blend, so you no longer
have to buy individual bottles. Check it
out at
stashblend.com, link in the description
section below, and use the discount code
the stash Spider Farmer. Check out their
new white grow tent, which comes in
various sizes. It has a 200D canvas
density, making it tearproof and
waterproof, rollup doors for easy
access, and a highly reflective Myar
interior. More information is linked in
the description section below, and their
420 sale is still going on now until
April 30th. Discount code Mr. Growit 5
works on both Amazon and their website
spider-farmer.com. And we are back and
I'm joined with Milo. Hi Dave. How you
doing today? Good. How you doing? Doing
good, man. Thanks for joining me today.
So, you have actually entered in and won
grow competitions in the past. And
that's one thing I really want to dive
into today. I want to learn how you go
about it. And I'm not just talking about
what competitions are out there and how
to enter them, but your specific
strategies that have helped you win. I
have to charge everybody a billion
dollars then if they want to know
exactly cuz then I'm going to tell you
the winning formula.
No, I'm just kidding. Of course. Of
course. Yeah, I don't have a problem
with that. Awesome, man. Sounds good.
But before we get too deep into things,
can we do an introduction? Maybe tell us
a little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening. Sure. Um, I've been
growing on and off for 25 years, I would
say. On uh professionally, uh, you know,
in the legal market for the last five
years. All right. And then what made you
get into entering competitions? Um, I,
you know, I I always had people tell me
that I that I grew really good
flower.
So, I wanted to see if it was just, you
know, people blowing smoke or if if I if
I my flower was good enough to compete.
I I just felt like that was the next
logical evolutionary step was to go get
into competitions because if everybody's
telling my flower's so good, my flower
is so good. Um let's see if it's good
enough to beat other people who hear the
same thing as me. You know, that was
kind of just my motivation there. And I
felt like if uh and you know, I also
thought, you know, I don't want to just
compete locally because I think that's
what everybody does. I wanted to go
other everywhere I could possibly do it
and compete to really showcase that
yeah, what I have is special because I
felt like it was. And what competitions
have you entered and what awards have
you won? Um, I've won the Colorado
Connoisseur Cup. I I guess that was the
first competition that I really entered
seriously. um you know as a solo grower
and wanted to test my skill and and my
uh um selection process you know uh I
wanted to prove that my selection
process was superior to a lot of these
other guys in the competition circuit.
So, the Colorado Connoisseur Cup is a
8-monthlong blind judging competition
um here in Colorado, and I um I entered
that first with my Dante's Inferno
number six feno that I hunted um some
years ago, and it was really special,
and it it it took first place. Um, from
there, I believe the next competition I
won was
the I want to say the Cultivate Supply
Showdown
um, here in Colorado again as well, put
on by Cultivate Supply Store. Um, that's
another blind judging competition. Um,
and I was able to come out first place
on that one as well, which was really
cool. And the the very next competition
I believe I won was in Las Vegas. It was
the Candy Connect Community Candy Battle
Royale and I won that again. All of
those competitions I won with the same
Feno, Dante's Inferno number six. Um,
except for the second win on the
Colorado Connoisseur Cup I won with one
of my newest fenos, the 5280, as well as
my second wind win on the Connect uh,
Battle Royale. They had a The first
round of the Connect Battle Royale was a
candy battle royale. The second round
was candy and gas. So, last year I won
with Dante's Infernos number six, I won
uh best overall, best candy. This year I
won best gas with the 5280. So, which is
what I was going for. I was like, last
year I won candy, it'd be cool to go in
there and win gas this year, which I was
able to pull off. Man, that's so cool.
So, million-dollar question here is, is
Dante's Inferno number six available
anywhere? Seed form, clone, anything?
Yeah, I've I've released some I've made
some S1s and I also have the clone
available, but the only thing with that
cut is now it's extremely volatile and
it has a tendency tom under like the
slightest stressor. So, you have to
really be in tune with the plant and
understand how to how to feed it um and
how it grows to really be successful
with it because if not, it can get wild
on you and it'll pollinate a whole room
and then you're kind of like ah you're
you know, you're not liking it. So, um,
it's not something that I ever really
recommend for people. I have had people
buy it from me before because they've
been willing to take on the risk. Some
have been successful, some have not.
That's really interesting. I hear from
other breeders from time to time where
it's like we've have this picture
painted in our head that any type of
genetics that herm out is a sign of
weakness, yet you're over here winning
competitions with it. Right. So,
Exactly. That just proves that um you
know that's my my thinking precisely is
always outside the box just because
something you know don't get me wrong if
it hurt to the point to where like it
was detrimental every time but if it was
if it's manageable in the flower is
worth it which it really is. I mean it
the level of uniqueness um again we'll
go back to competitions after the candy
battle royale I won spanabis in Spain
with the same pheno. So to go from local
competitions to statewide competitions
to worldwide competitions with the same
cut and win over and over and over all
blind competitions. I have nothing I you
know Spain I I've never been to Spain in
my life. I don't know anybody in Spain.
You know to go there and win was just
like wow. Like I know what when I have
something special and I knew this feno
was exceptionally special. In all my
years of being a connoisseur going back
to high school, I've never seen anything
like it, smelled anything like it. So,
and it's really the flavor profile that
gets you. Um, you know, there's
good-looking we good-looking flower
everywhere, but the flavor profile is
what really stands out. And it's like a
it's like a cherry
uh rotten fruit, cherry sugar candy
concentrate times like a hundred. it it
the smallest amount in the room will
permeate the entire you know space that
it's in. I I can have some at home. I
have about uh you know around 3,000
square ft at home and I can have like a
fairly small amount on my countertop and
it'll literally fill fill from basement
to the top floor all with the scent and
it's like it's almost like like like
some type of air fresh. It's amazing how
it just spreads. Like I've never had any
feno in my life that's done that. So,
you know, that's I think is one of the
reasons why it's won so many
competitions. Um, and the, you know,
it's not just, you know, a lot of people
ask me, how do you do it? How do you do
it? How do you do it? I don't think
it's, you know, knowing how to grow well
is important. Um, but really having that
flavor palette to know when something is
different or to know when something is
special, I think is what really can make
you stand out from the rest. That makes
total sense. Now, how about your grow
style, right? How are you growing these
plants? Are you indoors, outdoors? Are
you in soil, cocoa, hydro, organic?
Indoor cocoa. I run the Athena Pro line.
Um, as you can see, I I I've been
running Athena for years. I've never
been successful with any other nutrient
line in my life. And I'm not going to
say that there isn't something out there
that's equivalent or better, but I just
never ran into it. So, I use it, you
know, I use what I know works. Um I I I
grow in 100% cocoa, but I can grow in
any media. I prefer cocoa over rockwool
just
environmentally. Um you have a much more
room for error with cocoa. If there's a
slight error with rockwool, it can cost
you an entire crop. Uh error with cocoa,
you have a you you have a buffer. You
have some room to bounce back. For
instance, like if you didn't w let's say
you missed in a watering event with
cocoa, that can destroy your whole crop.
There's no bringing those plants back
once they reach a certain level of
dryback, you know. Um, with cocoa, they
can be wilty and you can water and
there'll be enough stiletto in there to
bring them back. Got it. And with that
Athena lines, it's actually I just got
my hands on it. I haven't a chance to
run it yet, but I've heard that sticking
to the actual feeding chart is what you
want to do. You don't want to actually
go outside of that. Are you going
outside of that at all or I have my own
special feeding program for Athena 100%.
Um I'm not going to say that I go uh
outside the chart in ter I don't use any
other additives, but I
um I have my own my own style, my own
way that I like to do things. Okay. And
then for flour that you're growing for
competitions, are you doing anything
differently on a feeding aspect? No. No.
the same way I I I grow, you know, at
the same way I've always grown my
flowers, the same way I grow it for
competitions. I don't do anything
different. Um, I just focus on I think
one of the main things with high quality
flour in my opinion is the drying
process. A lot of people rush that or
flub that and it tends to uh once you
lose turpps, there's no way to bring
them back, right? So, you know, the name
of the game is to preserve the flavor
profile and if you even have one. Um,
but that the N if you have a solid pla
flavor profile and you can preserve that
and it translates into, you know,
smokable flour, then that is going to
be something that's going to set you
apart from the rest. And I I I would say
n that's one of the biggest mistakes
that a lot of these growers and grows
and facilities make is rushing the
drying process. If you're drying your
flower in a week, you're doing it too
fast and you're going to have a
substandard product in the end. Yeah, a
lot of people they just mess up towards
the end. They get through the whole
growth cycle, all of a sudden they get
into drying and then they they mess
things up and all and and it blows my
mind because why would you spend all
this time, all this money, you know,
growing trying to grow the best quality
product ever to rush the last week? like
dude 10 to 14 days is a proper amount of
time even a little bit longer but I
would say you know 10 to 16 days tops
depending on your uh environmentals in
your dry space. I was going to ask you
about the environment conditions. What
are you aiming for for temperature and
humidity and drying? I like to run 6565
the whole way through. Oh okay. If and
that takes you to the 10 to 16 day until
it's dry and then you put it into jars.
Slow dry is what you want to really
preserve flavor profile. If you rush it,
you're going to ruin it. It still might
look good. It'll be it'll it'll be
smokable and people will like it, but
it's not going to be what it could have
been. It'll never go back. So, slow and
steady is the way to go in my opinion.
And then do you take it after drying and
you do a dry trim and then put into jars
or do you use grove bags or what's your
storage? After drying, I package ready
for sale. I personally believe that
flour is best when it's freshest. I
don't believe in any threemon you know
crazy long month cures.
Um about two week dry two week cure
ready for market is is is my my honest
opinion. That's when flour is at its
best. Um I mean but I've also had flour
that I've entered in into competitions
that I've had in my freezer for 6 months
and taken first place. So, uh, I think
knowing how to preserve flour, like
knowing when that right time to, um, to
fully package your flour and and have it
like ready to go is is what you need to
do. Got it. I want to back up and talk
about traits. Now, you already talked
about in the competitions that really
flavor was something that stuck out in
yours. Is that all that they're looking
for when it comes to picking a strain
for competition? Or are people looking
actually plant structure, potency,
effects, like what what's really
prioritized when it comes to traits? A
lot of these competitions, um, in my
opinion, they look
for all of the above. Um, you know, they
look for flavor, they look for
structure. Um, a lot of the ones that I
like to enter, I like to enter
competitions that look for flavor
profile as one of the judging metrics
because in my opinion, I think that's
one of the most important things and one
of the things that we've kind of lost in
today's recreational world. Uh there's
so many of the same flavor profiles
regardless of name out there that it's
just it's just, you know, brought the
the industry and my point to a level
where there's nothing unique left.
Everything is the same. Everything
smells the same, tastes the same, looks
the same. And I'm really trying to step
away from that and bring back things
that I remember. things that I remember
as a connoisseur, like as a teenager,
was always a unique flavor profile. You
know, there's there's flavor profiles
that I can remember right now at 47
years old that I ran into at 16 that I
still haven't seen again, you know. So,
those are the kind of things I'm looking
for, something unique that I've never
seen before. And I look for judging
competitions that have that as a metric
because I believe that's a that's a a
strong way to win because, you know,
it's like that that that excellent meal
or that, you know, that superb drink or
whatever it might be that you had that
you it's always flavor pallets that
stick to your memory that really like,
you know, leave that lasting memory in
my opinion. Understood. Yeah. I hear the
same thing from so many people to where
everything just tastes the same these
days. You know, a lot of similar effects
as well. very dull. A lot of people are
saying that there's a lot of dull
flavor, smell, effects, and that uh it's
really tough to find good stuff these
days. So, well, and I think that's
because a lot of uh you know,
recreational, you know, you have two
types of growers. You have a corporate
model, which is a lot of the industry
right now, unfortunately. And corporate
models, they're not in it for the love
of it. They're in it to make money. So,
you know, a lot of those models when
they step into the industry, they're
thinking, uh, what's the best genetic?
Oh, it's gelato. We need gelato. Let's
buy as many gelato clones as we have.
And, you know, and that's why there's so
much of that out there. Uh, they're
they're not looking for uniqueness. And
then you have guys like me that really
want to bring, you know, something cool
to the people. So, I think uh guys like
me are going to win out in the long run
cuz the corporate model is not a model
that's sustainable. I hear you. I think
ever since it's gone recreational a lot
of these states it's gotten worse and
going down to being the connoisseur and
and really being craft more craft style
to where you're bringing that uniqueness
like you mentioned it's far and few
between. So right corporate model is is
not sustainable in this industry at all
in my opinion. Yep. Uh it just it's just
not. People want the the people who want
quality are the ones who are going to
last. Agreed. That's a whole
conversation on its own, right? Let's uh
let's get back to growing. I do have a
good question here for you that I think
a lot of people are going to want to
know the answer to. Lighting. When it
comes to growing these plants for
competitions, are you doing anything
different as far as lighting a
particular strategy that you feel like
gives you an edge in quality or tricom
development? So, I don't grow uh my
flower any different for competitions
versus like if I was growing it at home
for myself. Um I have the same standard
throughout, you know. Um but lighting is
very important for Tricom development. I
I run Thinkrow LEDs, which in my opinion
are one of the more superior lights on
the market today. There might be
something better. Uh there might be
something equivalent, but I don't know
what it is. I haven't run into it yet.
So, with that being said, Thinkros are
my go-to lights. They have like the most
amazing spectrum tuning, uh, UV, far
red, all those things are important for
and will increase tricom development as
well as a early finish. Uh, you know,
you can finish a strain that would
normally take 58 days and 52 with the
with proper spectrum tuning. So, um,
which can, you know, significantly
increase profits and yields if you're
looking at it from, um, you know, a
business standpoint. So, are you adding
in UV? You mentioned UV. Are you adding
that in? If so, what's your strategy for
that? 100% I use UV and far red. Uh,
usually I alternate those spectrums the
last 15 minutes
before the plants go to sleep in the
first 15 minutes before they wake up.
So, you'll just get either straight far
red or straight UV just depending on
where I'm at and um what exactly I'm
trying to achieve. But the end goal for
all of that is increased tricom
development, increase flavor, early
finish. And the UV and far red, is that
only for the flowering stage? Correct.
Okay. The entire flowering stage or late
flowering only? I use it through the
entire flowering stage. Like I said, I
alternate um when I'm using it depending
on where I'm at and what results I'm
trying to achieve. And then you touched
base, you already mentioned that you
don't really do anything differently for
flower that you're entering into
competitions versus your own personal
grow. No. So for your environment, what
conditions are you typically aiming for?
Um, in terms of temperature, humidity, I
mean, it really just depends on where
I'm at, but I usually keep temperature
around, you know, between like 78 and 82
degrees, just depending on where I'm at
in the flowering stage. And humidity can
vary as well, anywhere from 60 to
50% just depending on where I'm at in
the flowering stage. I I make
adjustments daily according
to environmental readings, according to
runoff, like you know, little things get
adjusted usually daily. So, it's not I
don't really have I can't say I have a
set 100% set SOP for how I grow. Things
can be adjusted, you know, according to
how the environmentals are in play
daily. Interesting. Okay. So, you really
It sounds like you're really fine-tuning
things day by day. Now, how about CO2?
Are you supplementing that at all or no?
100%. CO2 is a must in my opinion for
especially if you're running uh high
PPFD. Um people need to remember that
more you turn your lights up, the more
you should turn your CO2 up. Those
things, those two CO2 and PPFD should
always correlate. And then what do you
typically aim for for a ppm of CO2?
Right around 1500. But like again those
adjustments are usually made like I'll
make adjustments in CO2 levels
throughout the weeks. So anywhere from
1100 you know 1500 or more just
depending on what I'm trying to achieve.
Okay. Yeah I've heard of uh studies
around that range. I think it was
like400 ppm was uh like a 30% increase
in yield or something crazy like that.
So yeah supplementing CO2 you can
definitely get a increased amount in
yield. uh you just got to make sure that
obviously your other conditions are
fine-tuned as well. You increase the
light levels and environment is dialed
in, nutrition and all that stuff.
Another important factor is uh under
canopy air flow. A lot of people don't
uh you know take that into
consideration, but the more air flow
that you have in your room, the better
and healthier your plants will be and
the more they'll respond positively to
the rest of your environment. That's a
really good point. Yeah, I definitely
think that's one thing that a lot of
people sleep on is the under canopy air
flow. Yes. Get air flow in the root
zone. They love it. Now, how about
precision stress techniques? Are you
doing anything throughout the grow that
is, you know, I have before? I think
precision stress techniques work really
well for a smaller grow, you know. Um,
but I think when you start getting into
larger facilities, it just becomes a
tedious thing that doesn't really
produce that much more for the workload
that you have to put into it. Like if
you're a guy with an 8x8 tent, yeah,
pinching stems and bending branches can
really help you increase what you can
get out of that space. If you're, you
know, working with, you know, a 500
light canopy, it's a waste of time. How
about like drought stress and stuff like
that? Absolutely. Dryback stress is is
definitely something that uh um
increases, you know, growth. Uh you
know, just it just depends on like how
fine-tuned and precision you can get
with that stuff. I personally prefer
hand watering, but I'm, you know, I can
run irrigation as well. It's not a, you
know, I've I've done it all. Um, I
prefer hand watering because I like to
be up and close and personal with my
plants. But, you know, past a certain
size, again, it's just not practical.
So, then you have to turn to something
like irrigation strategies. And they can
work great, too. You know, I think I've
come up with some really good formulas
for irrigation strategies and I've seen
them work well in multiple large scale
facilities that I currently consult for.
Can you give us an example at all or is
it just kind of vary by grow? It varies
by grow 100%. 100%. It really just
varies by grow because you have to
tailor it to in the environment. You
can't just be like, you know, this is
how you do it and and think it's going
to work like that anywhere cuz that's
really not the case. Understood. Yeah.
Speaking from a small home grower
perspective, that's that's me. I feel
like that's a majority of the audience
as well that are kind of listening into
this. A lot of things that people are
using now are the moisture meters. The
AC Infiniti has one, Ecoit has one. Uh,
but being able to see a percentage of
moisture in the medium has been helpful
for me and I know it's been helpful for
a lot of people. So using that as a tool
to kind of measure drybacks is something
I'm currently kind of playing with a
little bit more. Yeah, my way was always
lifting pots. Lifting pots. The lighter
the pot, you know, then we're the closer
we are to getting to watering. So
that was, you know, always my go-to. But
yeah, moisture sensors definitely. I
mean, if you even get fancy, you know,
like they have Growlink and stuff like
that where it's all AI controlled.
There's a lot of I think we're
definitely heading into um a future in
the industry where a lot of things are
going to be like high uh proficiency,
you know, uh computer models that are
just going to do everything
automatically. And um you know, so I'm
I'm hoping to kind of beat all that out
and and kind of get you know, what I
know how to do out there before
everything becomes too automated and
because I feel like it's going to be
pretty much like all other corporate
models. It's going to produce, but it's
not going to produce good quality. But
who knows? I mean, AI is is is
definitely being integrated into
everything. Maybe they'll come up with
an AI that produces, you know, the
highest quality. We'll see. Yeah, it'll
be really interesting to see what comes
forth in the future here. I mean, I
think a lot of people are scared to kind
of see what comes of it. If I can get
some robot trimmers in the house, let's
go finish the whole finish the whole
room in 24 hours. Just work through the
night. Oh, that'd be fantastic. Yeah.
So, the final weeks of the grow are
arguably the most important weeks,
right? One of the common strategies that
a lot of people do is they'll they'll
lower the temperature in the final weeks
of flowering in order to try to conserve
those tarpen when you're growing. And I
know you said you mentioned your
personal grows are the same way you grow
for competitions. Correct. What do you
do in those final weeks in order to make
sure you have the highest quality smell,
flavor, and bag appeal? So, I think uh a
lot of those things, you know, it's it's
a it's a combination of things. It's not
just what you do in the grow, but do you
even have a good feno that has those
qualities in the beginning? So, if you
have a good feno that has those
qualities, okay, how can we preserve
them? And and yeah, uh lower
temperatures the final couple weeks,
but not really much more than that. I
would say even more important what you
do the final few weeks is after you
harvest, those last two weeks of drying
is the most important to preserve
flavor. look, you know, tricoms, how you
trim, do you are you are you, you know,
fisting every every nug or you holding
stems while you trim? All those things
play a part into quality at the end, you
know? So, you can have all the SOPs in
the world, but if you don't even have a
good fo, you're not going you're never
going to achieve that look, that taste,
that quality. You're always going to
grow something that's like a little bit
less than that. And you're wondering,
you know, what do I need to do
different? Well, maybe it's the genetic
from the beginning. you know, and maybe
you have a great genetic and know your
SOPs aren't correct. So, you I would
figure out which one it is first before
you say, um, you know, this isn't
working for me or I I can't achieve
these results like why can't you achieve
those results? Is it you? Is it the
plant? Or is it both? And are you
willing to accept that? One of one of
the I think one of the biggest uh
roadblocks for growers is
ego. You know, nobody wants to admit
that they have an ugly baby, right? Like
that's your that's your kid. That came
from you. That's like you don't want to
you're not gonna call your kid ugly, do
you're going to love that kid, right?
Like nobody wants to do that. But the
reality is not every kid's going to be
beautiful. And if you can admit that to
yourself, you don't have to admit it to
everyone else. If you can admit that to
yourself, you can you have the ability
to grow as a grower and become something
better than what you are.
So me personally, I always try to leave
ego at the door. I'm always ready to
learn something new. If you show me
better than what I do, I'm all
ears. You know, if you can show me
equivalent to what I do, you have all my
respect. But if you're showing me less
than what I do, I don't really have time
for that respectfully, right? So I'm
here to learn. So if I' if you're
showing me less than what I do, you
can't teach me anything. And it's not
that I don't I think I'm better than
you, but I'm here to
learn, you
know. So, that's my philosophy in in the
garden. I'm I'm here to learn and I want
to learn from, you know, anybody that
can teach me something I don't know. And
there's what seems like an endless
amount of things to learn in this
industry since science is continuing to
uncover new things. And for me
personally, that's what makes this
working in the space so exciting because
there's always something to learn,
always something fresh. It's not just
rinse and repeat every single grow.
There's so many different ways you can
grow this plant. And uh yeah, I take a
similar approach to you on that way on
that avenue where I'm always learning as
well. Yes. And there's more than one
avenue to success. You know, you got
your organic guys, you got your salt
guys. I'm not hating. You got your
synganic guys. I'm not hating on
anybody's methods. I know I just know
what works best for me and I like to
stick to that. But there's more than one
way to skin a cat and there's multiple
ways to success with the plant. 100%.
So, we talked about the final weeks. How
about flushing? A lot of salt growers,
what they'll do is they'll do a flush
prior to harvesting. Now, first of all,
there are so many definitions of
flushing. It's it's mindboggling. What
is your definition of flush? And do you
flush before harvesting? My definition
of flushing is bringing the EC in the
media
under.5. Um, so I do flush. Absolutely.
And I usually like to flush like the
last 3 to 4 days with, you know,
straight pH RO water, no nutrients, you
know, and just rinse everything out.
Bring the bring the EC all the way down.
But usually the last few weeks of
flower, I'm bringing the EC down slowly
anyway. So by the time I hit flush, I'm
probably at around 2 EC and I'll drag it
all the way down to.5 over the last four
or five days, depending on the media. If
you're in Rockwell, it's comes down a
little quicker. If you're in cocoa,
usually about four or five days, the
last four or five days. And by then, you
know, you're seeing dark purples and and
the color should just be busting
everywhere in the garden. Okay. And then
are you a firm believer that flushing
will lead to the color of the ash being
white versus black or
um I don't know. I think there's some
studies out there that kind of have
disproved that. I think it kind of boils
down to how much uh you know um calcium
and you have left in your in your in
your media. Um but I
don't you know the whole flushing like
there's been a there was a I can't
remember who did it but there was a
study out where you know they didn't
flush any flower and they did a blind
test with flower they did flush and
people picked the flower that wasn't
flushed 100% of the time.
So, you know, and that that was done by
RX Green Technologies, and they are a
nutrient manufacturer. Okay. No, that
makes sense. A little more context
there. Yep. Don't flush. Okay, that
makes sense. I need a little more
context on that when I just heard that
and I thought, huh, interesting. But
yeah, that that kind of makes more
sense. Of course, people who want to
sell you nutrients are going to tell you
it's it's fine. Put as much in there all
the way till the end. But yeah, I just
wanted to ask you that, get your take on
that. I know that it's very split, very
um still debated. I probably flush
because I've always done it in the 25
years that I've been growing. And I
guess it's one of those things whether
it be truthful that it that it works or
not. I know that it's kind of just
ingrained in my DNA. And I if I I don't
like to do things like what I'm what I'm
doing works, right? So I don't like to
do things opposite of what I've always
do because if what I'm doing works, I
don't I don't need to change anything.
Makes perfect sense. And it's clearly
not detrimental. and you're winning grow
competitions doing it that way. So, when
you're harvesting, are there any
specific techniques that you do to
preserve tarpen and avoid damaging those
tricoms? Uh, yeah. When I when I when I
I try not to touch the
flower, you know, when trimming, just
try to hold stems while you're trimming.
I like to hand trim. I don't machine
trim anything ever. Um, I believe in the
time that it takes to hand trim. Again,
we're I, you know, I'll I'll digress
back
to why are you going to spend all this
time and all this money growing the best
possible product you can only to throw
it in a machine and have it chop it up
and and you know, I I prefer a hand trim
absolutely every time. And I think that
preserves quality. As a matter of fact,
I know it does. Personally, and I know I
haven't used every single machine
trimmer out there, but they don't do as
good of a job generally as a hand trim,
right? And if you're taking that flower
and you're entering into a competition,
well, you want that to look as pretty as
possible, right? Cuz a lot of these
competitions are are going after bag
appeal as well. Correct. Now, what about
the testing? Is there like like how much
does lab testing matter in competitions?
Most competitions that I enter don't
require it. Uh but you know I don't I'm
not a believer in I don't like to enter
competitions that require you know where
uh a percentage is a metric you know I I
that's not because some of the best
flower that I've had you know had you
know a percentage of 17 18%. You know
versus some and I think a lot of labs
flub these numbers. I think a lot of
them inflate numbers, you know, because
if if your business is to sell
results, you know, you make the results
look good, they keep coming back. Yeah.
I've had so much flour where was like
lower THC, like I would say lower, but
like around 15% THC, and then you put it
side by side with something that was
like 25% THC, and you get more wrecked
off of the 15% THC. So, it's it's not
all about THC. And there's so many
cannibaloids we haven't studied yet as
well. Yeah. Yep. One of the biggest
misconceptions out there is that it's
all about THC when really it's there's a
lot more to it than that, right? What do
you think is one detail that most
growers overlook when preparing for a
contest?
um
uniqueness. You know, I I you it's hard
for someone
to know what's good when you've never
seen anything better than what you've
seen. You know, I think there's an
experience that comes into play. I think
that's why, you know, I've been able to
win the things that I've won is because
I have 47 years under my belt. And of
those 47 years, I probably spent at
least 30 plus, you know, as a
connoisseur of the highest grade and
always s sought that out. No matter
where I live, no matter where I was, I
was growing it, I was looking for it, I
was smoking it. So,
um, and just I guess my ability to to
recall flavor pallets in my memory has,
you know, is one of the things I believe
that gives me an edge. So, I think
that's one thing that if if growers can
increase your mental
library of flavors beyond what you're
normally used to can give you an edge in
competition because when you bring
something new, that's what wins.
Something new, something special,
something different, that's what wins.
Absolutely. I believe I'm going to be
going to the DGC cup. Are you going this
year? I I am not going this year, but um
you know, I thought about entering and I
think I might enter next year. That'd be
awesome. Yeah, that's been around for
several years now. It seems like it's
getting better and better. I wanted to
ask your opinion on judging. Uh if you
have any feedback for me going into
this, basically they're going to give
you uh they give everybody a little
chillum or whatever and you can go
around and sample everything. How do you
judge something like that with when you
have so many samples? It's so hard. Like
literally, I go for the sample that
stands out the most first. Nose. nose
first because after you, you know, you
sample however many, you're going to be
like, "It all tastes and smells the
same." So, uh, if you have all the
samples in front of you at one time, I
would smell everything first, then go
from there. The ones that smell the
best, put those to the side, try those
first. The ones that have no smell,
they've already lost in my opinion. You
know, if there's no flavor pie, you
already lost. Out of there. or if
there's like 10 jars and eight of them
smell the same, the eight out of there.
I'll go I'm going to go with the two
that smell completely different and
unique. Pretty straightforward there.
Yeah, that that's really good advice.
That's smelling them all first. Yeah,
I'm going to have to because you're
you're cuz that you know your your
oldactory senses are going to stay for a
while. So, you can you can definitely
get the different flavor profiles just
through your nose and you know we taste
with our smell. So, you're going to get
the full flavor like that first and then
like I the ones that stand out there are
the ones that I would like to try for
sure. And if that smell translates to
smoke, that's definitely along the lines
of a winner. Got it. Yeah. You bring up
uh something that reminds me of I was
smelling a whole bunch of different
flowers not too long ago working with a
breeder on a collaboration and uh one
thing we did between smelling was we
smelled some coffee. Holy cleanser was
great. Yeah, probably maybe some
mothballs or something. I don't know.
Something like that might work though,
for sure. Yeah. So, I think I'll
probably go to DGC with uh with a little
K cup of coffee in between each sample.
You smelling that? Yeah, that could
definitely work. For sure. So, I know
there's a lot of people here that are
tuning in that they're looking to enter
in competitions. What's the biggest p
piece of advice you have for someone who
wants to enter in a competition?
Um, try to have something different than
the rest.
Um, you know, be confident in in the
quality of your product. Like have be
honest with
yourself about what you have. Uh, I
can't, you know, I see I see it. So, but
like again, I'll just go back to nobody
wants to say they have an ugly baby, you
know, like no, nobody's going to do
that. Even if you but if you can admit
it to yourself, you don't have to scream
it out loud to everybody, but if you can
admit to yourself that you might need to
work on your skill level to really
compete, that's that's probably the best
piece of advice that I could give. Be
honest with yourself about what you do.
Never tell yourself you're the best. Let
other people tell you
that. And if a lot of other people tell
you you're the best, take it to
competitions and see if you're really
the best. I think that's a good way to
go about it. They mentioned the ugly
baby thing and one thing that uh reminds
me of are these ugly plants I grew and I
you probably gotten these ugly plants
before where there's like some sort of
weird mutation or something. I swear
these ugly plants some of them turn out
to be fire like really good nugs dense
frosty flavor smell incredible. So,
well, what what what I mean by the ugly
baby is not necessarily appearance, but
it's more of this is something I
created, right? And no one like it's
like I'll give you another analogy, like
a chef, like no, you know, you got
certain chefs out there like no matter
what they make, they're going to tell
you it's good. Even if it's not, just
because it's something they created. And
a lot of times when people put time and
work and energy into something, they
never want to admit to themselves that
it might be subpar to what everything
else out there of people doing the same
thing as you. They want to say, "No,
mine's is the best. Mine's is just as
good as yours." Even if it's not, you
know, or mine is better than yours when
it's clearly not, you know. So, again,
being honest with yourself is, you know,
the first step to success. Be true. You
know, if I I can't I'm my worst own
worst critic. There's a lot of times
where I'm like, I know this ain't good
enough. I can't tell you how many fenos
I've thrown in the trash.
Thousands. You know, be honest with
yourself about just because you put time
and energy and work into something
doesn't mean it's going to be good.
Doesn't mean it's a winner. Doesn't mean
it's
beautiful. You know, it can be all those
things to you, but if it's not all those
things to everyone else, you don't have
anything. respectfully. Well said, man.
This podcast episode has been very
insightful for me. I've definitely
learned quite a bit of things about you
and how you grow your plants and little
things about competitions and even to we
got to the point of judging, some advice
on judging competitions. So, I
appreciate you coming on to the podcast
today and sharing your insights with us.
Let's wrap things up here. Can you tell
the listeners how they could find you
and is there anything upcoming in the
future that you got going on that you
want to talk about? Yeah. Uh, the
easiest way to find me is on Instagram
at Mile Highday420. Uh, might be a
little shadowban, so you have to type in
the whole thing, but I'm fairly easy to
find. Only one with the blue check mark.
Um, I would say coming up are for me,
um, competition wise, I I definitely
plan on doing the Connect Community
Battle Royale again. I would like to get
in some more licensed competitions in
the state. um they just had the THC
Classic not too long ago, so we'll see.
But I'm always going to be looking to
compete no matter where I'm at. Um I'm
also going to be spending a few months
out of the year down in Argentina um
growing down there at a medical facility
and uh putting out the flavors to the
people in South America. So, I'm really
looking forward to that as well. Mary
Jane in Germany in uh in June. I'll be
there as well. Man, I've been wanting to
go to that. I'm not gonna be able to
make it this year, but I know so many
people going to that. So, that should be
a good one. I'm entering that this year
and I'm looking to to take home the gold
if I can. I think I have some really
strong contenders, so we'll see. Well,
good luck, man. I'll be rooting for you
for sure. Thank you. I'll have a link to
Dave's Instagram down in the YouTube
description section below so you can
easily get to his page. Give him a
follow. What questions do you have in
regards to entering competitions,
preparing for competitions? Let us know
down in the comments section below.
Definitely want to give a thanks to the
folks supporting on Patreon.
patreon.com/mrgrowit. 100% of what is
donated through Patreon goes right back
to the podcast. The folks are being
scrolled on the screen right now or in
the producer tier. Special thanks to you
for your support. Dave, once again,
thanks so much for coming on, man. This
has been awesome. Something a little
different than uh than what I usually do
on the podcast. Not sure how familiar
you are with it, but entering
competitions. This is a brand new topic
that we've never done before. So, thank
you so much for coming on and sharing
your insights with us. Thanks for having
me. All right, everyone. We will leave
it at that. Thank you so much for tuning
in. I'll catch you in the next episode.