coming up on garden talk
stable businesses they're looking for
people with actual experience and
education at a collegiate level
obviously you have full control it's
done by yourself you can kind of make
your your standard operating procedures
to match your time schedule and what
you're doing when you have you know 20
30 50 lights in a room it makes a big
difference compared to two lights in a
homegrown wet trimmed product looks
really great for photography so if you
like to take pictures of it to show off
for your instagram what trimming's kind
of a fun way to go in horticulture
there's usually more than one way to get
to your end product there's a lot of
different methodologies to grow your end
product and just because you're good at
doing it one way or near homegrown does
not mean you can come into someone
else's horticulture facility and change
what they're doing
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 56. in this
episode i interview envy closet med
grower he has been gardening for 10
years and he grows a variety of plants
such as tomatoes peppers cacti medicinal
varieties house plants and more he
started as a home grower and then worked
his way up into working in commercial
facilities and that's what we're going
to get into today from home growing to
commercial growing thanks to all of you
who support this podcast or patreon if
you'd like to support you can do so by
going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
big shout out to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is a
plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products thanks to
spider farmer for being a sponsor a new
grow light they released here in 2022 is
the se 1000w this was designed
specifically for those of you who run
co280 grow space and really want to
maximize the light intensity it has a 10
bar design for an even light spread
pulls 1000 watts from the wall and comes
in at 2.9 micro moles per joule efficacy
the recommended coverage area is four
feet by four feet or five feet by five
feet use discount code mr groit5 to save
on all spider farmer products and i'll
leave a link in the video description
section below a big supporter of this
podcast is ac infiniti they sponsor this
podcast and i use their products ac
infinity now has gardening tools and
accessories such as heavy duty fabric
grill pots trimmers grow room glasses
drying racks plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr growit during
checkout for a discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with envy
closet bed grower how you doing today
i'm doing great chris it's a pleasure to
be here i'm excited to be on the podcast
i'm excited to have some topics to talk
about and i think it's uh it's a
blessing to be on here talking with you
so i'm ready to get started
yeah we've been friends for several
years now you were on my twitch live
stream not too long ago
and we had a really great conversation
about a bunch of different topics and i
think it'd be good to have you on here
garden talk so we can speak specifically
about gardening you know one of your one
of your specialties for sure yep so what
i want to get into on this episode is
home growing to commercial growing
so there are so many people out there
that are home growers right now that
their dream is to eventually work on a
commercial facility right so you know
whether they live in a legal state and
there are already facilities open and
they want to get their foot in the door
there or maybe they're in a non-legal
state that's going to turn to be legal
and they want to be all prepared and
ready to go for when it does become
legal so they can get into the industry
on that avenue and you've done that
you've gone from home growing to
commercial growing so i thought you'd be
a great person to have on this show
today for the record you were the one
that came up with the
topic for this one so props to you for
that one
thanks yeah i uh you know some of my
background i started off more or less as
a home grower i won multiple cups home
growing
and uh you know i really
care and try to try to stay with the
home growing community as as it relates
to obviously many different plants and
gardening but particularly hemp so i i
did a lot of that for many years and
then i've also managed facilities i've
managed uh you know both facilities and
i've helped consult for different
facilities and my next project actually
is a large hemp grow in tennessee that
is all complete indoor facility
managed commercial projects as well as
homegrown projects at a very high level
and i think i think it would be a good
topic we could get into and talk about
some of the differences between how you
would manage a home growing how you
would either be an employee and or
manage a commercial grow and what things
you need to look for in that so
that's going to be good it's going to be
really good before we get too deep into
it though you gave us a little bit of an
introduction can you do a full-blown
introduction there's a lot of things to
be said of course for sure but tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
yes i uh well i got into gardening when
i was young
in vegetable gardening anyways my mom
always liked to have a vegetable garden
out back of our house in michigan as i
got older i got more and
medical plant production and uh
did a lot of that when i was younger
then i went eventually moved to in
nevada which was a legal state for
medicinal plants and got into home
growing with a with a license to home
grow there eventually won multiple
different cup awards and
and progressed my youtube channel for
home growing with intents and closets
and various things along those lines so
from there i progressed into helping
manage growth stores and horticulture
stores so i've sold a lot of
horticulture equipment made a lot of
deals and and contacts with various
different horticulture companies
and
progressed from there to actually
managing a horticulture facilities
incredible so living the dream live in a
lot of people's dreams which is uh
working in that commercial environment
so what
you know kind of taking a step back and
and talking about qualifications right
not anybody can just walk in off the
street and apply to some of these places
you have to have qualifications right in
order to begin so what qualifications
should folks have before applying to a
commercial facility
well it honestly all depends on what
you're trying to get into some of the
entry level positions you really don't
need a whole lot of of qualifications if
you just want to be a basic trimmer for
instance a lot of times they will hire
you on with absolutely zero experience
because it's kind of tedious work and
it's entry level to get you in the
business
um other entry level positions might be
like a basic garden helper where you're
just going through and plucking leaves
and doing that sort of thing you know
you're not usually in charge of any
watering or in charge of too much as far
as you know the irrigation or
fertigation of your crops and some of
those again you can get in with just
basic cultivation knowledge basic plant
knowledge a good work history in other
fields obviously no matter what you're
getting hired for someone's going to
want to make sure you show up to work on
time you're credible you get along with
your employees you know all those things
that are that are general amongst any
job field
and that's more or less how you get into
it a lot for the entry-level positions
it doesn't have as much to do with
having a ton of experience it has to do
with being a good employee that they're
able to train to do the function they
need
now as you get up from there there's
also a lot of mid-level jobs you know
like specialty horticulture jobs like a
propagator or a room supervisor and some
other things like that those type of
jobs usually you want to have some a
little more advanced knowledge of
horticulture
you're also going to want usually one or
two years experience either as a mid or
entry level
employee already in these type of
facilities so that way they know you
have some experience in what you're
doing
and once you get to that point it's
important that you at least have some
employee management experience too if
you're managing a room and have
employees underneath you they want to
make sure you're you're a good fit to
deal with other employees so a lot of
that is more hr related and a lot less
horticulture related stuff but you got
to have those skills in order to
progress
into higher level positions within these
horticultural facilities
um
progressing up from that you can get
jobs like lead cultivator and you know
lead grower master grower it goes by
various different names depending on the
facility but a lot of times in those
they really do ask that you have five
plus years experience within a
horticulture facility you also by this
point should have some secondary school
or college experience in horticulture
agriculture or botany somewhere within a
related field so they know you're also
classically trained with science on how
plants work and that's that's usually
pretty important by the time you get to
that uh that higher end of things and
obviously you're going to need multiple
years of employee management at that
point you know because you're going to
have teams underneath you not only just
employees but also supervisors and you
need to take care of your entire team so
again once you the higher you go up in
these ranks um employee management
becomes very important as well as
obviously as a lead cultivator you need
both
advanced to expert level experience and
knowledge in horticulture itself
so that's what that is and then the the
last kind of section i got here is
support jobs a lot of the larger
cultivation facilities don't only have
cultivation based jobs there's also a
front desk slash intake clerks a lot of
times that help you know take the phone
calls for the facilities take in the
orders that that the cultivator orders
in for supplies and you know various
different things like that there's
commercial sales managers which are
another more high-end job where they're
actually in charge of selling the
products that your clothes business
relationships and obviously there's also
data specialists sometimes there's uh
like in the medical field there's metric
system in many different states that's
required and you need a data track of
everything and they usually work very
close along with the commercial
cultivator in order to make sure
everything stays on track and everything
is up to regulation based on the state
you're in
so and those jobs can vary on what you
need to get into those positions a lot
of times you know front desk clerk you
usually need other front desk experience
and that sort of thing if you're going
to be a data specialist i kind of want
you to have some knowledge of metric and
some knowledge of how horticulture
facilities run you know if your
commercial sales manager you're going to
want to have multiple years experience
and possibly degrees in sales and
working for different sales because it's
a higher end position that usually pays
well so
that's that's kind of the four different
facility your entry level mid-level your
lead jobs you know production managers
and such and then your support
so
so lots of different areas that you can
kind of get into i think generally
speaking a lot of folks think that
master grower is kind of the end goal
and running a facility you know kind of
on the floor dealing with the plants
directly is one of the main options i
think a lot of people go for but yeah
definitely starting out from the bottom
and kind of working way up into one of
those positions is certainly a
possibility but i feel like going right
into one of those
high level positions that you mentioned
having an education you know they're
going to look for that right they want
you to have some sort of either
bachelor's degree or doctorate degree or
something um that relates specifically
to
cultivation yes and i don't mean to
interrupt but yes you are 100 right and
that's mainly the change in the job
market over the last 10 years as a lot
of states have gotten medical programs
and become more open to growing medical
plants they've they used to take on
cultivators from say the black market
that just knew what they were doing as
things progress more into
more into
stable businesses they're looking for
people with actual experience and
education at a collegiate level
that makes sense i remember back in 2016
when this state just went wreck we're in
nevada you were in there as well and
they just started bringing on
dispensaries right dispensaries just
launched in 2016 and cultivation
facilities were just opening up and i
applied back then because that's
something i wanted to do
and then it was so i couldn't even get a
response back it was like it was like
the market was flooded and what i was
told by insiders is that you have to
know somebody in order to really get
your your resume pushed up to the people
who are doing the the hiring aspect of
it and it can be difficult to find those
people you know so i you know i ended up
eventually giving up and just
just continuing on my home growing and
doing the media side of things but
how would you recommend folks actually
go about applying to these commercial
facilities so they don't run into these
dead ends well like you said it's it's a
or like we were briefly talking about
it's kind of a different setup now than
it was five to ten years ago five to ten
years ago you very much had to know
someone have the end get get your name
in someone's ear nowadays it's run a lot
more like most corporate businesses a
lot of times you can fill out online
applications for different positions
if you can't find an easy way to apply
for a facility that's near you and you
know what's there you know go look at
their website go look at their social
medias and ask them how you can how you
can apply for these positions try to be
outgoing with the fact that you do want
to work for them
yeah and like i said sometimes sometimes
it can be hard to find these particular
places so you might have to directly go
out and search you know for for their
direct websites they're not always on
indeed or some of these bigger job
engines now sometimes they are again
this is a larger commercial operations
nowadays and they do very much many of
them post indeed so it all depends on
the facility you're looking looking
towards it depends on on how they're
doing their hiring but a lot of times
nowadays this day and age you can find
online applications or or websites
linking to these different horticulture
companies that you can then apply for
okay that makes sense
let's get into the home growing versus
commercial growing side of things and i
want to go through some of the
individual processes or different stages
of growth and kind of what home growing
entails versus what being in a
commercial facility entails you know
let's be honest here home growing is
small side of things some of those
processes that are done just aren't able
to be scaled up to
a large amount of plants right so i
think there's some some big differences
throughout growing from from home to
commercial growing and you've worked in
the facilities before so you can
definitely give us some insight on the
differences so let's start with you know
starting from the beginning propagation
and seedlings
what differences would you say would
take place between home growing and
commercial growing when it comes to
propagation seedlings we can get into
that first of all we'll start on the
home growing side obviously you have
full control it's done by yourself you
can kind of make your your standard
operating procedures to match your time
schedule and what you're doing um also
like you said it's you have a lot more
availability to pop seeds on a lower
level when you're working on a
commercial system you want the
consistency of having consistent crops
and and consistent output of your
product and by popping seeds and having
different variables that may in the end
cost your company money so or cost your
company in less revenue you know it's
kind of looked at the same in the
economic world if you're not maximizing
your revenue you're losing money when
you look at it from an economics point
so a lot of times in facilities you have
much less variables which means much
less seed popping also when it gets to
cloning
sometimes you use slightly different
equipment because let's face it if you
have two lights or less you're not
usually going to need a full tray of 50
clones
so a lot of times as a home grower i'd
get inch and a half pre-wrapped rockwool
blocks break off what i need and clone 6
or 10 or 12 plants at a time whereas in
a commercial facility chances are you're
going to need hundreds if not thousands
of plants for your next cycle so
everything's done on rockwool sheets in
the 10 20 tray for the most part or you
know it's it's done a lot more
consistently over a larger scale it's
not made to match your size it's made to
it's made to match what you need going
next in the production line so again a
lot of times i'll use like inch and a
half or two inch you know 50 cell rock
wall sheets in a 10 20 tray as compared
to the individual wrapped cubes because
then i can just clone in groups of 50
and when i need a thousand clones i
might clone you know 1050 clones and
then take the best thousand and run
those for my next run as compared to at
a home grow if i need 12 clones i'm not
going to use a rockwool sheet i'm going
to just take those individual clones and
take what i need so some of the actual
procedure can slightly change and some
of the equipment can slightly change but
then on top of that also propagation in
a facility is usually done in a
propagation room or in the mother room
and you're able to maintain higher
humidities throughout the entire
environment
a lot of times in home grows people just
don't invest in their propagation area
the same they would in their flower
areas so it's usually you know an extra
closet space or i got an extra light
over here in the corner of my room and i
you got to spray your clones a lot more
to keep the humidity up on them if
you're in a dry area and that sort of
thing whereas in a facility your
humidity is on point because you bought
it so it's you know there's a little
less of the spraying of the clones a
little more consistent procedure let's
get deeper into the environment because
you mentioned that you know temperature
relative humidity co2 airflow air
exchange
all of the things all those things are
going to be somewhat similar but there's
a lot of differences in how they're
controlled from
home growing versus commercial growing
for example you know a dehumidifier is
gonna be a lot smaller in a home grow
you know and say a bedroom for example
with a couple tents it's gonna be a lot
smaller than it would be in a commercial
facility where they have this
massive room you know so i i imagine the
equipment to be a lot bigger maybe
multiple pieces of equipment controlling
things can you talk just about
environment differences between home
growing and commercial growing
yeah well of course like you said
there's definitely going to be
inconsistencies based on the size of the
equipment but a lot of your parameters
are still going to you're going to try
to keep the parameters somewhat the same
usually when you have that larger
equipment and you have a better sealed
position in a facility you have less
variation in what's going on so you can
be more consistent both with your
temperatures humidities that sort of
thing also with home grows many many
times you're not running co2 i know some
of you guys are but the majority of home
growers aren't running excessive co2 and
they're cycling air from their room out
of their room or for instance with tent
grows you you condition the room and
then cycle air through the tent whereas
in a facility it's more about
conditioning your growth space and
making sure it's consistent throughout
the entire growth space
so
um
yeah a lot bigger equipment um usually
almost always co2 injected on a
commercial level there's i haven't been
in indoor facilities without co2 because
it is that much of a benefit to your
production but as a home grower a tent
grower it's really hard to get those
elevated levels and that can sometimes
lead to you needing slightly less light
in running slightly less or less
strength fertilizer lower ec fertilizer
because you don't have the carbon to
increase that photosynthetic rate
whereas in a facility with the co2 you
would run things a little more to the
max to try to get your max production
out of it virtual air handlers have hepa
filtration and things built into them so
it can help clean the air column of
molds and mildews and things like that
whereas a lot of homegrown acs you know
the dual ducted acs and window acs and
even small mini splits you're not going
to have that type of filtration in there
so it's it's about controlling those
variables on a larger scale to make sure
you don't have
any loss of production whereas on a
small scale it's about doing things that
fit around your lifestyle so you you
know sometimes have to work around work
schedules and things like that and that
can change when you're timing your
lights of the day and
all sorts of things so your environment
can be a lot more variable in a home
grow i find then commercial
because there's money riding on the
commercial not just your personal but
there's money riding for investors that
do not take no returns as an option
so
everything has to be consistent and run
to the facility's sop when it comes into
that also cleanliness uh can be slightly
differently you know there's times when
be a little lazy in my home grows you
know i
like back to propagation i might cut
clones with the same scissors on all
four of my strains in my home grow if
you're in a large commercial facility
and you're cutting thousands of clones
you better keep some alcohol near you to
keep those scissors clean you don't want
to be transferring any contaminant that
might be on one plant to a thousand
plants that can make a huge issue so
you know that those are the type of
environmental ish differences between
the two and uh i guess the last thing is
is in commercial you're not wasting
space on conditioning it's not like i
said with tent grows where you condition
a room then cycle it through no if
you're conditioning a room you better
have plants in that room that's one of
your biggest expenses outside of labor
so
you better better make sure you're
pushing it as best as you can definitely
some good call outs there so
significant differences when it comes to
homegrowing versus commercial facility
for for those reasons you mentioned i
can't imagine any commercial facilities
using those tme naturals canisters
shaking them up and putting them all
around
per unit would be through the roof if
you're using a yeast and sugar-based co2
release um you yeah
in fact there's another difference for
you too a lot of homegirls that do run
co2 are usually 50 pound bottles of co2
and that sort of thing and once you
scale up into a commercial facility
that's 5 000 square foot or bigger a lot
of times they switch over to
um liquid co2 tanks and then inject in
that way so you can have you know large
500 gallon liquid co2 tanks
you know or compressed co2 tanks that
hold a lot more and then it's piped in
through your whole facility instead of
being a bottle in a corner being
released through a regulator so there's
you know quite like you said quite a bit
of differences on equipment and both
their size scaling capabilities yeah i
was going to ask about the the co2
change i'm glad you got into that now
air flow and air exchange is also kind
of the important piece kind of touched
on that a little bit on a home grow you
talk about air exchange you know having
a tent versus grow room they have fans
of the commercial facility there are
fans all around the facility right and
the air exchange is yes another thing
right having
air being exhausted sometimes i believe
correct me if i'm wrong from multiple
areas not just one area being exhausted
from how do typically they go about
you know air flow and air exchange in a
commercial facility well a lot of times
air exchange is actually less than a
non-co2 home grow because you're trying
to maintain keeping the co2 in your
environment now uh based on some
regulations at least i know for a fact
it is in nevada you need to have a co2
purge just in case something breaks and
it gets above certain levels it'll
automatically pump the co2 out of your
room as a safety regulation that's
something you would never have on a home
grow you would just look at your monitor
when you walk in if the number's too
high turn off your co2 and get the hell
out you know
whereas in a in a facility you need to
have these regulations in place to
protect your employees so a lot of times
you have you know co2 purging units
which are could be a fan on a co2
controller where if it gets above say
five or ten thousand ppms whatever your
state regulation is it'll automatically
dump all air out of your room from
within two feet of the ground
and that way it'll pull all the heavier
co2 from the bottom of the room out and
everything will start to in there and
and maintenance your equipment to make
sure that doesn't happen and again with
the home grow that's that's not
something you would have going on and
then also in the commercial facility
like i said you'd have less air exchange
so you're not wasting your co2 for the
most part there are some facilities set
up to do a night dump where they dump
all the air out of their environment at
night replace it at night and then when
the lights kick back on they'll
re-release more co2 but as for co2
efficiency and cost efficiency that's
usually not the best way to do it in my
opinion i would keep it more or less not
dumping co2 you can get a little bit
more oxygen exchange just from employees
coming in and out the doors and then
maintain as much co2 in the room as
possible with its sealed and less
exchange now air flow which is the
second thing you had kind of brought up
there is also a little different in a
facility because when you have such big
rooms you need to make sure the
temperature in this corner of the room
this corner of the room the middle of
the room the front is consistent within
a degree or two otherwise you're going
to have very inconsistent canopies
growth
uh growth situations and possibly
chances for contamination if humidity
you got pockets of humidity and such so
there's again a lot bigger equipment
used you know there's a company called
shaffer that makes fans that can launch
air in quite a quite a distance that's
really useful there's other other fan
technologies that actually mount on the
ceiling and pull air up and cycle it
through the room and that'll really help
with your consistency of making evenly
dispersed amongst your room when you
have you know 20 30 50 lights in a room
it makes a big difference compared to
two lights in a homegrown okay so
definitely some some major differences
there for sure let's get into the
vegetative stage uh for a little bit
here
lots of things that home growers do that
really aren't done in the commercial
facility side of things you know maybe
we should start with kind of watering
and feeding right when you're dealing
with
hundreds
thousands of plants i don't think a lot
of commercial facilities do hand
watering right they're on some sort of
automated machine fertilizer you know a
dosatron or something like that you talk
to us about the differences between you
know
fertilizing and watering
yeah of course and and there is quite a
few different companies that uh that
deal with different fertigation and
irrigation equipment but on a home
growth scale it's just not worth buying
this equipment like like you said
dosatron some dosatrons can be a couple
thousand dollars just for us a single
peristalic pump and a controller you
know and if you have a two light home
grow it's not necessarily worth your
investment to throw in that much money
or say like an argus fertigation system
can cost thirty fifty thousand dollars
or more that touch screen controls for
all you you're not going to need that at
a home grow you're just never gonna get
your
your value back from buying a 50 piece
of equipment whereas a facility that's
ten thousand square foot or more they
can probably get their money back on
that fifty thousand uh dollar investment
so you're right a lot of times home
grows
there's a lot of hand watering majority
of the time in veg in order to get
things to size just because it's it's
also harder to
put in irrigation when you're trying to
cycle things on a smaller level if
you've got two plants that are young and
veg two plants that are old and veg
they're gonna be drinking completely
differently and it's almost easier to
hand water at that point but if you have
500 plants on these five rows and 500
plants on these five rows you can set up
fertigation equipment to feed those 500
how you want feed those 500 how you want
and then you end up with uh
not a more consistent but a more
more efficient plan of feeding both in
labor cost because you got to remember
commercial facilities one of your
highest costs is labor costs if you're
hand watering you're going to need twice
as many employees as if you're using
irrigation equipment
so
that that is a huge difference in the
vegetative section another big uh
difference is the amount of
experimentation you can do and like i
mentioned earlier as a home grower you
can pop different seeds you can run
different strains you can do a lot of
different things to excite yourself
about your horticulture experience when
you're in a facility you need to follow
the slps whatever the lead grow or
whatever who's that ever in charge of
that they set up those sops for a reason
they know what they're doing most of the
time
most of the time but they uh
on top of that they they set it up in a
way so that way it works for their
production techniques
and
when in horticulture there's usually
more than one way to get to your end
product there's a lot of different
methodologies to grow your end product
and just because you're good at doing it
one way in your home grow does not mean
you can come into someone else's
horticulture facility and change what
they're doing that could very much
change the outcome and the time
schedules of what they have going on and
that is a very big no-no so once you get
into uh
facilities again you're using larger
irrigation systems
consistency is a key there you want to
consistently grow well oh my camera's
getting fuzzy there it goes
but uh you uh consistently want to stay
to these schedules because you're on
very strict time schedules on when you
need these plants ready for their next
stage of growth whereas at a home grower
if you want to let it grow a week longer
and let your plant and flower finish a
week later you can kind of get away with
that if you try to do that in a
commercial facility that week could be
thousands of dollars worth of production
cost for no harvest now problem to the
investors and the money people that are
paying your salary so
that's that's kind of the difference is
in the vegetative system um your time
schedule is super important you're not
experimenting you're doing what's needed
to get these plants to the next stage
based on the slps and you're usually
involving irrigation systems as compared
to hand watering once you scale up the
larger size facilities
i imagine plant training which is often
done in the vegetative stage is going to
be a lot different too right you
mentioned labor how labor can be
significantly more when it comes to hand
watering well if you're in a cultivation
facility and you want people to do
defoliation or lollipopping or you know
low stress training or any type of these
these hands-on training techniques it's
going to be more labor cost so i imagine
that they cut back a little bit there
compared to what home growers are doing
to their plants talk to us about the
differences with plant training of
course and uh
with that respect some of that plant
training is still done because it's very
important a lot of defoliation and
lollipop is still done on a commercial
scale because you need that air flow for
your ipm prevention to help prevent mold
growth and mildew growth and things like
that so a lot of those techniques are
still used and that's just a labor cost
you know management's going to have to
endure but you're also right about the
fact that there's a lot less lst there's
a lot less topping because and this is a
regulation issue most home grows for
medical plants anyways are regulated to
how many plants they can grow so if you
need x amount of product out of your
medical plant but you're only allowed
six flowering plants
you might want a much bigger plant that
takes more topping and training and lst
and a much longer veg time in order to
get your desired result whereas in a
facility we're really trying to minimize
the amount of veg time we have and if we
need to fill more plant canopy space we
will add more plants in
and it's actually less labor cost to put
more plants per area than it is to grow
a much bigger plant i know you have
another episode that was that was very
good about why you grow smaller plants
from a year so i'll go on this podcast
it's one of your more popular episodes
you guys should check that one out too
when you're done with this one
but um yeah that's that's very much why
the the production cost and the
regulations on home growers lead right
lead home growers to grow larger plants
in most areas
whereas commercially we fill it with
more plants that are
in the same size root zone same
consistent size canopies so that way we
can match it to our irrigation systems
and all our inputs and everything grows
evenly
um
yeah and
yeah i think that's all the notes i have
on that one that's there's that's the
main difference is those regulation
differences and and the fact that home
growers sometimes need to grow larger
plants
you touched upon ipm and i want to
circle back around to that and get a
little bit deeper into ipm because you
know it's a
much larger scale with commercial
facilities compared to homegrown right i
mean a typical home grower is going to
oftentimes just use a small 48 ounce
hand sprayer and spray their plants yes
you know with that or use a chappin a 2
gallon chap or something like that yep
and i have some of those myself
yeah when you're on the commercial
facility side of things when you're
dealing with more plants you know 50 100
plants thousands of plants often see
people go to like
the backpack style ones which spray
further
you know more of a mist compared to some
of these hand sprayers can you talk to
us about the differences with you know
ipm and spraying and all that stuff yeah
and like you said you briefly touched on
it as with everything else your
equipment scales up with the size you're
growing in fact even if you look at a
horticulture perspective from say large
scale greenhouses production greenhouses
for cut flowers and things like that
they have giant booms that go through
their whole greenhouse and and can
fertigate and or spray pesticides just
just to cover that much area without
needing the labor costs involved and at
small to mid scale commercial facilities
like you said a lot of times you're
using a five gallon backpack sprayer
because otherwise if you're mixing up a
gallon half gallon at a time you're
going to be mixing all day and trying to
spray as compared to getting your work
done and continuing on to the next path
uh the other thing i need to
mention with that is as a home grower
you're not limited in what you can use
as long as you're growing safely you're
using things that are not carcinogenic
you're using things that have low
toxicity and a low half-life so it can
break down quickly you're pretty much
open to use whatever you want on your
home garden now the regulations for
facilities are twofold there are
agriculture regulations for pest
management and pest application in
almost every state and federally that
you have to follow so a lot of your ipm
specialists inside your facilities will
actually need
to be regulated by the state and they'll
actually have to take classes and be
certified in order to apply pesticides
on top of that within the medical plant
market there's also
direct regulations by those states that
have legalized the medical plan so
almost every legal state has their own
set of regulations on which pesticides
you can use which pesticides you cannot
use you know for instance there's a
strong it's fairly toxic pesticide for
killing water molds called metal axle in
almost every medical state you cannot
use that product in nevada you can so it
has a long half-life it's toxic but it's
not carcinogenic
nevada you can other states you can't
and as long as you use it based on what
the label says so that way you're
following the federal regulations
then you can
use it in a facility in nevada you use
that same product on a facility in
california
so you got to know your state by state
regulations as well as your federal
regulations on who can apply pesticides
and what type of certifications they
need before they are allowed to do that
legal so i gotta have a lot of knowledge
in regards to that because i'm sure it
gets pretty muddy going from state to
state the impact it can be astronomical
right if you're spraying the wrong thing
on there you send that crop over testing
all of a sudden it fails tests and your
entire crop is wiped out and you can't
put that product on the shelf
yes and then you're gonna have some very
mad investors very very mad investors a
lot of times you if you lose more than
two percent of your crop throughout the
year your investors are not going to be
too happy if you break the five percent
mark failure rate like
you they're probably looking for a
different cultivator so there's a lot of
line for sure flowering stage let's get
into the differences between home
growing and commercial growing within
the flower stage yeah uh briefly this
one is is kind of kind of repetitive of
some of the other things again you you
need to make as a home grower you make a
cultivation plan that works for your
schedule a lot of other times you have a
job you have other things going on in
your life you have a family you need to
maintain that schedule
a large facility on the other hand might
just run two or three shifts of
employees and it's not about oh the
lights have to be on now because i can
work on it it's we set up the lights
based on what's most efficient for our
facility and the employees work around
that schedule so it's a little backwards
to those regards
also in a homegrow a lot of times you
can run your plants as long as you need
to get them to finish to cena since the
way you want in a cultivation facility
timing is everything if you are running
a nine-week flower room when it's day 63
you are harvesting whether that plant
needs two or three more days or not
that's just the way it is because within
a day or two you have veg plants that
have to be in that location and if you
over veg your veg plants now they're
sitting longer in veg and that's a waste
of resources and money spent
in the previous cycle so again timing is
everything commercially whereas you can
kind of work things around a little bit
to your liking into your schedule as a
home grower
and then uh secondly um
consistency consistency consistency
follow the standard operating procedures
the lead growers are put there for a
reason they have again like i said
earlier if
the you need to follow the procedure
they have to grow there's many different
ways to grow a healthy plant they have a
setup plan they were put in there for a
reason so if you're a mid to entry level
employee just follow what they're saying
even if you have a different idea on how
to do it bring that up in a question
form to the lead grower bring that up
later but do the work they tell you to
at that time even if it's inconsistent
with your own knowledge yeah there's so
much on the line for sure throughout the
the entire grow really you know it makes
me wonder you had mentioned being on a
set schedule and how they're harvesting
flowers even when they might not they
might need a little bit more time right
so i imagine how many facilities are
harvesting early to where like it's a
potency isn't at its full potential and
potentially you know clear trichomes for
example where it's you know the effect
doesn't last as long or it's a you know
different effect and what the that
cultivar truly brings out and to work
around that a lot of times the
facilities work plants that match their
facility if you have a plant that needs
10 weeks to flower and it seems to grow
in someone else's facility great but in
your facility seems a little bit slowed
down and you have a nine week or eight
week flower schedule you're cutting that
plant out of the lineup after one run of
it and switching to something that grows
properly in your environment whereas a
home grower like i said you might just
give it the extra week because you like
that effect you like that plant you're
not doing that on a commercial level
it's about making sure those ends meet
for your investors
so you have to make those tough
decisions that are a little bit tougher
in this regard in a cultivation facility
than what they would be as a home grower
now harvesting getting a little bit
deeper into that you you know mentioned
that they're on a strict schedule they
need to do it at a certain time but how
about the physical process of of
harvesting it varies quite a bit from
home grow to
commercial facility can you speak on
that a little bit yeah as as a home
grower you more or less harvest and when
it's the endocynosis like i said you can
be growing different plants and you do
it based on what you want we already
kind of touched on that but
uh um
yeah you also have to match your dry
space so a lot of home growers don't
necessarily have dedicated dry rooms and
dedicated gear rooms
like what you would have in a facility
so if your dry room is half full and
these plants that you harvested a week
ago still need a few more days to finish
leave your other plant and flower a few
days
finish those ones trim them up then
harvest just so you can cycle things
through because again kind of like
propagation usually your dry room and
your propagation as a home grower are
kind of your last thought you think
about your flower room first your
bedroom second everything else how can i
kind of build it around in a cultivation
facility there is rooms dedicated to
drying on top of that as an indoor
facility you also are going to pretty
much always have humidifiers and
dehumidifiers in that room because the
first few days after you harvest and you
have a room full of of medical plants
it's going to release a lot of water and
you're going to need a dehu to keep it
down after three to five days or so the
water really slows down a lot and in
some situations you can end up a little
too dry and you might actually need a
humidifier in that room to keep you at
that perfect consistency whereas a home
grow you're more or less tailing it
tailoring it around your climate when i
lived in nevada i would need a
humidifier if you live in florida you
would need a dehumidifier but you
probably won't need both you can get it
close and do pretty decent um
differences is a lot more control over
what you're doing and then also in a
facility your harvest is usually done by
a harvest team so they're clearing a
whole room at one time and filling their
dry room whereas like i said in a home
grow you kind of tailor it to based on
how much room you have when your plants
are ready and you kind of muck around
your schedule in order to get the best
product you want
timing is money in a commercial facility
and you cannot do that it's about having
a team that can efficiently de-leaf and
harvest these plants get them the way
you can get out of cleaning that room so
that way within 24 to 48 hours you have
new plants in that room
whenever i'm drying at home i always get
like a little jealous i always think
about like how it is a commercial
facility and how much easier it probably
is having a dedicated drying room with
controls for temperature and humidity
because i you know it it's not easy to
to control that those aspects depending
on you know the climate you live like
you mentioned where where in nevada
where i live it's very dry so i'm always
having a humidifier and oftentimes i
just dry in my grow tent and
there is variation in the you know the
temperature and humidity you know i
don't really have a air conditioner at
all times you know in a in my drying
room or growing room to where i can get
a low temperature uh for example a lot
of people go after like 60 60 60 rule
right 60
humidity yeah 60 degree fahrenheit
oftentimes i can't get that low as far
as the temperature you know i'm at 65
sometimes even 70 and you know the
higher the temperatures get the more
terpenes are being evaporated you're
losing that so i do get jealous not
being able to have a steady temperature
humidity when drying in particular
because getting down to those feel like
if you have a dedicated driving room
like in a cultivation facility it's much
easier to conserve those terpenes and
control that drying time than it is you
know at home i i agree with everything
you said there that is very much the
truth trimming so at home grow you have
the opportunity the wet trim of dry trim
people have preferences some people like
to do a wet trim some people like to do
a dry trim
often times nine times out of ten
they're using hand trimmers you know so
they're spending the time to have a nice
manicure buds or they have you know
there are small home trimmers like those
bolt trimmers that you can use i think
those are halfway decent but on a
commercial facility some facilities from
my understanding still do want to do the
hand trimming but oftentimes they're
doing they have large trim machines now
which are handling pounds at a time he
talks about trimming kind of the
difference is homegrown versus
cultivation
yeah
well you kind of went into some of the
basics of it the majority of home grow
is almost always completely hand trimmed
from the larf nugs all the way up to
your top buds it's as much hand trimmed
as possible because people don't want to
invest in the machines for small scale
when you get into a facility usually
it's either machine trim or a mix of
machine and hand trim they'll take the
top quality buds have those on a trim
team hand trimmed and then all the mids
that are still sellable they'll usually
run through a machine and have that as a
different quality of product and or
sometimes mixed into the top end batch
depending on how it looks but
for the most part you're right there's a
massive difference in equipment as there
has been through every bit of this
podcast so far um
and when you're when you're talking
about trimming also when you're trimming
at home the majority of your smoke most
of the time the majority of of the
product you're making is your own
personal product so you can be a little
sloppy with your trimming you don't you
can leave a crow's feet here and there
and you know under trim some stuff if it
has really sugary trim leaf on it and
you're fine with that because you know
it's for you anyways who cares
when
you're in a commercial facility that
product is not yours that product is
going to a consumer some consumers are
more picky than most of you
if they see a crow's feet on there
they're going to be on their instagram
complaining about your facility so you
need to trim very tight very cleanly if
you are a trimmer for a facility there
is no
leave a little bit because it's sugary
it's make that look as best as possible
so that way you have the best of bag
appeal and you can leave the best
impression on your consumers for your
facility
um also like you said what versus dry
trimming a lot of home growers and again
this is based on climate if if you have
a a much
drier
area you might want to dry trim anyway
so that way you have some sugar leaf
protecting your product and it'll slow
down the actual evaporation rate out of
it and you can get a little longer dry
out of it
whereas if you're again in a much more
humid area you might want to speed that
up a little bit because you're having a
hard time keeping your humidity below 60
percent so it might be more beneficial
for you to wet trim
whereas in a facility where you have
everything set and perfect it's almost
always dry trimmed first of all the
majority of machine trimming equipment
works off of dry trimming not wet
trimming so in order to use the machines
almost always you need a dried product
not always there's a few that wet trim
but most of them dry trim and then on
top of that it's uh it's about the
evaporation of terpenes and terpene
release if you have your environment
perfect and then you can kind of seal
those buds to slow down the amount of
air or evaporation off of them you can
retain a little more terpene so usually
dry trimming is best unless like i said
you're in a home environment to where
wet trimming might allow you to dry at a
more proper rate that's the only time i
would recommend and on a side note wet
trimmed product looks really great for
photography so if you like to take
pictures of it to show off for your
instagram what trimming's kind of a fun
way to go
and then curing curing is kind of last
piece i want to get into on this episode
talk to us about differences of curing
home versus commercial okay again um
when you're curing at home a lot of
times it's in glass jars or smaller bags
the the chicken bags or the turkey bags
at the biggest depending on the size of
your grow and then you're more or less
putting them in a closet putting them in
somewhere that's dark to keep them going
but a lot of times you're sitting at at
your room temperature or whatever and
you're just letting it finish up on its
own again you don't just like drying you
don't necessarily have a dedicated room
for
your curing stuff
now in a facility you have to have a
dedicated room for your curing stuff
because that is a finished product that
is worth money
you need locks you need security you
also need a room to be able to house it
all also it's not usually batched in
small batches like that um the majority
of states including nevada i know you
can only test a batch that's five pounds
or smaller above five pounds you need a
second test so a lot of the times you're
using uh like five gallon buckets with
sealable lids or
uh they make uh larger turkey bags like
the ostrich bags and stuff is the actual
name of them on the liberty bags that um
hold quite a bit more product and that
way you can keep closer to like a three
to five pound batch at a time test each
batch individually before your product
goes out whereas a home grower you're
not worried about testing batches and
regulations so you just match your
container size to the size of your grow
put it in a closet burp your jars every
once in a while you're good to go in a
larger facility like i said you're kept
under lock and key and security it's
also usually a little bit cooler room
kind of like your dry room you're going
to want it 60 65 degrees so that way
everything stays with the moisture
content you set it at and you're using
larger containers to actually cure and
finish that up to about a five pound
point in most states
yeah i was going to mention that the
temperature control that happens during
curing and typically in home grows i
mean a lot of people don't really care
about the temperature at least from my
experience a lot of people don't really
care about storing in a specific
temperature just
room temperature and if their
temperature increases you know like i
live in the desert i have some home grow
jars right next to me right now in this
room and i'm in regular air temperature
and you know it's just personal home
growth yeah so it doesn't really matter
to a lot of folks however one thing to
to keep in mind that if you're not in a
temperature controlled if you're
you know if you're sitting at 75 80 plus
degrees you could be losing those
terpenes right you probably are losing
those terpenes i was gifted one of those
wine fridges it's where i control the
temperature it's much easier to conserve
those terpenes when it's you know under
a right temperature
controlled area yes
okay so we went over a lot here taking a
step back and just given some general
advice to the folks listening you know
what advice do you have for those
looking to make that transition from
home growing to commercial growing okay
i do i have a couple pieces of advice
for you honestly um number one
and
this is obviously depending on on who's
in charge of the hiring and cultivation
but don't brag about your home grow
that's one of the number one things you
can do to kind of screw yourself out of
a job if they know you have an active
home grow going at that guaran at that
time and you're producing a lot they
look at that for a couple different
negative reasons one you could possibly
bring in pests that are can are that are
specific to medical plants
to that facility
and they don't want that increased risk
at all and that can help you hit a glass
ceiling even if you are the most
qualified candidate
on top of that there's also try to work
towards your formal education like i
said it's not the same marketplace it
was 10 years ago you really need to have
some formal horticulture education in
order to progress through the tiers at
these at these facilities
um so i i highly recommend going back to
school learning what you can about
horticulture i also highly recommend
mentioning you have experience you you
mentioned that you're good with
horticulture you may even mention that
you've had a home grow do not brag on
your home grow that can be a problem and
put you in a glass ceiling so watch out
for for those mistakes and then also
work towards your formal education so
that way they know you're serious about
horticulture in general and that can
increase your chances and look good
amongst the those that are looking to
employ you lots of good information
there for those looking to make that
transition from home growing to actually
working in a cultivation facility
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future
all right well uh you can find me mainly
i'm more active on instagram now envy
closet med grower i also have quite a
bit of old material on youtube that you
can look through like 400 some videos
many of which is very educational some
of which is just video logs of my
gardens but uh you can check me out on
youtube envy closetmed grower i also
have a website
nvcmg.com where i sell some horticulture
lighting and videos there
and uh for the future i'm actually in
the process of moving to tennessee to a
hump production facility i just recently
got
signed a signed an employment agreement
to start next month in eastern tennessee
up in appalachia helping them grow a
bunch of cbd based hemp
so that's my next task is moving to the
east coast to this i'm kind of excited
for the opportunity and it's a it's
a pretty decent
small to mid-size commercial facility
running horticulture lighting group
lighting and
and you know it's it should be a fun
experience for me so that's my next task
is commercial management of
premium indoor cbd hum that's awesome
i'm really excited for you sounds like a
great opportunity for you
for sure
so i'll definitely have a link to nv's
instagram and youtube down in the
youtube description section below for
those of you tuning in on youtube if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
just search for them you'll find them
they'll pop up
if you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single week i am releasing these garden
talk podcast episodes and i would love
for you to listen to future episodes
envy thanks so much for coming on to
this podcast today this has been awesome
a lot of great information for those
that are looking to transition from you
know home growing to the commercial side
of things um you definitely revealed a
ton of good information that's going to
help people on their journey there so
thanks so much
to everybody tuning in thank you so much
and we will catch you in the next
episode peace
[Music]
you