question taking the defoliation leaves
and mixing them in with your soil that's
cooking I do your thoughts I do too I've
done it before and had some good results
now you're going to get people who are
going to be against it hot composting
right you're you're adding organic
matter into the soil that could heat up
hurt Roots potentially I still do it and
I haven't had any issues that I visible
issues that I can see so I definitely do
it you know it'll break down and become
usable nutrients for the plant I'm a
proponent of that also proponent of
doing the chop and drop as defoliation
just dropping it right down in the
medium having that as your mulch layer
help retain moisture in the medium so
yeah I'm a proponent of that although
there are some people who are oppos it
any good Black Friday deals on grow
lights yes there's definitely a lot of
good deals out there but one that comes
to mind right away is from today's
sponsor Mars Hydro if you're a beginner
they recommend their ts series LED grow
lights for intermediate or Advanced
Growers check out their fce series and
they say for the Masters out there take
a look at their FC or FC Evo series they
have budget friendly lights dimmable un
know ppfd some have Smart functions and
some mod include their High efficient
Samsung lm301h Evo diodes that Black
Friday sale runs from November 9th to
November 26th and they told me different
products will appear on sale at
different times during that time frame
so keep an eye out their website is
mars-hydro
docomo have you been continuously using
the same soil have you run into excess
and to test the soil I've been running
the same batch of soil now for five
grows if I remember correctly I have not
actually gone and done a soil test it's
genuinely recommended to do a soil test
between grow Cycles some people do a
soil test when we're going from Veg to
flour as well but getting a soil test
can be costly it adds up especially if
you are getting Consulting to have
somebody interpret the results for you
and give you advice on what you need to
mend in so I've just been taking the
Gamble and just doing uh just a mending
on top of it and so I have not actually
run into any excess issues due to over
fertilization I've just kind of stuck
with the 30-day rule where you know
you're basically amending every 30 days
and I use the fertilizer Blends this
round and last round I use kiss Organics
nutrient pack one cup per plant 10
gallon container for this I was using
craft blend same deal one cup per plant
and every 30 days and of course that
initial amending that comes in there too
so but now long story short I have not
run into any excess issues probably
should send it out for a to solo test
just to see what it looks like you know
just for out of curiosity purposes but
I've just been taking the Gamble and
like uh hoping for the best you know
which I think a lot of people is what
they do do you have any favorites when
it comes to synthetic nutrients yeah
Blue Planet nutrients Blue Max two-part
cow mag I love running just that I'm
running that right now that plus the
stash blend so this is just the additive
the only additive I'm really running now
when I'm using synthetics yeah that's
pretty much my favorite really is Blue
Planet nutrients I actually used a
three-part in all their additives to
with good success so is scrogging
outdoor a crazy idea and would you
recommend blue mat or something else for
watering indoor scaring outdoor is not a
crazy idea I've seen so many pictures of
amazing scrog results Outdoors so no
it's not a crazy idea I think a common
thing that people do instead of scrog is
they will uh just utilize a TR stn for
support keeping things up not so much
trying to create an even canopy like you
do indoors with scrogging and also I
think a lot of people they'll use the
net but they also do like just a I think
it's a 45 degree angle bend on that
initial stem and that's it as far as
training of course lollipop and stuff
like that but so that those are a couple
different approaches there blue mats I
recommend for indoors that's what I run
I love the blue mats they're so
hands-off I mean I do grow was where i'
come back a week later and plants are
fine you know just water only the
organic amendments in there already
amended in there and uh go on vacation
come home everything's great some people
have had blue mats fail on them I did
have a fail on it trying to remember
exactly what the heck happened like one
plant failed it didn't like flood my
house like some people have reported it
happened to them just cuz and it could
be user error right if you're not
adjusting the dial on there it could
certainly fail right if you're not doing
it if you're not setting it up properly
but if you follow the instructions set
it up properly two notches back just
like they say in the instructions you
should be good I had one what the heck
happened like one dried out out of
nowhere I don't know if there was like
maybe a kink in the line or something
you know not the main line but the the
carrot line that branches off maybe
there's a kink in there or something but
one plan kind of dried out so I had to
like reset that whole carrot so I have
had them fail before but uh as long as
you're monitoring things and checking on
it daily you know every couple days days
you can correct issues like that since
you had the EVO 3 what's your opinion
now so AC Infinity EVO 3 LED grow light
I love it bar style light is for a 2T X
4ot grow space I'm still running into
this day I've been running it ever since
it came out earlier this year and I love
the fact that you can connect it to the
app so I have control over it on the AC
Infinity app so I can you know control
the light schedule control the dimming
amount that it's set at so on and so
forth and um yeah seeing some good
results Great growth I have a par meter
so I'm able to kind of dial in the light
distance I'm able to you know again
adjust the dimmer down if needed and
bring it closer or increase the light
distance and ramp it up whatever power I
want to get so there's some flexibility
there with with the dimmer and such but
I love it no complaints have you ever
had to recalibrate one of your blue ma
carrots midcycle if Cell mind sharing
how you went about getting it going
correctly yeah so this is pretty much
just what I answered I check on them
almost every day just to for that ease
of mind I'm going in there and just
looking to make sure that things still
functioning correctly certainly there's
times where the initial install the next
day I'll go in there and I'll see like
it's dripping pretty fast and I'm just
like hm might need to be adjusted right
it doesn't seem like it should be
dripping down that fast while some of
the other plants seems to be dripping at
a normal rate so then I'll go in there
and make the adjustments right and once
you use the blue mats long enough you
can kind of feel exactly where you need
to stop it's around that Two Notch back
as they say on the instruction some
people do a notch and a half back but uh
yeah absolutely I always I think pretty
frequently I go in there and kind of
tinkering around with it specifically
the day after install I'm going in there
and checking and some of them I might
have to recalibrate slightly how do you
reset the blue ma carrot after went dry
pinch the tubes take it out and
completely refill and reset yeah so you
you can you can pinch it and then that
way you can take it out refill and reset
what I did actually is I had another
carrot that I already had soaking so I
was able to do the swap pretty quickly
there so yes pinch it swap take the old
one out put the new one in and then
connect so I don't know if you have an
extra carrot or not I got the 12 pack so
I do have some extras kind of lying
around most of the time at least unless
I have 12 plants growing my stash PL
came in today any any suggestions on how
to use it I'm growing in soil soil frch
I personally recommend half teaspoon to
1 teaspoon per gallon of water basically
mix it into water and then water your
plants with it it's that easy that's the
most efficient way to use it I know some
people are sprinkling on their Roots
during transplant that's not really
recommended by the scientist who helped
develop it some people are using it in
dwc at a I believe it's a fourth dosage
and uh they're seeing some good results
there but yeah just plain and simple mix
it up in water make sure it's mixed in
real well and then water your plants
with it I have two electric guys they're
out of business now what do you think
about them I have to keep them turned
down or my plants don't like them I
always had really good success running
the electric guys I had the v1s the V2s
and the v3s I thought it was a great
company excellent customer service
quality product many people are still
running the electric size right now with
great results I think the original V1
was what released in 2017 if I remember
correctly and uh here we are what 6
years later and they're still working
great yeah you got yourself a good light
there how does someone start a living
soil bed without going to build the soil
kiss Organics go there instead no that
there are more companies of course than
build the Soil Direct competitor is kiss
Organics kis Organics shout out Tad
hussy you can also go to search
Clackamus cot soil mix now it might be
on the Builder so website as a recipe
but you can buy the individual
ingredients elsewhere some people could
could start on Amazon you know they
could buy the three parts you know
whether it be like a cocoa a form of
variation and um some compost worm
castings to start plus a fertilizer
blend people definitely start a living
soil bed without going to build of soil
there are other options out there for
sure but I personally do love build of
soil they are um not only have great
products but uh Jeremy over there doing
his thing on Instagram YouTube is mostly
what I tune into a lot of great
information there have you started
teaching a little one about Organics yet
maybe some light reading of your new
book before
bedtime yeah so for those that don't
know I have a daughter now so newborn
she was actually born uh over a month
ago now October 5th is when her birthday
is and um so I'm still in the barely
getting any sleep stage apparently that
lasts for what the first year or
something like that don't get don't get
much sleep because you got a little one
there but uh no I haven't started
teaching her about Organics yet she can
barely hold up her head
so uh but I should start to read her
some information about that on a nightly
basis right then maybe by uh you know
two three four years old she'll start
gardening with me who knows