coming up on Garden talk mother plants
aren't the same as production plants you
have a different strategy there we don't
want too much nitrogen
too much nitrogen depletes the stored
carbohydrates in the plant it'll slow
down rooting when you take the cutting
if you wait until the plants are
suffering they're turning brown and
dying say oh let me just add some of
this it's not going to magically bring
them back maybe they'll come back a
little sooner than they would have but
really you want to do it before the
stress happens if you've dissected your
soil after a grow you'll see that
there's pockets of roots where the water
was flowing in their pockets where
there's no roots at all with the Yucca
would be more even sponge of roots
Nature has all the answers this isn't
anything new they have all the answers
if you know where to look and then if
you can work with nature in an
intelligent way now you're a gardener
now that you're really doing your job
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 92. in this
episode interview Harley Smith he has
been gardening for 27 years and is
currently the chief science officer for
Total Health cultivation he's regarded
as an expert in Plant Nutrition as well
as organic biostimulants he is also well
known in this community for bringing
information that's backed by science in
this episode we get into various topics
tips and gardening hacks that are backed
by science if you gain value from these
podcast episodes please click that like
button and also subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already that way you can
be notified when new episodes are
released if you'd like to support even
more visit patreon.com Mr growit there
are various rewards set up for those
that support and you can pledge any
amount that you like 100 of the money
that's pledged through patreon goes
right back into the podcast it helps
this podcast keep going so thank you all
that support over there before we get
into it I want to acknowledge that one
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
free gardening information of all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who help make that goal
possible thanks to grow strong
Industries for sponsoring this episode
they have Gorilla grow tents which I've
used for many years they are well known
for their thickness durability and
height adjusting roof they also sell
super closet products which consist of
grow boxes grow cabinets grow tank kits
and hydroponic systems to see their
products in action check out their first
ever grow strong grow off go to their
website
growstrongindustries.com linked below
and use the discount code Mr Grow it for
15 off AC Infinity is sponsoring this
episode they have two different series
LED grow lights the ion board and the
ion grid the ion board fixtures are
board style and use Samsung LM 301b
diodes while the ion grid Series has an
open Center design and uses Samsung LM
301h diodes I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow lights and
you can use discount code Mr Grow it if
you're buying off their website AC
infinity.com that discount code works
for all AC Infinity items or discount
code Mr Grow at 15 if you're buying off
Amazon thanks to Mars Hydro for
sponsoring this episode they have a ton
of deals going on right now for their
Black Friday sale which is happening all
month different products are on sale
each week everything from grow lights
grow tents grow tank kits ventilation
systems and more also check out their
live stream on November 25th where
they'll do several giveaways go to their
Black Friday page at Mars Dash hydro.com
sale to see all of their deals I'll link
it in the description section below and
you can use discount code Mr Grow it to
save even more
and we're back welcome to the Garden
talk podcast today I am joined with
Harley Smith how you doing today great
good to be here yeah glad to have you on
you have been highly requested many many
people uh requested for you to come on
so I'm really thankful that you decided
to come on today today we're going to
talk about a whole bunch of various
topics tips and gardening hacks really
techniques that are going to make things
easier for you and save you time I
actually attended Harley's Master
Growers course a few years back
excellent course I learned so much and
I'm excited to have you on here today so
I can pick your brain a little bit but
first can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
sure I'm Harley Smith as you introduced
right now I'm today I'm the chief
science officer for commercial
production facility Total Health
cultivation in Michigan but I started
back in 1995.
uh almost getting close to 30 years ago
and back then I was a video producer I
wasn't a gardener I was making videos on
science and technology
and I was hired by a company called
Superior Growers Supply and they asked
me to produce a video introduction to
Hydroponics for schools
so I knew nothing but by the time I
finished the series I knew enough that I
knew that there's something to this
Hydroponics I really got hooked I knew
it was a great way to teach the science
that knew that there was a great need
for it especially here in the United
States because we were so far behind the
rest of the world so I ended up getting
in as a career of working with schools
setting up Hydroponics Labs all over the
United States doing professional
development workshops for agriculture
teachers about Hydroponics I was showing
people how to improve the nutritional
quality of food and improve the plant's
natural resistance to pests and disease
and I got quite the reputation
in fact I got such a reputation for
knowing the science that I finally got
the white jacket I was hired by a
fertilizer manufacturer in Michigan to
be their director of research in this
that's just the beginning of the story
and it goes on don't ever forget the
most important part along the way I got
my first grow light
an oscillating fan and started growing
tomatoes and herbs in my basement and
then
that's where the real journey began it
wasn't just doing the research and
interviewing NASA scientists and
Educators it was actually Hands-On and
that's where a little trial and error
made some of those rookie mistakes and
maybe today that we we could help new
other Growers avoid making the same
mistakes that we probably made early on
a trial and error turned into trial and
success and here we are still standing
so pretty significant background there
you've been doing this for a very very
long time and I know from taking your
master gross course you know a lot about
chemistry and chemistry really combines
with gardening quite a bit and I'm sure
we're going to get into quite a bit of
chemistry as we go on here today but
let's start with clones can you talk to
us about things that can be done to help
clones root and maybe anything else we
need to know about clones rule number
one
healthy moms healthy clones
you have to have strong healthy mother
plants and it mother plants aren't the
same as production plants if you have a
different strategy there we don't want
too much nitrogen
too much nitrogen depletes the stored
carbohydrates in the plant it'll slow
down rooting when you take the cutting
so first rule reduce the nitrogen to the
low end of sufficiency for moms and then
it improved the uptake of calcium
because if the calcium forms the glue
that glues the cell walls together you
get a stronger vascular system the plant
takes up and distributes all of the
Essential Elements more efficiently so
they all build up in into the into the
tissue so you take the cutting
separating it from the mom it has to
depend on the stored carbohydrates and
water and nutrients that are in that
cutting
so if you have a strong healthy mom lots
of stored carbohydrates it'll root
faster and and afterwards now another
thing you can do
once you start to get the initial
rooting early on those initial roots
coming out you can add some kelp
extracts
and kelp has auxins in cytokine kinens
that will stimulate more lateral root
growth and more root mess so first this
is the material itself that's the most
important and then you can do some
things to help the plant take up
nutrients and get a good strong Health
Head Start I know some people are going
to cut their clones at a certain angle
for example they say that that helps
with rooting is there anything to back
that or is that just something that
maybe somebody picked up tried out
thought that I rooted faster but may not
actually root faster it's it's not a
huge difference
but I do I cut on a 45 degree angle
simply because it gives an oval so you
get a little more surface area for the
roots but you could cut it straight
across and you'll still get rooting but
you know there's something to it but
it's relatively insignificant I know
some people that will even scrape the
the outer bark a little bit just to uh
to show more of the surface area of that
Precambrian layer
but who has the time to do that on large
scale yeah me as a home grower I've done
that before where I kind of scraped out
the sides a little bit to help with the
rooting and that definitely has worked
for me in the past so yeah it is
beneficial but if the mother plant has
deficiencies or it's all stressed out
it's not a good thing to take clones
from and that's why I kind of want to
get into next is stress tolerance of
plants what are some things that
gardeners can do to improve plant stress
tolerance okay well
I think the number one thing is this is
where biostimulants come in
and to play not just the nutrients
themselves
but Virginia Tech for example did a
10-year study on biostimulants and they
found that a combination of five parts
humic acid
human phobic to two parts kelp five to
two ratio work 50 percent more
effectively than either one and one of
the things that that combination did is
it stimulated the plant to make 50
percent more of an enzyme
called superoxide dismutase that
protects the plant against stress heat
stress salt stress UV stress
plant will stay green longer recover
faster
so that would be a key if the plants but
the best way to do that is before the
stress
because you're making plant protection
agents to protect against the stress if
you wait until the plants are suffering
they're turning brown and dying say oh
let me just add some of this it's not
going to magically bring them back maybe
they'll come back a little sooner than
they would have but really you want to
do it before the stress happens
and should that be applied as like a
soil drench or foliar or either Ah
that's good if stage zero of cloning is
doing a foliar spray with that same
thing the kill the the humic
orophobic I like either one I kind of
prefer phobic for foliar
over humic humic morph for the soil
pulvic more for hydro or for the and add
a little bit of Yucca extracts as a
wetting agent to it a very small amount
so that the water doesn't beat up on the
surface spreads out in the film so two
weeks before you take cuttings do a
light mist with the kelp fulvic acid
little Yucca that's all it takes but
don't do it any more than once a week at
the most once every two or three weeks
even will have a noticeable beneficial
effect on the plant so it will help
the plant literally pull nutrients into
those tissues pull in the sugars and the
nutrients so their store the battery is
fully charged
so yeah you can use that at the roots
because you get more root mess there's a
sponge to take up water and minerals and
then you take use it at the surface on
the leaf to pull the nutrients the
cytokine is literally pull the nutrients
into the tissue so you got to push from
The Roots pull from the leaves lots of
beneficial Trace elements too you're
adding
yeah if you have a healthy mom along the
way you are going to see a very high
percentage of rooting and there'll be
shorter period of time than normal
that's a great tip you mentioned Yucca
and I think a lot of people are probably
watching this I have a lot of beginner
and intermediate folks I'm sure there's
some people out there that haven't even
heard of what Yucca is can we get a
little bit deeper into that I know you
wrote an article for maximum yield all
about Yucca and uh you know what is
Yucca and what are the benefits of using
it by the way you can go to the archives
the maximum yield
if you do Harley Smith
maximum yield you'll they'll show a lot
of my articles you could probably read
the whole article but Yucca is a desert
plant and The Roots can be used to make
an extract
which is has opponents in it kind of
soapy
and
it's a natural fungicide
and natural wetting agent both the
plants themselves will make saponins
uh as they're as a plant protection
agent against fungi attaches like like a
steroid steroid like attaches to the
cell walls of a fungus in it deactivates
it so butt plants makes opponents Yucca
is rich in saponins so it makes uh so
it's beneficial as a wedding agent so
the water will spread out in a thin film
on the leaf
when you add that and uh so it's more
easily and efficiently absorbed and it
doesn't beat up into and just make spots
on the leaves and it has a fungicidal
properties to it too even though it's
not a fungicide in itself although they
tested it over in Europe they've cut
back on copper fungicides in the fields
because it's heavy metal and it's
contaminating the groundwater in the
soil so they were looking for
Alternatives they did one study on
apples
where they just used Yucca and water
only into the spray and it was just as
effective as the chemical fungicide
so it's also biodegradable
so it's because it's just a natural
chemical
made by plants so as a I like it as a as
a foliar but you can also if you make
that foliar spray and you spray it you
have some left over don't put it on the
Shelf it'll go bad because it's very
biologically active
it'll be a feed the microbes so you
don't really want it on the Shelf have
any leftover use it at the roots the
Yucca also will help the water disperse
through the root Zone especially in
growing mediums in soil so the water and
the nutrients and the biostimulants get
to all the developing root hairs
around the edge of the pot doesn't just
go in and flow through and go out down
the drain it spreads out disperses yeah
from my understanding it can be very
beneficial if you have a soil that's
gone hydrophobic so uh it helps you know
as a wetting agent helps re-wet that
soil or we free moisten that soil I
guess you could say now my question is
is this would this also be considered a
surfactant yes
it's a natural surfactant
sort of like like soap would be
in fact it is a little soapy
but you can see it I mean if you'd want
to do an experiment you could take a
piece of wax paper and have a drop of
water or some nutrients and one and the
one with the yuck in it and just put
them side by side one will make a little
beat up like a puddle the other will
just spread out like a film
and having it spell like a film in the
root Zone that's a good thing
otherwise if water just follows the same
path we did the last time you watered it
around the edge or down through and it
builds up some pockets of salt and it
really if you dissected your soil after
a grill you'll see that there's pockets
of roots where the water was flowing in
their pockets where there's no roots at
all but with the Yucca would be more
even sponge of roots yeah I use I've
been using Yucca and I actually left the
bag open and it hardened up so are you
saying that is there like a shelf life
on it or can I just like re-crush it up
and then put it into water and mix it up
you could re-crush it it's very
very
hydroscopic is that it where it attracts
the water right that Hydrophobia because
the hydroscopic so if I get a bag of
Yucca the first thing I do is I take it
out of the bag and put it in a glass you
know I can get a really good seal on it
and you could probably even put a dust
skin in it too if you want to have a
last a long time on the Shelf but once
it gets wet it doesn't go bad it just
makes it really hard to work with and
you're using such a small amount it's
like a sixteenth of a teaspoon for five
gallons of water it's hard for me to I
just do a few grains of it put it in for
a quart of foliar spray shake it up
it'll start foaming
it doesn't take I can't even measure how
small a monthly you need to add so you
can scrape a little off of if it's
hardened up a bit scrape it a little bit
and then put it in it would work how
that makes sense and for the folks that
are using it as a soil drench can you
overdo it I know some people are using
it every single time they water their
soil they're putting a little bit of
yucker in there is that bad at all or is
that perfectly fine there's limits I
don't know what that limit is
um you can overdo it
but um just remember it dilute dilute
just take a small amount it'd be I've
never used enough that it hurt did any
harm at all
so um but theoretically you could do an
overdose of just about anything
including yoga okay good to know let's
flip it up let's talk about amino acids
so talk to us about amino acids and how
they can be useful well now you're
getting to the heart of my r d I don't
know why I got the jacket
um quick story
back in the year 2000 remember the story
from the class back in the year 2000 the
Dutch government made all synthetic
fungicides illegal
on food crops
because all of those fungicides had at
least the potential for negative side
effects on on human beings so they said
nope can't use it got to protect the
environment got to protect people from
the fungicides so overnight the
Netherlands cool overcast very assist in
the greenhouses very susceptible to
powdery mildew and mold this naturally
cold and damp
so the Growers started losing a large
proportion 40 percent of their crop to
powdery mildew gray mold so they had to
do something so they started they got
hold of some of the biostimulant product
from Germany coming out of Germany
that had some promising side effects to
use on plants
in 2001
I was invited to the Netherlands to
Amsterdam to visit to all the schools
the agricultural schools over there but
also to visit the greenhouses that were
doing the first trials with that organic
biostimulant Eco one highest level of of
Organics I got to interview the Dutch
grower who is doing the tug trials for
the Dutch government
he went from losing 40 of his crop to
losing zero
he got a 10 increase in yield over any
past year
and he was first in the line for sugar
content in the fruit he was growing the
best of the best it was actually that
particular grower was a strawberry
grower strawberries are very susceptible
to polyure mildew and mold so that was
kind of the torture test
so um I knew there was something to it I
I interviewed the German scientist that
that produced it
as mobizen he wouldn't tell me it took
about 10 years of r d on his behalf so
he wasn't going to give away his secrets
I came back
it's been four years digging
deep
I found it I cracked it it was amino
acids here we go two of the amino acids
glutamic acid and glycine
literally stimulate root cells to open
calcium ion channels
so instead of the plant taking in one
Ion at a time of calcium and then taken
it up in the plant they open the Ion
channel A Thousand Eye calcium ions tens
of thousands flow into the plant and are
taken up calcium there's the glue that
glues the cell walls together the plant
takes up more calcium
instead of the water in the interstitial
space you have calcium pectate pectin
the glue that glues the cell walls
together
when a mold Spore lands on a leaf it
doesn't germinate in the surface water
you could just spray it wash the spores
off but the foot is still in the tissue
and it comes back but if you use
the amino acids the plant takes up more
calcium
instead of water in the interstitial
Space by the time that mold Spore is
able to penetrate the cells to get to
the water
in the interstitial space and become
established it dries up and dies
so it isn't killing fungus it's not a
fungicide it's improving the plant's
natural resistance to the fungus it
stops it from getting established and
spreading that's why they were able to
reduce the losses to zero because they
never got hot hold now I don't I'm
getting excited about this one but not
only is there a physical barrier but the
extra calcium that the plant doesn't use
in the cell walls it will store it in
the vacuole of the plant it stores it up
later if a little bit of powdery mildew
or gray mold or gets a you know on a
leaf the plant recognizes the chitin
that's a chemical a chitin in the cell
wall of the fungus plants don't have
chitin
they have cellular cellulose
so it knows it's under attack it the
plant literally sends a signal molecule
from the surface of the cell to the
vacuole
to open up calciums and ion channels
inside the cell and thousands or
millions of calcium ions go into the
cytoplasm it starts to chain reaction
the plant starts a chain reaction an
oxidative burst which is the plant's
first line of defense against the fungus
or even against some insects so we're
building up a natural resistance of the
plants without using any chemical
fungicides
oh so it's it's revolutionary really
when you think about how much we as
Growers lose to mold and mildew anything
that we can do to give the plant a
competitive advantage
is is worth it and amino acids equal one
highest level of Organic certification
they also feed the microbes in the soil
you know that's a nitrogen source for
micro microorganisms to eat so it's a
win-win healthy mixed healthier soil
healthier plants I'll also remember your
kelp extracts which are very common for
gardeners they have amino acids in them
so some of us there microorganisms in
the soil by the way make amino acids
they make an End digestive enzymes
called proteases that break down
proteins into the building blocks of
proteins which are amino acids so they
literally they're making amino acids
right on the surface of the roots
they've been doing it without a store
hydro store for millions of years we're
just working with nature we're just
giving them a little push in the right
direction Nature has all the answers you
know it's not this isn't anything new
they have all the answers if you know
where where to look and then if you can
work with nature in an intelligent way
now you're a gardener now I can really
do on your job
and it's fun it's fun to see it actually
work let nature do the heavy lifting
right
well one other thing about amino acids I
want to bring up that I learned in your
course was it helps with well water to
prevent lime scale yeah that's that's
right that's true that's how I actually
got on
the clue got the final clue to solve
this mystery I have hard water at home
in fact it's very hard water so I could
literally when I added my phosphoric
acid to lower my pH the PH down I could
literally see crystals of calcium
phosphate forming then falling out a
solution like snowflakes
that's how hard it was and I had lime
scale clogging on my pumps and my
emitters on the side of my reservoirs I
couldn't even scrape it out the end of a
girl
but amino acids are what are called
chelators intermediate chelators Kila
means claw so they attached to Mineral
ions like calcium ions like a claw it
holds it tightly enough so it doesn't
react
doesn't lock up in the soil but Loosely
enough so it's released to the plant on
demand so that was my first clue when I
got my amino acid blend to work with
from vitamin manufacturer out ease
experimental product
put it in the first thing I noticed no
more lime scale
oh where did it go at the end of the
grow
instead of trying to scrape all that off
that lime scale off I literally took a
paper towel
wiped a little film of the algae rinsed
it with water from the hose it was clean
so where did all that calcium go
oh into the plant how did it get there
the amino acids and the calcium there's
some relationship there
that was the final clue so I went to
Google
um I did calcium amino acids and it took
me to some studies where they did latest
studies around the world where they're
doing patched clamp analysis and
learning learning about calcium ion
channels there it was
oh by the way when I went back to the
Netherlands a few years later for
another Tour on bio bio filters for
cleaning water naturally
but I was over there I told both the
research I was doing with the seven
primary amino acid chelates
they told me I knew more about their
product than they did
and they were pumping me for information
so yeah the amino acids they not only
chelate the calcium to keep it more
available from locking up but it also
stimulates the uptake of calcium and
plants do that naturally with the help
of especially with the help of
microorganisms in the soil oh and you
don't need you know there's a lot of of
amino acid products on the market now
and I think people have learned from me
along the way and some of the
manufacturers are adding amino acids
right to their nutrients so it's out
there just need to know where to look
definitely beneficial information for
those folks that are in Hydroponics or
even using just a reservoir and have
that lime scale being able to add in the
amino acids and get rid of that is is
huge I want to get a little bit deeper
into water particularly kind of chlorine
in water there's a lot of misinformation
out there unfortunately but um you know
if there is chlorine in the water
I'd like to know what harm does chlorine
do to the plants and what can gardeners
do to get rid of the chlorine yeah
there's there's two different forms of
chlorine
the Municipal Water Supplies you know
one was more of a chlorine type gas
that's used to kill microorganisms
harmful organisms in the in the water
and it can at high levels it can damage
root microscopic root hairs because it's
an oxidizer you know it's
killing the bacteria but also harming
The Roots especially at high levels now
chloramine is a more recalcitrant it
lasts longer in the water
uh according to the EPA though it's not
harmful to plants
or to people but it is harmful to fish
and microorganisms now if you want to
get rid of both you want to get rid of
the chlorine well if you want to just
get rid of chlorine you know that's the
only that's the only thing in the in the
Municipal Water just have a side
Reservoir and let the water sit
overnight the chlorine gas will just
dissipate into the air
put a bubbler in there it'll dissipate a
little faster so that's all you need but
if you have the chloramines they're not
going to dissipate but you can get an
activated charcoal filter it's not an RO
filter it's an activated charcoal filter
and there's some that are designed to
remove the chlorine and the chloramines
from the water so if you're if you're
hesitant and if you're going to make
compost tea you want to get rid of the
chlorine you don't want it to kill the
beneficial microorganisms in the compost
tea so you know just an activated
charcoal filter will do the job I think
a lot of people are concerned uh that
are growing in living soil and rely on
those microbes in the soil in order to
break down the Amendments so the plant
can uptake them they're concerned that
the chlorine levels in their tap water
is killing off all their microbes now on
the opposite side some people the
argument towards that is that once it's
released from the actual faucet the
chlorine level isn't going to do harm to
the microbes what's your take on that
it'll do harm
you know he'll do harm until it's
dissipated enough
I've I've done it I mean we've looked at
it under the microscope where you have
had some compost tea
and then we took and then we mixed up
another batch with the head the city
water and you could just see that they
weren't swimming around they're they're
sluggish the microbes are sluggish or
they're they're not even or they just
die with the chlorinated water but I
guess it depends on where you are
in general I don't think I mean I've
grown plants
for years in the city in this in the
store with City water never had problems
but once in a while you'll get a problem
with the water supply you get a heavy
water you get a little flooding in the
spring you get some backup of the sewers
and stuff and what they'll they'll do is
they'll they'll charge it with the high
levels of chlorine to to make it safe
and but they don't tell you
oh you know we just added 10 times as
much chlorine to your water and then at
that high level and you know it's going
to hurt your plants it'll it'll stunt
them you know they should grow back you
know I've used really high levels of
hydrogen peroxide on plants that have
root rot and you know it's stunning them
but they go in The Roots came back so
it's not one of these oh it's you know
yes or no but if you're gonna do compost
tea you should either use spring water
or at least let your water sit overnight
in a side Reservoir another it's good to
let it warm up to room temperature
anyway
I always recommend a side Reservoir and
hydroponics so the day before I do my
reservoir change I fill up my side
garbage can
with with my tap with my water and then
the next day I pump out my reservoir
take the pump put it back in the in the
side Reservoir fill it refill it it's
room temperature it's clean we're ready
to start a new crop because it's easy
fast and and it works well
so
uh you should do it and if you wanted to
to warm up the water a little quicker
you can put a submersible heater in your
side Reservoir to let it warm up quick
more quickly not a bit not a huge thing
but
I remember when I first started I
remember doing my reservoir changes and
bailing out the water with buckets
and after you know man what a pain it is
to do that take them down dump them and
get another bucket take a dumb bump dump
it up
how easy is this to put some submersible
pump a water mover with a hose
you know a simple water mover you can
get at Home Depot and have that whole
job done in five minutes
but with the side Reservoir you can
replace it with room temperature water
that's clean and free of chlorine
definitely makes it so much easier where
I live my city tap water comes in at 485
PPM so it's extremely high I don't even
use it because I've tried to use it on
Plants before and like they were not
happy with it so I ended up investing in
a RO system so now I use RO water I know
there's some people that have tried to
use a water salt they have a water
softener and they try to use that water
can you talk to us about the downsides
of that
yeah don't use the water softener unless
you change your salt
in your water softener
what a water softener does is it takes
the calcium and magnesium out of the
water and replaces it with sodium you
know salt is sodium chloride but you get
up above 50 parts per million of sodium
and the plants aren't going to reach
their genetic potential
so I mean if you have a hundred parts
120 parts per million of calcium and you
replace it with 120 parts per million of
sodium that's a bad day for your plant
so I bypassed that the uh on my water
softener or I've done this in the winter
where instead of using the regular
Morton salt sodium chloride there's
another type of Morton salt that's
potassium chloride
it's more expensive than sodium chloride
but then you're replacing the calcium
magnesium with potassium and potassium
is actually a fertilizer for the plant
it's the health element so you're doing
something good for your plants so I've
done that if I had to use the water
softener I would
yeah I would use the potassium chloride
salt
our o is great I love it but once I
learned about how to
turn my lemons into lemonade and get
more calcium uptake I haven't used my RO
filter unless I just want to top off the
reservoir you know with some fresh water
uh the RO water by itself does have has
no buffer so the pH can swing pretty
wildly so I'm personally I like to have
a combination if you're going to use it
a combination of tap water
and you know it's room temperature and
RO water so you have some buffer there
let's get deeper into pH what is the
optimal PH range for medicinal plants
and you mentioned buffer what are some
ways to buffer the pH okay a good PH
range safe 5.8 to 6.4 it's always been
the sweet spot I let it drift between
the two I don't try to get the perfect
pH all the time when I change the
reservoir I typically shoot for 6.0
some Growers will shoot for 5.8 either
one is good I just like 6-0 because when
I use the pH test kit
like the GH pH test indicator solution
if it's 6.0 when you're doing your test
it's dandelion yellow easiest color to
see so I can see if it's perfectly
yellow or just a little yellowish green
or just a little yellowish Amber and I
can dial it in pretty simply so I just
go for six hours being my my target but
5.8 is good too is that for Hydroponics
as well as soilless Medias as well as
soil soil you can go a little bit higher
in PH you can go more like 6.5 is a good
Target but it can go up to 6.8 you know
in that area because
microorganisms that's the the closer to
neutral is better for the microbes in
the soil
so that's their favorite and as the
microorganisms are colonizing the roots
they are making organic acids that lower
the ph right on the surface of the root
Zone it could be two points lower than
the surrounding bulk soil so you can go
a little bit higher
also your with soil you're going to want
to adjust your pH of your soil before
you even start
and once it's your pH is of your soil is
right it's buffered it's hard to change
the pH one way or the other so the pH of
the water that you're watering with
isn't as important anymore
because the pH is right there where the
plants want it
but with Hydroponics you know you want
to try to you know water is not a buffer
for pH so it's really easy to change pH
of water and hydroponics
host you're talking about buffering uh
if you want to add some buffering
capacity to your Ro so you don't have
the wild swings
spiking and crashing pH
just add a little like I said add 50 50.
tap water to your Ro you're adding some
some buffering capacity some calcium
carbonate magnesium carbonates you're
adding some beneficial Trace elements
that that are good for spring water has
some illness from the earth with it as
well
um and or you could add a small amount
of humic acid to it if you have that on
yourself that will add some buffering
capacity too
um
in soilless mix the humic acid will
raise the pH of acid soil it will lower
the pH of alkaline soil so it does have
a nice buffering capacity has a lot of
positive and negative charges on it to
hold and release hydrogen ions and
hydroxyl ions so it buffers that makes
sense yeah so in your master Growers
course you mentioned that plants will
produce 18 to 20 percent more essential
oils and hydroponics I'm talking about
you know terpenes cannabinoids why is
that and also is there anything else
that gardeners can do in order to
increase essential oil production yeah
that was one of the very first things I
learned in my research on hydroponics
for that very first video I did for
schools on introduction Hydroponics
there was a study done it must have been
in in the 80s late 80s on hydroponics to
the University of Minnesota and they're
the ones that discovered you know
measured it that plants grown in
Hydroponics at 18 to 20 percent more
aromatic oils than full field grown
but they didn't really say why
uh I don't really know exactly why what
it was about it but one thing about
Hydroponics all of the essential
elements are there in the perfect
balance lots of good aeration perfect
water it really helps the plants reach
their true genetic potential
and part of that genetic potential is
the production of the terpenes so I
think that may be why
just with just Hydroponics alone if
there was such a difference
um now to increase terpenes
I found in my I did research on my own
along the way and found that healthy
stress
improves the terpene production
healthy stress it could be well a very
common one to use is drought stress
because you can do that toward the end
have have longer periods more dry back
between when you hold waterings and the
plant will respond to that and make
terpenes the other way is salt stress
with you that's why I love to do in
Hydroponics because it's easy to just
raise your your EC the electrical
conductivity so it's a little bit salty
makes it a little harder for the plant
to take up water and then as a response
they make antioxidants to protect
themselves against the the stress and
some of those are flavonoids and and um
other molecules and terpenes and I did
do anything one experiment to approve
that because I kind of knew that I was
taught that early on in my career but I
mixed up some hydroponic nutrients
three different strengths one was half
strength one was full strength according
to the directions one was high strength
and I did side by side in the same
environment
the plants with the highest
strength the highest EC had the the
darkest colors the richest Aromas
strongest flavors and I wasn't like oh
yeah I think this is a little bit I mean
it was dramatic difference you can see
it
you know the three jar side by side you
could see the different color it's the
intensity you open up the jar and take a
sniff you could smell the terpene
profile and just in your face so I would
get the highest prices because it was
the highest amount of of vitamins and
highest amount of of the of the terpenes
so um
yeah so that really helped and um when
it was trying to be more competitive
with tomatoes I could do the same thing
I could raise my EC up even higher
the uh you get 50 more
of the lycopene content that's the per
the red pigment
and you could so it's red all the way
through
I could get um
30 percent more vitamin C content just
by raising the EC because again some of
those vitamins that are manufactured are
a stress response from the plant
so you don't want to baby them too much
you know give them some healthy but too
much stress they can't take up enough
water to meet their needs and they start
getting crispy on the edge you get your
fertilizer burned and it has a negative
effect on the growth and and
productivity of the plant
so if you want to be a great Gardener
learn how to manage stress
manage the stress of the plant if you go
a little too high the leaves start to
curl at the ends you give then just back
off on the stress
yes but if if they're they turn they
start to curl and turn brown on the edge
you know you're going too far you have
to you have to make it write a note best
Growers are the best record Keepers do
not go past this EC
that's the top line for that particular
strain and just live close to the line
and your plants will thank you good
advice yeah I know a lot of people doing
Precision stress methods in order to try
to increase the terpene profile and uh
yeah I hear it from so many different
people that it works for them I mean
just me and my garden wind stress I mean
that that's a thing from I can I can see
the plants that are right next to the
fan that's blowing somewhat harshly
against it I could see a clear
difference in trichome production on
those plants versus the plants that were
further away so wind stress is a thing
as well I mean you talked about the
other ways that you can stress the plant
in a Precision method in order to
increase terpenes so that's really good
to know let's remember and you don't
want to get too much heat stress at the
very end
like when they're growing into the
lights because that will evaporate the
terpenes too so you'll lose some so you
know you might want to at the end kind
of cool it down a little bit to preserve
the terpene profiles and also that could
lead to foxtailing right which is a
characteristic that some people actually
like but a lot of people find it
undesirable you know and they're they're
final flowers so yeah he increased heat
can definitely do that my theory on the
on the fox tailing is the combination of
the Heat
and phosphorus
you know a phosphorus toxicity shows up
as a zinc deficiency and zinc is
critical for making the growth hormones
the auxins IAA so if you get too much
phosphorus and too much heat in
combination then the there it affects
the hormonal balance of the plants so
instead of the the flower buds filling
in they want to just do more cell
division and and foxtail out
but you'll see it if they're further
away from the lights you don't see it as
as much a foxtailing yeah now two
phosphorus is temperature dependent too
so if you have cooler temperatures it
doesn't take up as much phosphorus but
if you have high temperatures and high
phosphorus then it's taking up more
phosphorus too and then it can build up
the toxic levels in the tissue that's
interesting I hadn't heard that before
so we talked about increasing terpenes I
want to kind of flip it over to
increasing yield a common way to do it
very common is CO2 can you talk to us
about the benefits of supplementing CO2
and what CO2 level is ideal okay oh yeah
I mean the light is the limiting factor
so you want to get the the most light
best quality light you can to your
plants and that's a whole other story
I'm getting ready to start some lighting
trials in a in a facility we just built
using interlighting and also sub canopy
lighting but you know light is number
one now once light is no longer the
limiting factor then CO2 becomes the
limiting factor if you're in a closed
room and the plan to use is up takes in
the carbon dioxide for photosynthesis
under those lights they can deplete the
CO2 in the room if they deplete it down
to say 200 parts per million the plants
will stop growing so a deficiency of CO2
is actually worse than the benefit
beneficial effects of increased CO2 so
at the very least you want fresh air
coming in to replace the the depleted
CO2 in your room at the very end now on
the other hand if you increase the CO2
in the atmosphere
to say 700 between 750 and
1500 PPM
you could see a 50 increase 30 to 50
percent increase in yield easily if you
have a good light an air movement so
so yeah but you don't need CO2 at night
only during the day you
um you don't want to go too high either
if you get up above
well up above 1500 you're wasting CO2
the plants will start to close the
stomata also here's the here's a little
tip I learned this along the way it's
better to ramp up your CO2 as well when
you're going from Veg to bloom and
you're under heavier production you
don't want to just go from
400 PPM to 1200 overnight because the
plant will have to adapt to that high
CO2 it'll close the stomata so
until it has a chance to adapt so if you
wrap it up slowly the plants will adapt
better and they'll respond better to the
CO2 because if they close their stomata
then they're not transpiring as much
they're not taking enough nutrients as
much you can even get a nutrient
deficiency
same way if you have excess you get to
say 5 000 parts per million a CO2 it'll
close up the stomata so much that it can
burn your plants it'll look like
fertilizer burn the edge of the leaves
will actually turn brown
you get up to ten thousand or higher
it's not even good to be in the room
for an extended period of time as a
grower you know so there's OSHA
standards there but if you but between I
think 1200 PPM for the is a good goal a
nice Target
now in Arizona in the Tomato production
hydroponic tomato production with all
that light
you know a cloudless day in the summer
High light intensity they'll go up as
high as 2000 PPM
during the peak of the day because the
plant can use it then
um
so um yeah I saw that they actually have
light sensors in the greenhouses that it
measured the accumulated sunlight for
the day and the computer will adjust the
CO2 for the prevailing
conditions environmental conditions
another thing they do commercially is
they they need to have heating at night
it's cold in the desert so during the
day they're they're using the boiler and
they're producing CO2
and then they pump the hot water into
storage tanks insulated tanks at night
they run that hot water through the
pipes in the greenhouse to warm the root
Zone and warm the canopy at night so
they're getting double duty CO2 during
the day when they need it heat at night
when they need it that's smart yeah and
it's very automated as well that's
awesome very automated there's one other
thing I want to get into which I think
the audience will gain value from which
is Bricks now you had mentioned that 12
or higher bricks pests won't recognize
the plant as food so I know there's a
lot of people listening in they battle
grow after grow after grow they've got
pests they're spraying their plants to
prevent pests they're spraying their
plants when they have pests but they're
not even looking at bricks talk to us
about bricks what is bricks how do you
measure it and how do you increase
bricks okay you know the the organic
gardeners
know know a lot about bricks they've
been using it for years you
um now remember
it's really this bottom line is the
measurement of the sugar content of the
sap that's the main measurement
uh it also kind of measures the total
dissolved solids as well
organic elements don't conduct
electricity
like sugar
so you can't use an EC meter
like you would for your measuring your
salts for your fertilizer you just won't
register on there but the more the total
dissolved solids and sugar in the water
the more it reflects refracts light
so a refractometer is how you measure it
you take a few drops drops of sap from
the leaf first fully developed Leaf near
the top of the plant you squeeze out a
two or three drops of sap onto a slide
of this refractometer look through it
and you can because it's bending the
light you can actually read it like a
thermometer what the bricks level is and
the goal for me anyway is 12 percent or
higher
uh for very healthy it's measuring the
indicating the the current nutritional
status of the plant
so to increase it first thing I do if I
go into a as a consultant go into a room
or into a greenhouse first thing I'll do
is a Brix test if the bricks is too low
I'm going to adjust potassium to nitrate
ratio in the fertilizer that's the very
first thing either reduce the nitrogen
increase the potassium or do a little of
both
the like I said if you overdo it with
nitrates which most Growers do they
think oh I need the yields give it more
nitrogen well they just did the plant
will it's a luxury element the plant's
going to take up nitrate nitrogen
whether it needs it or not
but it takes a lot of energy away from
photosynthesis
about 30 percent of the energy of the
plant goes into assimilating the
nitrates so you give it more and more
nitrates it'll it'll take a look at the
bricks the the
stored sugars go down
and also with too much nitrogen get big
cells with thin cell walls it's an easy
meal for insects
it it's a very easy for for fungus to
get attached so the number one thing to
increase drips bricks is not to over
fertilize especially with nitrogen cut
back to the lower end of the sufficiency
range of your plants and I do leaf
analysis too in their my facility and
check out what what the nitrogen is and
I've been continually been cutting back
even what I thought was a good number
I'm realizing the plants don't need that
much nitrogen and if I can cut it back
the bricks goes up and potassium on the
other end potassium is the health
element it helps in carbohydrate
metabolism to manufacture the sugars
also it helps in loading the sugars into
the sap and also it helps to activate
enzymes that will convert the stored
sugars the starches into sugars that can
flow to the flowers and be stored in the
fruit
so potassium is a good thing I like to
raise that but lower my nitrogen until I
find that sweet spot pardon the pun The
Sweet Spot now you can go beyond you
want to go beyond that you're going to
want to improve the uptake of nutrients
so the kelp humic acid you get more
lateral root growth more root mass you
have a sponge or Roots but it's going to
take up more water and minerals get more
chemical reactions higher bricks
so we can do it at the roots we can do
it with the foliar at the at the leaves
and we can of course
first just make sure we have a balanced
nutrient for the plants
and the bricks goes up
Trace elements are important for that
too because it stimulates metabolism at
the root Zone
and that stimulus metabolism of
microorganisms and there's some
microorganisms that literally make
volatile organic compounds that tell
that turn off the sugar signal in the
plant
so later in the in toward harvest the
plant doesn't know it has enough stored
carbohydrates so it continues to do
photosynthesis continues to make sugars
all the way to the day of harvest
so if we can stimulate some of the
microbes like bacillus sunless gb03
maybe add some molasses toward the end
the Molasses won't go into the plant
it'll feed the microbes and the microbes
will tell the plant make more sugar
um one last part of that is iron iron is
one of the limiting factors in soil it
gets oxidized turns into rust really
easily and then it becomes unavailable
but iron is a cofactor in the production
of chlorophyll the pigment that absorbs
the light and makes the sugars so we get
good iron uptake Trace elements
then that again is going to contribute
to your bricks
in the end
iron copper
manganese
um
are the big ones one more thing um
remember CO2 right at ambient CO2
rubisco the that's the enzyme in
photosynthesis that actually assimilates
the carbon dioxide
changes into organic carbon
um that is the limiting factor under
ambient CO2 if you're growing at high
CO2
then rubisco is no longer the limiting
factor because there's extra carbon
dioxide for the plant to take in and in
that case of the electron transport
chain becomes the limiting factor and
those that's where those Trace elements
uh availability are going to really
Shine for increasing your bricks at the
end so much good information bricks can
definitely be beneficial for sure this
whole episode has just been fantastic I
think my audience is going to get a lot
of value from it we are coming up
towards the end here and one thing I
want to give you the opportunity is to
tell the listeners how can they find you
and do you have anything upcoming in the
future that you want to talk about yeah
I guess so um not real easy to find me
these days because I'm I'm not teaching
my classes this year my online when you
did the master Growers short course but
I am going to restart that and I'm going
to add new material
because I've been working in the
commercial facilities for the last few
years so I have some things to add
to that I didn't do in the short course
but right now I guess the easiest way
would just be to email me send me an
email and say hey when your classes
starting up
I'll try to keep track of that and let
you know and my email is Harley
h-a-r-l-e-y like the motorcycle Dot
p as in Peter H as in Hotel
T is in Tom
Harley dot p h t gmail.com
so
just send me a just drop me an email and
then we can keep in touch uh I don't
really like getting phone calls and
texts because I work full-time it
interrupts me too much but an email I
check on it every day and um you know as
long as I'm not too exhausted after a 12
hour day I will I'll be happy to respond
or at least let you know what's coming
awesome are you on uh social media at
all like do you have a YouTube channel
or Instagram or anything like that or no
I don't have my own channel but if you
uh Google Harley Smith YouTube you'll
find a lot of free um workshops on there
in lectures
it's a good place to get started
I even have some that are just 60 second
long
little clippets
they're pretty popular
on different subjects
so start there
I do have an Instagram and my tag is
Harley 500. for Instagram but when I
started doing classes again I'll call
you because I'm really going to need to
learn how to do social media coming to
the 21st century for a little while here
get the word out
yeah let me know I'm definitely willing
to help I'll definitely have a link to
something to your Channel or to your
Instagram or something down in the
YouTube description section below so
folks can easily access that folks if
you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up also subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already every single
weekend I'm releasing a new Garden Talk
podcast episode and I love you to tune
into future episodes Harley thanks so
much for coming on this has been awesome
it's uh it's really cool that I was able
to go through your master grows course
and then be able to pick your brain
further because I definitely uh
definitely learned a few things in this
one and like I mentioned earlier in the
episode I think my audience is going to
get a lot of value from this one so
thank you so much for your time today
okay thank you for having me peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode