welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr growt and you're tuned into the
garden Talk podcast this episode number
149 in this episode I interview Paul
from wake and bake with Paul he is a
Sanic Gardener who grows in his garage
which brings its own unique set of
challenges he gets into detail on the
way he does it successfully everything
from equipment setup balancing the
environment's conditions preventing
pests and so much more if you want to
see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped me that go
possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
electric sprayers with a 2 L capacity
and an adjustable nozzle that can go
from a strong jet to a fine mist spray
their sprayers are battery powered and
can be used for 3 hours on a full charge
no pumping required and it's a one
button operation click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their sprayers and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend consists of
several ingredients in one so you no
longer have to buy individual bottles it
includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic based
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use to
discount code the stash
and we are back and I'm joined with Paul
from wake and bake with Paul how you
doing today not bad how are you pleasure
being here good good man thanks for
asking today we're going to talk all
about growing plants in a garage and I
feel like this is something that a
decent amount of people do grow in a
garage cuz they can't within their house
for whatever reason right maybe they
don't have space in their house or
whatever but it's really a topic that we
haven't gotten into much in any of these
podcast episodes growing in a garage
really comes with his own unique set of
challenges which we're going to get into
I feel like even if you don't grow in a
garage there will still be some
takeaways in this episode so don't go
anywhere if if you see the topic and and
want to run here but first can you tell
us a little bit about yourself and how
you got into gardening sure so like you
said my name's Paul um mid-40s guy out
here in Southern California Los Angeles
I'm in the Valley I've been married for
20 years actually my uh anniversary was
2 weeks ago so congrats to my wife she
stuck around
um four kids and I've uh I've been a
garage grower for the past you know four
plus years uh grew up a farmers's kid so
uh spent a lot of time in the fields
when I was uh young up towards you know
early adult but uh my my father had a
Vineyard and an almond farm so spent a
lot of time out in the field so kind of
was introduced to farming gardening at a
young age and you know a lot of that
kind of translated into you know kind of
what you see behind me is the garage
grow awesome and then another question I
like to ask in the beginning is what's
your gross style I mean I know you're
indoors in a garage are you in soil
cocoa Hydroponics are you using organic
or synthetic inputs what's your style so
like you know I I have a grow tent I
have well I have three grow tents in the
garage um I'm from a farmer's kid so I
kind of reverted to soil it's what I'm
comfortable with um and I guess it's the
common phrase these days is Sanic so I I
I like to give you know the plants uh
synthetic nutrients but I also like to
add you know worm castings and I also
like to you know feed in molasses from
time to time kind of help the root zone
so uh I guess that's what you would kind
of call singad in and we'll get deeper
into nutrients how you use them what you
use throughout the whole grow cycle
later on in the episode first I do want
to dive into you explaining your garden
setup that's in your garage now you
already mentioned you have three grow
tents in there what do you have for like
lighting and how do you do ventilation
and so on so forth explain your grow
setup so this one to my side this way
this is a AC Infinity 3x3 um I got the
complete setup with the uh with the
controller which you know it's hands
down it's fantastic I mean it it kind of
I don't want to use the word boring but
it really helps regulate so much of the
environment that it kind of it becomes
almost hands off uh this one behind me
is a competitor I'm not going to name
any names but uh some point I want to
upgrade I'm just you know the light is
pretty good but the I'm I've really
never been a fan of their their tents
you know truthfully in their customer
service they one time they told me to
sew something um on a defect and I was
just kind of shocked but uh thankfully
AC Infinity is not like that and then
I've got one over here on the side
that's a bit of a reject uh tent I kind
of you know picked up as something I
needed but you know the light in there I
have it's the uh green Sunshine company
the electric sky 180 V3 which I still
love that light you know what I I mean
it I think it works great so it's it's
hard to part ways with that one so I
might upgrade the tent and the and the
ventilation but I just I I still want to
use that light um you know ventilation
I've got you know I've got fans inside
there lots of lots of air circulation
and I've got an intake fan for all of
them um as well as an exhaust so lots of
air circulation um and you know there's
there's some things I do to just make
sure that I keep things clean as well
but uh that's the setup I have right now
kind of a variety of companies when it
comes to the other uh the last one the
one behind me is it's all competitor
stuff you got three different tent there
are you doing like Perpetual grow is
that why you have three different tents
or is it just so you can grow a certain
number of plants or what's the reason
for the three different tents oh you're
exactly right I'm a Perpetual grower I
kind of have you know different plants
and different life cycles just so I you
know so there's always a surplus but um
just to kind of keep things going plus I
like to play it's you know having you
know the right amount of plants in one
tent or something like that is
just gardening is fun right so you want
to play games you want to try different
things and you want to kind of enjoy
yourself and so if it's just all inone
it kind of makes it a little bit boring
so I kind of like to you know want the
Perpetual grow but also kind of
diversify and just kind of you know do
different things at different times with
different plants so now are you on like
a strict schedule for your Perpetual to
where like okay I'm going to do this
number of weeks in veg then I'm going to
flip that the flower and then so you've
got everything kind of rotating evenly
or you just kind of like wing
it you know
I my jars are full
so to Simply put it you know what I mean
like I I've got plenty so I you know
like right now you know the 3X3 has it
has one one plant in it and it's in a
Solo Cup it's the global grow cup so I
devoted you know that entire plant and
that entire setup to that bonsai tree of
a plant that's sitting in there right
now you know what I mean and you know
this one's got a a good amount of clones
and then the one over there in the
corner has a it's a Gary pton that's
kind of later stages of flowering so
it's it's in a scr so it takes up the
entire tent you know what I mean so it's
a variety you know I
play understood so in your grow tents
where your plants are growing what
environment conditions do you typically
aim for so I guess with that I mean
you've got your Optimum you know I I my
Bas is typically I go off of VPD you
know and and not strictly but you kind
of you know once you kind of get an
understanding of the variations that
you're looking for you kind of need to
you know where your your the relative
humidity needs to be in contrast to you
know the heat in the uh well I'm in
SoCal so the heat typically in the in
the tents right um but you know there's
Optimum conditions and I think there's
realistic conditions and then there's
getting by conditions I mean you know
actually when we met when you were here
in Southern California that couple weeks
was you
know horrible simply put the weather was
just horrible I mean it was you know I'm
in my I'm in my garage and it's 1: p.m.
and it's like 95째 outside and you're
just thinking like oh my gosh but I mean
at the end of the day the plants are
really resilient you know what I mean
they can handle a lot sometimes you open
the
tent and it's hot in there and the
humidity is low and the plants are
praying you know what I mean they're
just loving life and you're like okay
you know what I mean you tough little
critters you know what I mean so you
guys are doing pretty good but you know
I I like to be you know again I base off
of VPD you know what I mean I think one
of the important things is just to make
sure you've got a good functioning
humidifier you know what I mean just so
you're kind of always keeping that up
because in my experience is when it's
really hot if you can increase the
humidity it it decreases the general
temperature and the environment right so
um I think you know that's really
helpful and actually one of the ideas
that I had send AC Infinity because I I
I do the entire grow in in the tent
right I do the you know from seedling
all the way I use a I use a dome for the
seedling but you know when they're
little dinks to where I'm harvesting and
cutting down it's all in the grow tent
right so you know one of the one of the
you know the uh wish list items that I
had send AC Infinity was hey it would be
great if on the automation there was a
Notifier that you know when your
humidity is low the water in the
humidifier is low so you tells you hey
go fill it up again you know what I mean
because you never want to run out if
you're if you're drying or something
like that you in in a dry environment
you don't want to run out of you know
water in the humidifier right so I think
it's important I have another one
that'll tell me when it's when it's
empty but that's typically too late so a
warning sign would be uh magnificent but
that's the environment I'm typically
looking for you know it's during the
colder months it's usually you know 50s
to 70s in the garage hotter months it
could be 70s to 90s in the garage so you
know typically in the tent it's a little
bit cooler and then I've got some
you know some things that I use you know
such as what's really important to me is
an external AC unit that actually also
has a humid a dehumidifier in it um as a
means of being able to push in colder
air when I need to and I you know I have
a method of doing that as well but it's
important to me I think we'll talk about
it later but I mean if you're going to
invest and you're in a warm climate
something you need especially if you're
going in the garage you need to be able
to combat the Heat and so you mentioned
you trace you track after VPD do you
happen to know like for kPa do you
measure by that do you use that and do
you kind of have it in mind like okay
for this stage of growth I'm going to
aim for this kPa veg flower and so on so
forth you have those numbers so you're
just looking at a chart I use you know
there's some convenient things that I
use you know there's an app on my phone
it's like Dr Greenhouse I believe it's
called Uh VPD calculator so basically
you punch in you know the the the uh the
temperature and then you also punch in
the relative humidity and it kind of
tells you where you are um as far as you
know if it's if it's it's either humid
if it'll tell you if it's dry stress or
it'll tell you if it's in you know in
Optimum flowering uh conditions or if
it's in Optimum vegetative condition so
you kind of get used to it so you know
think T typically it's like a 15 Point
difference between the temperature and
the humidity for uh for flour and then
for uh for veg is typically about like8
you know what I mean so if it's if it's
80째 in the 10 you're probably looking at
like 72% relative humidity and that'll
kind of put you in a good spot with for
veg you know what I mean so I'm no Pro
and I'm no scientist I kind of go off of
you know experience I guess you kind of
know what temperature if it's at this
temperature I should probably be at this
humidity you know what I mean so and
then at the same time you you you have
built-in trust with the the uh
Automation and controls you know so
they're doing their job too which is
really
convenient got it yeah and when I'm in
seeding and veg I'm usually aiming for
like a point 8 to 1.1 kPa and then for
flower is like typically about 1.2 to
1.5 sometimes upwards of 1.6 kPa but
according to the pulse VPD charts that's
kind of the optimal range and then you
know a lot of people think that they
need to just be in that range and that's
it they have to if they're outside of it
they're screwed which really isn't the
case right like the plants will still
grow it just might not be that optimal
growth according to to VPD but I toally
get what you mean by like having the
experience and knowing okay I'm at 82 de
F I know I need to be between this and
this percent relative humidity you kind
of get that feeling and and most people
that are just using temperature and
humidity a lot of people really are
falling within that optimal VPD range
without even knowing it so so yeah I
just figured throw that one out there
well at the same time you see plants
outside you know you have plants outside
and it's 110 degrees outside and the
relative humidity is 27 degrees or
percent I should say and the plants are
all doing just fine you know what I mean
so it's like again there's Optimum
conditions and there's realistic you
know I really try to fall into the
realistic sometimes you just can't get
there you know what I mean it's if it's
just too hot out or if it's you know if
it's just too cool it's too dry you can
combat that with with the humidifier but
um again like you said most people just
it it falls within the range of
acceptable right the plant's going to be
it's dealing with it and sometimes you
kind of think maybe the stress is itself
in the with its uh with its triome
production and some of that stuff too
you know what I mean instead of it being
a perfect lifestyle for them good point
so that's inside your grow tent now how
about your lung room or really the room
that your grow tents are in which is
your garage are you aiming for a certain
temperature and humidity in your garage
so that way any air coming into your
grow tents are of the proper Temp and Rh
or or what you know that's a great qu it
this is my my lung room is my man cave
you know what I mean so behind me is my
kind of my grow area over here to my
side is you know kind of a bench with a
laptop you know my my whole you know I
when I'm working from home that's where
I'm working and in front of me is my TV
so when I'm watching you guys on your
podast when you know you on your podcast
with some of these other guys it's all
right here so typically my garage is
open and I'm hanging out in here and I'm
and I'm you know again I'm in SoCal so
typically the weather's pretty nice
you've got your hot time and you've got
your cool time but we don't get the Four
Season like some of these other places
where where people are growing so it's
often times tolerable if it's too hot
out the garage is closed and I'm hanging
out inside a closed garage if it's just
right you know the garage is open and
you know again there's a couple things
that I do you know whether it's you know
using the external AC unit if I need to
to help push in cold air if it's really
hot out you know what I mean even if the
garage is closed and it's still hot out
I you know I'll hook up ducting from the
AC unit
straight from the AC unit to where you
know it kind of opens up like this I'll
shove the ducting and I'll shove it in
there and I'll tape it on there so it
doesn't fall out and then I'll run that
duct hose straight into the intake fan
of my uh of the grow tent so it's just
pushing coold there right into there
right so just have to make sure the
filter on your external AC units always
clean uh so it's pushing you know
cleaner air but I mean if if you're
looking for a way to decrease the you
know the internal temperature of your
grow versus outside by up to 15 20째 I
you you're just pushing in cold air you
know I'm fortunate my garage actually
has a spot that's got a external like a
kind of a ex like a where air can
exhaust so I've actually taped the
exhaust from the AC unit straight there
so it's pushing all that hot air right
out of my garage so I can run the AC
unit with my garage Clos and it's
ventilating the hot air out and it's
pushing the cool air right into my tent
so it's really helpful I you know
depending on the climate you're at you
know you're in Vegas if for any of the
people out in Vegas going in their
garage you need an AC unit in there you
know or else it's it gets it gets hot in
there it's becomes a scorcher you know
so you got to have something the plants
will be happy but come on you know make
their lives a little bit easier right so
that's my lung room yeah I have a couple
buddies who grow in the garage I'm based
in Las Vegas the desert and uh
summertime it's from June July August
just about every day is over 100 degrees
Fahrenheit which uh I did the conversion
here because I didn't want to leave out
the folks that's using Celsius but over
37째 celsus and uh that's pretty hot here
and sometimes it reaches up to 110
degrees Fahrenheit yeah and my buddies
are growing in the garage out here they
have like you said they have an air
conditioner literally right in their
garage and so they're cooling that air
now on the flip side when you're in the
winter time it gets very cold so they
actually have to heat the place do you
have to use a heater at all in the
winter time to kind of heat up your
garage so the grow space inside your
grow tents for example doesn't get too
cold yeah you you know I I get inventive
you know with the AC unit you know I
I'll shove because I've got the 310 I'll
shove three duct hoses in kind of in the
line like this and it's just running to
all three t0 simultaneously which is
pretty cool so it's a three in one and
for you know I've got like a floor like
a space heater you know those you know
just $50 space heater and um I've
actually encl I've got I grabbed a tote
and I and I kind of enclosed it in the
tote standing vertically and I ran the
three duct hoses in there kind of
trapping the heat in that area as best
as I could so the intake fan was just
sucking in warm air from there and um
you know that proved to be successful as
well cuz you're you know again if you
you know if you've got multiple tents
andless you want to buy three space
heaters and throw them each one in the
tent which sometimes is too strong and
it gets too warm in there because it's
right on them you know what I mean but
if you're running the intake fan often
times it's got the uh you know the the
the adjuster on it right so if it's
pulling too much or too little you can
adjust that but I've you know I've used
a a big tote that I got from Home Depot
put the you know kind of leaned it
against the uh the space heater against
the wall and then I had the three uh
duct hoses going in there and just
sucking the hot air right from that area
and it helped warm the entire you know I
might be cool where I'm at because I
want the I want the heater on me but my
my tents are thriving with with the
right temperature
so that external that external help in
my opinion is really important if you're
in the garage whether it's that that
outside AC unit that's going to help
cool the
tents um and also the dehumidifier which
is fantastic when it comes to drying but
um and and also just a quality space
heater that that you could use if you
got one tent you could either kind kind
of Hose it in or whatever I'm not big on
putting the heater right in the tent
depending on how much room you've got
especially if it's going to be right
next to one of your plants so I kind of
like it to come from the general the
intake fan I'm just a fan of that that's
an interesting way to go about it having
it duck directly into the grow tents the
way that you're you're doing it there's
different ways to go about it right like
you could just do it passively and just
grab what's coming in from your garage
for example but uh that might not be as
good as the way that you're doing it now
followup question I have for you is do
you also have the rectangle intake vents
open as well or you only have the hoses
hooked up to the ventilation socks I
don't have them open I I if if I you
know if if I don't if the weather's
perfect the intake the fan is just kind
of sitting on top of the tent right um
and one of the things that I do to kind
of you know what I I like to cover it
with panty
hose the uh the intake fan if it's
sitting there by itself I'll cover it
with panty hose um as a as a really good
method to kind of filter
out stuff and you know um it'll kind of
blow your mind because if you kind of if
you clean it weekly you you know spack
it against like you know something
you'll just the amount of Filth that
just bounces out of there is disturbing
but at the same time kind of refreshing
because you're like wow this would have
all gotten sucked right into the grow
tent and just been part of that
environment you know what I mean but um
that's why I was saying clean the filter
on the AC unit if you're going to duct
it that way because you just you're
trying to make sure that anything going
in your tent is guess as filtered as you
can if you're not using you know the uh
like a carbon filter or something like
that as an intake to like kind of bring
in clean air that way but most people
these days kind of use the uh carbon
filter to to kind of kill the smell
right so it's usually the ex the exhaust
that it's connected to so good tips you
know I know we spent a long time here on
just the environment conditions and how
balance them and stuff like that but I
feel like it's it's kind of an important
thing to talk about when you're growing
in a garage because it's just it's so
different you know it can be so
different or it could be similar to
growing inside of a house but for most
people I feel like it's uh it's got its
own unique challenges when it comes to
environment but let's move on to other
parts of the grow let's get into some
Basics what do you typically use for
like container size and type and and I
think you mentioned you're in soil right
what's in your mix so containers
um well when I'm when they're seedlings
you know actually I kind of like to use
Clear Solo cups that I put inside of a
colored Solo Cup um because it you know
it helps you kind of look at the roots
you know you kind of know what's going
on down there and it's it's a really
kind of a cool cheat code um when you're
growing so but I start off in a in a
Solo Cup clear in a colored one and then
if I'm if I'm going straight into the
the final resting place the home that
it's going to be in I'll go into a a
fabric
pot um but if I'm going to transfer up
to it I'll I'll go from plastic into and
then the final one is a is a fabric one
just because transplanting is a heck of
a lot easier pulling it out of a plastic
pot versus a uh a fabric one cuz those
roots like to kind of dig into the
fabric ones right so it it could be kind
of chaotic to get them out of there um
as far as a
mix um soil so I like to use typically
my mix is like one3 happy frog from Fox
Farms and then you know 2/3 uh ocean
forest and then within that I like to to
add uh worm castings you know I used to
add peite but I feel like Fox Farms uh
has enough in there to you know air
rat's just fine I think in my opinion
but I used to add peite but I don't do
that anymore so it's just really it's
one3 Happy Frog two3 ocean forest and uh
some worm castings nice and did you
mention I think I met to what container
size those fabric pots are oh sorry
container size it varies typically if
you know if I'm kind of doing a simple
like a pheno hunt or something like that
I'll throw them into two you know two
gallon pots just so you know kind of
maximize the room um but typically I
kind of stick to the 3 to five range uh
depending on what I'm you know uh how
big I'm really trying to get them but if
you're in a tent they're going to get so
big you know you don't I don't in my
opinion you don't really need to get
bigger than a 5 gallon pot you know
unless you're trying to grow a monster
in a 5x5 or something like that but you
know I think three three gallons is is
is convenient five gallons is convenient
I was actually asking myself the other
day I'm like I wonder why they don't
make four gallon CU they make one two
three and five but they don't make four
which could be even convenient too but
uh I'm usually between three and five
there was a four I'd probably buy a four
that's just Diva yeah when s in it
growing I'm mostly the same as you
either a three gallon or five gallon
sometimes I like to just be in the five
because well for mostly just for like
watering purposes if I'm hand watering
you know the 5 gallon is going to need
to be watered a little bit less than the
three gallon for example so that's the
the only reason why I would really
choose a five over a three when I'm
Sanic gardening okay so you mentioned
your mix third Happy Frog two3 ocean
forest and then some worm castings now
eventually those nutrients are going to
deplete and you're going to need to add
in some more nutrition when do you
typically start your first feeding what
does it consist of and then yeah if you
can walk us through kind of the
remaining life cycle and how you do your
feedings you know
I kind depends on how the plant bigger
when I kind of when I start like if
they're thriving and they're growing
probably I don't know you know after
I've transplanted them from like the
Solo Cup into a a bigger you know uh
home I guess you can say um say probably
3 weeks something like that you know I
think the nutrients in the soil they
they last a pretty good amount of time
so typically about 3 weeks
two to three weeks I'm not heavy on on
the feeds so I I don't try to kind of
push too much on them and it you know in
my past what I give has shown me success
so probably about you know two to three
weeks um as far as what I did you ask
what I give what do I use yeah what do
you use for nutrient lineup so I'm a I'm
a kind of a creature of habit so when I
first started you know a lot of the
information I got was from a from a
friend of mine that was growing at home
um out in central California
more on on a grander scale uh for
businesses and um he introduced me to a
company called veg plus boom Bloom
they're out in San Diego and um you know
they have a part A and A Part B they've
got a foler spray as well as something
they call life which is uh their their
version of the micro rise but I've been
you know I've been using them for for
since I started and you know I I do add
some you know some Bloom additives and
such during flower but um you know when
they're seedlings I typically give them
you know RO water with some seaweed
extract um kind of helps I think it
helps the kind of just helps get them
started I think as far as like group
development things like that and then
once I once they're in veg you know
typically if I'm looking at PPM it's
it's right around like the 500 range um
with the uh with the part Aid that I
give um unless I give molasses that
usually help thanks to PPM I think
Skyrocket if I'm not mistaken but
uh during veg I just I just give the
part A you know I add I add some cow
here and there like to add silica um you
know I think it helps with uh with just
making the the plant just more sturdy uh
as far as branches and just being able
to you know carry some weight later on
right so I like to add silica and then
once I've kind of gotten into flour you
know you you add you keep everything
that I had before you know I I include
you know U molasses I like to include um
you know microorganisms so some
microbial noint inoculant as well to
kind of just make sure that the root
zone is active and you know breaking
down certain things and and giving the
plant the opportunity to uptake the
nutrients that it needs but that's when
I add the uh the flowering part of veg
plus Bloom and then I also um like to
add some uh Bloom boosters um just to
kind of help stack not always convinced
that those things are working or the
brands that I'm using are the best when
it comes to that so I'm kind of looking
at again it's tough for me to make
changes when it comes to the nutrient
lines because you know what I've used is
shown me success but I don't know if I
can get better right so you kind of have
that in the back of your mind you know
I've got I've got this which was sent to
me and I've got to work that into my
system it's just like I've got this
mental block when it comes to switching
up nutrients I'm like come on Paul you
got from the stash man they sent it to
you use the damn thing but I got to I
got to work it into my regimen you know
what I mean it's just funny how people
become you know I like to experiment on
one end when it comes to like plant
training and things like that but on
when it comes to like the nutrients that
I give I'm just I'm I'm very simple I
mean you know to the point where you
know I don't measure PPM anymore because
I know this is what I give my plants and
I've measured it in the past like like a
rocket scientist you know you're writing
down exactly what you're giving and you
know I I used to even measure the PPM
like I I'd add calag and then I'd add
you know that nutrient and then I'd mix
it up and then I check the PPM and then
I'd add the other things and I start
writing everything down and it got to
the point where I was like okay I kind
of know where all this lies at this
point I had two scoops of the nutrient
of the of the part A and then I had one
scoop of the part B and I had 5
milliliters of this and I and and then I
just at some point you know where the
PPM lies right so but that that's kind
of where I'm at you know great white
when I'm doing transplants um always
helpful you know as far as just dumping
it on there on the roots help helps the
development in the transplant so you
don't get any transplant shock so
call it simple but I have my routine I
guess yeah I see that bag of stash blend
behind you and I was wondering when you
when you're going to talk about that and
incorporate that into because you'll be
able to uh cut out some of those bottles
like you mentioned using seaweed and the
microbio inoculant and silica I mean
that's all located in stash blend so
it'd be interested to see if you
incorporate that in and able to cut out
some bottles and save some money that's
one of the whole reasons why we put
together that blend well you know what
I'm going to do so when we met at at
Grower's Gauntlet you actually gave me a
pack of uh chill out OG so I'm going to
grow those I'm going to grow those and
I'm going to use the stash so I'm going
to I'm going to break myself in and
force force it upon me to do what I got
to do to change that habit but um I'll
post updates you'll see them it'll it'll
be uh and I'll use the good old AC
Infinity setup here to make sure that
it's all perfect conditions but I'm
going to I got to I got to break myself
here awesome I'll definitely be keep my
eye up for that one for sure now you
mentioned you're using the veg plus
Bloom I've actually heard about that
company quite a long time ago now do you
follow their feeding chart at a full
dose or some folks will start with like
a half dose for example you know if I
remember correctly they're they're
they're looking for a little bit more
than what I'm putting in um but I think
I don't need to again I think that you
know when it comes to you know
harvesting medicinal plants you know I
get
I get what I'm looking for in them
whether it's the the the flavor the you
know the aroma um you know the uh
effects I guess you can say right so I
don't give the full dose again I stick
to my what I do and you know and you
know my ppms again I think I think it's
molasses right that when you add that to
your to your uh water it's the the PPM
spikes pretty high I think it was
molasses but my my PPM typically does
not exceed like 700 On Any Given feeding
so it's in my opinion pretty medium to
low okay and then I think you mentioned
that AR water is that what we're using
for a water source and then if it is how
do you go about the watering throughout
the grow cycle so I'm fortunate to have
an AO um Mach thing built into my my my
uh kitchen tap here um but at the same
time sometimes when you're trying to
pour like five gallons from that thing
it's not it doesn't give you what you
need right so um I'll get what I can and
then then my family yells at me because
they can't get new water so and then I I
go in hiding but
um my tap is not so bad so it kind of
runs at like I think 220 to 240 PPM
which is reasonable right it's not so
bad so you know I'll I'll use that water
too but you know what I'll typically do
is I'll pull um I'll pour it into like a
big container type thing and I'll let it
sit for you know a good day or so to let
the chlorine and whatever else is in
there and of dissipate and leave um and
then I I you know I use something called
drops of balance which you know maybe we
could talk about later but um it helps
clean the water as well of you know and
it helps it helps in in a variety of
ways but I I I like to water with by
hand so you know whether it's using a
bottle you know what I mean or a hand
pump if it's if it's hard to reach but I
kind of like getting in there it it it
forces you to kind of get get up in the
plants and really get a good look at
them and and so I I don't mind you know
and and typically if I'm going to travel
or something like that I I plant my you
know you can kind of play games with
your watering cycle so you could push it
one more day so you could then water one
more day later you know in a you know
down the road or whatever and then you
know that okay I'm going to be gone for
3 days so if I water them now by the
time I get back they'll be perfect you
know they'll want water again or or
feeding again but they're not going to
dry out you know so I I coordinate
myself on that but um I like hand water
it's it's a good excuse to really kind
of get up in there and see what's going
on you know yeah you mentioned the AO
system under the sink and I have the
same thing and same problem where my
fiance is like I used up all the
water and uh what I've done is I have
individual water jugs that I use now so
one gallon jugs and I just fill those up
and I have a whole line of them right
outside of my grow Ro I'm stockpiling
water a little bit so I try to avoid
running out of water at the uh at the
tap there but uh the RO system for those
that are kind of interested is a little
bit of a misconception people say oh
they're too expensive there are
thousands of dollars for a system which
isn't true there are systems that I
think I paid $250 for mine $250 for mine
and it's a one: one so uh the technology
getting a little more efficient here
before it was a 1 to three so for every
one gallon of R water you'd be wasting
three gallons well now with the uh the
one I have is 1: one it's called the
Apec r o s-100 it's an Essence series
what it's called I just pulled it up
right here for every 1gallon of RL water
you're only wased one gallon of water
and you can take that waste line they
call it you can take that and put it
into your own 5 gallon bucket for
example and use it on something else use
it on your house plants some people use
it Outdoors so fig I mention that stuff
that uh yeah or water isn't as expensive
as some may say it is and it doesn't
waste as much as it used too oh yeah the
efficiency of those things is uh it's
it's gotten much better that's for sure
so exactly when you're looking that's
probably one of the key things you're
looking for is what is the efficiency
right cuz they're all around that 200
plus like right in that range right $2
to $300 these days so it's which one is
the most effective one and and you know
least wasteful I guess right so for sure
and directly relating to water let's get
into pH do you monitor the pH at
all yeah that's one thing that I do um
religiously you know I I I like to I
like to kind of keep it in in the range
of typically I'd say 6.0 to
6.4 um my sweet spot is typically around
6.2 but I kind of do like them the flu
weight between like you know 6.1 to 6.3
if it's anywhere in that range I'm fine
um you know one thing I want to do more
frequently is is uh check the pH of the
runoff just to kind of see where that
sits um because it you know that's a
it's a pretty good indicator of kind
kind of am I am I you
know you know kind of what is it looking
like there you know what I mean you know
I know what's going in but how's it
looking coming out kind of tells you
what the uh kind of what's what's being
held up in the medium right so it's uh
something that I should be looking at
more more frequently that didn't
probably check in the PPM of my runoff
too um just to kind of see where that's
at you know got it and then you
mentioned that you monitor PPM I know
some people do PPM some people do EC
instead for PPM I caught that you do 500
PPM for veg what do you typically go up
to in flowering you know it doesn't
typically exceed 750 you know some of
the bloom additives that you know when
you when you when you include them
whether it's uh big bud or uh you know
there's a grow Tech monster Bloom I
realize the PPM doesn't increase
significantly when I add those to the uh
to my nutrients so it doesn't it doesn't
I don't really don't see it get past
750 so it's you know it's it's not it's
not too you know back in the you know
when I first learned from my friend you
know saying pushing 1,400 PPM on you
know with certain you know certain
things and and all the time and I
realized you know I'm I'm giving half of
that now and I think the quality of you
know my finished product is
significantly better so I mean at the
end of the day you
know while while most companies probably
are being as truthful as they can be but
they're not going to tell you to use
this much you know because then the
product's going to sit down on your
shelf forever right so they they
probably want you to kind of get through
it fairly quickly so they're probably
telling you what you should use at a
maximum is their minimum you know what I
mean like oh yeah this is what you need
to use because they want you to kind of
come back but I mean I could be way off
but what I do know is I give a fraction
of what they're you know I've been told
to and it comes out just
fine again plus this you know when
you're
if you're transplanting and you're
putting fresh soil you know you're
taking this and you're putting into
something here all this additional soil
that you've added into your pod is new
and it's filled with nutrients again so
you're kind of re-upping what was
depleted earlier to you know it's right
back it's right back in in the mix again
right so you don't in my opinion you
don't always need to be pushing them so
hard is that PPM numbers that you're
giving is that the PPM of the nutrient
solution going into the soil or is that
a runoff measurement that's going into
the soil glad I clarified that because I
think some people might be thinking that
was the the runoff number so okay so
that's the measurement going in yeah
cool okay I want to switch over now to
another thing that uh could be more of a
problem in a garage than it is just
fully indoor which is pests what do you
typically do in order to prevent pests
when growing in your garage so there's a
couple things um you know since since my
garage is typically open I know that I
get a fresh dose of dust and stuff
frequently right so you've got to keep
not only the inside of of the
environment clean at all times but
you've also got to work on keeping the
outside of the environment as clean as
you can too right so I think first and
foremost is be you know be tidy right
you're you're spending a lot of time and
energy into these plants and you don't
want to be lazy on that end of things so
you know keep clean um inspect your
plants frequently as well you know don't
be too hand hands off really got to look
close
because you know for those of you that
have you know you know Chris I'm sure
you've had pests in the past but when
you're looking at your your your flowers
if you're in flower or even if you're in
veg you're appreciating the flower and
you're looking at it but when you know
you've had pests in the past you don't
you you realize your eyes are playing
games on you now because you're kind of
looking away from everything and you're
looking deeper into things cuz you're
trying to see movement or something that
you know a bug or something like that
and it's just annoying right so I I try
to be as preventative as possible but
some of the things I do you know I'll
add sticky
traps you know sometimes I'll hang them
outside of my tent and I'll put them
inside the tent even when I don't have a
problem because it might be an indicator
of a problem on the horizon right so um
you don't need to have an issue to have
a sticky trap kind of in your tent right
you want to take pictures you could take
them out make the P the pictures look
pretty again but uh think when you're
not taking any pictures or videotaping
or something like that leave one in
there what's the what's what's the harm
right uh you know I mentioned earlier I
like if if my intake fans aren't being
ducted with like AC or heater I like to
put panty hose over them um just on the
cover um and it really is a fantastic
way of letting air flow in still but
really acting as a pretty darn good
screen to kind of keep that dust and
different types of sediment or whatever
it might be um outside of your plan
right so there's you know there's lots
of proactive measures you can do to make
sure that you're not getting uh any
infestation because when it happens it's
frustrating and then you got to play the
reactive game you know and and that's
it's no fun are you doing any like
sprays or anything and like the veg
stage to prevent pests you know I've
what do people use like uh dish soap and
water you know I think you know I might
want to I might want to look into using
that in the future I do use again you
know drops of balance you know you can
use that as a f year spray which which
helps
um it helps really kind of it's
preventative in in lots of ways it helps
prevent plant from like you know
intaking in insecticides and and things
like that but you know I don't aside
from spraying that I haven't really
sprayed anything unless I've needed to
you know if I've had an infestation the
neem oil might come into play if I'm in
veg um if I'm in flour that's a
different story you know then uh you got
different problems then got it now have
you had any major INF ation of any
pesel thankfully major I wouldn't say no
you know like I've seen pictures of of
spider mes and webs and like oh my gosh
like it's you know it that would be so
disheartening but you know I've had
problems with you know white flies uh
fungus snats thrips
aphids and you know white flies are
annoying looks like little dust flying
around they're really annoying but
they're not so hard to handle they
really are a sucker for the yellow
sticky traps so um those are really
helpful for those and fungus snats you
know um aphids and um thrips are much
more annoying you know actually uh this
one right here uh I had noticed some uh
some damage from thrips recently
actually so I had to uh and they're in
it's thankfully they're they're in veg
so I was able to kind of you know uh I
haven't seen any lately so thankfully I
think I i' I've beat them but I you know
it's kind of a number of steps to take
that again when you're in Veg it's much
easier if you're in flour I think you
know what I've done in the past and you
know actually what I did with this one
here uh for starters you
know uh use NE oil spray them spray them
with NE oil um not a preferred thing but
it does help right soak kind of the top
layer of soil and then I did a lot of
visual killing right so you're just kind
of your eyes are all over your plants
you see a little bit of movement you
kill them um while I was doing that I
had ordered some ladybugs off of Amazon
so ladybugs are you know they're you
know plant Warriors right they help they
help us they're not they're not evil
they they're what we want in in our
Gardens so ordered some from Amazon
unfortunately you know they showed up
during that extreme heat wave that we
had so I think half of them were
unfortunately deceased when I opened up
the uh the package they came in but I
let them fly in here and they did their
thing for you know I'd say a good week
just kind of let them take care of
business um and then you know it got to
the point where I pulled each pot out
and I made sure there was none on there
and they like to go underneath the
fabric pot so I knocked them off and put
them outside and then I uh gave it one
more spray of NE oil and then I used
icious Earth um as a top layer which is
really great it's also really annoying
cuz it's such a it's so it could be so
messy it's just white powder everywhere
right so um I I you know I top layered
it and just to make sure that if there
was any uh larvi or you know whatever
the middle stage of those things are
called people can't remember but um that
you know this would help kill them so
you know I was using the ne oil for the
plant itself see if I can take care of
whatever was on the plant still if
anything and then the dious earth I
think helped kill whatever was still in
the soil um and then afterwards I just
watered over that and thankfully but now
it's still little dust particles here
and there you kind of staring at the
plants you see little white specks
you're like what is that and then you
realize it's just dious Earth you just
kind of rub it out you know what I mean
but uh thankfully I've uh I think I've
rid myself of that problem so it's a
couple steps you know hopefully your
users get some information out of that
you know I know neem oil is a bit
questionable but you know you try to buy
the one that's just you know I think
they sell organic versions or the
diluted type or something but it it
ultimately helps you don't want to use
that during flour though during flour
probably just want to go the DI to Earth
on the soil and then let the ladybugs
have at them and then whatever you see
with your eyes just kill what you can
you know if it's something that's not if
it's a mild infestation if it's heavy
you probably you might have to just
scrap it depending on how bad it is
thanks for explaining that in detail I
know we have quite a few people that
battle pests and uh you definitely named
off some some good Solutions there for
people to try next I want to get into
misconceptions what would you say are
some misconceptions about growing in a
garage you know
you kind of hear different things from
different people you know I think that
when it comes down to it if you can
control your environment your garage is
as good as a laboratory you know what I
mean if if it makes no difference I
think that if if you have things dialed
in right and you've got the right
genetics you know you can grow
some high quality flour medicinal flour
or flowers you know Tomatoes whatever
you want to call it anything you know
any vegetables in this environment you
know and and
I was fortunate enough to be part of a
kind of an experiment where you know I
was able to testing is it's expensive
and even those home testing kits are
really pricey when it comes to medicinal
plants but I was fortunate enough to be
part of an experiment where you know
what I what I grew here right behind me
was sent to a a lab in professionally
testing and you know I'm not trying to
toot my horn here but you know what I
grew right behind me in in a garage in
Los Angeles San Fernando Valley uh
tested 30 plus and cannaboids and you
know 28 28.1% thca
so I was you know I was happy you know
you kind of become proud you're like all
right you did pretty good Paul not too
bad
so I think the the primary misconception
is this is not like an ouse you know
what I mean like an outside oh you're
kind of you know shunned and you got to
go in your garage like you can make it
work here you know there's some things
that you might need to use that a
traditional that's growing inside a air
conditioned climate controlled
environment might not have to or even in
a bedroom or a bathroom you know but you
can make it work in the garage that's
for sure good advice and so we do have a
lot of beginners that tune into this
podcast I want to ask you for those
folks that are beginners that are just
getting started growing in a garage what
advice do you have for them you know I
think the community is huge I think
there's no right way to grow plants
right plants kind of grow themselves and
you're just kind of helping them along
the way right so I think you know tuning
into you know podcast like this one
right here and then some of the other
people out there like you
know CLTV Northern scroger you know the
the the you know the AC Infinity after
dark folks you know you learn a lot from
different people you know I there's a
number of people you know when I first
started
growing you kind of feel like you're on
your own little little island you know
that you don't you know your friends
might not grow so you don't really don't
have anyone much to talk to and then I
kind of saw the Instagram community and
I was like oh what's this you know what
I mean and I you know started linking
with people from that from that
community and then I realized wow
YouTube has so many cool things um as
far as like medical going and things
like that and then I found Mr Gro and
then I found people like welcome to the
grow tent and Rose of green and you know
just a variety of these people and then
as time grew some of these other people
came in and you just kind of see what
works for you right you have to kind of
come up with your own formula you don't
always have to scrug you don't always
have to top you don't always have to do
these different types of things that
someone tells you you need to do in
order to to grow you know grade A
medicinal flower right no you know
there's different methods that are going
to work for everybody and you just have
to kind of dial in what's going to work
best for you and um and then go from
there and then another thing
is you know I know income and money is
different for different people right so
if just don't voluntarily go
cheap you know what I mean and and I
don't I'm not going to blame anyone for
going economical right you kind of go
with what works for you but chances are
if you're going to buy some dinky thing
off like Alibaba or something like that
you I can guarantee you're going to
upgrade it because it's not going to get
you what you're looking for so buy
what's going to work best for you you
know what I mean what what you know is
going to provide you the best
environment because you don't want
to spend a little bit of money and then
be able to grow something that's okay
right but if you maybe saved a little
bit more or whatever and put another1
$150 or whatever it might be into a
something that's got environmental
controls and something that's really
going to help
you um just grow better um I just say
just hold off save another paycheck do
what you whatever you have to do but
don't go cheap you know these cheap
lights cheap tents uh cheap neutal nuut
cheap genetics it it you're starting off
at a on a on a kind of behind right
you're kind of starting off at a
negative and in you know you could be as
good as you can be you can only get so
high but I think if you've got that that
the foundation of a good environment and
good lights and good exhaust and good
fans and all that stuff it's just going
to help you that much more right so call
it a team
game well said while we're getting
towards the end of the episode here can
you tell the listeners how they can find
you and what you have upcoming in the
future yeah so you can find me on uh
primarily on Instagram you know my my
handle's wake and bake with Paul um you
know I just opened up a Facebook it's
you know it's really nothing and I've
got a dinky YouTube channel with like
you know that many followers uh so it's
not really anything right right now it's
really my my Instagram um is where you
can find me and I think for Future's
sake you know I'm going to be working on
a couple of things um some more breeding
you know you know I'm going to grow I'm
going to grow the chill out OG and you
know but and I've got something growing
called cat piss right now that you know
I'm kind of looking I'm I'm trying to go
back to those that '90s funk that that
stink that that was out there from back
in the day you know I'm going to make an
attempt to kind of find that um I'm
going to keep working with you know uh
drops of balance um you know I I I did
an experiment with them a little while
back where I had a control and
uncontrolled grow and I'm going to kind
of focus on control all the time and I'm
going to add it in because what it you
know it really kind of helped uh at the
end it helped the tpine profile of what
I had what I had grown which was pretty
cool Shameless plug if you guys are
looking for any drops of balance or
anything from perfect Gardens do10
that's my discount code but it you know
I stand behind that product it was it
was really cool but I'm going to keep
playing you know I like to do different
things you know uh something that my
friend was showing me the other day is
called you know electroculture where he
had sent a picture of somebody that had
grown a plant with this huge copper wire
and I was like what is that and I just
kind of Googled it so for like 10 bucks
I bought something from Amazon it's like
a copper thing that kind of grows with
your plant and apparently the uh the
energy in the in the air it kind of goes
through the copper wiring and and it
helps plants Thrive apparently but I'm
going to keep doing some funny
experiments that I like to do
um you know I I like to you know I like
to play with plants it's it's fun it's
you know it's it's a good time it's a
passion awesome I'll definitely have a
link to Paul's Instagram down in the
YouTube description section below and if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
just search for you'll find them give
them a follow if you're a fellow garage
grower or getting into growing in your
garage or just want to follow for fun
experiments that he's doing also want to
give a big shout out to our patreon
folks being scrolled on the screen right
now thank you keep the lights on going
here in the studio everything from
paying for the editor to the podcast
virtual platform 100% of the money that
gets through patreon goes right back
into the podcast so special thanks to
you Paul thanks so much for coming on to
the podcast today it was great to meet
you in person at the grow Gauntlet and I
really glad you decided to come on to
the podcast here today and talk about
growing in the garage hope you enjoy the
rest of your night hey thanks for having
me and you know hopefully uh some of the
Growers got got some information they
might be able to use but thank you it
was a pleasure meeting you absolutely
all right peace out everyone catch you
in the next episode