coming up on Garden talk you have people
that are growing synthetic and they're
still you know coming out with the same
outcome as you so I stay kind of
open-minded in that aspect like I'm not
opposed to synthetic or organic I don't
think one is better than the other same
thing I'm sitting around 5.8 is being
optimal to me so I'm always like right
away I'm mixing my nutrient solution and
I'm phing it right to 5.8 because I like
to do everything for my phone all lights
and everything are hooked up to Smart
plugs so I could just control it from my
phone so I was like I get notifications
if something's down if the Wi-Fi goes
out like I know like hey this light
isn't going to cut on I need to manually
go do it because something just happened
like an outage happened in my area I
don't think we'll ever maintain what's
perfect to us because as soon as we hit
what we think is perfect then there's
going to be another goal set in stone so
we're always going to be chasing
something as far as perfect goes
foreign
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 84. in this
episode I interview doosa Farms he is a
YouTuber with nearly 6 000 subscribers
and has been gardening for two years
this episode focuses on gardening for
beginners problems and solutions thanks
to all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com Mr
Grow it before we get into it I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
AC Infinity is sponsoring this episode
The Grow tank hits are incredible you
get there ion board LED grow light their
grow tent which is currently the
thickest on the market the ventilation
system clip-on fan and the controller 69
to control it all you also get their
fabric pots a trellis nut plant ties and
trimmers definitely a good price for all
that you get in the kit I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these grow tent
kits and you can use discount code Mr
Grow it if you're buying off their
website AC infinity.com that discount
code actually works for all AC Infinity
items or discount code Mr Grow at 15 if
you're buying off Amazon thanks to Mars
Hydro for sponsoring this video Mars
Hydra has two new LED grow lights the
fc8000 and the fce 8000 bolt grow lights
are 800 watts and will work great in a
4x4 or 5x5 grow space the fc8000 has
Sam's Samsung lm301b diodes and the bars
are detachable the fce 8000 has Bridge
Lux diodes and there are more diodes for
a longer lifespan check out their
website at
mars-hydro.com I'll have a link down in
the description section below and you
can use coupon code Mr Grow it for a
discount on their products
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
doosa Farms how you doing today I'm
doing pretty good man how about yourself
I'm doing good good thanks for asking so
you have been gardening for a couple
years now and I really like talking to
gardeners with one to two years of
experience because it's somewhat of a
fresh set of eyes and I feel like things
can be learned from that and new
approaches can potentially be identified
I also think it can be helpful for
beginner Growers hearing about potential
problems that they can come across and
solutions to those problems and that's
what we're going to get into in today's
episode but first one thing I like to do
with all guests is in introduction can
you tell us a little bit about yourself
and how you got into gardening for sure
so
um like you said doosa Farms
um I've been gardening just under two
years now come December it'll be two
years exactly I got into it literally
just kind of like everybody gets into it
you know I wanna well not everybody else
say but I wanted to yield you know I
smoked already but I was like you know
what let me grow it I can just get
pounds and pounds so that's what I went
with and I started growing right away
quickly learned that you know not
everything is going to be what you
expect uh started the YouTube right away
for the first grow which is kinda
uh I feel like it keeps me true to
myself but you know the critics out
there not a lot of people the viewers
you know the first episode I State like
I'm a new grower but after that people
like quickly like they don't know
they're tuning in maybe in my week four
video and they don't know like hey this
is his first girl so like oh you suck so
you know so just battling just starting
right off with YouTube right away and
then going through that but
um
pretty much as far as like growing um
I think I've I try to like uh I got into
the content creation because I'm like
more of uh I've always I used to game
and I I was like you know what I was
already wanting to do YouTube I've done
it before let me do the same thing and
apply that to the plant starter you know
Channel I was already watching people
like yourself Mr Canucks pigeons uh CLTV
I was already watching a lot of these
people so I was like well let me just
start my own and let me start it from
day one and let everybody just see my
growth so when I'm maybe you know on the
same you know as far as subscribers or
level or whatever like when I'm 200
subscribers in people are looking back
like whoa look at those like this is
where he started at it's you know he's
come a long way like so I can go that
you know it kind of motivates people I
feel like if I if I show them that
they're like okay not everybody starts
as being the best or whatever but I feel
like that's where I can kind of come
into play and just show my progress
through that entire thing I certainly
have to be somewhat Brave in order to
upload your grow to the internet and Sir
you're gonna get a ton of haters
backseat Growers right those are the
ones people who just tell you how to
grow your plants without you even asking
about it so like for like the community
in general I feel like I feel like it's
pretty positive for the most point I
will say like 99 with one percent being
like negative here and there which I
hear a lot of people say that so I think
we can all agree that is pretty positive
for the most part
um because then like are you going to a
gaming page and you see a lot of hate
under those comments or people that do
pranks you'll see a lot of hate under
the comments and stuff like that but it
seems to go pretty well for our
community uh like this morning I get one
it's uh people like oh if I you know if
I grew for you know if I grew plants for
this long and yielded this much like I'd
kill myself or you know like the you
know typical hey but I get one this
morning and then I I like I said I try
to keep things pretty transparent I try
to show everything you know being a
content creator
I know sometimes things can get lost in
there we might not record everything but
when it comes to growing plants I you
know I put the days in there I put where
I'm at on the footage and someone sees
like I'm in veg uh during my plant's
growth at day 89 and they're like no way
you're you know a good grower can never
be great growing like that and I was
like I never claimed I was good nor
great I was like but I appreciate it and
I was like they're like I lost all
respect from you I was like okay that's
a silly way to lose respect for someone
but you know to each its own you have a
great day yeah I agree with you and like
the the community just creates there's a
lot of positive people 99 positive
anyways that's besides the point it's
cool that you're actually
a content creator now and you're
uploading your grow to YouTube so people
can view and you know show off what you
have maybe ask for advice and that's one
of the reasons why I got into it but uh
what would you say is your gardening
style right there's so many different
ways to grow this plant are you indoors
Outdoors are you organic synthetic soil
cocoa what's your style okay so I am an
indoor I am an indoor Gardener I haven't
done any outdoor yet as much as I would
love to I'm just not look once I move uh
into my house once I buy my house I do
plan to do some outdoor stuff but as of
right now I've only done indoor
um as far as my style I feel like I like
to say I try to keep it simple but
sometimes you know I have to keep it as
simple as I can because I do record
video I do footage you know but at the
same time I have to like do certain
things here and there to show the
audience uh things that I wouldn't
normally do like it's just adding the
camera to the mix I'm not saying like
I'm just doing something because of the
camera but I do have to add certain
things here and there just to make you
know I'm battling too you know I'm
fighting two fights I'm trying to make
sure I get some footage for this and
make sure I Garden so but I do try to
keep it as simple as possible to make
that uh have to add in the YouTube stuff
and the content creation making that a
little bit easier and just having fun
but yeah I do try to keep it as simple
as possible have as much fun
um organic and synthetic uh so I've only
done synthetic I did I want to do
organic because a lot of people
um this is my take on organic I feel
like uh I do have some guy green uh I do
have guy green on my shelf and I did try
to use it but how I feel about people
that some people that do organic
gardening is they uh there's there's a
few of them out there like when I first
found out about the organic gardening I
see a lot of people like pushing it and
there's a few of them out there where
they're just like that's the only way
you know that's the best way and they
put so much faith in everything into it
which I you know I feel like organic I
feel like you should try to be as
organic as possible but it's just to me
I relate it to people that do keto in
the fitness world for uh for the viewers
out there that into fitness and know
about people that on the keto diet you
know some people that are on the keto
diet they'll like really push keto like
it's the only way to get in shape the
only way to lose body fat and I feel
like I've relate that to some of the
people that do organic gardening because
it's just like those two personalities
like some other sometimes they can get
like I feel like that's the only way
well it's like you have people that are
growing synthetic and they're still you
know coming out with the same outcome as
you so I stay kind of open-minded in
that aspect like I'm not opposed to
synthetic or organic I don't think uh
one is better than the other like if
they they both they both get the job
done yes I would like to do organic just
for the sake of you know cutting back on
you know the footprint of uh pollution
and stuff like that but as of right now
I've only been doing synthetic and uh
I've ran started off General Hydroponics
I think that's like the typical that was
like the only thing I thought out there
that's the only thing I could find at
first was like General Hydroponics it
was like 30 bucks for three bottles so I
was like I go with the trio the floor
Trio and then since then I've only I've
tried some more General hydroponic stuff
but as of lately I just started for my
every girl I have one right now I've
been running Athena so those are the
only two you know bottle nutrients I've
used I did start off of one of my grows
right away I was the first Coco Grill I
was like I'm gonna do organic I really
wanted to do organic just to say I've
done it and I want to try everything I
want to see what exactly works for me so
I can because I don't know what I like
right now like I know what I like
currently but in a year from now I might
not like what you know I might not like
the same growth style I might have a
totally different growth style might
think this product is way better than
that product
so I started I bought the guy green got
some cocoa
um
that train I grew my plants you know
started them in a humidity Dome once
they got to a certain size they were
already kind of showing some uh like
they needed some nutrients they were
showing a little deficiencies so I was
like all right go and get them
transplanted so I could start you know
top dressing and feeding them well I
didn't know an organic with the organic
or with organic gardening and top
dressing it takes like a week maybe like
around a week to break down and when I
put them in there you know they're going
through that shock of transplant I don't
see any signs of recovery I'm just like
oh what is going on I'm asking people
they said yeah you should have like went
ahead and top dressed it before putting
them in there so the nutrients were
readily available so I was like you know
what maybe not this run maybe the next
run I was like I just mixed up some
bottle nutrients I was like and they
bounced back I was like all right I was
like you know cynganic or whatever yeah
they definitely take time to break down
and that is a common mistake that folks
make another common mistake would be to
keep the medium moist a lot of folks
don't do that when they're growing
organic and there needs to be that
moisture you're in there for proper
nutrient breakdown you know so common
technique when growing with synthetic a
bottled nutrients would be to let the
medium dry out between waterings so
they'll feed their plants let the medium
dry out and then once it's at a certain
point they will water in their plants
again and then kind of repeat that cycle
so they'll be doing dry backs or
somewhat drought stress I guess you
could say which can be beneficial to the
plant but with Organics you could
seriously be missing the boat on things
as far as breakdown and not providing
the proper nutrition to the plants
because the nutrients aren't available
so yeah I think that's a great tip to
some people call that like charging the
media or letting the media cook for a
while for that breakdown to happen so
yeah it's definitely could be helpful
now taking a look back at the last two
years that you've been gardening what
would you say has been your biggest
challenge that you've come across
um really I would say
so for my biggest challenge I would say
is really just chasing that being too
hard on myself I feel like I feel like
that kind of sums it up
um because a lot of us we are our
biggest we are our biggest critic and I
feel like I was you know stressing
letting comments get to me letting you
know he say she say just all letting
that affect me at first you know outside
of I'm already doubting myself I'm
already feeling like I suck I can't do
this and on top of that add in some
other negative stuff from the outside so
it's like other people see that I can't
do it but then I kind of like sat there
and it's like I can do it like you know
this person's doing it this person's
doing why can't I and then
so I just feel like you know really just
being that critic you know just kind of
like appreciating like I just did a post
uh on Instagram where you know I was
talking about
um it was it was an Instagram reel in
like the
it was kind of just like I said when
you're hard on uh when you thought your
Harvest was the worst uh but everybody's
like saying it's actually good and
you're just like surprised you're like
is it good like I don't know but like
everybody's telling you it is so it's
like okay like I did a good job and it's
just that that self-doubt uh and just
chasing perfect I feel like you know
everybody wants that you know the
perfect run and it's just gonna be like
in the rock of Eternity you'll just
continuously you know Chase perfect I
don't think we'll ever maintain what's
perfect to us because as soon as we hit
you know what we think is perfect then
there's going to be another goal set in
stone so we're always going to be
chasing something as far as perfect goes
I can totally relate to that now have
you come across any like deficiencies or
toxicities in your plants over the past
couple years
um yes so for deficiencies and
toxicities um I came across like of
course uh the typical like nitrogen
deficiency at first it was hard for me
especially being a new grower I'm not
the best at identifying stuff right away
like now as you go through them like
it's hard to relate to Google and tell
Google like hey my plants Leaf is this
like you know Google can't see it
um so I'm over here trying to explain to
Google but I'm a new grower so I don't
know these certain terminology I don't
know how to use certain words I don't
know I'm just like hey the leaf is
yellow I don't know how to explain like
it's wilting I didn't I don't I don't
even think to use that word wilting and
just really like related to where I
could find an article but okay this is
the problem but so I've run into like a
nitrogen deficiency
um I've run into like a you know low
light having low light light deficiency
because uh my lights went out and I was
just kind of like taking a step back I
was like you know I'm not going to
breathe down the plant's neck I'm gonna
take a step back and then like the day I
take a step back I don't know all my
lights are on automatic so
when that when I took that step back I
didn't go in there and check them for
like two three days come back in and
then I was like oh the lights are off
and I'm looking at the plans got some
you know yellowing at the top so I was
like okay turn as soon as the light
kicks back on they're good they bounce
back
as far as other deficiencies
um I have run into
I've run into like a
was a pH uh I've run into like a lockout
I run into like a nutrient lockout due
to pH and
honestly when I ran into that I didn't
really I didn't know like it was hard
for me to really tell what I was running
to when I because I originally started
in soil and there was a lot of mistakes
I made I didn't check my runoff I didn't
think it was that important I'm like hey
this is what I'm phing this is what I'm
running everything should be good that's
what's going into it well what's coming
out of it you know is that the same what
I put into it is that what's coming out
so I ran into stuff like that nutrient
build up
um you know the salt buildup and stuff
and the plants just not being able to
absorb getting you know the plants
burning wilting and just kind of dying
off that way because they just don't
have that optimal environment because
I'm allowing them to sit and pretty much
you know terrible condition
so when I kind of I kind of gave up on
soil because I didn't know that and
started dwc which is as like it was a
different ballpark right there
um and but that actually helped me
figure out like because and and dwc you
don't have uh the runoff you don't have
an actual runoff everything's in that
Reservoir um even in rdwc I mean the
runoff is circulating throughout
everything everything's all there the
water's just sitting there I mean it's
moving through Bubbles and stuff like
that but there is no runoff there's
nothing no drainage so once I realized I
started running into problems in dwc I
kind of related that back to soil I was
like wait you know I'm my pH is rising
or PPM is rising in uh dwc so I was like
maybe I was running into like some
problems with soil so I ran another soil
plant I checked I'm like start checking
the runoff and that's when I realized I
was like I'm over feeding you know I I
didn't know how big the runoff was I was
I was to see people say like hey check
your runoff but I didn't think it was
important so I I ran into uh you know
how to learn the hard way
um but I haven't run into too many
deficiencies most of the times it's
literally just like some sort of
nutrient deficiency uh you know the Cal
Mag is uh especially since I'm growing a
cocoa now which I learned that through
one of the garden talk uh episodes I
didn't realize the cocoa actually like
pulls some of that cow mag and it kind
of like takes you have to like up the
cow mag a little bit when growing in
Cocoa I didn't know that at first but I
previously watched one of your garden
talk episodes like a couple weeks ago
and then I found out and
huge difference in the girl right there
you mentioned low light deficiency
and I think what you're actually
referring to this first time I ever
heard anybody say low light deficiency
record I don't know why I said it like
that
uh I I think what you're referring to is
actually iron deficiency and that's
something super super common what it is
is basically it's a yellowing that
starts at the from the petiole so let's
get the base of the leaf and it works
its way up to the top of the leaf and
you see that a lot with new growth so
you mentioned that like your lights were
off for a day or two or whatever and
then you opened up your tent and then
you notice that the yellowing this
happened at the top of the leaves it
just hasn't received the light in order
to convert it to green and typically
what will happen is you put your lights
back on and with a matter of hours
you'll see those leaves turn from yellow
to Green I see this a lot with new
Growers they will they'll have their
their seedling it'll Sprout from The
Medium once the lights are off
so then the lights will come on and
they'll open up at 10 they'll be like
why is my lead why is my seedling yellow
completely yellow what's going on what
am I under feeding but little did I know
all they needed was that little bit of
light and it will convert over to Greens
so I thought that was a good call out
there they've seen a lot in the stretch
phase like after you flip the plant to
flowering those first three weeks
sometimes you get really heavy stretch
and so when your lights are off for that
12 hour period for example when you're
growing photo period plants you'll see
right when you turn the lights on you
open up your tent you'll see there's
some yellowing on the top leaves and
again there's no problem there that's
normal it's just with the new growth
it'll start off yellow if it's not
receiving light right away okay see
that's totally perfect makes it a little
bit simpler because I know whenever
whenever I get to flower I know that
they're stretching I know they're
demanding a lot more so with it being
like that I always seem like I got some
yellow growth I'm like hey maybe I need
to take this picture from like a
different angle so people aren't just
like oh your plants look yellow but you
know and I didn't really think about the
fact that uh that's I know in flower I
don't really typically worry about I'm
like oh it's common but at the time when
I wasn't when it was happening in veg I
was like sitting there like oh it's the
lights being out so I'm actually I'm I'm
glad to know that it's actually from the
iron and the plant's ability to like
actually break it down and turn green
yeah easy fix on that one and a common
misconception for for Growers for new
Growers I should say so you also
mentioned pH lockout now is there a
specific PH range that you're aiming for
uh yes with um when I was running soil I
was I think I was fluctuating anywhere
between 6.2 and 6.8
um but I'm no longer a soil grower I
probably the only time I've ever grown
slow again is maybe outside eventually
but I don't really plan on doing soil
anytime soon but for me I'm all
Hydroponics now I'm running Coco just
started my first cocoa run and then dwc
and same dwc and uh Coco
um same thing I'm sitting around 5.8 is
being optimal to me
um so I'm always like right away I'm
mixing my nutrient solution and I'm PhD
in it right to 5.8 and then that's where
that's where I try to stay I let it
fluctuate a little bit I may bring it
down to somewhere around 5.5 up here a
lot of people recommend that so
sometimes I'll you know Let it go down
to 5.5 or you know 6.2 being high but I
typically just 5.8 throughout the entire
thing I've always had good luck in Cocoa
in particular doing 5.8 pH so I'll mix
up my nutrients in my reservoir pH to
5.8 and then give that to the plants and
I've always had just really good growth
really good luck with that so it's no
surprise that you're having good luck as
well I feel like that's perfect and I
actually starting off in Coco say I'm
going to call back to another one of
your uh episodes it's the same exact
episode I do not remember his name but
he was talking about Coco and I feel bad
for not know his name but it's probably
doggo the Hut okay so I was watching I
was watching that video and me I
previously ran soil I'm thinking Coco is
the same thing as soil you know I didn't
really think I need to look anything up
different for Coco I'm like well I you
know I know what to do I just go in
there I'm phing to around 6.5 that's uh
that's what I was doing and I was still
kind of like having some the growth
wasn't what I thought it would be and
just things were being a little off I
was like what's going on you know
everything should be going well right
now and then I'm watching that uh
watching that uh episode on the podcast
and I found out I was like 5.8 when when
started doing I was like pretty much the
same because of my plants in dwc were at
the same growth stage so I was like I'm
making two batches of nutrients I'm
doing 5.8 for my dwc but going to do 6.5
for Coco but after watching the episode
I was like I could just saved myself so
much time by just doing one you know one
reservoir full of 5.8 and then just
doing I'm just saving myself so much
time so I started doing 5.8 right away
after that episode and from there I was
like you know 5.8 from here on out it's
all 5.8 nice now have you mixed anything
in with the cocoa like some people take
the cocoa and I don't know if you're
using brick or the bagged cocoa and some
people will take that and they'll mix in
like air some form of aeration whether
it be like perlite or Palmas or
something like that are you doing any of
that at all
um no but I have also seen some people
say that um
uh I've actually been doing right now
I'm just doing the cocoa breaks I want
uh the floor Flex cocoa breaks I just
found that to be like super easy when I
was looking online I didn't have a store
near me that just carried cocoa or maybe
they didn't carry the cocoa that I would
like so I was like you know go online
I'm looking at prices and I was like you
know what this these floor I keep seeing
these floor effects uh cocoa bags and
just other different varieties but I
kept seeing the floor Flex ones so I was
like you know what I'm gonna try that
out it seems pretty simple I've had
reptiles before I've messed with bricks
of cocoa so it should be the same you
know concept so that's what I want I
want the cocoa bricks and I just pretty
much you know prepped them that way I
didn't add anything to it just left them
exactly how they were and just you know
uh because they come dry so I just put
add some moisture they expanded and then
from there that I just kept it at that
all right so you didn't do any rinsing
or buffering of the brick it's common
technique that people do is they'll
rinse it out because it's a lot of these
come with a high salt content and that's
really really not needed for plant
growth well let me take that back there
is some plants that can take sodium but
some of these cocoa bricks just have an
excess amount of sodium in it so they'll
rinse that out and then they'll buffer
it in with like those they'll soak the
brick in with Cal Mag for example and so
that basically the cocoa particles
retain cations so think of it like a
magnet so that calcium magnesium those
are cations they stick to those cocoa
particles did you do any rinsing or
buffering or was it straight out of the
brick that you just grew in yeah well
right right away I guess I kind of rinse
a little bit because I had a friend they
told me as soon as they saw that I had
the cocoa breaks I was like hey I'm
getting ready to do these I knew that he
had already done some cocoa in the past
the same floor Flex bricks he hits me up
he's like right away he's like hey make
sure you like really um
you know rinse them off they like you
said the salt he said they're pretty
high like when I get them they're always
like already at like a three e uh three
uh three EC so I was like I was sitting
there nervous about that I was like uh
um okay so I I did kind of rinse it in a
way right away
um but once I like got it I didn't rinse
it too much I just kind of filled the
bags up and I had a lot of runoff so it
kind of got uh rinsed out but I didn't
really stress it uh rinsing too much and
I would check the runoff after you know
watering my plants and I've seen that
everything what I was putting in it was
roughly around the same
so I didn't have to worry about that too
much but I was nervous about that when
he told me that I was like oh no like
I'm gonna like burn my plants or you
know whatever I was like all the salt
build up I was like super nervous about
that so I did a little bit of rinsing
got it and you talked about pH a little
bit but let's get into EC and PPM that's
another thing that people will check
whether it be the EC or PPM of the
nutrient solution going in or the runoff
value are you monitoring the EC or PPM
at all
um yes uh with dwc I was I monitor I
used to monitor daily I would constantly
go in there and check daily but then
that kind of gets played out when I have
like seven different buckets and I'm
have to I don't have rdwc so I'm
checking seven individual buckets and
that's kind of like once I stopped like
I took a step back I stopped stressing
that portion so much I'm constantly
checking it because that was my con uh
that's what I was under the
interpretation that like I literally had
to check it every day and had to make
sure everything stayed in line but once
I kind of like you know I check it every
I check it two three times a week I'm
not really stressing it as much
as far as the dwc uh Coco anytime I see
some runoff you know I'll I'll check the
runoff just to make sure but yeah I
don't I don't typically uh check it all
too often for the PPM I go by PPM uh not
the EC I just feel like PPM is just to
me EC is just like the smaller number
and I feel like the PPM to me is just
it's a lot easier to uh understand and I
was like you know I'll just stay with
PPM because some some people like some
people only do EC so they'll refer to
everything as EC and like I just don't
have any knowledge of it like I could
look at a chart and like you know look
at a side-by-side comparison like okay
this PPM should be around this EC
um but I don't I don't typically uh
refer to the EC result at all even
though my meter does check EC I just uh
stick strictly PPM
which I do check uh the dwc I want to
make sure you know if my if it's
lowering if the PPM is lowering I'm like
okay everything's good the plant's
absorbing those nutrients properly uh if
the PPM is rising might hold on
something's wrong
um maybe I need to feed a little bit
lower dosage maybe something else is
going on for the you know maybe the uh
the mix wasn't right maybe something was
just off and I know there's some sort of
problems where the plants not absorbing
it
so I try to I do check it uh here and
there I do try to check my PPM and stay
on top of it but I'm not stressing it as
much as I did right away when I first
started okay yeah and there are
conversion charts that you can google
and find EC to PPM and you know some
people use EC some people use PPM I
wouldn't say one way is right and one
way is wrong right this one's a
conversion of the other right there's
also 500 scale and 700 scale meters so
you just have to be careful there and
and know what your meter is whether it's
a 500 scale TDS tester or a 700 scale
TDS tester because those are different
calculations from EC and just like that
I just learned something
yeah usually I think it's Europe is
usually using the 700 scale U.S I think
it's a mix between 700 and the 500 scale
so yeah the best way to go about it in
my opinion is to contact the
manufacturer if you're buying off Amazon
for example sometimes it'll somebody
will ask that question in the question
section on the Amazon listing so
sometimes I'll search that to see if
they reveal if it's 500 scale or 700
scale or you can ask the question see if
somebody responds or just contact the
manufacturer and they'll tell you what
what scale it's on and um also since we
talked about the pH just to touch back
on that because I talked about it with
the PPM but uh for my pH like I said I'm
keeping that 5.8
um but I used to stress it a lot like
I've already said I was trying to make
sure my every every day it had to be at
5.8 I'm constantly you know adding ph up
or PH down to make sure in my dwc system
that it was at 5.8 and once I stopped on
the my two previous girls I stopped like
doing that I just let it I was like you
know what I start day A1 I prep my you
know I prep my nutrient solution added
to the plants and then from there
I just I was like you know what I check
it the next day I see it went from 5.8
to like 6.3 I was like whoa what is
going on because I mean dwc it's common
so I'm like what's going on and it but I
was fighting the urge to pH it back down
to 5.8 so I was like you know what take
a step back I'm gonna see what happens
the next day it's at six this is like
almost like 6.1 6.2
um and then by time I just let it go
until the next water change which was
like a week later I come in there to
change the water was at 5.9 so I was
like okay the plant you know the plant's
gonna it fluctuates and you know the
plant it didn't seem like everything was
wrong with the plant so now I don't
really Chase my pH at all anymore
um I check it still but I'm not really
chasing it to make sure it stays at 5.8
I kind of let them fluctuate and do
their own thing as long as there's no
problems what type of water are you
using let's get into that a little bit
okay um
so I'm right now for the water I'm using
tap water uh which my tap water comes
out pH around 7.6 7.7 sometimes
um with the PPM being around 137
actually just I'm actually doing a video
today so I just checked it so it's at
137 as of today my PPN was at 137. I
would like to do some uh Ro reverse
osmosis I see like you do ro and a lot
of people do ro but I was like you know
what I'm in an apartment right now I
don't want to set up you know that I was
like you know I'll wait till I get to my
more permanent spot once I get to the
house once I buy the house I'll start
running some Ro but as right now I've
only ran tap water okay and then in
particular when you're in Cocoa how do
you know when to water what do you use
to determine when to water
um yes so when I'm watering uh at first
I was I didn't need I thought I was
needing water to run off like I don't
have like the best draining system I
just haven't been flitch I don't have
like a flood table I just haven't flood
trays so I have you know seven different
cocoa plants so I'm having to you know
keep moving plants out of the way and
you know just move the plants and then
dump the actual tray out itself so that
can kind of become a little work when
especially as the plants get bigger
so I try not to do too much as far as
the uh the runoff but I still do get run
off I just try to make sure I don't get
too much runoff but I'll still move the
trays and drain them or actually have
like some suction uh that I'll just get
all the water up with like a shop back
so I don't have to move the plants
around
but
um I started at first I was only
watering maybe once a day and then as of
recently the plants started they started
and taking a lot more they start really
around like week three around week three
of veg they really start picking up the
consumption so from there ever since
then I've been doing two times a day I
do it right uh write a little bit after
lights on and then right at lights out
I've been running like that and so far
it's been good
uh the runoff I don't really get too
much runoff and when I come in there
sometimes I knew I've had to start
increasing the the amount of water I've
given them so far because sometimes I
come there and it'll it'll it'll be the
the cocoa will be a little bit more dry
than it was the day before and I'm like
hold on let me now I need to start
adding more because we're in that uh I'm
still in that stretching phase of flower
so I've been you know up in the water
but I still do two times a day common
question that you get from beginners a
lot is how much water do I add in and
you know the answer to that is just it
depends right there's so many variables
when it comes to it what size is the
plant if you're watering a small
seedling you're obviously going to give
it less water than you would a
full-blown plant that is in the
flowering stage for example so I always
get that question it's so hard to answer
it I usually have to find out more
information about how far along is the
plan how big is it what container size
is it in how moist is the medium to
begin like there's just so many factors
so it's so hard to to answer that
question yeah I I get asked that like
I've been asked that a few times we're
like how often should I water them like
I would like explain break everything
down to me I need all the information uh
how you know your light the light
intensity
um do you have any fans going are the
fans blowing directly at it like is it
drying up uh what's going on with what
is the live stage because you know me
starting off I got a Seedling I don't
want to just like just gouge it with
water I was like I don't need that much
that's just a waste I'm wasting my
nutrients at that point you know we got
to be you know save as much as we can so
it's like you don't you don't need all
that
um but like you said there is so many
factors that come into play and that's
where we you know just gotta relay that
information like so I can kind of help
you in because I can only see so much
from like a camera or just from the
message that you said like it's it's so
vague you know you got to break it down
we got to get it because I'm not there
so you have to really give me that
information so I could try to help you
because I'm still learning myself so one
thing that can really help is the
moisture meters I'm not sure if you used
one of those before but you can buy one
of those for like 10 bucks 15 bucks
those work pretty decent you get some
mixed results on them you do need to
calibrate them there's also the digital
moisture meters I know sustainable
Village makes a digital moisture meter
they're the company that makes blue mats
the automated drip system and so I
haven't used the digital one yet I've
actually been wanting to get my hands on
one I think they're around like 85 bucks
or something like that and they can
certainly be valuable if you're like if
you're unsure about how much moisture is
in the medium you can get one of those
and that way you can really dial in your
watering that way yeah I haven't I
haven't personally uh I was looking into
the moisture meters at first because I
was running to problems like this looks
like over watering or this looks like
underwater and I'm like I don't really
know where is that you know that meat I
need to be in that like the perfect
little area where is that at so I was
like I thought about buying a moisture
meter but then I kind of just like
figured it out but I do want one just
for the sake of having it it's kind of
cool so I could see like maybe what I
thought was enough it might not be
enough or maybe I thought was too much
might not be too much yeah it can
certainly be helpful on that Avenue
let's flip it up let's get into
environment now there are so many
different things that we could talk
about when it comes to environment
temperature let's start with that what
do you typically aim for in regards to
temperature yeah so for temperature
um
for dwc temperature is like a huge
factor that is one of the factors I
would say top three factor I put it at
number one but
um
temperature is definitely I keep it
round for for the entire room depending
like the actual room itself I aim for
around like Max 75 degrees but with uh
that's when I was running like soil or
if I was just running cocoa 75 but in
the 70s would be cool with me just
keeping it in 70s in general but because
of dwc I'm having to keep everything
down and at first I was originally you
know making sure my entire room was like
68 I was making sure it was at 68
sometimes 65 you know I was trying to
make the entire room cold that way my
plants roots that way I can keep them in
that Optimum range the temperature so
I'm not running into things like root
rot so but then since then I've actually
so I don't have to have the entire room
you know electric bill skyrocketing
because that AC unit is trying to keep
the whole room cool since then move the
AC unit because I have all dwc plants
inside of one tent and I've been able to
move that AC unit into that tent alone
and I keep the actual temperature around
like 65 to 68 pretty much inside that
tent and then how about humidity a lot
of people will track the relative
humidity and adjust that is there a
specific humidity that you aim for
um yes I do typically stay I kind of
throughout the entire process I guess
starting off I'm around like like for
seedlings well they're in the dome so
like a 90 plus but
throughout the rest of the grill I'm
aiming I'm just keeping that 50 I just
keep my dehumidifier set 50 sometimes if
it's a super humid day and I see like
the the water is building up or I'm
going to be gone and I want to extend
the life because I don't have uh the
dehumidifier draining outside I have a
draining against just to a bigger bucket
which I know it takes a couple days but
sometimes if I want it to last just a
little bit longer if I'm going to be
gone I'll crank it up to like 60 so it's
not fighting too hard to keep it at 50
percent but around 50 is where I stayed
throughout the entire grow okay yeah
General range specifically for beginners
now we could get into VPD Vapor
pressures episode which is the ideal
humidity to be at for what temperature
that you're at and that helps to ensure
that the stomata on the leaves are fully
open and then taking that CO2 release
that water vapor so on and so forth but
putting VPD to the side the general
range that is often recommended for
beginners is between 40 and 60 percent
relative humidity so you could certainly
stay within the that range and get to
harvest you know no problem and staying
under that sixty percent is generally
recommended in order to prevent things
like poultry mildew from forming for
example now air circulation is going to
be a big impact to that there are lots
of benefits to air circulation what do
you do for air circulation uh so for my
air circulation I'm running I actually
have a tower fan inside of one well on
one side that's in I'm running a tower
fan I actually want to get more tower
fans and just run solar tower fans
because I just like the at any stage
it's good you know it's still going to
be blowing an even amount of air
throughout the canopy uh but I do have
one tower fan and the rest is just like
I believe like six inch oscillating fans
I'm not sure the exact size but I have
oscillating fans and I'll have to prop
them as the plants grow sometimes I'll
have to like prop them up on something
or hang them from the ceiling but as of
right now that's like the only uh thing
I'm running for uh fans and osculating
and then well I have a air pulling out
from the AC Infinity I do have that
pulling air out but as far as fans goes
it's just a few oscillating fans and a
tower fan most recently I've been using
the AC Infinity clip-on fans I clip onto
the side of the grow 10 and oscillate
those things are pretty cool I want to
get I want to get one I want to get one
I saw it yeah because it makes it so you
can just ride onto a pole yep I actually
have four of them and uh you know the
way of positioning the fans in your
growth spaces something that not a lot
of people talk about and some people say
there is a right and a wrong way to do
it and I'm not here to say that this is
there is a right way and a wrong way to
do it but a common technique people will
do is they'll put like two two of those
clip-on fans towards the lower part of
their grow tent for example so it's
blowing underneath the canopy and then
on the other side of the grow tent up
more they'll have the fans blowing above
the canopy through the canopy so you
have this constant whirl around in the
actual grow tent or growth space now
some people will just they'll say oh you
can do that or you can just position
them anyway so air is just whipping
around in all different directions so a
couple different ways to go about it
some may say one way is better than the
other but both ways is is going to
actually move the air around so that it
the plant does have access to that CO2
which is needed for plant growth and
then yeah air exchange like you talked
about I'm using the AC Infinity one as
well where it's just it's so awesome
being able to be hooked up to a
controller and now it's actually on your
phone as well so you can actually
control the airflow on your phone with
the controller 69 they have a Bluetooth
Edition a Wi-Fi Edition which I just got
my hands on it makes things a lot easier
because right now I'm just running with
the remote but I definitely want to get
one where I'm able to control because I
like to do everything for my phone all
lights and everything are hooked up to
Smart plugs so I could just control it
from my phone so I was like I get
notifications if something's down if the
Wi-Fi goes out like I know like hey this
light isn't going to cut on I need to
manually go do it because maybe
something something just happened like
an outage happened in my area so I know
I need a prep for that so it kind of
gives me that listing to worry about
when I'm away and then I also have like
a camera hooked up so I can like kind of
watch just in case I'm like oh it looks
like there's a problem happening over
there yeah that helps I mean I remember
back in the day none of this stuff
existed I was like open up the tab and
you know disturbing that environment and
I live in a very dry climate so I'm like
opening up the tent humidity is escaping
you're seeing a drop in humidity and you
know closing it up and it's so much
easier to just be able to look at the
phone and see what the temperature and
humidity is there looking at the camera
and being able to see that the plants
are okay that the lights are on like
they should be so on and so forth so
yeah automation is just
I know there's some people against it I
was like I know some people prefer like
everything manual because like those
factors like power outages and stuff but
it's I guess it's just the generation
but it's just I like like I like to make
life easy I like to I like to enjoy
everything I'm very tech savvy I like to
use my phone I'm on it 24 7. so if I
could add one more thing to this to make
that just a little bit easier then I'm
cool with it I did I did use the for
timers at first I didn't know smart
plugs were a thing I just went and had
seen the ones where you uh it's like a
dial uh and you just you pull uh you
just pull the pins out whatever it's
pretty much just it's what you just plug
and salad and it just spins until it
gets to that dial and then it cuts off
so I did use that at first but I was
like I don't know I don't like it I was
like I prefer to like see the time and
know exactly which time it's going to
cut on yeah it's funny you mentioned
that those timers you know went from
that style to the digital style which I
still use and then a lot of people using
the smart plugs now they don't even use
timers anymore those digital timers that
are made specifically for you know
Hydroponics for example yeah I feel like
eventually well now they have I've seen
recently speaking of automation I've
seen uh hey Abby
um I'm not sure if you're familiar with
that but it's pretty much uh it's a dwc
system and it's pretty much a full setup
like tint a light is inside of it and
it's a machine it's like the size of
maybe like a two by two tent maybe
smaller than that but it's pretty much
just for one plant or you can probably
run smaller plants inside of it or they
may have different sizes but I've seen
one and it's it's fairly expensive it's
like a thousand bucks but
it's literally a whole automatic system
everything temperature controls it has
AC built in everything is just automatic
about it you can control everything you
can feed it from your phone you just put
like little food Tide Pods inside of it
and I was like all right that's like
another step like I was like I would try
it out if it was like reasonably priced
but I was like I'm not paying that much
just to you know put a thousand bucks
into one plan I was like I'm cool on
that like I don't need to go that far
into automation I'm not that lady I'm
not that lazy
you know there have been a handful of
those systems out there in the past
decade and uh all of them suck for for
uh medicinal plants I mean lettuce you
know or leafy greens sure but uh people
have been trying these systems he's been
spending the thousands of dollars and
realized hey it's better to just spend a
thousand dollars on a grow tank kit and
than it is to send on one automated box
which yeah it's supposed to control the
pH this is a Reservoir in there there's
Lighting in there but they're all just
terrible so yeah it is it it didn't even
look good I'm looking at it I get like a
little the person I've seen the video
from they like show inside of them
looking at like the aeration the bubble
output and I'm like is it most likely
going to run into root rot I was like
he's gonna run into real ride no it's
terrible I want to go back to lighting
issue you talked about have you ever had
like a power outage that you had to deal
with at all or no
um as as far as long term like for some
reason like you know there comes times
there's like maybe a week where it'll
happen like a couple times but it'll
like be quickly back on there was one
time where my lights were out for maybe
a two three hours and at that point
after like usually when they go out
there out for a couple minutes and they
may just pop right back up within like
five minutes but when they were out for
like after like 30 minutes of being out
I'm sitting there like okay anytime now
an hour I'm just like I don't see it
storming outside why is the power out
and I'm just I was sitting there like
super nervous I was like oh no like this
is like what do I do like I don't have a
generator I don't have any sort to get
my my lights back on and then with dwc
if I have like soil plants they they can
make it a couple of days with no light
and bounce back fine but like if power
out being a dwc like their oxygen is
gone I'm like what do I do do I just
like sit there grab the air stones and
start blowing in my mouth I was like I
don't know what to do I was just sitting
there like scared I was like I don't
know where to go about this uh but after
like three hours they cut back on uh I
didn't actually run into root rot that
run I was surprised I was thinking I was
like oh no it's the plants are going to
be done but they didn't even they
weren't even bothered they they just
kept growing they kept doing their thing
once the lights go as soon as I heard
like the beep I had uh I think my
dehumidifier the AC unit it beeps every
time it comes on I heard the beep and I
was like yes I just like screamed I was
like so excited I was like power is back
on and I was like I'm so good but since
then I was like when I move into like a
more permanent setup I was like I'm
gonna like invest in something like a
generator or something where I could
temporarily or you know just get my
power back and running while the outages
uh taking place it can be worried so I
have a lot of people reaching out to me
talking about how their power went out
and now the lights came back on and they
were off for a certain number of hours
and they're really worried about well we
know that light leaks and light
interruptions cause plants to go
hermaphrodite right so that's the main
concern for a lot of these people so
like the question is if your lights are
out for 30 minutes what do you do like
is that enough of a light interruption
in order to cause your plant to harm or
not there's some people who their lights
will be out for three four hours
and then they'll go right back on and
their lights will be on for three hours
and then they'll be off for the 12 hours
and things just get all out of whack
General recommendation that I've been
told and what I've been doing whenever
I've encountered a power outage is if if
the lights are off for 30 minutes or
longer you may want to consider keeping
the lights off as if you were starting
your dark period
so for example if your lights are off
for five hours you have a power outage
for five hours you may just want to and
then your power comes back on you may
just want to keep the lights off for
another seven hours and then you've
completed your 12 hour dark cycle now
they're going back onto a 12 hour light
cycle and then hopefully your plants
aren't stressed out but there's really
no firm technique that's gonna say for
sure no your plants aren't going to harm
out
it really becomes a tricky situation
yeah like what that said with the outage
that's that's like one thing that kind
of like taught me the lessons like you
know what dwc it may not be the best
thing in the world like because that's
Alice preaching I was like I love dwc
but that made me realize I was like you
know what it is a very you know it need
everything about it it needs it needs
electricity and it needs it doesn't it
can't you know go through it can't
withstand an outage so I was like you
know what I kind of like sort of dialed
back on I was like you know I'll do
fewer plants fewer bigger plants and
then everything else I'm just gonna do
cocoa that way I have that buffer if
something like that happen and I don't
have to solely rely on electricity yeah
yeah that's definitely a good way to go
about it so we did talk about a ton of
problems that you can come across in
your grow and solutions to those
problems coming up towards the end of
the episode here one of the questions
that I could ask is getting advice for
new Growers you know you've been growing
for a couple years now you've gone
through kind of the beginner stages of
it some may say you're still kind of in
the beginning stages but what general
advice you have for folks that are new
to gardening that main thing is going to
be not uh not being that critical in
yourself and really just sitting there
and trying to learn you know
you don't have to reach out to someone
and learn from them you could learn from
you could learn through just research
reading a book you know yourself you
have a book you could you know keep it
simple really just keep everything as
simple as possible and you don't have to
know everything that's like the biggest
concern is like as a new grower I feel
like I've reached a point where I was
like you know what it was like a big
drastic change I was like growing I felt
I felt new I felt like I didn't know
anything and then I really just started
focusing on like not trying to know
everything not know the terminology and
just like sitting there like uh it's
strained I don't have to say cultivar I
don't have to like you know just there's
so much information out there I just
need to know what I needed to know and I
feel like that's where it comes into
play just know you the core stuff no if
you can make it from seed to harvest
you're good you know you can it may be a
bad Harvest you may not produce the best
you may have harvested two or you may
have ran into several issues but really
just learning and being able to correct
those issues the next time just trying
to constantly improve and fix those
things and pick those little tweaks here
and there rather than
just stressing yourself out about not
knowing everything like it just
continuously keep it simple just make it
simple on yourself and you're going to
save yourself a huge headache you're not
gonna you're you can't compare yourself
to someone uh some people I don't have
much Growing Experience but I'll have
people like yeah I'm trying to grow like
you how did you do that I'm like
honestly
go watch a couple videos ago you'll see
I was just where you were at I'm telling
you with time you're gonna get so much
better and so will I alright well said
yeah good stuff there
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upon in the future
um yes you can find me here on YouTube
um for or for viewers not on YouTube uh
you can also follow me on YouTube at
doosa farms and you can find me on
Instagram at doosofarms
d-u-s-a-f-a-r-m-s
um
short for Medusa but doosa farms uh as
far as what's upcoming
um it's really just folk I'm gonna do
more lives of course more growing stuff
I'm I'm really starting to get into that
I feel like I've hit that point where I
could
teach some stuff because I'm teaching
people privately so I feel like I
reached a point where I can kind of
publicly say some things that I feel
like I know so I'm I'm getting to that
point where I'm like I'm starting to put
some information out that I've come
across or something that's helped me at
first I try to avoid doing that because
I didn't want somebody like hey he
taught me this and it didn't work but
now I feel like I reached a point where
I've helped enough people in private
that I could publicly say it so I don't
have to have too many people hit me up
privately it's already public
information out there so a lot of that
stuff's coming
um it's just honestly it's going to be
huge I'm going to be getting a full room
growth set up once I once I move into a
house I'm just gonna deck out a full
room similar to somebody like turkey
high so stay tuned today I'm going
through the entire building process
maybe some people here and there can
give me some pointers and help me in the
right direction show me what I should do
and what I shouldn't so just follow
along the journey and see how it goes or
grows whatever you want to say sweet
I'll definitely have a link to your
YouTube channel down in the YouTube
description section below and then if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
just search for them you'll find them if
you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up also subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already every single
weekend I'm releasing one of these new
Garden Talk podcast episodes and I would
love for you to tune in to future
episodes do so thank you so much for
coming on today I really like these
beginner gardening conversations it
brings me back and helps me think about
the basics again so thanks for your time
today thanks for talking about your
experience and your knowledge so far and
hope you enjoy the rest of your day all
right you too take care appreciate for
having me on peace out everyone catch
you in the next episode