coming up on garden talk a mandating
with like the natural fertilizer so i
add a lot of the guano the bone meal
blood meal and i found that just really
making my own mix turned out to be the
perfect solution and really just helped
to cut a lot of cost it just goes to
show that by having the pearlite and
creating those little pockets it really
does help you know the root system the
plant and the overall health term you
want something that runs cool something
that's not too heavy something that does
not run too hot and is full spectrum and
has the external dimmer those are the
main things that i look for when buying
a light it's not necessarily all about
like spending loads of money to achieve
a perfect setup plans can't tell if
you're using like a super expensive
piece of equipment over it or if you're
using like a three by two frame that you
built and made your own scrog net out of
it just knows it's being trained
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 62. in this
episode i interview matt from the icann
thc channel he's been gardening for 12
years and many of you know him from his
channel and podcast here on youtube in
this episode he talks about gardening on
a budget with limited resources thanks
to all of you support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible big thanks to our sponsor
gorilla grow 10. check out their carbon
filters to help get clean
contaminate-free air the filters remove
odor pathogens disease-causing spores
contaminants dust and bacteria from the
air they use a two inch thick layer of
coconut carbon which is the most
eco-friendly and sustainable source of
carbon it has a significantly higher
density of micro pores compared to other
forms of activated carbon this results
in it being 50 more effective at
absorbing odors and contaminants go to
the website grow strong industries dot
com and use discount code mr grow it for
15 off ac infinity is a sponsor of the
podcast coupon code mr growit will get
you a discount on their products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infinity down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with matt
from the i can thc channel how you doing
today man i'm good i'm good i'm finally
happy to be on here with you you know
we've been talking about it for quite
some time now i'm just happy to be able
to finally jump out and chill out with
you chat and see what's going on man
thank you for having me it's an absolute
pleasure
yeah no problem i'm familiar with the
youtube channel you're a fellow content
creator busting out growth videos and
you have a podcast now and just a whole
bunch of good content so i'm glad we're
linking up today and we're able to uh
to merge our minds a little bit and have
a grow conversation you know
yeah most definitely i mean you've
honestly been an inspiration for me and
like a lot of my girls so mad respect to
you shout out to you um the whole from
the stash podcast all the fam pigeons
and rob man all of you guys are awesome
so mad love mad respect to you guys dude
that's so cool to hear that's awesome
for sure for those listening in matt's
been in a situation similar to a lot of
you listening to this podcast today uh
really having to keep things budget
friendly
he lived in an area where it's difficult
for him to get grow equipment both in
person and even shipped to him so he
learned to do a lot of stuff on the
budget and found ways to take an
alternative approach when needed so
that's really what i want to get into
today in this talk but first can we do
an introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening
for sure for sure um well i got the
channel but i actually started gardening
long before the channel was created so
my first grow was like a medicinal grow
back in like 2010 2011 it was out in the
uk in southampton you know so shout out
to the uk mad love um it was actually
with one of the hps bugs as well so it
was like a little closet grow
hps bulb really hot um a lot of mistakes
were made i got some nice um magic beans
and ran those and it actually turned out
to be a male variety
so and it was a bit in vain but the
lessons learnt were fantastic um other
than that i grow a lot of other plants
in my garden as well so i like like
house plants such as snake plants spider
plants aloes uh even the mother of
thousands that propagates like crazy
i also like like thyme basil mint
oregano those sort of stuff because i
really like to just throw that in there
in my cooking and use that try to be
very self-sufficient so um gardening's
just always been something that i lean
to i mean my mom got me into it when i
was really really you're small so shout
out to her as well you know fully in the
foundation gotta give credit where
credit is due right
awesome yes 100 dude
so what do you think you're what would
you say your overall style of gardening
is like today are you are you mostly
indoors outdoors you grow in soil cocoa
hydroponics do you use organic inputs
synthetic inputs what's your style
um well mainly a lot of soil i've grown
outdoor and i've grown indoor my
preference is indoor just because you
can really control the environment you
can control what goes in there and you
can control the light the humidity the
moisture you can control all that good
stuff so that's sort of like my
preference i did grow outdoors i ran
into some challenges with that uh such
as the past the uh
nature's automatic clock you know from
12 to 12 that sort of stuff it was
always on that cycle for me so that was
a bit difficult in itself um i've grown
indoors now and like i said i use a lot
of soil that's my preferred style of
growing i will sort of amend it with
like natural amendments the bat guano a
lot of organic stuff i did start off
with like the bottle nutrients um but i
sort of veered away from that as i got
more like knowledge behind me
so
that we can get into that a bit more
later on but for now i pretty much say
that my main style of gardening is like
an organic style which basically
moves around soil it centers around the
soil i like to use potting mix and
natural amendments i'm not big on the
hydrophonics simply because i haven't
tried it yet
i have tried pure peat moss mixtures but
that turned out to be very acidic and
very hard to like work with so i found
the easiest way and like i said keeping
it on a budget turned out to be soil so
it always just turned back to soil for
me and that was just the easiest way to
to move on a budget you know
i was going to ask you you know first
question what do you use for medium and
containers and that's soil are you like
using the native soil out of your
backyard and like rehabbing it to
you know inoculate with microbes aerate
so on and so forth making it into usable
for
medicinal plants or are you actually you
know is available locally to where you
can buy soil either by the bag or by the
yard or by whatever fantastic question
well i've actually used like a lot of
soil from the backyard and just sort of
like revamped it so i'll try to like i
said get a lot of the bat guano because
you can get that locally um in the
caribbean that's where i'm from actually
try that in tobago right now i'm in
colorado so back in trinidad and tobago
you did get like a lot of um grow
supplies the nutrients and that sort of
stuff but because it was imported there
was a slight like increase in the price
on those sort of stuff especially if you
want to bring it in yourself you got to
pay customs and taxes and stuff so i
found that um just like trying to
circumvent that using the easily
available organic fertilizers are a
great way to just give the plant what it
needs right so i found myself getting
into that a lot um i don't know if that
actually answers your question but i did
find myself getting into that a lot and
did you have to add in any microbes like
a lot of people don't inoculate with
microbes did you were able to purchase
microbes locally at all it was just not
available for you
um it was not really available uh the
the typical ones that i would get would
be like even just the mycorrhizae
sometimes you get that a lot
but that's more like fungi and bacteria
and stuff so it really was necessarily
that available um back then but now that
i'm in colorado i think it'll be easier
to get it but that said uh when i was
growing back in the caribbean a lot of
the fox farm soils and stuff you were
able to get that so i did try to run
with those a bit
and my experience with those was sort of
hit and miss
but i did have great results with like
the regular pro pro-mix and again i go
back to amending with like the natural
fertilizer so i add a lot of the guano
the bone meal blood meal a lot of that
sort of stuff and i found that just
really making my own mix turned out to
be the perfect solution and really just
helped to cut a lot of cost because you
can get a lot of these natural
fertilizers for pretty cheap and you can
get them at a lot of grow shops you know
as opposed to trying to buy and bring in
the brand name stuff so that's just
something that i've learned um but to
answer your question in terms of the
inoculation of microbes not all that
much to be honest with you yeah you're
probably getting a lot of the microbes
from the amendments anyways all natural
balances
you know a lot of that comes comes with
it so
that can definitely help with the
breakdown process and such now what
about containers so you mentioned you're
using soil with the amendments but what
do you use for containers
um i've tried a lot of containers that's
a great question chris um i've had a lot
of containers so like i found that
keeping it simple often works best so
like the fabric ones those are great
they're you know pretty inexpensive
they're reusable but i found that when
using the fabric ones it can be really
difficult to transplant out of those
especially if you got a big plant and
the roots like really busting through
that fabric um you can cause a lot of
damage to the roots and i've actually
shot the plant already so i if i'm using
the fabrics i tend to try to use them as
the final part right so when it comes
down to what pots i actually use i use a
mixture i start off with the plastic
parts i find that those are very easy to
you know transplant out of they're
durable um and they hold the water very
well you know if i'm using a smaller
fabric pot i find that water runs out of
it a lot and that can be stressful you
know just
i've actually seen one of your videos
where you talk about the dumping water
over top method when you're ordering
your plants i do that a lot so i've got
a really heavy hand and just having
water everywhere in the grow room isn't
always ideal so i like the fa the pla
the plastic parts to start off and as we
go into like the flowering stage then i
can pop them into some of the fabrics
and then i'll harvest from there soon
after but right now i'm actually just
using some of those like super cheap um
like almost like a plastic film so it's
like 90 cents i think i paid for one of
them and it's just like a sort of
plastic film with a few holes and i
added a few extra holes just to give it
that extra aeration and stuff but um
that's that's really what i grow and i
try to keep it simple i try to figure
out what works best for me because a lot
of people depending on their environment
where they're growing uh different parts
will dry out faster depending on your
environment right so like the fabric
ones will dry out a lot faster in
certain climates as opposed to the
plastic ones so you really got to find
what works for you and what works for me
was the plastic and then transplanting
into the fabric as they get
older or the transplant into flower that
that sort of stage so um that works best
for me but i've seen a lot of people in
the caribbean where i'm from growing
like in um buckets they use like very
creative stuff you know um wheelbarrows
they're a lot of creative stuff because
it's not always ideal for them to go out
and you know spend money on the plastic
parts and even those plastic parts can
be pretty expensive you know back in the
caribbean so um a lot of ingenious ideas
have been seen on um on my facebook
group i've got a facebook group where i
post a lot of uh stuff that i can't thc
channel so i've seen a lot of girls out
there just being so creative and you
know mad love to him but for me i like
the plastic parts when i start off and
then go on to the fabric ones
i was gonna say there are a lot of
creative ways out there and a lot of
people are using the five gallon buckets
that they get from like lowe's or home
depot those are pretty cheap i think
like two three bucks or something like
that for those containers i've seen
people use like peanut butter jars and
like the like large tubs of peanut
butter and like turning that into grill
pots or just like large plastic
containers you know from food and stuff
like that so like there are ways to go
about it uh one thing is just going to
be aware of is that you don't want light
to be able to penetrate through it that
could potentially lead to algae growth
of course if you see an algae growth
then that's one of the signs of
over watering you know too much water in
the medium as well but algae does grow
off
the light there and then as far as one
other thing i want to mention is those
air pots
i don't know how much they cost but like
i'm thinking if you're using like your
native soil which can be somewhat
compact
um not a lot of people add like perlite
a lava rock or something like that to
add in aeration because these plants
don't grow real well in a compact medium
at least the medicinal varieties that
were that we're referring to so maybe
having those air pots would probably be
beneficial to make sure that there is
air getting to the root zone um you know
and so it's not choking up the roots and
stuff like that so i forgot to mention
that one 100 i would agree with you on
that and just to add to that point
actually when i'm actually using native
soil outdoors i would actually add a
hefty amount of perlite because that
perlite sort of like goes to your point
it helps to um add oxygen to the roots
it has to break up that really thick
soil because i've actually grown in like
some native soil on its own nothing
added it was literally just like dirt
and when it got wet it became like mud
so the roots had a really tough time
penetrating through that mud and really
establishing themselves so it just goes
to show that by having the perlite and
creating those little pockets it really
does help you know the root system the
plant and the overall health you know so
i second that honestly yeah and then you
mentioned the amendments as well you
touched upon them but i'd like to get
just a little bit deeper into them so
for the vegetation stage what are you
using for amendments and like when are
you top dressing if you maybe let us
know what ratios you're using if you
know of and then also for flowering same
deal okay so recently i've got into like
using the gaia green amendments uh when
it comes to top dressing so initially
i'll use my um i'll just go for a very
basic potting mix since i'm up here in
colorado i've just gone to walmart and
got like a cheap three dollar bag of
potting mix and i'll try to amend that
myself as best as i could with like um
bad guano
bone meal blood meal worm castings um
a few other things i'm just sort of
missing right now but that will usually
help me out for the first few weeks of
the plant's life you know sometimes i
might add some kelp in there as well and
that really does help a lot but that
helps me out for the first few weeks of
the plant's life when it comes down to
um the flowering stage when it starts to
need a lot of the
p and k ratios you know the phosphorus
and the um
potassium and that sort of stuff then i
sort of need a bit more nutrients the
plant starts out so give show me science
that it's really hungry and it needs
some more food so at that point then
i'll start to like um top dress with the
guy green but because uh the guy green
takes a little while for it to actually
work into the soil for it to break down
for the plant to absorb it what i'll
start to do is two weeks or so before i
actually flip the flower i will top
dress because i know that i'm going to
flip the flower within the next two
weeks so i'll give the chance the plant
a chance to break down everything absorb
it through the roots and that way you
know i'm sort of ahead of the game
because it's always harder to recover
from a deficiency than to deal with that
up front you know so that's just
something that i've learned always
always harder to like recover than to
deal with it up front
um but when it comes to like just the
overall
my overall feeding stage cycle and stuff
what i would say is that
the natural side of things has worked
fantastic for me i haven't really had
any signs of over feeding or any signs
of burning
if there are issues with slight
deficiencies sometimes i may just use
like
a little nutrient booster and maybe
liquid nutrients like there's liquid
organic nutrients such as kelp like i
mentioned before
that's a fantastic thing that i use i
love it i use it all the time i'll mix
that up and i will just you know add it
to my water and water it in so that sort
of helps the microbes it doesn't um
attack the microbes or anything but i
found that it has great results for me
okay so there's your approach with soil
the containers nutrients throughout the
life cycle one thing i did want to
mention is that you know a lot of people
seem to be taking the natural farming
approach and that is the way you can
save money you know learning and
learning k f jadam which we're not going
to get into on this episode but there
have been uh like two or three episodes
in the past here on garden talk with uh
with some people that have a lot of good
knowledge in jadam and knf in particular
and it's easy to save money that way you
know what i mean because you're actually
going out into the woods
and uh getting your own indigenous
microorganisms for example uh in your
own you're creating your own fermented
plant juice and your own fermented fruit
juice as well so there's like so many
different things you can do
and those ways you can actually save
money because you can use things that
you probably have laying around that you
could you don't have to go and spend
money on so 100 and then there's also
composting right i mean that's a whole
other avenue we could talk about is
people who are composting their waste
and turning that into
things that they can put that they can
toss dress into their medium and have
usable fertilizer through compost right
and of course the
microorganisms the beneficials so i
don't know if you compost at all
or not yet
um
i've composted like a few times but like
in my experience it just becomes so
smelly and
it can like
just really get to you and like
especially my small small crib like the
grow room is pretty close to like where
my studio was um so just to have to like
inhale that all the time was a bit rough
um but that said it was a fantastic way
to you know inoculate the microbes just
to get the microbes going in the soil
just to feed that plant some organic
stuff because like you said a lot of
stuff that you're going to throw away
anyway you can use that stuff to feed
your plant once you understand the npk
values and npk ratios what the plant
needs and when it needs it you can like
really dial in on your feeding schedule
what you're feeding the plant you
realize like okay i don't actually need
all these
fancy bottles of
nutrients i don't need 37 bottles of
nutrients to feed my plant
in reality during the flower the veg
stage they like a lot of nitrogen they
like a lot of micronutrients as well you
know the calcium magnesium that sort of
stuff when you go on to flour you want
to give them a lot more of the night the
potassium the phosphorus that sort of
stuff once you get an understanding of
that and where you can derive those
natural substances from you can feed it
to your plant through the soil like it
may take a longer time to break down
depending on how you feed it that's why
composting is so important even like
compost teas are a great way to get it
to the plant quickly i've brewed a lot
of compost teas and it's like a
fantastic pick-me-up for the plant i use
it quite often but again the smell is
horrific sometimes so um it all really
depends on when you want to do it and
how you decide to do it you know
that's what i would say it all depends
on how and when you do it yeah i
currently have a verma compost bin so
i've got the worms in there i have
european night crawlers and red wigglers
in there
and uh it's about seven months in
so um still haven't actually taken any
out and tried to top dress plants yet
still kind of feel like i'm seeing some
breakdown that needs to happen now it
was just winter time so it slows down
all the activity slows down the
breakdown slows down and all that stuff
but for in my experience
it doesn't really get smelly unless you
have that imbalance of carbon to
nitrogen
or if it's like too wet in there it can
attract mites and you have no population
of mites which i went through
and so i i think it's like a balancing
game i'm still trying to figure it out
i could still consider myself a beginner
at this point when it comes to
vermicomposting but it's fun it's fun to
learn and and just knowing that hey
maybe another six months down the road
i'll be able to take compost from there
top dress my plants and i won't even
defeat any nutrients at all you know and
i mean this is all waste that i've
compost you know turned into compost
through that there's also bokashi
composting which i'm just learning about
now
which seems to be
a little bit better
in various ways
and i won't get into that because i'm
still learning but there's a book called
bokashi composting and that's what i'm
reading right now to learn
and you can use like additional scraps
that you can't put in your traditional
compost pile vermicompost so i'm going
to start a bokashi bin soon
do some bokashi composting and uh no
just hope for the best try it out should
be fun
that's awesome dude um i think what you
said actually about the humidity as well
is a completely
that's an awesome point dude because
back in trinidad and tobago the humidity
was unreal it was so humid so that was a
big part of like causing a lot of
the imbalance that you referred to you
know so it was very difficult and i
guess that's one of the uphill
challenges that i faced um so great
point great point chris let's get deeper
into environment a little bit you know
let's start with lighting first and then
we'll get into like temperature and
humidity and co2 all that stuff so
lighting
how do you suggest going about lighting
when you're on a budget
um when you're on a budget lighting can
be a bit tricky especially for if you're
going on indoors because um a lot of
growers want the best lights and lights
can be pretty expensive but the truth is
you don't always need the best lights
brand name lights there are a few things
actually that you may want to look for
when you're buying a light like the
spectrum
um because you want to probably stay
away from some of the older tech
depending on your grow setup it can get
a little bit hotter on the hids leds
have turned out to be you know awesome
lights nowadays so i would highly
recommend the leds so there are a lot of
things that you can zone in when you
look for but mainly i would suggest that
growers look for the full spectrum
lights uh stay away from the older
attacks such as the blur pro lights
those lights are they're okay but you
know we we've kind of gone past that now
um so i really recommend the full
spectrum i recommend one with an
external dimmer that really does help
you when you're like just want to
increase and decrease the brightness
one which can be adjusted as well so
those are the main characteristics that
you look for and a lot of the flight
companies offer those characteristics
and the great thing is that a lot of the
light companies also offer like budget
friendly lights so they'll have the
the cheapest version or the most cost
effective version for the um beginner
grower and a lot of those will you know
have those bases covered so if you were
to get one of those you can always get
another one later on you can manipulate
the lights you can use the light bleed
to your um your benefit
rather than having one huge light so
when it comes to that i would suggest
that um those are the main things to
look for you want to look for full
spectrum you want something that runs
cool something that's not too heavy
something that does not run too hot and
something that is full spectrum and has
the external dimmer those are the main
things that i look for when buying a
light
and again different lights for different
stages of plant growth right so if you
have a seedling or you have a young
plant and veg or maybe even a cloning
station you don't want to have a huge
light let let's say a mars hydro fc 6500
which is what i have downstairs that
will that definitely fry your stuff
right um so a smaller one is
will will work great so different light
for different plant stages of growth
depending on your setup i know some
folks who being on a budget they only
can get one light and they might choose
that mars light uh you know being able
to dip it down like you said i think is
key
you know you might be wasting light for
a period of time while the plants are
seedlings but i i think they can grow
into it but some of the man some of
these
prices of lights are insane now there
are a lot more budget-friendly options
you know there's lots of people out
there that are saying that the prices
are going to come down over the years
you know as is more competition
as production gets cheaper
prices should come down over the years
they have been for the past five plus
years
they have been coming down more and more
and more but yeah that initial
investment can certainly be painful
there are some blurple lights out there
from my experience that do put out
enough photons for
plant growth and actually put out
equivalent to some of these top lights
out there
but like you mentioned their older
technology the spectrum they've got the
heavy on the blue and the red so it
looks purple
and some people say that the morphology
of the plant is impacted from that
also with the active cooling versus
passive right with the active cooling
you have the fans on there it's using up
more wattage that's a failure point you
know if your fan breaks on it that you
know do the cooling's
screwed on that so you might want to
consider a passive cooling light for
example
but yeah there is a lot to talk about
when it comes to lighting and what to
look for
i think it really comes down to getting
the right amount of light because
these medicinal plants in particular
they're heavy on the lake they can take
a lot of light is what i'm trying to say
and so some of these grow lights you see
on amazon and stuff like maybe some
small bulb maybe they're 20 30 40 bucks
it's not going to be enough really to
grow anything worthwhile in my opinion
it just doesn't put out the photons
needed for good growth so
something to be careful of another topic
there that
there has been multiple people on that
podcast that has talked about
there's one in particular it says what
to look for in a grow light
search that on youtube
and then also i'll grow like buyers
guide 2021 with chilled led that was a
great episode that uh that'll help those
folks that are looking to buy a girl
like kind of what to look for because
there is there's so many different
things that you can freaking look at on
these grow lights and it gets
overwhelming because there's so much to
learn and you don't know what to focus
on and and so on and so forth so
now how about uh environment you said
it's difficult for humidity i think you
had mentioned offline that it's
difficult for temperature as well how do
you control like temperature and
humidity and what do you typically aim
for on those things
okay uh well those two things were
really difficult to manage um as a
caribbean girl growing in the caribbean
it was really difficult to manage those
things because it's extremely hot and
it's extremely humid so especially if
you're growing indoors um in a grow tent
you'll definitely need a carbon filter
and an exhaust fan that helps to manage
uh the air circulation inside of the
grow tent i actually had to add some
standing oscillating fans just to help
with that um
air air circulation and air movement in
there as well but
sometimes that just blows around hot air
right so thankfully i had an ac unit
installed in the uh in the bedroom i had
to run that 24 7. just to counteract the
lights um the the heat coming off of the
lights the the heat from the environment
in general um so i ran that 24 7. my
bill was
amazingly
high
and aside from that actually i had to
run a dehumidifier so i had one of those
big dehumidifiers like um what mr
canucks grows and i hooked that up to a
drain hose and had that draining
directly outside so that actually helped
me to get my humidity down to around the
50s the 40s the 50s especially during
flower that was the sort of range that i
would look for just to avoid any butt
rot i tried not to go too much lower
than that
because i didn't want to run into any
issues but that said um when you're
using a dehumidifier and an ac unit in
your main grow room um
at the same time you kind of run into
issues if you're trying to clone or if
you're trying to run seedlings right
because that's sort of the other end of
the spectrum as to what seedlings like
seedlings like more humidity seedlings
like more moisture so what i did is i
found myself having to get a mini
humidifier and i have to put that into a
separate little seedling tent so it was
really difficult just sort of like
dialing in um all the the temperature
the humidity and all those sort of
environmental factors just because of
where i was living and a lot of growers
probably find themselves in that same
sort of predicament but once you get
like the right pieces of equipment you
can really help to counteract and set
that off so in terms of humidity when i
was in flower um sorry when i was in
seedling stage or veg i would aim for
like um 75 percent all the way down to
maybe 65 maybe 60. if i was in veg then
maybe 60 to 50
and flower i would probably try to go
down to 50 to 40. so somewhere around
there um and i did a lot of my
measurements of temperatures in degrees
celsius that's just because of where i'm
from but typically the environment the
temperature outside will be about 35
degrees
so it can get pretty warm in indoors it
can get pretty warm as well but i would
aim for like around the 26 degrees 23
degrees um sort of range that didn't
always happen but that's what i would
typically aim for and if current were to
go or electricity were to go um trouble
man trouble honestly
so yeah that's that's pretty that that's
the difficulty of you know growing out
in the caribbean trying to get
everything set up in a for a home grower
anyway so yeah just about every area it
can be difficult to control temperature
and humidity no what about co2 were you
doing anything for that at all or just
doing the normal co2 levels
normal co2 levels i didn't uh supplement
any co2 like there were so many pieces
of equipment already in my setup that um
just managing another one just seemed
like a daunting task you know so i had
like like i said a humidifier a
dehumidifier an ac unit grow light grow
tank fans um the works it was really
just i just didn't think that adding co2
would have done too much more for me at
that point you know so i didn't get into
that too much honestly how about water
what are you using what were you using
for water when you were out there
boy i mean how was the local tap water
did you have to get filtered were you
catching rain water what were you doing
for that
great question actually
um rainwater actually worked great
surprisingly that natural rainwater out
there worked fantastic so i used that
quite often but for those times that i
couldn't get a lot of water or couldn't
get enough i would typically just fill
it up from my tap i ph um in the
early stages so i know what the ph was
coming out of my tap and i just
occasionally randomly test it just to
make sure that it's all at that level
and once it's at that level and i
realized that okay the ph doesn't
actually move much i can just water uh
use the water from my tap but just to be
safe i'll actually use the water for my
tap fill up a few gallon buckets and i
would let's set that down for a few days
and let that uh stale that's what we
call it you know just let the water
stale and just let all those um heavy
metals or any chlorine and that sort of
stuff sort of neutralize and settle or
whatever and um that that's all i would
do so i wouldn't get too um complicated
with the watering process simply because
i knew that the ph of the water coming
out was acceptable for my plants were
you actually adjusting the ph like did
you have a ph beater you had access to a
ph meter or using those drops yeah
yeah
no i used a ph meter so i actually had
one of the cheap amazon ones um and i
started off with that and then i got
like a blue lab on just to like make
sure that like the cheap one wasn't
actually setting me up or anything
but it came out you know the similar
reading so i realized like okay this is
fine um it was usually around seven or
seven point something something around
there
and it was okay for me so i worked with
that and um yeah so how would you go
about determining when to water um
fantastic question because that's
something that stumps a lot of beginner
growers and i see you talk about that a
lot on your channel like over watering
is a huge problem among beginner growers
um yes guys plants need water but
water can also drown the root system so
for me i try not to over saturate i find
that less is more
if the plant is
lacking water it tends to dry up it
tends to get really soft to the touch
and you can tell so for me for watering
i like to um wait until the plant is
show signs of needing watering i could
tell i touched the leaves quite often to
tell like you know if the leaves are
full of uh if the leaves if the plant
has been recently watered then the
leaves tend to be really thick and
swollen like almost swollen but then if
they're not like you can like fold them
over they're very malleable
you can actually literally feel it so i
get like really in there with my plants
i touch them i feel them i lift up the
pot that's another way that you can tell
how heavy it is um how much water is in
there
so that's typically what i'll do and
when i actually go to watering i
try the easiest method possible i just
fill up a bucket and dump a bunch of
water over there and let that drink you
know i just let it settle down in there
um usually i don't see any runoff so i
try not to water with runoff because i
don't um one and here enough i just
don't want any runoff i don't want um
any over saturation at the bottom of the
plant pot either
i have seen instances where water can
just settle down there even though
you've got like holes and stuff in the
bottom of the pot so i try to avoid that
and for me less is more the plants can
always recover quickly from um or easier
rather from over underwatering as
opposed to over watering over watering
can be fatal you know if you underwater
your plants you water them and they'll
be okay if you over water them then
may the god be with you
now what about plant training techniques
are you doing any of those at all
throughout the grow
yeah i've actually done quite a few
plant training techniques my favorite
method is lst i like to couple that with
topping so once the plant reaches about
three or four nodes around there i will
do the first initial topping i don't get
too technical with it i really just get
in there pinch it off and watch it grow
i use these little lst clips which i
mentioned earlier for those who may not
be able to see it's simply just a little
clip which allows you to bend uh the
branch of your plant without breaking it
and in so doing you can expose lower bud
sites to light and so forth and that is
just a really great way to increase
flowers increase yield increase health
and potential the plant um you'll be
you'll be happy with it so for me lst is
a great way to you know manipulate the
plant and speaking of training lst is
also a great way that i found to get
into the bonsai experimenting side of
things you know
but that's probably a whole different
episode but um yeah lsd for me and
topping is the way to go okay and then
what about like are you doing any super
cropping at all or filming
or now yeah um i do fem um if i miss
when i top yeah i accidentally filmed
in terms of the super cropping i don't
go out of my way to do it often unless i
really have to so like if one of the
branches are reaching too close to the
light or um they're just getting too
tall during the pre-flower stretch then
yeah i'll try to super crop it and stuff
but it's not it's not like my favorite
approach to doing things i'm not
necessarily sure why because i've done
it i've done videos on it and i've had
great results with it but i'm just not
the hugest of fans i prefer the lst um
because to me i can achieve the same
results using lst and just like one or
two tops you know i try not to go too
crazy with the topping either
relating budget into this
i feel like there's a lot of people out
there that you know that are on a budget
they have smaller spaces
and that's why i want to talk about
training is because that does help keep
your plants confined to a small space if
that's what you're working with and so
i'm glad you're talking about lst and
some of the training techniques you do
because it can be helpful for those that
are in a smaller space for example
definitely
now are you doing anything to prevent
pests at all oh when it comes to pests
man i've i've ran into some serious
issues um growing out in the caribbean a
lot of a lot of pests out there um
i ran into like the aphids the spider
mites mites in general
a bunch of different stuff right so i
found that prevention is a lot better
than cure and having like an ipm routine
an integrated pest management routine is
really key so typically what i'll try to
do is on occasion i will just spray down
the the grow room firstly i'll keep it
extremely clean so i'll spray down the
grow room with like rubbing alcohol i'll
keep the tents clean and so forth after
every grow i'll reset
um aside from that on a weekly or
bi-weekly basis i will just do like a
little spray that i'll spray onto the
leaves and that will have like
peppermint um neem oil just some of the
very organic stuff but when i did run
into issues back in the caribbean i
don't recommend this to anyone but i did
have to use some of those uh more heavy
heavy duty style
insecticides on the plants just to get
rid of the infestations that i had and
it's not recommended but it did work but
you've got to be very very careful with
it man so definitely to avoid getting to
that point i'll recommend to anyone have
an integrated pass management system
which you use because that can save you
like a lot of headache in the long run
there's a lot of natural stuff that you
can use like i mentioned the peppermint
extract um even rosemary extract stuff
like that you can use that and mix it up
make your own mix and you should be good
to go apply it like
every two weeks or so just to avoid any
issues guys okay
and yeah that's that's what i would say
for my ipm
i know there's a lot of people that use
essential oils they have diffusers right
so they have essential oils going
throughout their house and stuff like
that you can actually use those oils
right as an ipm right you you would
dilute it you'd have like a lot of
people use dish soap as a surfactant but
water a little bit of dish soap use
about a teaspoon of dish soap and then
some drops of the essential oil and then
you mix that all up and then spray it on
your plants and that's an easy way a
cheap way if you haven't already have it
on hand it can be a cheap way to help
prevent pests from invading your grow
space it deters pests really it's uh
pests don't like to come close to your
plants on that avenue so yeah there's
something there dude
so taking a step back and and just
talking about like general advice like i
mentioned that there's a lot of people
out there that are on a budget you know
what i mean maybe they're either a
beginner just kind of getting into it or
they're somebody who has intermediate or
advanced knowledge and they already have
their
own setup going budget-friendly setup
jeffy general advice for those
at any level that are trying to do
things on a budget with limited
resources yeah i would definitely say um
keep it simple keep it very simple a lot
of times um guys remember that plants
have been growing for millenniums
without our intervention you know so
there are a lot of things that you can
do just to mimic the natural environment
that's not necessarily the most
expensive way of doing things so try to
keep things simple as possible you know
there are ways that you can uh use
natural substitutes instead of
the bottle stuff you can use um
even when it comes to like setting up a
grow tent you can build your own um
important grow tents to the caribbean is
super costly so i actually built my own
out of like pvc and roofing insulation
so like these are great ways to get a
budget stanley fed up um get things
running um on a budget and really just
maximize your plant's potential you know
so that's one suggestion that i would
have if you can like hack a lot of your
grows then definitely try to do it
you can lose like um the
cake cake covers as humidity domes you
may have one of those at home those
things really come in handy uh there are
a lot of things that you can just be
creative with you can create your own
plant labels from like yogurt containers
um there's a lot of stuff a lot of stuff
you can create your own pvc scrog using
pvc frames
and the screws and you know like uh
twine and wire you can there's a bunch
of stuff so guys really get creative
think outside of the box it's not
necessarily all about like spending
loads of money to achieve a perfect
setup simply because plants have been
doing this for such a long time without
our help so you just need to guide them
along the way and you don't need plants
can't tell if you're using like a super
expensive uh piece of equipment over it
or if you're using like a three by two
frame that you built and made your own
scrog net out of it just knows it's
being trained right so think of it that
way and um just try to think of the
budget friendly ways of doing things
because there are there really are guys
so i hope that that's that's helpful
well said yeah lots of good tips there
and i'm sure they can go to your youtube
channel and probably learn more ways to
keep it budget-friendly right can you
tell us how the listeners can find you
and also wrapping things up you know
what do you have upcoming in the future
100 dude um you guys can find a lot of
stuff on my channel the i can thc
channel um i'm on youtube i'm on
instagram i'm on facebook on facebook
we've got two private groups one is the
grower support network and one is the
gross helping girls group
together we're reaching about 20 000
members so check it out if you haven't
already it's pretty awesome um we went
out to canafest this weekend as well met
out with a lot of high
high again and a lot of other great
content creators and people in the
industry so definitely to check us out
guys we got a lot of stuff going on the
talking loud podcast we're hoping to
maybe have mr growiton esteemed guest
one day um you know and we actually
started a new series called the weed in
the news series so shout out to my wife
for that so um just mad love mad love to
everyone who's been showing love hope to
do a lot more for you guys and thank you
so much for having me on chris it's
fantastic to chat with you awesome
thanks for coming on definitely a fun
talk for sure
i'll definitely have a link to matt's
channel down in the youtube description
section below if you're tuning in on one
of the podcast platforms just search for
his name i can thc and his channel will
pop up lots of good quality content
there if you enjoyed this episode click
that thumbs up button lead feedback if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
such as apple podcasts or just comment
down below if you're on youtube
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already i release these podcast episodes
every single weekend and i'd love for
you to tune in to future episodes matt
once again thank you so much my pleasure
fam enjoy the rest of your day peace out
everyone you too thank you so much dude
peace fam
[Music]
you