coming up on garden talk because it's
much better for a plant to have slightly
less nutrients and work your way up
then to basically force your plant to a
nutrient lockout
through that osmotic process and then
have to reel it back
in there's these ec fans coming out
right now
which basically can operate with digital
controls
which can make them work a lot better
with controllers
and they operate on way less wattage
especially in the summer i'm always
adding co2 and people are like oh what
kind of crazy co2
operation you got going in there and i'm
like dude it's a four by four ten just
get an exhale bag or two
hang it up you'll be fine so if there
are any home growers out there who are
like you know what
i love doing this i want to do this for
a living i want to make a career out of
it
start reading manuals on a lot of the
technology watch a whole bunch of videos
and read some manuals on how they work
and you're you're basically halfway
there
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr grout
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 17.
in this episode i interview nate lipton
nate is the owner of growershouse.com
which is one of the largest grow
equipment suppliers in the u.s he is
also the host of canna cribs
a show where they tour various
cultivation facilities nate grows plants
in both a small greenhouse located in
his backyard
as well as an indoor grow tent he grows
a wide variety of plants
such as leafy greens melons broccoli
cauliflower medicinal herbs and so much
more
and we talk about a wide variety of
topics in this video
from nutrients to auto watering to
feeding charts to led grow light tests
and a new product that's coming out to
the market soon if you're tuned in on
youtube there are chapters set so you
can easily navigate to different topics
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already and click that thumbs up button
if you're listening to this podcast on
one of the podcast platforms please
leave a rating in review
and if you like these episodes and you
want to support the podcast even more
you can do that through patreon the link
to that is patreon.com
mr growit i'll leave a link to it down
in the description section below
before we get into the episode i'd like
to give a shout out to our sponsor for
this episode
dutch pro nutrients dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that was established
in amsterdam back in the early 90s
and as of a few years ago their products
are now available here in the usa
they have base nutrients additives ph
regulators
really anything needed for proper plant
nutrition dutch pro is now officially a
long-term sponsor of the podcast
so you'll be hearing their name a lot
i'll leave a link to their amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use code mr grow at 10 dp
for a discount on their products all
right now let's get into the episode
all right here we are nate from grower's
house how you doing today
dude i'm doing pretty well chris how are
you i'm doing good thanks for joining me
so we've known each other for a little
while now right we met in mjbizcon
oh is it 2017 or something like that
yeah about that i don't know when you go
to mjbizcon
for like so many years in a row they all
just kind of like
do this so and then
and then we linked up recently while you
were in vegas you were doing a whole
bunch of episodes
of uh your show which we'll talk about
and uh yeah man it's good to be able to
sit down and do this talk with you we'll
learn a little bit more about your
garden
and then we're gonna go over some
additional questions that we have
uh for you today so you ready to get
going yeah i'm ready to get going and
what the
what the viewers and listeners should
know is that chris and i had an amazing
chinese dinner in las vegas when we were
there and we had like three lobsters
and a table full of plates and it was it
was awesome night
it was incredible yeah for sure um so
for those that don't know who you are
can you just tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening
yeah so um you know a little bit about
myself right now i'm the co-ceo
of you know a group of companies uh the
largest one being growers house which is
an equipment supplier both to
hobbyist and commercial growers so like
16 000 products
you know everything you'd carry from
like irrigation to lighting to rolling
benches
hydroponic systems nutrients stuff like
that but then we also do have some
youtube channels
in a forum so we have growers network
and then
you know the youtube channel that we'll
chat about a little bit later which
people can check out
and um let's see other than that you
know how i got started i guess
is just being one of those curious kids
in college who starts growing
and uh next thing you know you're like
which way should i go in my life
you know and i was like maybe i'll you
know go into something related to
finance or something like that but
turns out my internship told me that
that was not the right choice and i
decided to go down this path
and i've been doing it for man it's like
13 14 years
at this point been in the hydro and like
growing industry
crazy i'm looking at your youtube
channel the growers host youtube channel
right now and i'll link this down in
the youtube description section below so
you guys can go to that
uh but if you sort by oldest to newest
you've got videos from like eight years
ago and you see
got a different hairstyle back then huh
yeah i had a different everything style
back then
especially shooting style but yeah we
have
those two channels um that probably will
be in the description below
but yeah don't look at that ones from
eight years ago definitely look at the
ones
in the last year that's probably better
those ones are antiquated you know
uh yeah but your it looks like your
channel is mostly about like equipment
different equipment that you have uh you
know i assume you sell this all at
grower's house
and um i know you talked you know you
said you wanted to talk about light
testing which we'll get to
towards the end of this episode yeah
sounds great
so let's talk about the garden so you
have
a garden right i don't know if you grow
do you grow indoors or outdoors and what
type of plants do you grow
yeah so right now people do ask me that
question a lot they're like so what
what are you doing you're growing like a
humongous outdoor plot or a greenhouse
or like a 50 000 square foot indoor and
i'm like well
you know not really i kind of have a
little set up at home
both kind of what i would consider a
really small greenhouse almost like a
hoop house
that's where maine like mainly like the
the veggies grow
that we play around me and my girlfriend
and then we do have the indoor grow tent
where i do a little like r d research
and development on like new products
coming out you know
we do resell other products but we do we
have a lot of our own product lines
you know we have our own grow tents you
know our own carbon filters
fans i've had our own line of leds so
when those products come in i like to
test them out and see if they they work
well
if they do awesome if they don't we make
some tweaks
um of course sometimes we find you know
a new partner to partner with
but that 4x4 for medicinal plants that's
inside
is um you know it's relatively basic
growth
and uh lately you know i tell people man
my day job is like it takes a lot of
time like i'm usually working six or
seven days a week
on the business the equipment side so
we're helping other people grow
and when you do that you realize you
barely have any time for yourself
to grow sometimes so what we try and do
is
you know uh maybe we'll start with the
veggie garden and then we can move to
the medicinal
garden but on the veggie garden it's
like you know four foot by eight foot
kind of hoop house thing
growing like some days you just wake up
on a saturday and you're like you know
what
i'm gonna go get some plants you hit up
the nursery in the morning grab a coffee
on your way out
like that is like those mornings that i
dream about
um then you just go pick some things so
most recently we got
some broccoli some cauliflower
you know my girlfriend was all about
getting the nerve garden kind of the
traditional thing so
like oregano rosemary thyme
things of that sort parsley and then we
tried some funkier things you know we
tried some yams
out there too and we did try some melons
which
it's funny i think we got these seeds
and we thought there are melons and they
turned out
to not be melons so you know that's
always
a fun surprise too but in arizona it's
tough like you basically grow
october through maybe may then in the
summer you just
shut shut the outdoor one down it gets
way too hot
uh on tucson it'll be 100 you can get up
to 110
and then that greenhouse would be like
150 probably you know it's
just everything would bake but when you
go into the medicinal garden
you know like i said working six or
seven days a week i really want to set
it up to just be
fully automated in a way so i like
what i like to say is you know i want
someone out there to write a book
please viewers write this book i would
read it if someone had it but
you know how to grow medicinal plants
for the busy person
and i will give you the outline of how
to do it so
let's see uh get a 4x4 ten
step one step two um i got an auto pot
foresight system so some of you guys
have probably heard about that
the good thing about it is you don't
have to plug it into anything it's
totally gravity fed
waters the plants as they need water
um so with four plants and a four by
four
um you know on the medicinal side you
could yield
you know with a good light probably end
up yielding um you know about a
pound and you know what i would say is
i could fill up that reservoir and about
two weeks later i can come back
and i would not have opened the tent for
two weeks
i just filled the reservoir with
nutrients which is about 12
gallons ish so it depends on how big
your plants are how fast they're feeding
um but then you just have a few timers
you know for your lights to go on and
off at the right times for your
ventilation to go
on and off at the right times and it's a
super set it and forget it system
uh i loved it and like in those buckets
you can choose what media you go with
and
what i'd probably recommend most is
filling the these these autopilot
buckets into about four gallons each
and they gravity kind of feed and then
they will
wick up through the media and i'd fill
it probably the first
inch or two with hydroton so clay
pebbles
and then on top of that you can kind of
add whatever media you want
um so i go with cocoa
straight cocoa and you know you can use
a lot of different cocoas ones i would
recommend is like
you know kanakoco is great even mother
earth cocoa is great you can go mother
earth straight cocoa with perlite
um you know some people even go into
soilless mixes like a pro mix that would
also work really well
but the cool thing is you can even put
like a
um like a nutrient dense soil
above those clay pebbles and it works
really well in that system and then you
can like rely a little bit less on
nutrients if you want
because you know with the cocoa you
definitely want to make sure the plants
have that full nutrition
in that reservoir but you could do like
an ocean forest
inside of that or a vermifire which are
two soils that
come packed with enough nutrients that
like three or four weeks in you know you
can be totally fine
and then add some light nutrients
thereafter
so pretty good system i like it quite a
bit that's kind of my r d system because
usually i'm testing out like
lighting is very common and then
different forms of environmental control
but i leave the
hydroponic system relatively the same
let's talk a little bit more about auto
watering so i have the auto pot system
too
i think i had like the six pot or
whatever
and uh i think i used like four and then
two of the plants ended up being male so
i went down to two
yeah but it's so easy to use like you
said is gravity fed
i was actually i did
perlite on the bottom two inches then i
used foxar motion for
soil like you had suggested or you
talked about
and then um i was actually top dressing
with organic nutrients and then my
reservoir was only plain water
so made things pretty simple now this
last run i did have
a little bit of issues because that top
layer does kind of dry out a little bit
and when you're using
organic nutrients in your top dressing
that top layer should be moist
so i need to figure out a way around
that whether it be a thicker mulch layer
on top of it or what but
yeah i mean using that auto watering
system was definitely made things a lot
easier
so you're putting nutrients within that
reservoir
right what brand of nutrients you're
using and are you using any sort of like
like pump or air stones or anything to
like mix it up
so the nutrients stay in solution they
don't just settle at the bottom or what
yeah yeah so let me actually right
before we jump into that i'm going to
give you a couple suggestions on your
side
so when you order auto pots you get this
um
what you've probably seen it's almost
like a mesh piece of fabric
that you put on the bottom that keeps
particulates from getting into
and clogging some of the so that some of
the drains
the copper disc yeah yeah exactly and
you know you can actually use things
like um
think of it this way water can permeate
basically any type of fabric
right you can make another layer of that
and what i would do is put the perlite
if you want to you can add another um
layer of like uh
even think of it like this way like a
cheesecloth right and then you
put maybe an inch or two of your ocean
forest on
dress some of the nutrients in your top
dressing
which you'd actually do a bottom
dressing add a layer of soil
dress a little bit more and that way as
it wicks up it'll pull the nutrients up
with it so it's not
missing them because it's not wicking at
the top
so that's one thing you could do in the
future that
might be helpful for that organic style
because that's that's really cool too if
people want to go organic but also have
a hydro system
that's a good way to do it like you were
just talking about um
yeah so yeah i tried to uh i tried to do
it that way and
so sort of create a super soil to where
it would be
more dense in nutrients so i added more
nutrients on top
of the fox farm and then more nutrients
in to try to get it to
last the entire grow now those auto pot
systems i'm not sure if they're
different pot sizes but they're about
four liters
i believe is the pasta just under four
liter pot size
and it just the i guess maybe i grew veg
the plants for too long or what but
within flower i started seeing those
deficiencies and
that's why i know i didn't have that
super soil i didn't have enough
nutrients in there
so maybe i didn't need to go heavier on
the nutrients in the future i think that
that would be a good idea for sure yeah
yeah potentially um you know that could
be a way to do it but i do think they're
four
four gallons not four liters is a
heads-up
oh yeah okay yeah sorry four gallons yes
they're and they do have like an xl one
which i forgot
i think it's like six gallons or
something but it's a little bit bigger
um but i haven't i haven't used those i
just kind of go with the standard
auto pots um but they're modular so it's
like look
you have one plant that's just
absolutely crushing it then you have
another male just take out the other pot
super easy you know but going into oh
yeah so like i guess
in the latest r d run that i was doing
um
nutrient-wise i was running this new
nutrient line
that were actually participating in
bringing to market which is called
ventana plant science
and um you know it's been about two
years in development
and you know most nutrients i will say
they're
um they're based on a lot of the same
kind of
macro and micronutrients that plants
need so macros
you know being your npk and then micros
being a lot of those
kind of smaller elements um that people
don't hear about as much
you know you're boron your zinc things
like that um
but the interesting thing about this one
is there's a
kind of like this proprietary amino acid
polymer
that we've been playing around with that
this formulation chemist built
which has been pretty awesome because it
was like supposed to be
like it should and could be patented but
as soon as you
patent kind of like a formula for a
nutrient
basically or anything like that you um
you release more information
about how it's made and like that is
something so that's why we call
basically a proprietary instead of
patented so you want to keep some of the
secret sauce you know like uh
kind of so that we can keep the secret
sauce to secret sauce but the cool thing
is we're gonna be
um you know selling it under the ventana
plant science name
and the the interesting thing is this
polymer this amino acid polymer it's
actually made from the shells
of mollusks so like sea creatures
yeah the shells of moles have this very
interesting amino acid and then they
polymerized it
meaning that they made it in a way
that's just
hyper absorbable for plants and it also
breaks down other nutrients to be
more more absorbable by the plant so
um george the formulation chemist this
guy's been
we met him and uh he's the one who
developed this and we were like man this
is the
smartest person on plant nutrients we've
ever met
um and that's you know me and um
one of our other people on our staff
renee who's uh
been you know she was the director of uh
sales director for botanical for like a
decade
and so she knows her nutrients really
well um and
you know i love talking with her about
nutrients and she's she's written
like a lot of the labels you know for
the old school labels that people have
seen for botanical
but um man george is one of those guys
that like
you just want to like crack open a beer
and sit and just let him talk for like
an hour
you know and he's just such a nice guy
but
you know he developed it they've been
trying on a commercial garden um there
were well a few of them for the last two
years
and we're having some pretty good
results so i was trying it here and
the plants grew amazingly and yeah
that's the last r d kind of thing that
we were doing but it's
kind of like a pretty standard nutrient
line when it comes to the amount of
bottles
you know it's not advanced nutrients
with 18 i think it's like a six bottle
uh kind of formula and then um
yeah the proprietary amino acids in a
product called flava
it's like flavuh yep
so the best way i can compare it almost
is like
if you had like um what are people
familiar with almost like a
turbinator meets blood candy in a way
so that's that's some effects you can
see something like that
those six bottles are those aren't all
base nutrients or
is it base nutrients plus their
additives
exactly yep based nutrients plus the
additives so
um there's well there's a kind of more
of like a home gardener line and there's
a commercial line but
um you know i was uh they're basically
the same thing it's just the commercial
lines more
in like a it's like a soluble powder
because that's how
most commercial gardens use their
nutrients a lot easier to transport
store um can be a little bit cheaper
when you're buying in bulk like a pallet
of nutrients
but it's basically a grow in a bloom
and then um there's a cow mag and
there's a silica
and then there's the flavor and then
there's a pk
and that's basically the whole lime yeah
all powdered
so no the the at home one is all liquids
okay and then the commercial line is um
all powder
except for the the flava product because
that one has to be in a solution for it
to
that proprietary amino acid polymer to
like work
properly so that's the only liquid yeah
okay and then you said these are going
to be released soon i assume that
the way folks can find out when they're
released is probably to sign up to your
email list is that right the growers
house email list i assume that you guys
will make some sort of announcement or
something
yes let those folks know that it's
available
yeah maybe we should like help her you
know hire you for our marketing
department or something
a lot of times we're like um it's it's
funny we operate this way but
when it comes down to it like we're
growers and we're not like
like i like to say we're a company of
growers but that that comes with its
pluses and minuses
what that means is we're not
experienced at launching product lines
so we just like like to r d the products
as much as possible make sure that we're
making something that like
we love it's doing like as good as it
possibly can and we stand behind and
we'd recommend to our friends
and then we have to figure out how to
get the message out there so that's
that's the part we're probably not as
good at
we're probably good at growing the
plants uh the marketing side yeah we
could probably use some help
so any marketers out there want to work
with us um that'd be great but yeah fill
out the email list
that's funny yeah i'm not good at
marketing either so many people comment
on my videos like you should be
promoting your book more
and blah blah blah and i'm just like i
never like think about that stuff like
i'm thinking about
the garden and like showing off the
plants and talking about the plants
yeah but that's what happens yeah i
could use a marketer too so anybody
in marketing uh hit me up yeah we can we
can we can share them you can work for
both of us it'd be a fun time
that would be awesome that'd be awesome
but getting back into
the grow let's talk about water source
so are you using ro water tap water rain
water
what are you doing for water yeah oral
water for sure
um like i told you the way i grow uh
when i'm doing r d i will say like
i do love you know fully organics like
sometimes you feel like
like my garden outside with all the
veggies totally
organic right 100 and sometimes you're
like yeah i really want the garden to
just be
all full of these meals and you know
manures and
basically everything that you feel like
is just coming out of the earth and
putting it back into it you know we have
a compost bin
so i compost and uh when it comes to the
r d
side though on the medicinal plants in
the grow tent um i like to have it
a lot more dialed in in a way where
i'm i'm the scientist controlling all
the levers
right so when i was talking about the
clay pebbles and just straight coco core
um totally inert right add the nutrients
in
and that's the way that you know
basically i like to operate
and i want my water for those nutrients
to be basically as close to zero parts
per million as possible
so um through an ro system if as long as
it's working properly you're going to be
between like zero and 30 parts per
million
um if you're like north of you know you
can see your membranes starting to go
out when you're like
kind of north of 50 but it's not too bad
even up to 100 it's like
like your water's still great once you
get over 100 it's probably
make sure you're checking your filters
and everything like that i actually had
a filter go out on me and i didn't
realize it
and uh i was growing with it and my
plans started to look like
hot trash and uh then i checked the ppm
on my rl and it was like higher
than tap and i was like okay well
there we go i think i had to change out
the membrane or something like that so
that's a huge
tip right there is make sure you're
checking the ppms
on your ro water because you could a
filter could just go and the memory
could go and it could just be injecting
tap water in there
yeah and you know i mean i don't um
depending on how you do it like
sometimes i put like a almost like those
like
20 or 30 dollar rubber mates you can put
like in a garage or something where you
can have
row filtering into it with a float valve
so it automatically shuts off when it
fills
and then if you have like 30 or 40
gallons of water i mean i guess
depending on how large your grow is
but if you're just doing a home grow
that'll last you a while so if you just
test that out once every few weeks you
know you should be good
but i noticed people who like fill up
their reservoir consistently with an ro
system
you are you know i guess you'd be more
prone to having issues because you'd
have to be testing
basically every time ro is putting water
in your reservoir or in your
plants which could be every day for some
people depending on how their system's
set up
that makes sense yeah now for the
nutrients you know you mentioned you're
in coco
inert medium you're adding the nutrients
correct me if i'm wrong but this isn't a
synthetic line that you're
that you've got and that's so salt-based
and that um are you following a feeding
chart
and this feeding chart that you guys
have
is it for medicinal plants is it going
to be a full dose is
accurate for medicinal plants or should
it be like every other nutrient almost
every other nutrient line where
it's typically recommended to start with
a half dose and see how your plants are
yeah and you know it's um so there is a
feed chart both in
meters per gallon and ppm for it so
um both those are available on you know
the url for the site's actually
ventanaplant.science
so it's not ventanaplantscience.com but
if you go there you will see
the two different bean charts but uh you
know the funny thing is with with
nutrient lines
um yeah almost all of them kind of
overstate yeah basically the
concentration of nutrients you should
give to your plants and i do
always really recommend going at half
strength and even for this one i would
start going at half strength
and then work your way up because it's
much better for a plant to have slightly
less nutrients and work your way up
then to basically force your plant into
a nutrient lockout
through that osmotic process and then
have to reel it back in
so that's honestly one of the reasons
why a lot of
people recommend that and people they
usually have a better experience with
nutrients when they go that way
and the the interesting thing is you
know some plants will do
they will look 100 healthy under half
strength
and even if you start pushing into
three-quarter strength
and even up almost to full strength some
plants
you won't even notice a difference and
they're just
they're they're you know they're they're
really adaptable to nutrient
concentrations
you know some strains some plants and
cultivars but
some are not then you have to find the
sweet spot so i wish there was like a
uh general kind of rule or guideline i
could give to people where i say
you know here it is just do this close
your eyes walk away and everything will
be fine but
it's just not that easy you know so
um i think people if you think of it
this way psychologically
if you have by the way just going back
to that last point if you are feeding
half and your plant is looking great and
then you go up the whole
you know 100 and it's also still looking
great you probably just want to go back
to half anyways because at that point
you're just kind of wasting nutrients
um like money you know and your plan is
probably going to do just fine it'll
adapt to what it needs
but psychologically if there was a
nutrient line who said you should feed
you know five mils a gallon
and then your plant is looking yellow at
five mils a gallon in some ways that
show a deficiency and then you increase
it to ten mils a gallon
you know sometimes people are
psychologically
like wow you know i'm oh i'm like i'm
feeding this plant so much i'm so far
above it's almost like taking medicine
like do you want to take double the dose
of a medicine do you think that's
healthy you're safe
so psychologically it's better to tell
people the limits
over here than rather to underestimate
the limit and
hopefully depending on the cultivars
you're growing you know someone is
somewhere between that 75 to 100 range
of what you give them
and i think psychologically that's a
little bit better for people to absorb
if you have to throw something out there
that makes sense
yeah now with these lines another thing
you had mentioned that it could be you
know overfeeding or
toxicity issue or plant problems in
general maybe yellowing or whatever
do you monitor the ph you know ppm
is another thing or ec there's another
thing that that people look at do you
personally do that do you recommend that
for this nutrient line
or some there's some nutrient lines that
have the ph perfect
advance has a ph perfect so you don't
need to worry about
ph your nutrient mix prior to giving
your plants so
yeah talk to us a little bit about that
yeah definitely and
normally i would if we're talking about
nutrients in general
um i do recommend ph
but of course mix your nutrients first
you know wait five or ten minutes stir
it up
test your nutrients out for advanced
nutrients ph perfect
um you know that is an interesting
product and it does work pretty well
this this nutrient line has developed if
you add it to
clean ro water and you add all the
nutrients during every phase like it
should actually be in the correct ph so
you won't have to ph
it so that is that is pretty cool it's
basically how the nutrient was designed
basically with uh
george's this comes back to george's
genius of like
basically what type of chemical
structure am i going to have in each
bottle
and how is that going to make it so that
it makes it as easy as possible so
this is i guess you could call it i
don't know i don't want to use that
terminology am i trademarked by advanced
nutrients but it is a ph balanced
nutrient so you don't have to jump in
there and the interesting thing is
the way it's designed the ph will
fluctuate a little bit
but as it basically goes to the plant it
makes sure that
the ph in the environment is proper for
the nutrients to be absorbed
which is the most important part so does
that mean that your solution always has
to be
exactly at 6.2 ph no you know
it can vary a little bit but people
don't have to jump in there unless
they're
you know ro water they're starting with
is that like a 4 or a 10 or something
you know
something absolutely ridiculous so
um yeah that makes it relatively simple
to do but when it comes to ph in your
water with other nutrients if they're
not
advertising that you know their product
has some type of ph balancing technology
then i
i definitely would recommend doing that
and uh when it comes to ec
ppm tds um
you know that's like saying miles per
hour kilometers per hour
you know it's it's it's like there's
different ways of measuring the same
thing
the concentration of nutrients in the
solution um
uh i do recommend i think especially if
you're growing the same cultivar over
and over
paying attention to your to your ec
or parts per million and seeing how the
plant responds like having your own grow
journal
is like the best way to do that uh
i would say you know starting off with
your the guideline we were speaking
about of just being at like 50
of what the feed chart recommends and
working your way up
that's probably the best way to initiate
it but you know a lot of times
i know people growing amazing medicinal
plants at
end of flower it's like 900 parts per
million
and then i know people growing amazing
plants and at the end they're
doing 1600 parts per million and
if you flip-flop those nutrient recipes
like you're probably not
going to have the same amazing plants so
those people are growing so
it's it's really about a positive
feedback loop
and in a way it almost it's funny
because it's like
people should treat themselves the way
they treat their plants and vice versa
and what i mean by that is journal for
your plants journal for yourself
you know if you had a funky day write
about it
and try and understand the association
between like you know what when i hang
out with these people
i always seem to have a really good day
and i can look back on that
and make those associations and then you
start hanging out with those people
again more and more
and it's no different with your plan
it's like what kind of cool things were
going on its environment when it looked
its best
now how do i recreate that again and
believe me if you just try and rely on
your mind and be like oh yeah i'll
remember it dude it's all good
i got this you're gonna realize that you
forgot
and then you're gonna like be chasing
your tail
so for me it's like even the smartest
people i know
are writing down notes referring back to
them because then you don't have to be
keeping like this
encyclopedic knowledge in your head
about what happened every day like look
what happened in your garden
in january 23rd you know do you remember
no no yeah i don't remember
i don't remember like the older i get
the more i realize the value of
writing things down and journaling
things and whether that goes to your
plants or yourself so
do you do i completely agree yeah i have
what i use is google sheets
and the reason why i use it is because i
have a roommate who also helps in the
garden as well
and yes being able to share that sheet
be able to refer to it both added notes
is key
and it's basically just pretty simple uh
you know on the rows you've got the date
and then on the columns you've got the
plant and then you know within
each cell you're writing down for that
day like what you're doing whether it be
um you know you're transplanted on this
day or
uh you know you fed in and this was the
runoff ph
or runoff ppm or ph even ph going in ph
going out
so just all those details it's good to
look back on especially if you do pop
into a problem
you can look back at those notes and say
oh okay
maybe this is happening because a week
ago or two weeks ago i did this
so i totally agree with you on um you
know using some sort of
journal diary whatever you want to call
it to track your plants
because you're you're not going to be
able to remember it especially
for me i grow like typically like 6 to
twelve plants at a time
there's no way i can remember all that
all different cultivars they all have
different nutrient requirements
so it's super tough what do you use to
track do you
use any sort of app or or just a piece
of paper or what
yeah no i'm a i'm a definitely a child
of the internet so i'm extremely digital
um and you know most of my notes either
go into
google drive shared spreadsheet or
evernote those are my two go-to's
so um i'm probably very very similar to
you and it's good doing it with someone
too because they they can kind of keep
you accountable in a way
you know they can prod you if you missed
a day or two and also like don't sweat
it like some people are super
perfectionist and they'll be like
oh i'm gonna start journaling you know
every single day of my growing operation
and it's
it's gonna be perfect you know i'm gonna
write like a paragraph each day
and then i'm also gonna do a hundred
push-ups and run three miles and you
know
dude like relax it's okay you just put
like a couple
small notes that takes you five seconds
don't set yourself up to fail
and like if you miss a few days oh man i
went out with my friends and wicked
hangover and i missed a day or something
like look it's
it's okay you don't need perfection just
like
if you can get it the majority of the
time you're doing yourself like
exponentially better than not doing it
at all
so it's almost like that one push-up
rule kind of thing like i have to use it
all the time i think i have to refer
back to it like every other week but
it's like look every morning just do one
push-up if you don't want to do a second
one you don't have to
but often times what happens is you like
you end up doing like 10 or 20 push-ups
because you're like you know what i'm
already down here
i'm already doing the push-up why should
i get back up but some days you
you just do one push-up you know and
that's just kind of the way it is
plants are like life you know they teach
you a lot
yeah that's a really great point for
sure yeah let's uh let's switch it up
let's talk about environment a little
bit
so um temperature humidity you know what
do you typically aim for
on those avenues yeah um you know it's
so funny
also because in in many ways um
people are like man your your homegirl
must be so dialed in and perfect
you know you you help build out these
like basically multi-million dollar
operations with their equipment and
things like that i'm like well you know
because i'm doing that sometimes i don't
pay as much attention to the one at home
as i should and
i will be the first person to admit that
um but
a lot of times like i don't like it's
it's basically in a room and whatever
that room is
is what the grow tent is so the thing is
in the winter
you know it's probably closer to about a
and being in arizona um humidity is
naturally pretty low so i do have to
find cultivars that can deal with that
um usually i am keeping like in flower i
do try and keep it around like
um 50 um in veg and then around 40
in flour which is a little bit lower
than probably the average person but
look i'm in arizona
right um but when it comes to
temperature around 75 in the winter it
probably gets to 80
maybe i might even creep up to 85 in the
summer
depending on that room it's just the
natural house is getting a little bit
warmer but
you know especially in the summer i'm
always adding co2 and people are like oh
what kind of crazy co2
operation you got going in there and i'm
like dude it's a four by four ten just
get an exhale bag or two
hang it up you'll be fine you know and
so that's what i do for that little guy
that's that's what i was gonna ask if
you supplemented co2 so
use the bags have you had good success
with those do you hang them above the
plants or what do you do with those um
definitely hang them above the plants
because co2 will fall um
you know so naturally you do want to
hang them out up there
um you know we did do some testing i'm a
very
big tester i love testing products like
i don't trust
most things that are given to me until i
can corroborate the evidence myself
especially if it's something that's
going to be like
for example product we're going to bring
to market right it's like
you know you have to make sure you
rigorously test the product to make sure
that it's it's good and
i got into that even before you know we
were coming out their own products i was
testing a lot of leds
these days i'm sending them to light
laboratories and doing full panels on
like other brands of leds cost a
thousand dollars per test
we do that we have a blog on our website
where we test a lot of that stuff
but i like to find like you know here's
the marketed
efficiency of the led and then most
often
here is where the actual testing comes
into the efficiency of led in terms of
u moles per joule so that efficiency
rating that a lot of people see
so a lot of led companies out there i
will i'm not going to name any names but
i will say there are a lot of companies
especially on amazon who say they are
like
2.7 2.8 new moles per joule and they
actually test at like
2.2 which if you think about it that's
like a 30
you know decrease from what they're
advertising like imagine if like you
know
vitamin c advertised you and like or a
pill like ibuprofen they're like oh yeah
it's 200 milligrams
and then you test it it's like ah it's
actually more like 140.
like that's not false advertising right
yeah i guess it is false advertising but
when you're in such a niche little
industry it's like
who who's the police you know of the
of the small industry i think they're
policing more like google and apple on
facebook and things like that
so let's get into the light testing a
little bit more that is something that i
had on on the list here that
we wanted to talk about so you've done
some light testing in the past
i definitely want to dive deeper into
that you know integrated sphere
is a test that's very common i'm sure
you
use that or you you've had you've used
that in the past or
at least had your third party testing or
whatever yeah can you talk about
like testing in a whole and kind of what
your goal there and so on and so forth
yeah so with integrated spheres they're
extremely expensive if you want to look
one up and buy one
um more power to you that means you
definitely got some
you know some play around money but we
do contract that out
um we actually do use you know it sounds
funny because it's like light laboratory
that's actually the name of the company
so it's not just a laboratory that tests
lights
um but they're out of california jason
jason gee i think it is or g i don't
know the best way to pronounce it
um he's one of the main guys over there
but he's tested a lot of lights for us
and so we do um a full panel
like we'll do a grid over like a 5x5 at
12 you know 18 24 36 inches
they do full testing um looking at
basically ppf and ppfd few moles per
joule they do it between 400 and 700
nanometers
and for those of you don't know that's
just kind of like the photosynthetic
range
they also test it from like i think 380
to 720 so a little bit of a wider range
and give you also
the ppf and ppfd for that
they do a full spectral chart so they
show you that awesome little funky wave
and you can see like how many blues are
coming out
in relative intensity versus the reds
and maybe some whites and oranges
yellows things in between
they also do a you know a chromaticity
graph which is a little bit
um maybe a little bit above the average
kind of late person to kind of
absorb but they do do that and you know
a lot of people i actually
who are customers of ours especially on
the commercial side when they're like
you know i'm thinking about this led or
that led
and i'm gonna be investing uh two to
three hundred thousand dollars which way
should i go
i want to be able to speak intelligently
about what
you know what way i think they should go
in and
based off of data not just necessarily
what a sales rep from the company
told you who happens to be you know
a really good friend or a great you know
um maybe sales person so
i i'd rather have the data kind of do
the talking for the product
but sometimes the data's not available
so
in a way i felt like an obligation to
start creating that data and making it
publicly available
and that's where the light testing kind
of came from and believe me i've tried
to test other products like i tried to
do a
fan test uh with like inline fans
because
people would call us and like everyone
buying a fan would be like
hey so um what's the quietest six-inch
fan that you have
and we'd always be like man i don't know
like this one's quiet when you put
ducting on it and a carbon filter but
is it quite as the other one so i bought
this like decibel meter
and i was like you know what we're just
gonna test it so we went up to the
office
bought like every fan in the market
started testing with this decimal meter
i think this is one of those really old
videos like a six or seven year old
video on grover's house probably still
up there i got it taken down probably
but we were testing it and i will say
like we got some measurements out of
that decibel meter
but the thing was also like all over the
place so like
that test in particular i i will be like
one of the first people to say like
we got some decibel readings for those
fans but like
when i was in that room listening to
them they were all loud like
like can i perceptively know the
difference no so you're like kind of
splitting hairs in a way
so like some of my testing goes really
well and some of it's like
you know i guess you can't feel fast
fail forward i guess
it's a good philosophy
now for the light testing you said this
information is publicly available
where would folks go to access this
information
yeah and how many roughly how many
lights does this consist of
all the tests yeah the i mean how many
like lights have i tested in my career
were probably
somewhere between 50 and 100 on the most
recent
and relevant blog post that we have up
that uses the
um the light laboratory that i really
like using
there's probably 10 ish up there
including like
gavita fluence hlg
growers choice california lightworks and
i
might be missing one or two but i know
coming up we are going to be testing a
few more brands and putting them up
there
i know that on deck we have like lux
illuminar um you know some people we we
do take
um some recommendations from people so
some people have thrown out led
companies
such as the think grow by troll master
science you know uh and
you know if there's any other led
companies that are really making
making waves in the industry then
they're probably worth testing but if
you go to growershouse.com
blog um that'll take you to our blog and
we have a lot of tests there but there's
one blog in particular i think if you
just google like
best led grow lights of 2021 uh in
google we're like the first or second
thing that comes up
and just look for the one that's by
growers house and that's kind of the led
test
and yeah awesome yeah i think that's
great information
for the folks to have you know
especially you know
as you know i deal with a lot of a lot
of home growers are really my audience
is what i like to think you know
not as many in the commercial side of
things i feel like more
indoors versus outdoors because that's
the way i grow so i feel like a lot of
folks
a majority of them maybe not everybody
are kind of similar to that so indoor
lighting is huge
it can be expensive and there's
definitely a lack of data
and misinformation like you mentioned
with people reporting false numbers and
stuff like that so you doing these tests
having this information publicly
available is huge
so thank you for for doing that for us
and uh i'll link
grosshouse blog down in the description
section if i can find that specific
specific article i'll link that in the
description section so you guys can get
right to it so you can see that
information right away
but uh yeah great stuff there good stuff
with the lighting for sure
yeah and you know we um so even though
i'm doing the r d at home i do have
r d with some friends at you know
licensed commercial facilities and i'm
actually also part owner one of
massachusetts
so we are doing some testing with leds
over there different types of
automated irrigation like so people are
wondering like oh do you just have that
little
rmd 4x4 like no we test it it depends on
the product line right
um so we have a little hobbyist product
line stuff like plant house tents that's
like one of our
tents so i tested that and that's the
temp i'm growing it but
that's obviously not relevant for the
commercial grower right
so yeah makes sense so kind of getting
into the commercial side of things
you've
you know you have your own show can of
cribs
and you tour dozens and dozens of
facilities over the years you guys have
been doing that for what are you on your
third second season third season
yeah set we're like finishing up our
second season finishing up the second
season
yeah so finishing up the second season
and then we're just gonna keep going we
have some fun stuff coming out actually
we have uh
yeah we have i'll just say this summer
there's gonna be a really funny video
that drops
that is very unlike what we normally do
so
check it out yeah definitely subscribe
to grower's network if you uh
are not currently so
question i want to ask you is in regards
to cultivation facilities and kind of
having the
the home grow in mind right like i
mentioned a lot of my audience is
probably home growers is there anything
you've seen in these commercial
facilities that
you think can be applied to the home
grower that maybe you don't see
the homegrower traditionally doing
you know um i would say
immediately the answer is absolutely yes
um
there are a lot of differences between
commercial and home um
kind of growing operations but even in
our last episode
uh we we filmed at shango in las vegas
um that that was just released and
there's this one section where we talk
about
propagation and like you know in that
propagation section
you know let me let me rewind for a
quick second when you go into a
flowering room of a commercial
cultivation facility it's like
it's it's so impressive and large
and expansive and the environment is
controlled by these like
you know 800 pound dues that hang from
the ceiling and there's
10 of them and there's 200 lights and
they have this
preva argus you know environmental
controller
and that also cost a hundred thousand
dollars as nets worked into their system
and they're monitoring by computers
that's not like your home girl right but
when you go into like the propagation
section even
it's like you know they're using little
watt clone lights on a little rack with
10 by 20
you know cloning trays with little grow
dang cubes and clonex
you know and i said that in the episode
i was like this is the same exact way
that you're probably going to be cloning
at home and this is exactly what they're
doing at the commercial facility
but instead of one cloning dome you know
with a few plants in it they just
end up having about 40 of them you know
with 50 clones each
and they do that consistently every week
but
it's it's almost it's almost like
comical
that you know cloning and propagation is
exactly
the way it is at home as it is in these
commercial facilities
so if you watch like any of those kind
of groups videos like in the propagation
you'll watch it and you'll be like
oh yeah like this is basically what i do
at home oh but oh they taught me that
little
you know maybe that that little thing
about like
you know kind of like shaving the outer
layer of the plant or something like
that these cool little tips but
you know what if we go deeper though
some of these commercial operations are
trying to keep um
uh the genetics of their plant you know
as as pure as possible so they're
getting into like tissue culture
which is something that not a lot of
people do at home
but you know when it comes down to it i
think in commercial operations
they're really monitoring the exact same
environmental factors
they just have to do it on a bigger
scale so they're checking their ph
they're checking their ppm
they're checking their temps their
humidity you know the
considerations when you go up to a
really large operation
are not a change in those levers
it's just a change in what technology is
needed
for you to monitor those levers at that
scale
and learning that so i
i wouldn't put commercial growing on a
pedestal from
basic kind of growing um understanding
and expertise
but i will say i do put it on a pedestal
when it comes to
how you get the proper technology to all
integrate together
and almost becoming a general contractor
of a commercial
garden like that's the people that i see
do really well
they really study the manuals on this
technology and
they they really read through that and
they try and understand everything about
the growing
operation and then they try and be their
own contractor and building it out
those are the people that do well so if
there are any home growers out there who
are like you know what
i love doing this i want to do this for
a living i want to make a career out of
it i want to move from
you know let's say you're a bookkeeper
now doing accounting and you're like you
know what but i love the plants i want
to be with them every day
you know i would say start reading
manuals on a lot of the technology like
watch
some candy cribs episodes because it'll
give you a lot of ideas and you'll hear
these brands come up
like these really sophisticated you know
elaborate ones watch a whole bunch of
videos and read some manuals on how they
work
and you're you're basically halfway
there
that's awesome good stuff there so
you are the owner of grower's house the
largest
retailers for equipment
you've got to have some insight on some
of these new products that are coming in
the future
so can you tell us can is there anything
you can reveal to us is there anything
that's that's coming out that excites
you
yeah um there is and you know it's funny
that the the largest retailer in the us
it's like we're not really the largest
but
if we're like kind of the largest like
single
store kind of e-commerce operation but
there's other bigger companies out there
you know than us for sure but uh when it
comes to cool
products um you know what i think a lot
of people are going to see
are so people might know like ac and dc
fans
most fans are ac by
you know where the electrical current
goes but
there's these ec fans coming out right
now
which basically can operate with digital
controls
which can make them work a lot better
with controllers
and they operate on way less wattage way
less power
and i don't know if people in the past
have been like man
you know they buy like a little rheostat
or a speed adjuster for their fans and
it kind of works
you know it goes from like 100 to 50 but
it's like not very precise
and things like that and you can't
really get from 50 to zero
like these ec fans will be like i want
it at 37
dial it in with an app on your phone
like you know and then
have it change because it's digital it's
like
basically the world is your oyster like
as long as someone builds a technology
just to like say oh yeah
at 847 i wanted to go from 37 to 62
but then an hour later i wanted to drop
another five percent because this
happens like
you can do all that stuff and these fans
i think will end up being like the same
cost as like the ac fans too which is
really cool so that's gonna be coming up
on the horizon
um i think everyone's gonna see a lot
more like wi-fi
kind of based and app-based controllers
for home grow tents
that are gonna be coming way down in
cost um
i've been like working on a project
helping out some people
with some stuff like that where it's
like a controller that
you know it's kind of modular you can
end up hooking up like
basically a um you know like a
soil a you know a soil moisture probe
and then you can hook it up to your fans
and then you can have a ppm probe in
your reservoir
and you know you can hook up a whole
bunch of other probes and it's all
based on this little one controller with
a touch screen and you can also
hook it to your router and check it on
your phone and your laptop anytime and
that controller will probably be like
like i'm helping these guys out if
actually if you go to homegrown
engineering that's like a little youtube
channel by this guy named volker he's an
engineer
and um german engineer who lives in
australia
great accent love his accent just
hearing him talk is like
put you know put you to put you to sleep
or meditate or something but
um that's a cool channel and that
product will be like 299 bucks or
something
you know like that's cool i love i love
seeing little things like that come out
um even on the more sophisticated side
you know there's um a lot of things
the interesting thing that people don't
know that much is
the commercial growers
there's the high value crops for this
industry
like there's so much investment in r d
in technology
that it's actually like spilling over
into other crops because they don't have
as much profit to like invest in this so
the high value crops are like driving a
lot of technological innovation
right now which is awesome because we
used to be like you know
the the runs in the corner that no one
paid attention to and now we're like a
driving force
in thought leadership but you know
there's
there's some very cool applications
coming out with like crop steering where
it's like
if you're not familiar with the term
crop steering yeah just please google it
read it really fast
pause now play again so uh
but they're taking all these factors
and you can like basically see these
really small deviations in a plant's
health
and then like bring it right back to
where it needs to so you're not waiting
a week
to see how something's going and then it
takes another week to respond to it it's
like
you're keeping that like what we can
call homeostasis or equilibrium there
and you're like
riding that wave perfectly so that kind
of stuff is pretty cool i think
awesome so lots of exciting things
coming on
to the market soon that's good to hear
oh yeah yeah and i think the cool thing
that we're going to see is like
raspberry pi's like homegrowers
just making their own stuff that i'm
excited for too you know
that's gonna be right yeah for sure so
wrapping things up
how can the listeners find you and what
do you have upcoming in the future
yeah how can they find me um on you know
instagram is really big
i i like don't really go on facebook um
so
i think i have one i just don't really
do stuff on it that much but i have an
instagram it's nate.j.lipton
they can hit me up that's probably the
most popular social media for me in the
industry but
um yeah i guess that's that's kind of
mainly it check out growersnetwork.org
that they have a forum like a grow forum
we have like 15 000 growers on there who
are
talking about all this stuff all day
long so that's a cool thing and
um man i guess i guess that's probably
about it
well nate thank you so much for coming
on to the garden talk podcast today
truly appreciate it and uh yeah i hope
you enjoy the rest of your day
yeah it's great great spending an hour
with you this morning it's a good way to
spend it so thanks girls
have a good one peace
[Music]
you