hey what's up everybody welcome back to
my channel for those of you who don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr grew it
and today I've got a q a video for you
if this your first time tuning in to one
of my q a videos I actually record them
live on Twitch and it's my goal this
year to record a new one each month so
if you have questions that you want to
ask me head on over to twitch.tv Mr Grow
it hit the follow button and then you'll
be notified when I go live next and if
you tune into one of the live streams
and ask a question you may be featured
in a future video okay I have rambled on
enough let's get into the questions
are you still growing freak Show I
harvested that so I got two cuts from
Humboldt Seed Co they were at MJ bizcon
and I was just crazy to think that it
was over a year now uh so I actually got
that Harvest both those plants and um I
didn't continue I didn't clone it and
not continuing on with it I liked the
terpene profile wasn't crazy about like
the bud structure and the way it grew
and so on and so forth so it's not
something I'm going to keep in my garden
but I actually still do have some of the
Harvest and uh good smoke definitely
good smoke do you have any experience
with blue mats yes I do I have a 12 pack
of blue mats that I've been using for
several years now I really like the blue
mats using them off and on you know no
good reason for why I've been using them
off and on hand watering is is fun
sometimes but the blue mats are so
awesome because they're so hands off I
have it hooked up to a 14 gallon
Reservoir that's sufficient for me
because normally I'm growing between
like six and of plants so 14 gallon
Reservoir top it off every three to five
days so it's not too much maintenance on
my side but I love the blue mats takes a
little bit to dial them in to begin but
once you put them down into the medium
you know the medium should be the proper
moisture level then stick them down in
there then of course just follow the
instructions they have really good
instructions on how you set them up and
they've worked out great for me
particularly when top dressing with
Organic amendments and one little tip
I'll mention that I've been trying has
been working out pretty good is a lot of
people will Top dress the organic
amendments and they'll top trash across
the entire medium right well these blue
mats particularly with the dripper I'm
using just the one dripper down some
people actually have a hose that kind of
wraps around I haven't done that yet I
want to do that but I've been basically
trying to get the amendments to be right
underneath where the blue mat has been
dripping and that seems to have been
working out pretty good because when I
have amendments on the other side of
where the dripper is the medium doesn't
stay moist on that side so that's kind
of the only downside of blue mats I know
some people have had issues with blue
mats particularly them they're not being
set up correctly or failing on them and
then flooding their grow tents and stuff
I've been fortunate enough to not have
that issue but I really do like blue
mats highly recommend blue mats next
question what complete grow tank kits do
you recommend ask Mr Grow It Well shout
out to our sponsor happy Hydro they sell
some really good grow tent kits actually
simple kits for beginners really
everything you need just adding water
they also have kits with the automatic
watering systems from blue mats and
autopods we're talking about blue mats
earlier and a lot of them come with the
AC Infinity products quality products I
love AC Infinity I'll definitely have a
link to their kits down in the YouTube
description section below and did I
mention that the kits include my book
that's right my beginner grow book is
actually included in their kit which I
thought was pretty cool so it's a
collaboration I've had with happy Hydro
including my book and all their kits so
big shout out to them and my viewers use
discount code grow kit at checkout for
temperatures percent off so thanks again
to happy Hydro are you using regular
water and humidifier so I actually have
tried using tap water in a humidifier
way back in the day and it turned out to
be a failure the reason why is because I
have so many minerals in my tap what I
have hard water and the minerals on the
tap water what happens is they'll be
like a white fuzz that kind of comes out
from the humidifier and gets all over
your plants inside of the grow tent and
believe it or not clogs up the carbon
filter restricts airflow particularly
that carbon filter sock and um has been
no good so ever since then I've been
using RO water for many many years now
some people use distilled water but pure
water without minerals in there do you
still have a worm bin yes I do so I've
had a worm bin for a little over a year
and a half now actually created a worm
bin for composting added in a brick of
cocoa some paper shreddings now I'm
adding in the usual you know coffee
grounds any greens that are left over
banana peels those are mostly what I'm
putting in there so some eggshells
although the eggshells I made the
mistake of not grinding them up so
eggshells you know you should be
grinding them up completely into a
powder and then and then kind of putting
it in there at least that's what I
believe you should be doing because when
I just crumple them up my hands and put
them in there I mean they're still still
breaking down now so uh don't do that
mistake
but yeah I still have it it's alive and
kicking I have some red wigglers in
there I had some European night crawlers
in there as well so just trying to get
some diversity in the worm bin another
question here does Mr Canucks do
interview would you try to get him on
your show he's been invited to both my
show as well as FTS the response I got
from him is he doesn't go on shows he
doesn't go on shows or podcasts so uh
but he mentioned that hey if that
changes he'll hit me up so fingers
crossed everyone regarding blue mat how
would you go about feeding Advanced
Nutrients just water in or run through
the blue mat Reservoir so what I would
do is I would use use it in the
reservoir you can do your weekly mixture
according to their feeding chart they
have it broken down between weeks right
so that's kind of what you're aiming for
to put in the reservoir now a lot of
people go with a half dose or even a
quarter dose of what it's recommended on
the feeding chart to begin to make sure
they're not there's no toxicity is Just
Happening especially with the auto
watering system when you have something
dripping down like that at all times so
probably want to start with a half dose
or something in a quarter dose but yeah
mix it right up on your Reservoir pH
adjust and then check on it each day you
know you might need to fill it up
depending on how much the reservoir has
dropped down you can also add in water
if you make your mixture too strong you
check that you see on it or PPM and
you're like oh this is too strong this
isn't going to be this might lead to a
toxicity issue in my plant because maybe
it's a smaller plant for example add in
water and dilute it down a little bit a
little tip there but yeah I'd mix it
right in the reservoir and have it
dripping down I wouldn't I wouldn't go
about like cutting off the reservoir at
all or and hand watering nutrients like
that what is the surfactant you use for
IPM again so I just use Dr Bronner's
Soap just a little teaspoon of it within
water some people do a teaspoon within
48 ounces of water some people do a
teaspoon within a gallon of water and
then adding in some essential oil drops
is what I've done in the past don't do
it as often now since I I use the
mammoth can control but I was using
Rosemary putting a bunch of drops in
there peppermint met was another one and
then neem oil I was using that as well
but yeah Dr Bronner's Soap very common
thing used for or surfactant or some
people would just use Dawn dish soap but
I know there's some controversy on
whether or not chemicals are involved
there so in Organics have you had the
top soil turn hard cement-like is this
from drying out too often good question
so I'm assuming you're talking about the
Amendments kind of the organic
amendments mixed into that top part of
the soil and then when it's drying out
it's hardening up yeah I've come across
that before absolutely and so since then
I've been adding in most layers I've
been adding in cover crops I've been
adding in soil on top of those
amendments and only try to avoid that
from happening and that's been working
out pretty good but yeah it's really
hard to sometimes mix in those
amendments and when you water it in
making sure that that top layer stays
moist it's always been a challenge for
me at least so adding an Emulsion layer
on top of it is going to help prevent
that from occurring but yeah good
question that has happened to me before
do you ever see yourself growing in a
living soil bed yes I do I actually have
a two foot by four foot actually I
already am growing in a living soil bed
but it's outdoors vegetables I have a
two foot by 10 foot bed by Grassroots
fabric pots big shout out to them they
make some really good living soil beds
yeah lettuce kale bok choy I had some
carrots in there spinach love the living
soil bed as far as for medicinal
varieties when indoor I have a two foot
by four foot bed but I never actually
set it up I have some concerns because I
could be moving maybe this year but I
hate to fill up a two foot by four foot
bed and then have to move it you know so
I think that's the only thing holding me
back from from setting up a bed indoors
have you considered putting fruit in the
medium to decompose would that help with
the microbes so generally you want to
put fruit or veggies or stuff like that
in compost first and let the microbe
cycle that and turn that into a compost
before adding it into your medium now
the temperature will kind of Rise when
things are being composted so generally
people aren't putting things like that
like fruits or leafy greens or anything
like that directly into the medium and
burying it down if they are they don't
have generally don't have plants in
there I'm not saying nobody's ever done
it and nobody's ever been successful
doing that but that's just kind of the
General Route that people go I've mixed
up plant material in bucket of soil
before and just let that sit for several
weeks and then planted a plant into it
and been fine but now never put fruit
directly into the medium have you ever
done that I've never really even heard
of anybody doing that to be honest would
you ever do a freak chill run again
um probably no I was talking about that
a little while ago I don't know if
you're here for that or not but I had a
successful Harvest still have some right
now but I did not keep it in my garden
so I'm not crazy it was pretty kind of
finicky grower in my opinion any
thoughts on throwing in a handful of
worms in each pot to assist in
decomposition and adding fresh castings
to the mix great idea I've done it I had
them in seven gallon containers I
probably wouldn't go with any smaller
containers I would use worms if using
synthetic nutrients but Organics
absolutely I'm actually shifting up to a
10 gallon Grill pot for organic so I'm
actually emptying out the soil from my
seven gallon containers I've been
reusing for several years now and then
putting them into 10 gallons I just feel
like with the bigger containers better
for for numerous reasons but
particularly with the worms which is
what you're asking about just kind of
gives them a little room so definitely
recommend red wigglers some people use
European night crawlers I have those as
well and African nightcrawls are the
three worms that you can kind of check
out and I've just purchased from Uncle
Jim's worm farm so online Source just
Google it I know a lot of people will
grab stuff locally as well I went to
Walmart one time in the bait section
they have worms they have like red
wigglers there and they looked awful so
I never ended up getting it but some
people will go to their local Walmart or
bait store and get worms there because
you get them pretty decently cheap
probably get them a lot cheaper than
Uncle Jim's worm farm another blew my
question lots of blue mat questions this
episode huh wow it's a good system it is
I travel for work non-stop can I use
blue mat in my one gallon than
transplant my carrot and plant into my
seven gallon absolutely yeah yeah you
can simply take that carrot lift it up
from that one gallon and put it into
that seven gallon you'll have to adjust
the dialing stuff to Redial it in
because it's it's going to be a
different moisture level and just I
found that dialing redialing it
recalibrating it whatever you want to
call it in that new container you'll
find yourself having to do that but like
always yeah just make sure that that new
container that you're putting it in is
of the proper moisture is of the ideal
moisture level that way when you hop in
the when you pop in that blue Mac carrot
dial it in it should stay at that ideal
moisture level but yeah you can take it
from one one to another and switch it
over real quick no problem what's been
the most challenging thing about growing
besides your humidity that's a good
question there's lots of challenges out
there isn't there so humidity has
certainly been a challenge as I assume
you watch my videos you know that I have
very low humidity right now 21 is what
I'm seeing right here in this room and
so it's super tough in my grow room to
keep the humidity up I have humidifiers
in there 24 hours three of them actually
and that grow Roman into grow tents and
um yeah other challenges heat can
certainly be a challenge particularly in
the summertime this is something I talk
about pretty recently on on the podcast
I released and basically during the
daytime when the temperature reaches up
to 100 degrees 110 degrees outside it's
tough to keep the temperature down
indoors especially when I have a grow
light on you know it's generating heat
so I try to just stick with you know 12
12 photos during the summer time keep my
lights off during the day other
challenges I mean I think everybody
comes across the challenge of just
keeping the plant healthy you know the
nutrition you know whether it be growing
in soil and having the right nutrients
in there right balance of nutrients
there's been so many times I've had
grower error over feeding under feeding
I definitely think it's a challenge to
dial in feeding you know it definitely
takes a little while certainly top
dressing Organics organic Blends in
particular can make things a lot easier
then you're just focusing on keeping the
medium moist and not so mixing up
nutrients on a weekly basis in a
reservoir pH adjusting and then soil
Genting your plants so thanks for tuning
in to this month's q a video all the way
till the end if you enjoyed this episode
click that thumbs up button and also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already and be sure to visit me on
Twitch at twitch.tv Mr Grow It click the
video right here to continue watching q
a videos and I'll catch you all in the
next episode peace out everyone