hey what's up everybody welcome back to
my channel for you that don't know me my
name is Chris aka Mr Grow it and today I
got a q a video for you if this is your
first time tuning in to one of my q a
videos I record them live on Twitch
every single month so if you have
questions head on over to twitch.tv Mr
Grow it hit the follow button make sure
notifications are on and the next time I
go live tune into it and you can ask
questions and if you do tune in to one
of the live streams and ask questions
they may be featured in a future video
okay now let's get into the questions
how many plants would you recommend in a
three by three grow tent and what's set
up like pot size 3x3 I would do four
smaller plants maybe two medium-sized
plants or one big plant and a three by
three that's what I would do as far as
pot size probably three gallon pots you
know if you're keeping it with the
smaller plants four smaller plants and
three gallons or maybe even shove a
seven gallon in that three by three and
just do one plant whatever you want to
do you can definitely have some
flexibility there when you Peach your
water does it matter if you use a glass
or plastic cup do I don't know if I
fully understand your question so when i
ph my water what I'm doing I use a five
gallon bucket put the water in there
then I'm taking the ph up or PH down and
then dropping it directly into the water
and that's that's a plastic bucket is
what I use now I'm not sure maybe you're
asking if it's a nutrient solution
inside that five gallon bucket then what
I'll do in order what they say is dilute
the ph up and Peach down first in water
and then pour it in the nutrient
solution so you don't have precipitants
and so uh yeah put into a little little
glass of water page up PH down mix it in
there and then put it into the bucket of
nutrient solution hopefully that answers
your question Mr Grote asks what is a
good bagged soil besides the one you use
in your videos well shout out to our
sponsor happy Hydro they sell soham
Living soil really really good product
Omri certified organic this is what a
lot of people consider as a super soil
now of course it's going to depend on
the size of container that you're using
but a lot of people are actually
planting into this soil and then growing
their entire plant all the way up to
harvest without adding any other
nutrients in there so big shout out to
happy Hydro if you buy from them it's a
one to three day shipping on their
product so it can get to you pretty
quickly depending on where you are in
the states definitely have a link to a
heavy Hydro down in the YouTube
description section below how long did
it take you to dial in your organic
growing I like this question so when I
first started using organic inputs I was
using Earth dust nutrients by the green
Sunshine Company rest in peace that that
brand is no longer exists they close the
door and the end of 2022 I'm not sure if
you guys knew about that or not but
that's a bummer but I didn't know that
you should be keeping the media moist at
all times so those amendments to break
down something I've been talking about
for so much over the years since I've
learned that and been doing that but
people still make that mistake as
they'll top just those nutrients in
water them in and then they'll go right
to what they were doing with synthetics
where they have dry backs you know
they'll wait for the medium to dry out
before watering again well with Organics
unfortunately the microbes go dormant
and then they're not breaking down
nutrients so keeping that Medium moist
keeping those amendments moist it took
me a few grows to really realize that
and dial things in I do want to get my
hands on a moisture meter though that
should make things a lot easier blue mat
actually has a well actually their
company name is sustainable Village they
have a nice digital moisture medium I'm
trying to get my hands on I think it's
like 85 bucks or something like that but
uh if I can get one of those I can dial
in waterings a lot better and then of
course adding in the blue mats that's
how helps dial in the moisture level but
yeah that was the main thing in regards
to dialing in organic growing was just
dialing in that moisture of the medium
no-till or super soil and what's the
difference so super soil is generally
just a soil that has all the nutrients
needed in it for the entire grow so like
I just mentioned sohum living soil they
consider it a super soil where basically
you just take that whole bag put into I
believe a seven gallon container for
like a 1.5 cubic foot bag and then plant
the seed in there and then you know you
do a 30 day veg or so once you flip over
the flour there should be enough
nutrients to last throughout the entire
Grill no-till is just basically not
disturbing the soil at all you're
basically just adding on amendments up
to that top of the soil and you're not
like disturbing it at all so two
different things there and uh yeah
no-till is a very common practice these
days with particularly with Organics
because you've got the microbes in there
that are working for you to break down
nutrients and if you're disturbing the
soil at all you're killing off microbes
so a lot of people are going towards no
till if you could go back and give
beginner Chris one tip what would it be
it would probably be learn what nitrogen
toxicity is because beginner Chris
overfed and had nitrogen toxicity and
wiped out a grill wiped out five plants
that came out terrible because of
nitrogen toxicity so beginner Chris
learn what nitrogen toxicity is if you
have very dark leaves and they're shiny
and they're curling then that's most
likely nitrogen toxicity and always
check the PPM or EC so that way you're
not over feeding Zaza genetics asks how
are things going with your chill out OG
going pretty good on the f3s right now
so inbreeding learned a lot from you
Zaza I hope you know that I'm doing the
inbreeding so I'm on f3s right now I'm
going to be planting the f3s and seeing
how they turn out but uh so far so good
I'm getting the structure I'm looking
for over overall I'm looking for kind of
the the smaller structure plant bud
structure of the briskero G it's
actually a Brisco OG across the Pakistan
Valley the Pakistan Valley is a land
race train actually by world of seeds so
kind of the smaller structure Indica
side of things of the Pakistan Valley
the bud structure of the preschool G and
kind of a mixture of the terp profile is
what I'm looking for but yeah so far
it's going pretty good long process long
process for this and I know there's tons
of people been asking me for them it's
just not ready should be ready this year
though fingers crossed what are your
go-to dry amendments in most recent
years I've just been using the builders
Hill craft blend I've talked about this
on my channel I have a handful of times
large handful of times but that's
actually has everything you need in
order to get through the grow and it's a
just one mix one blend for the entire
Grove so it's not a separate one for veg
and a separate one for flowers is what
I'm getting at and I'll do an initial
amending I was using a salmon gallon
container one cup of boil soil craft
blend I'm ending it in to begin letting
it cook for for a week two weeks
planting into letting the plant grow 30
days after the plant sprouted from The
Medium 20 to 30 days I'm adding in
another cup per plant and then uh really
every 30 days just a cup per plant onto
the medium top dressing it in and that's
it so that's been my go-to as far as
other amendments alfalfa meal kelp meal
use once in a while I've used grokashi I
like that for breakdown I like to
putting that in my compost bin as well
my worm bin insect frass another member
I like to use it's all I can think of
off top my head here yeah all that stuff
is really good what are you looking
forward to Growing the most in 2023 I
like this question so I'm actually about
to start a new run right now I've got a
cherry Atomic Sledge Hammer by welcome
to the grow tent doing really well I've
got a vanilla Cola F1 by cannabinology
that's also doing really well those are
gonna be harvested within two to three
weeks I'm really excited about both of
those my next run I have right here I
have a whole list of things a whole list
of things let's just go over we can
right rombury by freedom of seeds don't
know too much about that ended up being
a free freebie from attitude my old
roommate had it never grew it gifted it
to me might as well plant it runs by
homegrown Co Amnesia fast by seeds men
sour grape Rock Candy by welcome to the
grow tent all those four that I just
mentioned are Femmes so guaranteed
female as long as they sprout sometimes
they don't have a good male female ratio
so I wanted to throw some Femmes in
there to make sure I get some the rest
of these are going to be regular so they
could be the male or females I might
plant them grow them and have to kill
them off because they end up being males
but chillota Jeep by Mr Grow it that's
the F3 and grow that out peyote purple
with a cross of iso 8 by Prism Labs
isolate by Prism Labs curb stomper by
Prism Labs rubrics by Prism Labs orange
cello by Prism Labs Icarus Wings by
Prism labs they sent me their whole line
a while ago and I've been trying to get
a female out of the Rubik's orange cello
and Icarus swings but I haven't had any
luck there I've grown out the curb
stomper and ISO 8 and those have been
freaking fire and huge shout out to
chronic 420 ink he is uh well known
formerly of North genetics now he's on
prism Labs doing his own thing and just
everything I've had from him has been
fire so big shout out to him nonetheless
but not least Dead Ops OG cross with
Persian Prince I've grown out the Dead
Ops OG before fire love it still have
some and they can't control right there
thank you so much for watching this q a
video hit the thumbs up if you haven't
already and subscribe to the channel
also if you haven't done that already
and don't forget to follow me on Twitch
twitch.tv Mr Grow it and when I go live
next tune in hang out ask some questions
to continue watching these q a videos
click the video right here on the screen
and I'll catch you guys in the next q a
video peace out everyone