what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you watch a Max's channel got
another Q&amp;A video for you this week
the last Q&amp;A video was very popular that
a lot of thumbs up and we got a lot of
positive comments in the comment section
we've got a lot of good questions as
well so I am going to answer the
questions in this video and I'm also
going to answer some questions from the
video I released on my main channel the
other day so let's just get right into
it
got a question it's been about 40 days
and about a week ago my plants started
sexing in the vegetate now a pollen
sacks showed but no pollen came out and
hair came out of it so is it a hermie or
a fem I'd actually have to see a picture
to give you a more accurate answer if
you're only seeing one what you think is
a pollen sack and a hair coming out of
it it's probably not it pollen sacks are
in clusters so give it some more time
see if pollen sacks forum if there's
like a cluster of pollen sacks and then
you'll have your answer now even if your
plan is showing a lot of pistols hairs I
always keep an eye out for the potential
for the planter arms so I've had plants
in the past where you know they've gone
two weeks in the flowering stage and
they had tons of pistols real nice buds
starting to form and all of a sudden
that clusters of pollen sacs forming
right underneath them right next to them
so it's hard to tell sometimes you
really just got to make sure you're
constantly inspecting your plans for
both signs of it being an army as well
as pest look for pests why are you
respecting your plants as well you could
always post a picture on my forum mr.
grower calm slash forum post picture on
there I'm long they're just about every
day every one to two days answering
questions so if you post a picture on
there it can advise a little bit better
about the question someone asked about
fans not lasting I used to have problems
with fans until I realized I wasn't
using all real water my human fires
started using ro now and they're fine no
calcium buildup in the motors just
wondering if anybody else had this issue
great cold out so when you are using non
all RO water so it's two tap water for
example that has minerals in it you
could experience problems both in your
humidifier just might not last as long
one of the main issues that a lot of
people have is when using tap water in
humidifiers is they'll get calcium
buildup in their carbon filter and that
carbon filter that the pre-filter other
coverin filter sock gets all clogged up
and you got to remove it and clean it
but it quickly clogs up the carbon
filters so it's definitely not
recommended to use tap water in your
humidifier definitely use RO water it's
some type of filtered water or distilled
water so that way you won't have that
calcium buildup but yeah that's that's a
very common thing that happens now you
mentioned that there's a buildup and
motors I've never had that happen but
that's a good call out I can definitely
see that potentially happening can you
do an all-organic grow really interested
in organic grows so I've actually done
an organic grow before on this channel I
used organic dry amendments definitely
didn't turn out very well to be honest
with you I wasn't didn't get a good
result from the organic amendments I'm
not sure if you're talking about the
organic amendment way to do organic
growing or if you're talking about
no-till living organics yeah I'll
definitely do some organic grows in the
future great videos and thanks for
taking the time to share your knowledge
so I'm about to start my first crew and
I'll be using Fox from ocean for soil
and I have the Fox farm nutrients my
question is do I wait 30 days then start
feeding them or do I start the first
week of veg so I'm not sure what you
consider their first week and veg people
consider it different some people
consider the first week of veg the week
that the plant sprouts from the soil
other people consider that the seedling
stage some people consider the seedling
stage the first two or sometimes some
people even think the first three weeks
are the seedling stage then there start
cutting veg so I'm not sure what you're
talking about there to make things
easier for you it's basically about
twenty to forty days from when the plant
sprouts from the medium now you could be
transplanting into fresh soil during
that first 30 days and that fresh soil
has nutrients in it so it might be a
little bit longer than the
period twenty to forty days just kind of
a rough guideline now if you're planting
directly into your final container let's
say your final container is a five
gallon pot I've grown like that before
it's roughly about thirty days if you
hit if you had your plants with
nutrients on the 30th day you're fine
we're growing infox from ocean force
well I've had my plants with nutrients
as early as day 16 from sprout and
actually that's a really good results in
doing it that early but you know those
genetics could have just kind of a
nutrient hungry be a general guideline
20 to 40 days from when the plant
sprouts when the medium good hit that
with a fox arm nutrients I would start
with a half dose maybe even start with
the quarter dose and always check the
ppm of the run off when you're using
synthetic nutrients you could do the run
off ppm some people argue that a slurry
test would be better than a run off test
really you can measure it either way sir
in a five by five grow ten how many
plants will fit depends on how big the
plants are right so you could actually
shove a whole bunch of some plants in
there
and keep them small flip them to flower
super early and you'll be fine or you
could just plug one plate in a 5x5 and
vegetal longer and fill up the whole
grow space so it really depends on how
many plants you're looking to grow me I
personally like a variety of plants well
for a five by five I would typically
shove in five maybe six plants in there
and veg him for 30 40 days and flip them
and that should basically fill up the
grow space depending on genetics
actually genetics lighting nutrition and
all that stuff is going to impact plant
growth but yeah it really depends on the
plants you want to grow you couldn't
keep a bunch of plants in there and just
keep them small and flip or one large
plant that's for a while great video bro
how far do you keep your electrics guide
lights from your plants of flower and
flowering I really like to do 20 inches
I've gone down to 18 inches before
however
kind of late in flowering I experienced
a fox tailing
Fox telling it can be genetics but it
can also be due to too much lights I
kind of have a gut feeling that I just
had my legs too close and I started Fox
tails you know 20 21 inches away and
flowering is what I like to run with the
Elector sky lights that's on full power
how much blast this - how many gallons
of water I do one tablespoon per gallon
of water at what height do you start
flowering depends on growth depends on
the genetics some indica strains
I'll let veg a little bit longer and
grow a little bit longer because they
tend to be more compact and don't
stretch as much in flowering when I flip
them into flowering that three-week
stretch period now I've come girl it's
just Eva strains those are gonna kind of
be quicker to grow and longer into notes
take up more space so I won't i won't
veg for as long depends on genetics
usually I go by the number of days and
veg usually it's around 30 to 40 days
and veg it's usually about the right
height before flipping a flower but yeah
it depends on genetics really and growth
how often do you use microbes so I've
been using mammoth peat and I've been
using blue plant and nutrients reso mix
I kind of rotate with them kind of every
other so watering I'll water with
menapii and exploring they'll toss in
some microbes sometimes I'll skip it and
yeah it's just kind of randomly but
things like microbes can be added every
watering and you shouldn't see an issue
no inoculating your medium with microbes
isn't gonna do any farm my question is
do I have to start my photos in a small
pot or a cup and transplant I know me
just grow Otto's keeping them in the
same home now you don't necessarily have
to start in a small pot and then cup and
then transplant up you could just do it
red in the final container
some people will plant directly into the
final container some people will plant
in a small cup and then transplant up
there are pros and cons to putting in a
small cup and then transplanting up and
there are pros and cons to just plant it
directly into the final container I
actually did create a video on train
planning multiple times I'll link that
video in the description section below
explain more detail about the pros of
trance playing multiple times and
actually in the comment section that
this video there is some good call-outs
additional information that I didn't
mention within the video so I'll link
that down below for you was the winner
picked from the grill craft giveaway
yes chilled led they already picked a
winner for that and I think that winner
already received a light as well really
good information I've been watching your
channel for some time and actually I'm
quite up there from you so thank you I
have a question about hydroponic growing
though I know this doesn't have anything
to do with your current growth but I'm
starting a DWC grow DW c stands for deep
water culture i'm using right at rear
plus and I'm starting with seeds so my
question is when should I put my seeds
and plug into my five-gallon bucket and
net pots in other words how long should
I keep the seedlings of plugs separate
so unfortunately Erin I don't have any
experience in dwc at all I don't want to
give you an answer and then all of a
sudden I tend to be wrong so what I'll
do is I ask this amazing community that
we have here with the whole wealth of
knowledge if anybody has dwc experience
that has an answer to his question
please leave it down in the comment
section below
help Erin oh great video and thanks for
sharing your knowledge I also have read
your book as well as heard you talk
about how you're gonna do a revision
soon what kind of stuff can we expect to
change any update on when this will take
place a great question yes my book has
been updated although it has not been
released yet there's a couple things
that are pending and I'm waiting on so
soon I hope I updated several of the
sections within the book just adding
information so it's not going to be a
complete revision as far as the text but
there's a lot of additional text in
there good information for example the
feeding nutrients section has been
expanded to be a lot more clear than it
is in the version that you have right
now also a lot of the photography is
different I actually went on to
Instagram and found some cannabis
photographer
I think I've got like eat Peter 9
photographers they ended up purchasing
some of their photos I wanted to include
in the book so it's not just my photos
in there that there's other photos as
well from good photographers in the
canvas community and also the design is
different so I hired a designer to do a
redesign and I'm looking to do a hard
copy as well so all that's kind of in
progress I'm hoping that the e-book is
released within a month
okay well this video is getting long so
I'm going to stop it there thank you
guys for all the questions that you left
in the comment section if you have any
other questions please let me know in
the comment section and maybe I will
answer them in a future video also if
there are any specific topics that you
want me to cover let me know and I'll
leave it at that thank you so much for
watching and until next time peace
[Music]