coming up on Garden talk it's really
cheap and simple too to just build
whatever frame and size you want you
know get your extractor choose your
lights and then boom I use what's
available and one of the first things
available when I first started growing
again in Columbia was five gallon paint
buckets but like not used with paint so
there's no toxicities or anything you
just go buy a paint bucket it's like
three bucks or something I was like oh
it's so much better than going to the
gardening store they're like 10 bucks or
something here if you're all still a
little bit early in that flower and
you're seeing a lot of stretch on the
main stretchers if you need to do a
little bit of LST just a little bit to
slow her down and if you have to take
those two top four whatever suckers just
you know slow them down just a little
bit with a little bit of low stress
training this is a way to be able to
have your own medicine produce it for
yourself on a consistent basis in an
organic way where you actually know what
is inside your medicine and you get to
choose it
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 80. in this
episode I interview Dakota from homegrow
TV he is a YouTuber with over 21 000
subscribers and has a lot of experience
doing closet growing in this episode he
talks about growing in small spaces such
as closets thanks to all of you who
support this podcast through patreon if
you'd like to support you can do so by
going to patreon.com Mr Grow it before
we get into it I want to acknowledge
that one of my goals for this podcast is
to bring zero cost for information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible AC
Infinity is sponsoring this episode The
Grow tank hits are incredible you get
there ion board LED grow light their
grow tent which is currently the
thickest on the market the ventilation
system clip-on fan and the controller 69
to control it all you also get their
fabric pots a trellis nut plant ties and
trimmers definitely a good price for all
that you get in the kit I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these grow tank
kits and you can use discount code Mr
Grow it if you're buying off their
website AC infinity.com that discount
code actually works for all AC Infinity
items or discount code Mr Grow at 15 if
you're buying off Amazon
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Dakota from homegrow TV how you doing
today dude fantastic what an honor to be
on the show
Mr Grow it my bro can I call you Chris
now that you know we get to hang out
virtue like this for the first time of
course yeah absolutely dude no thanks
again bro for for having me on yeah I'm
excited for you to be on here and uh you
know the topic we're going to talk about
today is something that excites me
because it hasn't really been talked
about on my podcast yet which is closet
growing but really we're going to be
talking about like growing in small
spaces as well right so it's not just
closet growing but some people don't
have a closet they're just growing in a
small space we'll get all into that
because there's really some things that
you can do differently than you would do
in a larger growth space so kind of
narrowing it down specifically to those
small grow spaces closet growing I think
is going to be valuable to the audience
but first can you do an introduction
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yes
definitely definitely so my name is
Dakota originally I'm from Edmonton
Alberta in Canada right now I'm living
here in near Medellin Colombia and
that's a long story we'll get there but
uh no originally Canadian at heart
absolutely you know love it I think a
lot of people notice I'm Canadian when
they start hearing me talking my boats
still come out quite a bit and uh
my journey into growing and finding this
medicinal plant is actually quite
interesting and it's really cool to be
able to come on here today and be able
to share it because
you know the format that I get to share
on YouTube and stuff we don't really go
into my backstory so often and getting
to do a few interviews myself it's not
getting into the backstory of homegirl
TV and how we got here today so it's
really cool to to be able to dive into
that and what makes it so different is
the fact of like kind of like the age I
got into it at and how
um how I ended up finding it it was
actually my what I call my stepdad
um you know my mother's boyfriend at the
time and I was
and I had started to have my first kind
of relationship with you know the
medicinal side of it and starting to see
it I suffered a lot at a young age of
migraines I used to be like hardcore
once a month and this was like it'd be
either full one day or if not a two
three day migraine and my mom didn't
know at the beginning but I ended up
finding this you know to be a solution
and I came back from a trip and I was 16
years old and I go into the basement and
my stepdad shows me this little wooden
closet and it was built out of a wooden
frame and he said this system right here
what I'm about to show you and I had no
idea what's inside I'm like talk about a
you know a a build up of of uh of what's
to come and he's just like tell me the
rules first like what I'm about to show
you this is a way to be able to have
your own medicine
and produce it for yourself on a
consistent basis in an organic way where
you actually know what is inside your
medicine and you get to choose it and I
was like okay what is in this box you
know and so it was with a little screw
drill and he undrills it and it opens up
and I just see like a row of six little
plants and they had these little white
pistols coming out and I had never seen
the plant in that form I just had always
seen it in its final cured form you know
I wasn't edu you know this was my first
entrance into seeing this this format so
my entry into the to the growing world
was actually through you know through
family and show me step by step and it
was books like you know the grow Bible
or Jorge Cervantes you know course I got
you know taken through those steps by
steps but in person and given that book
and given that course and like the first
thing ever in my hands that was the
first like year and a half was that
little that little uh closet grow and it
was a three little step formula and it
was really like a two by six is what it
was and this was you know your flower
your veg and your mom room and your
clone room up top and it was like little
T5 bulbs for you know for the clones and
I didn't know any of these things and he
was just showing me the system and he
was like the first thing also he's like
that same day here's your Journal you
write down everything you do to these
beautiful plants and everything that
goes into them and you write down any
signs from here on out and uh this is
now you know like immediately just took
to such a beautiful hobby to see them
change from the first day I seen them
then go in the next day for a week later
immediately I was hooked I took it very
seriously and I seen the
you know the impacts of
the way you treat you know this plant
and what comes out of it after oh my God
that first harvest was the most insane
thing you know that that I've ever seen
still today and I'll remember it clear
as day that was kind of the grow getting
getting into my first kind of experience
with closet grows and that from there
that same technique went into grow
um slightly bigger spaces but it was
always still building our own wood
frames white reflective poly you know
grow tents wasn't something I heard of
yet or seen LEDs was something you only
seen in High Times magazine
um HPS was the light we were using then
for everything badge was just T5 so it's
nice little thin bulbs that we just put
on a nice little panel and it was a lot
of D you know do-it-yourself building
you know working with wood and kind of
doing it but that was getting that
respect and understanding for creating
your own environments in a small space
and that's what I thought the topic
today was so good to dive more into the
small space closet grow
uh compared to I do have you know
experience with bigger tents and bigger
girls then but that's what started it
all and I still to date now always have
you know these small two by fours or
Clothes Closet style grows because I
just found the importance number one of
controlling your environment and then
the ease of doing it in the smaller
space learning there was was gave me
great you know kind of uh Foundation to
go to a you know from there I think
we're building enough for 20 plants and
into something a little bit bigger and
that was you know a totally different
space but
the little the what you can do in just a
closet size built you know by yourself
at home and help it self-sustaining you
know Perpetual Harvest that absolutely
blew my mind it's pretty cool to hear
your story about how you started and
starting with a small space and kind of
working your way up into bigger space so
you have experience in in Bolt types of
environments right that's really cool to
hear I have to ask how did the whole
YouTube thing come about right so you're
real known for your YouTube channel
called homegirl TV I'll definitely have
a link to it down in the YouTube
description section below you currently
have 21
000 subscribers on your channel and I
must say your video production is insane
I mean you're up there with the best of
the best as far as video production
bringing everybody up to the next level
and as far as video production how did
that all come about so yeah that's a
great question that follows up through
that was my again getting into and
finding what it was like to grow finding
how easy it was to be self-sustaining
with your own medicinal you know plants
at home that eventually ended up coming
to a full stop when I get into again I
was so young when I got into it I
continued that until about you know 18
19 years old worked a few construction
jobs and then I actually was blessed
enough to have a friend who also worked
construction and he got into the world
of affiliate marketing online marketing
internet marketing and this was back in
like 2011 and 12 when I decided at 19
years old I'm going to get into
affiliate marketing and I'm not sure if
you're familiar with with authors like
Tim Ferriss the four-hour work week and
these different uh people in the self
development world that was one of the
first books I read was a four-hour work
week and I've learned about Geo
Arbitrage where you're getting paid in
US Dollars Canadian dollars and then
spending that in somewhere else so at 19
years old I went to Thailand and I was
barely making any money online but it
was gonna be more than more than it was
worth in in Canada so I took the risk
and I went with my buddy and and it
ended up really snowballing and turning
into more income that I could have
thought of at that time more freedom
that's what got me to Colombia as well
in 2013 we did nine months in Thailand
and then I came out to Colombia for just
three months that was my plan and that
was 2013. now we are in what 2022 I'm
still here absolutely loving it you know
traveling out here often but this is my
home base here in Columbia and since
then in 2016 I made a transition into
filmmaking and it was a lot in the
advertising uh filming in the marketing
world so as an affiliate marketer the
best way to sell a lot of my products at
19 was to create a video you know
driving and this is like back when
Facebook marketing was like just the
right side Banner ad with a photo and
then you click on it and it would go
like email and then video wasn't even a
thing yet on Facebook and so when it did
become a thing that was like I got to
learn this about Final Cut Pro in 2013
as well and I would just slowly do my
marketing videos and I found that on
Sundays which was my free day I was
editing videos till like 6 a.m of like
me traveling and all these like just
random things just trying to learn the
skill of editing and I sat down myself
and 2016 and that's like that's the
Blessed thing I why I continue to love
this plan so much because it was because
of this plan and on a creative session
just sitting there thinking and
analyzing my life I was like What would
life look like if that's all you did if
all you did was create film so in 2016 I
made a big risk and just started working
in the video World Learning the skill
set putting in the time what is editing
what are the basics of camera
and then oh my goodness a pretty much
pandemic or or the whole covert thing
started in 2020 I had been working in
film now just for a little bit I could
no longer travel to go to the clients
that I needed to go to in the events the
way I used to work and so I created uh
home go TV and I was like dang man what
if I did the same amount of effort
everything I was put into my clients
work their commercial work that stuff
and we just did it with this beautiful
thing that I used to do and I had
stopped growing for eight plus years
traveling client work you know and I
didn't know in Colombia you could even
grow 20 plants legally everyone here by
by residents by household is legally
allowed to grow 20 medicinal plants in
their house with no said license so when
I found that out and this was again just
around right before covid-19 I was like
I'm gonna create the channel and just
slowly again that transition from
working with client work and marketing
to doing homegrown TV which really I
would say six to eight months ago is I'm
like I just want to go full time I just
want to hang out with these ladies film
them see them go from seed to harvest
document that part so that's that's kind
of where the the filming and the
production value comes from from the
Homegrown TV side and the storytelling
from that past experience I had creating
marketing videos and and filmmaking in
the world that's awesome wow so coming
up on 10 years video editing total since
you said he started in 2013 so no wonder
why you're so good
yeah that's fine I really do love it so
transitioning over to Growing you talked
a little bit about what your gross style
is right you mentioned indoors do you
also do outdoor growing as well also are
you organic are you mineral based or
often called synthetic and what medium
are you in are you soil great question
so hydroponic systems so being here in
Colombia it's crazy to say this but I'm
100 indoor right now here in Colombia we
have 365 all year round it's 12 12 light
it's perfect conditions for outdoor and
some of the biggest outdoor grows in the
world are based out here and that's why
I see these major companies now coming
down from Canada you you know from all
around the world really uh licensing
land and moving that direction so do we
do it yet no and that's mostly just
because of the property I live on I
cannot wait that's my goal within the
next year to get to a place where I can
have 10 outside Beauties and then 10
inside again limited to 20 without going
to to get a license so 100 indoor right
now but cannot wait to get outdoor the
medium we use
um is I started here in Columbia and
this is trial and Eric here in Columbia
dude it's so much different than back
when I was in Canada what's available
right like I can't go get what I what I
originally learned with so it was a
learning curve the first year here and I
have a great grow bro that you see a lot
on the channel his name is Mr Q he runs
a company here out of Columbia he has
been growing like a year more than or
more than that here in Colombia so he
had his his company down you know his
his feet down and he's like dude go to
Coco and it's like it cost me 10 bucks
for like a big Bulldog like a big coffee
or like a big potato sack 40 kilograms
uh 10 bucks for that and it cost me 10
bucks for a big bag of castings
earthworm castings another 40 kilos is
huge and so I follow his formula what he
taught me and I play between just Coco
5050 with the castings and it's not the
same quality castings again that I would
be used to in Canada that you might find
in the states
um it it doesn't it's not like just pure
like oh this is just you know Worm poop
like you can tell it's a little bit
Earth still but there's a lot of great
minerals in there so I usually play
between a 70 cocoa to 30 uh we call
hummus uh castings or 50 50 playing
anywhere between those those kind of
ratios and then for nutrients
um what's really cool at home grow tea
we're always just testing new things so
we've done a six-month cycle with Mills
nutrients
um you know we did a year cycle with an
organic line nutrients that is actually
my grow Bros
nutrient line and it's just a scene for
me to learn again to get my feet wet and
see okay that was the difference between
this now we're running Cutting Edge
um split with crunk so we're testing at
different times and we're never just
running through like okay just one
grotesque we're gonna run everything for
six months let's run it for a while
let's see how it works and then from
there we'll decide do we move on and
test more nutrients or are we going to
stick with these ones and I think we're
almost getting to the point where I'm
just like okay I've tried enough for
like let's just hang low for like a year
two years and just run this stuff and
start to dial it in more now with with
the plants and see how they're reacting
gotcha okay and you mentioned that you
started in a small grow space really
your your closet is is framed in I guess
right you started in a framed area
there's a lot of people in a similar
situation to you where they want to
actually create a framed grow space
that's where you know around closet size
or it could be even smaller than that
talk to us in detail about how you went
about framing it even getting into the
details on like what size would you use
I I think you used either uh would use
the panda film a mylar so on and so
forth
great great question dude I love that
you're bringing me back to that time and
I really really hope uh I said that
watches us at some point because what
great times those were and I'd say like
the best way for people listening to
this or maybe watching this right now
um and thinking about building your
first one at home and like you wanted to
see someone do it I would go search out
Jorge Cervantes and like that original
grow course he shows you how to frame
out a room and the way we would do it is
we would look at the space so the first
one ever okay I know I have about this
much and we framed it about two by six
and again in Canada it's very typical in
most garages in your household you're
going to have power tools if not
someone's parents or his friends
someone's gonna have power tools if not
you would go Ransom when I first moved
oh that's what we go to the Home Depot
we'd rent what we needed and we just do
a day cutting measure everything out in
very simple framework you know I'm
really just talking like just you know
two by fours cut to the size you know
drilled together with with your power
drill
um depending on how big we went then
obviously we'd have side braces and
Brace it a few more but uh Jorge
Cervantes doesn't great bro in that old
school grainy film I think it's on
YouTube as well and he's up there and
they're just you know they're hanging
everything they're getting it up and
what we would use I don't know the name
but I knew it as black and white poly
and I don't know if it was made for
construction or if it was a gardening
thing
but I'm pretty sure I would get it at
the gardening store back then and that
wasn't something I would get at Home
Depot I can't remember specifically but
it was black on one side white on the
other and then what I liked about and I
still like about the idea of building
your own size grow room you can tailor
it to your own size you know and so when
I first did my grow my my grow on my own
outside you know without my stepdad
um taking me step by step we went a bit
bigger and we just custom built it to
whatever a basement was knowing okay we
just space out okay two plants we had a
track and a 600 watt HPS going back and
forth at the Times we're like okay we'll
put maybe two or three 20 in here okay
perfect and then so we just you know
framed it out custom with that and then
the poly with a little stapler stapling
it up you seal it you know you cut your
hole where your ventilation is going to
be very it's exactly what the tents are
today and that's why it's it's crazy too
to see the how easy the kits are you got
the holes in the bottom and you choose
where you want to open up the flaps we
were doing the same thing before I even
knew that existed and I'm just like like
wow bro like I'm just so fortunate that
I was taught that way at the beginning
and not just throw it in a closet
without you know sealing in some kind of
way having an extractor
um you know bringing the fresh air in
not knowing that just planting beans if
that was my experience getting into the
game I think I don't even know if
homegrow TV would be around now it was
really nice to learn the basics so you
know it's cool to even see people use a
closet they might not even seal it with
black and white sometimes but they do
have an extractor going out they got
things coming and they know no lights
going into that room maybe so there's
ways to do it without sealing it but
it's really cheap and simple too to just
build whatever frame and size you want
you know get your extractor
choose your lights and then boom for the
poly film I think it's also called Panda
film I'm not sure if it's a brand Panda
or what but yeah that stuff
you know for anyone listening in that's
looking to purchase that stuff there's
different sizes of thickness and some
are so thin that you can actually hold
up to light and you can see the light
right through it so you just got to be
careful that you're looking at the
thickness I think the standard thickness
is five mil I think the happy Hydra
actually has the thickest on the market
seven mil so if you're really looking
for a real thick one and a product
placement here happy Hydro shout out to
you guys I actually have some of it
that's what I used for my closet seven
mil thick on that stuff so it's solid
now what about lighting what did you use
for lighting back then and taking a look
back what do you recommend now for
lighting and space like that since back
then the lighting was a lot different
than it is today yeah dude HPS was our
main go-to for flower back in the day
and I love those t5s like I would even
bring them back now just those small
fluorescent little T5 balls were so
cheap and we would get custom and build
panels with like 10 of them on there you
know they would barely you know use up
anything and I remember even doing a
full grow from seed to harvest with just
those to see and I was like Blown Away
with like oh my God it actually produced
nugs as well I thought just HPS was
going to do that but no HPS was really
nice back in the day especially in
Canada in the winter bro it gets really
really cold so it was nice to have that
heat
um at certain times definitely during
the winter I can't in the summer as well
we were in a basement so it was it was
nice and cool
and uh yeah the great results but now
like especially with where I live now
and being in Colombia and even if I was
still in Canada LED I just really big
fan of LED because of the heat the
efficiency is so nice there's like
something for everyone's growth style so
it's like some people are really into
the bars some people love the panels you
know and it's just it's just really cool
to see where it's come and you know
we're always just testing as well
different things here on uh on the
channel on homegirl TV and it's just we
found some really you know amazing you
know just amazing results with I
remember the first time I tried a 200
watt LED and I was like I just you know
and in a two by fours which is a great
example and keeping the environment
small and it was just 200 Watts the
first time I ever tried one I was like I
wasn't expecting you know what I see on
Instagram these 700 Watts 1000 watt LEDs
crazy nugs dude it was unbelievable I
was like oh my God it just blew away my
expectations you know if you just have
it dialed in nice and have everything
turned in nice and with those small
tents I find it it's it's easy to dial
in the the perfect settings yeah that's
all you really need for a wattage these
days it can be very very low I mean for
a two by two space a lot of people put
100 watts of LED in there right you know
two by four space 200 Watts now you can
go above and beyond that for sure but
then you could potentially run into heat
issues you know with all that uh energy
consumption being drawn the heat coming
from the diode being in that small space
that can be difficult yeah let's get
into air exchange air circulation first
what's your ventilation system you
talked a little bit about an extractor
fan was there a particular brand fan
you're using to exhaust the air using
carbon filter too so on and so forth so
yeah ventilation I think that's a
perfect question for the timing that
I've just recently going through right
now because it was two or three episodes
ago on the channel we released something
on powdery mildew it's the first time
that's ever happened to me and I got hit
hard on like two of my tents because uh
in in Canada I've always took it for
granted we had a much drier Climax and I
remember not having to fight with 80 90
humidities like I have here so I was
like I'm one of my fans broke and this
was a
I won't mention the name but it wasn't a
brand any of us it was like the cheapest
one I could find on Amazon and extractor
and it broke down I didn't have a
replacement so I connected one tent to
the other tent to the two by four so
they would extract both and then go out
so I'm bringing power to mildew from one
into the other which I didn't know and
then it's all on the on the channel on
the episode I learned so much and so I
definitely respect more now and is
something we all know but I didn't know
the consequences until I was dealing
with powdery mildew now I know it has to
be on points and the main one that I'm
absolutely loving is the AC Infinity
because of the the monitoring like to
get to see the the humidity that's in
there getting to adjust the probe and
not having like an external little one
I'm absolutely loving and now having the
Bluetooth ones I don't have the Wi-Fi
but I have the new Bluetooth and their
Advanced setup and it's so cool to be
able to see it on my phone have alerts
set up and everything so for me that's
my go-to now and I don't think I'll
invest in anything else
um that's not going to be at least at
that level to be able to see now what's
going on monitor for my phone monitor if
Amanda event just in case something does
you know totally
have an error stop working which you
know and all the time I've been growing
that's the first time a fan ever failed
like that but it was enough to totally
mess up you know two beautiful tents and
uh yeah dude AC Infinity I'm absolutely
loving them right now and please please
everyone listening to this or watching
this don't make the same mistake I do or
I did
um it won't happen again on the channel
but uh yeah take your extraction your
ventilation seriously inside the rooms
I've always had clip fans but I've found
a lot of the clip fans I've worked with
in the past or I've used have never had
the power I wanted to but I'm finding
the new AC Infinity ones which I also
have like they have the oscillating ones
which I'm absolutely loving and the
other ones also getting to set the power
and controller power for my phone and
everything it's just giving me a whole
new realm of control and like kind of
Freedom so I'm excited to see how that
reflects the grows I'm doing my first
test in Harvest with with those setups
right now
um but yeah if I don't on the other
tents where I don't have the nice
oscillating ACS I'll run you know a nice
big from the Home Center like the Home
Depot Center a big fan up in the corner
one down below and if I need to maybe
another one just to make sure
everything's kind of somewhat dancing in
the room not break dancing and getting
nuts but just slightly kind of uh just
moving back and forth and say no to
powdery mildew yeah the air circulation
is so undervalued by so many people and
a lot of people don't have their fans
set up the way they should so their
flows as it should and a lot of people
have a real dense canopy so there's hot
spots and human spots and but yeah air
circulation in order for it to get the
CO2 that it needs now AC Infinity
they've certainly done so much in order
to make things a lot easier for indoor
growing right one thing AC Infinity
doesn't have though which maybe they'll
have in the future who knows is heating
and cooling so some people will run
heaters in their environment or some
type of air conditioning whether it be
the Standalone ones or the Century City
in the house what do you do for heating
and cooling dude yeah and that question
too they I can't wait till they do it
because the main question and me as a as
a you know a consumer of AC Infinity I
remember the first time seeing it and
making my order on on uh getting my
first inline fan or extractor fan and I
was like is it AC though is it is it
producing AC out is it making cold air
and I'm like going on the website I'm
like where's the AC in this thing
um I would totally didn't know at the
beginning but I can't wait for that to
to come out when I lived in the city of
Medellin which right now I'm only about
a half hour outside and uh Colombia is
the second most biodiverse country in
the world some say it's the first some
say it's the third there's a it's a you
know between Brazil you got Peru here
but it's up there meaning if I drive a
half hour this way it can get a lot
hotter and sometimes more humid if I go
half hour that way it can get colder and
I'm like I need I need a jacket on with
just a half hour just the elevation it's
in the mountains here so just being in
the city where I was a few months ago
eight months ago I think it was back
when I lived out there it would get way
too hot in my room so I need needed an
AC it would get it would get like 32
which I'm not good at Fahrenheit too hot
you know it was a few degrees too hot of
my optimal where I wanted to be and so I
would have to run it at night and even
running it at night I had to keep my
lights low because if not it was just
going to be too warm unless I had AC
moving a half hour to where I live now
it just and this was part of the
decision of why I moved here I was like
okay if I'm gonna take it serious it's
gonna be a big investment you know AC
all year with the amount of test rooms
that I want to do and stuff that's going
to be pricey if we go half hour over
there here at night it gets cooler it's
cooler here in general it can be a
little bit more humid
um but right now it's perfect like the
hottest I'll get is 25 degrees and then
I turn them off in the day and it sits
at 22. so my range is now like three
degrees on any 10 pretty much from day
to night being able to crank to 100 on
the lights that I do want to so I'm
really blessed being able to choose like
okay let's just move a little bit over
here and kind of control that way so if
I didn't though yeah I would be using AC
and a lot of people here in Columbia use
AC which has its own advantages you know
as far as keeping the humidity down
working in some of those areas I wish
you know maybe I had a curing room with
AC in it that would be really cool goals
you know maybe one day we'll get there
just my care room has AC it'll be
amazing but no for now keeping the
energy bill as low as possible no
heaters no AC one thing I just want to
add to that would be for air
conditioning that's a concern for a lot
of people especially in small spaces you
know closets you're not gonna really
really fit a standalone one of those
portable AC units in your closet uh
they're just too big I mean you probably
could but you wouldn't have much space
left for a plant of course it depends on
the size of your closet if you had a
huge walk-in closet then you could
probably fit in a portable AC but one
thing to keep in mind is that they
consume so much energy the Standalone
portable ones so much energy I had one
of those for a while and I was using it
and my energy bill just went through the
roof now the window ACS are going to be
a little bit more efficient but by far
the central AC is in the house and
that's what I use now is just the
central AC in my house I just lower it
down I'll freeze a little bit if needed
yeah but as long as my plants are happy
that is most forgiving on the energy
pill for sure so I just figured I'd add
that in and then for heating one thing I
just want to speak about is a lot of
people use those portable heaters and I
have one of those tower heaters I use
that all the time same thing with your
AC is it might not fit in that grow
space comfortably but having your
equipment outside of the grow space in
your lung room like the room that your
closet is in for example if you're
controlling the air in that room and
then once you have your exhaust fan on
you're bringing that air in well you're
bringing in the ideal air right the the
temperature and humidity that you've
been conditioned in your lung room is
coming into your grow room so just
figured I'd mention those few things now
how about humidifier and dehumidifier a
lot of people adjusting the relative
humidity in order to get into that
optimal range for plant growth using a
humidifier or dehumidifier at all
yeah great points and especially being
in those in in a small tent closet grow
two by four or anything bigger than that
it's you know talking about that last
issue that I did have with the powdery
mildew now that'll never happen again
and so talking about the two by fours
for example
again they're sometimes my favorite just
because I can control the environment so
easily and like I have small
dehumidifiers in every single one of
them just small you know the little
portable ones it doesn't hold that much
liquid so it would be nice to have a
huge one in the main room
um but it's just nice to see okay cool
we're getting to this point put a little
little portable one inside and it's
actually been keeping it in in the
perfect range
um seeing like 58 to like 66 so if it
gets crazy rainy and it's like really
really humid which again here I'm used
to seeing 80 it could be you know 90
sometimes so dehumidifier all the way
um the next big investment will be
getting two of those big ones I'm gonna
start with one let's see the difference
on the electricity bill but I'm gonna
get one of the big ones because
curing is just and drying has been
probably the biggest challenge of
growing in a very humid spot because
even you keep it good in the room now
curing it it's just a whole different
thing so if I can control the entire
room where all the grow tents are and
keep that at it at a certain range
that's kind of where I want to go and
just have that draining into a bucket
um much lower maintenance instead of
going in the tents every day taking out
the little dehumidifier water and
getting getting rid of that
so yeah definitely um dehumidifiers here
I wish I had the problem to have to use
humidifiers like you have right that's
what you have and the complete opposite
of you I've never had to run a
dehumidifier because my natural humidity
is like 30 now looking at it right yeah
it's exactly at 30 right now I'm looking
at my monitor and winter time it gets
even crazier it's like 19 18 so it's
like super dry here which increases
transpiration and plant growth it could
actually be a negative thing in some
cases so I actually have a humidifier so
I add in humidity now one thing I will
say about humidifiers is those will you
know you can shove one of those in a
small grow space either a small grow
space or a closet space levolt is the
brand that I've been using now and it's
way better than anything else I've ever
used this one is a top fill so you can
actually just take off the top load up
the water without having to like some of
the other tanks you have to like take
off the whole thing flip it upside down
unscrew it then pour it in it's like you
don't have to do anything that one of
your episodes that was that was really
cool dude it makes it easier I know it's
like seems like a small feature to some
people but it's like it's it's just the
convenience factor it's great
it's connected to your smartphone as
well so you get notifications when it's
out or when it needs to be cleaned which
is really cool so I love that one and
the tank I think is like a gallon and a
half so it's larger than a lot of the
other tanks on the markets so I can't
recommend that brand enough I did have a
leaking issue with one of them but I
think I just cleaned it and then now it
doesn't leak anymore so I don't know
what happened there but uh yeah full
disclosure yeah no thing looks solid and
that's kind of like the difference
between the dehumidifier
um and the small one the disadvantage
taking it out every day two days if you
forget about it just gonna turn off stop
taking out the the humidity compared to
if I had a bigger one I'm running the
hose it's going into the bucket there's
some things it really is making the work
that it's worth making the jump for and
investing like we think about LEDs as
being just the main thing or okay then
we'll think about our tent but man yeah
it's like it's not fun fun but sometimes
you're gonna have to draw up you know
depending on where you live in your
situation on something like that it
isn't the most exciting but man is it
going to make It's Gonna Save so many
headaches and just save you you know
just better buds
yeah I completely agree and that's why
most of the episodes so far just what
the entire episode has been on the the
space and the actual equipment that goes
into space I do want to transition over
now to actual growing the plants in that
small space and I think I want to start
with the container size right you're in
a small space what size containers do
did you run in your small closet grow
and I guess what size would you
recommend
so yeah I started and we I remember back
in Canada it was cool I haven't seen
these or used these since but this was
like back when it was like remember just
the plastic bags they were disposable
bags kind of like the grow bags material
we have now reusable these were like
just plastic and we were using one
gallon sea of green but nowadays
especially having a plant limit and
that's often a conversation you know
depending on where you're growing you
know or what the medicinal plant limit
is on where you are here it's 20 right
so I never want to go above that and I
usually want to say a few you know below
just to in case I want to cut a clone or
just have room to be able to play so the
size I often do now you know and I
always still like to you know know that
big Roots big fruits so as big as we can
go
um in the smallest of testing size three
gallon just to see certain strains how
they're gonna produce in a three gallon
and that's in a two by four small setup
I'll put either two or three in there
and if I put three uh three gallons in
then I'm Gonna Leave vegim Out you know
not as long you know four weeks maybe
and then kick them over whereas if I
have just two I could veg him out for
maybe eight you know six if we wanted to
just get into it and then have more room
in in there so I've done both and we
have several episodes on the Channel
showing both what it's like to have
three what it's like to have two using
three gallons
um but some of the other favorite ones
and a lot of people actually make fun of
me too of this one but in a nice way I
also kind of laugh at it I use what's
available and one of the first things
available when I first started growing
again in Colombia was five gallon paint
buckets so like you know but like not
used with paint so there's no toxicities
or anything you just go buy a paint
bucket it's like three bucks or
something I was like oh it's so much
better than going to the gardening store
they're like 10 bucks or something here
it's like this luxurious one and so I
just got a bunch of these five gallons
drilled holes in them and it was nice
because they were a little bit taller
and if I wanted to see a green I could
fit a bit more you know into into that
into that size
um and then the biggest is 11 gallons
and that's when like you know in a five
by five I can have five of these 11
gallons and veg them out for eight weeks
make them big you know if you want to
keep it to 20 plans can't do A C green
of 40. let's do five big ones you know
in in four separate rooms you know so
that's what I've also tested that's on
the biggest end is 12 gallons none of it
fabric yet but right now we're testing
two tents a two by four and a four by
four with all fabric pots and that's
from basement autoflowers homie that has
this fabric pots with the option to
train your plants which you know we'll
talk about talk about later
um so I'm again and there's the
differences there I like the non fabric
because I started with that when I first
got back into Columbia and I just found
if it's not the right quality you're
going to get leaking everywhere it dries
out quicker you just have to be ready
for the difference between growing in a
fabric pot
um and I found sometimes if you're away
from the house an extra day or if you
might miss a feed having the non-fabric
just kept it uh kept the the moisture a
little bit longer
and it was just something I just got
used to the timing of when they were
going to water and everything so now
we're going to be testing uh yeah
Fabrics I think we got three gallons and
five gallons I'm not sure I gotta double
check it might just be five gallons but
we're testing those right now as well
okay yeah there are Pros so many pros
and cons to running smaller containers
versus larger containers I mean if
you're running one gallon containers and
you're you're small grow tent or grows
the space or closet
um then you have a whole bunch of plants
to water if the plant is Big it might
dry out the medium faster so you have to
water more often versus if you're
running a larger container say three
gallons or five gallons maybe you have
to water less frequently you know what I
mean so that's just one of many pros and
cons to it we could sit here for the
next 30 minutes and talk about container
size but uh I don't really want to do
that but you did mention training and I
want to get deeper into that next
playing training staying in a small
space staying in a closet some people
need to train their plants to keep them
small also those stay within that space
what do you typically do for plants
training when you're in a small space or
closet
yeah I think yeah you nailed it it
totally depends again on the space and
talking about our small spaces first a
two by four to make the most out of our
two by four there's so many the way I
see it and I've gone to the extreme of
being the over trainer right like I've
done it and I've over trained the lady
and it's like week 10 veg and she's like
just short and there's like a hundred
things and I've gone the opposite and
I'm like let's just don't don't touch
anything and let her go through and I
found now I find you're you're in a
balance and you understand the plans a
little bit more especially when you know
this train I think it's always fun too
the first time growing out a strain if
you can just let it grow naturally to
see
that's great if you don't have the time
you want to get right to training but I
think there's a few basic things talking
about a small girl that we should do the
most basic and the first thing would
definitely be uh topping you know just
to not have one branch and if I have an
extra two weeks that I want to veg for I
love to top
um and that way at least I'm dealing
with Four Tops I've have some episodes
where it looks like we have just 10
amazing colas and that's from one single
topping that we did depending on the
strain right some I like to let's say
you know if you want to delay it a
little bit and let's say it's all on
timing I like to kick the next garden
over when that one's halfway done right
to always kind of keep things you always
got a consistent Harvest coming in at a
certain time so I'm like okay I want to
keep vegging these an extra two weeks
let's train them a little bit more let's
do a little bit of LST now right we
always pretty much do the topping but
right now I kind of living in that
flexible area my two by fours of just
how quick do I want to flip this over
into flower okay I know I have about
four weeks all right let's take our time
definitely do one topping and then from
there LST here to just make sure she's
not going to stretch too close to the
light
um you know that's I don't know in a
small space this happens to a lot of us
if it it's going to happen at some point
in your life it's already happened or
it's gonna happen in the future where
you over veg a plant or a veg a plant's
gonna over stretch and in a small space
you always have to keep in mind if you
don't know that that genetic or what she
acts like you know treat her like she's
probably gonna stretch a lot play it on
the safe end and don't vegger out too
long trainer so she's you know you got
yourself some good playroom just in case
she stretches a foot and you're still
you know good at least six inches away
from from the light if someone does make
that mistake of over vegging their
plants or maybe they think they veg a
good amount of time but then they flip
over to the flowering like cycle and
they get that two three weeks of stretch
and then they're really outgrowing that
space What are some things that they
should do
perfect yeah that's a great question
that just happened here recently I'm the
type of guy that always has his his uh
his fan and carbon filter in the room up
top and so the first time this happened
I was like oh my God like really soon
these are going to get too close so
first step let's get the fan outside the
room the carbon filter out the room get
the lights as high as you can so get
everything out of the room like as far
as ventilation that you can on the
outside of your extractor that kind of
stuff extract from the outside pull out
you know push it outside
um that's the first thing and let's say
you've done that or let's say you don't
have the option two and now no matter
what you're gonna hit it depending on
where you are uh
you know you can do a really late
topping you know there's a lot of people
who are very don't stress you're going
into flower you've already started
flower don't do that if you have to you
have to and if you like you you're
already week one flower you're seeing
what's going on take her off because if
not you're going to run into your
problem she's going to be touching the
light you're going to be crying she's
she's stressing out so that's one thing
if you're early enough to to be able to
to clip her out
um
I had another one I wanted to share
there I've had to take plants out in
fully she was just going to get too big
she was already too late in the flower
to start taking buds off so I really I
had to start over again you know on that
strain and that was really unfortunate
so yeah I would say to take out your
ventilation what you can raise the
heights as much as you can and then
early oh and that was the last thing
sorry so again if you're all still a
little bit early in that in that flower
and you're seeing a lot of stretch on
the main stretchers if you need to do a
little bit of LST just a little bit to
slow her down you know like if she's
gonna you see you're going right up and
if you have to take those two top four
whatever suckers just you know slow them
down just a little bit with a little bit
of low stress training and then that
hopefully should even out the rest of
them will start to come up and you'll
have more of an even kind of canopy I go
as far as even super cropping you know
when I get those branches that just come
up and just actually it's a form of high
stress train technically is have that
thing flop over and then the other
branches will kind of catch up that's a
good call though but yeah I've had a
handful of people over the years that
have sent me pictures and like I'm
running out of space and they just have
that one branch coming up and it's like
super close to the light and I tell them
I'm like you may want to sacrifice that
branch and they don't even think about
it you know you definitely can you
already mentioned this you definitely
can top that remove that branch and
that's actually going to help the other
branches that are lower right because if
you have this one branch coming up and
it's too close to the light you could
stretch out into the plant so much and
I've done this before to where it starts
throwing out nanners you know it's just
it's too much light stress it starts
throwing out dinners so cutting that
Branch off well then maybe the rest of
the branches are going to now grow just
fine because you sacrifice that one
branch so a lot of people don't think of
that you bring up a great Point yeah it
just and a lot of the photos we take on
homegroups video for Instagram sometimes
we take it at a point in the plant's
life where she's not ready for Harvest
but she looks the best for photo so
we'll cut her and then we'll take the
pictures and then we leave the plant
maybe to flower at Max on one strand we
push for another two weeks and
interestingly enough now that you say
that now I remember going back and we
looked at it after and it's like we
never took anything off we're like oh my
god look Everything Is Beautiful even
though two weeks ago a week ago we took
off you know our beautiful our catalog
one the rest now are like wow of all
matured so yeah I think yeah you don't
have to be where if you got to take off
a big one now you bring that up I've
done it for photography and yeah she uh
she will still mature nice yeah
absolutely how about watering is there
anything that you do in particular when
you're Watering your plants you know
specific to closet growing specific to
Classic growing not so much
um if I had to relate it too I do keep
my reservoirs obviously a little bit
smaller and let's talk reservoirs I
think you know for per tent because
um as a home grower whether you have a
small closet grow whether you have a 4x4
5x5 you know a ten by five whatever it
is
um everyone's gonna have a different way
of feeding it so what we do at home grow
TV with our water at least is we do a
reservoir we dechlorinate 24 hours
before at least and a small closet grow
depending on the plants I don't want to
leave my water out in the reservoir for
you know for too long so I like to just
monitor it and I use those same five
gallon buckets leave it out for 24 hours
before usually ten percent of what the
the pot is is what I'm giving it you
know for water and I'm moving now almost
to like almost daily where I'm almost
testing this with a few small gardens
and just watering them kind of daily
smaller amounts
so no big difference but what I will say
and something exciting coming up I don't
know if it's going to be great or if
it's going to be just totally not
relevant to plants but there's an
alkaline or it's just it doesn't have to
be alkaline but there's a water filter
that I used to use just as a person not
for growing and this is basically allows
me to control the pH that comes out of
the machine all the way from you know I
can choose 11 to pH 2.5 so I think
there's going to be some exciting stuff
in the future for homegirl TV and
experimenting stuff with water
everything from extracts to you know to
watering our plants and seeing the
difference is really something going on
cloning stuff like that but no as of
right now I'm very typical take out your
water 24 hours dechlorinate small little
Reservoir and yeah do that probably
about twice a week all right pretty
straightforward stuff there so we are
coming up towards the end of the episode
and one of the questions I like to ask
on most episodes is get a good device
for beginners so what advice do you have
for those that are new to closet growing
so yeah I know great question I think
advice for new Growers getting into
small closet grows maybe just small tent
grows two by four two by two whatever
that may be I would say definitely keep
it simple don't over complicate it and
get started taking it one step at a time
meaning if you don't have everything in
your budget right now to get the
dehumidifier we may have talked about
today to get the humidifier that you may
need maybe you need to start off with
um you know not your most ideal light
that you want to choose get your kit get
going don't over complicate it
um and I would also say as a side piece
to that is follow if there if you don't
have a grow bro that's going to take you
through this step by step I would follow
someone who has the results that you're
looking to achieve whether that's
someone who has a grow Journal seed to
harvest online whether that's watching
Mr gowitz content someone who's done it
proven the concept and follow that step
by step don't lose yourself in the
information of what nutrients what
genetics what light
get going have fun with it and then
because after your first two grows
every you know then you can start making
decisions your own choices and and kind
of play it from there but yeah I would
just say keep it simple and start having
fun growing in a small nice nice little
closet grow definitely keep it simple I
mean I know people who grow in a closet
they just have a light in there and
that's it they don't even have any
ventilation they don't even have air
circulation they just keep the closet
door open and they have a fan blowing
towards the closet door and the plants
still grow exactly they can certainly
get away with it you just might not get
the most optimal dance buds you know
that you're looking for but you'll still
get a harvest off of it so I like your
advice there when you talk about keeping
it simple because we did spend a lot of
time here talking about environment and
the equipment in order to automate the
environment because it it's very
important but you can certainly get away
with not having a lot of those things
exactly so wrapping things up how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future awesome dude
well you can find us on homegrow TV on
YouTube just home grow TV also on
Instagram am same thing home grow TV
and I think the future is where it gets
really exciting because yeah right now
we're known for a lot of seed to harvest
videos we do do lives meaning we're
going live right after this here on
homegirl TV's Channel we do interviews
not nearly as much as you brother you're
a master at that and we learned so much
from watching your stuff it's
you know we've done a few breeders here
and there but where is homegirl TV going
is I think to that documentary shorts
film
um showing Columbia showing the Breeders
kind of like that Strain Hunters what we
got to see back in 2013 I think is when
that that kind of came out that Strain
Hunters area that documentary style of
the story The Growers the people where
did our land races really come from
um getting to meet these these kind of
families who have been doing it you know
from generations to Generations here and
that's all they know that's what gets me
really fired up
um and also those tours so getting to
see being here in Columbia I really feel
like in five years you know what
Columbia will be known for will be
totally different than what they have
been known for over the last 20 years
because of the movement of what's
Happening Here with this beautiful
medicinal plant it's it's unbelievable
the attention it's getting so to be here
and to not be telling that story of some
major you know players down here I think
it would just be would just be silly so
that's what you can look forward to in
the future with homegirl TV some
beautiful shorts stories of amazing
tours of some beautiful facilities and
and uh some families that have been
living it for Generation to generation
that's really exciting I'm definitely
looking forward to seeing what you put
out on your channel in the future and
I'll definitely have a link to your
channel down in the YouTube description
section below if you are on YouTube
click that link and go to his channel
give him a subscription if you're on one
of the podcast platforms just search
from you'll find them home grow TV on
YouTube and he'll pop right up there for
you beautiful brother if you enjoyed
this episode click that Thumbs Up Button
also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already every single weekend I'm
releasing one of these new Garden Talk
podcast episodes and I would love for
you to tune in to future episodes Dakota
this was awesome man thanks for coming
on this was uh this is a really good
conversation about closet growing and I
definitely think it's going to be
valuable to a lot of people tuning into
this episode awesome dude thank you so
much again it's such an honor to be here
gives me goosebumps to see this
happening right now and to see you
through the screen hopefully we get to
meet one day in person at an event
somewhere in the states who knows where
but much love brother and thank you for
having me on thanks again all right
peace out everyone see you in the next
episode Peace