coming up on garden talk
you could
know nothing
when you started this podcast take that
three-letter acronym go watch my youtube
on it and make it in the next hour
and be applying it to your garden
successfully in
36 hours where it's not
as fine as a blender can make something
it's as fine as a microbe
eating it
and
passing it through its enzymatic process
and spitting out the raw materials or
the plant nutrients that's how fine it
is product when finished correctly is
better than anything you can buy on the
shelf for the cost of a potato and a few
grams of salt you're gonna have
something that's you know more than a
hundred dollars a gallon in value
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 67. in this
episode i interview chris trump many of
you know him from k f which are natural
farming techniques millions of people
have watched his natural farming videos
on youtube thousands have gone through
his in-depth courses and he's even
taught these techniques in several
countries across the world in this
episode we get into some of the natural
farming techniques that you can use in
your garden thanks to all of you support
this podcast through patreon if you'd
like to support you can do so by going
to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
thanks to spider farmer for being a
sponsor a new grow light they released
here in 2022 is the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co280 grow
space and really want to maximize the
light intensity it has a 10 bar design
for an even light spread pulls 1000
watts from the wall and comes in at 2.9
micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is four feet
by four feet or five feet by five feet
use discount code mr growth 5 to save on
all spider farmer products and i'll
leave a link in the video description
section below ac infinity is a sponsor
of the podcast coupon code mr growit
will get you a discount on their
products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
chris trump how you doing today
i'm doing great chris thanks for having
me
thanks for coming on today we're going
to talk all about knf so k f korean
natural farming there was actually a
couple people on my podcast in the past
that talked about a few of the k f
methods so i want to give a shout out to
them first greens goddess and also
bluegrass green thumb not sure if those
names are familiar to you or not but
both of them have actually mentioned
your name as who they learned it from
and they had suggested that i have you
on the podcast so here we are today
getting you on the podcast
and we'll talk about some various k f
methods
yeah i saw green scoutis in denver
uh last week i think um there was a
little meet up and um
yeah they're good people nice nice
well before we get too deep into the k f
methods let's do an introduction can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
kind of how you got into gardening yeah
yeah i um i was born on the big island
of hawaii and the um
i was born on a farm we were doing some
livestock as a kid and
and
my dad when i was pretty young got into
macadamia nuts
and then after college um
and some some work i
decided to go back to farming and uh
helped my family farm transition to
organic i learned natural farming in the
process as we needed a tool
that made more sense than traditional
organic but yeah i managed
our 750 acre
macadamia farm with my dad for about
eight years and uh then have been
involved since the last six years
my brothers now manage it and they're
doing a great job
um
yeah but i've since then have been i
managed a three acre farm in idaho for a
while and have
popped all around in
different places in the world and in the
country
working with farmers and
and
you know kind of teaching how to tend to
the microbial life the soil and partner
with nature so
pretty deep down that rabbit hole
somewhere along the line i think in
managing our farm and having to sort out
the details of
what we were doing in our process i
think i probably got a couple degrees in
microbiology just
continuing to learn and
so i've had the opportunity to um
advise uh
a doctorate thesis program in korea
congress university i still work with
them
um
i was asked to be on the research and
development board the international
macadamia society is the work on our
farm so i spoke in china a few times
over the last few years
up until 2020
to room full rooms full of scientists
and uh
yeah i think um
i think i've really come to have an
appreciation for the
need for uh systemic change and um the
part i get to blame at
i think a lot of my audience probably
knows you from your youtube channel you
know i'm looking at your channel right
now you've got over 40 000 subscribers
just on youtube alone i'm not sure what
other platforms you're on but uh
you know you're really one of the
pioneers when it comes to
bringing k f over to the states and kind
of bringing it to a wide audience i
guess we should say right i mean some of
these videos are back from like 2016
and if you click on one thing i just
want to point out is if you go to his
channel chris trump to search for it on
youtube playlists
there is 21 videos under a
chris trump how to korean natural
farming and this playlist alone i think
is
kind of really monumental to the move of
korean natural farming there's just so
much
detail on how to do these practices and
they're in a simplified form that's easy
to for a new grower to digest
so hats off to you on that one
you know your work is definitely noticed
by a large audience
and uh you know i'm definitely excited
to have you on today and and ready to
start getting into some of these
practices so people can make that
transition over from
you know bottled nutrients or even
organic over to some more natural
farming techniques such as the korean
natural farming techniques so cool well
appreciate you and and yeah 40 000 i
think just happened so
thanks to uh all you watchers
let's
start from the beginning and assume that
people don't really know what k f is
can you talk to us about what is k f and
why should gardeners implement gay and f
practices
yeah um
so
really it's only in the us that
we
add the word korean to it
um
and uh it's because of how we you know
came to know it um being master cho who
is the
uh creator of the uh current um practice
um he
um
his the full name is chohan hugh and um
cho being the last name on cubing his um
first name
and um
he's uh
um korean man um lives in uh outside of
seoul now with his son uh who is um
uh
and uh who's the creator of jadam
technology um just kind of little
background
this family has done a lot to
kind of open source share and so master
cho master kind of like sensei and
um if we were in
a
martial arts class you know masters
teacher and and uh you know um it's it's
a
title kind of like doctor and um
their work um
and then the freedom to kind of share
open source
um is really i think culturally the gift
in natural farming and something that i
feel like is an important
thing to continue and to pass on and
something i teach when i teach classes
like look how you've received this i'm
not there's no secret sauce being hidden
and held back there's not some you know
you have to
be you know fifth level to learn the
technology it's like here it's open and
freely shared and uh nothing held back
and and that's i think um
culturally something that um is really
important because
it's um i think it's part of the change
that's needed in the world you know is
that this isn't you know i'm sure some
people make a living
and um there's there's things to
sell and teach and whatever but
ultimately once you have that knowledge
nope there's no
uh copyright on it there's not a uh
you know clause or
anything and i think that's
um
a real
honor to have learned that way and to be
able to pass that on so i guess just a
little
footnote or stopping there for a minute
at that important detail that is in
natural farming um
the yeah it's it's practiced in
i think over 70 countries um that i know
of um and some of that history is uh
master cho traveling um and teaching he
got some political persecution um
following the korean war um because
there was such free sharing of
agricultural knowledge they marked him
as a communist and so there was a lot of
pressure and so he actually had to leave
the country for a while
under that pressure and went to india
and thailand and
and in those places it's just called
natural farming
and
and so i often refer to it as natural
farming
just because of that i've gotten to
travel a lot and experience those
communities and those different cultures
the japanese
natural farming community is amazing
a lot of great kind of innovation etc
and not a lot of it's in english sadly
but
natural farming is a
elegant method to partner with nature to
grow food
it's
i don't think the only way i think
there's a lot of traditional farming
technology that's incredible and you can
get to that same place
but the nice thing about natural farming
is it's this this beautiful package you
know you get this like box of technology
and the whole thing gives you everything
you need to really
be highly effective as a gardener to
produce your crop and so
um i think that's really
a special
aspect of what's
available in natural farming is just the
the kind of
you can master this one thing and it
really
one of the other things that it is is
it's a key
to understanding nature
not just
to be able to do
step by step a recipe but all of a
sudden you're like oh
that's how fermentation works and why
it's valuable and
i can use this to do that and i can
ad-lib this now that i've mastered that
i understand
and
so i think it's
it's a key to understanding natural law
i think as much as it's a farming
technique
and
yeah it's a series of recipes
the main one being this
imo process
where you take indigenous imo stance or
indigenous microorganism
um where you're you're taking a diverse
microbial community from a wild spot in
nature and re-establishing it in your
farmland and
that plus some of these nutrients you
can make in-house inexpensively
creates a wonderful tool for growing
food or medicine
i think there's a lot of folks in my
audience in particular that are bottled
nutrient growers right so there's
synthetic or mineral based nutrients
i myself was a bottled grower
you know for first six years and then i
transitioned over you know i learned
organic
gardening
whether it be an organic blend or
organic dry amendments and
now i'm kind of looking into the natural
farming approach so admittedly i haven't
yet started any
natural farming methods been learning
about it this year and i'm going to
actually start taking that leap so as we
continue to go on here know that i'm a
newbie when it comes to it a lot of
audience are newbies when it comes to it
but there are several benefits right i
mean going getting off the bottles you
can certainly save some money going into
the natural farming approach you can
save some time as well right you don't
have to mix up
nutrients each time you're ready to feed
you don't have to ph adjust the ph
adjust you know monitor the ppm
and also it's a more sustainable
approach to horticulture right compared
to
the bottles
i know one of the most common issues
around the world right now is the over
fertilization and the runoff of nitrogen
and phosphorus into our lakes and
streams causing toxic algae blooms
natural farming doesn't contribute to
that right so there's tons of benefits
out there for transitioning from either
bottles or even organic over to
a natural farming approach so i just
wanted to say that first before we kind
of move on one word that you mentioned
that i think is going to throw people
off a little bit is fermentation
so
fermentation we hear about fermentation
we know it's a anaerobic process and
generally speaking a lot of folks know
that anaerobic conditions can lead to
bad pathogens and pests particularly
like in your growing medium for example
however we're not talking about
anaerobic process within the medium
right we're talking about it within
other things
such as fpga ffj your your fermented
plant juice fermented proof juice etc
etc can you talk to us about like what
is fermentation and how you use it in
natural farming practices absolutely
yeah
that's a great question and you know my
my journey growing up on the farm
is much the same as yours
we were a conventional uh farm
so
bottled nutrients that came in a 40-foot
container and uh you know
just 30 30 30 fertilizer and roundup and
and even up until
when we really started transitioning to
natural farming we were a split
operation so 50 of the farm about
400 acres was um conventional still
roundup and
salt fertilizers and then 50
was was
organic and organic was struggling it
was not
nutrient-rich it wasn't productive
so i have much the same journey in my
farming experience and then to
transition to natural farming and see it
be
both cost effective and production
effective um was really cool
um and so
yeah fun to share that
um fermentation
is um
i think
i'll
i'll use
fish fertilizer as an example to kind of
explain the concept
so you can go to the store and buy
hydrolysate
and or fish emulsion and these are
processes
where they're taking out a
an oil
or a prime product from
fish um you know they're making fish oil
capsules or something and then the
leftovers they're
throwing through an industrial blender
and and pasta and cooking
down till they get a um
kind of homogenized liquid um that
on a microscopic scale
that is unprocessed
giant chunks of
fish flesh
if you look at it under a microscope as
far as a plant leave is concerned that
is undigested unprocessed
fish so you're just taking a fish paste
if you spray it on your plant and you're
smearing
a a
you know a
fish paste onto your leaf so now that
that fish that's been applied to the
leaf
has to go through a breakdown process
um where it's going to get washed off
the leaves going to fall on the ground
it's going to be
fermented digested in place in nature
through the microbes that are there and
then become plant available very little
of that is immediately plant available
until it goes to a digestive process
much like the digestion that occurs in
our stomach
nature and plant assimilation of
nutrients is very much the same as human
assimilation of nutrients and human
assimilation of nutrients
doesn't happen without microbes we don't
have blades in our guts
there's nothing
chopping up our food turning the adp and
atp it's microbial decomposition along
with ends of enzymatic
processes
that make our food
assimilatable we can digest it
the same thing happens in nature so
buying these bottled
fish nutrients they still have to go
through a breakdown process to become
plant available that doesn't mean that a
little bit's not available initially
but
that that breakdown does occur and so
um fermented uh our fish amino acid
which is the natural farming fish
fertilizer takes whole fish or fish cuts
and heads sorry if this is you know i'm
jumping into the the weirdest grossest
thing you know
right away but i think it'll help with
understanding
these this is something that if i just
take
you know blended blended fish and i
throw it on the surface
i get kind of um
[Music]
bacteria rises up and i get anaerobic
conditions happening
in the as that kind of break down and
putrifies
um
whereas in natural farming we take a
diverse fungal inoculum
imo
and we introduce it
with a balanced um
amount uh by weight of sugar and we put
the fish and the sugar and this imo
together and this very slow fermentation
occurs
it actually takes a year to be perfectly
done
where
the fungi actually breaks down and and
yanks apart these fatty acid chains and
so this material when it's finished
is completely assimilatable it's
completely
plant digestible
i saw foliar application in the root
zone it doesn't have to go through a
secondary
breakdown process for it to be usable
to the plant and we've pre-done that in
fermentation
um so um what occurs is something um and
this is an fpga and in this fermentation
process something called micronization
where it's not
as fine as a blender can make something
it's as fine as a microbe
eating it
and passing it through its enzymatic
process and spitting out the raw
materials or the plant nutrients that's
how fine it is and that's a that's a the
difference from a mac truck to a marble
on a microbiological or on a
micronization scale so
spraying
hydrolysate on your leaves you've
sprayed mac trucks those need to be
broken down to marbles so they can pass
through the cell walls
um in faa we've already gone down
through that micronization process and
so now it's the size of
marbles so to speak yeah so i hope that
kind of helps into why we mess around
with fermentation there's more to it but
that's
maybe a crash course speaking to the
that aerobic versus anaerobic aerobic is
what we want in our root zone absolutely
100 percent but
the
the reality is that anaerobic and
aerobic processes happen in root zones
all over the place you have a pocket of
nutrients in a forest leaves fall that
initial layer if the big wind storm
comes up leaves pile up in a corner a
bunch of the center of that becomes
anaerobic and that's how those nutrients
get processed down that pre-processing
then becomes ready food for the aerobic
microbes than to to go through and eat
and so it's really neat that it's
um it's a whole picture of nature and
not just there's good guys and bad guys
and everybody's coming to understand
that
that makes sense so
for the do folks what natural farming
practice do you suggest that gardeners
start with first you know i um there's a
best and i would say um in general
begin to learn and master the process of
making im04
and that is literally going to be i i
tell people it's going to be about a
year learning curve you're going to
spend about a year
learning how to do this
begin that journey so that you're not
starting a year from now on a year
learning journey
and and just trust that there'll be
failure it's like you're learning guitar
totally worth it and a ton of fun but a
learning journey
but
real easy entry easy to start um
master chose sun so that's best and
that's because we're in imo we're
producing this full
spectrum of beneficial microbial life
um
but master cho's son
you know learned this sat with farmers
and said oh this is too hard it's
challenging which i don't fully agree
with him i think it is
challenging but not too hard um
but he also
in his
approach to it decided he wanted to make
something easier and um he came up with
something called jms jadon microbial
solution and it takes potatoes
and a little bit of rice and some
microbes and that can brew out in 24 to
36 hours and a bucket in your kitchen
and
that
is full of yeast and beneficial bacteria
it doesn't have a ton of fungi in it
other than whatever just washes off your
initial material
but that is pretty low-hanging fruit as
far as
you could
know nothing
when you started this podcast
take that three-letter acronym
go watch my youtube on it and make it in
the next hour
and be applying it to your garden
successfully
in 36 hours with with no learning curve
so i would say that is a great way to
get and and i would say that product
when finished correctly is better than
anything you can buy on the shelf as far
as
bugs in a jug microbial solution so for
the cost of a potato and you know a few
grams of salt you're going to
you're going to have something that's
you know more than 100 a gallon in value
so yeah i would say jms is a great way
to condition your soil and um and get
those nutrients cycling
meanwhile learn that imo process and
then liquid imo can be made with an imo
2. that's probably an easy thing to jump
into too and that's something i
developed
and now um my teacher master cho teaches
when he teaches natural part
that's incredible let's get a little bit
deeper diamond you mentioned imo4 but i
know there's like imo one i am m2 so
qrikman from these are different stages
of imo you already kind of touch base on
what imo is indigenous microorganisms
but how do you how do you make it and
how do you use it absolutely so
in a untouched forest um you know a
thousand years of just
being left alone
um balance gets struck in nature um
the blacksmith moves to town the doctor
moves to town the grocer the farmer
the
you know transporter
all of these players have now struck a
you know balance think the wild west in
a small prairie town everybody needs to
be there and now you have the whole
picture of the community everybody doing
their part
and all necessary and all very different
in nature in an untouched area an
interior area that's healthy and diverse
those things those balances have
happened and what we can do
as farmers cultivating life
is we can go to these areas and um
harvest
that diverse
kind of uh
uh
capture it and bring it into our farming
systems
and um
one of the ways we do that is this i am
a one process
um where we
go out into the forest with some rice
and that rice has a high fat protein
profile so it's good fungal food it's
like an auger for fungi to grow on
and
and that
bloom now ideally has a
wonderful diversity
from nature and so
i just got the
great
gift of being able to submit samples a
bunch of my students submitted samples
to
a
dna
mapping lab where they mapped the dna of
a bunch of im04
and we had
some
200 species of fungi
and a single you know a handful of imo 4
and some
800 species of bacteria and yeast
and
you know just an incredible
uh array of diversity and so
just through this simple process like
you said that this stages so imo 1 is
rice in a forest imo 2 is the process of
causing that imo 1 to go dormant
which is important because we if we're
not using it right away we don't want it
to continue to
cycle down if you will and lose
diversity we want it to kind of stay as
a cryo freeze snapshot of the diversity
that we got that day one out of nature
and so we mix it with rice kind of like
you
put fish and salt for a long sea voyage
it keeps it from breaking down over time
so that imo2 is kind of the
stabilization of the imo1 im03 is taking
a small amount of that and causing it to
grow out
on a substrate we use rice bran and oats
are kind of the ideal substrate
along with wood chips and then some
nutrients like humic acid sea salt
um
fpj ohn brown rice vinegar so these
natural farming nutrients
it's it's kind of creating a party for
microbes to thrive in and grow
and then imo 4 we bring some of our
farms soil so if you're growing indoors
you could actually take some of your
potting soil and include that in the
grow out process
and you come up with incredible
incredible uh
final product by the time you get to the
fourth stage of imo uh
process you have a very
wonderful and diverse product that's um
it's never gonna shock your plants and
it moves right in and you
um it's it's like a giant engine you're
building kind of an engine and the
components are all these microbes and so
once you get it going now it's cycling
nutrients and uh you can you can take a
living soil garden bed and just top
dress it with kind of raw compost
and
and all that microbial life in there
just starts processing it and uh it's
like gas to the engine just keeps it
going
and you have very little effort needed
to feed your plants other than maybe
you've got a bokashi barrel where you
throw your food scraps in or you know
and and you just top dress your your
leftovers from your dinners and
breakfast you know and that's that's
your nutrients for your plants and the
reason that works and just doesn't
become a stinky mass
is because
there's this diverse microbial community
and then earthworms are are going to be
able to thrive there because they eat
those microbes um and
yeah it becomes a really
a living system like nature so you're
taking natural law
and and partnering with it using
the the building blocks of soil which
are really the builders are these
microbes and they are what cause soil to
be something other than
dirt
you know um
it becomes a
living ecosystem and um and so in the
natural farming process we can kind of
create and capture
that system and use it to our advantage
so imo for what's your general
recommendation for applica application
for medicinal plants for example yeah i
have a i have a short video called uh
applying a natural imo
application or something
um but it's um you you take this solid
material and you apply it at about 330
pounds per quarter acre or about a
gallon for 100 square feet so a 10 by 10
bed would have about a gallon it's a
very small amount it's think of it as
like cover crop seed
you know you're taking all these fungal
spores if you look at it under the
microscope it's full of just marbles
little fungal spores you throw it out on
your soil
with a little bit of moisture and it
wakes up and blooms and moves in and
multiplies and so it's really just an
inoculum it's a very high quality
inoculum like nothing you can buy
um and
yeah so yeah a small amount you could
top dress as much as an inch a solid
inch of this material and it wouldn't
hurt if you have more apply more yeah
it's it's great
another way to go about it is you take
that finished material you can store it
in like grandma cedar
chest you know that blanket chest or or
a little you know lunch box you make or
something at a theater and um and you
use a handful of that in a in a brew
for like a five gallon bucket
and uh you can you can cause it to bloom
in a water column and in the right
conditions and so
you can spray that foliarly i really
like that because
in nature we have
all these microbes actually live in the
sphyllosphere of a plant so
on the the leaves
if you look at it under a microscope
it's covered in fungi and bacteria and
yeast and that actually is its
protection we have the same thing going
on in our skin we exude
we
have you know salts and nutrients coming
out of our pores and there's lactic acid
bacteria and all these other microbes
that actually thrive on that materials
and live symbiotically in our skin and
we rely on them for protection from
disease and plants are the same way so i
like liquid imo for that purpose
liquid imo
for a lot of uh like
medicinal plants
um and even just general gardens we're
applying that at about uh once a week
foliarly um with great effect um
incredible um effect just by applying
that once a week gotcha another one that
you mentioned was lab lactic acid
bacteria i'd like to get into that next
um i did watch your video on that on
youtube so straightforward so easy to do
can you talk to us about lactic acid
bacteria you know what is it how do you
make it how do you use it etc yeah so um
lactic acid bacteria is this incredible
part of nature um in our systems we're
outnumbered about one trillion to one
for every human cell there's a a
trillion microbe cells in our bodies
so
um 70
of those are lactobacilli family
microbes and so our gut is mostly
lactobacilli family microbes
and
without those we don't do very well
we we desperately need uh lactose lactic
acid bacteria to um
to process our nutrients they're they're
like a trash collector or digester
they're um
they're a
facultative anaerobe so they thrive in
both anaerobic and aerobic conditions
they're a very important um
absolutely vital part of nature
you die all human life ceases without
lack of stimuli family microbes
um
we we have names for the medical
conditions when you get those that
diversity knocked out in your gut
and it's interesting we have a um a
medical process called uh
fmt
fecal microbiota transplant
and where if somebody's gut biome gets
knocked out through
you know
extenuating circumstances or
antibiotics or something like that we
actually take the healthy gut biome of a
healthy person
freeze dry it put in capsules and and
give it as an uh a
digestible pill or suppository to the
unhealthy person
re-establishes diversity and now they
can digest their food again
i met in china i met the guy who came up
with fmt and he was tickled pink because
i actually incorporated it in my uh
my speech
to the um my peers and macadamia nuts
and uh you know so room full of 500
people and he's just like i can't
believe you brought it into agriculture
i love that um
but lactic acid bacteria is good for
human health and plant health
and um it can be you know a lot of
people
um really kind of things i heard on the
internet they take
um
lab and it's like the one thing they
take away from the natural farming
process
and i would say that's kind of like
taking five percent
of the story and running with it but you
know that's okay you know some people
have great success and they report all
kinds of wonderful things just by using
that
but it is a small part of it in imo
production so in the whole imo 4 process
you have all the ilab you'll ever need
it's it's abundant so if you're making
liquid imo chocked full of led
and so you don't really need to do
the lab kind of process but
what i use lab for
even though i'm farming with imo is i
make it and i have it in the fridge and
i consume it regularly for people with
gi gastrointestinal issues it's
massively helpful
for
you know
skin or topical health or kind of
subtopical health people
can
take it
apply it to their skin
and get a
huge relief from stuff like yeast
infections and you know um
dr hoon park who's
a
peer of mine and a good friend and
somebody that really helped bring
natural farming to
the u.s
has crohn's disease and he's been
asymptomatic for over 10 years because
he takes an ounce of lab in his water
with every meal and so he as a
medical doctor
when people come in with gi issues he
just gives them a sheet on how to make
lab and says go and drink this with your
meals and people are
and so i've had friends cry because they
ate food that they couldn't eat for the
first time without getting stomach you
know violent stomach cramps because
they're inoculating their
their food pre-inoculating it with a sip
of lab that actually is the mature the
very thing necessary to digest their
food
and um so just yeah an incredible
part of nature something that we all
rely on but don't really know and
natural farming gives a very simple
recipe on how to make it
that's fascinating yeah and just to
reiterate for those wanting step-by-step
instructions on how to do lab i mean
we're kind of briefly talking about it
here i'll definitely have a link to
chris's youtube channel down in the
description section below or if you're
listening to one of the podcast
platforms just search for his name chris
trump and you can see the playlist and
you can see how he makes lab one of the
things that i noticed is that you really
don't need gloves or anything to
do this right you you'll see that
there'll be a separation process that
happens you can actually use the i guess
cheese curds or something like that you
can use that for a different process and
then the remaining liquid that you
strained
is your lab and like you mentioned you
can actually just drink that so
that's going to be probably one of the
first things i make it seemed like it
was pretty easy to make but like you
mentioned it's a very very small percent
so i'm definitely not gonna stop there
when it comes to it you know i i tell
people that natural farming isn't
something new it's not like
we're we're teaching
some new technology that we just
discovered um it's something that you
know a hundred years ago a lot of these
things were were well known kind of
tools
for every household you know how to make
cheese for example and consume it you
know it was
something that was a basic
food preservation if you had milk
because you didn't have refrigeration so
a lot of this is things that when we had
this kind of influx of chemical
agriculture we just said oh grandpa's
knowledge
2 000 years of agricultural tradition
we don't need that anymore we have 30 30
30 fertilizer and so
what a lot of natural farming is um it's
new in that it's the the package is this
elegant thing and and master cho
you know if you hear stories some things
came to him in dreams and there are bits
and pieces that are definitely new
but the the general concept of
kind of using um
natural law to grow food but also to
consume food um
it's it's things we used to know and uh
have forgotten and so just coming back
to um you know working with life i think
it's important let's get into fpga and
ffj so fermented plant juice and
fermented fruit juice and greens goddess
was one of the ones that had talked
about this on a previous podcast
and she broke it down in a simple sense
to where you can use like f pj
for the veg stage in ffj for the
flower stage or vice versa i can't
remember which one was which but uh
those seem to be very important aspects
of natural farming can you talk to us
about what fpga and ffj are you know how
to make them and kind of how to apply
them in your garden
sure
yeah and um
because i think a lot of online
joe and jim and
susie and john talking about natural
farming uh fbj gets this kind of high
platform
because it's so easy to make and because
it is a plant food
or nude plant nutrient um
it's kind of gotten a little bit more um
play in the online space
than we give it in natural farming
technology
so i do want to kind of
nod towards that that
fpga
ohn
all this plant nutrient
processes
where you're spraying on nutrients
they are the twenty percent of natural
farming the eighty percent being imo
um and the microbes that you would get
in the soil so this jms technology
talking about so just kind of a quick
nod to that um
ffj fermented fruit juice
is
the um
getting wild fruit
so
i think to talk about
in this space fpj and ffj i think i need
to talk about the things that i heard on
the internet the misnomers real quick
because there's so much of it and
it's i have a friend that learned fpj
and
she applied
the fpj as a plant nutrient to her house
plant just dumped it on the soil and
just
on the edge of killing her house plant
initially
and quickly she made an aloe fpj
um and applied it straight to the roots
um
at a
very low dilution rate you know kind of
a lot of it and um
got spotting on the leaves and disease
and the plant hasn't recovered
2-3 months later
a lot of people are saying oh i can make
this plant nutrient and then they're
just running with that it's like oh i
have the answer to
growing without bottled nutrients i'm
just going to dump a bunch of fpj on
things sorry i'm i'm getting into this
but it's so common i get these like oh i
did this it didn't work for me it's like
who told you to do that oh well this
website you know and um
so
ffj is a very narrow
um kind of use where you can apply it in
flowering but kind of towards the end or
not not abundantly you can still use
fpga
in that flowering stage um
what fpga is is think of it as a as a
very high-end boutique liquid compost
so you have this basically
liquid nutrient that you're able to make
it's like making compost the breakdown
of compost you get that those raw
materials and you can put them on plants
and plants love it fpgas like this
like caviar of
compost and liquid form
but one of the things um and and so what
it is is it's going out and finding a
weed
um or a plant that's green all the time
the bugs leave it alone
it it grows really quickly it grows
um it's robust or grows vigorously
it's full of beneficial biochemicals
that cause it to be so strong
it's also for whatever reason has
figured out how to
take nutrients from the soil very
effectively so that it's not
struggling to be nutrient dense
it thrives in your area it's going to be
different in hawaii than it is in
michigan or in uh in colorado or idaho
you know it's
each place is going to have its own
plan and and what you need to do to
really make fpj is go out
and change your vision
everybody's got these blinders on these
these glasses that cause you not to see
the weeds that you've seen your entire
life and just come to ignore
you know you look at oh the pretty
flowers and you don't see the
um maybe if you're in california by the
coast it's ice plant you don't see the
ice plant
or the
um
uh ivy or the
lamb's quarter or the um amaranth or
you know all these things that are weeds
and we're annoyed when they show up in
our yard dandelions
but really that stuff is so vigorous so
strong and if we harvest it and make
plant food out of it we actually get the
benefit of its abundant strength
as a plant nutrient and it's nearly free
just a little bit of sugar so free weeds
and a little bit of sugar becomes
um one of the best nutrients you can buy
or apply to your plant and
the process is pretty easy to do
um one of the things you don't want to
do is you don't want to go to the
grocery store and buy a bunch of fruit
and
make it into
stuff
there are some
people teaching that on the internet and
um you know
if it works for you it works for you you
can you can mess around with the
the uh
the
the changes people have made and i don't
think there's anything wrong with that
because it's still
a nod of natural law it's still using
some of this technology but if you think
about it
in a forest canopy or in grassland
the the weeds lay down they die off they
get digested they become plant food and
we're just doing that kind of digestion
process and using it as plant food
that's a simple way to put it i know
you're somewhat strapped on time here so
i'll just hit you with a few more
questions and then we'll wrap things up
i do want to go over water-soluble
calcium so wca can you talk to us about
that yeah it's it's uh wca is a great
tool for bringing calcium into your
growing system
you're using a calcium-rich material so
egg shells
or coral sand i like coral sand because
you don't have to cook it or oyster
shells if you use eggshells or oyster
shells those were living things that
have organic bonds and we have to trash
those organic bonds to use it to get the
calcium out of it so the cooking process
destroys those organic bonds so that we
can do a chemical reaction um and so the
chemical reaction is a high calcium or
basic material reacting with a vinegar
or acidic material we combine those and
it causes the basic or alkaline material
to react with the acidic material and
causes it to go into solution which
again micronizes it and makes it so the
plant can receive it through its cuticle
can receive it through its cell wall on
its leaves or is really easy to digest
in the soil so it's just um there's a
video on it super simple to do
and
it's a
low cost way to get a very high quality
calcium what we produce is called
calcium acetate and it's not something
you can readily buy at the store
that's partially because it's not a
patentable process it's a very simple
diy possible process
but it's also a very high quality
nutrient for your plant so yeah wca is
easy use it all the time
and uh don't be afraid of giving it a
try what's the shelf life on that um if
you make it properly it lasts years um
so like uh improper would be if you
undercook the eggs
um you have some of that organic
material will get in there kind of the
protein in the in the in the shell eggs
wall cell walls
that organic material will putrefy and
rot over time and you it'll start to
sting so it's about the quality that you
make it with if you don't take the
membrane if you don't kind of winnow off
the membrane on the inside of the
eggshells or
or pull off the membrane before you cook
it if you leave that membrane in there
it's an organic material it'll degrade
the shelf life and so um that's a
variable depending on the quality of
your process so if i make it a couple
years if a newbie makes it and screws up
maybe six months and then what would the
recommended application rate be for for
that generally we use that at one to a
thousand uh so much of this these
natural farming um
uh nutrients are used at almost
homeopathic amounts and it seems like um
it's too little like more is more and
people start applying extra
um it's not that way in natural farming
do it the way it's talked about um
so like
um
we were gonna talk i don't know if we
have time but we were gonna talk about
maintenance solution and maintenance
solution like if you're going to do one
thing applied to your plants do
maintenance solutions
on my website i should have in the next
month or so i should have my ohn and
available again i have it there because
it takes three months to make and people
you know hear about natural farming they
want to get started right away so i make
that available so they don't have that
three-month wait time
also gonna have faa which takes about a
year to make
and i haven't offered that in the past
but
again these things that are kind of
barriers to entry is part of the reason
for offering those
on my website but the
maintenance solution is fbj
oriental herbal nutrient which is like a
prebiotic
it's kind of plant health and then brown
rice vinegar and
those that small amount of nutrients
applied weekly can be all you need as
far as a foliar nutrient if you're
applying like a liquid imo or a solid
imo and feeding it with some
bokashi or compost or food scraps and
then applied maintenance solution that
can be your entire growing protocol
right there like nothing else going and
it becomes cathartic simple you can
spray yourself with maintenance solution
a little in your mouth
and it's this really
wonderful natural process but we're
using one to 500
fermented plant juice and so ratios real
quick i'm going to jump into this you
didn't ask me but i talk about ratios in
youtube it's a math problem
one to a thousand means if you have a
thousand water
what's one one thousandth of that
it's a division problem one one thousand
is the amount of nutrient you put in
that 1000 water so if i have
a liter
then i put 1 ml that's 1 1000 of a liter
right so if i'm spraying out a liter in
my little liter spray bottle on my two
plants or my little you know garden box
then i need 1 ml of ohn 1 to 500 would
be 2 ml of fpj
and then 1 to 500 vinegar would be 2 ml
of vinegar into my one liter spray
bottle and it's so little you know
you're like how can this like
20 drops of this thing do anything but
watch the plants react the plants get
shiny and green up and uh yeah sounds
like it's a very easy process once you
just learn the basics and put in the
practice yourself so what advice do you
have for those growers transitioning to
k f
enjoy the process you know the the
learning the learning journey is and can
be so fun
and um
you know instead of it being
the um
this
you know rigorous recipe of
you know how much
pink and green stuff you're applying and
salt fertilizer
it can be this learning journey and
it can affect kind of whole health human
health
also failure is a good teacher don't be
afraid of the failures um they will just
make you better at it um try and fail on
a small scale you know if you're trying
something new maybe don't try it on
everything right off
and really take a class if you get the
opportunity to come to an in-person
class um
it's i've i teach online i have an
online class
and i believe much more in an in-person
class because
taste touch smell matters or
hang out if there's somebody that's come
to a class that's around you you know of
somebody go hang out with them offer to
buy them lunch if they'll like do some
natural farming with you
because that little bit of nuance that
taste touch smell can really help you
kind of jump start your process i think
that's some really good advice
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future
yeah um
i have done um some podcasts obviously
uh something that i i jump on to so um
different places
had some of these conversations
always different
but i have a youtube channel you just
search chris trump i have a website it's
just christrump.com
and on my website i do have courses the
online course is a bunch of video time
it gets so much deeper into all the
details um i am updating that this year
with
about double the content
um so hopefully that happens this month
i've been
chipping away at it um
and that that will always be updated um
uh just added to over time um and then i
do in-person classes i have one in
ireland in june and then i have one in
cape cod
in october september late september and
then one in tennessee in september so
kind of east coast is getting the love
this year
as far as
in-person classes but come on out it's a
ton of fun the community aspect kind of
you taking a class with people that then
you're staying in contact and and the
growing community of natural farmers is
probably the best part i mean that's
that's invaluable it'll feel like a
vacation
um but yeah that's that's kind of what
i'm up to and um
you know i'm on instagram at soilsteward
and um
and then natural farming co
um facebook page so those are some of
the places i hang out and i love to
answer questions as i can just be
patient with me sweet well i definitely
have a link to your channel down in the
description section below so you guys
can head on over there and check out
what he has for content we just
scratched the surface today we did very
little when it comes to natural farming
as far as talking about it uh we could
sit here and talk for hours and hours
and hours and go for more and more
processes let's let's do it again
sometime
i was just about to say that i have a
feeling that the audience is going to
demand a part two and so we can continue
on talking about some of these things i
mean we can get into o h we can get into
deeper into the maintenance solution
faa ses so there is a lot more that we
can certainly talk about in a future
episode and yeah i'd love to have you on
in the future for sure
yeah and maybe uh maybe we get uh some
questions from your audience from this
one and we can answer some of those
absolutely so be sure to leave any
questions you have down in the comments
section below
and we'll leave it at that chris thank
you so much for coming on to the podcast
today this was a pleasure
and hope you enjoy the rest of your day
thanks man yeah it was a pleasure and
and uh good talking with all you guys
peace out everyone