coming up on garden talk but if you
start throwing things into the mix and
just kind of chucking pollen around and
kind of getting away from the grand
vision of what you actually enjoy and
want to keep carrying on that's when
you're going to run into problems the
purple thing is something that you
wanted
then yes that's something that i would
try to take into consideration when i
was looking for a male but what a lot of
people don't know is that pollen can be
extremely volatile and
it can become infertile very quickly
you're going to get a mix of your two
favorites you've now collided them
together and you're gonna get
potentially the best of both worlds i'm
looking for things like fast flowering
time resistance to white powdered mildew
how well they can handle the cold also
how well they can handle the heat
because it's still gonna get hot here
too if you can't eat the vegetable or
whatever it is at the end because it's
all filled with bugs or the plant was
diseased and didn't finish it then it
basically isn't any good anyway
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 53. in this
episode i interview canadian leaf
genetics he's been gardening for 12
years and he's been breeding for five
years in this episode he talks about
getting started with breeding he also
talks about stabilizing a cultivar
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com mr growit before we get into
it i want to acknowledge that one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring zero
costs for information about gardening
all plants to the general public that
being said i'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that call possible
big shout out to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast ac infiniti is
well known to produce high quality
products and provide excellent customer
service they have the thickest grow tent
on the market today
inline fans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
growit during checkout for a discount on
their products a big supporter of this
podcast is dutch pro they sponsor this
podcast and i use their nutrients i have
been using their base nutrients
formulated specifically for auro and
soft water i also have been using some
of their additives like calmag silica
and their root stimulator called take
root they have a few other additives on
top of those and ph regulators coupon
code mr growit10dp will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their amazon store down
in the description section below
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
graham but some of you may know him as
canadian leaf genetics how you doing
today
good man good
things are going well over here um
obviously by the name i'm up in canada
so i was doing a little bit of shoveling
earlier on uh but other than that it's
been a chill day just uh yeah show one
so i could get my groceries and now i'm
here hanging out with chris which is
always awesome so
nice good day awesome well i'm glad to
have you on board today
uh we are gonna talk about plant
breeding so kind of getting started
plant breeding i feel like there's a lot
of people out there who are
interested in haven't taken that step
yet in order to do it or they've just
started doing it
and they kind of need some more
information on which way to go because
there are i feel like there are several
different ways you can go when it comes
to breeding there are several different
techniques and ways you can stabilize
strains and so on and so forth so also
stabilizing a cultivar is kind of what
we'll get into today as well as as we go
along here so
but first how about an introduction want
to tell us a little bit about yourself
and kind of how you got into gardening
and breeding
all right so uh
i got into
uh gardening and breeding probably from
you know my mother at a very early age
she was uh licensed by health canada she
provided medicine for people who who uh
couldn't grow it themselves so that's
how i initially got into growing
um and and learning about
all kinds of plants was just because my
mother had like a very uh
you know sort of
self-driven kind of take on life where
she wanted to be able to supply her own
um
own whether it be food or
uh
food or medicine or drink or whatever it
was so
that was how i i originally got into
gardening and then that sort of picked
up into
wanting to be able to share
some of the things that she did back in
the early days with other people which
is what led into canadian leap genetics
um
yeah so that's kind of how i've gotten
to where i am today this mostly goes a
lot to my parents my dad was involved a
little bit too but mostly to my mom
yeah she really brought that the the
green thumb out of me and uh
brought me to this sort of breeding
point where i am today where i wanted to
bring that back and share with people so
that they could have success
growing uh different cultivars in canada
because as the as you know it's kind of
hard up here
if you're trying to grow and complete a
season
um
you know
regardless of whatever plan it is you're
growing you might run into the same
issues so you mentioned before we
started recording that you have been
breeding for about five years now how
many different cultivars have you
created so far
um so i think on the website i've got
probably
six specific different cultivars on
there that i would say
are
are completely stabilized and that if if
you get them
it's going to grow exactly what it's
supposed to grow
in regards to what i had intended for it
to do
yeah i think there's six on there i'd
have to double check but pretty sure if
i recall
and
i'm working on another one right now so
it'll be about seven
again it takes a long time to actually
get them
to the point
to a point where something is stabilized
so i was lucky having things
um that were
that were you know in
initially were sort of just being paul
and chucked around from my mother but
that would be going back like into the
early years and then i've brought it
kind of back in the last five years and
sort of fine-tuned the each one of those
into becoming those six that are on the
website
okay gotcha
so when somebody decides to start
breeding right what are the first steps
i mean are they to identify
two different cultivars that they want
to cross or what are the first steps
here
absolutely so the first things you're
going to want to do is you're going to
find
like your two
well
it your two favorite plants whether
each each cultivar might be different
too like maybe you get
your favorite is in the female side or
your favorites in the male side but try
to have them both be your favorite and
you're going to have to grow regular
seeds in order for this to happen you're
not going to be able to grow
unless you you want to use a female
that's been grown from a feminized seed
so then you'd be able to utilize your
favorite female or something like that
as long as you know that that's
that's a pretty stable strain you could
probably use that as a good base
starting point
as long as it's one of your favorites
and then you're going to need regular
seeds in order to get your mail
so that's when you're going to make sure
that that's also one of your favorite
things too because if you start
combining
something that's not your favorite into
there or doing something that's not
going to work in your climate whether it
be
something that takes has a longer
growing period or isn't as resistant to
cold or things like that
and you add that into the mix on top of
even that nice maybe feminized female
seed that is your favorite
you're you're going to be sad so you're
always going to want to make sure that
everything you choose at the beginning
is your favorite and then everything
whatever whatever works for you and it
works make sure that you're choosing
that and each time jeez man um
and and you're going to have an okay
start you know but if you start throwing
things into the mix and just kind of
chucking pollen around and
and not really
and kind of getting away from the grand
vision of what you actually enjoy and
want to want to keep carrying on
that's when you're going to run into
problems so if you're just getting
started choose things that are your
favorite
and
and make sure you continue to choose
those each time you breed but you're
going to start with two that are your
favorite
and and make sure that counts for the
mail too don't just chuck a pollen in
there just to create seeds
okay
i couldn't help but laugh your your cat
jumped up on your lap
i've got a cat on my lap too so it's
like pick up these cats that are laptops
anyways so the question i had actually
for that is
is it better to start with stable
genetics to begin with right so like say
somebody finds their prize pheno like
female but it's an f2 where f2s you know
we actually did a another episode where
we talk about what f1 is rf2 is they're
basically just different generations
generally speaking the further you go
down the more stable you kind of are
except for f2 it kind of opens up the
gene pool a little bit see more
characteristics so f2 is one of the
bigger ones as far as like the
characteristics you can potentially get
right so if you start with an f2
is that going to be less you know not as
ideal compared to if you're starting
with like an f4 and f5 something that's
more stable
well i guess it would depend on
what trade it was that you were looking
for and how important it was for you to
have that specific trait carried on over
because regardless of what you breed it
with
unless you're breeding like fellio which
is like breeding within
the actual like lines of like the family
genetics like breeding kind of like
brother and sister together um
as soon as you get outside of that
you're kind of starting all over again
so in some regard like i don't know if
that makes sense it does it does yeah
get a little bit too confusing but um
you know like
if you were to breed outside of the
family lines again yeah you're just
going to kind of start back over and
you've now created another f1 again
but it would assuming that the male is
outside but the um
it's always important to start with
stable genetics
uh regardless so
yes for the first one you always want to
start make sure you're using stable
genetics and not
again not kind of just chucking pollen
around and and making
things work like make sure both plants
are
are good
and and suit
what you want to see further on down the
line
while you do your fallen breathing to
kind of uh
um
really
pull out those traits and and solidify
them okay so what is meant by stable
genetics like in terms of a particular
stable genetics like when it only it
does exactly what you want it to so it's
it's if i wanted the plant to be purple
and grow
uh
one foot tall each time and have a
specific sort of flowering thing
um
and and a specific terpene profile and
uh things like that that would be a
stable genetic assuming that it did that
100 or very close to 100 of the time
um
you know i would say that it's pretty
stable if it's getting like 90 of the
time it's cool if you get a funny one in
there that still represents the plant in
the same way
like the genetics are supposed to but
maybe slightly different
but yeah stable genetics should be
something that's 100
or very close to 100 percent and
replicates the same thing almost like a
clone
okay so they have their two cultivars
right
they got their two cultivars that they
want to cross okay
let's say for the for this example you
have the male and the female of two
different different cultivars right yes
yep two different cultivars you want to
cross now oftentimes they're going to
first pheno hunt right so maybe they're
planting a batch of seeds you know 10
pack 20 pack whatever the amount of
seeds they're gonna plant then they're
hunting through looking for those traits
from that cultivar that they want to
then pass on to the kind of this new
hybrid right this because you have two
different cultivars that you're crossing
the end result would be a hybrid what do
you look for
in female plants we'll start with that
kind of what are the characteristics
that you're looking for in order to kind
of see if that's something a keeper that
you want to breed with i know it's
subjective it goes by breeder debris
there so for you what would you say you
kind of look for in female plants
um right so for me specifically again
this is something that would come back
to
uh whether or not that's some
that particular cultivar is stable or
not
right too when you're looking in it
because you'll be able to see like oh
all my all of it's looking
the same this obviously i'm working with
something that's good and if i
put this with with another stable
something else it's going to
they're going to combine and i'm going
to have to work with that in the future
and and hopefully both of them are good
so
when it's me looking for it in
particular and i'm working with genetics
that need to be resistant to frost
they've usually got i need them to
finish
probably at least by october 1st so
you're looking at a shorter growing
period than you than most people would
have
so i'm looking for things like fast
flowering time
um i'm looking for things like
resistance to white powdered mildew
how they how well they can handle the
cold also how well they can handle the
heat because it's still going to get hot
here too
so
those are some things i can replicate
but also a lot of that comes with
testing them outside as well
so both things have to happen and that's
also a way that you're going to find
whether or not your genetics are stable
and working environments if you get a
similar result growing inside and
outside
but those are some of the things that i
look for is
definitely a
short flowering time
resistance to cold white powdered mildew
resistance to insects
and then
after that
i look at
potency and things like
uh terpene profile and everything else
because if you can't eat the vegetable
or whatever it is at the end because
it's
it's all filled with bugs or the plant
was diseased and didn't finish it then
it's it's
it basically isn't any good anyway so
um
yeah all of those things come second to
me
but they still have to be top of the
line
so when you're growing out the females
are you cloning them prior to flipping
the flower and then grow completing the
female grow you have your clones on the
side and then you're you're picking one
and then you're you know keeping that
clone that you had or are you
growing them out then monster cropping
to bring it back into the veg stage
so i actually do neither of those things
i actually when i'm doing my breeding i
breed falil and i breed i'll put two of
them together two of my favorites and
then i'll work through those lines to
um
to create the stable genetics i don't
usually ever do any cloning or monster
cropping or things like that not because
i'm against it for any reason but i like
to start from each seed because i want
to make sure that each seed is
when it going to be the same whenever
somebody else grows it so i need to test
the stability that way but in terms of
breeding as well
yeah i always take
i always start from a seed and grow it
and make sure it
it
fits all the categories that i want it
to
and then i'll also grow my mail and i'll
have this growing at the same time so
that i can determine
um flowering times and things like that
between both of them both male and
female
so that i can see if that they're doing
the same things that i want so that
whenever
i breed those together it's going to
result in something similar down the
line as well as
combining traits together
that might be different but also work
together
so as the females are growing you're
actually you have a male growing
alongside and you're pollinating them
correct during that grow okay and then
you're growing them all out you're
smoking them and then you're picking
your your keeper from there and then
those you'll have seeds already
available for your keeper right
correct okay that makes sense yeah and
generally like when i'm
like
when you're starting with a stable
genetics usually you've already grown a
few
to to know that you that's something you
enjoy right like that's the main thing
you want to do before you even before
anybody ever decides like oh i'm going
to breed this one and i'm going to breed
this one
if you haven't even
grown it before
you you shouldn't even do it at all
because you need to do that first so
grow a bunch first and then find out
that you know that okay in this in this
cultivar in this
particular one i it has things that i
like so
you can go ahead and grow that because
when
if this is going to lead into probably
something we're going to talk about
later i'm sure in this video chris which
is when is a good time to
pollinate your female plant and when is
a good time to harvest your seeds
afterwards and how to get the best
result in that um
but yeah so that's that's part of the
reason why i do it that way too so that
they're at a particular stage of growth
both of them so that i can visually see
how the male is growing and and how the
female is growing
and usually i know how this plant works
and and in this particular cultivar
which you all should know if you're
going to get into this because you're
going to want to try to grow it to make
sure that it's what you want to do
before you start
because you're not going to be able to
smoke whenever you breed it is is what
we're going to get into talking about
later on pretty much
so you're going to waste the whole time
a whole plant
and two plants in fact depending on how
you do it because you're not going to be
able to smoke the pollinated female
because there's going to be way too much
seed depending on how you do it
gotcha
okay so flipping over to the male plants
side of things right so
like you mentioned that you're you're
you're combining the two i'm assuming
you're planting them all at once right
you're planting all these seeds you're
gonna you're gonna have your males and
you're gonna have your females
what do you look for in male plants for
selection
so
in male plants is much the same but it's
harder to
this is again where you're
you're kind of you're not guessing but
you're going to have a little bit of a
less
chance to determine for example like
terpene profile or
um
potency obviously or um
you know
uh flowering time you can tell like
those are those are that's the kind of
difference i mean because you can you
can watch the plant grow obviously but
you're not gonna be able to smoke it
you're not really it's not gonna have
the same smell that you're going to get
from a female that's produced the resin
and
anyways
you get you guys get where i'm going
with this so
um
what i look for when i'm doing it is
still the same way the flowering
structure is how close those node
spacing is together like if this is your
this is your plant right and each
knuckle is
where a new flower is going to begin
like how small is that space am i going
to get
tight branching flowers or am i going to
get flowers that are spaced far apart am
i going to get a different kind of
growth structure
is it going to be a bush is it going to
be
extra extra tall
or things like that and generally male
plants are usually more tall than female
because they're usually towering over
the plant and they want to spread their
pollen
down onto the plants so generally
males are almost always bigger but
that's not always sometimes not always
the case as well
so
you got to take that those sort of
things into consideration but those are
things i look for growth structure
flower spacing um
you know you can rub the stalk and get a
smell that way
and then the last thing would be just
like actual flowering time like how
quick does it take it
to start producing pollen and for those
pollen sacks to actually open up
because a lot of people don't know that
like you could have
a male well into flower and have all
kinds of pollen sacs but it's not
actually
it's hard to explain unless you've done
it before
but i'm sure that maybe maybe you've
seen it chris maybe other people have
seen it there too but it takes a long
time for those pollen sacks actually
open
for for though that pollen to be spread
around so you could have a male
you know
clearly it's a male for two three weeks
before you're into trouble
um
yeah
so those are things i look for growth
structure flowering time
and and flower node spacing when it
starts to produce those flower socks
because that's going to tell you how
that's going to translate into
your females flower spacing as well as
color obviously if it's got purple
leaves or it's got a purple stalk or
things like that okay
so i'm actually working on across i've
been using the brisker gmail with the
pakistan valley female
and you know one of the things that i'm
growing out the the f2s i grew in f2
recently it was a little more
stretchier than i wanted it to be a
little bit more right the bud stacking
wasn't as close together uh that i
wanted to be the you know internodal
spacing and things like that so yeah
that'd be the other term for yeah
talking about their like flowers and
whatever but so i'm i'm
so what i should probably look for and
give me guidance otherwise if you think
otherwise
is you know for males if i'm looking for
maybe the shorter males faster flowering
if i'm looking for you know just kind of
speed up the flowering so i can look for
that stem rub i've done stem rubs before
and kind of making sure that i get what
i want there lemony type smell is kind
of what i've chosen so far on it so i
want to make sure that's repeatable each
stem is going to have a different smell
but again you're
not going to get a huge variance but
it's going to be kind of specific to the
cultivar you're working with so if you
kind of know you're going to have an
idea right and should for males for
males should i also be looking at like
frost production on it or like coloring
at all like some i've had some males
that have you know the pollen sacks have
actually turned a little bit of purple
like purple in it are those things that
could potentially get passed on i know
we're going to get into dominant versus
recessive here in a minute or so you
know all those things can be passed on
absolutely all those things could get
passed on and uh yeah that's something
that i think is very cool is that the
dominant and recessive trade and the
talks about that and i'm sure there's a
lot of other people that have far more
knowledge on it than i do
um but it's something that i think is
very cool and is different
probably depending on which which plants
you're looking at as
as a whole as as just plants in an
entire species but
yeah is that is that purple that you
experienced in the flower going to get
passed on to
to the female
as
a dominant trait is it going to become
that all the time if you picked that
male for whatever reason or is that
are only going to show up sometimes is
going to be a recessive trait that's
sort of
locked into the gene pool but hidden so
you'll have to sort of look for it
throughout it um i don't know
so again i would assume that if that if
the purple thing is something that you
wanted
then yes that's something that i would
try to take into consideration when i
was looking for a male
um
recently i've been trying to do this
thing where i pulled on
like purple colors like per it has a
purple stock which is kind of unusual
and i wanted to pull that over and i was
having trouble and it seems that it only
shows up a certain time so you have to
be careful with that and i'm pretty sure
having a purple stock is a recessive
trait as where a purple leaf
it seems as soon as you breed a plant
that's got purple leaves with another
plant that's green the offspring all
seem to have
purple colorings of some sort
um
but not a purple stalk
so that's something i was trying to look
into and i'm not sure exactly how that
would
in your situation work with the purple
purple male you'd have to
try ultimately and if it was something
that you wanted to avoid then i would
not try
basically what it comes down to because
you don't want to add that into the gene
pool regardless of whether or not it's
dominant or recessive
because it means it could start showing
up in the future okay so after you've
selected your male and female let's talk
about the pollination process i know
you're outdoors you mentioned uh you're
referenced outdoors and how you're kind
of putting them together in the same
area do you have any tips for the
pollination process outdoors and then
indoors
i know there's people who like collect
pollen and then they'll pollinate at a
later date is there a certain day in
flowering where you feel it's kind of
best to pollinate in order to maximize
the yield of seeds that are created
okay so this is one of those things
where i'm testing the cultivars outside
to make sure that they're doing what i
want them to do and that's part of the
way that i test to make sure that
they're kind of the stable genetics or
whatever um but most of my breeding
happens inside so that i can make sure
that exactly what i want to get bred is
being bred and i don't have to worry
about again having pawn chucked around
or anything weird like that happening
i know exactly
which male is is mating with which
female because i know exactly which one
is pollinating the other one i know that
i don't have to really generally worry
about
cross-pollination or things like that
because i'm doing it in an enclosed
environment in a specific area
and if you've worked with pollen before
you know that
it it's quite easy to
breed them together each calyx each
each little hair on
on the plant can receive pollen from the
male and that will become your seed
and it's easy for that transfer to
happen but what a lot of people don't
know is that pollen can be extremely
volatile and it can become infertile
very quickly
so
generally what i like to do is i just
like to again this helps if you're
growing them side by side
and it helps if you're
got them in an enclosed area and you
only have the pair in there because
generally i'll grow them out and i'll
choose specifically which ones show the
traits the best that i want they might
all show the traits but i want the ones
specifically that show it the best
and that's what i'll put in my enclosed
area
when i go to pollinate i watch the males
see how long it takes for it to start
producing the pollen at this point in
time it's really easy to like you could
either take the male and shake it over
top of the female or
shake the female into it what's going to
end up happening is it's going to become
so pollinated anyways that
you're not going to be able to smoke it
but the idea is
because you've grown this cultivar so
many times or this or you should have at
this point
you'll know that the female that you've
chosen
is going to be okay and the male that
you've chosen is also going to be okay
because you have stable genetics so
when you go to
introduce your pollen however you choose
to do that
i like to do it basically
again as i said each
each calyx with this with the with the
hair can receive pollen and become a
seed so that's what you want to look for
in your female
as a good point in time to reference
when to pollinate because if your female
hasn't produced enough galaxies and have
enough hairs it's not going to produce
enough seed because you probably don't
want your male hanging around taking up
the space afterwards while your female's
growing
yeah so it's just i try to just
pollinate there and i always clip the
top butt off
and i keep it in a mason jar which goes
directly into the freezer labeled
again this is not the most ideal way to
store
male pollen but it's going to get you
about six months of storage
maybe a little bit longer if you put in
flour which like flour from from the
pantry flour because i've done that
before and it'll kind of absorb any
moisture because that's what's going to
make the pollen infertile or like not
allow it to
uh be viable to
to pollinate your females so it's not
really like a specific day in flower
where you're kind of aiming for it's
probably cultivar specific on to where
like you mentioned the there's enough
pistols kind of showing to pollinate and
have a good enough yield of seeds
yeah each one is going to be different
and again that's going to kind of play
into flowering time of your particular
cultivar um
but yeah if you have your male that's
ready to go and he's producing pollen
and he's ready to pollinate it depends
on how
that that's a good sign that one's
flowering quite fast compared to your
female if it if it's not
covered in doesn't have enough hairs
to receive the pollen in order to create
enough it depends on if you want 10 or
100 seeds right or a thousand seeds but
if you go too long
what can end up happening is that you
won't have enough time to actually allow
these seeds to mature
so
and then that also is a lost cause
because if they don't end up maturing
then you've wasted all this time
and then you don't have any seeds that
are viable at the end to actually plant
as well so that's where there becomes a
fine balance of
is it too early or is it too late it's
so it's always better to do it earlier
in the cycle
so that you can at least have a long
time for those to become
mature and viable as opposed to earlier
but if you go obviously too early it's
you're not going to get many seeds
and then you don't have a lot to play
with in the gene pool if you're working
on the early stages you're going to want
to have a lot of seeds and you don't
want to have go in with just 10 seeds
into a next generation isn't going to
give you a lot of
come on man don't get
isn't going to give you a lot of uh
pheno hunting to do for sure so you're
not gonna have a lot of options to
choose from going into the next ones
which is not something you want to set
yourself up with okay
so you've pollinated you're female how
long
uh should like when should you harvest
the plant in order to maximize the
amount of
yield you get of seeds right i mean
you know i know you don't typically
smoke the plants that you uh pollinated
and stuff like that so you just let the
plant go like
you know 9 10 11 weeks like further than
you typically would so you can kind of
make sure that the seeds are are
developed enough absolutely so
like we just talked about
i kind of like to hit that sweet spot
where i know i'm going to get quite a
large amount of seeds depending on
what stage of the process i'm in whether
it's creating a lot to be able to
bring this cultivar to the public or
am i just trying to create
like a small amount like 500 so that i
can work
through those 500 and pull out the
traits that i want to create the next
generation as i'm working to create it
more stable
so
if i'm trying to bring in
more seeds i'll just wait a little bit
longer
so that it has more hairs and the
flowers has just become a little bit
more developed but the main key is is
that you never want to pollinate without
having at least two months left because
it takes about eight weeks
roughly for a seed to mature at least
through
all the tests that i've done at least if
you leave yourself that much time
a flower or for at least the plant at
least two months of plants plant growing
whatever it is two months of plant
growing
you're going to be okay
um
so yeah if your plant has a
14 week flowering cycle or however long
the flowering cycle is that'll buy you a
little bit of time to
push that calyx production a little bit
further so that when you pollinate
you'll get more seeds
but there's not really any exact time
other than the possibility that you
could go too late
and then afterwards like like you said
earlier i just leave it until it's
basically at the very end where it
variant it's life can't push any more
you can almost see the seeds want to
fall out of the plant pretty much you
could
knock them off if you wanted to
that's ideal because you're in my
situation the plant's going to have over
a couple thousand seeds on it i'm not
going to pick through it to try to to
smoke it i find the easiest way is
actually throw the whole plant in a
ziploc bag dry it a lot
roll the whole thing up
and then you'll be able to it'll
basically like separate the seeds and
the plant matter and then i've
done tests before where you don't want
to know you don't want to know the seeds
far outweigh the plant matter and then
you're like oh that was a lot of work
for
all this and well i guess now you get to
enjoy the fruits of it afterwards
depending on what you choose to do right
but
that's where it comes into play
where you don't want to do that if
you you number one aren't for sure that
you want those seeds in the future
and number two you aren't for sure that
you'd enjoy smoking it and number three
you better have some extra stash hanging
around because
if you don't have any other growth space
and that's specifically what you're
doing
that harvest is going to kind of be a
little bit of a sad time gotcha yeah
that makes sense
so after you
pollinate you've harvested the seeds the
offspring right f1 right that's an f1
generation so we put your two favorite
cultivars together like here in our
beginning sample and we've created the
f1 and so if you want to further
stabilize that you could actually plant
those and do the same process right you
would just repeat the process you'd pick
a female pick a male by showing your
desired traits you would pollinate and
then the offspring of that would be an
f2 right yes and then so how far and
that actually like i mentioned in the
beginning that opens up the gene pool
right so you get a greater variety in
f2s yeah because you're going to get a
mix of the two things that you just your
two favorites
you've now
collided them together and you're going
to get potentially the best of both
worlds in this next generation that's
what's going to happen here
um
and then it's and then it's up to you in
that particular one you find your
favorites again and you keep repeating
and not so much if this is when it's
really time to
pick
exactly what you want uh in terms of
in terms of growth
down the road and what you want to
determine this plant's
outcome to be um
every time you know like you gotta
choose this is what i want it to be
every time
and
you're gonna see
as you breed through f2 and f3 and f4
um
those choices that you made are going to
start
becoming more just dominant in the
in the in the pool of pheno hunting each
time you do it you're going to see
oh my gosh it's it's way more purple
than
it was last time i picked two purple
plants and now it's way more purple
than before
do you want to continue on the purple is
is the question that you need to ask
yourself as the breeder at this point in
time or do you need to
take a step back
and and take away the purple um
those are all questions that that kind
of get into um
in into what
what kind of choices you
like how how you want the plant to
basically
basically be when it's stable and what
you want the end result to be okay so
going down generations f3 f4 f5 become
more and more stable
at what point is the cultivar considered
stable well it depends on
on if you've thrown
thrown it a genetic curve ball somewhere
down the line or if each time you've
been specifically selecting
those traits and again that kind of
uh again that thing i just said about
purple like if you just like decided you
wanted to do two purple ones for some
reason
you got a like a couple of purple ones
in your f2 for whatever reason and for
some reason you decided you wanted to
breed those two together for whatever
reason even though you were looking for
a green cultivar and now in f3 you're
like oh boy
now like 75 of these are purple
or more
what it what does that mean like how am
i going to get away from this i didn't
want to have purple in my in my thing
well you're going to have to
take a step back go back to where you
introduced that purple
and and maybe even go step back further
and and start from that seed pool like
never get rid of your seeds so you can
step back to the beginning generation
and then start all over again so you
never
got into this purple scenario
so that's why each each time if you want
to be
stable you're going to have to choose
specific traits that you want to see and
be very very picky
about
those traits especially in the first
first one to three
generations until they start seeing
those traits repeated and when you start
seeing them
repeat it a little bit more you can kind
of
relax and then kind of fine tune that
into maybe one or two more things that
you want to see specific
changes happen whether it's you want the
plant to be a little bit bigger okay
well
pick one that has everything in it in in
f in f4 for example you're like oh i
want it to be just a little bit bigger
now well that's would be a genetic curve
ball that you're going to kind of throw
it
but if you make sure that it's not too
far off like everything else is the same
but it's a giant
giant giant male but it still has a
purple stalk or purple leaves and you
want a purple for you want purple for
this time it has purple stock purple
leaves purple flower purple buds but
it's giant
pull that one in as your genetic curve
ball because it won't be so weird in
your in your
in your next gene pool that hopefully
you'll start seeing purple everything
still not green but then there might be
a few in there that are giant so then
find the giant female
and the giant male in your next
generation
to pull that giant part into your
growing cycle
yeah but but the idea is to be very
specific in those first
first generations to choose what you
want because if you're not and you're
just kind of
doing willy-nilly like
oh
this is good then you're just going to
get that whenever you go later on like
your next generation again is just going
to be kind of random because you're just
doing random stuff
but as long as you're very specific in
choosing
traits that you want
to see represented throughout
throughout the plants uh
family tree then you're gonna be okay
that's my two cents on that like as long
as you as long as you continue to choose
traits that that
are what you chose at the beginning it's
going to keep
keep
dominantly representing that could you
consider an f3 stable or no that's too
soon
f3 is a little bit too soon i think it's
i think it's f4
for me when you really start to see
uh the fruits of your labor sort of
speak come in from the next from
the past choices that you've made
and then again but that's also a point
where things could get screwed up where
you could throw at that genetic sort of
curveball and then you're kind of back
into a spot where it's like
that one was too different
for whatever reason i don't know why
because again things could be a little
bit different in f3 or f4
you might have one that just for some
reason is a little bit different just
different enough that it screws things
up for you
so then you might want to step back
which would bring you into back crossing
if you want to pull in the original
things
you used because you're kind of far away
you could do that as well depending on
how on how
on on how far off you've you've done a
genetic manipulation let's say
you might want to go back
gotcha okay
let's talk about testing a little bit so
oftentimes breeders will
send out their seeds to a group of
people you know for testing prior to
releasing the seeds to the public right
how many people should be testing these
genetics before releasing to the public
and do you have any kind of best
practices i know that you know different
cultivars are going to grow differently
in different latitudes like are you
doing anything like that to where you're
making sure it's shipped out different
areas so people are growing in different
areas to kind of see what's going on
absolutely
yeah
okay so yeah for us absolutely i try to
ship
stuff to the east coast and stuff to the
west coast
just to make sure because they're
entirely different growing environments
but i want to make sure that you get the
same in this in this
in this scenario you want to make sure
that i'm getting the same kind of
i want the plant to be purple first
we're just going to keep going to this i
want the plant to be purple for whatever
reason um but yeah if i ship it to both
sides it better be purple
you know it better grow right but it
better be purple regardless of what spot
it's in because that shouldn't make a
difference on the color of the plant
really
again there are some things that could
come into play whether it's
weather or location or things like that
but that
it then becomes not part of the gene
pool and we're not talking about
breeding at that point um i want the
purple to be genetic part of the plant
not brought on by the weather or
something like that right
so yes i ship things across to both
sides of the border unfortunately i
can't ship things to the states or i'd
haven't really had a good
figured out a good way to do that yet
that i feel safe about doing it then i
could start going down that road but
otherwise it's really easy for me to do
it in here in canada
and then like again if you're talking
about how many seeds to grow
this is kind of brings you to that stage
we were talking about it earlier on in
the video where we're talking about how
many seeds are you going to get from a
plant
so
if you only got 10 seeds that's not a
very good spot to start
because
you're not
you're not going to get a good enough
example from those 10 seeds so you're
going to have to choose the best out of
the 10
and then i would start all over but that
would never be
i wouldn't even call that an f1 at that
point
even though it is
you just you have too little of amount
of seeds to actually determine what
genes or
things could be found in the gene pool
anyways
so let's say for this example you have
a thousand seeds
let's say you have a thousand seeds you
counted them
i've done it before it's annoying they
probably make seed counter things but
i've counted it before
um
if you grow i don't know well i guess if
you grew a hundred of them then you
would have grown ten percent of the seed
lot right
and that would give you a good
good chance to see
like a very like a good display of
what's going on within your gene pool
even though it's only 10 percent it's
100 seeds it's going to give you a good
idea of what's happening
throughout the remainder of the seeds
i probably would go a little bit further
to say if you did 150 15 depending on
how
um
you know how crazy you wanted to get
with things you could test maybe 200 do
but i think the 10
somewhere in the 100 to 200 range is
going to give you a good idea of what
what's going to happen with the rest of
the seeds and what what is available in
the gene pool anyways are you sending
out to testers each generation are you
doing f1s and then sending out testers
f2 sending are you like finding what you
want and then sending out it like
f4 f5 yes yeah like i'll do pretty much
all the work
like let's say 90 of the testing but the
final amount of the testing is when i
need to have that bulk amount of seeds
grown that i can't do quite by myself
you know whether it's having a hundred
done at once of one thing so that i can
make sure that it's good to go
um
it's not that i can't do it but i have
other things happening too at the same
time that it's hard to
do
to just drew as anyone would know it's
hard to just grow a hundred of one thing
so it's not that i don't want to do it
myself but what it also allows is to see
if
other people's growing methods or other
people's growing environments or things
like that affect the traits that i've
chosen
and how they interact with each other
and whether and how they interact with
the the cultivar interacts with the
grower the environment all those things
so no i don't send out previous
generations but i send out the specific
thing that i'm kind of
the one that i think is one
when i fine-tuned it all the way that's
the one that i send out to kind of have
be mass tested at the time to make sure
that it is
the one and then i can go okay and then
i'll do one more breeding of exactly
those specific traits folial in that
same
with that cultivar that i've had
everyone test
and then usually in that next one which
will probably be like an f6 or f5
depending on how i'm doing on if i've
been lucky or
i've i've worked working with cultivars
that are very generous to me in that in
that regard
then yeah it could be an f6 i'll i'll
make the f5 that everyone's tried and
then that'll be the one that
that gets put on the website
and
you could pick up and it's probably
going to be
90 the same at that point got it all
right i think that was a pretty good
recap of kind of how to get started with
breeding and stabilizing and definitely
covered a lot in a short amount of time
so appreciate you dropping the knowledge
this time around tell us how can little
students find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future um well in the
future right now i'm working on uh
breeding in an autoflower and a photo
period together which i know is
something we didn't get a chance to
touch on in this video chris but
sometime in the future maybe we can chat
about that um
so that's what i'm working on right now
i'm probably at the fourth generation
and i'm just starting to see
some autoflower traits come in but i've
also got some other cool things like
trifoliate going on which is kind of
when you get an extra chromosome put in
but this is getting into like way extra
breeding stuff so maybe another time
around um but in that meantime i'm just
working on that i'm fine tuning it
before i even get to sending that i've
got to make sure they're all autoflower
which is kind of the cool part about
that it's a whole different
uh
different ball game because you're
changing the actual flowering
the way the way the plant responds to
light
which is cool
so i'm working on that and uh other than
that you can just find me again at the
website you can email me at
canadianleafgenetics gmail.com you can
find me on the instagram also canadian
leap genetics
i'll do my best to respond to you
all i'm not very busy right now
as you know i'm up in
in canada so it's winter time and i'm
taking it easy pretty much
so uh
yeah
if you guys are in canada get in touch
and i'd love to send you some seeds if
you're not i'm sorry i can't but maybe
in the future sweet well i'll definitely
have a link to your instagram down in
the youtube description section below so
you guys can easily access that if you
enjoyed this video click that thumbs up
button trying to get as many thumbs up
as possible
if you are on one of the podcast
platforms particular apra podcast please
leave a rating or review
and subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already every single week i am
releasing one of these garden talk
podcast episodes and i'd love if you
would tune into future episodes well
graham great episode once again
appreciate your time and i hope you
enjoy the rest of your day
yeah thanks a lot
peace out everyone
[Music]
you