coming up on garden talk when you
completely
saturate your medium and get it to what
we call field capacity
and which is where you can pick it up
and squeeze it
and you don't get maybe but one drop
come off your hand
that's how moist your soil should start
out the stomata tend to open
right before sunrise or right before
your indoor lights come on
so if you can spray 20 to 30 minutes
before sunrise or before your lights
turn on
the stomata will open and soak up what
you just sprayed onto the leaf surface
and then you have what's called a green
manure or a green mulch
and then that will decompose in place
also and help
boost the nitrogen in your soil the best
advice for anybody starting new on an
organic route
is do less you're going to want to do a
bunch more stuff
because you feel like you're not doing a
whole lot but do less
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode 11.
this episode's guest goes by the name
green goblin 510
he is an organic gardener that grows
plants both indoors and outdoors
he grows tomatoes leafy greens peppers
herbs and of course medicinal plants he
has a youtube channel with over 2 000
subscribers
and he's part of a live stream that airs
every tuesday
on cltv in this episode we talk about
getting started with organic gardening
more specifically we talk about how he
grows his plants
with organic inputs if you're watching
this on youtube please click that thumbs
up button
if you're tuning in on one of the
podcast platforms like apple podcasts or
spotify
please leave a rating and review i would
greatly appreciate it
i was actually going through the reviews
and reading them recently on apple
podcasts
and it's super motivating to see all the
positive words that were set on there so
thank you to everyone who has taken the
time out to leave a review there
if you're liking these episodes and you
want to support the podcast even more
you can do that through patreon
patreon.com
mr growit that'll get you there and i'll
link it down in the description section
below for everyone that's tuning in on
youtube
all right i've rambled on enough let's
get into the episode
all right gree goblin 510 how are you
today
pretty good you good good thanks for
joining me it's about time i get you on
this you're part of the
basically part of the cltv family right
and oh yeah i see you on their live
stream every single week
uh you know i've already talked with rob
i talked with trey
and now it's time to talk with you so
thanks for joining me today
not a problem not a problem so today
we're going to talk about
you know getting started with organic
gardening and kind of what you do
in your garden um with organic inputs
growing organically so
first before we get into the growth side
of things can you just tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
growing
well i got into growing mainly as a
medical benefit
um i broke my leg and sprang both my
ankles on a trampoline
and you know i got some injuries from
that and then
just from that i got lower back pain
from trying to take care of the lower
leg injuries
so that helps out a lot and then i got
into growing a lot because
my mom also has an autoimmune disease
and that also seems to help her out a
lot
nice yeah actually back in 2006 i broke
my well i
tore ligaments in my ankle from a bmx
bike accident
and i remember whenever i put my leg
down like the blood would just rush down
into my leg and it would be extremely
painful
swollen yeah and and cannabis was one of
the things that actually
solved that for me you know it covered
in my pain so
um you know that's kind of one of the
things that helped me over the years
and so you have a youtube channel you uh
we got ourselves a visitor here
rudely interrupted so you got a youtube
channel
um can you tell us a little bit about
that kind of what you do for videos on
there
yeah yeah i like to put out um diy like
organic inputs
and that you can use in your garden and
different weekly updates i like to put
out
in my you know highlighting different
plants in my garden
and then just teaching people as i go
on how i like to grow all different
types of plants honestly
i think i've watched every one of your
videos except for i think three i missed
very very informative kind of
step-by-step diy type stuff uh highly
recommended i will leave a link to his
channel
down in the description section below so
you can click on that
and uh head on over there press the
subscribe button on there and
and check out his videos but he's very
very detailed in his videos which is
something i really like so
cool all right let's talk about organic
gardening so what do you typically use
for a medium i typically
make my own medium i've been technically
reusing my own medium for around seven
or eight years now
and just re-amending with uh worm
castings and compost and
dry amendments and you know reworking
that in there and keep
using that same soil so what does it
consist of what was kind of the star was
it like a peat based or a cocoa yeah it
wasn't
based okay do you know what the ratios
were
on it it was the the the one-third
aeration one-third
sphagnum and one-third compost worm
castings the
you know what a lot of the recipes out
there on the internet
are got it and then what type of compost
you use i think i remember from one of
your videos used a
different type of compost compared to
what other people use i like using a
mushroom compost because it's a little
bit more
fungally dominated and having that
little more fungally dominated compost
in your soil mix
helps the uptake of phosphorus and
potassium
which are key elements later on in the
plant's life
and all throughout the plant's life but
and then what do you use for aeration
um i like to use rice holes and
clay pebbles i'll make sure those two
the clay pebbles don't break down
as quickly as the rice holes and then
the rice oils actually break down
a little bit and add a little silica as
they do break down
so a third a third a third of that
do you add any additional amendments on
top of that to begin
um that would i would call my base soil
and i would just plant like little
seedlings or
cuttings and into my base soil
and then i would take a portion of that
and also
add a bunch of amendments to that and
use that for
older plants more maturing plants got it
now what containers do you usually start
in
uh i usually start in either solo cups
or
similarly sized nursery pots okay and
then
i'm assuming you're transplanted into
larger containers at what point do you
usually transplant and then what
containers do you usually kind of go
into
i usually go from the solo cup size
up to maybe a one gallon and then maybe
to the the final
home that's mainly for space saving that
makes sense
so your initial mix has compost in it
right it has nutrients already in it for
the plant
at what point do you do your first
feeding
um about 30 days in actually about two
or three weeks after
they're you know sprouted or cutting or
whatever
they are i'll transplant them into that
one gallon
and inside that one gallon will have
some of that soil that i mixed up with
the amendments
and then i'll transplant it into the
seven gallon
and i'll also have amendments in that so
throughout that entire time span it's
getting food
and at the 30 days i'll top dress that
makes sense and then
uh when you transplant are you using any
mycorrhizal fungi in there
are you adding in like any worm castings
or anything like that or what
um i like to use a fungi
like mycorrhizae fungi want to have it
and if i don't i'll just go straight in
to the soil because when in a living
soil there a lot of it's already there
to begin with so adding some more never
hurts
but if i don't have it i'll just go and
transplant it right into my living soil
and then i don't think we talked about
what sat what type of containers do you
use do you
prefer plastic fabric or what
i like a plastic one there in the
smaller containers the one gallon solar
cup
and then fabric for the rest of the time
just easier to deal with the smaller
plants in the plastic containers
that make sense easier to transplant out
of right yeah okay
and then so your first feeding comes
around day 30
at that point you're saying they're in
their final containers which you use
seven gallon containers as your final
containers what does your first feeding
consist of and how do you apply it
well my first feeding consists of
literally a top dress of
craft pines uh build a soil craft blend
and uh it has a good mixture of a little
bit of everything
kelp alfalfa meal some rock dust some
oyster shell powder
just a nice mix a little bit of
everything and i'll use uh
two tablespoons per gallon of medium
which happens to work out to be about a
quarter cup
per seven gallon pot i'll top dress that
in and i'll
rake the amendments in to the top layer
of the soil a little bit
and i'll water that in sometimes i'll
use the compost
tea and water that in got it we'll talk
about compost teas in a little bit here
um now when you top dress do you also do
you do any
mulch layers or cover crops at all
i i like to use like barley straw as a
mulch i heavily endorse the use of cover
crops i just don't use them in my indoor
garden
i use them more in like my beds outside
and
stuff like that i find the cover crops
in pots to be a little more work
than they might be worth if you had a
decent like a 4x8
living soil bed that might be worth
doing the cover crops as well
but in smaller containers i don't see a
huge benefit
okay now when do you usually when you do
use
cover crops say outdoors when are you
typically planting them
typically probably a good month or two
before
the intended crop is planted in that
spot
and then i assume since the cover crops
growing up you're kind of like cutting
it down so you're able to
to plant in that seedling so it's not
yeah so lights
down to that spot and then you have
what's called a green manure
or a green mulch and then that will uh
decompose in place
also and help boost the nitrogen in your
soil so
often called chop and drop technique is
that kind of what you're referring to
there yep okay
so you're chopping it down putting it
right down as a mulch layer on top
do you put any you said barley straw i
use barley straw as well
do you put that over that green layer at
all or no
if i'm using them in combination i'll
lay the
cover crop seed down first and make sure
you know that's nice and watered in and
whatnot and then i'll lay the barley
straw over top of it
and they'll grow up in between the
barley straw and it creates a nice
like mat of protection on your soil
i've been doing something similar to
that and uh yeah it's been working out
pretty well for sure
all right let's take a step back and
talk about ipm so integrated pest
management
is there anything that you do in order
to prevent pests from
getting into your garden well other than
doing a weekly ipm spray of like
essential oils or a treatment enzyme
cleaner
or even just water just spraying your
plants down with water
just being diligent of not going out for
a hike and then going to visit the
plants
you know just things like that having a
very clean garden area
don't have any spots for pests to hide
and it's a lot easier to keep them from
attacking whatever plants you're trying
to keep protected
and then another thing i like to do is
um
i'll plant different bait plants per se
around my property and the
the insects will like to attack those
plants more and stay away from the
plants that
i would like to keep around what do you
use for bait plants
well that that's kind of the hard thing
to say for to recommend to people
because it's going to be different for
everybody's different location whether
you're in a
more northern climate or a southern
climate
or you know a more desert arid climate
but
honestly if you want to find out the
best one for your area
is to go take a hike and look at ones
that are being attacked
and you'll find the ones in your areas
that
will be great bait plants that you could
plant around your area
and there's a there's an app that i like
to use on my phone
i think it's called naturalist and you
can
take a photo of whatever plant you're
looking at
and it will try to cross check it
against a bunch of different plants in
the world
and it gets pretty close and it'll you
can
identify a plant relatively easily
by doing a little bit of research and
you can use that plant in your area
that makes sense so for essential oil
spray that you use what do you typically
use for essential oils and you said you
apply them on a weekly basis right
yep uh every week i like to do a spray
and i like to alternate it from like the
essential oil to maybe the treatment
enzyme
so maybe water to maybe need and i'll
just
keep rotating them every week just to
make sure that
if any pests happen to come along
they uh they get nipped in the bud right
away
the essential oil blend is i believe
it's clove
garlic it's a bunch of different
essential oils i use the essential oil
blend from
build a soil it just happens to be the
easiest way to go about it because they
blended it all together and gave it to
you in a bottle
off you know at a fair price
and then otherwise i could go out and
buy all the separate ones and mix them
myself but
it would get a little expensive i would
have more
but i'd rather support a good company
and get their product absolutely
builds the soil is doing great over
there they've got so much good
information
good products they're definitely kind of
leading the way when it comes to
growing organically and teaching others
how to grow organically so
definitely series over there yeah all
right so that's ipm now how about
foliar feeding do you need type of
foliar feeds throughout the grow
um every couple of weeks i like to do a
foliar feed that consists of a
full power fulvic acid and a little bit
of kelp meal
and i'll soak that in a bucket and then
for
maybe 20 or 30 minutes a tablespoon of
kelp meal
and that umic acid and
then if your sprayer can't handle it you
can throw it through a little bit of a
coffee filter or
strain it out a little bit because the
kelp meal might clog up your sprayer
and filter that out and i'll spray it on
my plants and they love it
the kelp meal has lots of enzymes and
minerals in it
and the humic acid helps release those
enzymes and minerals i've never used
kelp as
a foliar but i have used it as a top
dressing
and also kind of helps include it and
recharge as well so it's kind of like a
soil drench
i have to try it as a foliar now i
watched your video
on foliar feeding you have a very
in-depth video and i'll link it down
in the description section below so
people know about this but
a lot of good information very detailed
can we talk a little bit about
when to spray i thought that was very
interesting about you talked about
the stomata openings and kind of the
ideal time
to spray your plants yeah the uh the
stomata tend to open
right before sunrise or right before
your indoor lights come on
so if you can spray 20 to 30 minutes
before
sunrise or before your lights turn on
the stomata will open and soak up
what you just sprayed onto the leaf
surface and it'll be
more effective for your feet so about 30
minutes before now i know
some people are probably watching this
probably going to be a little bit
concerned
that you know with droplets being left
on the plant
the light comes on that high intensity
light it could potentially kind of burn
your plants due to
the droplets kind of acting as a
magnifying lens
i think in your video you had mentioned
if you're doing it 20 to 30 minutes
prior
and you have the oscillating fans on the
plant should very well
be dry at that point is that correct
they should be mostly dry and at least
not no more having the water drops on
the leaf surface
they may still be wet a little bit but
the big drops causing the magnifying
glass type effect should be gone
also if you use aloe or
yucca in there those are wetting agents
and it will actually help prevent some
of those dots from even forming
it'll just make a nice smooth coating
over the leaf that's awesome i've been
using yucca a lot lately
having my reservoirs just to my my spray
bottles that i use to spray the top of
the medium
and then also mixing it in with just any
soil drench that i use
this stuff's awesome you talked a little
bit about aloe i know on your channel
you use a lot aloe in a bunch of
different ways can you explain some of
the ways that you use aloe
i use aloe for in my foliar sprays
for cloning as a cloning gel
as a wetting agent for
watering and for pretty much anything
you know if i get a cut or a neck or
bruise in the garden
i'll use it right then and there and
it's a great
i have like three or four of them in my
garden and i just cut little pieces off
every so often when i need to use them
and i'm good to go i don't have to buy
cloning gels or wedding agents
as much yucca is a little bit more
powerful of a wedding agent
than aloe but aloe also has saprons and
different enzymes in it that help
the plant turn on its own defense
systems against
pests and diseases even though there
isn't a pest and disease around
so i also like using that as a in my
soil
drenches or foliar sprays to help the
plants just enact their defenses a
little bit early before they
run in any problems i haven't used
dallow yet but
after watching your videos on it and how
you use it step by step
i'm definitely have to try that in the
future because it's a common house plant
right it's something that a lot of
people just keep around their house
and uh you know being able to have that
in your house and then cut off a piece
to use
for for rooting or as a spirit or
whatever can be beneficial so
that's something i'm definitely gonna
best practice i'm gonna shamelessly
steal from you and
incorporate to my god and that's the
whole point of this this podcast really
is to
talk to girls from all over the world
all different styles are growing
and see what they do in their garden and
that's what they're successful doing
so people listening can incorporate in
their gardens you know trying out these
different things it can be really fun
to try new things so again thanks for
for sharing uh tips like that because
it's helpful for uh not only me but
everybody tuned into this so oh yeah not
a problem you gotta pass the tips along
all right so let's take a step back to
uh feeding again
now you've done your feeding in the veg
stage how long do you typically
veg your plants for do you do any other
feedings in
veg or are you flipping a flower and
then doing more feedings
usually i'll just do that one feeding
and veg veg might be
anywhere from a month to a month and a
half depending on the cultivar
some like to be a little squatty and
slow slower than the others and
some like to shoot up and grow a little
faster than the others
but uh yeah usually it's about a month a
month and a half
and i'll put them into flour about two
weeks into flour i'll use a compost tea
and that's usually about it i might do a
top dress
right when i do that compost tea another
top dress depending it
if it was the month and a half i might
do another top dress
and the compost tea when i flip but
other than that it's just water from
then on
so i assume the other top dress is going
to be craft blend more of the craft
blend
as the top dress same ratio as before
you know
maybe a little bit of insect for us
mixed in there
and then for your teas what does that
consist of
um worm castings and a good source of
compost whether that be a mushroom
compost or
a regular you know thermal compost
and then i'll use a cup of the buildus
oil
a little bit of the humic acid and a
little bit of the aloe
and bubble that up for 24 hours so you
usually do a
five gallon bucket like what's your
what's your ratios for that
five gallon bucket sorry about that yeah
and then what do you
use for a food source in your tees
um i like to use a it's a product from
florida it's a florida raw sugarcane
crystals
i like to use that it's a little more
easier to measure out
and put into the compost tea
and it's a i find it's a little bit more
of a simpler sugar for
the microbes to eat they don't have to
work through the molasses type
structure of molasses
you know that's the sticky runny-ness of
it
and it's much it like becomes a
homogenized mixture so that the microbes
can eat it easier
so you don't use molasses at all in your
garden to use any type of
sugars as a soil drench at all
throughout the grow or is it only really
sugars in your teas
just in the teas okay now do you use any
microbial inoculants throughout the grow
um i definitely do um i definitely like
a product recharge is a great product
and then also there's a product i use
called dr earth
flower girl that has amendments in it
and it's also inoculated with
mycorrhizal fungi and a few bacteria
and when i mix my soil i
use a cup of that along with the craft
blend
are you using them at all like there's a
soil drench throat to grow at all or no
nope just that initial inoculation
and then the compost tea does give them
a boost when i do that
i i do maybe two compost tea the entire
grow cycle
do you monitor i know this is a question
that um
well i was gonna say you might laugh at
me for asking but
it's a common question for beginners
especially though the ones are just
starting
growing organically is do you monitor
the ppm or ec
at all or no um the easy is
kind of all right to monitor as an
organic grower because
that tells you how active your microbial
life is
so that can give you some indication of
how good your soil is so
that number is not completely useless
but the ppm number
uh i don't use because there's inorganic
and
organic you know solids that are coming
out
of a runoff test and we don't
you can't determine what ones are which
with that ppm meter
got it and are you doing in order to
check the ec are you doing
like a slurry test were you doing a
runoff test or or what
um there is a nice probe test
from hannah instruments that you can
literally just
put in your soil and it will do perform
an ec test for you
now what about ph do you monitor the ph
at all either in your nutrient solution
prior to giving to the plant
or any type of like slurry or runoff ph
test
um every once in a while i do test
my ph and my coming off my tap to make
sure that it's
you know around the same i do have it
filtered with a
activated carbon filter that i replace
frequently
but i do test the ph coming from the
city of municipal because
once in a while it does change and i
might have to correct it because
it it'll go too far one way or the other
other than that i don't monitor the ph a
whole lot my soil
unless i'm running into issues i might
actually do a ph test for my soil okay
so
switching over to water you're using tap
water that's filtered
now is your filter also taking out like
any
chlorine or chloramine at all or do you
have to
let it sit out for an additional people
usually let it sit out for like 24 hours
or something like that so the
chlorine will dissipate that's why i do
have the uh
the activated carbon filter is that it
is a it does
filter out the chlorine and some of the
chloramines
not every filth not any filter will get
all of the chloramines unless you're
doing ro
but cutting it down to acceptable levels
of
parts per billion per billion not
million
is good enough for me now watering is
one of those things when it comes to
organics it could be a little
tricky right it's easy to over water
your plants
uh when it comes to it is there any can
you tell us like how you do your
watering you know are you using a
pitcher
to to dump it all in there are you using
a sprayer and slowly spraying or how
exactly do you water
and when do you know when to how do you
know when to water on the smaller plants
i do like to use a sprayer
to water them in the solar cups and
maybe even the one gallons
because it's a little bit more accurate
of measurement
of how much water you are giving them um
on the seven gallon ones i do use like a
pitcher
per say that's a one gallon pitcher
and it happens to be that most the time
i can use that entire gallon for that
seven gallon pot so it works out quite
well
when i know when i need to water is i
tell by
how the pot feels how the weight feels
of the pot
and i know it's kind of a vague answer
for a lot of beginners
but when you completely
saturate your medium and get it to what
we call field capacity
and which is where you can pick it up
and squeeze it
and you don't get maybe but one drop
come off your hand
that's how that's how moist your
shoulder your soil should start out
and be and then you should keep it
around that moisture level
while allowing it to maybe drop and wait
a little bit you can tell by
picking it up and then okay it's a
little bit lighter spray a little bit
more water in there
okay and then in between waterings
um you know soil will dry off kind of
from the top
down in a sense so that top layer is
drying out you know one of the first
things to dry out
um you know of course it depends on grow
pot
if you have the um the fabric pots
it might actually dry out from the sides
right are you spraying with a sprayer at
all the top of the medium in order to
kind of keep that moist in between
waterings and how if you do
how frequently do you do that um in the
one gallons and solos probably
once a day i'll spray a little bit of
water in there just to keep the
top and the sides moist um and
by a little bit of water i mean
literally like two seconds per pot
i'll spray some water in there and then
on
the larger pots um i have the good mulch
layer that we were talking about earlier
which helps
and they need water nearly every day in
that stage of their life
anyways so i'm watering nearly every day
anyway to keep it moist now what do you
do for
plant training so as the plants growing
um you know i
have seen your channel i kind of know
what you do for plant training not sure
if it's changed up
uh since you created that video but can
you talk about what you typically do for
plant training
typically i might top a plant maybe one
time
depending on the cultivar other than
that i like to low stress train
everything out
to get some nice branching happening
and then build some bamboo cages around
them
so they can be supported in the
you know later stages of life yeah the
bamboo cages is what i
i saw in your channel i thought that was
pretty cool technique
for keeping things upright you know
because uh
some of these cultivars i mean geez they
get so um flopping all over the place
towards the
flowering because the buds are so so
heavy and those bamboo
style that you did would definitely help
with that so
it's good stuff there now what about
lighting what do you typically use for
lighting
or what do you have for lighting in your
garden right now uh right now i'm
mostly led and i still have two
hps left most of my leds are
hlg leds i got a 650
diy kit in which i put together over on
my channel
and then i also have a 480 watt
one of their older ones that's a 550 v2
and i also have a their 300 watt version
as well nice definitely have some
quality lights over there i had the 100
v2 for a while grew a plan with that
and i was super satisfied with that
they've got some really good products
over there
now for light distance do you have a par
meter are you dialing in your light
distance through a part meter
are you just going by the manufacturer's
recommendation
or what um for the longest i did not
have a power meter and i just went by
you know how the plants are reacting and
the manufacturer's recommendation
but now i do have a parameter so i can
kind of dial it in a little
closer than just
watching the plants and using the
manufacturer's recommendations
but by getting that par meter i did find
out that i was pretty close
without it so that was nice to see
as well which parameter are you using
i have the apogee m500
oh okay yeah i got that one i also have
the mq 600 620
i know the 620 is kind of the extended
range one it's good for leds
the 500 is just that what 400 to 700
nanometer range
yeah the blue the blue one the blue
sensor
of the apogee super useful to have one i
mean they're super expensive right 500
plus dollars
for a good par meter but being able to
you know for energy consumption purposes
you can dim down your light
and get it closer and if you have that
par media you can kind of ensure that
you're not giving your plants
too much light so i typically aim for
like 200 to 400 ppfd
in seedling stage clones and mother
plants
400 to 600 for veg 600 to 900 for
flower and then if i'm supplementing co2
i go get a little bit higher than that
uh maybe around a thousand
or so maybe yeah do you monitor what do
you typically aim for there
i i try to aim for right around 900 to
during flower and same numbers for you
know seedlings and veg
i i don't supplement co2 so i can't
really push it too much further than
that
i was going to ask if you supplement co2
so you don't use any of those
co2 bags any canisters no tanks nothing
like that
just kind of relying on the air exchange
the air exchange and i do
i do grow in a basement and i do have a
couple of co2 sensors down here
and at all times it's around 800 ppm
so i mean i could supplement to get a
couple more hundred ppm
of co2 down here and maybe push the
plants a little harder but
i'm i'm good with what i get
800 is not bad at all i mean what is it
like 400 is natural
co2 is around there i know it's always
changing but right now it's about
400 so being at 800 that's that's
definitely a better
what co2 monitors do you use um i
actually
put them together myself i use a
raspberry pi
and i make a whole bunch of sensors and
have those sensors report
back to the raspberry pi
i'm a little bit of a geek in that
nature
and uh you know i like to do that myself
and
save a little bit of money in the long
run too that's awesome i
have the co2 monitor by co2 meter and
it's like this
round meter it's like pretty big and uh
i wish they had one that would you could
just hang i mean they do have one i know
troll master hasn't has one we can just
kind of hang down
so you can get it within the canopy
reading but like i have this big round
thing that i can't like
shove into my canopy right now i feel
like that's one thing that's lacking
right now is good co2 meters
especially one that could link to your
smartphone right i don't even know if
one exists for that
i had to make one he had to make one
right
so i hope to see that uh that come out
from
some of these companies in the future
cool so what temperature
do you usually aim for um i'm usually 76
degrees
to up to 83 degrees in in the flower
room
okay that's flour do you do anything
different for veg or ceiling or about
the same
they're about the same all the heat
and temperature that's coming out of the
flower room
i just pour onto the veg room and
keep them warm and then and any excess
heat from there i'll pull from the veg
out of the house so as far as air
exchange
are you pumping all of the air from the
flower room
over to your bedroom and then kind of
like passively intaking into your flower
room
and then you have like another in-line
fan in your bedroom that you're
exchanging air from there or what kind
of yeah i have a
intake fan on my flower room
taking in fresh air and then i have a
out
put fan from the flower room blowing all
the high air onto the veg area
and then i have yet another inline fan
pulling air out of the veg area
out of the house and there's around 24
7.
the one pulling out of the house is on a
temperature
um setting now how about humidity it's
another thing that that a lot of people
monitor throughout the grow
what do you typically aim for humidity
and the different stages of growth
i'm usually at like 60 percent and veg
maybe a little higher sometimes if i do
a foliar spray it'll be a little higher
obviously for a little bit
um i'm around the same in
flour 55 to 60 percent humidity
and flower now what about air
circulation
so i mean humidity temperature there can
be pockets
of high humidity temperature so air
circulation is huge do you have multiple
fans
in your grow environment where do you
typically kind of place them within your
environment
i like depending on the model of fans
some some are a little stronger than
others but i like to place them around
every four feet
so around every four feet whether that's
a one for a four by four
area or two for a four by eight section
but around every four feet i like to use
a fan and
keep it on low i always keep it on low
because i like the air movement
and i like the plant leaves to flutter a
little bit but i don't want to push them
too hard
yeah that constant wind especially when
you have a fan blowing directly onto the
plan you'll see wind burn
right the the outer edges of the leaf
will kind of brown up and curl down i've
had one burn
so many times it's so easy uh with some
of these fans because they're so strong
to to get wind burns so
that's a good tip to have it on low all
right so we covered a lot in this
episode
is there anything else that you can
think of that you kind of wanted to talk
about in this episode
i mean if i were going to add co2
supplementation in my flower room i
would start growing
different mushrooms different gourmet
mushrooms in my flower room
and that way i get another product from
it and i could
you know eat it and cook with the
mushrooms
and i'd also get the co2 from it that
way you get kind of the best of both
worlds
absolutely do you have any other tips or
tricks
for those that are maybe watching this
and just starting the organic route
what advice do you have for them the
best advice for anybody starting new on
an organic route
is do less you're going to want to do a
bunch more stuff
because you feel like you're not doing a
whole lot but do less
watch the plant do a little bit of
training you don't have to do a lot when
you're growing organic
and you have a soil set up so don't try
to do too much
awesome advice really really good advice
there for sure
so how can the listeners find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
uh you can find me on youtube at
greengoblin510
also on instagram greengoblin510
i got weekly update videos coming i got
a new mars tent and a fc 4800 that
i'm going to be doing a series in and
growing uh four
primal punches in there and come check
out the series
awesome once again i will link green
goblin's channel down
in the description section below and
also link a couple videos that relate to
what we talked about today
i know for the foliage feeding is one of
them i think you might have a video
directly on
aloe i can link that down below as well
but
a ton of good information on his channel
feel free to
click on that and and check it out so
green goblin thank you once again for
coming on
to garden talk today i greatly
appreciate it any fine thanks for having
me
awesome uh awesome host good talking
with you man
look forward to talking with you more in
the future sounds good
all right man have a good one
[Music]
you