coming up on garden talk if someone had
a pretty good base mix and had used some
synthetic nutrients in it at a time or
two they could probably still turn that
into a living soil environment over
a short period of time the microbes will
remediate quickly they'll remediate just
about anything quickly anything really
from the ocean is going to be salty and
possibly
contaminated we also like planting stuff
like carrots and radishes and things
that are going to penetrate the soil
and feed everything in the soil or below
the soil the quality is absolutely
higher
the more research you do up front and
the
more prepared you are going into that
situation the better your turnout's
going to be for sure
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 55. in this
episode i interview james from red dirt
raised he's been gardening for his
entire life and he currently runs a
commercial facility in oklahoma in this
episode he talks about several different
things such as transitioning from
synthetic to organic ferments
water-soluble mineral inputs and more
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
thanks to aec infiniti for sponsoring
this podcast they sent me over their
grow 10 which has a canvas density of
2000 d making them the thickest grow
tent on the market today it has an
aluminum plate that mounts your
controller to the grow tent with the
light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has 50 thicker steel
poles and carries two times more weight
than the standard grow tents coupon code
mr growit will get you a discount on
their products and i'll leave a link to
their website down in the description
section below dutch pro is a sponsor of
the podcast coupon code
mrgrow10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit10dp for a discount on
their products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
james from red dirt raised how you doing
today
good how are you chris doing pretty good
thanks for asking excited to talk to you
today we're going to talk about a whole
bunch of things i think are going to be
valuable to the audience listening in
we're going to talk about transitioning
from synthetics to organics we're also
going to get into things such as
ferments
water-soluble mineral inputs cover crops
and so much more but first before we get
into those things what we like to do is
an introduction so can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
you bet my name is james i'm the owner
of red dirt raised
and we have
a small
family ran medicinal farm
medicinal plant farm in oklahoma
we started it in 2019
and
have been gardening all my life
other types of plants vegetables
house plants
but have been commercially
commercially farming in oklahoma since
2019.
that's awesome and i know you i believe
you started out
with synthetics right and then you kind
of transitioned over organics and that's
really what we're going to talk about
today first kind of
before talking about the transition and
how to go about it
general question here which i mean i
know the answer but
i think it's important for the audience
to know the answer as well which is why
make the change from synthetic to
organic
for us uh it was all about quality
initially
if you've
if you've tasted the difference in an
organically grown
tomato
as to
compare to what you may go buy at the
grocery store
you'll know immediately you know the
flavor
uh is is quite a bit
stronger in that organically grown
tomato
same thing goes for medicinal plants
the quality is absolutely higher
you're going to see a
more diverse terpene profile um
higher cannabinoid content altogether
and then
you know for us a lot of it had to do
with sustainability
um
being able to
provide your plants with the food they
need
instead of using a bottle
uh
using something from the earth
or maybe even you know a ferment or
something that you have
uh made there yourself
but
now it was uh it was a number of reasons
for us
um you know if you're running a farm
commercially
uh the bottom line is always gonna
help steer decisions and overhead on any
size farm isn't small
so
you know that was another really
attractive uh selling point for for me
trying to choose what direction we were
gonna go
uh but it all started with quality
if you've had organically grown
medicinal plants
you know the difference
one major thing you mentioned is
sustainability right now certainly there
are pros and cons to growing both ways i
believe sustainability really stands out
there you know going out and spending
money on nutrients every single round
can be expensive and you can certainly
save money going to organic side of
things i think that's a lot of reason
why folks transition to the organic side
of things because you can save a
significant amount of money if you do
things right transitioning over to
organics so i'm glad you mentioned that
one
most my audience are home growers right
so they're in containers they maybe buy
a bag soiled and they're starting to use
synthetic nutrients oftentimes what
they're doing is
throwing out that medium right they're
throwing out after they finish their
grow
they're usually throwing out that soil
and then buying a new bag of soil
starting fresh the reason why is because
things such as salt buildup can occur
which can you know once you plant your
next crop you could potentially your
higher risk of running into issues also
there can be a nutrient imbalance over
time that can happen within the medium
now you're out on a farm right so
there's no like
there's no throwing away the soil and
starting fresh right you have to kind of
you've already used synthetics you have
to use that same soil in order to
transition to organics so what are the
steps to kind of go about transitioning
from synthetic to organic
so depending on scale um you know
that's that's there's a few factors
there that are gonna um
i think really line out the steps for
people
um for a tent grower
uh somebody at home uh with a small
garden
you could just simply
well
education is key first of all
try to educate yourself as much as you
can for us it was huge making that
decision
because
it's a totally different system and if
you screw it up
it can be costly so
we went with raised beds
and you know if somebody were growing in
pots and using bottle nutrients
they could go to uh something that fits
their
tent which uh you know i think a four by
four you got a four by four or three by
three bed
and then the same goes for four by eight
or you know anything bigger
but um
you know
i uh
after lots and lots of research we
decided to
to use basically the same base mix that
everyone else uses
which is 33 percent compost 33 percent
peat or cocoa or you know your
desired media
and then 33
aeration or a third of each or however
you want to say that
um
but
uh you know at home or commercially
commercially it's gonna be quite a bit
more complicated but uh
in a tent
at home
[Music]
someone could
either find a local soil yard
that's already mixing something real
similar to that and a minute themselves
or
you could go with a great company like
build a soil and
buy something that you know
products that already have integrity and
and are already mixed
we mixed everything at home
and went and bought
pete from lowe's
which was canadian sphagnum peat moss
we like
rice holes and pumice for
aeration
but you can use
uh other types of aeration volcanic rock
and
you know people use perlite we've
actually got some soil that has perlite
in it um
but
you know and you can source your own
compost uh that one's tricky as you
probably know
um
you know that's that's really where
you're probably either going to be
making or break it i would say is
finding good compost so
we did that at home and uh are even
doing some composting here at home
and we're trying to do a biocomplete
compost
which is what i would suggest for
anybody that's really more like your
soil food web and elaine ingham
school of thought
but uh
amending your soil is going to be a
little different if you're if you're
commercial
i don't suggest using certain products
um
kilt meal
anything really from the ocean is going
to be
salty and possibly
contaminated with
things in the medicinal plant market
that are going to cause
you know health risks and issues like
that
heavy metals
you know
but uh
there's also
some easier ways to dial things in and
for us since we were commercial we
tested our soil
uh
we were really doing that under the
guidance of brandon ross
and uh
doing it consistently
uh you know once a month at least
if you've got rows
uh and you're using raised beds
um
you know that that gets a little bit
tricky
because
uh each individual bed is going to be a
little bit different and if you're
growing different cultivars that's going
to change things up a little bit as well
different plants pull different things
from the soil
so
um
but really
there's some great uh information out
there already uh coot's mix and that
recipes uh
already out there
for people to easily
access
i think you can even get you know a lot
of build-a-souls recipes and what
they're using
uh just off their back
uh you know but
we
prefer
soybean meal uh alfalfa meal
and try to avoid things from the ocean
not just because of heavy metals and
other contaminants but because of sodium
and
you know salt buildup so
once they get that mixed
um
you know if they're not gonna test their
soil
uh i would inoculate
plant and take off uh because it's gonna
do pretty awesome and it's gonna do a
lot of the work for you and it's gonna
get better with time
uh we like using cover crop and other
things like that to help with
you know the uh the the full cycle there
that's happening in the soil food web uh
things breaking down we do use worms
uh worm castings even but once you get
the worms in the bed you really don't
need the castings a whole lot anymore
they're doing a lot of that for you
uh so
um
i can keep going you want me to
i i did a follow-up question i should
ask this in the during the intro but on
your farm
what's the you said you're in raised
beds how many like what size raid beds
are using how many plants are you
growing things like that
so we have three flower rooms indoor
um we have a veg and mother and
propagation area um and then we have a
greenhouse that we just built
um
you can uh you can find a lot of that on
instagram at red dirt raised okay
we just uh just gotten that finished and
really 2022 is gonna be where we're
getting to display
uh the spaceship we built out there
because it's honestly
better than our indoor operation
and more sustainable
uh more regenerative you know we're
gonna be using the sun we'll also be
doing some no-till
out there i think eventually
we uh we've
taken and had a lot of people bless us
with advice and information over the
last few years uh like brandon
um
but we'll also be doing some ferments
and do ferments indoors
um just in
not in not in uh
high amounts
we really try to let the soil food web
do as much of the work as we can
and then
um
you know brandon is mainly a
water-soluble
guy and a lot of his information and
recommendations have been
with water soluble so that's a really
easy way to get balance in your soil and
after testing
um you know on a commercial level where
you're trying to keep production
consistent that was
a big deal for us we uh having that in
your in your toolbox is huge you know we
will get deeper into water soluble
mineral inputs and a little bit here so
okay so you're in beds
and you just kind of started with your
own soil mix versus trying to revive
the native soil in in the ground now my
question for you before we move on is
can home growers reuse the soil where
synthetic nutrients have been used in
or
or do you think they should just start
fresh with making their own soil like
you mentioned with the 33 33 33 mix
i would definitely say start fresh
uh with that 33 33 33 um
that's not to say it can't be done
uh but that's not the way we did it
and um
you know i i would assume that if
someone had a pretty good base mix
and had used some synthetic nutrients
and at a time or two
they could probably still turn that into
a living soil
uh environment over
a short period of time
the microbes will remediate quickly
they'll remediate just about anything
quickly
or
revive
you know um
allowing them to do
most of the work has really been key i
think for you know especially no-till
farmers but
um
for us as well uh trying less is more
kind of attitude you know
um
really allowing
uh the plant and the soil to have that
symbiotic relationship and
stay out of their way as much as
possible
that makes sense
so for the
33-33-33 mix i just released an episode
recently with jeremy silver from build a
soil not sure if he caught that one or
not but he gets real into detail about
33 33 33 and what to use when you're
soil building so we won't get too deep
into that in this episode but i do want
to know what initial amendments you're
putting within that mix
so um
initially we'll start with a really good
compost which is going to have more
nutrients in it than just about anything
uh else you're going to put in there
already broken down and ready to go
available
but uh
we'll also add alfalfa meal
we might use a little bit of green sand
we might uh
use a little soybean meal
um
we do have some oyster shell meal in our
soil
uh but not a lot
um
we use some gypsum um
calcium sulfate
there's a little cow phos in our soil
worm castings you know which are going
to be a great source of nitrogen
and then we fired it up
oh about three weeks after actually
getting soil in beds
uh with worms
a little bit of cover crop and really
kind of let everything go for
you know 20-21 days on its own before
planting
okay and then eventually those nutrients
you know majority of them will deplete
and then you have to re-amend like a lot
of folks when growing indoors they'll
have that initial amendment and then
they'll do a top dressing you know
roughly 30 days
into the grow
typically you know folks will do it
before flipping the flower they will do
it 20 to 30 30 days into flower so this
is the general way of going about
feeding you know we're talking indoors
after you do those initial amendments
that you mentioned the initial planting
you said you wait 20 days and you plant
in at what point do you do any other
fertilizer add in any more you know top
dressing or what
i think midway through flour is a pretty
good point um
you know if
if you've tested your soil and you know
the balance and the nutrition levels are
there
then you may be able to do a run with
water only and
you know that's kind of the goal um
but
we like malted barley
we use
we use regular water and only do that a
couple of times a week in those beds uh
but occasionally there will be a feeding
there will be a little bit extra in
there
and
you know some people will just top dress
if we can uh we like to water in as much
uh food as we can as much nutrition as
we can as much
inoculation as we can
the water really helps
uh
spread things out you know
absolutely now circling back to the
water soluble mineral inputs what water
soluble mineral inputs do you use
so we're
pretty big on
uh soybean amino acids
uh hydrolysate soybean hydrolysate um
you get a high quality uh version of
that and it's pretty water soluble
and they make a form of calcium sulfate
uh
gypsum
uh that is really fine and powdery and
is fairly water soluble
a lot of people are familiar with
epsom salt
magnesium sulfate
we use it
and
it you know extremely water soluble
potassium sulfate
uh you gotta watch what you buy because
there are chemical versions of these and
then there are mine mineral versions of
these
and i suggest uh like down to earth
uh
products that you know have been mined
and
uh aren't
some byproduct of
you know industry
but uh
for the most part uh that is it we do
use humic acid uh in powder form
and um we also use a humic fulvic full
power
but that's really i'd say the majority
of the water solubles that we use
so you mentioned a ton there when do you
generally
apply those water soluble mineral inputs
i'm sure there's different times for
different different ones right
sure um
cool thing about those is you can top
dress them and literally get
like a full run you know seven eight
weeks before you really start seeing
uh levels depleting
or you can
do
small feedings with them and water them
in
uh you know once a week
um
the soybean amino
the humic acid is something that you can
use uh almost all the way through
and i mean
vegetative stage on into flowering
uh you could cut back on the soybean
aminos because of the high nitrogen
content
i would say probably week five
um week 4 a flower
especially if you're running a system
like ours where you have other sources
of nitrogen
in the soil already
but
the others uh you know calcium sulfate
gypsum uh
obviously uh all plants uh
like calcium
um
some more than others medicinal plants
or hogs and
they're gonna they're gonna want calcium
source strong source of calcium and
magnesium all the way through
uh growth really uh vegetative and cloud
but uh
potassium sulfate you're going to use
that quite a bit more in the later
stages
i would say
uh in lighter amounts um
and your
first three four weeks of flower
and then that's gonna get a little
stronger in
probably weeks four through eight four
through ten
i know there's some that you mentioned
that people often use as foliar feeds
you know they want that fast acting
perfect example would be if you have
you're starting to see magnesium
deficiency they'll do a full layer of
epsom salt
magnesium sulfate do you do any foliars
at all for those water-soluble mineral
inputs
we do
we like to use
the magnesium sulfate
a bioavailable version of silica
we uh we also pull your feed some ohn
and
um
a lot of our ipm is foliar
about to get off track there i know we
can get into that later but
let's see if i'm leaving anything out uh
even microbial uh
foliars you know we we have a couple of
different products one made right here
in oklahoma called wind river
and uh it's great in soil and as a full
year
um
see if i'm leaving anything out
i think that's really about it a few uh
stimulants
you know there's a couple different oils
that we use
that will stimulate uh the plant's
immune system if you will
and i think that's about it for four
years how often do you inoculate
microbes once a week at least we're
doing something uh you know we've got a
couple of different inoculations that we
like to use
some are more uh
well most of i'll be honest or more
fungally dominant
but we do have a couple of different
products even that we like
we've used
you know everything under the sun fish
[ __ ] um
mammoth p
uh but honestly
there's nothing like really good compost
and uh
you know you can do a lot of people
don't like to do teas indoor especially
um because of the risk you may take uh
brewing
uh
bad bacteria
so uh you know a top dress of compost
especially if you're using a good mulch
layer will go a long way you can water
that in
or
you can do
a concentrate you're basically straining
uh the compost
into the water and um
and creating a concentrated version
there and then using that to water in
instead of uh
brewing you know
and i'm i'm drawing a blank uh your soul
food web folks
uh are probably bigger your elaning and
folks are probably bigger on these
terminologies uh
and know them well
but uh
that's that may be a little safer
version and we often do that but we also
do teas and um
you know we use some uh species of
fungi
as
food cycling nutrient cycling
and you know
they're a benefit to the plant's health
and then
some are going to be more for ipm and
you know to keep pest pressure down
uh other bacteria
fungi and pests i'm glad you brought up
the the risk of brewing a tea which is
that you're brewing anaerobic bag
bacteria right which that's happened to
me before you know not having enough air
stones in the bucket and then giving it
to my plant and all of a sudden the
plant looks like crap for like several
days and it's like
you know eventually it bounced back but
it was a significant step back you know
so it can absolutely happen you know
making sure you have enough air stones
in there is important
some people actually put a airline going
directly into their bag of compost that
they put
into the bucket i don't know if you do
that as well or anything like that if
you've heard about that tip but i
thought that was pretty interesting
we haven't tried that um
so
uh we have a brewer that we built with
the help of leighton morrison um not
sure if you're familiar with him from
future cannabis project they do living
spoiled conversations
but leighton helped us uh build a brewer
here that we love it's a 55 gallon
tap coat tank
tone bottom
and then it's plumbed
and
has a really cool
uh air pump going to it that's
quiet and
low maintenance
but with that air entering the bottom
instead of using a stone it eliminates
the
need to clean a stone or you know
buy new ones you know you gotta you
gotta replace those things
after a while just from gunk
but um
now we've loved that brewer and
you know we'll use it even just a mix of
feeding
just to aerate our water not necessarily
to brew a tea
but just to have good aerated living
water
and
moving water
but
yeah
we that eliminated a lot of the
the bad issues with brewing for us and
then you know a few different things uh
about brewing
uh
you know our tips that we've been given
are um
you know strain your compost instead of
brew it that can often be uh
very helpful and you can
make that concentrated version of that
inoculant that away
and then water that in
but if you're seeing any brown uh around
the ring or the top of
your brew uh and you are brewing a tea
the stuff that starts sticking to the
side of your bucket
uh or your tank
that's usually uh
i believe kind of a bad sign of
that bad bacteria brewing that
anaerobic bacteria growing or maybe i
was told that it was waste of some sort
from uh you know the microbes
but um
anyways we tried to limit the times we
you know when we started out it was
sometimes 24-48 hours
of brewing
and then uh that eventually
got to where it wasn't really any more
than about 12.
and
by that time we're watering it in
and usually don't see any of that brown
film
stuck to the side
at that point so
i think that that avoids a lot of that
anaerobic activity
you know people run into you do like a
48 hour brew and you got a stinky
smelly uh
you know and that doesn't always happen
i think if you have enough sugar
carbohydrates in there for those
microbes to feast on and they don't die
off and they probably thrive for
you know not real sure how long but
yeah i typically do no longer than 24
hours sometimes i'll pull a little bit
earlier than that just to kind of safe
side things but i don't really do teas
that often i mean like you mentioned in
the beginning something you can just top
dress compost and water that in right
that's very effective as well so i'm
glad you mentioned that let's flip it up
let's talk about ferments i want to get
into this this is something that i
haven't done myself but i hear more and
more people talking about it so can you
talk to us about ferments what are they
how you go about doing them
you bet um
so we're in no in no way are we um
experts in ferments but
uh
van from k f garden
um
i met him at a convention here in
oklahoma in 2020 i believe
and uh
ended up using some of his techniques uh
we started off uh
with kind of his baseline in veg which
was humic and aminos
which is a great combination by the way
i'm not saying that's all plants need
but
we've seen good results from it
the the ferments that we used were his
versions
uh k f
and um
you know i think he's doing things uh a
little differently kind of a hybrid
version if you will
for him you know he lived in la i
believe and
didn't didn't really have a farm to
do knf
on
korean natural farming
and
i think simplifying it
was was probably what he was going for
but anyways you know fermentation
taking
fruit and vegetables
with sugar and allowing
or without i think a lot of people
actually do it without and
allow that stuff to break down
and
you know same process used for making
alcohol
but
all those nutrients become available
again
and
at some point you can stabilize it with
his recipe we were only going a couple
weeks
and using lots of different kinds of
fruits and veggies
um
and uh you know you try to
be responsible uh uh go get organically
grown fruits and vegetables and start
there if you're going to do it that way
but i think the whole premise behind
korean natural farming is probably
using the land you have you know to grow
those fruits and vegetables and then
fermenting them and
you know using that to feed some plants
feeding plants you know and you're kind
of speeding up that process with
fermentation
um
van's idea behind a lot of it
is
even
i think trying to push certain
cannabinoids and terpene levels uh and
using certain
fruits and vegetables uh to target those
um
so we started using this bloom ferment
and have now for
i would say five six months
with success
that's in a living soil system and
raised beds
and it's not only using ferments uh so
we're definitely a lot of the times
using less
than the suggested amount
and sometimes if we feel like they
really need something we may give them
more
but
um combining that with that
soul food web
i've seen nothing but amazing results
from
and you know i know there's a lot of
controversy there
uh
but i mean all in all it's uh
we're we're still doing the same thing
and we have the same goal
so for us it's always been about quality
you know
uh not necessarily
you know there's almost belief systems
built behind these methods
and if you veer
one from another
the community doesn't necessarily always
agree on stuff like that so
but for us it's always been about
providing the best possible medicine we
can
um and so if that's combining some of
these methods together
that's fine with us
do you have like a general recipe that
somebody can follow or like a source
that a noob like me can go to
and learn how to start fermenting
you bet uh go follow
uh
knf garden
um
go follow
uh you know uh jeremy has some great
ferment uh products that i've seen
available
so that's another good source
you know don't come to us for that
information necessarily i can give you
uh you know the
recipe that we use but
we're not uh
knf gurus by any means
uh you know the the man himself chris
trump
um
i believe that chris trump on instagram
lots of good ferment farmers out there
lots of good guys still in
cali uh humble region
using ferments uh
man i wish i could uh
i wish i could name them all off
on the spot
uh but that right there ought to get you
started and van's method is so super
simple
um
you know
you can't go wrong there uh i think he's
even selling uh his bloom ferment
uh so you can go buy that and just start
there and see
you know the difference but
uh
you know he uh uh
claims you're gonna see a greasier um
terpier flower and we have seen some
great results
uh from
our experience with that so
i think uh i think you can't go wrong
with
with his stuff j plant speaker i think
is another guy that may do some
hell i think masonic does some k s stuff
uh
you know lots of good teachers out there
yeah lots of sources there i'm familiar
with some of those names and not but not
all of them so i'll definitely be
following some of those names for sure i
do want to get into cover crops a little
bit so we're talking about making that
transition from synthetic to organic
cover crops is something that's optional
but a lot of people use it because there
are benefits to it right so for example
i use clover for a cover crop a white
dutch clover is the kind that i use
and one thing i've learned is that it
helps with nitrogen fixation so it's
actually taking nitrogen from the air
converting it and putting it to the soil
that's in a form that the plant can
uptake right so that's just one benefit
on one particular type of cover crop
there's a whole different types of cover
crops out there with various amounts of
various types of benefits for sure what
do you use for cover crops and kind
what's your process for planting them as
well
we're big on clover as well
and
native grasses are great you know
you just got to be careful
what seed you're starting with
uh because you never know how enough
that was grown or harvested
uh so you know build the soil
uh here in oklahoma we've got red bud
soil company and they make some great
cover crop blends
um
you know we also uh like planting stuff
like carrots and radishes and things
that are going to penetrate the soil
and feed everything in the soil or below
the soil
but uh a process
for planting cover crop
for us
uh we started with cover crop after
initially filling our beds and
everything
and then
we'll replant cover crop
after harvest when we've got access to
the soil again
and
really that's about it uh
that that
really takes care of itself
uh really well you're letting nature do
its thing
and
um
not too complicated
there you know so between grows when
you're planting that cover crop
how long are you letting that cover crop
grow and you know you're cutting it down
and letting it die off is there like a
period of time you know like two weeks
or a month or what's your time period
so uh we'll we'll plant and basically
let the cover crop grow
until it's um
maybe becoming annoying you know getting
a little bit out of hand
uh we may chop it back then
but a lot of the times we'll let that
naturally uh occur as well
and and i haven't had to do a ton of
uh maintenance now we don't use near as
much cover crop as a lot of people i've
seen
um
cantwell over greenlight productions has
usually got a pretty nice green bed
going it looks like and
we don't use quite that much i think he
uses dichondra and some other things
that we haven't tried yet but are very
interested in
um but yeah i would say uh
you know experiment with stuff like uh
carrots and and radishes and growing
even you know companion plants
uh with your medicinal plants uh or your
vegetable garden
um
now you'd be amazed uh
the difference in a bed full of plants
and a pot with one
and what you see going on there
uh they definitely enjoy one another
i think so too i've seen it
for sure
yeah so there are a lot of people trying
to make that transition from synthetic
to organic right taking a step back
generally speaking
what advice do you have for those
trying to make that transition
i would say be patient
uh
you know
everything may not play out just like
you want
especially that first run or two
you know if you're doing a no-till type
of method
that less is better mindset will go a
long way
and uh don't water so much
you know that's probably
one of the most common mistakes that
people make
going from
synthetics to organics
uh if you're using
a decent sized pot which i've heard
jeremy and others talk quite a bit about
uh
you know
there's gonna be enough moisture and
nutrition in that pot
to last that plant beyond you know what
we normally would think
and uh
yeah you know just be patient and
spend as much time reading and and
searching for
information as you can
uh an ounce of prevention is worth a
pound of cure
so
you know in an organic system where
things are a little bit more permanent
uh
the more research you do up front and
the and the
more prepared you are going into that
situation
uh the better your turnout's gonna be
for sure
well said
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future uh so the
listeners can find uh me and my family
rant farm at reddit raised okay on
instagram
and our website will be up soon red
dirtraisedok.com
um
if you come to oklahoma uh or if you're
in oklahoma you can find
uh the dispensaries and shops that we're
in
on our
instagram account or website and
yeah that's really uh
that would be the place email would be
redirtraisedllc.com
that's about it awesome well i'll
definitely have a link to at least your
instagram down in the description
section below i know youtube's kind of i
don't really like the medicinal plants
being linked down below so i'll see what
i can do as far as links to to your
stuff if you enjoyed this episode click
that thumbs up button i want to get as
many thumbs up as possible that helps on
youtube in particular in order to reach
more viewers
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already or press the follow button on if
you're on a podcast platform and share
this episode if you think others would
obtain value from it james thank you so
much for coming on to the podcast today
definitely some great information i
learned a thing or two and i think this
is valuable information to my audience
as well so thanks for coming on and i
hope you enjoy the rest of your day
thank you chris you too
[Music]
you