what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extras channel I've
got an unboxing and short walkthrough
for you today this is the gold wireless
thermometer and hygrometer this one is
actually Wi-Fi enabled they do have a
different model that is a
bluetooth-enabled basically this unit
not only tells you what the temperature
and humidity is when you're standing
next to unit but it also includes an
application that you can download on
your phone and you'll be able to see
what the temperature and humidity is
through the app as well as set up alerts
and we're going to walk through that a
little bit later on this video first
let's start with the unboxing of the
unit so as you can see here very nicely
packaged in this separate box right here
there are a few pieces to where you can
assemble into a stand or you can use one
of the pieces as a wall mount and I'll
show you how to do that in a little bit
this card right here has a little bit of
additional information it gives an email
for support so if you need any support
you can email them and it shows what
their social media is as well and lastly
is the user manual okay so my cat Stella
has decided to join me
she's pretty interested in this as well
and in order to get it to function you
basically just pull out this tab in the
back and then as you can see the unit
has that turned on now I'll remove the
clear plastic film and the unit is now
operational you can now see both the
temperature and the humidity okay so I'm
gonna quickly unbox one more of these
they actually sent me over four units I
personally have multiple grow areas so
I'll be using this device in four
different areas actually and on this one
I'm gonna actually place it into the
stands so you can see here I'm
assembling the stand it just simply
slides in super simple
[Music]
for now I'll place this one on the floor
microspace typically what I'll do is
I'll take a canopy temperature reading I
have my sensor push hung at the canopy
level right now
but I may eventually switch it out on
the other device I am going to mount it
to the wall and I only need one of the
pieces out of that separate box not both
of them so the piece that the unit
actually slides into is what I'll be
using and then I'll take the 3m
double-sided tape that is provided in
the box as well and then I will stick it
to the wall
okay now we'll go into the app and we
will do a quick walkthrough so first of
course you've got to get the app it is
available on both iPhone as well as
Android so I just downloaded the app and
I now have it open I just clicked the
top right corner to start you can see
that they have several different pieces
that are compatible with this is not
just thermometers hygrometers you can
connect LED strip lights copper wire
lights LED bulbs they've got other
lights and also additional smart home
accessories such as they do have like a
smart plug water leak detectors and so
on and so forth now the app is asking me
to sign in I actually need to sign up
this is the first time I've ever used
this okay so after signing in I am going
to add in the two devices so I simply
find the device on the list and click on
it
then it's gonna actually show which
devices are nearby so it can detect the
units that are on and you can simply
click them to activate them now it's
asking to hold down the button on the
device for three seconds to sync it all
together which I'm doing right now and
as you can see once it's synched it
actually blinks it gives the opportunity
click done now I'm adding the second
device doing the same thing we're just
basically find the device on the list
hold down the button on the unit for
three seconds that it all sinks together
alright so in the app it is gonna show
the temperature and humidity as you can
see here it's actually one of the
devices is actually selected at the
moment and you can change this from
Fahrenheit to Celsius you can also look
at the data in different ways whether it
be look at it for the day look at it for
the week month or a year I obviously
don't have any data yet since I just
activated device so it'll take time for
that to accrue going back to the main
menu can see both the devices are
visible there and then browsing around
to some of the different menu options
here is where you can add more devices
like I talked about a little while ago
here's some more things miscellaneous
things in regards to their community and
then here there are different profile
options that you can change let's click
back into one of the devices and let's
set the temperature and humidity ranges
so as you can see here I'm setting the
temperature range first in order to
activate I need to slide over the alarm
me and then when we go back into the
main menu can see that it does actually
show what the range is right there on
the home screen which is pretty cool
again a link to this product will be in
the description section below I just
wanted to do a quick walk through today
to show you guys what it's all about
what do you think of this unit let me
know in the comments section below
and I'll leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
peace
[Music]