coming up on garden talk the biggest
variable for me that i've noticed is the
phenotypes genetics genetic genetics but
the phenotype within the genetic has
been a big focus for me for the past
like maybe five years
sometimes you end up getting a bunch of
variations that are keepers i just was
over at a buddy's house today and he had
so many that they were dramatically
different enough that they should almost
have different names
make sure you label properly it's so
crucial so important you'll be so bummed
out when you're like oh man i didn't
label this funeral right and that was
the best one like it could be this or
it's this and it takes three more cycles
to find out they'll see somebody who's
just knocking out of the park they've
got to realize they got a very good
phenotype potentially good cut or
they've hunted the right one or they
just got lucky that happens sometimes
too but finding the right characteristic
expression within that particular
genetic i think is huge for any grower
to get the best results
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 69. in this
episode i interview rob from cltv he is
back for a second time on this podcast
this time around he's going to get deep
into the process of phenol hunting
plants something he has a ton of
experience doing thanks to all of you
who support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
call possible a big supporter of this
podcast is ac infiniti they sponsor this
podcast and i use their products
ac infinity now has gardening tools and
accessories such as heavy duty fabric
grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow it during
checkout for a discount on their
products thanks to spider farmer for
being a sponsor a new grow light they
released here in 2022 is the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co280 grow
space and really want to maximize the
light intensity it has a 10 bar design
for an even light spread pulls 1000
watts from the wall and comes in at 2.9
micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is 4 feet by 4
feet or 5 feet by five feet use discount
code mr growth 5 to save on all spider
farmer products and i'll leave a link in
the video description section below
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with rob
from cltv how you doing today hey
brother i'm doing great man happy to be
back on the show i feel like i don't see
you enough so i'm happy you brought me
over here
i was gonna say you're no stranger to
garden talk podcast right you're on
episode number one the very first
episode of this podcast was you
and we talked all about fertilizing
plants that one actually has over 261
000 views so it's like the the second
most viewed on youtube and of course
it's on all podcast platforms as well
but a ridiculous amount of people tuned
into that and there was a ridiculous
amount of people that had
real positive things to say about you
about that discussion and people want
you back for a part two so thanks for
coming back here dude get my lips dried
out with all that love though that's
pretty awesome man i really appreciate
that dude that is that's that's really
cool especially to see a conversation
like that that gets to the nitty gritty
of basics and then
you built so much more on the podcast
you know what i'm saying it went to
next level science so it's really cool
to see the inception to where it is now
yeah pretty incredible so today we're
going to get deep into pheno hunting
this is something that you have several
experience with
and you're very passionate about it too
so i'm really excited for this one but
first can you introduce yourself to
those that didn't catch the first
episode we did together yeah
if you don't know i'm rob from cltv from
the stash top buds rob blogs two
different channels um been a grower now
for about 14 years uh medical program
here as long as it's been available
since 2008.
so
let's say i've been growing legally for
14 years
definitely have some experience with
other plants but my main favorite is our
favorite herb and
overall since making content and i feel
like i
teaching people i've learned a lot as
well i've changed i've pivoted i've
grown with synthetics organics and the
biggest variable for me that i've
noticed as the phenotypes genetics
genetic genetics but the phenotype
within the genetic has been a big focus
for me for the past like
maybe five years once i really got got
away from the pick and mix and focused a
little bit more on
finding the variety within the single
cultivar
genetics are just so important i mean
that's like the emphasis on it sometimes
i don't think is enough between
particularly new growers like they don't
understand the importance of genetics
like you can have a dialed environment
you know lighting so on so for nutrition
can be dialed in but if you have bad
genetics i mean it's just it's not going
to come out anywhere near it would as if
you had good genetics
so um yeah phenotypes genotypes let's
get into it
let's dial it back for beginners though
like what is pheno hunting and why do it
no good question there's actually a lot
of debate kind of the bro science side
of female hunting people argue pheno or
geno hunting this is kind of a thing but
final hunting i feel is more of course
finding the characteristic expression
within the cultivar so i use the analogy
of let's say you have the same parents
and you've got brothers and sisters but
you all are a little unique but you all
maybe have the same gap like myself if
you don't know if you're just listening
or you all have you know hair color that
everybody's got red hair well it's a
genetic trait that's carried through but
there's still individuality between each
sibling so it's comparable when you see
a cultivar it's going to be similar
there and then plus the genetic
expression within your environment so
looking for the right cultivar when you
say you want to get a certain genetic it
may not even be that same genetic i for
example had a
i think it was agent orange
it orange something i can't remember
what it was but there was one cultivar
one version of it essentially one
phenotype that was very java coffee-like
and one that was very citrus and orange
i unfortunately was in the pickame
pick-and-mix phase of not knowing you
know different genetic expressions so i
got the java one and it was like this is
bunk i don't like this and it's like
well it was not the right phenotype and
that's really you know it took me about
nine years before i started really
realizing i'm like man i'm comparing
apples to oranges so to speak i'm
comparing my buddies totally different
cultivar essentially i mean it's the
same but it's different different
characteristic expressions that came
from it so that's when i really dove
into phenol hunting and i thought that
when you're looking for genetics you're
not looking for just genetics you're
looking for a particular phenotype
within that genetic so it's changed my
whole approach and i think a lot of
people when they look at one of their
buddy grows they'll see somebody who's
just knocking out of the park they've
got to realize they got a very good
phenotype potentially good cut or
they've hunted the right one or they
just got lucky that happens sometimes
too
but but finding the right characteristic
expression within that particular
genetic i think is huge for any grower
to get the best results
yeah so each seed is its own phenotype
right if you were to grow one plant and
then take clones of that plant that's
still the same phenotype so just a
couple things to mention there for for
those that don't know
but yeah there can be
so much variability depending on the
genetics depending on you know what
generation it is is it inbreeding that's
done how far down has it gone now we're
kind of getting to de breeding a little
bit we're not gonna really touch on that
topic deeply but
genetics there's variations that happen
with characteristics like you mentioned
and the environment definitely comes
into play heavily
when it comes to different phenotypes
and how they express themselves so do
you pheno hunt males plants female
plants or both currently just female
because i'm not doing any breeding i
don't have the capacity probably even
mental capacity to uh to do any breeding
i'm not on dr growit's level in terms of
even being a hobbyist and giving it a
shot mainly because right now i like to
just find different flower that i like
and while i can find that with breeding
there's some amazing breeders out there
that i'm gonna let them do their job and
then
you know maybe one day when i've got the
space i'll throw my hat in the ring but
for now i like what i got so i'm looking
for females usually only okay so females
only and you're starting from seed right
and then how many seeds are you planting
for your final hunt it's funny i i
thought i was doing a decent amount
until we had matt mooney on from the
stash
and he's talking about doing a hundred
and he's like yeah you know i'm gonna do
a little bit she's probably 100 i'm like
up
a little bit oh
okay well i'm doing 10 on average is
normally what i've done the most i've
done is 20 at a time and at that point
it was because i heard that there was a
lot of different variations of the same
cultivar so i figured why not i'm
looking for one in particular i'll cut
the rest off i just want one
and
sometimes it doesn't happen it's like
getting a pack of baseball cards or
pokemon cards you're looking for a
particular one
you kind of get duds sometimes you end
up getting a bunch of variations that
are keepers i just was over at a buddy's
house today and he had so many that they
were dramatically different enough that
they should almost have different names
they're not even in the same family like
it's
it's crazy those are the type that i'm
concerned about when you recommend it to
somebody because they may not get that
same phenotype issue which is where the
argument of cuts like we talked on from
the stash again referring back of where
you can't secure that exact phenotype
unless you go about that process
differently you can do a major hunt find
a bunch and then keep that secured or
you have to find that cut it's not as
easy as some would think it would be
really nice if we could plant a hundred
seeds like you mentioned and
and hunt through those but the reality
of it you know a lot of folks are home
growers i have a plant count i'm sure
you have a plant count as well in your
state so we have a maximum number that
we're allowed to grow
legally so staying with that that's
certainly important and you can still
have a phenol hunt within the matter you
know you could do like five plants ten
plants like you can do a low number it
doesn't have to be a hundred plants in
order to do a true phenomenon like you
mentioned you might not find what you're
looking for right so you might plant 10
15 seeds whatever and then none of them
are actually what you're looking for in
that cultivar then you start over right
you just you you kill off those plants
or consume those plants whatever and
then you just plant new seeds and
continue your hunt that's perfectly fine
yeah i'm doing that right now with the
chill at og and depending luckily i know
the guy who having to breed it so worst
case condition
if i don't find the one i'm after growth
wise they're just on point they both
look like twins but one is hungrier than
the other and one of them is noticeably
more tracked out than the other but who
knows at the end you know but it's hard
because when you're limited on the
phenotypes you have you're literally
kind of stuck between the two options
but it's cool you know at some points
but when they're so similar that's where
it's like where do you decide like which
ones you keep you know they're like the
same
then it's a good sign but i do sometimes
like those genetic variations where you
have
one that leans this way more sour
more more funky and another one that may
be more deep gas or more sweet so that
way you've got a little bit of variety
but also grow very comparable so that
way your candy or canopy could be even
and you do it like that you see um
gorilla butter they've got white
truffles that's one that i have that's a
cut most people just know it as that
genetic but it's actually a named
phenotype
you know gorilla glue number four that
number four is a number four for a
reason you know what i'm saying the
phenotype usually the number is what
people did nowadays to identify these
particular characteristics i personally
think it's okay to rename a cut as long
as you give you know respect and you
mentioned that this is a cut of this
particular cultivar but it's getting to
the point now where the the phenotypes
are the more focused what pheno did this
person have what phenos at that
dispensary what pheno did they they
secure if you're just getting seeds you
don't really know you're just saying i
got these seeds we'll see if i get it in
this pack
you know
that's true that's very true so when
you're starting your pheno hunt
what medium are you using to begin and
then also i guess container size
container type you talk about that yeah
um so when i first get started i'm
usually using like a solo cup to get
started with cocoa i'm usually nine
times out of ten using royal gold's
tuper but they run out often where i'm
at locally so i'll use an alternative as
close as i can i'll use maybe coco loco
and cut it with a little bit of base
regular cocoa and if anything add a
little perlite for some aeration and
then i start really like low on my food
if any food at all to begin for
nutrients whether that be organic side
or
mineral base is low dose to get going so
that way i can get the
the stronger growing obviously seed but
not overpower and kill it and burn it
when it's young because again i want to
get the most natural best
characteristics and expressions from the
genetics so i know which one i want to
keep
from there i'll move up to a larger pot
usually either one gallon or a three to
five it depends if i'm using a cloth pot
sometimes i'll just go right into a five
it just uh
i guess more for a mess not necessarily
anything behind that i just don't like
making a big mess and then uh just plain
water with uh light nutrients usually
low on like
150 200 ppm very very low
so
using synthetic bottled nutrients or are
you talking organics yes for synthetic
bottled nutrients appreciate you pulling
that one out okay yeah it's interesting
that you mentioned cocoa as your medium
because
there are so many variables that can
happen just within like the soil for
example within the medium and you're
starting with coker starting with an
inert medium do you have anything
against starting in soil like that's
pre-charged with nutrients does that
kind of
i mean there's so many variables i
personally feel like if you're starting
in a soil that's already pre-charged
with nutrients you really don't know
what's in that mix
not every single one of those mixes can
buy it kind of be the same off for each
container i mean but when you're in
cocoa you're starting with an inert
medium you're mixing up your nutrients
that are the same ppm and you're
distributing them all to the to the
individual plants right so it's kind of
like more dialed in as far as feeding
what are your thoughts on like
phenomenal i mean certainly can still be
done within soil but like
what are your thoughts overall on that
avenue no i i that's a very very valid
question i think if you're looking to
scale or if you're in a caregiver
operation or looking to go craft or
commercial that should be a big focus
you want to get the best expression
period but if you already have an
established garden you want to integrate
what works for your established garden i
don't think changing everything to fit
one cultivar would make sense unless
this is the one that you need for
medicine and it's going to change your
life or your family's life maybe but
otherwise like if let's say you are a
firm believer using uh
you know build a soil and you're running
that and you don't want to change
because you're like well i've been using
this mix forever you know then make sure
it works with with what you have if that
genetic doesn't that phenotype doesn't
well then it's telling you it's not
meant to be in your garden that's that's
my belief at least personally but if
you're looking to take this as a
business or profession or a real serious
hobby then maybe you do want to start
totally clean
and
get the best version of that particular
cultivar the particular phenotype of the
cultivar doing it that way i don't
really think about it in that way but
that's that's a great point that you
made there that makes sense
so you've got your plants growing and
during a phenol hunt the plants are
going to start to show different
characteristics there are many different
characteristics that you can look for
when phenol hunting what characteristics
do you look for it's a good question as
well so only recently have i really
really focused on leaf to bud ratio
wasn't a big thing for me before um the
stacking of the nodes how tight the
nodes are in the leaf to bud ratio
because i'm a solo trimmer 90 of the
time and big shout out ac infinity
because i got the trim bowl from them i
can use that that'll help but for the
most part
i've had some cultivars that i let go in
the past you know a couple years 11
roses being one of them it was great
very very nice one
but i hated trimming it so that's like
my first factor is like
is this a squatty
leafy mess that's going to it's going to
be a lot of work to train it let alone
finish it that's like number one as i'm
looking then that speed of growth now it
depends because
prep example chill out og was slower
grower for me big wide but not tall and
lanky like my others but the the
stacking of the nodes i was like
like this growth here i can have these
big tall you know amazon women here that
have stretchy nodes or i have these
shorter ones that are compact with not
crazy leaves so it's another check in
the book where i'm like man that leaf to
bud with the node stacking really makes
a big difference it kind of trumps the
the speed of growth for me because again
i'm going to potentially get more yield
once it's in flowers and flower
so there's that i don't really focus a
whole lot on
like the leaf size or
anything in that sense but i do look a
little bit on some genetics i notice
will get those natural purple stems like
just reddish kind of purple stems i do
try to avoid those ones when i can it
just seems like they want more or less
they're a little finicky but some
cultivars lately especially i've been
noticing
they purple up as a plant and that's
kind of like in the genetic makeup of it
so i look at something that doesn't show
me the the tendencies of stress early on
something that's not going to show me
that it may need more down the road that
it's going to fit within my cycle
because i don't want to have especially
synthetic i don't want to have multiple
different containers or reservoirs with
different amounts of nutrients for a
couple different cultivars if half of my
room something and the other half is
that maybe but otherwise like if you're
not working in my mix already
he gots to go it's not gonna it's
that'll again kind of push everything
out because it's like man i really have
to work hard to make you last
versus i mean you got to put in work but
if i'm already putting work over here
and what's already established what i
like
i'm not going to throw the risk over
here with this final hunt to take
something in that's going to mess up my
whole cycle
and then once we're in the flower of
course i'm looking trichome production
i'm looking at um
i wouldn't say i'm i'm
huge on bud structure per se i don't
want fox tilly stuff but i do like some
stuff that's got some density i don't
like super airy you know fluffy
sativa-like so to speak in terms of
plant growth structure so i'm trying to
find something that that fits and has
that tightness to it but also has the
trichomes to look color is not a big
deal at all for me personally and purple
is just purple but when you get that
it's a nice perk to pick wow look at
this exotic stuff here change the game
you know
it's
it's not a huge deal but the number one
factor for me number number one
is those terps types of flavonoids
flavonoids find out later but the terps
if i'm smelling that and i don't smell
anything or if it smells like something
i don't like at all it's like i'm
getting rid of these clones right now
don't even want to do this not even keep
her around personally okay so you named
off a large handful of things that
relate to the morphology of the plant uh
and also the the chemotype as well you
talked about now how about
do you look at when the plant starts to
flower at all or the total flowering
time does that matter to you at all or
no total flowering time is one for me
only recently again i find that out with
the gmo where i was like i could wait 13
weeks worst case i pull these others
these two are still in here for a little
while and i'm good well if you grow them
like your others they're huge and take
up space and your canopy is wonky and
weird because of that setup depending on
your setup if you've got a 4x4 it might
be the whole tent if you've got a larger
space or an open space it's throwing
everything off and i can't stand that i
can't stand the something that's going
to be a staggered cultivar that doesn't
necessarily give me the results i want
so if i know it's going to be a long one
it usually doesn't even make it into the
grow
this one was just sheer ignorance me not
looking it up so yeah i don't
necessarily focus too heavy on that but
i guess at the in the same
same side like a late bloomer so to
speak something that's it doesn't get
going quicker that also is an issue for
me too sometimes because right now i'm
dealing with that with the um the white
truffles
it's like i have to grow that all
together otherwise it just seems like my
canopy fills out it stretches longer
than the others do it it keeps that
stretch going versus the others start
flowering quicker and i'm like man i've
got a canopy that slides down like a
mountain
they don't have to put it up on crates
or something to make it real even and
when you're using trellising or anything
for stability that could be a real
headache so i guess i do look at both
factors they're just not as crucial
other than the time of how long
it takes not doing 13 weeks anymore ever
okay and then going back to the smell
one of the common techniques that people
use when they're phenol hunting is the
stem rub technique so they take their
fingers
and they'll basically rub the stem and
then they'll smell their fingers and see
if they're it's what they like it's what
they're looking for do you do that
technique at all or are you doing
something else you know i have in the
past and usually if it's got a sharp
smell then usually there's sharp
terpenes but the distinct
distinctiveness of that terpene i don't
get from the stem rub i get either if
anything like a lime with chlorophyll
cucumber kind of smell but it's sharp
where i'm like
that's good it smells smells like flour
you know but not
like the gas or like the berry or
whatever the actual flower really gives
but when i smell one then it smells like
nothing it's like is
nothing there you know i literally don't
smell anything that's going to be
different for me because i just right
off the bat my assumption this could be
placebo my assumption is the flower is
going to be the same way
so then i it just drops down in my book
when i'm like in my phone i'll usually
document everything in google keep and
then i have evernote that i'll use for
like just backing up the specific
details i don't always have to add a lot
of stuff but if there's something like
that i'll be like this one smells like
cardboard
there's nothing here this is drywall
okay and then another common thing that
people do is they'll deliberately
stress their plants
at certain times throughout their grow
now they do it for for various reasons
right they could do a
a stress for feeding purposes to see how
well it handles nutrients they could do
stress to try to bring out more trichome
development are you doing any type of
precision stress throughout the grow at
all while you're female hunting so my
first run and i feel like you'll
probably ask me about this at a certain
point my first run when i'm doing a
final hunt i don't
do a whole lot to the plant sometimes
i'll
barely even low stress train or top it
you know what i'm saying just because i
want to see what it does naturally i've
had a few cultivars that grow like
christmas trees and i've had a few that
come out looking like they've been
topped like naturally top themselves i'm
like what how do i have so many goals on
this one i did nothing that for me shows
a lot of just natural characteristics
for the growth then after that i'm like
all right well what can i do to
manipulate this better should i
do more of an aggressive high stress
training or should i do like an actual
lower technique lower stress technique
and at that point it's usually the
second or third run before i even really
start to get to manipulation in that
area
now with with nutrient stress i usually
never do that because i've already i
have a perpetual growth so i'm already
running ones that i like in there so i'm
not going to just increase heavy on the
ppm they see just for the one
but
if i'm doing a full room like i did
recently with the uh the truffles which
is a particular pheno i had but it's do
i want to keep this genetic in my garden
i ended up going higher in everything
like even my light was more intense just
to see how it it turned out and it
handled the stress pretty well tons of
trichomes the fade was insane on it
looked better than any i've seen in
person personally of any of these
truffles and i can't take the credit for
it it just seems like that genetic can
take a little more and in its defense
will express more you know cool color
more trichomes more terpenes more things
like that
so i don't go too hard early but i give
it some time to integrate it into my
garden before i really
you know hit it gotcha and then you did
touch upon
training a little bit
i know some folks what they'll do is
they'll go as far as you know in order
to testify the vigor of the plant
they'll actually snap branches to see
how the branches snap
do you do anything like that or no i
don't but i've got a buddy who does that
all the time he's very very very
aggressive with the plant to see he's
like see if he ends up getting seeds or
something
i'm like oh i'm trying to see if it
hermes which i guess like you know i get
where that comes in because what if an
accident happens once you have this in
production so to speak you really should
stress test it just like anything that
goes to market it gets a stress test if
you give it the most perfect environment
it's like yeah of course it does good
but you know
move it to somewhere more difficult and
it's not going to perform the same way
so giving a good stress test could help
me personally i don't i don't go that
hard with it i don't want to break them
my goal at the end is to have a decent
amount of high quality product and
if i'm
delaying the the flowering period or the
vegging period by doing some stuff like
that it's not beneficial to me
personally unless i have a lot of
you know clones from that particular
phenotype so that's usually the second
run where i'll get a little more well
second or third and i'm like oh let's
see what this does let's see if i top
this or bend this down or just crack
this over here just put a little tape
around it see if it recovers
you know and
it it's good to find out but then at
that point i've already kind of decided
what i've liked in terms of flavor so
then it's like is this that much better
of a grower that i can sacrifice a
little bit of the terpenes and a little
bit of the end result product for this
and i guess the mentality for me isn't
the same as for someone who's looking
for production for you know caregiver
caregiver side of hand but we'll just
say other reasons
wink wink if you're not watching but
some people may be focused heavier on
the yield and they could sacrifice a
little bit of the terpenes and more and
more people don't care as much about
terpenes which sounds crazy but i'm
realizing this people just like myself
who will drink corona or bud light or
miller light aren't chasing after the
flavor of beer as much as we are the
effect of beer as for somebody you know
same with flavor for for flour they may
not be looking for that crazy unique
terpene but they want something in the
ballpark a light undertone
so somebody may be looking at a
characteristic or treating it a certain
way for different variables than myself
that's a really good way to put it it
seems like more and more people are
caring less about biomass and more about
things like blood density
terpenes
and so on so forth i'm actually doing a
phenol hunt right now so for those that
don't know i have my own cross
it's briskero g male i cross with a
female of pakistan valley and that's
named chilo do g it's actually
inbreeding i'm going down to generation
f2 right now i'm working on that going
to an f3 but i don't do any training i
didn't do any training this run just
letting the plants grow naturally seeing
how its natural shape occurs right i was
looking particularly for that branching
to naturally come out
versus i mean i get some cultivars where
you just got that one cola coming
straight up and really not much side
branching but having that branching and
having a more even structure it's easier
to train in the future have that even
canopy even bud structure across all the
branches so on and so forth so yeah i'm
just like you where i don't really do
much training i just kind of look at the
plan naturally and see how is that
structure looking you know yeah 100 i
think that's where you can really decide
if this genetic just out of the gate is
a beast just like i mean anybody can be
an athlete if you train enough and you
work out enough and you take the right
supplements maybe even steroids if
you're weird like that but whatever you
want to do you can get to that point too
and some people are natural athletes
where they're just this ox and just a
tank and it's like man you're a lineman
like look at trey and look at me i
cannot defend you running down to the
the finish line like i may push one
person trey will debo somebody nadamikon
zoo style step on you walking through
boom boom you'll see that with plants
too you'll see some big hearty monsters
that are just these next level ones that
you don't have to do as much work to and
you're yielding like crazy and others
that you really have to manipulate to
get to that point
so you really want to see the natural
characteristics i feel in a female hunt
before you
you do that i agree
i do want to go back to lighting for a
few minutes here uh you touched upon it
a little bit some people are actually
going to push their plants with lighting
so they're trying to they're measuring
the ppfd they're measuring that par
and they're trying to increase it and
give it um the maximum amount as
possible and seeing how the plants are
going to react other people what they're
doing is they're
lowering the light level and they're
kind of making sure that the plant isn't
suffering you know what i mean that it's
it's it's coming across without having
issues that it's like a normal grow i
guess you could say nothing extreme are
you doing any sort of light manipulation
uh either stressing it with more light
or you just kind of having normal light
levels or reduce light levels when you
are phenomenal so kind of like i
mentioned uh before once i get
once i decide i like this flavor and i'm
gonna keep it around then maybe i'd
start doing more of that i'm doing it
right now with the white truffle and
that's not necessarily a phenotype it's
just a cultivar a phenotype of the
cultivar so
once i get further i do that but i
really like to just integrate it into my
garden so i don't want to push it like i
know i would never go that much higher
with my light so why do it i know i
would never add much more nutrients so
why do it like i wouldn't go and just
randomly break branches so i do it you
know what i'm saying like i want it to
fit into my garden or else it's not
gonna fit into my garden my flavor
choice is one thing i'm very blessed i
work with companies like franklin field
so they can grow some stuff that i may
not love i mean i love it but i mean i
love to grow
and then i can grow the stuff that fits
for my particular garden i notice right
now everything i have is
kind of lenkier got that sativa like
look other than the cell at og which is
squattier and thick tight colas already
and
so far like that would have to be a solo
run you know what i'm saying like the
cello would have to be like mono crop so
to speak where i'm just going to run
this
by itself so i could fill the room up
canopy's even train the same done right
versus these lanky ones that i have to
really manipulate and work to even fit
in the same space it's just
the cultivars don't match together so
my light intensity of what i would do to
increase it is going to be when i do
maybe the solo run by itself after i've
kind of run it through my personal crop
i see how i like it see it's doing good
move it to a four by four then push it a
little bit like man can i get maybe more
out of this can this handle more like
this may be that that random unicorn out
there that hits all the marks but then
also can take more so i can push it i've
got this uh x3 ultra from chiltek and
it's like let's see what we can do baby
let's see what we can do you know so i
imagine since you're doing different
stressors throughout multiple runs a
common technique that people do i
believe you do is you take clones at
some point so you'll grow the plants and
during the vegetation stage i don't know
how long you're vegging the plants for
but at some point you're taking clones
and then you're having those clones kind
of like on the side on standby and then
you're finishing up your phenohunt and
then you're i guess you're taking those
clones and then you're doing your next
run is that kind of how that's working
yeah yeah the next clone would be like
my temporary mother which i usually
don't keep a mother plant around for a
while but just to secure that genetic
i'll have one that i'm like well i'm
just going to cut on you you're not
doing nothing just to make sure i keep
you like i don't want to sacrifice it by
mislabeling something or it gets lost in
the mix not happening so usually what
i'll do is about two three weeks before
i flip in the flour i'll do my you know
stripping of the bottom area and i'll
take most of those cuts sometimes a
couple from the tops but to make sure i
got an adequate amount of time for
recovery before i flip the flower now
flipping a flower isn't necessarily
being in flower just a light cycle so i
still got that thyme that little window
of vegging still so to speak so the
plants really fully recovered by the
time i go back in there now the next run
of clones is already sitting in the
cloner they're going and i'm growing
them with less
like a full intention i'm doing the
manipulation to the plant i'm doing some
training but knowing that hey i may not
keep these four here depending if i
don't like this pheno like i literally
will go in there call the herd if i have
to i don't want to have a room full of
stuff i don't like i've got
way more flower stuff i don't like than
what i do so currently even still like
don't even want to smoke it so it's to
the point where you you really have to
pick and choose when you're in a smaller
space and you're final hunting like how
many clones am i going to take because i
may not keep all these clones i've done
that before where i've got 10 of each
and it was so stupid because i only
wanted to keep one out of five of the
phenotypes
and so i had 50 when i was more i had
more more patience at the time
and it was a big mistake because my
whole run was just stuff i didn't like
man it was just as flat as it gets to
80s booty just nothing so
for me how i will run my stuff is three
clones of each sometimes two and it'll
be labeled as uh like chillado ga
chiloto gb total gc and then i've got
those added into my phone and i know
that they're within row a
one two three row b you know what i'm
saying so that it's pretty easy to know
what i've got and that way once it comes
back through the larger plan that's in
flower that's labeled chill at oga child
gb i could choose the one i like and say
i really didn't like this one over here
so you're gone but you two i gotta we're
gonna run you again i'm gonna i gotta
see which and battle of the bands with
you and see which is better because a
lot of times for me i don't know to the
second or third run
like from going from from
directly from the start yeah your plant
may be hardier and you have the tap root
and everything there you're doing great
there but then from a clone
i feel like i can really find like do i
like this smoke is this what i want
growth is a big thing but i'm a
connoisseur so i want to know after a
run or two how it's reacting to my
garden how this next one was acclimated
to my environment that's when you really
see the the phenotype expressions i feel
like is when your environment gets used
to it when i first take in a cut it's
like that runs pretty good i see it's
good but the next one is like damn i
don't know what i did but this is fire
it's like i changed nothing it's just
been here now i think it's getting used
to my routine and the plant is
acclimating to it how long are you
typically keeping your plants in the
vegetation stage when female hunting
this one was longer than normal because
i wanted to take a fair amount of cuts
so i kept it in for about maybe nine
weeks ballpark normally it's six to
eight weeks at the most like at the very
most because again the stretch that i
normally get with the other cultivars i
didn't know anything about the cellos in
particular because that's what i'm doing
the phenom hunt of right now i wasn't
sure how they'd grow it's like are they
going to be lanky is going to be tall
then how fat and squatty they were to
get going and then they morphed in a
couple weeks i'm like
all right so we're just going to see
what you ladies do and get you going
longer and then i had did a little bit
of training to it to two of them that
were just a little link here and i was
like yeah it's
i see how you grow you know what i'm
saying like i'm going to train you and
then there were dudes so i'm like no
no if i was hunting for males they would
have been prime candidates because they
reeked like outside smells when i cut
him down the garbage reeked so that was
a
probably a good breeder i probably
should have got you some final in there
but
when you're looking for
what's right for you sometimes you got
to give it a little more time because if
you want to take a fair amount of cuts
you're going to be putting a plant in
there that's not at its full
potential because it's been hacked on
and chopped out and worked you know
yeah i get exactly what you mean
so you've got your plants growing
at what point you start to kill off
plants are you letting them grow all the
way through and killing them off are you
like looking at the characteristics
during each stage of growth and then
killing off plants like for example
killing off plants in the vegetation
stage then maybe you're putting him into
flower and then evaluating what they
look like and then killing off plants
and flowering so on and so forth how do
you go about like killing off plants
yeah because i'm more of a connoisseur
than like i'm a grower but i'm a smoker
more than anything i feel like i'm a
gore because i'm such a smoker and so so
picky but i do love to grow um i
normally don't let it go until it's
fully cured like i won't even consider
cutting them they're they're gonna stick
around until i know and then sometimes
again that second run i'll let it go
through again
if i would have done this maybe i let it
go a little longer you know i know it
says you know 60 or 70 days but maybe 75
baby would have would have brought up
something more so i usually will wait
you know i'm not gonna kill it there's
been too many times i've had my great
white buffalo so to speak the one that
got away man and it's
it's depressing there's this sour cush i
always remember i'll never forget it so
good and then uh holy grail cush that
was another one i went through 10 packs
of that one ten packs never found the
same phenotype
so it's like
you can't let stuff go until you know
and it's just it's man those are bars
too but it's mandatory it's mandatory
you gotta you gotta let it go through
all the way to see because it could
change in the last couple weeks that
cure could change the game but if it's
growing so poorly and it's going to ruin
your production
you may want to call herd just depends
yeah because i mean there's good i know
there's some female hunters that they're
looking for that vigor and if they find
like in the vegetation stage that it's
just a overall weak plant they'll kill
it off then i actually did a fetal
hunting talk with northwest jay on this
podcast as well i think it was like
episode number five or episode six or
something like that and he was talking
about how he's never killed off a female
plan he's always done the same thing you
do which is let it grow all the way till
the end harvest dry cure
then consume and then kind of make his
decision there so yeah that's
a couple different ways to go about it
for sure
depends on who you are kind of what
you're looking for within the plant on
whether or not you're going to kill off
plants at all or if you're just going to
let them kind of grow through
my next question which you kind of
already touched on a little bit do you
select just one
pheno that is a keeper or multiple
phenos and you kind of already mentioned
that you know you go through the first
run you'll have multiple keepers you'll
put them through a next run as well are
you going through these multiple rounds
at what point you know that this is the
one
all other females that i've been working
with are going to get killed off it's
crazy man it's only been more recently
with the new genetics like the last time
i remember the last genetics that i
popped
that
there was a clear winner and clear knot
was tga sub cool where i was like i mean
they're all good but this is like this
is obviously the one they're talking
about this is the vortex this is it you
know what i'm saying like boom boom boom
we're good as we're now it's like
the stability of a lot of the genetics
it's not always a bad thing but it's
like there's so many variations that i
find within these where i'm like man
that's so different like it's nothing
like this yet the plant looks the same
but the flavor isn't even in the
ballpark like this is gassy funky this
is total lemon
like how did they
come in the same pack but they look the
same so at that point it's like yeah i'm
keeping them around but if it's like
well this one just is a mild version of
this
like headbanger is a prime example
headbanger was either
kind of flat heavier yielder like it it
looked the same but it yielded way
better but the smell was just really
mild same with the flavonoids and the
other which was smaller yielder looked
comparable in the structure but fire
terps just
so it was like well dead ass obvious
which one am i going to keep as the
connoisseur the one that as potent as
can be that's that's my keeper so i
think it does depend on the genetics
you're dealing with these newer age ones
that don't have the right cross or don't
have the right testing
you may find a few you may find like
five six you know some of the older ones
that have been tested and been around
and been
selected properly it seems like you find
less dramatic shifts within those
phenotypes so you won't need to keep as
many there's no reason to have two that
are really comparable what's the point
you know
i know what you mean i'm actually like i
mentioned going through a phenol hunt
right now and
i'm looking really for a shorter plant
because the brisker og side of things is
very tall stretchy typical og very
finicky once it gets those heavy buds
it'll just be flopping all over the
place while the pakistan valley is real
short stout
real nice bud stacking and uh kind of
stays upright it doesn't really flop
over like the like the brisker does so
kind of keeping that plant short was one
of the things i was looking at however
in this grow i'm seeing that the ones
that are a little bit taller
are just packed on with trichomes so i'm
like oh great i mean geez
do i really want to go for the smaller
one at this point or do i really want to
look at the one you know keep the one
that has the just covered in trichomes
like there's no
it's not much of a comparison now the
other ones are starting to stack on
trichomes here later on in flowering
which i thought was pretty interesting
but like right off the bat this
particular female just stacked with
trichomes and it really
made me
question whether or not i'm going to
keep the shorter one out of the bunch
just because it's it's shorter right
because the trichome production i mean
that's something that is more important
for me
of course when i'm gonna go through
smoking them all consuming them all and
so on and so forth but uh
it was kind of interesting how things
kind of flip-flopped a little bit for me
as i'm going through the hunt yeah well
like it that's the big thing too is
as a connoisseur i kind of like the the
fact that i can get two
two holographics in my pokemon card so
to speak in my pokemon pack as where
before you each get in one you know so
it's like saying with seeds we'll say
that's my analogy for you nerds out
there um is is you can have
more really cool options in one pack
we're spending that kind of money on
these that's kind of cool man like
people will be like oh which one did you
get you get the one that lean more
brisker or like that's that's cool then
you'd eventually have a cut that's like
oh this is the particular cut of this
because there's two or three highly
sought after phenotypes in here like i
think that's really cool in my opinion
versus like
duh duh duh duh dank
like that's what i'm more used to with a
lot back in the day and while those are
usually more
stable so to speak that's what people
will scream about
as a kind of sewer man i like to have
some variations i think it's cool yeah i
agree with you so there are so many new
growers that are coming onto the market
today you know starting to grow i mean
we've got
rhode island that just legalized for
example there's gonna be a whole bunch
of people from rhode island coming on to
grow and they're gonna start phenol
hunting so we have a lot of beginner
phenol huntings that are tuning into
this podcast today what advice you have
for someone who's new to fetal hunting
labeling make sure you label properly
it's so crucial so important you'll be
so bummed out when you're like oh man i
didn't label this funeral right and that
was the best one like it could be this
or it's this and it takes three more
cycles to find out
you gotta run them all again to be like
ah
i don't know well it cuts a cut like you
won't know until part way through the
growth and then you're seeing some
characteristics but how familiar are you
with that plant when you just ran it for
a final you know i've lost some great
great phenotypes great ones by being a
[__] and doing too much at once doing
three hunts with 10 packs or 10 per pack
each and so i'm documenting all these
different phenotypes and just trying to
find if it's male or female let alone
the characteristics of what i want to
keep or what i don't want to keep
there's too many variables that come
into play so if you don't properly
document and and
track things as you're wasting your time
you just you just grow a lot of seeds
that's all how do you physically label
the plants there are different ways to
do it some people have those like
plastic tags that actually wrap around
the branches some people just do the
plant tags that you write on and stick
within the soil what i'm doing this
round is i took a sharpie and wrote on
some painters tape and then stuck it to
the side of my plastic grill pod
how do you label your plants the ladder
that's that's what i do oh ghetto good
old-fashioned tape and well it sometimes
leaves an ugly mark on your pot for me
it's very easily visible to see i'm like
boom boom boom all right boom and for me
right now my left side is all chilled oh
g's of my tent so i know these are
chillato g's so i look for a b c you
know easy there now i've only got a and
b which worked out because those are the
two i like the most and
i don't have as much of an issue when i
organize it properly in that sense now
not only will it be visibly right there
but i have it in my phone just in case
humidity or some sort of thing happens
the tape falls off
whatever i just know that i mean they're
in trellis so they're not moving they're
being scrogged like not fully scrub
these are just being trellised my other
side's being more of a screen and green
technique and i know left over here
right over here it's like battle
battleship you know battlefield
battleship i know that in this
coordinate over here this is this ship
this one over here this is the ship
meaning you know the chill at ogs so
i've got my process down but when you're
doing a bunch at once
and you're moving stuff around and
they're not all stationary like very
visible i think honestly probably
putting them right around the the stem
or the branch itself for the some people
on the branch the side like an apple
tree or they'll do it around the the
base
of the i'm just pretty medicated we'll
say i can't even think of the word the
stem
stock stock samsung stock
and then you talked about
documenting it and
i'm sure you have some sort of you talk
about the columns so is it like a
spreadsheet that you have on your phone
like google sheets or something like
that or like what is your
doc like tracking document look like so
on uh evernote you can add tables
evernote's a free program or you could
do the premium version i have premium
because i use it for business
but you can have a table that you set up
and then you could do a b c d e f g
one two three four five six seven eight
boom boom boom boom and lay them out
like that so that's usually i'll do it
visibly
or visually like that so that way it's
easy for me to just pop it and look doom
good to go and that's linked to my
google keep which says vino hunting i
just click that opens up evernote
boom it's right there and then that kind
of correlates with my cloner so i can
see the cloner set up there and then
basically in that
like the numbers and letters the first
ones are always going to be the ones
that are actually in those letters the
other ones are going to be my grow text
because i don't have abc
in the grote i just know that it's laid
out one two three four five six seven
eight usually i do eight my four by
eight then i'll do four in my four by
four so these are in a b c d
so it's pretty for me it's simple i used
to do color coordinating and then i was
doing way too much phenohunting and i
couldn't get enough colors i'm like why
can't we get like an auburn
or like a lime green so i can you know
differentiate all the stuff but it's
it's not easy man it's not easy mine's
pretty similar to what you imagine i use
google sheets which another free program
similar to microsoft excel
and on the
columns so up top i actually have the
plant so whatever plant number it is for
example and then on the rows going down
would be the date
and then uh and i'm just basically
looking at the date and then scrolling
across to whatever plant and then
entering in my notes
what are some of the things that you
log like are you tracking you know
feedings are you doing ph ppm are you
doing transplant dates like what are you
putting on that log i usually do feeding
on there so like if i'm doing
uh
for a long time i'd do like three times
a week i'd feed but in the past
year i've been feeding every time i
water other than one time it's like if
it's i go in the room and it seems like
really dry and then like the humidity
fluctuates here in michigan often so at
that point i'll change it but i notice
that the plant if it's having any signs
of stress that's when i'll market it's
like all right well i'm switching to
flowering nutrients let's mark it let's
see how it's going to do
oftentimes with those ones i don't have
to put anything back there again unless
it shows stress but at least have it
marked so i can go back and say all
right at this time and it shows the last
time the document was edited or it was
modified on evernote so i'm like this
date did this here okay clearly that was
the problem it's very obvious to see
like you know i consume a lot of my
products so sometimes i forget gotta go
back and check awesome cool i think that
gives a pretty good picture of how you
do your pheno hunting i mean there's so
many different ways to go about it we
talked about just you know some of the
characteristics that you can look for in
your plants i'd love to know in the
comment section below for you guys
tuning in what do you look for in your
plants when you're feno hunting
definitely let us know so i appreciate
you sharing your secrets with us on how
you do your final hunting tell us how
can the listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future well i'm
on a show with a dude named pigeons420
and another guy you may know may or may
not know i'm not sure um because it's mr
growit
from the stash podcast uh check us out
on youtube or twitch
then uh rob blogs another place i kind
of just
put random stuff that i'm doing or you
know some garden updates here and there
different things periodically stuff that
doesn't include my partner in crime not
crime all legal
trey strong's over on seal tv that's
another
show we have and then top buds with
pigeons uh 20 as well so all those are
available on twitch and youtube find the
socials over on instagram rob cotb
and then watch cltv for all that make it
easy just watch seal tv boom
sweet well definitely a link to your
channel down in the youtube description
section below if you're on one of the
podcast platforms just search for him
he'll pop up if you enjoyed this episode
click that thumbs up button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend i'm
releasing a new garden talk podcast
episode and i'd love for you to tune in
to future episodes also in the
description i'll definitely link down
the episode one that we did so the first
episode first time around and if you
haven't seen that one tune into it it's
gonna be a lot different that was almost
two years ago i can't believe how fast
time has flied that was the start that's
how we kind of started you know that's
how we linked up from the stash game
shortly half us nuts yep yep we started
uh just off of that episode and then we
started a whole new podcast after that
and then uh continued on with the garden
talk and here we are two years later so
crazy all right i'll leave it to that
once again rob thanks for coming on and
for all you tuning in catch you in the
next episode peace