coming up on garden talk pressure
treated two by fours
i spaced it out around five feet and
goes the length of 34 feet
and then i have the opening on each end
with a door
green lacewing larva and that's what the
alison flowers are for
because they'll eat that while they're
staying around and getting to the mites
or getting to the
other pests the plant doesn't care i'm
an advocate for that i really don't
think the plant cares about
the science that we keep trying to
implement on it
i think it's overboard and just a sales
tactic
the california spider mite will swim
through almost all your products
you have to be spraying diligently like
every three days
it was 122 degrees in there and the
plants were just
praying not worried about a thing
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 22.
in this episode i interview frosty
mcnasty he has been gardening for seven
years
and grows a variety of plants such as
tomatoes
bell peppers strawberries medicinal
lavender
rosemary sunflowers and much more in
this episode we talk about greenhouse
growing we cover everything from how he
built his greenhouse
pest prevention supplemental lighting
light deprivation
and a little bit about how he grows his
plants and his greenhouses
that's right greenhouse is he has
multiple if this is your first time
tuning into this channel i would love to
have you subscribe
if you're listening to this podcast on
apple podcasts please leave a rating in
review
that helps with ranking and also helps
reach more people some of you have asked
about other ways to support the podcast
i do have a patreon if you'd like to
support in that way the link is
patreon.com mr growit and there are
different tiers on there that unlock
various rewards before we get into the
episode i'd like to give a shout out to
our sponsors
the first sponsor is dutch pro nutrients
dutch pro sent me over their entire
lineup of nutrients and i'll be using
them in an upcoming grow
they are a plant fertilizer company that
was established in amsterdam 30 years
ago
their nutrients are available in several
countries across the world and they have
everything needed for proper plant
nutrition
they have different base nutrients
depending if you're in soil or cocoa
hydro and also different base nutrients
if you're using hard water or ro water
to really dial things in
they also have ph regulators and
additives such as calmag
silica pk booster and more i'll leave a
link to their amazon store
down in the description section below
and you can use coupon code
mrgrowit10dp for a discount on their
products
the second sponsor is spider farmer
spider farmer now has a bar style series
of led grill lights
they have the se3000 a four bar fixture
for a three foot by three foot grow
space the se
5000 a six bar fixture for a four foot
by four foot grow space
and the se7 thousand a six bar fixture
for a
five foot by five foot grow space these
grow lights have quality components
and they're sold at a lower price and
comparable fixtures on the market
they also have other style lights such
as their sf series which is a
board style they have grow tents an
inline fan
and a carbon filter i will leave a link
to spider farmer down in the description
section below
and you can use discount code mr growth
5 during checkout
for discount on their products the final
sponsor is
manscaped summer is here are you ready
to unveil your beachbod
you're in luck our friends at manscape
just launched their 4th
generation performance package which
includes the lawnmower 4.0
you heard that right the 4.0 also inside
this package you'll find their weed
whacker
ear and nose hair trimmer crop preserver
ball deodorant
crop reviver toner performance boxer
briefs
and a travel bag to hold your goodies
compliment your summer bod with a trim
from the leaders in mail grooming
the sun is shining and calling your name
fellas join the 2 million men worldwide
who trust manscaped
get 20 off plus free shipping with the
code mr growit
manscape.com that's 20 off plus free
shipping
with the code mr growit at manscape.com
escape the shrubs and reads this summer
and shine with manscaped
alright now let's get into the episode
all right so here we are with frosty
mcnasty
welcome to the garden talk podcast how
you doing today
i'm great man thanks for having me
thanks for having me i've been watching
you for a while
it's crazy to be up here
yeah thanks for joining me i've been
watching you for a little while too
and uh one thing i noticed is that you
do a lot of greenhouse growing
and i haven't had anybody on the podcast
yet that does greenhouse growing so i'm
super excited for this one to kind of
dig in
and find out what you do in the
greenhouse so
but before we get into all of that can
you tell us a little bit about yourself
and kind of how you got into gardening
well a friend of mine showed me that
plants are the future
you know you need to learn some
agriculture feed your family if the
worst case scenario
so we just started out strawberries bell
peppers
all kind of easier things squash
everything like that
zucchini and um the greenhouse is great
because you can just control
the cooler season you can heat it up
and you can vent it out when it's hot
when it's hot it is kind of
difficult to keep it cool though
that's a issue so you decided to launch
a youtube channel and now you're
showcasing plants right
when did you launch the youtube channel
and um how many subscribers are you up
to now
uh uh embarrassingly i'm only at 5500
subscribers
and i've been doing this for like 2016
but um it's starting to pick up more and
more now
people are seeing the channel and
they're like i never seen this channel i
would have been subscribed
so maybe i'm doing something wrong in
the algorithm yeah
yeah youtube algorithms is definitely
tough to to work around i mean they'll
black you lose to you like that you know
no prob
no problem so but now 5500 that's a good
amount there's people who would kill
that that much
you know that's that's a really good
idea so
and then you also have a podcast channel
now huh can you tell us a little bit
about that
yeah the green table podcast with my
co-host beast coast
we're having some fun over there that's
how i initially found
out about you is through that podcast
you did an interview with thc titan
uh the breeder of square one genetics
and that one
uh i was super stoked to hear he dropped
some gems on that one
and uh yeah you guys are doing your
thing over there i'm super pumped
that you guys have that going something
i tune in from
time to time and uh for those audiences
watching or listening in
just search green table podcast on
youtube and you'll
come across it so yeah i appreciate the
look man
we're just over there having some fun
kicking back definitely good times for
sure
so let's get into green house growing so
let's talk all about greenhouse growing
i think it's probably most appropriate
to start with kind of
you know i know you have multiple
greenhouses right so
can you tell us like a little bit about
what size greenhouses they are and the
construction
like uh you know there are several ways
to construct a greenhouse what do you do
how did you build it it's all a learning
a learning thing the first greenhouse
was a 10 by
34. i still have that uh and i'll just
use the space because that's what i had
if i could go longer or wider i would
have but for some reason this 10 foot
is so easy to manage you can
put the great amount of plants in there
everything can be healthy the fans are
going down
um the center row i have about four
beams going down the center
pvc goes over well let me just start
about the construction
so the outside i'm using two by fours
uh pressure treated two by fours i space
it out around five feet
and goes the length of 34 feet and then
i have
the opening on each end with a door
uh you just construct a door you know
it's just simple
two by two framing something really
simple just to keep it open or closed
to vent out and then i run it two by
four across the top
for the frame and then put 20 foot of
pvc and that goes from
just just started at the 2x4 and wrap it
all the way around the top
screw it in put some plastic on it and
that's it
it's really simple what type of ply is
there a special type of plastic that you
put over the top or
or what uh six mil plastic works
i had this woven plastic but it wasn't
uv rated
so it the sun just burnt it up before
the season could finish
wow okay and then i know in one of your
greenhouses you have like a material on
the bottom
too it's like a black material on the
bottom shade cloth
shade cloth no it's not shade cloth it's
actually ground cloth
um it's woven also it allows for water
to go through
but not that fast
and it stops the pests from coming up
and eating your plants
so that's pretty good and that's like a
six foot roll by 300
get it for like 80 bucks and then you
also have the shade cloth up top too
right
sometimes this this this summer has been
crucial in california i don't know if
you're in california but um
it's crucial now i'm in vegas
it's hot out there too but yeah it's
been hot and dry so i've been needing to
cover the plants up
just give them a break so it sounds like
your construction is
pretty cheap right you mentioned you
know pressure treated wood that comes up
there's beams along the middle
uh it to two by fours kind of looping
around
plastic up top you get the cloth on the
bottom how much does something like that
roughly
cost would you say that greenhouse cost
me about
800 bucks about around 800 the plastic
is the most
expensive thing the plastic is costing
around 400 bucks a roll
you know um from 250 to 400 depending on
the size
the width and the length and the other
greenhouses those are four by
fours along the edges because this
needs more support because it's wider if
i could take it back i would just do 10
foot greenhouses though
very simple and then how are you
attaching the plastic
to the actual beams and stuff is it just
like a staple gun or what do you do no
no no that'll rip up
fast so you use those one by twos
like fern strips cut little pieces and
then just kind of screw it into the
plastic tight screw it into the wood
where it just smashes against the um the
other each
opposite sides of the wood and the
plastic in between
it keeps it all tight in that size
greenhouse how many plants do you run i
mean i know it's going to vary depending
on what type of plants you have you know
if you're growing lettuce
kale bok choy some type of leafy green
give it a lot more plants
in a greenhouse that size versus a plant
that particularly takes up like a 2 foot
by 2 foot space
a three foot by three foot space so on
and so forth so for you
for the plants you're growing how many
plants do you roughly
fit in those grow those greenhouses um a
good rule of thumb
is about two feet by two feet per plant
and i want some walkways
to get in and water even if it's set up
with
irrigation you still want to be able to
get in and
pick leaves and hand water sometimes
so in the 10 by 30 i have 60 plants
in a 20 by 30 i have two separate rows
so i have 96 plants gotcha
so you have two separate walkways how
wide are the walkways so you can get in
there about a foot and a half
okay yeah about a foot and a half so
about 18 inches or so
okay that makes sense and that should
get you should be able to get in there
do whatever you got to do
watering's a big thing right yes um what
type of water do you use do you use in
rain water
tap water well water tap water our water
comes out around
1 40 ppm so it's fairly
good i never seen any any issues with
cal mag or mineral deposits or anything
it's pretty good
and then so it's basically directly from
a hose are you
is there like a filter sometimes people
will attach a filter to it
to filter out some of them i used to use
filters and everything but
i've seen that it doesn't the plant
doesn't care
i'm an advocate for that i really don't
think the plant cares about
the science that we keep trying to
implement on it
i think it's overboard it's just a sales
tactic
i think the plants have been growing
fine and it's it will continue to
yeah there's a lot of things that we get
into and a lot of things you hear online
people on videos try to overcomplicate
the process
and i've had a lot of guests over the um
the six months that i've been doing this
i have just mentioned that they like to
keep it simple you know and so
doing things like that where you're not
filtering out some of the things
that are in there the plant will still
grow for sure now are you doing hand
watering or do you have an auto watering
system
or what i have both i do both
um i like to feed with hand watering i
like the food to get everywhere in the
media
so in the 20 by 30 greenhouses
i use beds so twice a week i'll
hand water the beds and then the rest of
the time i have it on the time dripper
and just straight water like once or
twice a day
because it's hot during the day so got
to keep it hydrated
gotcha can you talk a little bit more
about the dripper system you have you
assume you have it hooked up to like a
reservoir
what size reservoir would it be and how
does that work
the drip system i have is hooked up to
the main
spigot for the house like a house spigot
outside garden hose type
and from the spigot i use a 25 pressure
regulator 25 psi
pressure regulator a regular walmart
garden timer
and that goes to a water hose to
the um to a wide connector filter
like a 150 micron mesh filter and then
from there
it goes to the half inch hose
and that hose goes around in a loop in
the greenhouse
and then little quarter inch hoses go to
the plant
connected to four gallon per hour
drippers got it and then
how long did you say you had the time
how often does that timer come on
i turn it on 5 30 in the morning for 20
minutes
and then i know you have one
greenhouse with beds and then i've seen
in some of your videos you have grow
pots
as well and you're in soil what size
grow pots
are those plants in 10 gallons okay so
is it 10
gallons those are the fabric pots and
not the fabric ones i use the plastic
because
i'm always changing my mind so like beds
i think are the future for me
and i didn't want to get smart pots
spending 10 bucks a pot
that's like 600 bucks for 60 plants
where i could spend like 50 cent
and have um the same amount for way
cheaper
that makes sense and it works i don't
get any of those issues
a lot of people will say that the
plastic is going to get too hot the
roots are going to burn
things like that but i've never seen any
issue
like i said again it's a lot of sales a
lot of sales tactics
so for soil what type are you using is
there a particular brand you're using
are you creating your own mix
or what it depends on how you want to
work
if you want to live in soil you want to
amend your own soil
and do your own thing if you want to
feed
it really doesn't matter what soil like
what do you what are you worrying about
the soil for if you're going to be
feeding it
anyway because it's just the media to
hold the roots in
and keep the stalk strong right so i
just use a regular happy frog
for outdoor it's just simple got some
mycorrhizae in there to help start it
off right
and after starting off i'm going to be
feeding it so i didn't really worry
about that
now with the beds i got compost in there
i got um soil builder that has all the
feather mills
and chicken manure bat guanos
things like that in there but um as far
as really amending my own soil i haven't
done that yet
okay so it sounds like cooking if i'm
wrong it sounds like you're doing two
different things where you have
using synthetic bottled nutrients on one
greenhouse and then you're kind of doing
the living
soil organic in your beds is that
correct
yes wouldn't now what are you using for
the bottle nutrients
house and garden okay do you use their
complete lineup and do you follow their
feeding chart or do you
do a half dose or how do you do the
feedings i noticed a thousand
milliliters
per 55 gallon drum for a and b
the whole way through nice so no
additives no cal mag no silicone no
nothing no cal mac
um epsom salt
sometimes sometimes epsom salt but for
the most part it's just a
and b it works keep it simple
and i know on your living soil side of
things what are you using for nutrients
there
and then i know i know you're also doing
a cover crop as well i've seen
a video where it was just sprouting up
can you talk to us about what you'd use
for nutrients and then
kind of your cover crop and such the
living soil thing kind of got screwed up
i started it off like that but i ran
into a nitrogen deficiency
like a really bad one it just wasn't
getting any nitrogen
so i went to house and garden i had to
give it give it what it needed
and then they just perked up greened up
and i was like you know what
i'm gonna practice this next year on the
living soil side of things
i'm gonna go ahead and cover crop still
keep that healthy and
and cut it down and kind of just work
the soil a little bit for next year
but for now i'm just gonna go ahead and
keep the house and garden thing going
because
i can't waste time and you know i don't
want to waste a crop
that makes sense yeah gotta do what you
got to do right you do
and the cover crop i love it it's just
it just looks great
just looks like you're out in nature it
looks like a whole another world down
there
it's beautiful and what were you using
for cover crop did you say
it's a mix on amazon just like a five
pound bag of cover crop
like 20 bucks i just got a few of those
and sprinkled it got some clover in
there
a couple types of clover and other stuff
i don't remember
okay and you sprinkle that on at a
certain point or did you sprinkle it on
like
when the plant first sprouts do you wait
or what you're actually supposed to do
it a long time before
but i didn't i kind of sprinkled it on
after i um
planted and watered everything in and
then about a week or so
they start growing up i also got some
alyssum
flowers yarrow um
what else do i have in there uh two
types of yarrow actually
and i'm using that because i want to
start giving some beneficial
bugs and that'll help feed the bugs
so i'm trying to i'm not a professional
at the living soil thing i'm just trying
to figure it out
continuous improvement right you got to
keep on learning that's one thing i love
about gardening is there's just so many
different ways to do it yeah
and uh the continuous learning i mean
it's not like you're doing the same
thing over and over and over again right
it's always changing pushing yourself to
learn more yeah it's always changing
there's always something new
and what i'm starting to learn is like
when you look at gardening you look at
the planet earth it's always changing
there's wildfires there's
monsoons they got everything on this
planet but the plants still live
so just keep on trying new things and
figuring it out yep absolutely let's hop
over into environment so
with greenhouse growing you know it's
completely different from
uh growing indoors right i know you have
an indoor operation as well
you know indoors temperature humidity
can easily get out of control and
there's
pieces of equipment where you can put in
there to regulate
greenhouse is kind of going to be a
little different there let's go one by
one let's start with temperature so
in one of your recent videos i saw that
you don't even have a temperature gauge
on there because you feel like you can't
control it so let me ask you
how high have temperatures gotten do you
you don't have any type of cooling in
there at all
or no i don't um
in the 20 by 30s it's really like hotter
over there
and it's funny because it's not far away
from the 10 by 30
but it's like for some reason it gets
hot in there
it was up to like 107 one day
and the plants were happy they didn't
care about it
as long as the plants had water at the
roots they were fine
they were just fine nice yeah i mean
they're resilient they can take it right
they could take it i went to a friend's
house and
you could walk up close to his
greenhouse and you could just feel the
heat coming out
and i was like why don't he lift the
sides up what's wrong with them
and i get closer and i'm like i'm caught
going in there it was 122 degrees in
there
and the plants were just praying not
worried about a thing it's amazing
plant could take it wow and so you lift
up your sides right
i had to and it wasn't even for the
plants it was more like for me
just to make sure that they were getting
wind flow and things like that but they
never looked
bad you know so i think a lot of times
we do things for us
instead of the plant because the plant
can take it so just to kind of go back
you have that plastic that wraps
up and kind of up and around and over so
you're just basically lifting it up on
both sides
yeah so the sides when you have the four
by four the two by fours for your
support
you're screwing that that um fern strip
up at the top so it gives you the
bottoms
to roll up and just use a regular clamp
to keep it open something simple you
know this is simple greenhouse they have
way better automated systems it costs
20s and 30s or thousands of dollars but
just for this
it's really simple just lift it up
roll it up keep it tight put a clamp on
it and now your side's open
yeah sounds easy yeah and lifting it up
it's good to have that flexibility yeah
you can aerate
right i can imagine some people building
a greenhouse and not building that
flexibility into it
so then they're kind of scrooge in a
sense it's funny because i didn't at
first
i kept the size down and i figured that
the
that the openings on each end will
create a wind tunnel
but when it's not windy you got to open
those sides up
you have to that makes sense now in the
winter time
uh you know temperatures can get pretty
cold there do you do anything in regards
to do you have any like heating system
or anything or do you just let
oh you shut it down you don't even grow
in the greenhouse at all in wintertime
what months typically is that um
right when it's over like september
october
let's go ahead so with the with these
beds if i decide to keep the same
structures
which i might not because i noticed that
i'm losing
um a lot of square footage by having
three separate structures
instead of one large one it's a lot of
square footage that i could fill in
a lot of blank space so i might just
scratch the whole thing and start over
gotcha so utilizing space is a big thing
for you huh it's probably one of your
main goals to do is utilize
space well at first i like things to be
nice
and um you know i like nice lines i like
things to work right
i like one one
plant variety in each greenhouse
so i could have everything cohesive
so that's why i made three but now i'm
looking at i got owls down the
greenhouse
inside the greenhouse and around the
so let's cancel out the betweens and
insides and use all that space for
canopy
and just make one big structure make
sense
makes sense now what about humidity kind
of sticking on the environment thing
humidity
um are you doing it can't really do too
much
so whatever the humidity is outside it's
going to be inside
and humidity comes with rain right
so i'm not doing anything in the raining
season so
i never worry about it it's down to like
twenty percent
it's fine it's really weird
coming from indoor to greenhouse because
all those
all the people say 75 50. that's like a
norm
right for indoor and now with led lights
they're saying
82 84 65 70
humidity vpd and such i've seen the best
flower in the greenhouse
with total different numbers
i'm talking about 84 in the day 55
at night colors exploding out through
the buds
fro you know what i mean everything
a lot of color a lot of color
i can imagine yep for sure now
when humidity gets high one of the
concerns and this can happen in a
greenhouse
i don't know if you've encountered it
before it's pottery mildew
have you encountered a pottery mildew at
all or
no nothing okay that's good no yeah
because it's not high in a greenhouse
well it it is it gets high for
i cover the greenhouse at 5 pm and i
uncover at
10 o'clock to induce flowering on
certain varieties
in that time it's humid and it's hot
in such a short time i don't see any
issues
and you also have plenty of air
circulation anyways i've seen your
videos
um can you talk a little bit about air
circulations how many fans you have
for that greenhouse i have four
and um and one and three in the rest
and it's enough airflow it's enough
airflow
you go in you can feel air movement
that's all that's really needed
just keep it up top you know keep that
keep that air circulation and then the
sides and the
other opposite ends they keep a nice
nice low vortex of wind
so that's great yeah it's so key
for sure now what about co2 anything for
co2 or
just outside co2 you can't do anything
because it's not a sealed space
it's never sealed if that greenhouse was
sealed you're talking about
160 degrees you can't do that
you know you can't do that yeah unless
you would have cooling and stuff like
that
but um yeah and that's a total different
structure
we're talking about way more
construction way more power
it's it's not difficult it's just a
totally different construction
cost will go through the roof right with
all the electricity consumption
no no you could use a swamp cooler
okay on one end enclosed
like uh like you put boards up create a
wall
put a swamp cooler there and have a
small
fan on the opposite end that just
makes the um cool air flow through the
greenhouse i thought about that too
you know i thought about a lot but it's
working simpler
without buying the expensive equipment
and things like that
cool let's switch it up and let's talk
about lighting so one of the benefits of
growing outdoors in a greenhouse is you
get
free lighting with the sun right
so you don't have to spend any money on
electricity consumption there which is a
good thing
i believe you're using supplemental
lighting as needed
can you talk to us a little bit about
what you use and when you use it
well when you want to extend the daytime
a few hours
maybe four hours in the beginning to
keep things in a vegetative state
i just use these led strip lights
and they work they work pretty good and
i just use those
keep it on a timer and uh
that's it that's only for like a few
weeks after that
i'm just using the sun and the sun is
the best
if you have a par meter you know what i
mean
you go outside it's 1700 par
you know it's it's un it's unrivaled
you can't mess with it you can't
replicate it either
and it's like it's the best yeah and
when we're talking about the
supplemental lighting
uh you just a very small amount of light
is needed right you're not going to need
to
power you know 400 600 watts per 5x5 or
whatever um
you just need a small amount do you do
you know how many like watts
each of those led are any idea how much
oh those are only uh like
18 watts a piece it's nothing
and they're bright enough and the plants
will still
droop like their sleep but they're still
they're still
collecting that light and keeping it in
that in that vegetative state
so it works i know you said you have a
par meter do you have any idea how much
power that is just with the supplemental
lighting you know i never checked that
okay that would be interesting yeah it
would probably be around
i would think around 200 maybe 400 ppfd
at the most
probably not even that probably like a
t5 right like a t5
just like 200 that's it yep not light is
not a lot of light is needed for
supplemental lighting
that's cool it's not i see people with
kavitas inside and it's like
what are you doing overkill man
that's a lot of electricity yeah oh it
adds up
now how about light deprivation um
can you talk to us a little bit about
that what you do for that
that's simple that's what i mean by um
using a supplemental light
for a few hours when you're first
planting
you want the roots to expand through the
pot until
before you flower right so sun comes up
at six o'clock
this is just for hypothetical sun is up
at six
goes down around say it was going down
around
seven but you want to go veg so you need
five more hours to supplement a light
until 12. so that's your vegetative
state
now when you want to stop that you cut
off your supplemental lighting
and you tarp it i type at five
i type at 5 pm so i pull a black sheet
over
that's light proof leak light leak proof
um put that down over all the sides
put like some cinder blocks on it to
keep it down
and i'll keep that on until 10 at night
when it's
as dark as it's going to get for the
night uncover it
and let the sun wake the plants up in
the morning
so i use so i'm really at 13 hours of
darkness
gotcha now this black sheet uh
do you know what type of material is it
is it is actually a black tarp
or no it's just a six mil
black and white poly like the panda film
they got they got way better ones
because these rip a lot so next year i
would not be using them because the six
mill is just the cheapest set of bunch
and it's really probably made for um
just people that's doing it for a season
you know
and if you want to get more technical
this 14 mil woven
that will not rip at all but we're
talking about 1400 bucks a roll
you know but it's worth it when you
think about it if you're going to be
doing it it's worth getting the right
stuff
even the right clear plastic the same
thing
have you ever had any problems with kind
of doing that transition to where
plants turned into hermaphrodites or
anything
or if you messed up the light schedule
i'm just kind of wondering curious on
that
sounds like that would be something easy
to mess up on well
when you look at a par meter you will
see that
you can see and the par read like five
five compared to 1700
it's not going to affect it you see i
think the higher the the light intensity
is
during this daylight the more leeway you
have
for its night cycle you see what i'm
saying
i think it has a little more leeway but
like i said i'm not a scientist i'm just
knowing what i see
and i know i have rips in the plastic
sometimes
like little spots and nothing ever
happens
whereas indoor that might be an issue
yep
i know a common question i get all the
time is like
oh the moon has light and why don't
plants continue to grow on the moonlight
and stuff like that and it's like well
it's not enough photons of energy it's
not going to
drop drive photosynthesis at all right
so
it's not that's uh that's what i'm
saying like we could see but the plant
doesn't absorb that
light not that starlight or moonlight or
nothing
even like uh my neighbor has a bright
light in his yard and i was scared of it
because it's like so bright but it
didn't it didn't register on a par meter
it wasn't registering anything let's
flip it up and let's talk about
plant support so i know you do a couple
different things to support so once the
plants grow up big
to a certain point they might have
flowers on them they're so heavy that
are going to kind of flop all over the
place so
can you talk to us a little bit about
what you do for plant support
well in the beginning in the beginning
i just use a bamboo steak to hold them
up and get their roots strong enough to
hold yourself
if i need it you know not all plants
need it
then after that just trellis trellis
works
and trellis is needed when you got a lot
of plants you need trailers
because that'd be a lot of bamboo and
then you'll need to clip i use these
orchid clips
i don't have any here but i use these
little orchid clips and just clip a
stalk to the bamboo
not the bottom stalk but like the top
just clip it to the bamboo
and that works great at what point are
you adding in the steaks
in the trellis too late always too late
i'm always waiting to like week two a
flower to add trellis and
i should start off with trellis right
over the canopy
and then go into flour so it gets that
support on all of it because i always
start late
i don't know why i was wrong with me but
i gotta fix that
are you doing any type of like plant
training uh whether it be topping
defoliation um leaf tucking
lollipop anything like that or always
lollipop
i always clean up the bottoms um and i
always top
i just keep it simple and top i've been
doing that for like six years
just just top get about eight tops on
there
that's that's enough for me
that's enough some people argue and say
veg two weeks longer talk more and talk
more and it's like two weeks is a long
time
i don't we're on schedule you know so
no i'm gonna do it this way you gotta
love back seat growers
always somebody on their computer
telling you how to grow your plants all
day
all day in the comments do this do this
do this and i check their page and i'm
like
what are you doing you know leave me
alone
that's funny no two girls are alike
you know everybody does it their way
like outside
i don't see the need for a full
trellised canopy
because the penetration of the sun is
going to get down to the lowers
and it's all going to be usable material
in my opinion all right ipm
and pest control so integrated pest
management
we probably should have talked about
this first i feel like i always talk
about this last at the podcast but
really i mean this is one of the one of
the more important things right
especially when you're growing outdoors
is
these pests they can completely ruin
your crop if you're not if you don't
have things under control
it's very important yeah and it's one of
those things that um
i lack on sometimes uh
trying to be more preventative but it
seems like
a lot of products just don't work like a
lot of stuff just
especially with spider mites i don't
know but
the california spider mite will swim
through
almost all your products you have to be
spraying
diligently like every three days or
even with the beneficials i didn't see
any
anything um really work
so today no tomorrow tomorrow i'll be
getting some green lace wings in
green lace wing larva and that's what
the lesson flowers are for
because they'll eat that while they're
staying around and getting to the
into the mites or getting to the other
pests
so hopefully this works because i'm
ordering 5 000
and i've got it on a schedule to come
every week
so every week five thousand five
thousand
so hopefully this works because i tried
to
neil sillis californica's predator might
i didn't see anything work
it just didn't work so it's spider mites
in particular that you're battling are
there any other pests
that you're a fits okay aphids i had
aphids
and i sprayed spinosad and i never seen
an aphid
again it was amazing i was like wow this
really works
and that was just a safer brand went in
there sprayed it and they just
disappeared
i was like okay that works i got to keep
that in the
in the tuck yeah and i'm liking this
take down spray
from monterey take down spray that's
working pretty good
also and it leaves a nice little coat on
your leaves
a little shine so it's pretty good okay
so those are some of the pests you've
you've encountered and kind of how you
battle them
do you do anything in like the
vegetative stage
as like is that preventative at all are
you doing like a neem oil
are you doing anything uh any type i did
i did neem oil i did sulfur i try to i
try to mix everything up
because i always have plants around so
you know how plant you know how pets are
they they
they they leave like um
kind of what's the word i'm looking for
like they get immune to it
over a while it builds up like a
tolerance to it a tolerance yeah
so kind of mixing it
everything clean whatever you use just
keep using it
switch it up and just do it at least
once a week
at least once a week right when you
think things are just perfect
spray just do it and a lot of people say
they don't spray they don't do this and
it's like here's
it's necessary it's very necessary
just don't spray bad things you know
don't spray the bad stuff
yeah there have been times where i've
been lazy on my outdoor garden my little
vegetable garden i have i have a two
foot by ten foot bed and
uh you know when you miss the sprays and
stuff i think i missed the spray like
three or four weeks in a row
and then and then we get all the way up
to harvest time and i'm
going into harvest and just loaded with
aphids and i'm just like
yeah the aphids suck because they look
disgusting
they just look disgusting it's like oh
no you don't even want to touch it or be
around it
but yeah the spinner said spinoza works
for the
use the spinosad just once a week just
use it i'm gonna have to try that out
for sure i haven't used spinosad yet
really yeah that's like yeah that's like
a secret ingredient in a lot of things
yeah that's great well i mostly grow
indoors
and yeah you don't really need much
indoors you know as long as your
environment's pretty clean and stuff
like that and you take the precautions
that not going directly from outdoors
directly into your grow tent and stuff
like that so you can kind of get away
with
not doing a lot of these ipm stuff i
can't do that
i can't i'm everywhere so yeah i just
got to stay up on my
my sprays and a lot of a lot of times
you'll pick up
problems from your garden supply also
so you got to be careful with that
you know that's a good point yeah that's
a really good point a lot of people
a lot of people going to that garden
supply dropping their
issues off right there so
be careful amazon you know just order it
come to your door and just just do it
like that
all right so we went over quite a bit
today couple final questions
there are a lot of people who are just
getting started with greenhouse growing
and i imagine that there are people
clicking on this
this podcast episode and they're a
beginner they're looking for
advice what advice would you have for
somebody who's kind of just
starting out greenhouse growing for a
greenhouse i get a lot of dms
all the time about questions about the
greenhouse
don't overthink it just build the
structure
and think about what could go wrong
while you're building it
for say like you're using pvc
without a center beam it might collapse
on you
you never know pvc is hard but it might
collapse
so use one inch pvc you know
make it thicker um cemented in
siemens your boards in your support
boards
um and that's about
it because you can get away with doing
the cheapest greenhouse ever
it'll work you know it'll work but if
you want to be
if you want to be in it for the long run
just go ahead and spend
the right amount of money for the right
items
and just and just do some research
and look at the new look at the new
greenhouses that are built with steel
and try to replicate that that's what i
would say try to replicate that
purlins you know what i mean just go all
out
but if you can't buy a cheap greenhouse
from amazon
and that's the best starter that's your
best start right there
steel structure vented roll-up door
you know that's your best that's your
best bet i think that's some good advice
yeah for sure
so where can the listeners find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
uh frostymcnosty on instagram
on youtube the green table podcast on
youtube and instagram
and for the future i'm just um i have a
strain
called shorty air it's a
it's a it's very nice i plan on 2022
that strain being a lot of places
a lot of places so yeah just just
keep on being an asset to the community
not trying to take from it just trying
to help
and be a support for other people
awesome
i will link a frosty mcnosty's instagram
and channel down in the description
section below and also i'll link it to
your podcast channel as well
so yeah i appreciate that i appreciate
that cool yeah head on over there
give him a subscribe or a follow
and uh yeah frosty thank you so much for
coming on to the podcast today
definitely a lot of good information
and uh thanks for having me thanks for
having me hope you enjoy the rest of
your day
all right you too
[Music]
you