what is up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and today i've got a part test video for
you this is the roi e680 led grow light
i actually did an unboxing video on my
main channel i'll link that in the
description section below
in this video i'm just gonna do the par
measurements so i'm not going to be
talking about any of the features or
anything like that now the meter i'm
using is the apogee mq 500 this measures
just a certain range it measures from
389 nanometers to 692 nanometers plus or
minus five nanometers so if any light is
being emitted from this grow light
outside of that range it will not be
shown
according to the listing for this light
it emits 1700 micro micromoles per
second ppf
this meter is going to measure in ppfd
so it's a spot check
if you're not sure what i mean by ppf or
pvfd you may want to read my buyer's
guide on led grow lights i explain what
those are in that article as well as
some other good information that is good
to know when searching for an led grill
light i'll link that buyer's guide in
the description section below so for
this light i'm going to take four
different uh height measurements i'm
going to start off six inches which is
what it says in the owner's manual then
i'll go up to eight inches which is what
it says i believe on the website
i'll go to 12 inches and then i'll do
one that's 24 inches
this does have a dimmer on it on the
screen i'll show what percent it is
dimmed so it starts off 100 you can dim
it down to 80
then 60 then 40 so keep an eye on the
screen and then you'll see what
percentage uh this unit is dimmed down
i'll start off six inches away
this is a two inch sensor so really the
height is
six inches from the top of the sensor to
the light i'm really not going to talk
in this video maybe towards the end
i'm going to let the measurements do the
talking
[Music]
so
my
[Music]
oh
more
[Music]
so
my
[Music]
all right so i will actually be growing
with this light and i just wanted to
take a few minutes to go over kind of
the results and what i'm going to hang
the light at for the different stages of
growth so when my plants are in seedling
stage or if i'm putting any clones
underneath it
i think i'm going to do 24 inches away
dim down to 40
uh basically the ppfd reading dead
center was at 380 and
uh the reading actually in the last the
corner diode when i brought that
sensor up all the way into the corner
right underneath that last diode is kind
of where i paused the video and i got a
319 reading on that corner diode for
seedlings of clones i usually aim
between 200 and 400 ppfd so that's right
there in that range my plates for the
vegetation stage i think i'm going to do
i got a couple different measurements
here not sure which one i'm going to do
at 24 inches away 80 percent dimmed dead
center comes in at 750
and then that corner diode comes in at
580. so for plants in the vegetation
stage between 400 and 600 ppfd is what i
aim for
another height distance that appealed to
me was 12 inches away 40 percent dimmed
down to
dead center came in at 554 and then that
corner diode came in at 359 ppfd so
right in the range where i want to be
for vegetation stage maybe that 12 inch
distance at 40 is for early veg because
the ppfd number is a little bit lower
and then later on in veg it looks like
the 24 inches away 80
would be kind of better for late in the
vegetation stage when it comes to
flowering i actually have three
different distances here that kind of
stuck out for me so i guess for early
flower maybe 12 inches away 60 dimmed
down dead center came at 800 the corner
diode came in at 600 so usually between
600 and 900 ppfd is what i aim for in
flowering another distance that stuck
out was 24 inches away 100
the dead center was 922 and that corner
diode was 700. the last one that stuck
out for flowering uh was 12 inches away
80 percent it came in at 11 20
ppfd in the dead center and then 750 on
that corner diode now some of you guys
might say 1120 that's a little bit too
much four pints of flowering especially
since i just said i like to go for 600
to 900 ppfd one way you can get away
with running a higher ppfd and the one i
recommended is running co2 so i actually
do i have been running co2 this last
girl on my phenol grow series on my
patreon page
i did run those uh co2 canisters by tmb
naturals
and just having additional 100 200 ppf
i'm sorry 100 to 200 ppm of co2
added to my environment will allow me to
run a higher ppfd number so that's why i
figured i'd mention that one that one
stuck out that's what i have four
measurements where i think i'm gonna run
what do you think about these
measurements let me know in the comment
section below and i'll leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]
you