what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you'll watch a my extra channel here
I have the grow craft x3 LED grow light
this is by chilled tech they sent me all
this light and in this video I'm going
to do a part test and I'm also gonna do
a heat test on this light as well I
already did a video where I unbox unit
and talked about some of the features
that videos on my main channel if you
want to see what comes in the box and
want to know what features this light
has I'll link that video in the
description section below also in the
description section will be a link to
this grow light so you can see the
listing and I'll show a discount code
down there as well for the power test
I'm gonna use the apogee mq 5 under par
meter this meter measures from 389
nanometers to 692 nanometers and the
measurements are in ppfd so if there's
any light being emitted from this
fixture outside of that range it's not
going to show on this meter and if you
need to this channel these part tests I
do just to give you a general idea of
what the power output is it's not going
to be exact I'm taking measurements
under grove tent and the reflective
walls could increase the part numbers so
just keep that in mind this LED grow
light has a flower and coverage area of
a 2 foot by 4 foot and I'm taking
measurements in a 2 foot by 4 foot grow
tent this light does have a dimmer on it
when I take the measurements I'll make
sure the dimmer is set to 100% so full
power I plug the grill light into my
kilowatt meter let's look at the amps
and watts I have the light fully dimmed
and it shows 0.24 amps and 25.6 watts
okay now full power 2.66
amps 324 watts alright now let's get
into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
just reminder that a link to this LED
grow light is in the description section
below along with the discount code
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time
pace
[Music]