welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody if you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
Garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 113 in this episode I interview
Nick nikol live he has been on the
podcast once before episode number 76
where we talked all about carbon Nick is
the owner of rooted leaf agretech and
his been gardening for over 25 years he
has advanced knowledge in plant science
and in this episode he breaks down the
science in regards to many gardening
myths that you hear or Bro Science that
many gardeners Implement in their Garden
in order to try to achieve a better
result this one is awesome it is the
longest episode yet and pack full of
good information get your pen and pads
ready because you may want to take notes
for this one if you want to see
highlights of these podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube that
channel is dedicated to short bite-sized
clips of these podcast episodes I also
have a gardening Channel with over 130
videos showing the plants that I grow
I'll have that channel linked down in
the description section below one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode they now have humidifiers
called the cloud Forge I've been using
the cloud Forge T3 which has a 4.5 L
capacity and can be filled from the top
it also includes a hose so you can place
the humidifier outside your grow tent
and feed the hose into your grow tent
saving you precious space it also
connects to the controller 69 Pro so you
can control it from your smartphone I'll
have a link in the description section
below so you can learn more about their
humidifiers and the discount code Mr Gro
15 works on both Amazon and the website
AC infiniti.com stash blend I've been
using stash blend for over a year now
and it's awesome one of the things that
I really like is that it saves me money
it's a whole bunch of different inputs
in one so I no longer have to go out
there and buy a silica bottle then a
separate seaweed bottle beneficial
bacteria then a separate one for microle
fungi all of that plus more is in this
one blend go to stash blend.com to learn
more about it and I also have a link
down in the YouTube description section
below and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with Nick Nicol from rooted Leaf
agretech did I pronounce your name right
yep Nick Nicol yeah yes got it how you
doing today I'm doing pretty good man
how are you doing good it's your second
time on the podcast uh the first one was
a fan favorite 261,000 views so far
incredible I think it's up there it's
got to be top five top five Garden talk
as far as number of views you talked all
about carbon and just so much knowledge
bombs were dropped in that episode if
you are listening to this episode right
now haven't tuned into that one you're
definitely going to want to tune into
that one after this one I'll definitely
have a link in the YouTube description
section below so you can easily get to
that one this one this one's going to be
good as well can you introduce yourself
for the audience members who don't know
you sure yeah my name is Nick nice to
meet you for those of you who we who I
haven't talked to and certainly I'm
looking forward to hearing from a lot of
people that I've already spoken to um
I'm the CEO of rooted Leaf agch we're a
carbon based fertilizer manufacturer
that's based in Washington state and um
we've been in business since about 2019
and we've really developed kind of a
unique platform for manufacturing
fertilizers and the idea with what we're
trying to do is treat carbon like a
macronutrient and in the cultivation of
most crops um food crops and medicinal
crops it makes a lot of sense to keep
carbon as the number one most important
thing that you as a grower should be
focused on and obviously in the first
episode that we did um I dive into great
detail about that so I would highly
encourage and recommend people go and
check that out if you want a deep dive
into why carbon is the most important
macronutrient by far yeah we even did an
episode on from the stash quite recently
and that one blew up tons of value being
dropped there I'll link that one in the
description section as well just so much
good information coming from you and you
hook up my viewers with a discount code
uh correct me if I'm wrong that's still
active discount code Mr growt on your
website rooted leaf.com I'll will link
that in the description section below as
well so if you're interested in picking
up some NES carbon based NES use that
discount code get a little bit of save a
little bit of coin there yep yep Mr grow
it gives people 20% off um rooted
leaf.com check it out if you guys have
any questions feel free to reach out um
to us on Instagram I'm usually the
person that answers the messages so if
you guys want a little bit more
technical information than what you find
on the website which we have a lot of
really good information on the website
about our products we're very
transparent about what we're doing and
what goes into each product but um
certainly I'm open to discussion about
uh you know how much further the rabbit
hole goes or how much deeper it goes so
yeah check it out Mr Grow use the coupon
code sweet so today's topic this is
going to be a fun one I've actually done
this similar Style on a couple different
podcasts in the past and people love it
we're going to be talking about bro
science things that people deem as Bro
Science and really there's there may or
may not be science to back it up but
we're going to go through a whole bunch
of things here today and uh it's going
to be fun man I'm excited me too I enjoy
the sort of the rapid fire approach too
and being able to answer a whole bunch
of seemingly disconnected questions and
by the end of the conversation we'll
actually have a it's like a jigsaw
puzzle you know the individual pieces
once you start to make sense of it you
kind of see the big picture and that's
what I want to try to help people
understand in their Gardens is how do
you get the most out of anything that
you're growing whether you're growing
roses for competition or you're just
trying to feed your family and grow some
tomatoes and lettuce in the backyard
hopefully there's going to be some good
content and some of the um myths
misconceptions truths and Hal truths
that we'll look at today will help
enable enable people people to get
better results and achieve a greater
level of success yeah and you have a lot
of knowledge in Biochemistry right so
like the chemical processes that happen
in living organisms and to be honest
with you biochemistry is one of those
things that go over my head and uh I
think it probably goes over a lot of
people has is it's just so so complex
and you do such a great job of grasping
onto it understanding it and then
relaying it in lay in terms for the
audience so let's start going through
some of these questions and I'm sure
there's going to be a lot of things that
relate to biochemistry that you're going
to be bringing up here so first up grow
light sunrise and sunset feature so it's
often said that hey replicate Nature
Nature has a sunrise they have a sunset
there's a light spectrum in there that's
different for both of those that's
what's best for the plant so grow lights
now have a sunrise and sunset feature
now Dr Bruce bugby shout out to him he
actually did a study in regards to the
rate of photosynthesis for a sunrise
sunset versus just turning the lights on
full blast and he had mentioned the
plants were able to take it full blast
so that's one thing that he kind of
uncovered there in in one study of
course studies need to be repeated in
order for it to be true fact blah blah
blah so on and so forth but sunrise
sunset feature is there any benefit to
this or not I definitely think there is
I think when you're trying to get a
holistic expression of the planet makes
sense to consider that some of the light
energy coming in during those early
morning hours or even in the late
evening um you know it's not primarily
used for photosynth is there are
wavelengths of light that come in and
they just kind of help spread a certain
kind of message in the plant so it can
kind of start to express different
things maybe do things like close the
stomata um at night time certainly this
is true um you know typically when
studies are done on things like this
what they're looking at doing is just
measuring one variable and in this case
it would be let's say Quantum yield or
the the photosynthesis overall in the
plant and when you take just that narrow
slice out of the rest of the plant and
what the rest of the plant is doing um
you know it becomes a little bit more
clear like yeah I mean plants will take
in the amount of light energy that you
give to them and if you just full blast
turn on the lights right away and then
just turn them off at nighttime if
you're only measuring
photosynthesis um you know you'll see
the results skewed from that perspective
but if you're looking at things like
gene expression or even the migration of
the phytochromes from the outermost
layer of the leaf where they are during
the daytime to a little bit closer in
the nucleus of the cells at night time
there's this physical migration so if
you took a cross-section of a leaf and
looked at it from the side like a
profile shot you'd find that the leaf is
very Dynamic the the um chlorophyll and
most of the pigments that absorb light
energy those are going to be close to
the outer layers of the leaf right and
as you get into the deeper layers of the
leaf more of that light has been
filtered out and of course on the
underside of the leaf almost all of the
light has been filtered out and the only
thing that's really coming through is a
little bit of green light that's why you
know plants look green effectively from
the underside they also reflect a little
bit of that wavelength of light too but
um you know the the point I'm trying to
make here is that there are
physiological processes that happen that
have been um fine-tuned over the course
of millions if not tens or even hundreds
of millions of years um plants are very
used to the rising and the setting of
the Sun and there's nuanced things that
happen that have to do more with gene
expression and kind of like the big
picture of what a plant is as opposed to
just like hey photosynthesis you know
Quantum yield and carbohydrate
production and Calvin cycle these things
are just like tiny components very
important components don't get me wrong
they're kind of like the primary engines
but you have all these accessory things
that um get tagged along with it so I do
think that you know natural sunrise and
sunset um really are going to just help
create a better expression in the plant
overall that makes sense now what if
this grow light just simply Tunes up the
amount of light and doesn't change that
Spectrum to truly simulate sunrise and
sunset would you say that's kind of a a
wasted feature or would you still see
that as being valuable um yeah I think
there could be value to it for sure um
you know I think to replicate perfectly
what the sun does kind of depends on
where you are so to speak like if you're
you know in the southern hemisphere
Northern if you're high altitude for
example you might get more UV light
exposure on those plants versus a lower
altitude you might get less so there are
differences for sure and there's no such
thing as a light that can truly
replicate the full spectrum of the sun I
mean the sun sun is just um you know it
operates on a fundamentally different
principle no one really has like a
nuclear reactor that's powering their
grow lights they often times have LEDs
which are totally different in terms of
the mode of operation you know or they
have high-intensity discharge like metal
highlight and high pressure sodium
lights those things are fundamentally
different um than what the sun is and
how the Sun puts out you know different
wavelengths of energy and really that
full spectrum I mean it's not just the
visible light spectrum it's you know
infrared for example the planet is
heated by the Sun as well um so there
there are things to consider outside the
context of just what the plant is
capable of absorbing for the purpose of
photosynthesis got it really good points
there now how about the 24-hour light
cycle there's lots of folks who say that
the plants don't need a resting period
at all they can just blast it with 24
hours of light and the plant will grow
better than if they were on an 186 light
cycle for example people on the opposing
side say no plants do need a resting
period with the lights off this also
talks about the you know not just the
plants have benefit from lights off but
the microbes in the medium as well need
that resting period what's your take on
that yeah and I think it kind of stems
from the same um issue overall as when
we're looking at things from just that
scientific perspective it tends to we we
get this very narrow slice and so
photosynthesis is like a car engine for
example and all the byproducts all the
things that you want your plants to
produce all the wonderful Aromas and
fragrances and flavorful compounds and
things like that those are driven by
light
um but it's much like a car engine yes
you get more horsepower if you leave
your car running for 24 hours a day but
in reality sometimes you have to let
that you got to turn the engine off so
that the accessory belts and everything
else doesn't like get burned out and get
worn down um the same thing is true for
plants as well because they've evolved
to capture energy from the Sun during
the day and then during the night
they're not necessarily uh inactive it's
not like the plants go to sleep they're
actually still very metabolically active
and a lot of the activity associated
with plants at nighttime revolves around
taking the sugars that they've produced
throughout the day and doing things like
maybe maintaining their own internal
temperatures maybe feeding some
beneficial microbes and fungi um there's
also something to be said about um the
stamata and the way that the water flows
in the plants this is maybe a little bit
more minor of a difference but you know
when the when the lights are on or when
the sun is out plants are taking up
water from the roots and transpiring it
from through the leaves um when the
lights turn off and the sun sets the
stomat on the leaves close and so you
have this reversal of a pressure
gradient meaning that the water from the
roots is no longer flowing up like it is
when the stomato are open when they
close actually what ends up happening is
the roots can actually secrete organic
acids and all the byproducts of
photosynthesis during the day the roots
will actually push that stuff back out
into the surrounding medium which is the
rizosphere that narrow like 1 to 2 mm
just outside the root hairs and it's
this secretion of the root exit states
that attract the microbes attract the
fungi and that's really where the plant
can kind of modulate its relationship
with those microorganisms to help
optimize the chemistry of whatever is
going on um so you know it is important
in my perspective to maintain that that
Synergy with what plants have been doing
for so long anyways because a lot of
times when you start hybridizing plants
particularly those are that are grown in
indoor controlled environment kind of
scenarios you know they get really
sensitive to certain types of
environmental stressors I mean yes you
can run your engine 24 hours a day but
the moment you flick the timing belt the
whole thing just snaps and breaks apart
so this is similar to how certain you
know crops when they're growing indoors
in controlled environments you you know
the the stability of them tends to go
down over time so if you have like a
dehumidifier in the room for example and
it puts off a blue light just a tiny
tiny little amount of light that can be
enough to trigger something in the plant
that makes it become stressed out and
and give you different results than what
you're looking for maybe you know the
plant starts to um go kind of down this
path as opposed to the other path that
you wanted to go down so these things
typically don't happen in nature because
there is a moon out there in nature and
even during a full moon a lot of the
genetics that are just like wild growing
um they don't respond negatively they
don't have these stress responses they
don't have their photo periods disrupted
by the tiny tiny little amount of light
the that the moon reflect so I feel like
a lot of the sensitivities and a lot of
the instabilities that have been created
over time have been artificially
selected for so to speak because a lot
of people don't understand what they're
doing when they run their car engine for
24 hours a day and then they wonder why
the belts are starting to get worn down
and everything is starting to break and
it's just wear and tear you know that
type of thing so what's your personal
recommendation for light cycle for the
vegetation stage and then recommendation
for light cycle for the flower stage
well it depends on where the gene pool
comes from I think if you're growing
something you know closer to the Equator
they can handle longer uh periods of
daylight shorter periods of um you know
the dark dark
period um but if you're growing
something that's maybe a little bit more
Northern or a little bit more Southern
probably something closer to like 186
would be pretty good you know 18 hours
on 6 hours off um you know in some cases
20 hours on 4 hours off I do think that
there's a real benefit associated with
having that dark period for regardless
of what you're growing or how you're
growing and I I do think that there's a
benefit and a value associated with that
dark period um but the the it is a
little bit plast you know there's some
plasticity because it also depends on
how much your plants are capable of
handling if you give them really really
good air flow and the VPD is always in
that perfect spot and the soil chemistry
is just right and the light intensity is
perfect but not too much plants can
Cruise along at that optimal spot for a
lot longer versus if you have the lights
just a little bit too intense they
quickly become saturated and maybe you
know if you have your lights on for 18
hours you might start to notice right
around 12 to 14 hours your plants almost
look like they're not sad but they start
to like get a little droopy or like
they're getting ready to go to sleep
because they're kind of reaching that
point where the equilibrium is being
thrown off and they're kind of um trying
to catch up to the strats rather than
string staying ahead of it and being
able to deal with it so when the leaves
droop towards the end of the light cycle
are you saying that there is an
indication that something is wrong or is
that a natural thing that happens with
all of these medicinal plants is they'll
dro down before the light cycle
naturally um in some cases it could mean
that it's too much light yeah you you'd
want to take a look at the you know
visual morphology of the plants to see
if you have any burned Leaf tips you
know that's a that's a big one in
particular plants if the transpiration
is a little bit off and they get
stressed out um if they are a little bit
too dry for example you know they'll
tend to have those burned Leaf tips um
and it could be a sign of too much light
intensity I would say to some extent it
is natural for the plants to want to go
through those day and night cycles just
like plants want to go through wet dry
Cycles you know they like being really
saturated lots of water available but
only for a very short amount of time you
know most plants you can't grow fully so
the roots cannot be fully submerged they
can be exposed to a large amount of
water but for a short amount of time and
then they kind of go the pendulum swings
the other way and they start to the soil
becomes much drier for example and The
Roots start to dry out and these W dry
Cycles are very um advantageous to
plants because it allows them to balance
their chemistry and their metabolism out
I think the same thing is true of day
and night cycles for sure the plants do
have this tendency to kind of go back
through and create a balance in that
swing um if you optimize the grow
environment and you optimize the
chemistry of the plants the leaves will
typically not um droop like that they'll
stay kind of nice and perky and active
um and so you can in those situations
you can push the plants a little bit
harder maybe a higher light intensity um
but you know it's also true that plants
have circadian rhythms a lot of these
plants are really looking towards the
not only the um you know exposure to the
sun itself but also the duration of the
day versus the night as a mechanism or a
trigger for that flowering process and
it can also factor in temperature as
well for certain um plants like hops for
example um you need to hit particular
temperatures in order to actually
initiate um flowering in hop species got
it how about darkness before Harvest uh
this is something that a lot of folks
have done over the years I've heard
benefits everything from more tricomes
are produced secondary metabolites
ripening there's so many different
things that are said in regards to
giving you your plant a period of
darkness before Harvest is giving your
plants a period of darkness before
Harvest beneficial at all I would say
largely probably not when you look at
the underlying mechanics of how um
certain compounds can be produced like
the monotes and sasines things like that
um you know THC CBD all these compounds
they're very energy intensive compounds
which is why they require exposure to
direct light you know if you're growing
some of these plants in a you know like
far away from the light under low light
intensity with low pressure and low
stress overall you're probably not going
to get the best results but if you have
a high-intensity grower environment with
high-intensity lights that light energy
is directly what feeds those
biosynthetic Pathways and so by cutting
out that light energy entirely you're
actually directly bottlenecking the
process and instead of creating a
greater throughput in that particular
path way you you might stimulate the
plant to respond in a particular way but
it's not going to be the the type of
response that's fundamentally hardwired
and linked to the light energy coming in
and then being utilized through a very
complex process obviously photosynthesis
first and then those sugars being
transported broken down and then you
know the turpine synthes enzymes acting
on them and polyketide synthes enzymes
acting on them too to create ol ofic
acid um these things are fundamentally
driven by exposure to life so I would
say that it's a little bit of a
misconception or a myth however there
are um examples of you know some
compounds that might be produced by the
plants which create a little bit more
rounder or nuanced experience maybe this
is more for people who are connoisseurs
and aren't necessarily just seeking a
high concentration of active metabolites
but they want that broad spectrum of
metabolites um there could be something
there but it would be largely a personal
bias more than like an objectively true
thing um I think it's objectively true
to say that you would probably um see a
decrease in the overall concentration of
some of these metabolites particularly
because again their biosynthesis and
accumulation is tied directly to the
light energy that's coming in and if you
break that no way got it that makes
sense and just a quick note a lot of
these questions actually came from the
audience so shout out to those folks
that have followed me on Instagram ATM
mr. grit that's the only account I have
on Instagram just uh FYI there are a lot
of impersonator accounts on that
platform unfortunately but I asked this
question about what Gard mths they've
heard or broscience things and tons of
people had submitted things in so this
is kind of like a Consolidated list of
not only things that people have
submitted in couple of them I have
thought up couple of them you had
actually mentioned that you wanted to
talk about so um just wanted to mention
that there and some of the questions
have been asked to other guests in other
episodes in the past but definitely want
to get Nick's Insight on these as well
so another thing that people do before
harvesting is they flush their plants
run water through the medium or they
will simply cut off nutrients they won't
feed nutrients for the final one to two
weeks before Harvest some people go even
longer than that now there have been a
couple studies on flushing Arc screen
technology study comes to mind for me
where they really found no difference
between flushed and unflushed buds give
me some insight on your end does
flushing your plants before Harvest
provide any benefits it's a little bit
of a myth and a misconception you know
if you think about how things work out
in nature plants don't necessarily have
a choice to stop taking things up it's
really about how they metabolize the
various elements and how those relate to
carbon metabolism in the first episode
that we did we had kind of tied all of
the macronutrients like the npks and the
calciums and magnesium so on and so
forth um to what plants are trying to
achieve because all of it just
ultimately comes to carbon metabolism
and I really feel like a lot of Growers
are leaving yield and quality on the
table if they're cutting nutrients out
too soon because this whole flushing
process is a little bit of a miscon
conception from that perspective of
you're going to get an increase in
potency or you're going to get an
increase in quality um that's generally
speaking not the way it works um and
then even furthermore if the goal is to
flush some kind of residual salts away
from the roots to prevent them from
being taken up or whatever um it would
actually be a beneficial practice to
incorporate a small amount of um some
potassium that has organic acids
associated with it because those organic
acids can directly participate in these
types of salt Bing and detoxifying
processes that I think a lot of Growers
seek when they add just plain water into
the medium um the other thing to
consider too is that the constant flow
of some of these minerals working their
way into the plant is very very
important for that long uh for that
long-term sort of stability of the the
the flow or the you know the whatever
product it is that you're whatever plant
it is that you're trying to grow um
getting a little bit of calcium getting
a little bit of potassium in with every
single watering is going to help with
certain things like Gene Express I
charge conductance and if the plants are
doing you know photosynthesis during the
last couple of days um or even the last
couple of weeks of their
life um a lot of the carbon that flows
through the plant from photosynthesis
plants are looking towards some of these
minerals to help create a little bit of
a charge balance between them so
potassium is actually a really good one
to talk about in that uh from that
perspective because if you feed
potassium to your plants during the mid
to late stages of flowering you're
actually increasing the overall appetite
that the plant has for taking CO2 out of
the air and this directly and you know
in conjunction with light obviously this
directly impacts the overall production
of tpin and um other compounds that
people might want from their plants
that's interesting I didn't know that
ice flushing this relates to what we
just talked about with flushing now ice
flushing for those that don't know is
really just taking bunch of ice dumping
it on top of the medium before Harvest
letting that ice melt cold water down in
the root Zone
and it is said that this actually
stresses the plants into making more
secondary metabolites tricomes for
example and it also brings out purple
color is there any truth to any of that
yeah I would say that the antoin which
is the purple pigments you know the
biosythesis of them can be tied to um
exposure to cold and I think part of
what it has to do is like plants have
membranes that are that are like
phospholipids and if you've ever taken a
glass of cold water and added a drop of
oil into it the temperature of the water
forces the coalesence of the oil so you
get this like distinct glob or drop of
oil that floats on top um whereas if you
have a glass of warm water and you drop
oil inside of it that oil could disperse
a little bit more evenly across the top
so it tends to like stretch out and it
tends to not just Clump up together like
this you know um when you put ice on the
soil and Ice flush your plants really
what you're doing is exposing them to
cold temperatures that create a sort of
brittleness if you will with the
phospholes lipids because again these
are these are phosph lipids they're oils
they're they're you know fats
basically um and the plants defensive
mechanism is it doesn't want that fat to
kind of coales like that because for
their cell wall membranes for example or
for the Integrity of these membranes
it's really important for them to be
able to kind of stretch out and maintain
that adequate reach that they have
across the the full volume or surface
area of wherever they're located um and
so antoin which are those purple
pigments can be produced by plants
because they'll kind of modify the
properties of those phospholipids a
little bit they'll allow them to be
exposed to colder temperatures without
necessarily becoming so brittle and
cracking if you will and that's um
that's an important consideration but um
ultimately I think putting I you know
the ice water fles thing I think it can
actually do more harm than good for a
couple of reasons one is that anytime
that we're talking about that purple
pigment being synthesized those antoin
directly compete for
substrates um with you know like CBD and
THC and some of these other molecules um
there's a competition between the two of
them so you have a building block that
either gets diverted to make a purple
pigment or it gets diverted to make
something called olic acid um and there
there's a little bit of cross talk
between them so they kind of get
balanced out but the idea is that plants
are taking in CO2 from the environment
around them and the real question is
where does that carbon go because if the
carbon goes towards making a purple
pigment it could have instead gone
towards making a monot turpine or or a
sasquat turpine or maybe some CBD um or
other
canabo um and so it becomes a little bit
of a problem in that context the other
reason that it could be an issue is
because when you have really cold
temperatures uh in the feed water you
know if you're exposing your plants to
that it's the flow of energy coming in
through photosynthesis typically that
energy comes in and you want to get your
plants to express all of those wonderful
colors and flavors and Aromas that you
possibly can but when you expose your
plants to low temperatures what ends up
happening is that energy actually gets
diverted away from the production of
secondary metabolites and it instead
becomes uncoupled from ATP generation
and there's something called
thermogenesis which is just generation
of heat you know the the Practical sort
of application here might be like every
time that you eat a meal you might
notice your body temperature actually
goes up a little bit um and this is
possible to measure I think it's been
done a number of times but when you eat
food your body's breaking that food down
and is releasing that energy just as
heat because your body needs to maintain
a particular temperature in order to
operate efficiently homeostasis is what
this is called so maintaining the
optimum temperature to allow all the
enzymes in your body to function all the
proteins to work properly and really you
know you don't want cold and brittle
joints like some people might notice
this if they have really sensitive
joints when the temperatures go down the
joints become really stiff and the
joints become really sensitive and this
is part of the same phenomena in Plants
meaning that if they're exposed to cold
temperatures that are below their
threshold instead of taking that energy
from the Sun and producing compounds
with it they'll take the energy from the
Sun and produce heat with it and the
goal of producing heat is to raise the
temperature of the water that they've
been exposed to so that it becomes
sufficient for their basic operation and
that's always just an energy tax placed
on the plant so I would say ice flushing
is probably not um very beneficial it
does slow down total transpiration in
Plants it does decrease the availability
of nutrients you know if you've got a
cold glass of water versus a hot glass
of water you can fit a lot more sugar
inside of that hot glass of water you
can add teaspoon after teaspoon and keep
stirring and that hot water will
dissolve all of that Sugar way more
effectively than a glass of cold water
is going to dissolve that same amount of
sugar and plants are faced with the same
problem they take CO2 out of the air and
they're trying to create sugars and in
order for those sugars to be properly
dissolved inside of their own tissues it
requires the water to be at a particular
temperature and plants are very heavily
invested in maintaining that um
temperature you know margin because they
don't have the ability to just put on
another layer or or jacket if they get
too cold or they can't like stand up and
walk somewhere else where it's a little
bit more ideal they have to deal with
the environment that they're exposed to
and if that environment is cold their
primary focus becomes less generate heat
psycher metabolites are useless without
a functional cell to begin with you know
the the primary purpose at that moment
in time is going to be for the plant to
take the energy from the Sun and create
heat which is a problem when you're
trying to create colors and flavors and
Aromas and all these things another
thing that's doing is it's really
slowing down your microbes right the
lower the temp the slower the microbes
function and if you're relying on the
microbes in order to break down organic
matter and cycle nutrients so the plant
can uptake it well you're kind of
slowing down that process by adding ice
water into your medium there I
personally what I usually do to bring
out the colors towards the end of
flowering is I'll just lower the ambient
temp you know the the room temp into the
low 60s high 50s degree Fahrenheit and
that uh that usually does help bring out
some of the colors I would think that
might be a better approach to bring out
the colors if that's kind of your goal
is to kind of get some colors out of it
doing that route instead of doing the
ice flushing yeah yeah and there's that
antifreeze sort of mechanism that we
talked about too you know just dropping
the temperatures a little bit will um
create a little shock in the plants and
they have a vested interest in not only
um offsetting the temperature changes
but also producing compounds that can
help them deal with or mitigate that
kind of stress so um that's where the
purple pigments start to come in they
can modify the way that some of these
compounds behave at really low
temperatures like those those fatty
acids and those oils which tend to just
kind of Clump up and come all together
this is not an ideal state for all of
your cells to be in because you want
your cells to take up a large surface
area large you want that plasticity you
want that cell to be able to kind of
move around and expand because there's
always water coming in during the day
the vacul fill up as the roots take that
water water up so you want the cell to
be able to expand and then also to
contract once the water leaves the vacu
and then gets destined for
photosynthesis or for transpiration but
this constant like water pump phenomena
where the plants are swelling up as they
fill up with water and then they're kind
of shrinking back down as they um as
that water leaves the vacuum you want to
maintain this Dynamic with plants and at
really cold temperatures the outer
layers become very brittle and it
becomes difficult for the plants to
effectively expand without cracking the
you know outer layers of the cell walls
and don't like that because you know it
starts to create oxidative damage it
starts to you know destroy the cells and
the organel so they produce these purple
pigments that modify those phospholipids
and even at low temperatures now the
plant can properly go through this
expansion and contraction process good
info let's move right along here next up
we have stem splitting so some people
actually split the the stem or the stock
during the grow typically it's a little
bit before harvest in order to stress
the plant into producing more tricomes
does that actually work I don't think so
um you know it kind of depends on what
flavor of Tricom we're talking about
there's a couple of different ones um
you know there's the ones that have
heads on them with the stocks there's
ones that have just the stocks with no
heads there's ones that are just the
heads sitting on the surface of the leaf
with no stocks and then there's some
that are non- glandular tricomes that
are either phytolith uh deposits like if
you grow cucumbers or if you grow
tomatoes those pokey little um spines
that grow all up along the stock and
particularly for some varietal of
cucumber they can actually form on the
fruit itself those are cystoliths if
they're calcium carbonate deposits and
they're phytoliths if they're some kind
of uh silica deposits so for plants that
take up a lot large concentration of
silicon zucchini and squash or good
examples of plants that can do this
they'll actually secrete those and make
non- glandular tricomes and those serve
defensive purposes as well so I would
say if you're talking about in the
context of glandular tricomes the ones
that have the stocks and the heads it's
probably not going to increase the
biosynthesis of them there are a couple
of studies that are coming out that
particularly done on like hops for
lupulin glands then also on lavender
buds which produce a large large
concentration of lolu and merine you
know aamine campine these tpin might be
quite familiar um to your audience you
know lavender buds has been shown that
um there's a phenomena that happens in
the early stages of flowering where and
this may not be true for all plants but
effectively the idea is that the plant
is in the first 2 to 3 weeks of
flowering the plant's trying to figure
out which of its tricomes are going to
be the ones with the heads and with the
stocks coming off of it and it starts to
dedicate resources really early on
because plants are Master mathematicians
they really really good at doing math
and they're really good for planning
ahead they're always trying to build uh
an understanding of what's right around
the corner you know they're trying to
build up stockpiles of energy so they
can deal with changes in the environment
things like that but all this ultimately
to say that the presence of these um you
know the bulbus the capitate stock
tricomes is what they're called but the
ones that have heads on them the
decision to make those is made several
weeks in advance before it actually
extends Off The Leaf surface and becomes
an actual stocked Tricom with a head on
it so the plant's trying to plan and and
try to figure these things out pretty
early on in the process so to do it just
before Harvest um doesn't really give
the plants enough time to adjust
properly because as far as the
expression goes um of the plant you know
they make these decisions several weeks
in advance before it actually happens
that's why I think focusing on what
happens in the first two to 3 weeks of
flowering can actually set the plants up
for success for the second half of
flowering so you can get the best
possible results um and to you know
answer the question more directly or
more specifically I I don't think that
it would be directly connected to an
increase in yield or quality you may see
some tpin come out or not TP I'm sorry
you may see some tricomes come up but
those may not be the ones that become
concentrated in oils those may be more
defensive compounds like the non-
glandular tricomes or even the ones that
don't have heads they're just the stocks
that come out yeah cuz they Tri con form
right but in order for it to get that
potency takes a little while right what
what's the uh timeline on that like when
a Trion was formed typically you're
about going from clear to cloudy to
Amber what's the general timeline for
that transition well it kind of depends
on I mean it could take several weeks um
you know the transition between uh
particularly when you're going from like
cloudy to Amber it's really the when the
color starts to form inside of those
triome heads that there's an indication
of some change in the chemistry and
sometimes what could be happening is the
compounds that are inside of that triome
head could be um starting to oxidize and
as they oxidize the color will change a
little bit and a lot of Growers will
look at this as a sign of maturity like
the plant is ready to be harvested um
there are certainly cases where like if
you feed the correct things to your
plants if you have a dialed in
fertilizer program your plants will
inherently be able to resist that
oxidative stress so they may develop
those Tricom heads more rapidly in the
first let's say half of flowering
they're going to like develop them a lot
faster and the flowers will grow out a
lot more but then when the triom heads
themselves are starting to to become a
little bit more cloudy and milky they'll
hang out in that transitionary space
between being clear and being Amber for
a lot longer so they'll resist the
degradation associated with that that
ambering effect you know they'll go
through the first half really rapidly
but then for the second half it takes
them forever seemingly forever to finish
up and to um properly oxidize so you see
that color change happening um a lot of
what happens inside of the Tricom heads
as far as like the change of you know
the constituents and what those
molecules are inside of there those are
driven by non-enzymatic processes
meaning it's not something ins inside of
the plant that's actually causing this
discoloration It's actually an
environmental stressor and I think it it
makes sense to pay attention to certain
plants like hops for example it's a
really good example of a plant with um
it has brackets on the outside of the
flowering cone and then the lupulin
glands actually face inward there are
other plants um Tomatoes may be a good
one as well where the tricomes actually
pointed out you know if you look at the
the stocks and um Leaf surfaces of
tomatoes you'll see that those tricomes
are actually exposed to the to the
surrounding environment um that's an
important consideration too cuz when
you're just exposed to the Out outdoors
with no protective sheath like hop cones
have that the bra itself is an actual
physical sheet that protects it you're
more likely to get oxidative
decomposition just cuz it's exposed to
the air you know that's good to know all
right moving right along this next one
is actually from a viewer I got a little
scenario here shout out to canabas 420
he is on my Forum he posted this MRG
grow.com Forum head on over there there
if you want to connect with some people
like-minded people who grow got a lot H
Growers indoor outdoor some commercial
Growers pop on there but feel free to
stop by MRG grow.com Forum sign up to
that and feel free to share your grow or
you can ask questions in there but
canabas 420 posted about carbonated
water and whether or not it's beneficial
so I'm going to read off his scenario
here and then uh you can give me some
insight on it so he had mentioned that
he uses carbonated water to water his
plants and carbonated water lowers the
pH drastically to four to 6 pH he had to
up the pH to over 10 pH to get close to
his liking so he dumped a bunch of pH Up
in there and was wondering if that's
safe to use also wondering when the
carbonation wears off will the water's
pH shoot back up to 10 pH so I might
have read that a little bit wrong but
basically he's seeing these pH
adjustments with adding carbonated water
in there so can you give us some insight
on carbonated water whether or not it's
beneficial to use within the grow yeah
carbonated water is not beneficial to
use in a grow there's a couple of
reasons for this the primary reason is
that carbonated water contains CO2 and
CO2 inside of the water likes to not
stay in the water so it goes up and out
of the water um so these swings in PH
actually follow this equilibrium between
carbonic acid that's dissolved inside of
the solution or the liquid phase and
then the CO2 that's being spontaneously
off gased this is actually why this is
the same exact phenomena why if you open
up a can of soda on a hot summer day
well first off all all carbonated
beverages are pressurized the reason
that they're pressurized is because if
they're not pressurized the CO2 wants to
leave in a normal atmospheric setting
just like Outdoors uh or even just
sitting inside of a living room because
we're not in a pressurized environment
anytime that we have CO2 present inside
of a liquid solution the natural default
tendency is or the default state is for
that CO2 to escape back out into the
atmosphere so um this this is why the pH
swings because initially you have a high
concentration of carbonic acid that's
present um which lowers the ph and then
if you just let that you know can of
soda or carbonated water sit out for
long enough it will eventually go
completely flat it'll still have you
know it'll be mildly acidic but um the
point is that the CO2 doesn't want to
stay in there so it doesn't really serve
a benefit to the plants um also it's
worth mentioning that the the oxygen
that's present that's attached to the
carbon is what um creates an energy draw
on the plants you know they have to use
the power of the sun to break that
oxygen off of the carbon so it's not
like you're doing the plants any favors
by watering in CO2 it'd be better to
have instead of the oxidized carbon or
the one that has the oxygen it'd be
better to have reduced carbon meaning no
oxygen inside of it things like organic
acids are a really good example of this
because they already have that power
that energy is already kind of built
into the bond um that the molecule has
with you know the carbon based molecule
has a particular amount of power power
that's stored inside of it or energy
that's stored inside of it um the other
thing to consider too is that often
times carbonated water can interact
adversely with minerals like calcium for
example you can start to form
bicarbonates bicarbonate residues in the
soil and the buildup of bicarbonate can
actually be quite harmful this is why
when you look at applying things like
oyster shell meal or crab shell meal or
any kind of shell meal that's a calcium
rich even even eggshells from chickens
they have the same problem of the
carbonate there is not very conducive to
plant biochemistry nor is it conducive
towards soil chemistry and a lot of
times it just kind of like it binds up
and ties minerals in a way that makes
them less available for plants to take
up um bicarbonate residues can also
Drive the ph up as well this is why
often times I see well water that has a
high pH well water can be alkaline the
pH sometimes can be eight or nine
because there's calcium in the Pres you
know calcium is present inside of that
well water but it's specifically in the
form of calcium carbonate or calcium
bicarbonate you know there are these
various carbonate um you know molecules
attached to the calcium or the Magnesium
or the potassium that make it a little
bit less soluble overall so it could be
a little bit of a problem more than it
is a good way to deliver carbon to the
plants that kind of make sense yeah I
actually have a lot of bicarbonates and
actually a lot of sodium in my tap water
and that increases my pH and uh I didn't
really know the impact of it at first I
mean I tried to use my tap water before
you know I wanted to be more
eco-friendly here in the tap water
instead of uh having to use AO which
does produce some some waste water which
I actually use that in my outdoor Garden
so I'm not truly truly wasting it but
having the sodium and bicarbonates in it
screwed up my plants so I'm never using
those ever again I'm forced to kind of
filter it out and I feel like bicarbon
it's kind of sneak in people's regimen
in in a sense in their source of water
right so yeah I'm glad you mentioned
that and called that one out yeah yeah
and that kind of that Dov tails
perfectly into a question about you know
like adjusting the pH I guess you could
say you know is that what what would you
use to adjust the pH obviously you know
it's an important
consideration um I do think that in some
cases like for your water in particular
if you have a lot of calcium carbonate
or even sodium
carbonate um particularly if it's high
in calcium you know the the least
effective way to adjust the pH is going
to be by using a phosphoric acid based
or a sulfuric acid based pH Down and the
reason for that is because if you have
high calcium dissolved in the tap water
or in the well water and you're putting
a large amount of phosphorus or sulfur
in with that you're going to create
calcium sulfate which is gypsum or
drywall or you're going to create
calcium phosphate which is what your
bones are made out of and neither one of
those two forms of calcium is very
soluble so what you're doing is taking
the calcium that's naturally present in
the water and exposing it to a compound
that decreases the availability of that
calcium I would say it's a much better
better idea to use something like
vinegar to adjust the pH because that
particular um form of calcium calcium
acetate is significantly more soluble
it's like thousands of times more
soluble than the calcium phosphate and
the calcium sulfate so for every drop of
vinegar that you put in you could be
increasing the availability of calcium
significantly for the plants rather than
decreasing it the other thing to
consider too is that a lot of the
interactions that organic acids have
with carbonates is one that they'll
attack chemically the carbonate Bond
itself that that you know the carbonate
is bonded to a cation and they'll attack
that Bond free up that mineral and
effectively keate it or complex it and
then the bicarbonate gets off gas to CO2
because of that chemical attack if you
will that uh proper pH down like a
vinegar based PH down would be able to
afford um most of the vinegar out there
that you buy at the store is going to be
around 3 to 5% acidity if you're dealing
with really really hard well water it
might be beneficial to find something
stronger they do make like an 80% acetic
acid solution sometimes it'll be called
glacial acetic acid um the stuff is very
very concentrated you know phosphoric
acid is interesting because you can open
up a bottle of 75% fos acid and smell it
and it smells actually kind of sweet
it's not unpalatable but if you try to
do the same thing with 80% vinegar
you're going to burn your nose your eyes
are going to burn you're going to cough
and it's just not going to be a good day
so I would recommend people to use
vinegar if they're dealing with water
that's high in calcium but find the
appropriate strength if it's 3 to 5%
that's perfectly fine it's going to work
great nice little benefit there too is
that any kind of excess organic acid
excess vinegar is going to get rapidly
metabolized it's a really really good
food source for beneficial microbes and
fungi in fact acetic acid residues or
acetates are the most common metabolites
in all of nature everything has an
acetate associated with it at some point
everything that microbes do um dovetails
perfectly into acetate based chemistry
and same thing with fungi and plants as
well they all utilize very very high
concentrations of acetate so it becomes
very difficult to throw the equilibrium
in the soil off it becomes very
difficult to burn the plants you could
easily overdo it with something like a
sulfuric acid or a nitric acid
phosphoric acid you know you can really
damage um if taken too far you can
really damage the physical and chemical
properties of the soil plus the
biological qualities of the soil but the
same thing is much hard hard to achieve
when you're using organic acids like
vinegar it's so difficult to put too
much in obviously you you'd have to like
really go overboard but you know um
point being ultimately that there's a
huge buffer range as far as what's safe
and what's acceptable I'm going to have
to switch to vinegar after hear in this
one yeah cuz that was one of the
questions is a lot of Growers swear that
using some sort of organic or allnatural
PH adjuster is better than using like
phosphoric acid for example lemon juice
was named you talked about vinegar
baking soda was also named so you would
generally recommend for them for folks
to go after those sources versus
synthetic sources I would say in mosta
in almost all cases yeah it makes a lot
of sense to do it that way um and keep
in mind too that you know the organic
acids like the if you're using lemon
juice for example or if you're using uh
vinegar those types of acids are quickly
metabolized by almost all organisms on
this planet um this is a really
important consideration because
when plants are exposed to high
concentrations of these acids they can
take them up and they'll just burn them
as extra fuel sources it's not a problem
for them to intake you know pretty much
everything that you throw at them and to
be able to actually properly metabolize
it plants have not evolved similar
mechanisms to deal with high
concentrations of phosphoric acid
because it just doesn't exist out of
nature like there's no such thing as
phosphoric acid out of nature anywhere
but there is such a thing as vinegar and
acetic acid and citric acid and ascorbic
acid acid which is what you're going to
find inside of lemon juice which is
Vitamin C basically citric acid is a
little bit different I think a lot of
people associate citrus fruits with
citric acid and certainly citrus fruits
produce some citric acid but they
primarily produce a different kind of
acid called ascorbic acid which is
vitamin C and that's the chief organic
acid that they produce but um ascorbic
acid is useful in Plants it's actually a
fundamental in all plants that are grown
anywhere on Earth ascorbic acid is one
of the fundamental non entic
antioxidants inside of a plant meaning
if you knock out ascorbic acid and you
just prevent the plant from having it
there is no such thing as a plant cell
anymore it can't function without
ascorbic acid it's fundamental to the
existence of a plant so of course it
makes sense if you supplement organic
acids like vitamin C to the plants that
they naturally have a very uh
sophisticated way of dealing with it
they they can fun you they break they
can take it in break it down and then
funnel that energy towards any number of
things but that's not true with sulfuric
acid or nitric acid or phosphoric acid
so you'll find that the tolerance that
your plants and your soil and your
microbes have for vinegar are
significantly greater than you know for
phosphoric acid and some of the
synthetic pH Downs um I would avoid
using baking soda if possible because
baking soda is typically um it's a it's
a carbonator or bicarbonate um and that
could kind of create some some issues
overall so now can some of these pH Up
PH down sources kill off microbes that's
a common thing that people had mentioned
like hey if you're using these things
they're killing off microbes now
obviously in their raw form right isn't
vinica used as like a cleaning method
it's like it's supposed to kill off
microbes so like in its raw form it'll
do harm but people worried that when
you're using ph up and PH down just in
water it's still harming microbial life
once you're actually pouring that into
the medium is there any truth to to that
or is that just Bro Science for the
purpose of the dilute feed water that
you're applying to the plants it's not
really going to harm the microbes in
fact like nitrates for example which I
think a lot of people associate with
detrimental effects on soil biology
nitrates are very common they're a
natural source of nitrogen um they get
produced by microbes they get produced
by you know thunderstorms when there's
lightning that goes through the sky that
intense heat that plasma that's
generated breaks dite nren gas bonds
apart in the atmosphere and if there's
rain it'll take that you know nitrogen
that's been broken apart and solubilize
it and rain down some nitrates that's
why plants actually look you know after
a thunderstorm the air has a particular
smell and plants may look a little bit
more perky and a little bit more green
and it has partially to do with the fact
that there's soluble nitrogen fertilizer
being created as a part of this natural
process so nitrates are very very
natural um when used excessively I think
they can throw equilibriums off in soils
and it takes a long time to actually you
know destroy the soil biology because
the soil bi biology will do everything
that it can to stay alive um if you're
talking about like the specific
mechanism of action for oxidizers which
are like you know potassium hydroxide
based ph up I mean yeah they'll break
down cell walls they will completely
denature DNA and they'll cause
irreversible damage to anything that it
touches plants fungi um microorganisms
even humans shouldn't be exposed to
pottassium hydroxide but again for the
purpose of creating D dilute feed water
um usually it's not measured in that
kind of way um you know pottassium
hydroxide is used to make soap and last
time you washed your hands with soap it
didn't cause a chemical burn right so
the way that something is ultimately
processed informs how it's going to be
metabolized or how it's going to be
accepted into a system um I would say if
you're just dosing your plants with just
straight ph up or pH Down um that's
going to cause some serious damage but
again when you're talking about the tank
of feed water that's made that you're
going to apply to your plants usually
that tends to hang out in a PH range
that's mostly acceptable and the
concentration of nutrients is also um
pretty universally accepted for all
plants and all microbes and all fungi
you may notice a decrease in the overall
activity of certain like fungi for
example that are known to help plants
access phosphorus in phosphorus limited
conditions this is one of the benefits
that um you know beneficial might uh
beneficial fungi can bring into the
garden but if you're not deficient in
phosphorus that one little pathway could
get turned off but there's other
benefits associated with having that
fungi there you know there could be some
stress response or stress related um
benefits there could be some disease
suppression benefits fungi produce all
kinds of wonderful antimicrobial
compounds antiviral compounds these can
be useful for plants um outside of just
their ability to help fix and make a
little bit of phosphorus more available
to to the plants got it and you kind of
touched upon the next question here a
little bit but I'm going to ask it again
in case there's anything else that you
can add to it which is synthetic
nutrients killing off microbes now it's
often said that mineral-based or
synthetic nutrients salt-based is going
to cause a high seleny environment
that's going to kill off the microbial
life in the soil now some people say
that that's true you know a lot of
organic gardeners they avoid bottled
nutrients because of that and other
folks say that that's false that these
microbes are able to withstand the henan
environment down in the root Zone what's
your take on that I mean I think soil
microorganisms are capable of living in
environments that um are pretty intense
I think there's some evidence to suggest
they can even survive on comets that
have been you know maybe not comets but
like some spacecraft that have been
launched toter space I remember there
was a study that was done on water bears
tardigrada was the genus and they had
launched them into outer space basically
Bally noticed that you know the intense
radiation outside of the atmosphere of
the earth um these water bears were
capable of surviving and and actually
reproducing so um in some cases I think
the same thing is true of fungi and
microbes I think there's even a theory
out there that suggests that either
beneficial microbes or fungi you know
once came from a different planet and
they somehow survived on a comet that
smashed into the planet and that's how
life started or spread so if you just
look at the uh ability of these
microorganisms to survive in extremely
harsh environments it becomes clear that
you know a little bit of ion ionized
fertilizer isn't really going to damage
them sufficiently enough to kill them um
I would say in most cases the microbes
themselves have the ability to resist
those types of stressors if you will and
then also keep in mind that anything
that really directly benefits the plant
the microbes will find a way to dovetail
into that operation because their
primary interest is in getting sugars
from the plant right so they form these
beneficial Rel relationships the plant
will photosynthesize and produce sugars
and even if you're using a synthetic
fertilizer as long as the plant is
healthy and it's growing it's very
likely that the plant is capable of also
supporting beneficial relationships in
the soil too so that's a major
consideration um I will say that there
are um physical and chemical changes
that can happen to the soil depending on
how much organic matter is going to be
present inside of a feed program I guess
you could say if you're just feating
pure salt-based fertilizer with no
organic matter whatsoever no humic acid
no se plant extracts no terrestrial
plant extracts just salt-based
fertilizer over time the introduction of
high concentrations of these elements
can start to strip away at the organic
matter and it's really the loss of the
organic matter in soils that's tied to a
decline in the populations of beneficial
microbs and beneficial fungi so if you
can focus on building up that healthy
soil chemistry effectively what that
means is that you're building up the
supply of carbon available for those
microorganisms to thrive on and if that
if anything attacks that directly like
you know nitrates and other um
salt-based compounds that come in
through you know salt-based fertilizer
programs those can actually start to
directly impact the concentration of
organic matter and as that decreases so
too does the populations of beneficial
microbes and fungi but as far as the
direct link between you know the
salt-based fertilizers and the viability
of beneficial microbes and fungi I think
it's a little bit more disconnected like
there's there's other layers of stuff
that you have to work through in order
to get to that Downstream effect of yeah
this damaged the soil biology well how
did it damage the soil biology it
stripped all the carbon um it removed
everything that the microbes depend on
for Life basically and you know that's
ultimately what ends up happening got it
yeah I appreciate you expanding on that
one I still I mean I've been working in
the industry here since 2015 and this is
something that has has been brought up
since then and still to this day people
still bring it up and still want to talk
about it so appreciate getting your
Insight on there and giving us some uh
some additional information so these
next couple ones on the list were
actually submitted by you something you
want to talk about first up let's talk
PK boosters give us your Insight on
those I think there is a little bit of a
myth associated with PK boosters I think
people overutilize phosphorus without
understanding exactly how it's going to
get metabolized in the plants and the
important thing to remember is that most
phosphorus in the maybe not most but
let's say half of the phosphorus roughly
that you apply to your plants is going
to get recycled in the plant it's not
going to just get sunk into some like
calcium for example get sunk into a cell
wall it kind of hangs out there and it
doesn't really interact with the rest of
the plant once it's been deposited so
plants naturally have a very high
appetite for calcium they can take up
monster quantities of it because they
know there is a terminal sink they can
just shove it in a cell wall and they
don't have to deal with it so if they
get a little bit more than what they
actually need it's perfectly fine cuz
they they can always find a place to you
know put it into and and make a new cell
wall out of um but for phosphorus
because it's primarily recycled in
plants or it becomes a constituent of
membranes um which are also more or less
like fixed you know they they don't um
regenerate or they don't require as much
replenishment like calcium and saw walls
does um this being the case means that
the optimum concentration of phosphorus
to expose your plants to is actually a
lot lower than a lot of Growers think
and I think according to the research
articles that have been put out there
most plants will do well with about 30
to 50 ppms of Elemental phosphorus what
you see on the labels is actually not
Elemental phosphorus it's phosphorus
expressed as
p205 so there's a little bit of a
conversion factor how do you go from P
to p25 there's a number you multiply by
I think it's like 4364 or something like
that but you know quick Google Google
search for those of you who are
interested just type in conversion
factor
P to uh p205 you know do that and then
you'll find a calculator online that
will allow you to convert it but
basically 30 to 50 ppms is kind of The
Sweet Spot for most plants and to give
you guys some context in the vegetative
stage of growth where your plants are
taking in a large concentration of
nitrogen you can feed upwards of 150
maybe closer to 200 parts per million of
nitrogen compare that with 30 to 50 of
phosphorus um pottassium you can feed in
some cases I've seen you know in excess
of 400 parts per million probably closer
to 500 parts per million compare that
with 30 to 50 of phosphorus and then
same thing with calcium calcium can be
fed in massive concentrations 200 plus
ppms no problem and again phosphorus
clocks in 30 to 50 so in a lot of cases
I think when adding too much of a PK
booster into the soil really what you're
doing is encouraging the tie up between
the phosphorus that's needed in low
concentrations and the calcium that's
needed in high concentrations and this
is why during the mid to late stages of
Bloom plants tend to slow down they get
yellow the disease pressure start to
creep in things like um molds and milus
petrius these things start to become uh
disease pressures for plants not because
of anything to do with phosphorus
directly but rather a lack of calcium
that's caused by excess of phosphorus
fertilization it's also worth mentioning
that because phosphorus doesn't have an
actual sink for most plants I mean it it
does if you're growing for seed right if
you grow some flowers out and you want
those flowers to actually be pollinated
and to develop a seed the actual seed
itself is a good sink for phosphorus so
you can if you're growing for seed and
you want good viability from those seeds
it makes sense in that context to do a
little bit of a PK boost particularly
during the seed formation stage because
then the plants will take up the extra
phosphorus and they'll actually sink it
into the seed but if you're growing just
the flower
and you don't want any seeds the overall
maximum for phosphorus is going to be
much lower because again there's no seed
and so there's no sink for the plant
this is an important consideration okay
let's move down the line here I don't
want to take up too much of your time we
definitely pass the hour mark by now but
lot of good information I'm going to hit
you with a few more here and then I'll
let you go foler sprays or foiler spray
I think some people pronounce it foiler
some people pronounce it foler either
way tomatoes tomato
spraying with the lights on versus
lights off now some people say this's
harm in spraying with the lights on
other people say it's going to be fine
what's your take on that um it depends
on what it is you're applying to the
plants and it depends on the nature of
the keyate itself I will say um it's
worth paying attention to what happens
in a tropical rainforest where the sun
is always out and it tends to rain quite
a bit and it seems like tropical
rainforests are pretty uh diverse in
terms of the total number of plant
species so these are very very
biodiverse regions there's a huge number
of plants that are growing and they've
kind of evolved these mechanisms to deal
with you know the the Sun and Rain being
present at the same time um there's no
real like magnifying effect I've heard
people um say something like that where
water droplets can kind of magnify the
energy of the sun um I don't really
think that's the case to be perfectly
honest I do think that there's some
cause for concern if you're dealing with
you know compounds that are insoluble
that are present inside of the water
that you're applying like carbonates for
example if you've got well water that's
a very high TDS and it's not treated and
it's not filtered doing fure sprays of
that could result in some kind of damage
because what ends up happening is as the
outer layer of the leaf dries the
minerals that are present inside of that
water end up not being absorbed properly
by the plant and they tend to hang out
on the outer layers of the leaf so as
the water evaporates and the leaf
surface dries off they're prog
aggressively begins to be a little bit
of salt formation that happens and it's
really that salt formation that can you
know create some problems for the plants
if you have organic acids if you've got
amino acids or if you've got some
chelated forms of nutrients those
typically get absorbed pretty rapidly
through the leaf surfaces and doing
foler sprays with the lights on is
generally speaking not an issue um
obviously it makes sense you know to
test on a small number of plants first
and maybe turn the lights down a little
little bit maybe at 50% if you've got
the ability to adjust the light
intensity but if you've never done
something like that before or if you're
curious to see if the nutrients that you
have are available through the leaf
surfaces that's a good practice pick a
small number of plants turn the lights
down a little bit spray the plants
during the middle of the day and see
what happens and then from there work
your way up to gradually becoming more
and more comfortable feeding your plants
um with the lights on doing F your
sprays I think it can in a lot of ways
it can actually be highly beneficial
because water itself has a very high
heat capacity it can absorb a lot of
heat um and this is important on days
where it's very very hot in fact I
remember a couple of years ago here in
Washington it was very hot you know
maybe 2 or 3 years ago in August it was
something like 110 and we typically
don't get that hot here in the Pacific
Northwest I mean for us a really hot day
is like 85 to 90 so for us to be
sitting at 110 was like freakishly hot
and I remember going outside I was
growing some zucchini and cucumbers at
the time I remember going outside and I
ful sprayed my plants with a calcium
chelate it was 110 outside it was 100
p.m. smack dab in the middle of the day
you know in the middle of August and the
sun was directly overhead I mean they
could not have gotten any more intense
um but because the keyate that I was
spraying was 100% available for the
plants to take up it didn't burn them at
all and I used a pretty hefty dose I
used a dose that was somewhere between
80 to 100 ml per gallon which is
astronomical I mean I would typically
for this calcium chelate I would
recommend people use it um at the rate
of maybe 10 to 20 Mill per gallon and I
ended up using it 80 to 100 milliliters
per gallon which is crazy high
concentration so if there was any kind
of phytotoxicity associated with that
compound itself it would have manifested
itself within a matter of minutes
because the leaf surface dried out
within 10 minutes but the plants
actually looked a little bit more perky
they looked a little bit more Upp and I
I attribute part of that effect that I
saw to the fact that I sprayed water on
the leaf surface so all of that heat the
leaf surface temperature it was just
baking in the sun it was getting
scorched and it wasn't doing too well of
course I come and give it a cool spray
of water that water soaks up that heat
just like a sponge and the leaf surface
cooled down dramatically now instead of
the engine overheating within plants now
we've brought that engine back to its
operational temperature range now it's
just kind of cruising along through the
rest of the day so I would say there's
some real benefits associated with the
timing of application being the middle
of the day if you have those types of
stressors where it's very hot and the
light intensity is very high and you
know you have a good fully key product
that's not going to cause phytotoxicity
issues that's good to know this reminds
me of conversation we had with por
cantes actually didn't get a chance to
um to talk to him about it I had him on
the from the stash podcast that episode
is being released in a couple weeks here
but one of the things that I wanted to
talk to him but couldn't talk to him
about was reverse foler feeding so I
actually have a little excerpt from his
grower Bible book and I'd like to get
your thoughts on it since it relates to
folar feeding and it's talking about
clones it says the clones from the lower
branches root easiest because they
contain more of the proper hormones
clones quickly develop a dense system of
roots when stems have a high
carbohydrate and low nitrogen
concentration so it's recommended to
reverse folar feed which will leech
nutrients from leaves especially
nitrogens to reverse folar feed fill a
spray with clean water and Mist mother
Heavenly every morning for 3 to 4 days
older leaves may turn like green growth
slows as nitrogen is used in
carbohydrates build so my interpretation
of this is if you're just spraying water
on the leaves it's actually impacting it
in a way where nitrogen is being used up
a little bit more is there any truth to
that or is this kind of outdated
information I think it's a little bit
outdated information particularly the
idea that the lower branches tend to
root out easier um it's very well
established and known now that it's
actually the meristematic tissue the
apical meristem that con contains the
highest concentration of oxin which are
the primary rooting hormones most
Growers are familiar with these little
gels that they get um root gels they dip
a cut inside of it and it kind of coats
that um you know the the actual stem in
the cutting so that is a synthetic
rooting hormone called indol 3 butyric
acid the natural analog what that
synthetic version is trying to replicate
is a natural rooting hormone called
indol 3 acetic acid which is the primary
oxin and as I mentioned just a few
minutes ago acetates are the most
abundant metabolite in nature here's an
example of what what I'm talking about
the primary growth hormone in plants is
called indol 3 acetic acid it's an
acetic acid residue basically so it's
important to keep that in mind but yeah
that is going to be most concentrated at
the apical meristem um and those tend to
have the most vigorous growth associated
with them anyways the lower branches
tend to not grow as fast as the top
portion of the canopy the top portion of
the canopy is the one that gets the
majority of the transpiration stream so
all that good nutrition that's being
lift up from the roots it's actually
being preferentially transported to that
apical meristem the newest smallest site
of growth so that it can constantly uh
provide a stable supply of building
blocks of nutrients and elements to feed
the growth of the plant and so if you
can capture a snapshot of that you get
you get a snapshot and by snapshot I
actually mean you know you take a cut
off a plant that's very healthy growing
very vigorously very rapidly those are
the types of characteristics that you're
likely to see come out of that
um The Cutting itself and there are
strategies that I've seen work out
pretty well where if you take care of
your mom plants with a particular
combination of folar sprays you can
actually load those rooting hormones up
inside of the plant so that when you
take the cut it actually has precursors
for indol 3 acetic acid inside of it so
you don't need that um gel anymore you
don't need to dip your Cuts or your
clones and wait you know 7 to 10 days
for them to root out you can actually
put that natural compound inside of the
plants it gets absorbed through the fol
your spray in about 15 to 20 minutes
later you take a cut and then everything
inside of that cut is going to be
exactly what the plant needs then
propagate new roots and to grow out
successfully and usually Growers will
save a couple of days instead of 7 to 10
days on uh rooting we you know might see
about 5 to seven days instead no I'm
going to have to try that a little
shortcut there a little grow hack there
yeah the amount of stuff that we have
learned over the years I mean that quote
that I mentioned was from a book that
was written in 2006 and we have learned
so much since 2006 it's awesome the
amount of information that we've
uncovered through science and just
regular experiments has been exciting
it's really exciting and I'm excited to
see what happens here in the future I'm
going to hit you with two more and I
saved the two funnest ones for last for
some they might seem completely
outrageous others they say that it's
legitimate let's hear your take on this
music for plants does playing music for
your plants help with plant growth I've
also heard that playing bird chirping
noises helps with plant growth whether
it be a I don't know if it's the stamato
opening or what but those are a couple
things I've heard what's your take on
that it's a really interesting topic and
I'll say that the um the underlying
logic was actually developed in the late
1980s there was a researcher um Don
Carlson I think was his name at
University of Minnesota I want to say if
my memory serves correctly but anyways
you know researcher in 1986 um had put
forward this idea that the stomata
themselves could be the the conductance
of the stomata meaning the opening and
the closing of the stamata could be
influenced by um sound frequencies and
so what he did was he exposed those
plants to 3,000 Herz to 5,000 Hertz
which basically mimics a bird chirp in
the morning and what he found was over
15 years of research I believe it was
that there is in fact a correlation
between playing noises bird chirps Maybe
music even to some extent in the overall
impact that it has on the the growth of
the plants um I I'll I'll kind of back
up one step and say that plants are
remarkably sensitive to their
environment they're exceptionally
capable of taking in a variety of
different inputs they're trying to
measure and sense every possible nook
and cranny of reality that's external to
them because again they don't have a
choice they can't like get up and move
around if the environment's not ideal so
they're always trying to figure out
what's going on in the environment
around them they're taking in as many
data points that they possibly can um
and with that being said they are
sensitive to sound waves that come
through them um with specifically in
reference to the way that the stamata um
open and Clos it's it's less to do with
the physical opening and physical
closing of the stomata and more to do
with the maximum size of the stomata
being opening it's maximum conductance
how how open does it actually get um
think about that like a fuel injector
for a race car you know if you're trying
to create more horsepower inside of the
system you need those fuel uh injectors
to squirt more fuel for every second
that the engine is operational and so
this kind of effectively translates to a
way that the stomato open and close
because if you have stomata opened a
little bit further even if it's a 10 to
15% increase in the conductance of the
stomata then um you know you could
theoretically achieve a 10 to 15%
increase in productivity in the plants I
will say that this has been studied
extensively and it's not just like this
one factor that determines it all
because you know ultimately
photosynthesis and even stodel
conductance is driven by a very
fine-tuned Balancing Act plants will
open and close selectively based on a
number of different things that occur
during the winter time you know the
sun's still out but maybe some certain
species of plants aren't growing because
to them it's less about the exposure to
the Sun and more about what temperature
it is right and then in some other cases
plants are very sensitive to photop
period triggers this is how initiate
flowering and so there's all of these
different influencing variables that
ultimately kind of converge together and
that's the final response that the plant
has but if you have everything kind of
dialed in if you have good temperature
good humidity um it's very it's very
true that exposing your plants to the
right frequencies can actually make a a
difference in their growth overall and I
think that's possible to measure um I
think people maybe have taken it a
little bit outside the context of how
that theory was initially
developed and how it's been tested um
but it's certainly true to say that
plants will respond to frequencies just
like they respond to frequencies of
light they'll respond to frequencies of
sound that's interesting yeah I heard a
couple things that relate to this
singing to your plant so kind of along
the lines of of playing music for your
plants but I've heard about this old
wives till or something it was this lady
who sung to her plants and then the
other plants she didn't sing to and she
saw better growth in the plants that she
sung to I'll come to find out it was
just the carbon dioxide that she was
emitting you know from her her exhale
that was contributing to the the growth
it wasn't actually the the singing that
did it so I thought that was kind of
funny to to bring up up not sure if
you've heard of of that one or not I
have yeah I also wanted to bring up in
regards of playing music for your plants
that the DB would have to be crazy loud
in order for it to be any impact the
equivalent of a jet engine going off
that's when uh you know has to be that
loud in order for it to actually make an
impact to the plant I don't know if
that's true or not but I've heard that
well you know it's interesting I mean so
there's a branch of science called
simatics and it's basically the effect
that sound frequencies have on the
formation of um you know like on
geometric patterns that can be formed so
the idea basically is like you've got a
subwoofer and you put a little bit of
salt on top of the subwoofer and
depending on what frequency is being
played it will generate a different kind
of you know geometry I guess you could
say um a lot of it is is pretty
fascinating it's interesting to see what
exactly happens but it's certainly true
that but um water will respond to
certain types of sound frequencies you
know you can kind of change the geometry
of of water so to speak and so I imagine
there's a similar mechanism that could
actually be at play here you know a lot
of this stuff is very very subtle and
very nuanced um and a lot of it is just
like maybe considered a little bit taboo
and we just don't have the
instrumentation that's sensitive enough
for us to be able to accurately measure
some of this type of stuff so the um
General consensus right now in the
scientific Community is probably that
it's a little bit teric more than it is
practical but there have been a lot of
really good research articles that have
been coming out especially recently that
kind of bridge the gaps in our
understanding because they have more
sensitive Machinery now that it's
possible for us to make these
measurements and kind of you know
separate the signal from the noise in
some other cases like what you just
mentioned you know the singing of that
this lady she sang to her plants it was
actually the CO2 that she released which
caused the increase in yield and so that
that's there's some signal there and
then there's some noise there too and I
think being able to peel it apart is
what we're kind of getting to a spot of
being able to do um and and certainly
there's good reason to think that plants
are going to respond to this type of
stuff I mean they kind of evolved they
coevolved they attract pollinators like
birds and like other you know uh bees
for example and so it it stands to
reason that they could also maybe
there's some electromagnetic interaction
there too um I think this was actually
something that was determined to be true
with uh the way that lavender um
interacts with bees I guess lav lavender
if I recall correctly um the study was
demonstrating that lavender actually
lavender plants emit a particular
frequency it's not something that you
can hear it's not audible frequency but
it's still a frequency that gets emitted
and it allows the bees to navigate
towards the the flow that's ready to be
the nectar is ready to be harvested out
of that particular flour and when the
bee harvests nectar out of that bud and
it flies away the electromagnetic
frequency is no longer there it's maybe
turned off for about 1 minute to 2
minutes while that bud you sort of you
know the nectar kind of fills that butt
and again I I maybe butchering the
explanation overall of what this study
demonstrated but the idea was basically
that yeah plants are emitting if not
noises that are audible to the human ear
there's still frequencies that they're
putting out there in the surrounding
space around them to try to attract
these pollinators some of those
frequencies are not um compounds you
know we often associate attracting
pollinators with the production of vol
compounds things that we can actually
smell and this is true it does work like
that but there's also something to be
said about maybe other ways of
attracting beneficial pollinators and I
think this opens up a discussion around
these electromagnetic things that we're
starting to be able to measure and
quantify and better understand um so
yeah there's something there for sure
that's incredible that's super super
interesting it reminds me of a
electroculture and that's the last one
we're going to talk on talk about today
you know I don't have a lot of knowledge
about Electro culture I just see these
Tik Tok videos and Instagram reals where
these guys are like sticking things into
the ground and attaching to the plant
and can you explain to us what electr
culture is and is there any value to it
does it actually work or is this like
not something that works whatsoever yeah
and electr culture is interesting
because you know like we just talked
about with um with bird chps and with
noises you know that came out of a
university in the in the 1980s you know
so there was someone that did actually
did a lot of work 15 years worth of
research and he was able to demonstrate
and and you know prove pretty much that
there is something at play here um
whether or not he was 100% right is less
relevant than the fact that he
discovered something worth exploration
you know there's definitely something
going on let's try to characterize it
let's try to figure out what's happening
electrial culture is a little bit older
um probably goes back to like the mid
1800s maybe the late 1800s people were
trying to figure out if electrical
Fields had any kind of impact on plant
growth and you know keep in mind this is
before we even knew or you know had a
very good understanding of NPK
fertilizer we had no idea what the
Essential Elements were for plant growth
we didn't know calcium from phosphorus
back then you know this stuff was
characterized much later but the idea
basically is that with electroculture
you are creating an electrical field for
the plants typically it's a piece of
copper wire or copper tubing that's used
um in this electrical field will impact
plant growth or benefit plant growth um
I think a lot of people misunderstand
what is actually going on there are some
benefits that can be associated with it
but there's so many different like you
know variables that could happen like if
this then that if that then this there's
all these like dependencies that get
formed um I think when we're talking
about strictly you know electric culture
is intended to create an electrical
field okay so let's look at that what
happens when you subject um soil
particles to an electrical field well if
you have ionized compounds ionized
elements like ionized calcium ionized
magnesium or whatever those ions
actually get affected by the electrical
field and they can actually move a
little bit differently and so the idea
basically is that yeah electrical Fields
can actually dovetail into nutrient
metabolism and plants at large but then
the modifier for that is like yeah but
what if you don't have ionized particles
in your you don't have ionized atoms
inside of your soil because mostly the
soil is not full of you know ionized
particles we're dealing with like
mineralized forms of nitrogen for for
example not ionized forms of nitrogen
we're dealing with complexes that are
more or less stabilized we have this
sort of like thing charge balance thing
figured out if you amend your soil with
calcium sulfate you're not dealing with
ionized calcium at that point and so the
electrical field is maybe a little bit
less relevant overall I think people
also misunderstand the electrical field
by thinking that it directly feeds
photosynthetic Pathways and that is
actually not how it works at all um
plants use the power of the sun they you
know convert um
light energy into chemical energy
through the electron transport chain but
the electron transport chain and how
it's evolved to work in plants is much
different than a piece of copper wire
and electricity that flows in that
copper wire the two like very little
connective tissue between the two of
them and I think it's also worth
pointing out that copper itself is
considered a micronutrient inside of
plants yes it's used for its
electrochemical um properties I believe
this is something we had talked about on
your show last episode but it's
accumulated in small concentration in
the plants and you know my suspicion
there is that if there was some real
benefit associated with this generation
of electric field that could help
stimulate plant growth nature probably
would have found a way to incorporate it
into primary metabolism a little bit
further and to a more you know deep
extent than it currently is inside of
plants um for very long time now you
know preceding the existence of any
human on earth um plants have been doing
this photosynthesis thing with no help
at all from copper wires that have been
stuck into the ground and generating
electrical Fields um electrical Fields
can also impact the um functioning of
certain like protein complexes and
certain enzymes but again these types of
things are typically not found in nature
and so plants have not really evolved
ways to optimize being exposed to these
electrical fields in a way that like
massively increases their yield or
quality um that's why the results that
you see out there are so mixed some
people swear by electroculture because
they have 25t tall corn plants and the
ones that didn't get electroculture are
only four or 5T tall but then there's
other people who do the exact same
studies basically and they find no
difference associated with it so I would
say it's not one of those things that's
like a primary driver I'd say if if you
have ionized nutrition that could
benefit from being exposed to an
electrical field then sure you you'd see
some benefit as far as nutrient
metabolism goes but it's not like this
hidden portal where you can access
another level of your plants performance
altogether I think that's that's a
little bit of a myth or misconception um
but you know there's again there's
something interesting to be um studied
here and looked at in Greater detail but
I do think we need to better
characterize what exactly these
electrical fields are and how they work
in the context of nutrient metabolism um
enzyme activity and certainly the
biosynthesis of some secondary metabits
that that might accumulate in higher
concentrations but I don't think there's
anything that's really conclusive out
there there it proves it one way or
another um ultimately plants have
electron transport chains but that's
fundamentally different than the way
that copper conducts electricity and
creates an electrical field it would be
interesting to see some future studies
that come out because I know people are
studying it and I know people are are
using it and so I look forward to seeing
what uh what people come up with in the
future wow what an episode this has been
uh this has been awesome I think it
might actually be the longest episode
yet we usually don't go this long but I
wanted to continue because I was just so
intrigued by this conversation and uh we
had a long list of things here and I
think we touched upon a whole bunch of
different things that is really going to
be valuable to the audience so I
appreciate you coming on today and I
have a feeling that people in the
comments are going to be requesting a
part three and I would love to open the
invitation up right now to have you come
back on for a part three in the future
and i' would love to open up the invite
to the audience to leave some questions
in the comment section for part three
free so questions you have for Nick it
can be anything it can be in in regards
to any of the topics we had here today
also it could be carbon you also have PL
nutrition Nick has a wealth of knowledge
in many different areas so fire off some
questions down in the comment section
below and maybe I'll use them in a
future episode with Nick Nick thanks so
much for coming on here just a reminder
that coupon code Mr grow works on his
website rud leaf.com pick yourself up
some nutrients and uh yeah save some
coin with my discount code Nick let the
people know how they can find you and do
you have anything upcoming in the future
that you wanted to talk about oh man
we've been staying so busy um we had the
busiest month of November and December
that we've ever had and it's nice kind
of growing you know we're in 48
different states now and um we're
picking up some interest from
Distributors large large Distributors
too so it's it's fun staying busy um but
for those of you who are interested in
reaching out and learning more you can
uh get in touch with me on Instagram uh
the rooted Leaf is our Instagram and
then check out our website rooted
leaf.com we have a ton of really really
good information about what goes into
all of our products we've got a really
big resources page you'll find all the
feed charts that you need you'll find um
fol your spray charts SDS sheets labeles
all that good stuff pretty much anything
that you could ever want as a resource
you'll find on there um and feel free to
reach out to us on email as well I think
Instagram is a little bit better um I'm
typically pretty good about responding
quickly to people so if you have
questions definitely feel free to reach
out I love talking about this stuff so
there's something that you want to learn
about a little bit more or maybe you
want a particular Point clarified um
definitely feel free to reach out and
I'll do my best to get back to you guys
in a timely manner awesome and I'll
definitely have a link to his Instagram
down in the YouTube description section
below as well along with the link to his
website once again thanks so much for
coming on I I truly appreciate it this
has been awesome and I look forward to
doing another talk with you and yeah
hope you enjoy the rest of your night
peace out everyone catch you in the next
episode