welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 162 in this episode I
interview Josh Gro he has been gardening
for 12 years and is the producer for
both the dude Grow Show and The Jug
dealers podcast Grand studies a lot of
different things one of them being
lighting here in 2025 what should you
look for in a grow light is
supplementing far red worth it is
supplementing UV worth it we get into
all of that plus more in this episode if
you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow both of those channels will be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
me the goal possible thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their Advanced grow kits which
include nearly everything you need to
start growing indoors they have several
different size kits and they all come
with a grow tent grow light ventilation
system oscillating clip fan a controller
69 Pro and so much more click the link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about their grow kits and
the discount code Mr Grow at 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend is
a 215 plant additive that can be used
with synthetic bottle nutrients or in
living soil systems simply mix half
teaspoon of stash blend into a gallon of
water then water your plants with it
ingredients include corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and micro risle fungi
check it out at stash blend.com Link in
the description section below and use
the discount code the stash spider
farmer check out their genius grow
system ac5 power strip kit this power
strip features five Independent
Electrical sockets allowing you to power
and control five separate devices and it
can be managed remotely through the
spider farmer app you can connect your
grow light clip fan inline fan
humidifier and more more information is
linked in the description section below
and discount code Mr Grow 5 or on both
Amazon and their website spider-
far.com and we are back and I'm joined
with Josh Gro how you doing today I'm
very well man how are you doing good man
thanks for asking happy to have you on
the podcast today to talk all about
lighting this is something that has
changed so much over the years and now
we're in a New Year 2025 and I can't
wait to pick your brain on things to
kind of look for in a grow light we're
going to be getting into so many
different topics that relate to life Li
in you mentioned to me that you've been
doing a lot of research on it so I'm
eager to hear kind of some of the things
that you found out well the thing about
it is is that this is the you know it's
a plant it it grow this thing has been
growing for you know hundreds of
thousands millions of years like there's
not a ton of new science that comes out
week to week as far as like the actual
like oh we found out there's a new
nutrient riboflavin you know it needs
more riboflavin and so you know it's one
of those things like how do you how do
you keep up with what's going on out
there and one of the things that changes
week to week is not only the technology
of lighting obviously with all all the
different Tech that comes out but also
the science of it it's one of the least
understood aspects of uh lighting and so
when we were talking about what we
wanted to talk about it's like oh I'm
I'm super hyped on not just the lighting
and the technology but the interaction
your ppfs your DLI uh how these
different lighting Cycles affect what
the plant does how it produces biomass
versus the the voc's the volatile
organic compounds that we all like to
consume and uh yeah that's pretty much
been my uh my obsession over the last
little bit so I stoked to get to talk
about it with you that's awesome well
before we get too deep into lighting can
we do an introduction tell us a little
bit about yourself and kind of how you
got into gardening of course so uh as
some of you may know my name is Josh
grambo I'm a comedian here in Denver
Colorado I've been touring the country
for the last couple years and then uh
I've been a a you know a consumer my
whole life my entire literally my entire
not even my adult life even going into
my adolescent life and it's always
provided for me every turn every turn I
go it just seemed like when I was in
high school and I did I didn't know
where my friend group was it's like oh I
found these super cool guys that are all
enjoyed the same sort of stuff
skateboarding and hanging out and all
that stuff and the plants are right
there as part of the lifestyle and then
I need to get out of Iowa where I'm born
I'm from the band slip knots hometown of
De Moine Iowa and so I got to watch
those guys flower and leave EV they
still have houses there but it was very
uh you know inspiring to watch these
guys that I was a a freshman to their
senior so I always say I know them but
they don't know me sort of thing but I
got to watch them go from De Moine and
step up to the big leagues and I learned
that if you put in work you can actually
do things in this world and that led me
to getting out of De Moine I was a
refugee essentially I left uh De Moine
so I could go to Colorado and you know
start a family and be safe and work you
know I never fortunately never had any
serious interaction with the officials
out in the world so I was able to get
away scot-free out of a Prohibition land
as we call it and uh yeah and then when
I got to call around it's very very
expensive here it's very hard to get
around and once again the plants
provided away in again then as the
bottom started falling out of the market
and everything started kind of changing
and going the way of uh you know what is
happening now that the the butterfly
cocoon into corporate world that we're
going into it it just wasn't that uh the
profit incentive will say to do it the
way I had always been doing it and so I
stepped away and I was like let me start
doing comedy and I I went and I did I
did it I I didn't do it like at the
arena level but I you know I started
grinding my way up takes years and years
of grinding that and after a big road
trip I did a 5we tour all across America
started in Florida ended in Utah
zigzagged from from Maine to you know
Tennessee Iowa Minnesota every you know
I think we did 28 States and 35 nights
had the most fun of my entire life and
we made good money on the trip and I
came home $300 in the negative and I was
like man when I get back to Denver I got
to figure out like something that can
like be my my uh you know supplement
like the real thing that I I I can do to
make money and kind of provide you know
going room to room playing to 50 people
that's fun but uh actually like being
able to start a community of my own and
just so happens the week that I got back
uh the dude grow show which i' had been
a big fan of uh lost their producer and
I had over uh the lockdown and
everything when standup got taken away I
kind of gave myself a mini film school
education and on the outside of that I
didn't know why I didn't know what I was
gearing up for and turns out what it was
gearing up for was to try to spread the
message of this plant out to the world
and so it just it came by all of my
loves being funny making content and
dealing with these plants that we love
it was just a matchmate in heaven and as
soon as uh I started in it that I mean
I've been obsessed uh ever since it's
pretty much been my uh the last two and
a half years all I do is just think
plants lighting YouTube uh engagement
Community it's been so fun so the plant
provides and man it's provided a lot to
me that's awesome yeah let me just say
you have done an incredible job over at
the D Grow Show helping uh produce their
shows huge huge increase in quality
looks like viewership has increased
significantly since the old producer to
the new producer you and so all the
changes that you're doing have been seem
to be very positive you're doing a great
job over there so just want to say that
I appreciate it we uh had our Channel at
88,000 subscribers and was deleted by
YouTube for linking out to seeds which
are you know 100% fine I don't know
what's going on and so that was a big
kick in the teeth and that really REM
motivated me I could have just joined
the team and been like oh all right you
know what what do you guys want to do
but when that happened it's like well do
we quit you know like this is a
conversation that was had in a meeting
do we stop doing this and I was like we
can't you know I just through
coincidentally one of the things that
brought me to Colorado was growing and
so I had grown for a while but uh I as
as I told to grow it before we started I
was like I killed more plants than I
probably grew in my early early day days
so I knew it was going to pay the rent
when I got to Colorado so I'm I'm
dyslexic I'm not a huge reader so I'd be
on the forums i' be on your roll it up
your icy mag you know but how much can
you really glean from that and this new
thing called podcasting had like came
out in 2014 you know not in 2014 but
really gained popularity in the 2013
2014 and I got into the Adam Dunn show
and a show called John do radio in this
little fledgling group called the dude
grow show and so I've been a fan oh I
might be one of their first fans
honestly like I started listening on
episode 13 and we just recorded episode
1,718 the other day so man shout out to
those guys for going through the
adversity they get the they get the the
OG points for they did it before it was
cool over a decade yep it's incredible
incredible contributions there so what
would you say your grow style is do you
grow indoors or Outdoors soil cocoa
Hydro organic synthetic what's your
style I've always been uh indoor guy
it's uh it started as like uh you know
my friend's older brother he was the guy
that introduced me to like consuming and
everything so this is like a family I've
known since I was two next door
neighbors best friends with the youngest
brother friends with all the older
brother I was like I was a de facto
sibling so when he would go out of town
I would get tapped he's like hey I'm
going to Hawaii for two weeks like I'm
gonna teach you how to take care of my
plants like oh cool you know and pretty
all I remember from that day he would
just yell at me more C cow mag put your
cow mag on it you know that's all that's
all I remember from that and then so I
was like well when I get here I need to
really get my uh my game dialed up so as
I started educating myself it became
quite clear that the easiest most
effective way for indoor cultivation for
at least how I was going to be
performing it was to be to into Coco I
messed around with Pete for a while and
uh you know having a day job I'd be out
in the world and sometimes I I couldn't
get home in in time and i' I'd get lazy
and it and it wasn't exactly like the
thing that was the most important to me
when I was living in Iowa it was just
kind of like how do you get good product
well you know you can meet all the
people in the world and pay out the nose
or you can get yourself some some
genetics and just go that way and so
when I uh started taking the serious as
go I I became a Scotty real disciple he
was always a a a growing Coco sort of
guy so I was like all right let me start
growing a Coco found great results
immediately and what I found is that
when I did it right when I used the
nutrient program the way it was designed
and gave the plants what they needed and
the time they needed all of a sudden I
found I don't even need cow mag it was
one of my early insights of like uhoh
the people that taught me might not know
as much as I thought they knew and that
hole in my knowledge base I'm a I'm a
real like you know aggressive learner I
love learning I I'm a I used to be a
professional poker player I'm a very
very highlevel guitar player
I standup comedian I'm a 3D animator
with blender 3D animation software I
just I just have to learn and when I
have a hole in my knowledge I get real
crazy about it and I have to learn
everything and uh that's what's kind of
queued me on to my journey that's what
became so perfect about getting in the
com media game is that like I truly I'm
not in this just for a paycheck I
literally I you know the paycheck's
great pay your rent with the rock you
know we're just able to pay our rent
through the patreon supporters and all
that sort of good stuff but uh yeah I
just I really love a good puzzle and I
think growing is one of the funner
puzzles that I've came across so yeah
Coco indoor uh went from HPS to LED
that's a whole conversation that you
know that's what kind of got us going on
this topic right immediately uh as far
as lighting and yeah so I I I I've
learned a lot in the last little bit and
it just keeps changing month to month
I'm I'm stoked sounds like you're real
passionate about this community and
you're real driven to learn more and
improve and all that stuff so that's
awesome to see pack of nerds bro pack so
let's get into lighting now one of the
things I want to ask right off the bat
we have a lot of folks who are shopping
for grow lights right here in
2025 what should Growers look for when
purchasing a grow light well that's the
the question is uh is right off the bat
is uh what it's kind of like it's the
the map you know where are you trying to
go is where you're going to try to get
you know so like let's say you're in a
tent and you're inside your bedroom I
mean right off the bat we've kind of
nixed HPS out of the the picture you
know we're not going to be able to grow
with high-intensity Lighting in a in a
small tent atmosphere it's it's you have
to air cool that's one of the things
that's really uh got me educated on this
like even 10 years ago is you know
growing in a pre- LED environment where
you're stacking lights together in a
small room room they all had to be
vented hoods so we'd run air through the
hoods so we'd remove all that heat and
the byproduct of that is you were
cooling the bulb and so color
temperature like you you'd have like an
more orange uh uh number uh for the HPS
and that's that number is it's an actual
temperature color is temperature and so
when you're lowering the temperature of
the bulb to its actual spec operating
thing you're losing a lot of spectrum
and so I started learning like why is it
my friends that like have like gavitas
strapped to their ceiling and their
giant basement are getting what you know
the same gen we'd all share genetics
back then it was it was tougher you know
there wasn't all the sea a lot of the
the the genetic Banks were over in
Europe and stuff and you'd be ordering
off the back of magazines like it was
sea monkeys or something you know it
wasn't wasn't a lot of trust as far as
like the system so it was really relying
on the community so we all share
genetics we find things that we we liked
we got the Forum cut of the of the
cookies like back back back in the day
when first came out and I'm noticing
these guys are getting way better
results than I am and the only thing
that was different is I was venting them
and then turns out as I started
educating myself sure enough I was
losing a lot of spectrum you're losing a
lot of power that's supposed to be
hitting those things so if you're
choosing I would say uh there's a lot of
controversy controversy right now about
HPS versus LED and one of the things
that's very very interesting is genetic
expression phenotypic expression and I
work with The Jug guys The Jug dealers
over at New Millennium nutrients and uh
jiren always likes to say phenotype is
genotype times environment so you and I
have the same cut we got the same
genetic profile but then you put it
outside and I put it in a tent and
they're going to express differently and
so I always wondered where did all the
things that I loved in the 2000s where
did they go I still I still get the the
name some oh here's the strain you want
and they give it to me and it's got the
name and it looks kind of like it but it
didn't taste the same didn't smell the
same didn't didn't quite look the same
what happened was it was it genetic
drift you know was it all the Clones are
being abused or people lying is it not
the thing that I did and then as I
started meeting more people more
trustworthy guys that are ogs in the
game I started getting the real stuff
I'd get the real cuts from the real
people they still didn't Express why is
that and so I started digging in another
hole in knowledge and I realized oh it's
because they're not grown under vented
hoods with GH nutrients packed together
in a tiny room VPD out of control like
even bad growing conditions if there's a
a a phenotypic expression that you enjoy
the only way you're going to get it is
through an quote unquote an inferior
growing process because what plants were
selected under is what they will Thrive
under especially if you're not running
things like if you get a genetic and you
just take clone from clone from clone it
will acclimate to your environment but
it will never it it's code is locked but
when you uh take something and you breed
it like if you back cross something and
you self it and you self it against
itself and you the genetic remains it
shuffles the deck and I always remember
that family that I grew up with they
were I was friends with the the old the
middle the youngest brother well the
oldest brother he was like a genetic
copy of the mom the Middle Brother was
like a genetic copy of the dad and the
youngest brother was like a direct split
and I started understanding like oh okay
there it is when I was dealing with
plants I started getting okay recessive
genes I see what's happening it's like
some of the grandparents come in some of
the mom comes in different eye color
different skin tone different hair color
it's like okay I get it and then you
take the twin brothers and you raise
them in different places and they're
going to act completely different Twins
and raised in the same room finished
each other's sentences yet twins ra
raised across the country can have
surprisingly different lives it all
started coming together and this comes
back to lighting where one of the
biggest things that you can do to change
your environment is the lighting so if
you chose an HPS versus LED one of the
things that really makes LED Superior
Superior to HPS is that you don't need
the cooling for a a watt is a watt so if
I have a th000 watt LED and I have a
th000 watt HPS technically speaking more
light there the same exact heat but the
LEDs produce more light for that heat so
your output is there so it's not that
LEDs are cooler or you know there's more
efficient so a watts of watt a watt of
heat equals x amount of BTUs and you're
going to get what you get turns out that
when you measure things like Leaf
surface temperature right when you go in
there with a little a little thermometer
gun and you point at at the leaf the you
need to run your room slightly hotter
with LED because there isn't that
infrared there's almost no infrared that
when you see those red diodes in an LED
that's them trying to stick some red in
there because they don't come with it
whereas HPS uh high pressure sodium just
kicks out the IR that's why you could
feel the heat coming off it that's why
if you go to a restaurant you you'll see
the IR heaters you'll you'll have
something that isn't glowing it's not
red it's not hot you know to to like
visually hot there's no color coming of
it yet you're getting blasted with this
this heat that's coming off of it and
that's the just a pure IR lamp that's
hitting it you think that uh that
wouldn't have a you know we'll just I'll
raise the temperature a little bit but
what is kind of interesting is that the
leaf surface temperature it actually
affects like the the the biotic
structure of what's going on like heat
stresses and things even though the
there's micro boundary layers that
you're plant creates that's why we like
a lot of air flow and get them going and
it breaks those micro boundary layers
across because it it it's just got this
micro layer of insulation we'll call it
and so you want to knock that all off
and so just raising the temperature of
your room doesn't necessarily get the
plant leaf surface temperature all that
much higher whereas if you're bombarded
with that IR it gets it way higher I was
like oh so even the things that we kind
of consider not valuable in growing oh
it is affecting the metabolism of the
plant this is why I'm not getting that
that diesel expression I want that 2 3
diesel you know like uh lifestyle Rob
and I when we were hanging out in Vegas
you know we're just the right amount of
Boomer Millennial that uh we remember
that 2003 diesel baby where'd it go it
still exists you just have to grow it
wrong according to 2025 standards got it
yeah I feel like these days particularly
in the H grow Market that I feel like a
majority of people are going with LED
versus the hid you know hi that whether
bhps or MH or even CMH falls into the
hid category high intensity discharge
but yeah as far as what to look for when
purchasing a grow light I think first
thing right off about is coverage area
what area are you trying to cover if
you're looking for a 2ot x 4ot coverage
area well you can filter it down by
there and then you can kind of get into
the granular details of what's the power
output what does the light spectrum look
like and then you can even look at like
the dodes drivers people get really
really deep into what's the btu the heat
output so there's a lot of different
things that people can look at when
they're shopping for an LED grow light I
want to narrow it down to Spectrum here
you see a lot of grow light listings
that have full spectrum they advertise
full spectrum is it safe to say that
it's sufficient for growing medicinal
plants from seed to harvest if it's
labeled as full spectrum of course one
of the things that we'll like to talk
about I work with a company with jug
dealers DLI Dutch lighting Innovations
and one of their sayings is like you can
get any crappy Chinese light off of
Amazon and run it for a year and that
thing will be banging out pretty decent
Harvest you know but as you get to your
third run your fourth run your fifth run
all of a sudden there's degradation and
the light output starts dropping and the
power input doesn't drop so as your
efficiency starts LEDs uh cheaper LEDs
that you get they will be like I said
the the watt per output is higher than
than an HID light but but after year two
you go measure it it can drop down it
can get down to half so you're loose you
can lose three quarters efficiency if
you don't so one of the main things is
the old saying buy once cry once get one
of the trustworthy companies you know I
I personally I have two tents that I
grow in one has the DL Dutch lighting
Innovation LED in it the other's got a
hlg Horticultural Lighting Group LED in
it they're both high quality they both
have a you know I almost couldn't tell
the difference between the two as like
output although I use one for uh vegging
mainly and the the other for the flower
but it it's a big thing it's also to be
considered as a power of your house
that's another reason that led is so
important most HID lights are 240 you
know you have to you have to plug it
into a dryer Outlet or get a special
switcher box then goes into a ballast
that then goes into the light it's just
it's so much production whereas if you
can just get a a decent LED light plug
it into to the wall of your bedroom it's
it's kind of like the reason that
there's a Renaissance in game right now
is because all of a sudden you know
there is a time where carbon filters
didn't exist you know people would spray
gels and cologne and crap all over their
rooms because how do we get rid of this
smell and so between carbon filtration
then the upgrade in the tent technology
then the upgrade in the lights all of a
sudden literally everybody for under
$1,000 doll you can get a perfect setup
and grow amazing plants and then all of
that sunk cost it you you will pay
yourself back however you're getting
your your material you're putting in
your body however you're getting that
you're paying for it and uh it's gonna
it mounts up faster than you think if
you write down $20 here $50 here you're
going to hit that, pretty quick you'll
probably spend it whereas if you get
good equipment it's going to last for
years and you're going to 20x your
initial Sun cost so buy once cry once
get one of the reputable companies it's
really good I know Samsung just went out
of business
everything or not out of business but
out of the LED game and they're one of
the big breakthroughs that that that
gave us this full spectrum and on that
subject I was always uh a CRI guy so
this is color rendering index the sun
being 100 right so we're trying to match
our lights against the sun like what is
this and HPS is very low it's it's like
50 CRI at best you mentioned metal Halli
that's uh or not metal Halli but ceramic
metal Halli and that's what I end up
going with I was growing under a
double-ended 315 so I was running 630s
as a double double bulbed uh hoods and
the CRI jumped from like 50 up to 80 so
when these LED lights came out well God
they're like 95 oh my god well this must
be the answer to all my problems well it
is and it isn't if you're growing once
again that selection problem if you're
growing modern genetics and a lot of
people are growing the modern genetics
and there's no problem with that I love
people hate on the candy strains the
fruit strains I love you know I love
it's all a place in time like I I love
the the gassy stuff the fuy stuff the
rank nasty stuff but uh there's a place
for that sort of stuff and so these grow
lights are great they mimic the sun
almost exactly but not perfectly and
especially once again like uh humans are
a great uh analogy some people are grown
in the Saharan PLS you know and they're
bombarded with sun they have darker skin
some people were raised the the foggy
London Town and they have lightskins so
they can try to pull up more stuff it's
the same sort of thing you put me in the
Sahara Desert I'm not g to get much work
done you want me to work the Fe you know
I'm not going to get anything done yet
you put me in a a dark basement which is
the ambient line oh yeah I know I know
exactly what to do here that's your
plans if they were bred to be under HPS
that's where they want to be they'll do
fine they'll exist if you force me like
you put you kidnapped me and put me in a
mine I'll work I'll be sunburn as hell
and I'm going to I feel like hell but I
will get the work done same with your
plant it it it will do what you needed
to do but it's not going to do the thing
that it did back in the 90s 2000s but if
you're growing that modern stuff yeah no
problem it's the it's literally Picture
Perfect matchmate in heaven I uh I love
the LEDs for the the ease of use that's
the that's number one yeah it does make
them a lot easier to use so if full
spectrum is sufficient for growing from
seed to harvest how about about the
companies that have specialized light
spectrum that they advertise here's this
spe the spectrum that we have does it
actually translate to better results or
is it mostly marketing gimmicks well
company to company for sure some of them
it's just marketing gimmicks right the
thing that gets me about it is that the
thing that the trend that's going on
amongst like you know I am very we we
have a a check your privilege sort of
saying around my world I get it I hang
out with some of the best Growers with
the best genetics the best equipment all
the best knowledge and I get to watch
them from afar what's going on what are
they doing what are they talking about
and one of the things that's popped up
is is mixed Spectrum I'm seeing a ton of
people like in commercial facilities
they're doing these checkerboards where
they're putting an HPS light in between
four LEDs and then they'll just be
checkerboarded all over and so it's it's
fat this is where the science is way not
caught up to the the Bro Science the the
anecdotal data the anic data if you will
and uh you hear a lot of people I see a
lot of people and I'm watching people
who's putting food for their children on
the table based on these results and
they're swearing hey man I'm getting
better results with these mixed
spectrums confuses me because if we have
a full spectrum LED light right like
it's covering all the bases that the HPS
is right well maybe not necessarily it
there there's little gaps in the spect
if you look to a spectrograph it's not
just like a flat sine wave you know it's
not just like here it is it's it's like
a it's a squirly durly sort of thing and
different compounds are diff are
generated by different things and so
like as I mention with the infrared
there I would have thought as I educated
myself there was nothing to do with ir
in there but turns out there is so all
of a sudden I'm like all right well I
don't have all the science and there is
not science the only science that's
coming out is done by the lighting
companies
themselves I know you take that with a
grain of salt but when you have all the
homies who feed themselves and their
children based on these numbers and
they're saying that these mixing of
spectrums is having a result not just on
quantity but also on quality and I think
as we move forward that's what we're all
really trying to hit now like the the
days of yield being number one I think
those are fairly over and I think
quality is King these days I totally
agree with you on that one it seems
except for the the commercial facilities
we do have quite a few people that are
working in commercial facilities and
they still have a hammer coming down on
them trying to get more yield you know
from the uppers for the most part
quality uh but there are still some
folks that that have to stra for yield
because uh their business relies on it I
guess you can say I want to get a little
bit deeper into far red light which is
something that you had mentioned a
little bit here can you talk to us about
a far red light specifically between 700
and 750 NM what does it do to the plant
and then also is it worth supplementing
far red light or do most grow lights
have enough far red that it's not worth
supplementing well it's uh this is
something that uh this is like the
something i' I've been hearing about for
10 years but once again still is ever
evolving it's it's uh it's funny we had
we recorded episode of The Jug dealers
podcast the other day and uh I I happen
to know once again I I've been in the
world I've watched certain people use
far red to effective results for the
most part and then I'm talking with
these guy here the jiren and Gabe two my
most like respected grow brains in all
the thing and they both look me in the
eye and they're like you're wrong and I
go bro well I was like I thought they
were G be yeah of course the flower
initiation that stuff works and they're
like no doesn't do anything doesn't
exist in nature I'm like so this
controver you know this goes deep like
this is one of the those controversial
things there's the there's the and
there's the UV we'll get to I find that
to be not since organic versus synthetic
have we had as much debate in the
growing community and so as far as the
far red some people can be confused
right off the bat so we should probably
clarify that I mentioned the red earlier
as as the IR the infrared and so when uh
as grow mentioned the par when you see a
par chart it's what does a plant see
think of it like the visual spectrum of
a human right we don't see X-rays and
gamma Rays we don't see microwaves and
radio waves but we see visible light
same sort of thing with the plant it's
got a visual spectrum that it can see
but just the same way as x-rays Shores
hell affect us if we're bombarded with
them same thing things outside of the
par range also affect the plant and so
uh infrared is outside of that par range
way outside of it and so it it's like I
said that's why it's interesting it's
like oh it's outside of par yet it still
does affect the metabolism of the plant
there's also that's infrared now we're
discussing far red so that is slightly
on the end it's just dipping over the
side of the par range a little bit in a
little bit out and it does quite a bit
of sort of stuff uh a lot of negative
stuff as well as positive one of the
main things that uh I think as I can
speak because you know there's there's
not a ton of science science out there
as as far as this stuff once again it's
a lot of the companies and I trust a lot
of the companies Shane from migro I
trust this guy you know I there
characters out there Jer from the Dutch
lighting Innovations I trust him so when
these guys say things I listen and so we
can start with uh the negative sort of
effects that the far red will have so
far red is a just like if you can think
like the reason that x-rays are so
powerful is they're a really small wave
they're very intense it takes a lot of
energy like if I want to make something
like jiggle fast I got to put a lot of
energy with it and so versus a radio
wave right it's this giant huge thing it
can wrap over your house and still get a
signal on the next one whereas if I shot
you know an x-ray burst at your house
it's going to hit the wall it can't go
over it's too small of a wavelength and
so you can think of the the uh the far
red kind of like that it's a bigger
thing so it can get past your canopy it
can get past your leaves it can get down
lower so if you have a forest and you
got a bunch of trees that are shading
out a plant a little plant that's trying
to grow down there our little favorite
High valued plants that we like to grow
if we put that underneath a giant forest
canopy right it's not going to get any
of that that delicious par that we're
talking about but what it is going to
get is some of that far red because it
can get through the canopy and it still
hit it and what that tells the plant is
stretch baby stretch you're not getting
any of the yummy light that we need to
grow we're getting all that red light
and that means that there's light above
us but we ain't getting it so we got to
grow up there so one of the things that
I've seen a lot is people that will uh
use uh their far red lights all cycle is
that they're getting a lot of stress now
some people like the stretch this is a
interesting thing of uh at the the 58
jug dealers guys we like to say it's
it's like think of uh like a bloom
booster right is like an additive right
it's not it's not required it's just
it's GNA get you farther I think of like
the these UV the the the far red things
like that that these are the the
additives that we're adding and some
genetics need more cowc that's where it
came from some need less some need so
same thing some genetics some cultivars
as we're now calling them they uh or
should probably should have always been
calling them strains are for mushrooms
and and flu cultivars are for plants
just to clear up any we still call it
strains we can still say it no one's
don't don't be a Snicker puss don't
don't talk down to someone because they
say strain we get it cultivar you know
but some of these cultivars they uh they
need more than others and so if you got
like these little tiny squat plants that
you want to grow up maybe you you have
techniques for increasing that that
intern noal spacing one of the things
the reasons we don't like stretching is
because it takes no to node of those H
those flower sites it increases it and
then you get these giant topheavy things
that want to bend and break and you're
having to give them more silica so that
way they have a little bit more
elasticity to them and everything just
gets changed so if you're one of these
like highlevel thinking Growers like my
buddy from bre genetics a JLS monster
he's one of one of the best breeders in
Colorado and he was like I like I run my
far red midcycle I I like a little
stretch like he'll grow these this
Colonel chem that I love I I got some of
it sitting over here and man amazing
he's like it's too squat the nose are
two together I I sometimes I get Bud
mold okay I would have never thought
like okay maybe this guy wants dress cuz
he he's getting betrus at the end of his
Harvest he's like this loosens up some
of those tight flower sights and okay
I'm learning holy crap here's another
thing I would have been like that's bad
I could say that's bad don't stretching
as bad is it not if that's exactly what
you want to keep your plants that keep
you happy and healthy happy and healthy
so uh on the positive side of it is the
flower initiation this one my friends
have legit been doing forever you can
think of it just like I talked about
with how red are these big giant things
well before our eyes can actually see
the sunrise we're actually starting to
get bombarded that's why it starts to
heat up a little bit before the sun even
comes up we're getting hit with that IR
first it's the biggest it's coming down
it's cooking up our atmosphere and then
that far red is coming in and so even
though the sun hasn't crested the
horizon yet it's still throwing some of
that far red that our eyes can't
necessarily even see but the plants can
and that tells them to wake up same
conversely when the Sun starts to go
down it crosses the Horizon and then all
that visible light is blocked by the
horizon yet some of that red is still so
big just like the x-rays hitting your
house versus the radio hitting your
house you can hit the radio in a big
city even though it's blocked it it your
plant sees ah there's that outgoing red
time to go to sleep so people called
this the flower initiator you'll run it
for 15 minutes before your lights turn
on and 15 minutes after your lights turn
on this tells that them that it is fully
time to wake up and fully time to go to
bed and they will go it takes your
plants you know an hour to so I I once
again cultiv our specific some some
plants go to sleep very very fast and
some other take forever just like people
it's almost like life is like life you
know they're so much like us it's it's
almost spooky and so it will tell them
wake up go to bed and they go faster and
then so they're they're able to produce
sugars and oxin at night and interchange
with the roots the the roots and the the
chots as we call them they both are
doing different roles one's creating
oxygen people always think that the
plants well they create CO2 well did you
know the roots create oxygen that's why
terrariums can exist blew my mind when I
started Le you can put a plant in a
sealed bottle and it will live because
its roots are producing oxygen and its
uh flowers are producing CO2 and it can
circulate through the two blew my mind
and so if you start shortening those
days or not shortening your days but
getting them to go to sleep faster
you're actually day after day in a you
know a 60 to 80 Day flower cycle you're
actually pulling several days off some
people are saying I'm pulling a week off
of my plants this is the point I try to
make with jiren and Gabe on The Jug
dealer show where they're like no it
doesn't do anything and I was like I
think we're talking quality I don't
think it does anything to increase
quality you're not going to get more oil
and those voc's from this but you're
taking time off of your schedule so it
it it's more I guess this could be
lumped into the yield category because
if you can jam another harvest in your
garden each year even if you're losing a
little bit of weight run to run you're
gaining that weight back plus by jamming
a whole extra harvest in there I think
that's something we all can get down
with got it yeah so they're definitely
pros and cons and sounds like that con
that you mention is really subjective
right actually I had uh somebody on the
podcast pretty recently Dave Baker shout
out to him he was on there talking about
autof flowers and one thing that was
pretty interesting is he actually uses
the far red for autof flowers cuz he
wants that stretch he wants that veg
growth uh to happen you know he wants
the biggest plant as he possibly get in
an Autoflower obviously we all know that
it's limited on his time frame for veg
it automatically flips to flower right
so that veg time frame is super super
important if there's any stunting growth
you could have a significantly smaller
plant so he utilizes far red supplements
far red in order to get a bigger stretch
on his Auto flowers before they actually
flower I thought that was interesting
that is interesting and this is what
learning looks like people go people ask
questions like how do you know that and
I go cuz someone smart told me it once
and I listened autof flowers that's fasc
because exactly like I talked about like
getting Bud rot and stuff that's usually
an outside uh outdoor sort of thing you
know but a lot of people do get it
indoors and I could totally see you get
that that giant Christmas tree you can't
really top an Autoflower the way we
would top a normal photo periodic plant
plant so you get this giant Christmas
tree Cola going up I could see totally
increasing that intern Noles length
gives you more room for those buds to
grow tells them there's more space for
them this makes sense to me absolutely
so would you say it's worth adding in
like for people actually go out and buy
the lights to supplement or is it just
kind of like an a plant additive where
you can get it but it's kind of like an
optional thing and it'll take you a
little bit further but it might not be
worth it for some so you can type into
Google Google image search at some point
after this podcast everyone listening
just type uh law of the minimums chart
or graphic the law of the minimums right
so if you take a barrel and it's all got
level sides right you can fill the water
up to that level of the barrel now you
take one plank of that barrel and you
hammer it down five inches right well
the height of what that Barrel can
contain is now its lowest point right
that's just what it is the water's going
to flow out that hole until it reaches
to that equilibrium point of that that
lowest Plank and that's your new water
level you pull that plank up now you can
fill it all the way back up and it's
it's a great chart I think it's Lee
Big's law of the minimum I can never
remember exactly the the Fella's name I
I I learned from college educated people
yet was not college educated so I have a
hard time retaining some of the it's
it's a knowledge fire hose out there
these days grow it's hard to maintain
all this stuff you know so yeah look up
law of the minimums and uh I would say
for
sure we we'll say this even about
something as pedantic as CO2 don't worry
about it until everything else is dialed
in if you're not hitting your DLI your
preferred ppfd you're not even going to
be able to uh like you're going to get
that's another thing about giving it
more light it's it's this weird cause
and effect Loop right don't worry about
having CO2 if you don't have enough
light and then don't worry about putting
more light in if you don't have CO2 it's
like a weird all all apes are monkeys or
all monkeys are Apes but not all apes
are monkeys sort of thing it like
depending on what you're doing is so I
would say for sure just a short answer
to the question is yeah it should be one
of the last things you're worrying about
but if you have your room dialed in and
you're like I don't know how I could
possibly make it any better yes now
we're talking you're the person that
should be kind of thinking about that
but if you're a new grower you're buying
your first tent you're like should I buy
some Far red no
no your your light will contain enough
to be perfectly adequate I think that's
a good way to put it now how about
ultraviolet light UV light 100 to 400
nanm what does that do to the plant and
is that worth supplementing or do most
cites have UV in the spectrum that
supplementation isn't really necessary
so here we go this is the one that uh
puts fear in my chest because all of a
sudden girl I'm a man of science right I
I study Quantum Mechanics for fun I love
the particle Zoo you want to talk about
how time dilation works with muons life
cycle being shorter than they can get
from the Earth to the sun yet they crash
in with the Earth every single
millisecond forever how is that possible
I'll talk that for you forever right I
am a man I love science I love love love
it questioning science is part of
science folks I know we live in the most
divisive times ever and when you say
things like ah you can't believe the
science you get put in a category right
of like you're you're a political person
you're over here you you voted for this
person all sorts of crap gets brought up
so I with a big asterisk go into this
next subject is that once again there's
not many people doing science on this
and the people that are doing the
science are scientists they're not like
consumers the way we are there they're
not looking at it from the perspective
that we're looking at it right so just
what this is we we totally planted a a
fertile bed of seeds for everyone's
knowledge base that now we can catch up
to this because expression right
different plants different cultivars
different genetic profiles recessive all
these different things are in affected
by different things so now I'm a
scientist I have to do things one at a
time I can't test multiple varials
simultaneously I have to get a baseline
agree with my peer group that this is
the Baseline and then when I want to
change something I change one variable
and then I I do I get more results then
I'll go back I'll change something else
and you start doing these onetoone tests
over and over and over and over again
thousands of times and then a full data
set that's full and useful starts to
emerge well we only have a handful of
guys you know and one of the ones that
gets thrown in my person face every
single day of talking about this would
be our esteemed member of this community
Bruce Bugsby I love Bruce Bugsby very
very much this guy is a genius but the
man is a scientist so when he talks
about things like so I I'll get i'll I'm
burying the lead here a guy like Bruce
Bugsby says UV does not affect plants
right we've done the studies it's it's
not creating more oils it's not creating
more cannaboids it's not creating more
flavor molecules it's just not well I
happen to live in Denver I work for the
Dutch lighting Innovations I work with
these guys very closely they're they're
part of my friends friends and they sell
a purpose made UV light it's a it's a
hid uh it's not HPS necessarily it's
it's inspired by it but it's a UV just
light it it's a it's a burning ball of
gas that's just like the sun putting off
all that UV that's what's growing here
it's one of the only full spectrum UV
lights there there's UVA there's UVB and
there's UVC you can think of a is just
ambient a Scotty reel on the dude grow
like to say b stands for burn and C
stands for cancer you know it's gonna it
hurts you UVC is not good so in our
Earth's atmosphere thankfully since UVC
is so dangerous for us it filters out
almost all of the UVC but we still get a
lot of the UVB and a lot of the UVA and
so they come out with a light that
directly mimics that it's exp it's you
know it costs money and I'm watching
people all over put it in and keep it
and I'm saying what's going on so my
friend turpan Kyle he's one of the best
Growers I've ever met I know this guy
for 10 years he is literally the
smartest man as far as like Hands-On
plants he loves the science he loves the
data he loves talk and grow and he goes
I'm going to try it uh you know and he's
a he a just the way that a scientist
would only do one very at the time he
had his his room dialed in what else can
I do he's looking for tpine production
he calls his company tacana and uh it's
all about those turps and so he's like
let me try it and he just he's
instantaneously he's like dude after
three runs I mean I'm getting this is
once again anecdotal he's like I'm
getting like eight to 10% more tpin as
you do he'll do uh BHO runs of of the H
of the oils and it fractionates and so
you'll get like a crystallin layer
you'll get like a and it's it's
different lay and at the very very tippy
top is just pure Tarin and so you can
scoop those off you can weigh them you
can actually do data and he's like man
I'm getting 10% more TPS off of this
stuff one of the other things that UV uh
will do once again so that's why I
preface with that the there's
controversy here you got groups of
people in the academic Community saying
that it does nothing you got groups of
people in the
Hands-On practitioners and they're
saying it does so just the that's why I
press I'm a man of science but in the
aspect of UV I'm choosing because the
science isn't I believe the science
isn't in yet the data that we have is
pointing at a suggestion but I don't
take that at face value yet maybe in
2030 if that's still if there's all
these tests are going and all there's
more and more and more bug bees of the
world all confirming this I go okay
maybe my friends are full of crap and
they got that 10% not full of crap but
they did get that increase maybe there's
some other variable that they weren't
aware of but as it stands now I believe
that it does and uh but one consequences
if you are a yield person it reduces
biomass but it
increases the we think of the the the
Trikes and everything all all that is
all the oils that's the sunscreen it
puts it on there as a protective layer
it doesn't want things landing on it it
doesn't want bombarded by the all that
UV so we like positive stressors in our
world you know I'm a big uh some people
do the low stress training I'm a high
stress trainer boy I I bust I'm breaking
necks in there I love I love it you know
just like you know you'd see like old
you know [__] John Claude vanam you
know movies and they're they're punching
gravel you know like like ah and they're
they're creating micr fractures in their
hands and when those micr fractures fill
in with all the calcium and things that
we take you're stronger and beefier and
you got these giant thing well we've all
seen if you break a plant it gets this
giant knuckle on it right well my buddy
Jay Maestro he goes well to hell with
knuckles I want my whole plant to be a
knuckle so I break I'm popping
everything my plants just look dead
people I grow with are just like what
have you done you've killed it you
monster 24 hours later it's right back
to praying you know it's all it's all
good we're trying to create positive
stressors and uvi I believe is one of
the most positive stressors you can get
now you can't work under this it is bad
for you so in these commercial
facilities that do have these they run
them about three hours a day and people
can't be under them they are quite
dangerous uh don't play games with UV uh
you can get the light here's here's
another thing about UV is that you
talked about Shady marketing practices
here's where the shadiest marketing
practices come out is the different
types of UV best UV out through glass
from a bulb you know the these these
high pressure bulbs the UV the Dutch
sliding UV bulbs that's the best hands
down it's the only only product that's
like that on the market after that you
get the bars you have these bars the
bars work the bars are great you can get
good UV a out of it you can get a little
bit of UVB no C obviously and we don't
want too much C anyway so I I also like
the bars the once again migro no no
relation to them just like the guys they
educate the world they give it out for
free and say if you like what we give
you come try our products well I have
friends that have tried it and had good
results so far then we get to the LEDs
that is a noggo LEDs cannot maintain UV
so think about if you put a red chair
out in the sun bright red chair right
big you got this lawn chair you it's all
right it's cherry red it's gorgeous now
you put it out there for a couple
Summers you go out there it's like light
pink after a couple years why is that
because all that UV light is breaking it
down you know it it it attacks Plastics
and it just degrades them quite quickly
well your LEDs are essentially made of
these different plastic uh uh molecule
yeah polymers and such and they uh they
break down so literally as you're
running UV through these things they are
degrading themselves so just like I
talked about spectral degradation of
Cheaper LEDs there is no LED on Earth
it's literally breaking itself from the
inside so maybe you'll get a couple
weeks of great production out of some of
these diode based UV systems but they're
going to they're going to break
themselves pretty quickly and now you're
just running heat in your garden to a
light that is producing near nothing so
that I would say go with the the full
the Full Spectrum Glass then the bars
avoid the LEDs good to know now you
mentioned DLI quite a few times here in
this podcast I want to get deeper into
it I have a lot of beginners on this
podcast some might not even know what
DLI is can you explain what is DLI and
what do you aim for so I had kept
referencing DLI it's a clever company
name Dutch lighting Innovations that's
not what we're referencing here
is they kind of took that as like their
cute name of like ah D what it actually
means as far as like botanic you know
Botanical means is uh is Daily Light
integral how much light can a plant
absorb in a day think of your plant as a
bucket and phot photons like raindrops
you know how much can it actually hold
and once a bucket's full it's full and
so the the DLI of your plan is how much
of those raindrops of energy can it hold
per day how much does it need to be
called a day here's one of the things
that really got me like one of those
knowledge gaps that's like oh I got to
do some homework this is fascinating
I've been growing 10 years before I
learned we call it a photo period right
we should really call it is like an
anti-photo period or lack of photo
period here's the thing that actually
dictates your photo cycle is the
nighttime this blew my mind Scotty and I
at dude grow you know we'll we'll enjoy
our favorite uh compounds late at night
and we'll have discussions all about
this it's all we ever talk about and we
started thinking about this insane
concept right we play God with our
plants right we we give them we are we
let there be light we say and so there
is light that is you know we we have
that level of control they don't know
what a 24-hour day is right so think
about if you had a a a cultivar
especially that was not hungry for light
and you hit its DLI super early what
necessarily because you're the the the
photo period is the 12 hours of dark
that's what creates a a flower cycle and
so we can't interrupt that we don't want
to interrupt that all that much it'll
create a lot of stressors in the plants
maybe that's what you're looking for
some people I know like our friends in
Southern Colorado down there will uh
they recommend certain like you know do
a 168 sort of thing and that creates
controversy works for them they they
they like that positive stressors you
know maybe they're trying to stress
their plant in in a manner there but
just to keep it we want our genetic
stable we don't want them selfing doing
any sort of weirdness throwing nanners
or anything so we want to make sure we
hold that 12 hours of Darkness but
there's nothing special about that 12
hours of light all we need is to hit our
DLI hypothetically speaking Mr Grow what
if we had a plant that had a low DLI
we've got a high intensity light or LED
that that's really kicking those photons
down and we hit our DLI in eight
hours couldn't we theoretically just cut
cut cut this show give him the 12 hours
and now we've got a 20h hour day a 20
hour day and what's that gonna do for he
get if we're talking about flower
initiators sneaking in an extra Harvest
could you sneak in another Harvest could
you could be doing six or seven runs a
year all of a sudden my head starts
going crazy I start looking into it
there's these like gas slamp techniques
where they like will do things like give
veg plants an hour like mid cycle all
this crazy stuff I I recommend going
through the old forums so much of it is
a Bro Science but so much of it still
works you know some one of the things
that blows my mind about science is how
much the old boys were right holy crap
they were you were right I don't know
how you knew that but you actually right
about it so yeah there's a lot of old
test so here we are thinking like I
thought Scotty was like no there's been
these different light schedule sort
before I never heard of it a 20-hour day
that's unheard of a nine a nay week what
what are we doing so all of a sudden it
became like the uh the the main thing I
was thinking about was like man is there
any place that documents DLI of
cultivars like see how like bait we're
so infantile in our knowledge of these
things like these like there is so much
room to grow no pun intended as Growers
like holy crap like is there any anyone
leave it in leave a comment there's a
great time right in this video right
below you have any experience with this
because this is I'm going to check back
the comments and I like Andrew huberman
calls it anec data so anecdotal stories
from your smart friends it's not just
anecdotal it's anic data man that counts
you telling me things work you're a
smart guy and I believe you and you have
a little bit of your own data to prove
it I believe it so leave a comment I
want to know I'm going to read them yeah
I think DLI is one of those things that
isn't talked about as much as it should
be in my opinion right A lot of people
just go after the power what how much
power and ppfd are you giving your
plants right but having the light cycle
knowing how much how long your lights
are on and how much par you're giving
running those numbers to a DLI
calculator which you can find online
just by doing a Google Search and then
figure out how much DLI your plants are
actually getting and then is that too
much or is it not enough and you know
for medicinal plants around 40 I think
is safe I've heard upwards of 60 DLI
what do you typically do you have a
specific number that you kind of aim for
for DLI or or what these are the so I uh
unfortunately had a a a little uh
relationship ending over covid you know
they being locked down together for a
couple years we uh got on each other's
nerves a little bit I had my mom pass
away and all sorts of drama went on in
that couple years and so I went from
growing in amazing Grow rooms my whole
I'd never grown in a tent my whole life
I've been growing 10 years never GNA I
always had to grow rooms giant two-car
garages fully sealed you know nothing
gets in nothing gets out it was the
Glory Days and so I just started growing
intense this last year and then I just
moved to my new apartment so here in the
last like two years while while I've
been increasing all of my grow knowledge
my anic data has not been there I
haven't had my friends or my hands in
the dirt doing so I get all the
different uh reports from my friends
like you telling me like okay these are
the numbers but the way my brain works
is like since I don't you know I'm not
in there with with you know the photon
app or all these different things that
come out checking out what the ppfd and
everything is uh I don't have my
personal personal recommendations so I
don't I don't have numbers for you I
like like I said I'm a man of science I
do not ever want to come on a big
platform like this and spew anything
that's out of pocket so I will defend UV
I won't give you a DLI based on my
personal experience because I don't know
and it's tough uh you can burn up your
plants a little bit you know you you can
have a little bit of that you got to
make sure that's where the CO2 comes in
if you are going to increase that DLI
and especially that ppfd and I believe
ppfd is photosynthetic Photon flux
density I always say you go from Stoner
to quantum mechanics in four moves in
this game it's ridiculous you go well
you do it like this why well because uh
radiation of light goes like this why oh
well because as different uh photons go
why because quantum mechanics I don't
know that's so funny yeah I appreciate
your honesty there you know not
everybody knows everything man this hour
has flown by we are coming up towards
the end here and we just scratch the
surface when it comes to lighting there
is so much more that can be come with
this conversation maybe we can do a part
two in the future where we can go even
further on this but we're going to wrap
things up here can you tell listen to
how they can find you and what you have
upcoming in the future well the number
one thing I'd say is uh my Instagram I
uh I'm Josh Gro j o h g r m b o and
grambo was his name though it's like
Rambo but I'm a G you know one of those
sort of things and so yeah I'm a standup
comedian I got taken off of the road to
uh I'm I'm an Entertainer not just
standup I'm a musician I have a I
actually have a uh a themed band coming
soon possession with intent it's like a
metal B I'm talking with I can THC he's
a rapper of trying to get him to uh come
on Matt let's start a band bro you know
so like I got a lot of dogs in the fire
all of the YouTube stuff you know it it
takes care of itself the community I
don't have to tell you our community
that we share in this growing Community
it is hands down the best Comm I've
worked in many different fields doing
production as I cut my teeth on my way
to find this I worked for a sleep
education company it just taught you how
to sleep better and feel better and we
get flamed every day by haters and
nonsense and crazy spammers and all
sorts of weirdness I can't believe how
good this community of growing is and so
you guys I mean you'll see in the
comments people are forc this video has
got 400 people watching it and only 50
likes get in there and like it it's like
whoa chat's like hurt you know hurting
everyone to like and share and
everything that's awesome but uh so yeah
the the community that takes care of
itself but if you want to help me go
follow me on Instagram helps me get uh
uh more gigs as far as comedy helps my
reach if you own a bar a Tavern you want
me to come you want me to come as a grbo
the comedian Gro the grower I will show
up in force with my funny friends my
knowledgeable friends we'll do your
events the uh all the jug dealers guys
we're we're working we're going to
spannabis this year so here in the next
few weeks we're gonna be heading over to
Spain for spannabis hanging out with
Adam Dunn and jiren and all the guys
over there so I'll be super stoked for
that so if you're interested uh about
all this knowledge and weirdness go
follow me over there on Instagram Josh
Gro that's the main thing that supports
me other than that just keep growing the
Dank baby awesome yeah this community
totally is just so incredible I've was
in the other communities before and this
is like no other the friendliness is
unmatched I'll definitely have a link to
gano's Instagram down in the YouTube
description section below so you can
easily get to it and give him a follow
also want to give a shout out to the
folks supporting on patreon
patreon.com your support is greatly
appreciated the folks that are being
scrolled on the screen right now are in
the producer tier special thanks to you
well grbo thanks so much for coming on
to the podcast today this has been
awesome just that lighting is one of
those things where I really enjoy
talking about and listening to the new
information that's out here and thank
you for your time and I hope you enjoy
the rest of your day love it so much man
that was my goal and I feel achieved so
grow on all right everyone peace out
catch you in the next episode