welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody if you that
don't know me my name is Chris aka Mr
growt and you're tuned in to the Garden
Talk podcast this episode number 119 in
this episode I interview Steven raiser
but many of you know him as potent ponic
he has been on the podcast once before
episode 64 we talked all about
aquaponics while I got him back on the
podcast this time he talks about growing
genetics the best way possible in your
climate Steven has grown in several
States across the US and several
countries around the world so he has a
lot of experience growing in different
climates and he reveals a lot of great
information that relates to this topic
if you want to see highlights of these
Garden Talk podcast episodes search
Garden talk clips on YouTube that
channel is dedicated to short bite-sized
clips of these episodes I also have a
gardening Channel where I have over 13
videos showing the plants that are in my
garden I'll have that channel Linked In
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
all-in-one pH pen which measures pH EC
TDS and temperature the sensor probe is
replaceable and it comes with sword
solution and calibration Solutions click
the link in the description section
below so you can learn more about their
all-in-one pH pen and the discount code
Mr Grow 15 works on both Amazon and
their website AC infinity.com happy
Hydro they have some of the best
complete beginner grow kits on the
market today their kits include a grow
tent grow light ventilation system grow
pots soil nutrients and more they have
36 different kits in their beginner
category and also have advanced kits
cheap kits and kits that include an auto
watering system go to happy hydro.com
Link in the description and use the
discount code Mr grow during checkout to
save on your order stash blend I've been
using stash blend for over a year now
and it's awesome one of the things that
I really like is that it saves me money
it's a whole bunch of different inputs
in one so I no longer have to go out
there and buy a silica bottle then a
separate seawe bottle beneficial
bacteria then a separate one for microle
fungi all of that plus more is in this
one blend go to stash blend.com to learn
learn more about it and I also have a
link down in the YouTube description
section below and we're back welcome to
the Garden Talk podcast today I am
joined with Steven raisner how you doing
today good thanks for having me back
thanks for coming back we did one
episode in the past so some of you might
remember that one he goes by potent
ponics and last episode we talked all
about aquaponics which isn't a very
popular growing method but you can
definitely grow some really good plants
that way but this time we're going to
switch things around really going to
talk a lot about genetic diversity
and growing genetics the best way
possible for your climate you know
there's so many differences that can
happen you have so much experience
growing around the world really you've
been grown in different countries so I
think it's going to be a really good
conversation with you to kind of reveal
some information tips tricks and so on
and so forth but before we get too deep
into the episode can you introduce
yourself for the audience members who
don't know you sure my name is Steve um
I have a company called potent ponics I
also have a podcast called growing with
fishes um we've been around now for
eight years um so we've been making a
lot of awesome content uh similar to
yourself with a lot of you know similar
similar type uh structures but um my
main U work is uh doing consulting for
uh all different types of living soil
and aquaponic systems and farms uh all
around the world with a variety of crops
the majority of it being medicinal uh
plants are essential oil producing
plants and then the rest of it being
food production crops mainly organic
certified for the for the aquaponics um
there isn't a lot of people that can
come in and set up those types of
facilities or troubleshoot them when
they run into auditing problems um so we
do a lot of internal audits uh and um
mainly lately the last 5 years or so
going to different countries and setting
up large facilities um specking out the
equipment specking out the systems the
pumps the filtration you know P you know
setting up the different Sops and all
the different protocols and coming with
different solutions especially in in
Oddball places I'm sure we'll get into
some of them in a little B uh uh you
know learning different things in
different cultures and you know it seems
like every part of the world has like a
different piece of the puzzle really
figured out like to the unth degree and
uh it's always fun to um learn from
these different indigenous cultures uh
and kind of combine all that knowledge
into a a working system got it so like
what countries have you grown in or
areas have you grown in maybe I know a
might be quite a long list here maybe
just spitball off a handful of them sure
yeah so I've grown in Canada all across
the US Puerto Rico Jamaica um Zimbabwe
South Africa Thailand um Colombia um and
I'm sure I'm forgetting so oh St Vincent
and I've been to grows in swasiland or
east stini now uh as well
as sure I'm forgetting somewhere but uh
quite oh la I've seen some grows and La
as well Matt all over the place that
that's wild all right so let's first get
into genetic diversity break it down for
us what is meant by genetic diversity
sure so genetic diversity is kind of
what is the different phenotypic
expressions of the different plants in a
given region um so but also in mutations
as well you have things like freak Show
um uh ABC um and and uh crows foot is a
bunch of other ones as well that can be
genetic variation but U mainly what
we're going to talk about today is kind
of the differences between the different
land races uh and the different stuff
that was in you know different regions
um Jamaica for instance had very few it
was almost no land race left by the time
I was there in 2016 most of it had been
crossbred with Western you know poly
hybrid stuff they're really think maybe
one time did I see anything that was
even you know pretty uh natural looking
I guess for lack of a better term it
really surprised me because Jamaica was
always kind of known as being like this
really wild place but there's a lot of
cool genetics there but you know it's
almost all contaminated with Western
stuff now whereas when I was in Africa
especially like in remote parts of
Zimbabwe none of that stuff has seen any
kind of um you know uh uh outside
genetics because of the wars and the
isolation and the sanctions and all the
other stuff there isn't a big export
culture there right so they're not
bringing in different genetics in order
to to crossbreed for for export so
they're just growing what they like and
what's what's been growing there so um
it's always kind of interesting the
different motivations of the different
places um if you think about it this way
too why is it that the biggest places in
the world for the different genetic
diversities that are kind of known for
being these epicenters are Jamaica which
was a huge trade Hub in the Caribbean um
you know Durban which is a huge trade
Hub in in southern Africa especially the
the anywhere really where you had the
the um what was the name of it the East
Indies Trading Company or West Indies
Trading Company or whatever it was back
in the day um anywhere you know in the
17 1800s where you had a lot of this
heavy trade that's where you have a lot
of the kind of meccas for these genetics
Morocco being another one that was a big
trade Hub you know all these different
places that we kind of think of as being
like the best places to go and Source
out genetics most of them were huge
trade hubs and back in the day you know
from you know 1,00 through you know the
1800s you would keep you know hemp on
your your boat um as part of your sale
production in case you have a ship wreck
you know you can grow your own ropes and
sails and things like that um and uh uh
you know other plants as well uh
medically that they would grow to keep
as medicine on the pl on the boat and
that's why you have a lot of these
different really cool land races in the
specific regions that you have is
because it was part of your boat
standard boat repair kit for the better
part of a thousand years so if you did
any kind of long sea travel you brought
pine trees and you which is why you have
pine trees everywhere and also why they
call everything that you can make into a
mast a pine tree there's lots of non-
pine trees that are called pine trees as
a common name that's another reason for
it um you know there's all these
different stuff but but that's the
reason why you have that you know
epicenters of of genetics for medicinal
plants that we all enjoy is because of
that you know boat repair kit type stuff
and then people kind of growing large
volumes of that and kind of finding you
know through pheno hunting those those
better cultivars in those regions that's
interesting and yeah the medicinal
plants have been transferred all around
the world at this point really and some
genetics they might grow really well in
one area but they don't grow well at all
they actually can grow bad in other
areas why is that well a great example
of this would be you know Leaf width
right so in I just came back from living
in Thailand for almost a year uh the
really narrow Leaf varieties of plants
grow much much better uh in Thailand or
anywhere in the tropics um freak Show
would be another one that does extremely
well because the reduce reduced Leaf
surface uh in the hot sun they don't get
heated up as much uh and they don't have
to sweat as much and drink as much water
not sweat but you know respirate through
this
um they're not losing as much water per
day because they have a reduced surface
area so they can grow much easier and
have a lot less heat stress whereas if
you take a broad leaf like a a plant
that came from a much more Northern
climate um you're going to have you know
instant Leaf burn you're going to get
sunburn those plants are going to have
to work a lot harder to bring up more
water because they're losing more water
per day through the leaf structure uh
and it really can U make a big
difference but that's the you know I
guess the biggest reason why you would
choose one or the other or kind of the
biggest things to look for when you're
growing in the tropics versus growing in
Northern climates Northern climates
doesn't matter if it's narrow leaf or
Broad Leaf anywhere near as much if
you're going in the tropics you know if
I take a a you know Broad Leaf
um uh you know variety it's just not
going to do well and we even saw saw
that um in a lot of the genetics we were
testing there you know uh anything that
was super super broadleaf a lot of
blueberry and things like that just
fried in the sun um because it just
couldn't handle it so definitely and the
freak Show really is one of the best
ones if you're going to grow in full sun
in a really really brutally hot climate
it really really is one of the best
Durban would be another one that grows
extremely well does not care if it's 105
out we'll do just fine you know most
cases okay now can these genetics adapt
to different climates for example could
you take a broad leaf from the northern
climate bring it down to the tropics and
then have it grow naturally let's say
let's say it's out in the wild outside
and over 20 years let's say 20 years
later will that genetic adapt or will
you just see poor growth for that 20e
period Well I think you definitely could
have you know some level of adaptation
if you could get them to finish off you
know in a lot of cases the plants don't
make it all the way to harvest because
of this the Heat and the stress and all
the rest or you know past pressure
that's another one too like for instance
when I was in Thailand you know if
you're in the marier areas or the rice
fields like where I was growing
initially um those are all almost lemine
dominant completely um terms of of chemo
profile um and that lemoning really does
help get rid of those bugs that kind of
like that environment more whereas in
the mountains you get more of the
chocolates and the mangoes some of the
other you know funky Sandalwood um type
type uh turpine profiles and that really
H is more adapted to like the white fly
and the other different pests that are
up there that's the plants that are
surviving and not getting eaten by the
bug so that that plays a huge role in
that turpine expression as well as well
as what's going to survive and not
survive you know um you know that's
that's the other component to it aside
from just the climate is that you know
if it doesn't if it has a c now another
one too I was at a couple two different
facilities and I've seen thrips
specifically feeding on pineapple um
flavored varieties eating all of the um
pests off of the plants so they eat just
the pests off which is really weird it's
good if you don't want pollination I
guess but uh uh they would just crawl up
to the top eat all the pests and then go
back off the planet it was the weirdest
thing but I've seen that on two separate
occasions specifically with pineapple
flavored varieties so sometimes you even
just get a pest that that really cues in
on one or two cultivars and you just
can't grow those particular cultivars
because the pests are they like magnets
to them so you know and other times too
hey if those couple of plants are going
to take all my bugs off of the rest of
the plants that's fine I'll sacrifice
those and and we'll just you know
sacrifice those to the Lord of light at
the end of the season uh like we do our
ticks that we find on ourselves yeah
sacrificial plants this can be uh handy
I know some people grow plants
specifically for that you know to try to
attract pest to those so the other
plants can grow well I want to get
deeper into the different areas you've
personally grown in have you tried to
like transfer genetics from one area to
another and just seen a poor result or
had a good result yeah no every
everywhere I've go we found ways to get
the genetics there I was the first legal
person to import seeds to Zimbabwe um
and we went to go pick up the seeds at
the airport and uh I don't know if I
told you this story or not but uh uh we
went to go pick up the seeds I had all
my paperwork from the you know the
health department and they're like
you're here to pick up seeds like yeah
you're going to get arrested like
whatever like give us your paperwork and
he checked in and it had the SE right
seals on it and stuff so he goes up to
his boss comes back down and he um puts
the box out with all the other boxes to
kind of like test their dogs this is cuz
they're having fun with it now once
everything's on the up and up and then
they put take it out and they search
around the dogs don't hit on the box and
they went from being really chummy to
like really pissed off uh so that was a
that was a pretty scary few minutes
until we could get the box and get out
of the airport but uh that was that was
really fun but um I've grown a lot of
different places and I would say that
the only time we've really had a lot of
negative issues was well partially was
trying to get CBD and CBG cultivar to um
grow in uh the uh the tropics so those
in particular were were very difficult
uh because the Heat and the natural
higher manganese in Zimbabwe in
particular um has a really high base
level of manganese in the soil and if
you have high manganese that tends to
really increase the um expression of
other particular compounds that you
don't want if you're trying to grow for
for you know EU compliant cultivar so um
it kind of pushes that outside of the
range so between that and the heat um
you know it kind of causes you to always
test hot so that was a big problem um
that was really hard to kind of deal
with and the end of the day we real
Ended as selecting through through
phenotypic and and cultiv our selection
finding the right ones for that but it
did take you know we got to get rid of
about 40% of them because they just were
always testing hot you know for for the
compliance that we had to grow for for
that particular customer but um that was
the only time we ever really had a ton
of problems with the cultivar
specifically I mean you always have a
percentage of what you're going to try
to grow there is just going to hate that
climate and just do crappy and you just
have that's part of the game right you
matter what you're trying to do there's
always going to be a certain percentage
of of genetics that are just going to
not like your particular grow method no
matter what you're doing um so that's a
big part of it and then also too just
making sure that you can kind of get the
the biocurity that you need in a lot of
these facilities they're used to Growing
traditionally and that can be a big big
difficulty but that was kind of the
biggest problems now in Jamaica there um
nothing really gets that large very few
of the genetics I've seen that were
really growing in the Hills you know get
much above 3 or 4 ft tall so you're not
getting that much yield per plant um so
that was definitely another issue and
you're going to go with much more denser
planting um I have some videos and stuff
on it on my YouTube of of what that
looks like in the Hills above uh uh out
in West Morland um I have a lot of good
friends down there I always love going
down to the island uh and uh and hanging
out and seeing a bunch of the
traditional grows I got lots of good
homies down there and spend a lot of
time down there now in um Zimbabwe
Zimbabwe was really weird because we had
a lot of um you know traditional
rosarian grow that just were growing
gigantic trees and they didn't care if
it was taking six or eight months in
fact the uh best pining cultivars I've
ever had were and I still have um are
from the hills of nyanga uh up kind of
on the mosan Beek um Zimbabwe border
there's a ton of incredible genetics
there that have totally uncontaminated
still um and I think that kind of
subsaharan Africa is kind of The Last
Place on Earth that aside from maybe the
Himalayas that has a lot of untouched uh
genetics that haven't been contaminated
yet um it's the only place I've seen a
lot of genetics was was in Zimbabwe and
and you know on the border of mosan Beek
there um hands down like I don't think I
saw anything that had any kind of
Western structure to it it was very very
nice you know gigantic you know candal
abas uh um and uh what was interesting
there is they brag about how many snakes
you get on it so like if you have a lot
of snakes on your your plants the snakes
will rub themselves on the resin glands
to get rid of ticks and things like that
because it makes them they don't like
the resin right so um it's like a
bragging rights if you have like uh lots
of snakes in your grow which I thought
was a bit insane considering the species
there but um you know you have to deal
with green mambas and stuff I'm I'm not
down for finding snakes in the in the
grow that's crazy yeah I've never heard
that before that's that's pretty wild so
you mentioned like a percent of genetics
kind of not working out for the average
hom grower what would you say like if
they're ordering seeds online from say
different country or whatever and they
get it and they try to grow them within
their home grow indoor setup what
percentage of genetics would you say
won't work out I would just say um you
know avoid stuff that's from the tropics
that gets large that's going to be the
number one thing like um we recently had
the temple tie that I did a a collab
with with with Jordan um on uh on
growcast and we released a bunch of
those gentics and the the biggest issue
with those they get you know 10t tall by
week N9 from germination where you going
to grow that in a tent right you need to
hack the crap out of it to grow Stu so
avoid those types of cultivars you know
a lot of your traditional trop
equatorial land race stuff not going to
really do well indoors or you know maybe
start it indoors and then finish it
outside kind of thing if you're going to
do that um that's going to be your
biggest you know challenge every you
know otherwise just if you do decide to
take them on just prune the living crap
out of them make sure you know every for
to 8 days you are doing some type of
light trim on it to keep them manageable
in size or train them or you know super
crop them or whatever it is you need to
do to keep them inside your space and
also to remember like most cultivars
with a few exceptions kind of stop
growing after about 24 to 30 days in
terms of stretching once you flip their
life cycle so you know keep in mind that
plant might grow another you know 2 feet
3 feet on some of these more equatorial
strains that don't queue in quite as
head hard is some of the the northern
strains that are a little more used to
to queuing in on that indoor 1212 um you
know sometimes it can take them a little
longer and if you have you know you
don't want that thing to be growing up
into the lights and and not haven't even
flipped yet you know I've seen people do
that too and just have to totally make
like baskets out of the room you know
and correct me if I'm wrong but the
genetics that are down in the tropics
are more longer flowering strains right
so looking at 11 12 13 plus weers
sometimes down there is that right oh
yeah yeah and even longer you know I
there's definitely some cultivar I've
seen both in Africa especially in Africa
and to a less extent in Thailand you
know that can take you you know four or
five months of flower um and a real real
long time to actually finish off what
also is interesting is a lot of the
equatorial varieties have a minimum time
too so they have like they're going to
veg for two months or 3 months no matter
if you start them in 1212 or not like
the the temple tie that I have um
absolutely like it's going to get to 10
ft tall no matter what unless you are
hacking the crap out of it even if it's
under 1212 or even 1111 um you know or
1113 rather uh it's still going to grow
like you know absolute Gang Busters and
just ignore the fact that it's you know
50/50 because it's the the it strain
grew up the whole time and the you know
equator right so it's going to it's used
to that 12 hours and 12 hours so it has
kind of a minimum flowering time now
what's cool about it is some of them
once you're past that time you can take
cuts of them and they'll finish in you
know 9 to 12 weeks which is not that
much far off from a lot of your typical
cultivars I know a lot of stuff now is
eight weeks but most stuff is really N9
or 10 um if it's really good so a lot of
them can still fall into that range but
you're going to have to veg it for like
you know four or five months before you
know that Mom before you could really do
anything with it in terms of quick flet
fing so that's another thing to take
into account too with the equatorial and
I don't hear people talk about it as
much the other one that I've noticed too
is with the equatorial stuff and to a
lesser extent with the CBD lines as well
if you keep them under 24 hours of light
it causes herming and and a lot of like
hormonal problems where I'll get nanners
on them if I have them under 24 hours of
light for veg but if I flip them and
just do a 1212 or even 16 and8 U I don't
have any of those issues like the
nanners Stop and they never come back I
don't have any flowering problems with
them throwing nanners it's just that
like stress of not sleeping um I've
noticed particularly in land race as
well as CBD in particular seem to really
you know heavily fall into that um that
range where it's going to be a huge
problem for you I haven't heard that
before that's pretty interesting yeah
I've gotten myself into a little bit of
hot water I guess just to S kind of IGN
I don't say ignoring flowering time but
like I grow a whole whole bunch of
different cultivars in the same tent and
you know I didn't really look at the
flowering time too deeply on one of the
cultivars it was actually Hades thrown
by Zaza genetics sh out to ZaZa and uh
this one went for like 12 weeks
everything else finished in 8 n and so
this one was just lagging Beyond and I
knew something was up once I flipped a
flowering and it was stretching and
stretching and stretching and then 4
weeks into it it's like still grow I'm
like what the heck I'm like oh great
that at that point I knew it was longer
flowering and so like I thought it was a
really good tip what you mentioned is
like yeah be aware of this stuff right
like plan around it because you could
get your hands on some genetics and they
may sound good but if you're not look at
the flowering time that could really
throw your grow a little sideways if
you're someone like me who was growing a
whole whole bunch of different plants in
one grow space well you could have a
whole bunch of plants finished first
then have this one plant lagging could
throw off your whole grow cycle really
the other thing I would mention too is
like if you have zamal which is The
Reunion Island R land race which very
few people actually have but I'm one of
the people that managed to get my hands
on some um shout out the the woman who
gave me those she knows who she who it
was um uh the other one that I've seen
with the same trait is freak Show in
Thailand a friend of mine canai um he
has a really good um
uh cultivar of freak show that does the
same thing but um those two strains I've
seen or heard of them in the case of the
the zamal The Reunion Island land race
um are actually can continue to grow
post flower right so they'll just reveg
and then flower again reveg and flower
again and keep going back and forth
between those two states so you can grow
them you know kind of perennially
without having to harvest the whole
plant back which is unique there's very
few plants in the whole Jean Pool that
have that mutation so I've only seen in
person the freak Show do it but I also
know that a lot of people claim that
zamal does it as well um but that's kind
of something where hey if you're going
to do that you know you have a big
structured plant and you're growing it
indoors that's kind of a problem if
you're in the tropics and you can just
let it grow in your yard all day like
that's not a problem right that's
actually a benefit so you know kind of
dialing in what exactly what it is you
want to do and you want from the plant
and the size of the plants that you want
for your particular indoor grow is going
to be a big factor into what your you
know selection is really good point I
want to Circle back to Pest Control
challenges what Pest Control challenges
have you faced growing in different
areas and do you have any tips for just
general I guess IPM or or pest control
that do Growers can take away yeah
there's quite a bit to this one so um
when I was in Jamaica for instance in
May and Puerto Rico is the same way
anywhere in the Caribbean anyone that's
growing there knows this um you have
butterfly season so all the butterfli
basically not all of them but it feels
like all of them like 60% of the
butterfly species all have like lay eggs
at once in April so they all hatch out
and you have this swarm of butterflies
that are all looking to lay eggs all
over everything in May in particular and
and anywhere in the Caribbean it's a
huge pain in the butt so but if you know
that that's coming you can get ready in
March and kind of keep BT on your plants
in March and April and and kind of head
that off so that as soon as they're on
the plants there's something already
working to get rid of them so that's the
kind of thing where once you've been
through a place through a full year or
even talking to local farmers hey what
do I need to worry about in the next 3
months what we need to worry about the
next four months and kind of learning
from the locals and what's often times
in the most of the world it's the women
that know all that stuff it's not the
men the men are the ones off running you
know fixing the tractors driving doing
all the other stuff it's the women in in
Africa and the Caribbean and many of
these other places that are the ones
actually working with the plant so
they're always the you know finding the
old wise wom in town is the one you need
to talk to 90% of the time in a lot of
these different you know especially more
Far Far Away places if you're really
want to get the good agriculture
information we had 80% women working in
Zimbabwe with us and they were teaching
us all kinds of cool stuff in terms of
identification uh another great trick
for identifying um especially in a large
scale for caterpillars is go out at
night with a black light um the
caterpillars and a lot of other insects
will glow like little Christmas
ornaments on your plants and they're
really easy to spot and Scout um that's
why especially in the summertime I'll
switch my work cruise to in you know
June through August to work at night
time you know we'll start off at 1:00 or
2: a.m. and then finish up by like 11:
or noon so that if it's going to be 100
you know whatever in the middle of the
day we're finishing up right as it's
getting hot you know same thing anywhere
where it's going to be brutal it's kind
of the work schedule you have to do but
what's cool is it makes it super easy to
start the day by scouting with black
lights and uh you know looking around
and seeing what what the heck is going
on in the field um so that was a great
way to kind of deal with a lot of those
issues in Jamaica um in Zimbabwe we ran
into some new issues that I hadn't run
into before so we had large locusts uh
and grasshoppers that would come in and
eat the center Cambrian layer of the
plant so they go up about a foot and a
half 2 feet high eat all the bark off
and then the plants will just flop over
right and it's like what do you do
against that and there's you know we're
getting overrun and this all happened
right when covid hit the South Africa so
they immediately sealed all the borders
with South Africa and South Africa is
where we the only place we could import
bio controls from right so that we could
use for resell into Western markets
because that was the goal was to export
all the flour so we have basically got
cut off from all of our supply and I'm
getting overrun by bugs so I call out
Chris Trump and I was like hey man I'm
kind of panicking I don't know what to
do right now can you give me some ideas
on like something I can make because I
am like cut off from the outside world I
can't import anything now because they
have like a you know all the borders are
shut now for bringing in anything
because of Co and he
told me about a method where he had um
he did an IMO 3 to four and in the brand
he had a bunch of weevils that had
gotten into the brand and he inoculated
it with this Weevil brand you know
infected brand and what happened is the
the Weevil got uh or flea beetles or
whatever it was in there got um infected
with the uh the fungi from the IMO that
that liked to kill them basically the
wild equivalent of a bab basana or
iseria fumier um that or whatever is
Corps fumier now I think they just
changed the name of it um they're always
changing the name of the bio controls
just to confuse the crap out of the pest
control people I swear to uh anyways um
that they were looked like little
popcorn kernels cuz they were covered in
fungi so he was like Hey this works
really good on the the the macadamia nut
trees for getting rid of the weevils you
know we KN we kind of been screwing
around with it but I haven't had anybody
to really test it on like a bigger scale
so we went ahead and I we paid a bunch
of the kids like like a nickel for every
10 or 20 grasshoppers they could find
and we had all the little village kids
running around getting all the
Grasshoppers they could into buckets for
us and um we took that we did a bunch of
IMO collections with IPO so this is the
recipe for this and it's something I
think anybody doing gardening uh should
really you know adopt this practice CU
it's really really good it works on a
really wide range of insects
grasshoppers um blister beetles Japanese
beetles Leaf hoppers um stink bugs like
a lot of stuff that's really hard to
treat normally um gr caterpillars and
gra uh and butterflies works really good
on these guys too um it will kill your
bees though if you spray them directly
with it it will infect them so it won't
take out your hive but if you spray them
and directly apply it um onto the bees
it will kill them so just make sure that
maybe you apply them in the evening when
the bees have already roosted if you if
you are keeping bees at home just to be
on the safe side it's just precaution on
that so uh if you're familiar with IMO
um and we'll we'll go through it and
assume that you aren't first you're
going to weigh about 700 g of rice and
put that into a bowl next you're going
to take 300 G of your locally collected
insects or purchased insect FR or go to
your local pet shop or farm store and
buy meal worms or crickets or some other
local insect is or take a light bulb and
put it above a bucket outside and just
let all the local bugs fall into it and
strain that and just try to get about
300 G of insect FR or bugs alternatively
you can use crab meal or Lobster meal if
you have to uh if you're in a
pinch next you're going to mix those two
together until you have a nice uh insect
infused rice mix then you're going to
cook the together combined in a in a pot
until it's about 80 to 85% finished with
the rice till it's a little bit stiff
still but not totally soft yet then
you're going to take that finished
cooked mix and you're going to put it
into a open um uh open weave basket that
has a a lot of holes in it and air can
flow through it really well uh and
you're going to put a good four or five
in layer uh in the bottom of that basket
then you're going to take a piece of uh
open screen uh and doesn't matter any
kind of screen will work or you can even
just take a piece of string and weave it
across the top um you just need to make
a cover for it that air can pass through
but you don't want to keep let the local
dogs or cats or squirrels or whatever
else Forest creatures into it um okay so
now you have your basket that has a
little screen on top now you're going to
take your basket full of uh your your
starter and you're going to put that out
into the forest or a part of your
property that has a lot of Duff or Leaf
litter or you know an area where it's
kind of naturally composting like you
would in a forest um the older the area
that's and the healthier the area the
better you know uh I like to do a good
you know 10 to 20 collections at a time
when I do this because you can combine
all of them and kind of get the
different microbial colonies from around
the different
area uh you're going to set that basket
out uh into your forested area and then
you're going to put a cover on top so
not directly on top of the basket but
you know a good foot and a/ half 2 ft
above it you're going to put a plastic
bag or an old dog food bag or a trash
bag whatever you can it just keeps the
rain from falling onto the rice the rice
doesn't get any more wet right you just
want to have it kind of like damp but
not soaking
wet uh then you're going to look around
the forest and see if you can find any
um pieces of branches or anything that
have a little um uh micro Riza on it and
just drop two or three of those or or
you know four or five if you want to
into the top of your basket just uh you
know underneath the screen so that you
do have a little bit of an inoculant
going on there now what's going to
happen is uh you're going to leave it
out there for 5 days I know maybe six if
it's a little bit cooler if it's really
hot you can sometimes get away with four
days but usually 5 to six days is what
it takes to do the collection now what
happens is you're collecting the natural
fungi that feed on the rice but also
that feed on the insect corpses
basically the kiten kiten feeding
insects um or no sorry uh kiten feeding
fungi that that feed on the
insects so um you're kind of capturing
all the local equivalents of Bavaria
basana and saer fumasi and all these
other bio controls that you're making at
home but you're Gathering whatever the
local species is from your particular
property or your particular region so
that when you apply this in your garden
you don't have to worry about you know
contaminating the ground or worry about
runoff or worry about if your kids
running through the garden while you're
spraying or if your dog runs by you uh
or if it drinks from the container it's
no big deal I can drink this stuff which
is cool so now your your basket's been
out there for 5 days you have your nice
solid block of fungi uh it's going to be
white maybe a little yellow maybe a
little bit of green in there but for the
most part it should be white or most you
know 80% plus white you're going to take
the basket back uh and then you're going
to take all of your different fungal
blocks that you have check them make
sure they're not all green if it's all
green it's gone to tricoderma now
trichoderma is good in some cases if you
got a fungal outbreak or whatever you
can culture that trichoderma and
absolutely use that that if you have you
know 50 a root rot or some other you
know powdery milde something like that
if you have to but we're not trying to
to collect the tri tricoderma tricoderma
can be a little too aggressive and it
can wipe out a lot of your other
beneficials if you use too much of it so
uh uh if it's too much green throw it
away um if it's not all green it's all
nice and white or white and yellow take
that and you're going to weigh it all
and put all the good collections into a
bucket you know if you put out 20 of
them you should get at least you know
seven or eight of them that are keepers
um you know if you get more than that
then great but you know don't feel bad
if you only get one or two that's
perfectly fine that's all you really
need so now you're going to weigh all of
that collectively so let's just say that
that we had uh 3 kilog of it so we have
3,000 gam that we had saved now we're
going to weigh 3,000 gam of brown sugar
and we're going to combine that and mix
it all together and it's going to
stabilize it by locking out the oxygen
with all of that Sugar um and that's
going to basically cause all of those
microbes to go to like a Spore form
so now we have a shelf stabilized
version that we can keep indefinitely uh
for for use as our store you know
basically shelf stabilized pesticide
that we've just made now when we're
ready to brew that we're going to take a
big scoop full uh if we're doing a
smaller batch you can do a tabl spoon
for you know a grow tent size if you're
going to do a larger grow you know we
were doing a uh you know four to six
cups of it to do um about 8,000 ft of
greenhouse it doesn't take that much you
put that into a big paint strainer you
put a AirStone or two in there and you
brew it up in your bucket or in your
trash can and uh uh brew that up for 24
hours now um the IPO should smell
freakishly like winter green uh when it
finishes it has this amazing Pine winter
green smell I can't tell you why I don't
know what I think it's the fennels that
are in it but um it it it comes out this
incredible like winter green smell I'm
I'm not sure if that's Universal it's
been Universal with all the different
places I've done it you might have a
version with your local biology that
doesn't make it happen but every time
I've done it that's what it smells like
so now you have this all good brw mix
that's basically the rewok up microbes
that you went and collected that feed on
kiten and now when you apply that both
either directly to the root system
through your fertigation just strain it
and and apply it right to the roots uh
you can also fol your spray it onto the
plants um and it works to kill a huge
wide range of insects but also uh
instantly provides kenes directly to the
PLS because those in that fungi broke
down that kiten from those insects
inside of it so you're also increasing
the S response to the plant the plants
now boosting its immune system and its
own defenses and you're directly
infecting the the insects that are on
the plant so it's kind of like a double
mechanism you're boosting the plant's
ability to fight the insects uh and
boosting it its nutrient uptake of
calcium uh at the same time which also
helps with insect resistance you're also
um directly infecting the the the pest
insects you know by applying spores
directly to their body which then infect
them and kill them and turns them into
little white mummies which is really
really cool but um it really is the best
pesticide that I've seen or the best
Innovation I've seen in in the organic
World in a long time and I think that
everybody should be sharing this recipe
you know with anybody they can because
it's a completely safe way to make a
pesticide that really kicks the crap out
of just a huge range of different
insects um and it's completely safe you
can drink the stuff and it's not it
might give you a stomach ache but it's
not going to kill you you know you're
not going to have to go to the hospital
there there's no kind of you know danger
that's awesome I appreciate you sharing
that recipe with us we have uh quite a
few folks that take notes you know
they've got their pen and Pad ready and
they're they're taking notes on that and
really with this this IMO recipe natural
farming technique and there's so many
different natural farming techniques out
there but yeah again thanks for sharing
that one I'm sure you've probably saved
quite a few Gardens now in the future
here because uh like you mentioned that
sounds like it's very strong and very uh
valuable for folks growing in different
areas to kind of prevent pests or tackle
pests I've even had people um use it on
Broad mites and have success as well
which surprised me because typically
things with six legs do or eight legs do
not work with with fungal bio controls
so um you know again I haven't had that
response but we have I've had reports of
people two different people in Thailand
using it to treat mites so um you know
you never know what you're going to
collect and and what it's going to work
for but for the most part it is amazing
for most of your larger insects across
the board what about like storage tips
and shelf life on it so the oldest one
I've had is about a year and a half old
and it was still pretty viable um I
haven't kept it longer than that just
because um you know it's kind of a newer
Tech that's only been around really
since two 2020 so most of the places
we're at we haven't Che you know we've
either blown through the whole batch
that we made or um you know some other
thing where we just combined it with the
next one you can combine multiple months
too right so I like to do a collection
every month and then I'll combine this
month last month and the next month you
know from the previous year so if I
collect it in February I'm going to put
January and March's collections in the
following Year's application and you
just combine those three when you make
it so a scoop of this a scoop of this
and a scoop of this and that's going to
give you the best biodiversity in fact
it's not that much different from you
know who used to do this first was the
Vikings they would take the the best
soil from the end of the grow season and
the you know right before Harvest put it
into empty Rams horns and seal them with
wax and then bury them below the frost
line and then when the spring would come
and the ground would thaw they would dig
those up and spread them back out on the
on the ground well they thought they
were like putting the garden Spirits
back onto the garden actually what they
were doing is just inoculating it with
microbes that were kept below the frost
line uh and then now they're kind of
just reinoculated their garden with the
best microbes from the previous years so
they had the same kind of idea it was
just a little bit different methodology
so a lot of the stuff is really much
older than people realize or we've been
doing similar practices we just kind of
refin them you know significantly since
uh since their Inception that's super
interesting so getting into different
areas I want to get into Garden setup
and design there's a lot of challenges
that can be faced going from setup area
in different countries or even just
different areas across the US what
design challenges have you faced and
kind of pivots that you've had to do
growing in some areas versus others yeah
so the biggest one hands down across the
board was power um in Zimbabwe we had
power from zesa from p.m. till about
5:30 to 6:00 a.m. and that was it the
rest of the time the power goes to the
industrial zones and you don't get power
so if you don't have power you know a
generator or solar or you know some
other way to power up whatever it is you
need to power up that day um you are
screwed so uh that was a huge part of it
setting up all that infrastructure
usually solar or or generators just to
get get by in the beginning and then
setting up solar pumps for long-term
irrigation um is really just almost
required once you get into most of the
remote areas um you know setting them
all up to drip lines and then also on on
a rotation schedule so like this field
gets flooded on Mondays this field gets
flooded on Tuesdays this field gets
flooded on Wednesdays and then repeat
again you know kind of thing so um that
type of stuff is really you know uh
indexing valves would be another one
where we're able to do large volumes of
stuff with one or two pieces of
equipment because it's switching between
four separate large zones or eight
separate large zones um the one thing I
would say with indexing valves is that
make sure you're checking them daily or
almost daily because if one of those
fails you know you're losing thousands
of plants if that that breaks and we had
that happen at one facility in Jamaica
um that I was working with University
technology Kingston they had one that
failed and it wiped out you know three
of the four rows of plants that they had
um because they weren't checking it
regularly on the maintenance once it was
set up the the guy just signed off that
he checked it and wasn't actually
checking it so that's another thing is U
making sure people are actually doing
and finding out like who in your local
area is actually reliable um that you
can count on you know is an another big
thing but the biggest thing too is just
drip lines drip lines are the best way
to do large scale you know outdoor any
kind because you're not going to get any
of that evaporative water loss um and
they're pretty easy to set up everywhere
in the world you can find the drip line
irrigation kits you know doesn't matter
if you're as far away as Zimbabwe um or
some of the other areas that maybe don't
have quite as much income uh in the
world uh um you can find drip line kits
at an industrial scale pretty cheaply
anywhere so um the next thing would be
properly sourcing fertilizers and and
pesticides in most of the rest of the
world is a lesson in Insanity um you
really have to hunt and peack and often
just import them from local countries
nearby um you know in the case of
Zimbabwe we had to import everything
from Kenya or Zim or South Africa
because they're the only two places that
have bio controls that we can get either
beneficial insects or you know all your
standard you know things like Bavaria
basana so on and so forth aren't really
that much into the rest of the world yet
yet with the exception of Southeast Asia
Thailand was an exception where Thailand
actually has a bunch of Bio controls
that we don't even have here yet that I
wish we I wish I had we have a 10in one
which is like a or five in one uh that's
B
militaris and uh verab basana iseri
medium and another one uh all combined
into one in one application and that
stuff kicks butt like like that's like
your especially for thrips that like
nukes the crap out of your thrips man
they just wipes them out um and that was
really a good Saving Grace for us for
thrips but um that's another thing too
in the US you can't do combined um bio
controls right so they don't they can't
legally sell a product that has bavia
basana and metum in it as a combined
application they have to all be
individual active ingredients because of
the pest control laws United States
whereas in Thailand you can have two
three four five bio controls and one
separate powder you put in the water and
mix it up and and run with it so um that
would be another big thing that's that's
different is that sometimes you at least
in Southeast Asia it's a little easier
for for the pesticide stuff to find what
you want but you know in Zimbabwe you
could buy paraquat at the hardware store
and it's sitting right next to the
ammonium nitrate and the barrel barrels
of peroxide which you know is not a very
good place to store all that stuff uh
certainly not in the open where people
are smoking cigarettes so uh it is a uh
you know you see some stuff where you're
like oh my brain hurts and I shouldn't
be anywhere near this place right now
but um you know that that's honestly the
the biggest challenge is power and then
sourcing stuff can be just if you aren't
used to to to and the hardest part of
sourcing is just finding whatever the
local thing is like in Zimbabwe it's
shopy and Lazada uh in Africa it's kind
of whatever a website that you can find
um so that a lot of it is just spending
hours searching for all your list of
equipment once you have your list of
equipment as far as sourcing and and
finding someone that can deliver it
within a reasonable time too that could
be another big problem depending on
where you are I want to get deeper into
genetic diversity just a little bit more
here talking about modern techniques
genetic engineering selective breeding
what role does that play in shaping the
genetic diversity of plants well as far
as um selective breeding I mean I think
that's one of the reasons why United
States is kind of the king of the
medical Plant World is because we you
know fought the man one closet at a time
you know we had at any one point you
know 60 to 80,000 different breeding
programs going in the us at anyone or
more right to supply it's always was
comical to me when you hear some of
these big MSO and corporate guys going
well there's not enough small producers
around to to to supply the country who
do you think supplied the country for
the last 80 years right like that's a
comical thing to say so I think but
that's why you have you know the us as
the leader on that genetically is
because we did have so many different
unique programs and every single breeder
had a different thing in mind each one
was chasing something different some had
a medical problem some were chasing hype
stuff some were chasing stuff that look
good some just happened to get lucky and
find a a gem in the rough and and ran
with it you know there's plenty of
stories with that you know Gorilla Glue
was was an accident plant you know
there's plenty of others out there that
you know were just something
accidentally got pollinated ended up
producing a gem you know so there's even
lots of stuff that was accidental um and
people didn't so I think that's really
the the biggest thing that's driving now
nowadays you have a lot of this genetic
marker assisted stuff and things like
that um you know there's definitely some
companies not that long ago that were
screaming about uh uh uh what was it new
outrageous new strains it's funny how
the company that said that the CEO got
fired and we've yet to see any of those
outrageous new strains um I know that GW
Pharma has a few genetically patented
strains that they've never released to
the public that they're internal that
I've heard from eth talking to Ethan
Russo but there's not a lot of people
doing the GMO stuff yet at least not
publicly and to be honest with you too a
lot of the market does not want GMOs
like
80% of the canas market are people that
already don't like GMOs right so it's
kind of a why would you make something
for a com for a market that doesn't want
that thing right there's certainly some
on the large scale commercial side I
think you know things like triploids or
or GMO stuff that's not going to be able
to be pollinated it's cool when you just
want to grow a field for biomass right
and not have any males or have your
neighbor neighbor be able to do his own
breeding program and not screw up your
stuff or have hemp growing you know seed
hemp or Fiber hemp where they're not
pulling males um and then you don't have
to worry about it for your home grow I
think that's or not home grow but like
for your other nearby commercial grow I
think that has viability for that type
of stuff but personally I'm I'm not I'm
not for GMOs or anything like that I
also think that there's a potential too
with autof flowers being kind of used in
that way with um and I've talked about
this a long time ago with Autos being
used to kind of control the market you
have triploids and Autos being like the
vast majority of what's available to Hom
Growers they have to buy each time once
we have Federal legalization it means
the feds can get their tax money each
time so I could see them doing some kind
of law where and again this is being
doomsday is but where the feds require
those to be the only seeds sold so that
they can control the market which you
know that would uh piss a lot of people
off including me um and it's something
that is scummy enough I could see them
trying to do hopefully I didn't give
them any
ideas so triploids generally are kind of
against that huh no I mean a lot of
great strains of triploids but I mean at
the end of the day if you're selling
seeds and people can't breed with
them that's kind of uh you're kind of
ending the line you know you're a lot of
us that are in the community happen to
to and a lot of breeders what are
breeders supposed to work with you know
if you're a new breeder just getting
into the game you know you're not
somebody that's been around for a long
time you don't have 2,000 plus different
Cult of Arts in your your selection like
I do or a lot of other people do that
have been doing this a long time you
know how are you supposed to build a
pool and to start working with to to to
to have the colors you need to paint
your picture right like you got to have
some different stuff so you can be oh I
like the trait from this one I like the
trait of this one I bet they'd be even
better if I combined them this way right
like that's what all of us have have
experienced when we're doing breeding
and by closing that door it takes away a
lot of the fun of of actually just
growing the plant so like again it's
great for commercial production I think
it definitely has a place in the market
but I wouldn't buy a 10 pack you know
put it that way I got my hands on the
Donuts triploid by Humbolt and I haven't
planted them yet fig I'd plant them and
try them out see see what happens there
but yeah I mean from what I'm hearing it
seems like there's more I don't know if
I should even say this but seems like
more cons and Pros I feel like it's
never going to kind of overrun the whole
Market I feel like fem are always going
to be the most popular right everyone
the traditional home grow is just going
to want fem and they're going to want to
be able to create their own seeds and
you can't really do that with tripid so
I don't foresee tripid
kind of overrunning everything and then
like regs and fem kind of being outdated
or obsolete but yeah it's kind of
interesting that's kind of coming onto
the scene here and seems becoming pretty
popular out of nowhere my other question
is is that what are the negative impacts
of that tripa genetic like does it make
it weaker to PM does it make it weaker
to some environmental factor or insect
that suddenly it you know because of
that mutation it it's not able to
express something that it needs to
defend itself like that's that's another
thing I always think about with this is
you might make a great plant but if you
know you breathe on it wrong and it gets
petritis uh it's not that great of a
plant right so so that's the other stuff
I worry about is uh you know a lot of
this poly hybrid stuff the moment I take
it and put it outside just gets wrecked
like like a lot of the super super poly
hybrid stuff did not do well in Thailand
it just got mold like like especially
when we're growing in the rice patties
needs to be have some level of of mold
resistance espe you know or it's just
going to not do well so um you know you
can solve a lot of that with things like
IMO applications and boosting the plants
but you can that only works so far
before you know just nature is going to
take its course too you know yeah that's
interesting I I guess it's not really
surprising in a way because um yeah I
mean this this whole episode has really
been about growing plants in different
areas and that's a good good example of
a plant that doesn't grow well grows
well in one area but doesn't grow well
in another well think of it too like why
do you have different genetic cultivars
in different regions is because the
genes are being triggered in the plant
immune system to defend itself for those
different things that increase those
different secondary metabolites that we
call flavonoids and tpin and other
compounds in the plant so if those genes
aren't being expressed over and over
again in an indoor grow where they're
kept sterilized especially if it's like
a a rock W grow where they're all super
sterilized how how are those genes going
to get activated that's why you see like
Hydro rockol stuff it's hard to get
above three% tpin for most people unless
you're really doing microbial
inoculations if you hit take those same
cultivar drop them in living soil or
aquaponics and they have that Gene
activation of all those different
microbes you're going to start to hit
you know four five 6% tpin uh on those
out of those same exact cultivars
because those genes are being turned on
suddenly so um that's the number one
reason why you need to get microbial
biodiversity in your root system is to
turn those genes on and get that turpine
expression on because that's going to
boost not only the plant's immune system
but also you know your yields and the
and the potency of your your medicinal
crops or even your lettuce and tomato
you know you want to have good flavor in
your lettuce and tomatoes or cucumbers
or or eggplant you better have a good
biological diversity it's why for
instance a living soil lettuce out of
your backyard tastes better than the
hydroc crap at the grocery store because
all of those genes are being turned on
inside the plant that make those
flavonoids and without that you you
don't have that gene expression that's
why if you continually breed something
in a sterile environment it's going to
lose the ability to turn those genes on
because why is it going to waste the
energy to to to make those compounds
anymore or to even try to turn those
genes on when it never has to deal with
it and neither did its grandparents or
you know it great-grandparents it has a
long-term you know evolutionary lineage
where it's not having to deal with that
stuff so it kind of makes for weaker
strains that are especially powdery
mildew seems to be like the number one
thing that these Ultra poly hybrids seem
to be just really weak to when you put
them Outdoors or you know certain insect
stuff they just have no resistance to
because again there there's no immune
system to these plants and I think
people kind of forget that part of it
that's a really good points there kind
of reminds me of you hear a lot of
people talking about genetic drift can
you talk about what genetic drift is and
how it's really impacted plants these
days so genetic drift would be either
from Super hybridizing something
especially with itself or having just
really old moms you know um remember
that the plant's kind of constantly
producing new tissue and it's again
constantly turning those immune system
genes off and on like we just talked
about so uh if you have the mom that's
growing in one kind of condition and
then the flowering condition are much
more different it's it's going to have a
hard time with that and also too as
plants age you they're going to have
some genetic mutation just from the fact
that the plants just living longer right
um the other thing that people forget
with is has some issues too when you
grow it too long because it wants to um
save its local genetic population so uh
it's going to try to hermaphodite on you
once it hits a certain age because
that's built into the genes of the plant
the same reason why like rootbound
plants will trigger for the same thing
because uh in the right you have a plant
and it grows and grows and grows it
doesn't get pollinated doesn't get
pollinated doesn't get
pollinated and now it gets a cold snap
or get some kind of like weather
condition that's going to potentially
kill the plant in the near future it's
going to immediately try to produce that
female pollen so we can produce female
plants so that it can die and next year
its daughters can come back and try to
be pollinated by outside genetics to
preserve that local population the
plants evolved to do that when it
evolved in the steps of of Mongolia and
Tibet which is where it's from Orin
originally um it it evolved that
mechanism so that it didn't go extinct
in its local region and and when you
think about an evolutionary that makes a
lot of sense for it to function that way
right uh and and and evolutionarily
that's a big Advantage but when you're
trying to veg it and keep it from
flipping that's a problem because you
know there is a maximum life on the
plants usually about a year and a half
two years where they're just going to
start to to get real weird on you and
some of those genes for that final end
of life thing are starting to turn on
because it's been alive too long or
maybe you stressed it out too much or
it's root bound after that or whatever
the the pressure point is but that
something's going to eventually trigger
those genes you know if you don't
restart it and take new clones even if
you clone it that clone's not going to
be exactly the same as that mother was
it's going to be close but it's going to
have a few mutations that are different
or a few adaptations phenotypic
adaptations that going to be slightly
different from that mother and over time
those start to build up and can cause
issues the other thing I see a lot in
really old ones and people often
attribute to genetic drift but usually
it's not it's actually viral infection
is is um you know particularly mosaic
virus and some of these others
where if the plant is healthy it's not
going to have any kind of negative
impact right um you know as long as it's
getting all of it needs and the immune
system is kept healthy but as the plant
gets older and older it's less able to
fight that so you get this gradual
increase in viral load until it hits
that critical point and now it's
expressing in the leaves suddenly um you
see sometimes too with hlvd hlvd in many
cultivars will perfectly be fine if it's
only detectable in the root system it's
not going to affect the yields of the
flower in fact Kevin mckernin has a
wonderful white paper on this specific
problem um whereas if the plant gets
aged and that Viral low gets up and up
and up now it's going to start to cause
that that leaf mutation and the upper
part plant mutation and things like that
as well so that's that's how like for
instance the Hop industry has has slowly
gotten rid of uh hlvd was they didn't
ever got rid of hlvd completely what
they did was they got rid of all the
cultivars that actually have problems
with it so it can remain latent in the
plant but not have yield effects or
negative yield impact so that you know
the industry is going to have to stop
you know with this idea that they're
ever going to get rid of it it it can be
latent in cucumbers and tomatoes and
corn right how are you going to get rid
of that you can't and it's pollen spread
so you could have a leaf Hopper go bite
the guy's corn and then reinfect your
plants right that you just spent all
this lab work on it's a it's a
it it's an impossible task you can't
eliminate it right the hemp the Hops
industry would have eliminated it a long
time ago they spent 200 years on this
problem and they still haven't figured
it out right so we're not and they spend
a lot of money as beer guys have as much
money as the the the medicinal plant
Growers do in terms of investment to
protect their plants so you know again
if if companies like uniu can't solve
this you know we're not going to do
anything magically different overnight
that's going to suddenly do it so um
this is you know another big issue where
especially you I can go into most Grow
rooms and find at least one or two viral
infected plants where people don't even
realize it especially mosaic virus where
there or or um I've seen a lot in the
last couple years on outdoor plants beat
um Leaf Crow virus or Bean Leaf Crow
virus where it causes the really cork
screwing and stuff like that um where
you know again it might not show in the
beginning but after the plants hit six
or eight months suddenly it starts to
rage out because that viral load has
just hit that critical point where now
it's going to express in the leaf tissue
so that's another one where you know you
don't see as much when you have big genc
gene pool diversities you don't have as
much problems um whereas with the small
polyhybrid stuff you do yeah viruses
vroid that's a whole another topic on it
so we could do a whole episode on that
it's kind of scary you know I mean I I
only imagine how many hom grows are
impacted without the actual grower even
knowing that they're impacted by it they
think it's a deficiency instead it's
actually a virus or a vroid that's
causing har to their plants and they're
just treading on water basically trying
to keep their head above water for that
for that grow so yeah crazy stuff and
I'm sure there's going to be a lot more
information coming out in the future in
regards to that one I did have a
followup question in regards to the
mother plants now you touched upon how
over time these plants are going to be
more likely to Herm right so keeping
mother plants around I think you
mentioned one and a half to two years to
keep the mother plant around is that the
longest that you suggest keeping mother
plants around yeah I mean ideally if you
can swap them every 6 months to a year
and restart them that's that's even
better um but yeah I mean the longest I
would try to keep something about a year
and a half to two years after that the
likelihood of you not having problems is
is pretty low you know you're going to
have some kind of issue at that point um
also size you know how if you're growing
something that long even if you're
hacking the crap out of it every 10 days
it's going to be a huge structure to it
at that point and it just gets
unmanageable and it's a pain to to take
new Cuts you get on a ladder and it just
it's just not safe right especially when
you get to bigger time and you're you're
just working on that many hours you're
going to have an accident so um um it's
much better to just restart them before
they get too large from a safety
standpoint but also from just a genetic
drift standpoint you're going to have
those issues with the the plants that
are that are too old and you're talking
restart from seed right you're not
saying grow the mother plant for two
years take a clone from it and then that
clone is your new mother plant you could
in theory you can do that as long as you
kept them healthy yeah again the the
reasons why you end up having problems
biggest ones is root B you know being
root bound um heat stress or or
infection or insect damage you know any
kind U light you know light leaks or or
anything like that as long as you don't
have those types of things um you know
you can kind of get away with rebooting
them for the most part again you can
only do that once or twice though before
you're going to still plant's going to
have a maximum age before it's just
again going to start having problems
they just get that those genetics the
plant's not designed to live that long
so you're kind of doing a bunch of stuff
where it's it's starts to make errors in
its copies when it's making new tissue
and things like that same way that we do
you know that's why humans get cancer we
start to have errors in our our system
as we get older it's why older people
have more than than younger people for
instance so it's the same kind of
problem got it so what other tips do you
have for growing genetics in different
climates number one thing would just be
you know narrow leaves and hot climates
and and wider leaves and and colder
climates would be kind of the the
Baseline for that um try not to grow
anything super poly hybrid in an outdoor
environment period or if you do don't
count your farm on it um I know the
first year that runs came out um I watch
people plant you know an unseen amount
of that in Oklahoma and I don't know a
single person aside from us that
actually harvested it um because all of
it rotted you know if you're going to
grow a really dense um flowered
structured plant uh in uh somewhere
where it's high humidity good luck you
better put a heck of a you know
probiotic uh regimen on that plant
you're going to have major issues um
really is a a huge Factor when you're
choosing that you know grow something
that's more open and Airy with a less of
a tight structure something that's
larger and brancher in those more humid
environments um making sure using IMO
and IPO um for your stuff simply doing
the lactobacillus IMO and IPO from
curing natural farming on any kind of
large scale outdoor is going to make
your life so much easier the plants are
going to be much more naturally
resistant through a wide range of
different Pest and pathogen issues um it
really is going to be your your best way
to kind of make things go as smooth as
possible I can't imagine growing
anything at scale anymore without you
know different natural farming
methodologies just because of how much
of a good job it does at preventing you
know petritis powdery mildew um and a
lot of the other heavier insect problems
septoria be another one where you know
I've seen people have huge fields of
septoria uh and wipe them out but I've
also saved a lot of them too by treating
malaab bacillus and then IMO
inoculations um you don't have a
store-bought product you can go to treat
septoria easily especially once that
plant's heavily infected that's going to
reverse that you can treat it with
trichoderma or some of the other ones if
you catch it early on but traditionally
the agricultural industry will tell you
to throw that soil away even right we
can treat that in 3 weeks right so this
is kind of stuff where the natural
solution actually works much better than
the chemical one so once you start to
learn some of that stuff you your life
will get a lot easier um when it comes
to the the especially the bigger scale
stuff but even at the home scale for for
tent Growers um it's just going to make
sure you don't have to go buy those
expensive inputs uh at the shop you know
you can at least get half of your or
2third of your pest control stuff just
from your own backyard which is great
there's some really really good tips man
this whole talk has really opened up my
mind quite a bit and made me realize
that the amount of knowledge I have
compared to what you can learn growing
in different areas I mean it's just it's
pretty much endless I think we're all
going to be learning about this plant
for the rest of our lives right there's
always more to learn there's things that
we haven't uncovered yet and it's just
it makes things so exciting and so fun
thanks for coming on today really
appreciate it can you tell the listeners
how they can find you and if there's
anything upcoming in the feature that
you want to talk about sure yeah um you
guys can find me anytime over at the
growing with fishes podcast on all
platforms um we cover a wide range of
different aquaponic living soil and
medicinal plant topics over there um you
can also find me uh over on um copy left
cultivars I'm on the board of copy left
cultivars as well we have a a really
awesome new um natural farming AI bot
that we're releasing as well you can
check that out on any other content that
we've done on that over at copy left
cultiv ours.com and um
uh yeah if if anyone wants to check out
any of my school and stuff I have a
bunch of online courses as well over at
apj class.com so um yeah uh thank you so
much for having me on always a pleasure
uh also if you want to like listen to
more of uh Mr Grow and I he was over on
my show the other day so not too long
ago so be sure to check it out and
listen to uh uh the reverse where I
interview him so if you enjoyed this
episode yeah it's been a couple times
now that I've been on your show I
appreciate you having me on and I'll
definitely have a link to your Channel
down in the YouTube description section
below and I always do as a pinned
comment as well so folks can easily get
to your channel and yeah let us know any
questions that you have down in the
comments section I love to read through
the questions and if we get enough
questions maybe we can get another
episode with you to come on here and
answer some of those questions because
you have a lot of real in-depth
knowledge not just on genetic diversity
growing plants in different areas but I
mean we had that episode on aquaponics
which was just loaded with information
you grow organically do a lot of natural
farming so there's so many different
areas we can go in definitely leave your
questions down in the comments section
below Stephen thank you so much again
for coming on this has been awesome and
uh hope you enjoy the rest of your night
yeah thank you so much again for having
me on and uh as a pleasure as always
thanks thank you peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode