welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
165 in this episode interview Jorge
cantes jge is a legend in the
horiculture industry with over 40 years
experience he is an author and has
written over 40 books I asked him a
variety of questions in this episode
such as the 24-hour light cycle
temperature cloning pruning flushing and
more if you want to see short clips of
these podcast episodes search Garden
talk clips on YouTube I also have a
gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks da Infinity for sponsoring this
episode check out their trim tray this
kit features three trays with sorting
and sifting screens to give you the
flexibility to catch leaves or tricomes
in addition to the standard catch bin it
features a food grade stainless steel
tray that when used with the sifting
screen let you easily collect tricomes
without getting them stuck there's more
to it so click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their trim tray and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and their website website AC
infiniti.com stash blend several
additives in one blend so you no longer
have to buy individual bottles check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash spider farmer
check out their upgraded SC series of
grow lights these grow lights are smart
app controlled use Samsung lm301h Evo
diodes which have a PPE of 2.85 microl
per jeel have a folding design and are
dimmable with digital display they're
passively cooled and can be Daisy
chained up to 50 lights more information
is linked in the description section
below and discount code Mr Grow 5 works
on both Amazon and their website spider-
far.com and we are back and I'm joined
with Jorge cantes how you doing today
good good good lovely beautiful day here
in um just south Barcelona man it is an
honor to have you on the podcast today
your Grower's Bible was the first book
book I ever bought I started growing
back in 2010 and I was I think a year
into it I ended up buying that book and
it was my go-to guide for so many years
you're real prominent figure in the
space and I'm just so excited to have
you on here today to talk about a
variety of different things but first
before we get too deep into those things
can you give us a little introduction
tell us a little bit about yourself and
kind of how you got into gardening yeah
let's see um actually I've always liked
gardening i' since I was a little kid I
like like gardening I was the only one
of my family that like gardening uh you
know little kids they grow uh two two
crops that all little kids grow radishes
cuz they're so fast like those little uh
all the little red ones
so oh what the heck do they call I can't
remember what they call them but they're
really fast they they're like 28
days and then the other one that all
little kids grow is corn corn uh sweet
corn because it's a C4 crap uh plant and
C4 means it it uh well most plants are
uh C3 which means they fix carbon you
know but C4 that means they grow faster
so um yeah it's it's one of those plants
that grows fast and you know I mean
it'll grow taller than you as a little
kid so it's pretty cool um yeah so I
started started with that and then when
when cannabis um came out I I just got
really interested in it and I lived in
Southern California and started growing
in the Hills behind uh Santa Barbara
little town right next to it called Mono
that means little little mountain in
Spanish and since then they've had like
mud mud slides and stuff but anyway I I
started a long time ago I wrote this
book here and nobody had published it
nobody they didn't want to nobody would
even print it so I had to print the book
myself I did all my own artwork it's
it's pretty pretty limited artwork but
and then there's I had a few photos but
all the photos were black and white see
um but that's all I could afford the
book sold is 96 pages sold for
$88.95 and I printed the the book myself
first year this thing sold 6,000 copies
that was that was back in 1983 just in
uh the
Northwest uh Washington and
and a little bit in Vancouver BC and a
little bit in Northern California but
since then I've written like um 50 books
50 books yeah at least at least 50 books
and they're published in 11 different
languages uh all the you know the five
common languages European ones and then
there's some other cool ones I got this
one I'm proud of quite proud of this is
a Japanese Japanese book is hydroponic
book I did here's another one I did this
is
the well it's it's like this this the
English edition here that's probably the
one that you saw that's the one I have
yep yeah yeah this is the one that
finally did really well uh but and this
is the fifth edition yeah fifth edition
uh from 2006 that's right and this one
this a Russian Russian
Edition um yeah so there's there are 11
different languages and then this one
this book here this one this is a
encyclopedia it's like definitely my
biggest best book ever but so I'm giving
this one away I give it away on my on my
website I've also done tons of video
lots of videos these are the videos I
did with the New York Magazine uh High
Times and did a lot of these and
actually
I it I I did one of them in Vancouver BC
or uh Lower Mainland actually and that's
in Canada I did another one in the
Netherlands mainly in Amsterdam and then
I did another one in in Spain and most
of that was shot around where I live in
in
Barcelona but uh the deal is I got on
the internet well I got on uh YouTube
early on and um I was made it through
that's when it was really expensive to
produce videos and stuff and so there
wasn't a lot of information out there
and the production values were well much
different than they are today so what
happened was um anyway I got uh these
videos went all over the world I mean I
I mean I literally had millions and
millions of views of the these and then
I started making my own um I made about
300 videos I guess yeah I do garden
tours and yeah garden tours and you know
um backyard stuff I had uh like what
three or four different garden beds that
were full of full of different varieties
of of plants and stuff and yeah I just
go through and did that but I I started
about God five five decades ago
like in the 80s early 80s and that was
my public life this book here came out
in
1983 and then after
that yeah gosh I mean it's it's been a
heck of a long career it's been more
than 40 years yeah well 42 years now 42
years I've been at this same stuff you
know I've traveled a lot I've spent a
lot of time in Europe um well I moved
moved here I've been here like
officially like yeah about 25 years so
over a third of my life has been here
spent a lot of time in or a bit not tons
but a bit in in uh Latin
America uh South America
Mexico Australia I've been Australia
haven't haven't spent any time in a in
Africa was was in Japan like like that
one book of mine Japanese where the heck
ever it is yeah so anyway I've done done
a lot and then I had to deal a lot
with uh this subject of Cu see these two
books are actually pretty much the same
book one of them is is is uh about a
specific plant and the other ones about
all kinds of different plants but this
is uh this book sold very very well for
many years until till life changed in
the United States let's put it that way
in the uh late 990s yeah yeah so that's
a little bit of background like I say
I've been at this a long time I know a
lot of people um and probably more
people know me I used to used to wear a
disguise yeah I used to wear a disguise
let's see
that uh well there's a little car of
this one of me in Disguise
here where I wear
dreadlocks maybe no I guess there's oh
yeah there's another book here that I
was in a disguise but I I just don't
always oh yeah there's Russian books oh
yeah here's here's some more disguises
of me this is me in the the videos I
wore the disguise because well back then
times were definitely different but what
was the the deal was uh there was no no
internet so it was really easy I could I
could go across borders and everything
all I had to do was look differently and
um it sure sure helped a lot it helped a
heck of a lot now it doesn't help at all
they just run my name either way any
name I want to put out out there they
just run that yeah they know who I
am but anyway I I've certainly seen a
lot of change I've seen patterns happen
you know uh yeah but lots of change and
uh that's probably the biggest thing
I've seen is Chang and there's way more
information about indoor cultivation now
way more than there used to be and we
know a lot more about lights and in
general uh well yeah indoor lighting
definitely incredible you have done so
much good work over the years uh you
mentioned yeah it was 1983 was your
first book that was actually two years
before I was
born you've been at it for a very long
time and you really paved the way for
not just an access of the information
but also for other content creators to
put themselves out there your DVD is
still on Amazon today so somebody could
actually look that up and watch it and I
actually watched it about a handful of
years ago and I just brought back some
memories you know what I mean yeah yeah
you can probably find it you know High
Times is they're they're I don't know
what you'd call it if they're in
receivership or whatever it is but that
they're in big trouble with the Federal
Trade Commission and stuff so I don't
know really who who's in charge of of
the asset there that that would be a
property you know all of these they they
own the rights to to to these
videos um so I don't know what the story
is there uh but you can probably find
them on on the internet I know they
wouldn't let me put them on my site and
I kind of kind of pissed me off a bit
you know I
mean I certainly made them a lot of
money you oh I can imagine yeah I can
imagine how much but yeah your content
has definitely been exposed all over the
world and so many people have gotten
value and learned how to grow medicinal
plants because of you so it's really
awesome what you did and you're you're
still going which is really really
inspiring to see now on this podcast I
do have a variety of viewers I've got
folks that are beginners some folks that
are intermediate probably a smaller
amount of advanced Growers but I feel
like mostly it's beginners and
intermediate Growers so I'm going to go
into some questions here and really this
podcast is kind of to get information
about like Hands-On stuff
and some of the stuff there some of
these questions that I have which I've
given you in advance it's really goes
off of things that were in your book I I
would kind of want to get a little bit
deeper into or clarification so the
first one I want to jump into has to do
with the 24-hour light cycle so a lot of
folks are just giving when they're
growing indoors they're just giving 24
hours of straight light and no hours of
darkness my question for you is is that
optimal do plants need a rest period at
all yeah they do actually uh you can
hype them up like that but what happens
here here's the deal it's just it's it's
real similar to people or animals like a
horse for example you ride that horse
too too long he's lathered up he I mean
maybe he can keep going but he going to
fall over dead you know I mean he's not
going to work too hard same with the dog
same with the person you know you can
only take so much if it gets too hot
outside you can't handle it your body's
got to rest and recover and that's when
the growth and and everything takes
place well when you got when you got uh
you you push the heck out of everything
uh plants people animals uh what happens
is especially in in Plants this the
cells aren't as strong they got weaker
walls you know it's just like not as
strong it's just a little bit narrower
and so everything is just like not as
strong not as strong so
um that happens that that's the first
thing it doesn't have time to catch up
and grow and and metabolize everything
cuz see they they've been growing
outside for like millions of years right
millions of years and they're used to
this regular schedule and anybody that's
grown very much at all any kind of
plants knows that you know the last
thing you want to do is uproot that
plant or change that plant schedule
because it likes a regular schedule so
yeah yeah it definitely definitely needs
a uh a downtime and you're not going to
make it grow any faster you know I I
talk to a lot of people
like some guys are are mechanics you
know that are into growing indoors and
they liken everything to an internal
combustion engine and it's not the same
thing they just don't work the same way
you know you got a lot more variables
here and you got soft tissue uh you know
you don't you you you you you've got
water not rather than than oil you know
uh complete different
values so yeah it's it's important it's
important mainly the the thing
especially new people you want to follow
what mother Nature's doing and it works
works every time or
usually good to know yeah I personally
go after the 186 light cycle for the veg
stage to give some rest period but I do
know a handful of folks that U strive
for the 24 hours of of light and so I
was just curious on uh yeah because
there's a lot of people that say that
it's perfectly fine and that plants
don't need a rest period others say they
do so yeah I'm happy that you uh
revealed some stuff for us here yeah
science says
that that there's a lot of chemistry
that goes on during that time got it now
one of the things that's in your book
which I wanted to bring up was talking
about the sex of the plant and how
environmental factors can influence it
so for example it says something things
like increased nitrogen for more females
lower pottassium for females lower temps
for male plants lower humidity for male
plants more blue light for female plants
is all that stuff still accurate today
yes yeah very much so very much so and
those are for and that's that's for
regular plants and basically all you're
doing is making um uh stacking the the
deck in favor of of more female plants
so basically you just you make a nice
life for the plant and they're going to
make more female plants you know another
what another dious plant the Holly for
example that's another dious one you
know um what's another one kiwis kiwis
is another one you know those are
perennials yeah okay got it yeah I know
there are testing facilities you can
actually send out take a sample of it
when it's a Seedling and send it out for
DNA sex testing so I wasn't aware that
you could actually get it tested and
then they could say it's female but if
you're vegging it wrong right if you're
two low of temps for example it could
increase your chances of males just look
at the list here longer days 18 plus
hours of light says more males so that
was a pretty surprising thing to me I
fig I'd just touch base and figure out
if that was still true or not yeah yeah
it's really interesting because you know
with the sex there's a lot of especially
lower animals and snails and worms and
stuff they change sex back and forth you
know from male to female or they'll be
both sexes yeah it's uh and plants too
it's it's like that yeah higher higher
things they tend to have it sorted out a
little bit better but not
always that's interesting so another
thing it says in your book it says that
medicinal plants virtually stop growing
at 85° F which is 25° C now is that just
certain genetics or all genetics will
CO2 supplementation allow the plant to
grow at those higher temps boy I'll tell
you you know when when I wrote when I
wrote that I was mainly talking about
well talking about the indoor indoor
plants and stuff and with outdoor plants
man you can push those a lot a lot more
and on some stuff I I just was you know
uh I either I didn't qualify stuff or I
was just playing wrong you know on stuff
but you look at you look at an outdoor
plant uh one that's planted in the in
the earth that was planted early on and
it's got a real deep tap route that
thing that I mean it can take a lot of
abuse a heck of a lot of abuse and uh
it's got a heck of a good water source
already and it's getting from very deep
and uh it's got tons lots of foliage on
it that it can also use to shade the
other other plants and if it's got a a
like ton like a real good source of
water and it's got a good root system it
can it can take way higher temperatures
than that as far as like the upper end I
couldn't tell you for sure cuz you
mentioned varieties earlier or strains
earlier that makes a huge difference
because see there's plants I know I
remember my friend God so many people
are dead now Felix is gone a Swiss guy
lived in tachino in the South part Pera
but he he he was growing what do you
call a per per perana tenses yeah from
teino teino tenses yeah he named you
gave it a Latin name U purple from toino
but it could take a freeze you could it
could handle a freeze and it could take
a freeze down to about like 20 25 26°
fah for a couple of nights uh you go
past three nights and would have trouble
but that that's that's definitely a
genetic characteristic you know
um it's big and and the same same for
heat CU if you look
at if you look at leaves it's so simple
it's it's real physical you look at the
the leaves the indicia leaves you know
where they grow and they're cooler in
the mountains they're wide they're
they're broad broad Lea because that way
they they they need that to gather more
sunlight and everything but you look at
the plants that get that get really
really high sun in the tropics they have
a narrow Leaf narrow Leaf you know and
so that's so it'll dissipate heat faster
you know it's it's all a function so
they they um they acclimate to all of
these all of these things
so we just got to really learn a hell of
a lot more than we know of about this
plant and and other plants too as far as
their specific tolerances go because we
we just don't know and a lot of times
people try to get you to say well I want
a general statement that's true for
everybody it's like well no like I'm
it's like saying I will cure cancer okay
which one which cancer will you cure
there's many types of cancer and
you can't just say I'm going to make a
or you can't just make General
statements because we really just don't
know
enough yeah there are so many variables
when it comes to Growing these plants
and science hasn't uncovered everything
when it comes to it and that's I think
one of the things that makes it so
exciting to be in this space is that
more and more things are being uncovered
it seems like almost every day every
week there's some new information coming
out there's studies being done on
different aspects of the plant and it
just really makes things more exciting
and fun to uh to grow these plants in my
opinion yeah 100%
100% I'm pretty
excited you know I'm like I stay with
this uh with this uh well life I mean
I'm I'm like 7 71 years old right so
like old guy now and I just don't know
anything different you know and it's
kept me entertained all this time so
so I think I think uh there's going to
be a lot of other people like this too
it certainly kept you entertained
absolutely for sure I want to talk about
clones next particularly taking clones
what part of the plant to take it in
there are a lot of folks that say the
top of the plant's the best some say no
the middle of the plant is best others
say the bottom part of the plant is best
what's your take on that what's the best
part of the plant to take clones from
okay when I first when I when I wrote
wrote that
uh did that did that research there what
was it said uh said they they wanted a
lot of cellulos cellulos stiff
cellulose that's that and I read that
several times and then I remember I was
over in in a uh Austria
Austria and I did uh a bit a video
actually a bunch of videos over there at
flowery field cuz see over there they
can grow they can grow clones and sell
them but they're not supposed to flower
them so you know my my buddy U Alex uh
his last name broke wall yeah he has
flowery Fields well he's a lawyer and he
figured the law out and he's figured he
figured it out about 15 years ago so
he's been making like literally hundreds
and thousands of clones every year since
then yeah so he's been very very helpful
but but those guys uh they had some
basic rules and that was uh you have as
many budding sites as possible or as
many branches as possible and they were
taking all the Clones off the top of the
plants where where they basically have a
high concentration of of um nitrogen and
that's just exactly against everything
there that that I read that I that I
thought I believe but it works great and
I've seen so many people do it since
then um so it really doesn't matter
where you take the clones from as long
as the plants healthy and growing and
healthy I got to qualify that because a
lot of times they could have uh what do
you call that powdery mildew inside and
you can't tell uh they could have some
kind of a systemic problem so that
that's incredibly important to keep your
plants clean and keep them keep them uh
sterile uh super important and then
another thing cuz see Alex really
impressed me a lot uh he doesn't keep
his plant his mother plants for more
than 6 months and he says 6 months is
about the uh the end of a productive
life for the the females and they do
real well during that time and they also
he also grows them in um uh what do you
call those the uh containers that are
self pruning yeah air air air pruning
containers yeah root pruning
containers and U yeah and keeps them
growing fast cranked up all the time so
yeah yeah but like I said doesn't bother
me to admit I'm wrong you know I mean if
somebody got better information fine
let's see it yeah I personally had take
clones from taken from all parts of the
planet I haven't had a problem with
rooting so I'm glad that you uh that you
mentioned that sure and you know um
usually for well for for clones uh the
one of the big tricks for for taking
clones is you have that uh have that
soil or your substrate just a a few
degrees warmer than the than the uh the
air temperature and that'll usually
stick your your roots a little faster
that that in the air but there's lots of
information on that now that's good to
know that's question I have is also from
your book I think it's going to shock a
lot of folks one of the common things
that folks do is they'll do def some
sort of defoliation a pruning of leaves
prior to flipping to the flowering stage
now in your book as mentions avoid
pruning up to a month before inducing
flowering since pruning diffuses floral
hormones flowering is slowed down if
heavy prune before flowering Peak
maturation is delayed for a week or
longer and it takes a month or longer
for hor hormones to build up to
pre-pruning concentrations I thought
this was super super interesting cuz
this people go against this quite often
now first of all is this still true to
today yeah well I'll tell you I've just
there was one study one study that I
that I read uh that that promoted uh
pruning indoor plants that were grown
indoors and that it proved that they got
like I don't know 10 12% more Harvest I
believe it was and I didn't I I I went
to look up to study before I uh the
program before the podcast and I
couldn't find it but that's the only
study that I could find and a lot of the
other information that I've gotten has
been um uh oh hearsay information or
anecdotal information no side by side uh
study that's that's really fir worm and
so that's that's why I said that and
then for outdoor plants definitely don't
prune them I mean I don't see any any
benefit
whatsoever and especially gosh
well if you look at this as far as
pruning goes or well pruning uh removing
the shade leaves because that's what it
is pruning trimming um they have
different meanings but removing the
shade leaves which is is
specific uh those guys uh I I think a
lot of people have a small garden and
they get antsy and they just want to do
something so they take off the leaves
you know and then I also see a lot of
people do this uh lollipopping they call
it where they take up all the leaves off
the b or all the leaves off the bottom
of the plant and I think that's crazy
because you already paid for all of that
light to grow those plants and then then
you're going to go and cut those
branches off it doesn't make much sense
now if you've got some really weak
growth down there sure cut that Branch
off fine but taking it off as a matter
of fact no I'd be growing all the way
all the way down to the bottom you know
the bottom of
the the ground you know it just it it
makes more sense cuz you know it's it's
just a waste like I say the light's been
spent the fertilizer been spent
everything's been spent but mainly it's
the time so you've got like 3 weeks of
time that you're not getting any benefit
from if you've done anything you've
wasted that time um yeah so I I I I
don't know I mean I just can't I can't
find any good information I and and I'm
hoping that people here will will put
these studies down because normally what
happens is people go well I do it it
works for me like well so what it
doesn't tell me
anything uh other than it works for you
but you you haven't qualified anything
so you got to you got to make uh an
actual study on this stuff still have so
much anecdotal Bro Science that's
floating around people say hey it works
for me so it should work for
everybody yeah or or what kind of
variety was it you know what was the
temperatures and everything all of
that's really important you know
absolutely yeah but when it comes to the
lollipopping I know one of the main
reasons why folks do it is they claim
that that lower that lower area if buds
form there it's more of like an area
structure and removing that will help
keep the uh the top buds Focus its
energy on the top buds kind of forming
and it helps with density and stuff like
that now I know it's Cult of our
dependent stuff like that but I think
I'd give you a heads up on why some
people are doing that and then as far as
defoliation one of the main reasons why
folks like to do it is to avoid like if
you have a real thick canopy powdery
mildew right so if there's like real
thick lack of air flow in there that's
one of the main reason just to prevent
powder mildew from forming so if you got
throw that one out there in case anybody
listening wasn't aware but the there the
way to solve those problems is with the
genetic
superiority because 100% that's the way
you do it that's that works and then
also with the type of cultivar you're
growing you know you you you don't you
don't have such a tight tight compact
flowers uh cuz
those those will make the the the
powdery me do or they'll make the
buritis or they'll they'll make a a home
for for insects and and M you know
um yeah yeah I mean we we've got tons of
tons of uh work to do as far as as far
as breeding goes cuz you know I mean
another one as far as breeding goes is
the the branches aren't strong enough
for example to hold the flowers up the
flowers will pull the branches over or
or uh some some some plants or a lot of
plants don't have a big enough root
system for example uh that's really
important or um yeah there you know
disease and pest resistant is resistance
is super important as well
and as far and also uh being being
immune to like uh heat and cold problems
you know huge huge huge deals huge
understood now one of the things that
kind of relates to this a little bit was
talking about inducing flowering in
particular waiting until preflowers have
appeared so I've heard that you really
should wait to induce flowering or or
switch to that flowering light cycle
right wait until the profiles have
appeared it said that such stress you
know if you go against that could cause
strange growth plants May grow into
hermaphrodites so showing inter interex
traits what's your take on that yeah
100% 100% because you know like I say
the plants don't change that fast and
and when they've been growing the same
way for for millions of years they're
not going to deviate from that very fast
you know so they're going to they're
going to stay growing that way right uh
and two like I mentioned before the the
cell walls that get more uh thinner
narrower uh they're not as strong and so
there's all kinds of stuff that produce
produces stress and you know any kind of
and and that would be photo period
stress because you'd like we've got the
ability to make the the uh the plant
flower at the induce flowering uh really
quickly by you know giving it longer
nights
so you'd be stressing the plant out that
and and stress they don't like stress
and in general let's say you know pretty
much everybody's grown like well
radishes I mentioned radishes earlier
but radishes as soon as it gets hot or
as soon as they're stressed out at all
they always bolt they go to Sea every
time and you know like I say most people
have grown radishes so what happens any
time a plant gets
dressed they want to they try to
complete their life cycle and produce a
viable seed in general that's the first
thing they do so anytime you stress out
a plant any kind of a plant they're
going to try to complete their life
cycle
and they're going to want to make and
want to and and and try to get them
planted in the ground so they'll be
healthy next year and they'll procreate
for another year um it's just so
straightforward and simple you know and
people people that aren't really
experienced with gardening think they
can go in and change all of that well
it's the systems already been set up
before you got
here that makes sense now another thing
I've heard talking about the amount of
light given to the plant or really
Darkness we know that when you flipped a
flower it's really the darkness period
that's going to have the plant to
produce Floren of the flowering hormone
does giving the plant less than 12 hours
of light induce any flowering FAS and
does it reduce yield yeah it reduces
yield um because there's that thing that
Daily Light integral uh it's it you got
to have so many um hours of light of a
specific spectrum and
intensity uh every 24 hours for for it
to to to to receive all the light it
needs to flower properly so if it
doesn't get that so if you've got if
you've got uh say it well 10 hours say
it's it's 10 hours of light yes so
you've got to stuff 10 hours or 12 hours
of light into that 10 hours right um so
it's got you just got to give it more
intense light and technically that's
that's quite difficult to do so that's
that's number one and then let's see
less light less light and uh yeah so you
don't get as much light it's not as
bright yeah so your DLI goes down so you
you're definitely going to get less less
production guaranteed guaranteed and the
other part is we don't know this this is
my feeling and I believe that it goes
all the way here we
have doas what we use here in Spain it's
like the whole Spectrum or fan everybody
you have the whole fan so you can have a
plant over here that that is
autoflowering that that flowers after
like 3 weeks right okay so so that's one
side and then you can have a plant over
on the other side that says one of those
really long season sativ that really
doesn't ever quit flowering it it
continues so you've got this entire
Spectrum from one side to the other
complete complete um well yeah Spectrum
maybe yeah it doesn't mean light
spectrum it means spectrum
of different yeah it's they're they're
completely different at opposite ends of
the of of the scale so I'm believe that
in between here is you've got everything
else too so with this one here you can
get uh 24 hours of light and this one
here you can have like 10 hours of light
or uh and longer longer photo period or
longer light period and longer nights
but everything in between is the same so
what does that mean that means you're
going to get plants that flower with 12
hours of light with 14 hours of light
with 10 hours of light we don't know
which ones because we don't know enough
yet and we usually and and and usually
with these plants since it's an out
breeder we don't know we don't know
what's
um
uh we don't know if it's stable or not
first it's got to be stable and then you
can measure it well there's so much
unstable stuff out there that that we're
not really doing our s a service of
making more
varieties that aren't stable so it's
kind of we go around in circles and it's
going to take some big agricultural
company to sort that stuff out actually
I think scking on the topic of light UV
light want to get into that a little bit
can you talk to us about UV light and
how it impacts triome development yeah
the the UV the what the example best
example I have there's information there
probably better information than this
but in Switzerland see you you used to
be able to uh grow any plant you wanted
in Switzerland um about 20 years ago and
a friend of mine was growing uh these
plants at 900 M and he also had another
Gard at 300 M in elevation right so 300
M about 1,000 and 900 M about 3,000 so
it's quite quite a bit of difference or
4,000 so so what happened
is the ones at at uh 900 M those plants
had really heavy tricomes on it because
they get more UV light and they would
put and and uh then the tricomes are
there or these the capitate stock
tricomes are the ones we care about but
uh tricomes just means plant hair you
know so it could be any kind of a plant
hair and there's within that
classification there's four Bas well
there's quite a few different types but
anyway uh with more UV light there's
they make more troms to cover up cover
up the foliage and protect it better uh
it doesn't necessarily make more potent
pyoms it just makes more of them so as
far as increase in potency no I didn't
see that but the number of tricomes yeah
now here's the this is also real
interesting the the garden down below at
M
uh it was the same potency uh
approximately as the one up
above in relation to weight because of
uh well no let's see in relation to
weight what do I mean if you took one
plant and that would that would weigh uh
say 100 G and then at 300 M and then you
take another plant at 900 M and that
would weigh 80 grams well they still had
the same
potency the same level of
of stuff in it pretty straightforward
answer there yeah I've heard pretty much
the same stuff over the course of the
past several years yeah I mean it's
that's what I found so far too and so we
all
agree that's
good I want to get into something a
little bit more controversial next the
flushing plants or soil prior to harvest
should Growers flush their plants or or
soil prior to harvest if so what are the
benefits okay the the number one is the
term cuz what they would actually be
doing they're not flushing the plant
they're actually leeching the soil
leeching the soil flushing is a
different term uh and usually people use
that term flushing and I made this
mistake until I was corrected uh so um
now it doesn't make any difference
whatsoever you can plant you can grow
right fertilize right up to the end what
what the the deal is
see now this is this is where my
perspective comes in this is a good part
about being an old guy cuz see when this
industry grew the the real money there
was there was real money in fertilizer
that's where the money was at because
people people needed it over and over
and then they could keep buying it over
and over well as we all know most of
what you find in fertilizer is water so
they take a little bit and and to make
to make a dollar like well say if we use
a dollar for example make a dollars
worth of
fertilizer uh that you would buy retail
it cost you about uh two to three
pennies to make that so you've got a
really a big a big uh margin there so
that's why everybody seemed to be an
expert in
fertilizers and because that's where the
only place to make any money at it and
that you couldn't make any money at
lights because they were made by big
companies and and you know or or the
other stuff you could buy all of that
stuff at the nursery but the fertilizers
if you had your special fertilizer well
then you could uh uh grow the best
plants the biggest plants so everybody
was a an expert well now you go into a
nursery for example any plant just any
kind of a plant nursery you know and um
you look and see you go to the
fertilizer section and you see there' be
about like 20 maybe 30 different
fertilizers
for I don't know two 300 maybe 500
different types of plants you got 20
kinds of a fertilizers for 500 different
kinds of plants but you got this plant
the one that we've been dealing with
this this plant here and what do we have
we have we
have one plant and like 500 kind of
fertilizers for it you know something's
backwards something's backwards well
it's called it's money money is the
thing that's made the big difference so
what they've done is and then they they
they make that uh the hydroponic
fertilizers they make all kinds of
different mixes with them and stuff well
that's just to take people's money out
of their pocket because I I never used
all that stuff and it's worked fine for
me um yeah so that's that's what I'd be
thinking out about more than anything
else I don't have any good statistics
here but you know I used to be I was a
garden Rider in in America you know like
a garden well Garden Riders of America
we had an association a National
Association um yeah and uh one of the
things that they that we learned there
was uh
see people put home gardeners home
gardeners put about 10 times more
fertilizer and chemicals on their
Gardens than they need to you know and
the same goes with indoor Growers too
they they they put a lot more stuff on
there than they need to and it's a real
good living and stuff but you a lot of
that stuff you just don't need you don't
need uh you know uh they got you loaded
up so heavily on on all the
fertilizers um I I wonder I mean you
know it's not a real I'm not going to be
real popular with the with a few people
in the
industry but man I mean all those
fertilizer guys made tons of money I
mean I made serious money and I never I
mean some guys had like seven different
products you'd put in got a little pot
here you got seven different products
you put in there that's a lot you I
don't I don't understand that now you
know and then the farmers I mean you
just need a little bit of fritted tra
Trace elements you know the fritted
trace elements those are the ones that
it means like claw so it it hooks it
hooks onto the the other elements and it
stays with them so um so it's
immediately available and then uh that
then your primary nutrients and that's
that's about it uh secondary ones and
they mix sulfur with everything every I
mean it's just like hooked onto sulfur
molecules hooked onto everything it
seems so you don't need any sulfur
because it's already there um yeah yeah
but if anything I mean I would for
people I would suggest that they get a
soil test you want to do something get a
soil test that's the best thing to do
because then you find out what you need
um you know and also with the organic
stuff people carry that over uh go
overboard on that I know I certainly did
in the first few years when I was
organic G gardening
uh gardening organically I had uh I had
I don't know maybe 10% organic matter in
the soil and you know five is a
lot um yeah but it it causes more
trouble than it's worth you know but
yeah I mean you go to a soil scientists
and they will always call it mineral
soil because it's mainly minerals you
know those guys are really well
educated and I'd listen to
them yeah it could be super helpful to
get that soil test and even talking to
an expert like I talked to Bryant Mason
the soil doctor I'm not sure if you know
who he is or not but he's excellent very
knowledgeable and he um does Consulting
he's a crop adviser so he can take your
soil test and then kind of give you
information on what you need to add into
it I think it's a great way to go about
it for sure I I do think you can overdo
it as well like you had mentioned like
you had done I've overdone it as well
when it comes to the organ organic side
of thing so it is possible I think
that's a misconception out there is
people say that oh if you're growing
with or organic inputs or all natural
inputs the plant's just going to uptake
what it wants when it wants so there's
no harm in putting too much which is
which we know now is uh is definitely
not true so no not at all I mean they
can you can you
can oh like hot manures for example
there's all kinds of stuff you can burn
with uh you look at that and it's
expensive too you know the the bat guano
that's really expensive and you
know you know how hard it is to chase
those little bats around have them poop
in a
bag it's a tough job man T job those
guys should get paid a lot
yeah that's funny I want to shift over
to drying I wanted to get your input on
what do you feel is the optimal drying
conditions and drying time oh man see
there you go uh there's all these
different variables uh first off it
depends on how the pl plants harvested
how big the plant is do you have do you
have the main stem is the main stem
there or is there going to be smaller
stems um you know
so say for example if you harvest
Harvest a plant and
um uh you you cut all the flowers off
the stems and then the leaves off the
off of the
flowers uh then you've just got flower
buds there well those can be put in uh
on on one of those uh little like dry
screens or something you know they have
those expandable net net shelves that
that open up and you've got uh usually
it's two or 3 feet across I think I had
I had one that was 4T across that was
really big it would hold a lot yeah but
um yeah you can you can dry them a lot
faster in there uh than than with a a
big plant a big uh uh plant where you
hold the the entire plant and keep the
stems because see there's there's
different um different levels of of
moisture see you've got a stem this big
well that's going to hold more moisture
than a stem this big you know they're
just different sizes so this has more
moisture than this one and then the leaf
that's real narrow or real thin uh will
will dissipate much quicker too so the
idea is to equalize everything out you
want to get you want to get out all of
those all the the pigments and stuff and
um God there's tons of tons of stuff in
there that makes it taste green or or
ammonia like um
but the dry the drawing volatized all of
that or just basically it it it
dissipates into the air uh so you can
get rid rid of all of that so it depends
on what you want you can either keep the
leaves on or keep or take the leaves off
right at first when it's Supple usually
smaller Growers will do that and then
big Growers usually
wait and they'll dry the whole branches
the whole plant first or parts of the
plant and then remove the leaves
afterwards it seems to be more efficient
that way um and then I'll tell you I
just got
these um I just got these things here
they're from uh
seedsman and there's apparently uh TPL
loock it's called TPL loock
yeah uh but it's uh 58 to 62%
humidity and the ones I've seen have
been well they go from 55 to to 60 65
but it depends this is this is
approximately how much humidity here uh
the way I do or or that you want your
plant have what I do is I did um uh
I I measured it uh what the flower
weighs when it's wet and then when it's
when it's dissipated 3/4 of its of its
moisture that'll be uh well say if it
weighs uh 10 10 gam when it's dry when
it's wet it would weigh uh 2 G and a
half when it's dry and that would put it
at a
approximately 70% moisture 60% moisture
in that range after that then you're
going to have to to check yourself my
rule of thumb the one I came up with
years ago is like when you snap the stem
if the stem actually snaps then it's dry
or if it's uh dry enough but you know uh
if it's dry enough to
burn um but I'll I tell you if you can
measure the uh the uh humidity or well
the moisture within the within the
flow
it's perfect perfect um to do it that
way if you can if you can measure that
you're you're best off um and then you
come down to the curing and the curing
I'm kind of like rambling on here the
the curing what you do is uh you want to
even out the moisture cuz you had the
the the real thin leaf and then the
thick stem so they'll hold different
moisture at different rates well you
want to balance that out and what what
curing will do is it it evens those
things those two moistures out hope that
was a r answer I kind of found found
myself rambling a little that's all
right I appreciate your Insight on that
one we have reached the hour mark here
so we're going to wrap things up can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and is there anything upcoming in the
future that you want to talk about yeah
let's see we got a lot of stuff I got a
lot of stuff going on uh you can go to p
j r
g- cantes c r v n tes.com for servantes
and you see this mug right here um yeah
and you can look up all kinds of history
about me huh
and there's lots of garden information
tons of garden information and then you
can go to that site and you can also
pick up this book here for free in 11
different languages and it's just like
600 Pages you know A4 format in Europe
or uh 8 1 12 by 11 in in uh the United
States and then let's see next month
right at a month from now is going to be
spannabis and spannabis in barcelon
and I've been talking to people and
making all kinds of plans and stuff uh
but that's that's a real big Fair it
used to be the biggest one in the world
uh but now Las Vegas is bigger the Las
Vegas fair and also the German Fair
um uh Mary Jane which is in Berlin and
that's in June in middle of June uh but
that that fair is huge it was is way
bigger than the fair we have here in
Barcelona and then also I'll be going to
uh haven't haven't decided for sure but
I probably will go up there to uh
Amsterdam to uh Green Tech and that is
really a good fair that is the biggest
um Horticultural fair in the world and
we have our own section there people
like us we have our own section you know
and before they used to kick us out all
the time but
now we can hold our heads up high I'm
very happy about that awesome so lots of
exciting stuff upcoming there I'll
definitely have a link to Jorge's
YouTube channel down in the YouTube
description section below so you can
easily access his Channel or thanks so
much for coming on this podcast this was
great a lot of good Insight here it's
really an honor to have you on here like
I mentioned I picked up your book almost
15 years ago now and I've learned so
much from you over the years so I just
want to thank you for all your
contributions over the years looking
forward to seeing what you have coming
out in the future and before I end this
I want to give a thank you to the folks
that support on patreon
patreon.com grow the folks being
scrolled on the screen right now in the
producers tier special thanks to you you
are one of the ones that uh keep this
podcast going so thank you so much or
hey we will leave it at that thanks
again for coming on to the podcast and
hope you enjoy the rest of your day hey
for sure for sure it's um late in the
day now so I'm happy all right have a
good night everyone take care I'll catch
you in the next episode