what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it you
know watch a mattress Channel this is
the gross star a 600 watt cob LED grow
light I purchased this grow light off of
Amazon at a discount and in this video I
am going to unbox the unit and also test
the power output first thing out of the
box is the user manual has a ton of
information about the grow life it has
some various safety information usage
suggestions specifications about the
light and warranty terms next is a wire
hanging kit one rope ratchet hanger a
power cord which is 6 feet in length 3
reflector cups which go over the three
cob LEDs the cob LEDs on this grow light
our bridge Lux and epaulettes and they
are 200 watts each I won't be going over
all of the features on this LED grow
light I will provide a link in the
description section below is so you can
learn more for the part tests I'm going
to use the apogee
MQ 500 power meter this meter measures
from 389 nanometers to 692 nanometers
plus or minus 5 nanometers and the
measurements are taken in ppfd I say
this in every video but this is just to
give you a general idea of what the
power output is it's not going to be a
hundred percent accurate
the reflective walls in the grow tent
could increase the numbers according to
the listing for this LED girl light it
has a core coverage of 3.9 feet by 5.8
feet which must be wrong this girl light
is a better fit for a 2 foot by 4 foot
grow space and I place this grow light
in a 2 foot by 4 foot grow Tim I'll be
taking measurements at 12 inches away 18
inches away and 24 inches away just like
all the other part test videos I do I
will let the measurements do the talking
[Music]
what do you think about these
measurements let me know in the comments
section below again I have provided a
link to this grow light in the
description section below and I'll leave
it at that thank you so much for
watching and until next time peace
[Music]