coming up on garden talk you're going to
leave that plant matter on there to help
give the plant a little moisture and
enhance or extend that dry period it's
the exact same thing with trying to
remove the dirt from your hands you
can't just use water you have to use
soap the baking soda and the lemon juice
work together as an agent to remove that
kind of grime without using the word
soap there was no other way to harvest
your herb it was wait for that stem to
snap it took me two harvests to realize
that is way too late if you've lost the
moisture in the stem
the buds are done in the first two weeks
of cure does this much to its smoke
ability but giving it a month
i think does that to its smoke ability
two weeks minimum but a month cure and
you're laughing you're laughing
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 73. in this
episode i interview pigeons420 i'm sure
many of you recognize him as he was on
episode two of this garden talk podcast
this time around we're going to get into
a handful of topics we're going to talk
about harvesting bud washing drying
trimming and curing thanks to all of you
who support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to
patreon.com mr growit before we get into
it i want to acknowledge that one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring zero
costs for information about gardening
all plants to the general public that
being said i'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible thanks to spider
farmer for being a sponsor a new grow
like they released here in 2022 is the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co2 in your
grow space and really want to maximize
the light intensity it has a 10 bar
design for an even light spread pulls 1
000 watts from the wall and comes in at
2.9 micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is 4 feet by 4
feet or five feet by five feet use
discount code mr growth 5 to save on all
spider farmer products and i'll leave a
link in the video description section
below shout out to gorilla grow 10 for
sponsoring this episode they have two
different size clone tents 18 inches and
24 inches the 18 inch clone tent is
designed to fit standard size seedling
trays the 24 inch tent which is the one
that they sent me is designed to fit the
super cloner 50 or two standard size
seedling trays they also have a clone
tent fan and filter which is designed to
fit perfectly in the rooftop micro mesh
compartment of both the 18 inch and 24
inch tents check out their website at
growstrongindustries.com and use
discount code mr growit for 15 off ac
infiniti is sponsoring this episode
their clip-on oscillating fan is now
released i've been using their six-inch
version for over six months now and i
absolutely love it it's easy to clip on
the side of my grow tent and it has 10
different speeds which makes it easy to
control air circulation they do also
have non-oscillating versions of these
clip-on fans these fans are currently in
high demand when they sell out of the
fans which i expect them too often you
can pre-order them for the next release
you can also use discount code mr growit
if you're buying off their website ec
infiniti.com that discount code works
for all ac infinity items or discount
code mr growit15 if you're buying off
amazon
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
pigeons420 how you doing today
hey i'm doing well man thanks for having
me how are you doing pretty good man
thanks for coming on you've actually
been on my garden talk podcast before
you're on episode number two and we
talked all about training plants
and uh for the record
it is the most viewed or most viewed our
most watched garden talk episode as of
right now 303 000 views on youtube alone
so just monstrous result off of that now
you're back again
and we're going to get into harvesting
bud washing drying and curing so i'm
excited for this one sweet i'm excited
yeah i uh i got famous off that first
video man i really appreciate it thanks
for uh making the name pigeons
yeah that was definitely good when we
talked about training plants and there
was just so many people that commented
so they got so much value from it and uh
you really
revealed your techniques and tips and
you do a great job explaining things in
a more beginner friendly manner can you
introduce yourself for those that didn't
catch the first episode we did together
yeah yeah uh you know what um i'm a
father i'm a husband i'm a volunteer uh
i'm a countryman and uh i make content
online and uh
it's uh it's been it's been a journey to
say nonetheless uh nonetheless um it's
uh it's had some peaks in valleys but
over the last say 12
months plus uh it's taken some
incredible uh some incredible turns you
know we've got the podcast our our fts
podcast and uh that's been really eye
opening we've met some really incredible
people on that uh on that podcast who've
really like opened up my mind and my my
perspectives on on growing this this
plant
and uh it it's allowed me to you know
kind of double down on my own processes
and make question some of my techniques
but uh nonetheless you know i'm i'm on
twitch i do uh i do gaming content kind
of lifestyle content over there and uh
you know doubling down on my social
media presence hope to hit a hundred
thousand subs maybe perhaps by the next
time someone sees this i'm already there
um but uh yeah and it's been it's been
an incredible journey to say the least
but uh still grinding doubling down on
uh on just being a a full-time content
creator awesome sweet
so let's get into let's start with
harvesting
um so the first question i have for you
is how do you determine when to harvest
your plants there's so many different
ways to go about it right i know some
people look at the trichomes some people
will look at the actual pistols of the
plant because maybe they don't have a
microscope to look at the trichomes some
will just look at the plants and see if
the leaves are fading you know the plant
we're talking about the medicinal plant
is an annual plant so no matter how much
nutrients you feed it eventually it's
going to fade how do you go about
determining when to harvest your plants
uh you know it's a great question i i
think if if anyone's been following me
for a minute they they know that i'm not
a scientific man
i'm really a hands-on kind of guy and
the number one factor that comes to
harvest is it's going to come down to
your time you know um often i find that
i would love to be able to harvest a
plant when it's when it's at its optimal
when those trichomes are at their most
efficient they're like that i prefer a
cloudy trichome you know when that fade
is really starting to take on when you
notice that it's taking less water it's
taking less nutrients um all great signs
but you know often enough i kind of get
caught up with life and and
work and and family
and next thing you know i'm either
harvesting it too early harvesting it a
little bit too late um speeding up the
process taking some corners um but but
if i was to have the optimal optimal
harvest time it would be as i mentioned
you know i'm looking for less intake on
water i'm looking for that plant to show
me that it's ready for ready for harvest
and typically it's going to come down to
the water consumption the the trichome
colors that that majority of milky
trichomes you're going to see a slight
hinge of that that amber and you're
going to see a little bit of a immature
clear trichome as well but all of those
things coming together lets me know that
it's going to be it's going to be right
for harvest and i'm looking through a
microscope to get a good close look
probably should ask this first but do
you flush your plants very common
technique i know you're a precision
grower with synthetic nutrients so
you're not really doing the organic side
of things a common technique is to flush
your plants or
leech your plants prior to harvesting
whether that be seven days prior to
harvesting two weeks prior to harvesting
i know some people go longer than that
i've seen upwards of 21 days to where
they're just cutting off nutrients and
just feeding plain water for the rest of
the grow or some people running gallons
of water through the medium in order to
remove as much of those nutrients as
possible and then allowing the plant to
fade after that do you do any type of
flushing before you harvest your plant
um well
i wouldn't say before i think it's kind
of a technical term but i wouldn't say i
i think flushing is actually the
beginning of harvest um now yeah i do i
do flush because i personally personally
believe that you should maximize every
moment every day that you get in the
garden you should be maximizing that in
terms of giving it as much food as
possible trying to give it as much light
as it can handle until that very last
moment and that's where i find flushing
is the most effective is when you are
pushing the limits so i like to most
plant most flowers are going until about
week nine
i'm pushing right till week nine when i
see that it's ready to harvest boom
that's when it's a nice hard stop of
nutrients and that's when i'm trying to
back down on those so it's
it's typically a flush like i know it is
a flush not a leech so it's you know uh
in three times of the water the amount
of the pot is kind of the rule of thumb
and that that's typically going to last
about seven days and not a whole lot
longer than well you know seven to ten
it's hard to write anything down in
stone but seven between seven and ten
days i can get two good heavy water
flushes in that time and then it's gonna
it's gonna get to a dried out state
enough where it's
it's harvestable gotcha so you're
flushing your plants how do you go about
harvesting what's your process
well you know the last few harvests that
i've had i've actually changed up my
method i because of the podcast you know
i've been opened up to the idea of not
only tent growing but
growing via a screen as well now i don't
want to use the actual term for
censorship reasons um but you know
growing via a screen i find it really
maximizes space maximizes plant um
optimize or
size
and that has introduced new methods for
me you know uh typically i've always on
a wet trim
chop the plant
trim it dry it and away it go
now i decided to do a full plant dry
where i would try to keep the plant
intact as much as i could trim it at its
base hang it upside down and then let it
dry
i found that i got a few more days out
of the dry but
not much not much i got a few extra days
but not not a whole lot so but but again
the few extra days is uh is a is a
breaking point and and one in which i
like it's a sale i'll take that extra
days every day so um i did see a
difference there but typically right
after the right after i find she's ready
to go she's gonna get uh chopped hung in
a tent um in in approximately
uh you know 60 degrees freedom units 65
degrees freedom units um and then i'm
going to push around the humidity is
going to sit around that 60 percent as
well uh it's difficult being in the
corner of the basement where i'm at is
to like
heavily maintain that
so that's a plus minus
but generally speaking cool dark
and not too damp
anything over 70 and you're kind of
going to battle that that moisture that
mold issue
um so definitely kind of kind of push in
that 70 percent but really you know
giving it that buffer so i think 60 is a
good good humidity number and that that
lasted for about seven days this time
okay and you mentioned that you
prefer to cut the plant at the base so
at the stalk and hang the plant whole i
think you brought up a great point i
personally live in a desert climate it's
very very dry here i'm looking at my
humidity monitor it's at 24
so that's extremely low compared to
other parts uh you know other climates
out there so i do the same thing to
where i'm cutting at the base
allowing the plant to be fully intact
all the branches the the buds are still
intact to that even the leaves are kind
of overlapping some of the buds and it
retains moisture a little bit better
than it would be to you know trim off
the leaves for example cut individual
branches and hang them individually that
would lead to a more faster dry and i'm
always battling with low humidity i'm
always battling a proper dry
time which we're going to get into
drying in a little bit but just wanted
to emphasize that is that the
cutting it at the base versus cutting
individual branches you can definitely
conserve that moisture and increase the
dry time a little bit if you need to if
that's beneficial for your climate for
example so i'm glad you mentioned that
one the more plant matter that's on
there that's alive and not dead and
crusty and and and you know wilted
you're gonna leave that plant matter on
there to help
give the plant a little moisture and
enhance or extend that dry period so i
believe the same concept can be applied
to doing a dry versus a wet trim if i if
i keep the trim until the dry i've
maximized the plant material on the
plant therefore giving myself a little
more of a of a
a head start or a little more advantage
when it comes to the end dried product
you know i want more time that's what i
want more time so if i dry trim
it's it's it's gotten the most amount of
time out of that so i prefer a dry trim
and not to mention you can get a little
more tighter to the buds
drying trimming you know it's it's a lot
easier you can you literally i barely
even feel like you cut you just kind of
like slide the trimmers along the buds
and like all those fan leaves can kind
of just kind of come off all in their
own
so yeah it's a lot easier i feel i find
i'm sure there's going to be a lot of
debate in the comments section about wet
trim versus dry trim and people like
what
true wet trim is easier what are you
talking about you're crazy so i think it
definitely comes down to personal
preference on that one always now
after you cut the plant down at the base
one of the things you're known for
you're very known for you had one of the
top viewed videos of all time on youtube
which was bud washing
can you talk to us about what is bud
washing and why do it
yeah it's crazy because i get i get
afforded the guy that buzz washes his
butt like it's like it was my idea but
it wasn't it wasn't my idea i i'm glad
to take all the the credit for it uh but
no it was actually uh there was a there
was a guy i followed by the name of doc
buds way back when i was in the forum
days when i was before i was vlogging
and when i was blogging
and um you know he i i don't even know
if he can take credit for it um you know
he he's the one that introduced me to it
but essentially
um
i i'm one of the first ones that put a
video of it on youtube that's really
what it came down to
and
it's it's essentially a process of of
handling your flour like it's no
different than a tomato or a potato or
an onion you know you wash it when you
get it out of the ground you know it's
dirty um and and so
you know i i that same concepts applied
to to harvesting your plants uh
up until as of just a couple harvests
ago i washed every single harvest that i
had
um and you know you go you do so by
combining three buckets typically it's
five gallon pails
one of those pails has a cup of baking
soda and a cup of
lemon juice in it the other two are just
plain room temperature water and you you
go about you know you chop your plants
immediately after harvest you chop your
buds into you know arm size so they can
fit in a bucket and yeah you dunk it in
the the lemon juice and the the baking
soda water first and you're giving it a
good swirl because you are trying to er
eliminate the the dust the hair the
grime the bugs that get that are
inherently getting on your plant
and and so you would then
let it dry or not dry but drip dry a
little bit over the first bucket apply
it to the second bucket
again getting now you're trying to get
off the the mixture of both the baking
soda and the lemon juice um and then you
you you let that drip dry and and again
in the third bucket to do the same thing
to kind of just rinse rinse the uh the
mixture off um the biggest concern from
people is well aren't you wiping off
trichomes aren't you washing off
trichomes and the reality is yeah of
course you are uh there are some dead
and degraded trichomes that are present
on those plants there always will be
from from from the beginning you know
trichomes are present on plants almost
immediately uh from from germination
from seed
and almost all the way through veg
you are going to have trichomes those
trichomes although single cell trichomes
are going to degrade over the course of
the flower period those are going to be
dead they have no effect they have
they've degraded past any point of you
know cbn or cbd or
any kind of
after product of thc and so
when you do the rinse those are going to
fall off generally speaking when you
hang them to dry and and and and they
bang about and they they they
go through the process they're losing
trichomes every stage of the way uh
that's a reality um
so but did it have a negative impact on
the plants itself and the trichomes the
potency absolutely not absolutely not i
i smoked some incredible herb
that was washed you know
the the there is no in my opinion
there's no argument to whether it
diminishes the potency
but
what opened my eyes in terms of whether
or not everybody whether it was required
for every single harvest was performing
my last couple harvests i did it via
tent i have great circulation via my ac
infinities um i've got a a quality lung
room and that's the room in which both
my tents reside where it's it's sealed
and the environments within are sealed
it's it's a room within a room you know
it's like
i i noticed that there wasn't as much of
a need i i
to wash your buds there was no there was
minimally minimal hair there was hair
don't i'm not saying that it wasn't it
was just completely sterile there was
hair but i didn't see the amount that i
was seeing before
i i was growing in a tent so i whether
or not
i one should wash every harvest or not
that's up to them i think it comes down
to personal preference i'm not gonna be
the guy that tells you that you should
or shouldn't i did sit on on on a
pedestal and say that i wouldn't smoke
anyone else's because they didn't wash
it
um i i'll backtrack those statements
however i want to know that the stuff
that i ingest is going to be uh is going
to be clean regardless i want to know
that it doesn't come in contact with
pesticides i want to know that it was
grown in a sterile environment i want to
know that it's free from disease all
these things and i think that it being
clean
is just a is another variable and it's a
valid one but it doesn't need to be
applied to everybody's
stash
i don't think a lot of people know that
tricoms as they go to different stages
right clear cloudy amber they actually
get to the point where they become more
brittle and actually snap off so
actually fall off so like you mentioned
those are the ones that you're washing
off right now
i gotta challenge you on this one for
the folks that prefer more amber maybe
they prefer like 30 amber for example or
more
would you say that
they shouldn't bud wash because there's
more jeopardy of them removing those
trichomes with the cbn for example you
know um i i would i would have to know
what the integrity of those amber
trichomes really are and at what point
do they degrade to a point where they're
breaking but again
you know
i don't know man i'm not a science guy
the thing is is that it's like you want
to have clean product if if you're if
you're growing in a in an area that
you're not confident
is producing sterile clean product wash
it don't don't question it don't
question it just be it should be clean
that's what that's my again that's
that's in my own opinion but um if
you're on the fence do you think you're
growing in a in a state that's clean you
you prefer that cbn you want those those
amber trichomes we'll just grow in a
tent grow in a tent with good air
circulation keep your hands out of there
don't drool all over your plants and
you're gonna be okay
going back to the first bucket you
talked about you talked about three
different buckets the first one has
creekman from wrong it's baking soda and
lemon juice
what exactly is the point of that
wouldn't just plain water all the way
through be okay or essentially trichomes
are water soluble it's like oil so you
you you're not going to lose anything
it's going to repel a lot of the water
so the water alone isn't going to get in
and remove anything it's going to just
be pushed away by the the oils if you
will
the now i'm reaching for this one but
it's the the baking soda is a natural
soaping agent
where it's going to sudden it's going to
get into the the crevices to remove the
hair the lemon juice juice is a natural
antiseptic which is then going to clean
and it's going to it's going to help
remove and rinse the grime away so
working together
it's it's a pair that that that works to
just work as like a soap if you will and
i hate the reason i'm hesitating here is
because i know people like to grab your
words so if i say soap they're gonna
they're gonna that's exactly it's what's
happening with soap it's the exact same
thing with trying to remove the dirt
from your hands you can't just use water
you have to use soap the baking soda and
the lemon juice work together as an
agent to remove that kind of grime
without using the word soap but that's
it that's it okay and then when you dunk
those branches into the water you
mentioned you got to give it a good
swirl
can you put them on time to it are you
talking five seconds worth of it are you
talking 10 seconds 20 seconds what how
long yeah seven seconds seven seconds in
you're swirling just trying to get in
you can you know
and then you're out so five seconds
you're out you're in it's yeah you're
not much more in there you again you
you're not losing anything but you're
not trying to abuse the plant either
which which
could definitely happen okay so five
seconds up to seven seconds is that is
that pretty easy bucket or is that for
the first bucket with the okay for each
bucket gotcha yep because you want it
you want a thorough rinse
and now is this gonna make the drying
time longer no no it doesn't it doesn't
make it longer at all in fact um if
there's anything i've noticed and then
this is where you know it's it every
harvest is a little different
some will argue that it's it has sped up
their drying um i haven't experienced
that per se
but i think it comes down really to your
environment um i always have a hard time
getting to five days dry it's typically
three
three to five days and it's dry
i was finding the exact same thing on
harvests where i wasn't
washing it's three to five days that's
kind of an unwritten rule and it sucks
it's way too fast but now that i'm
drying in a tent we can get to this
later it's it's definitely changed that
that time but no it does not enhance the
dry okay i actually found the same exact
thing i was just curious on on your
findings there i bud washed
honestly it's only been about two or
three plants and uh you know i did the
same exact method i used where i had the
multiple buckets
swirled it in i probably swirled in it
for about the same amount of time that
you mentioned and then hang in those
individual branches i found it was was
about the same dry time so interesting
to hear that you had the same findings
there and i think like kind of reverting
back to the cut the the trimming process
i think a lot of that had to do with the
fact that we're trimming each and every
branch you know and that's inherently
that's going to speed up the dry
significantly so if you if you people
have asked ball could you wash the whole
plant and it's like well if you're gonna
if you're gonna make a bucket big enough
you know but then you're wasting you're
wasting water you're wasting time
filling a bathtub to wash a plant i
don't think it's necessary but yeah i
think a lot of that had to do with the
trimming it's so small okay so if you
you've washed your buds then now they're
ready for drying how is your drying area
set up it's it's almost exactly like the
growing setup was um minus the light you
know i've still got the air circuit well
okay okay let me let me walk that back a
little bit there's a lot less wind
circulation that's for sure um in my
flowering tent there is a lot of wind i
don't think honestly you could light a
lighter
in in my flowering tent without it kind
of like flickering out you know because
i'm trying to move so much air i'm
trying to do the opposite of that when
i'm start trying to dry you know there's
no fans on uh except for
the the
my uh
i just called my c infinity my inline
people in my comments section were
saying that i didn't need to have that
on as well
but being in the basement being at 60
percent moisture i've got an active
humid
humidifier in there it
does not make sense to me to not
circulate that air in there in some form
or fashion sealing it off for two weeks
just seems like
just just a calling card for moisture
and mold and taking all that work and
just getting rid of it so so i i think
you know i did it right again i'm very
inexperienced when it comes to tent
growing i've always grown in a room
that's like eight by ten feet by eight
feet high you know very large room so
being in a four by four space i've
learned a lot and
both through experiment and failure so
this time i do believe that i went about
it correctly but i did keep one small
fan on at the very bottom of the tent
um
i don't think that was necessary i think
i should have just left the ac infinity
on and nothing else but
um yeah humidity in the tent was set at
about 60 percent um it fluctuated plus
minus about six i saw 66 and i saw about
54 50
so it did fluctuate it's very tough to
maintain
um i'm only running a small um
humidifier that holds maybe a little
less than a gallon maybe a gallon
and it's a real pain in the butt trying
to you know you gotta you gotta open
that tent up every 24 hours to fill that
humidifier
and it just it's plus minus and and it's
really unfortunate and that's as close
as i've been to a perfect dry
ever and it was still plus minus six to
ten humidity and and temperature your
dry setup sounds very similar to mine
like i mentioned earlier in the episode
i live in a very dry climate so i'm
always battling trying to increase the
humidity not only in my flower room and
stuff but drying as well so primarily i
dry in a grow tent i've tried in open
rooms before i drive in bathrooms before
because that was all that was available
kind of gross when you think about all
the germs and bacteria that might be
floating around in that bathroom but
that's besides the point
but normally it would be in a grow tent
very similar i've got a humidifier at
the bottom of the tent
blowing up towards not towards the
plants i usually blow it up towards the
side of the grow tent and then i have a
oscillating fan on the bottom of the
tent now the oscillating fan isn't
blowing air directly onto the buds i
found that it dries it out a lot quicker
when it's flowing directly on the buds
but allowing the
humidifier to blow that humidity against
the wall and a combination of having the
oscillating fan there it does
sufficiently add the flow around the
drying tent and then i also have the top
ventilation sock open
on the drying tent now i don't have an
inline fan hooked up to mine i just
basically have that oscillating fan
going and then
air is just naturally come flowing out
through the top now sometimes what i'll
do is i'll crack that grow tent saw the
airflow that way as well if needed
every 24 hours i'm going in there and
checking to make sure that i'm
exchanging the air entirely if there's
any sort of musky smell
i will uh i'll definitely take action
then you know air it out
maybe i'll have to lower the
humidity that's coming out of the
humidifier and then i also have a
temperature humidity monitor i use the
sensor push monitor and actually hang
that right down with the plants and so
it'll be at the level where the buds are
and i get alerts to my smartphone so
anytime the humidity is off anytime the
temperature is off
then i will be able to take action i
don't do anything in order to
increase the temperature or decrease the
temperature
naturally room temperature for me i'm
usually about 65 70 degrees fahrenheit
and that's usually fine i know some
people really like to go lower than that
you know 60 degrees fahrenheit for
example it's tough for me to get that
low without adding in
a air conditioner or running the central
air in my house which of course costs
money and stuff so i think there's kind
of a balancing act in there do you have
to add in any sort of cooling or i'll
say it heating as well
yeah heating yeah great canadian
argument uh yeah yeah i'm in the
basement and it's it's naturally pretty
chilly i i can't transition into freedom
units but i'm going to say that like it
just
like on average it's probably about
low 60s high 50s in my basement all the
time all the time
and sure that might be great for a for a
drying you know
but that's not good for for veg for sure
and you know
flowering in general you know you do
want to have a little more control on it
so i do actually have in my lung room i
have a space heater that runs all the
time and keeps the room at about a 70
yeah about 70 and uh it works really
well the space
my lung room is my old grow room so it's
it's about eight by eight by ten
and you know that little space heater
with the two four by four tents in it
works perfect perfect and it's on the
outside of the tents so that enter that
that air is getting sucked into the
tents and then and yeah like i also
drain a tent i didn't say that i also
drain a tent and uh i really enjoy it
like i is ac infinity a sponsor here
yeah oh yeah
yeah good yeah shout out to ac infinity
man and and using promo code mr growit
uh or which whichever one it is but
anyways
perfect um it's uh i love it man they've
got the the smart controller can read
everything on my phone it's got the
diode that goes down into the tent so i
can see or i can read how much exactly
the temperature is how much the moisture
is i can adjust the speed on it so
depending on how fast you want it i put
it on one
and it worked perfect this was this was
a great dry i was almost worried that i
had over dried at some stage but nah
everything came out really well i might
actually over burped it here just the
other day but
leave it up to me to fail but uh no the
inline i really think makes a world of a
difference when it comes to drying
nice nice so you mentioned your drying
setup your drying conditions
how long you drive for
how do you know when they're done drying
that's a good question
i remember when i first got into
doing youtube everybody always said wait
for that stem to snap
and that was it there was no other way
to harvest your herb it was wait for
that stem to snap it took me two or
maybe two harvests to realize that is
way too late if you've lost the moisture
in the stem
the buds are done the buds are done you
know what i mean like i just feel like i
feel like
you don't want a complete snap you don't
want the dust to fall when you hit the
uh when you when you when you go to bend
that snap i like some rigidity to that
stem
um i like to you know there's still a
little bit of a
but it it's just it bends under almost
its own pressure i feel like
what you what if you might
take it off the rack a little early you
can make up for that in the cure
the burp if you will um i i like to wait
until the outside of the buds are crispy
and you unfortunately you're gonna have
one of those buds i'm a hands-on kind of
guy there might be a science to it but
like i said i'm a hands-on kind of guy
and if you go to grab a bud there's
typically one bud more than others that
you might want to use but you go and you
just mush it and if that bud on the
outside is really crispy but
you can feel it it doesn't powder in
your hands first of all that's way too
dry that's that stem snapping or if you
you you crush it and it's still got a
little bit of bounce to it you know you
can feel that moisture in there as you
crush it it's like crush crush crush
crush all of a sudden bounce like a
sponge that's when i know it's done
there's a little bit of moisture left in
that bud that'll help me during the cure
and that'll help pull out some of those
those flavors and so on and so forth and
it won't it'll give me that that margin
of error during the curing process so i
completely go by the wayside of the the
snapping of the branch wait till you can
get a nice little crunch on the buds
with a little bit of moisture
and you're laughing and then after the
plants are dry you do the trimming
process trimming process is
it's extremely time consuming i mean i
remember it was like first time i ever
trimmed a plant i was like four plus
hours for this medium-sized plant you
know that just took up a a two foot by
two foot grow space it can be very
tedious now i know you can do a sloppy
job and maybe not get all of the leaves
off of there and speed up some things
and stuff like that but um do you have
any general tips overall for the
trimming process trimming sucks the
novelty of trimming wears off around the
second or third harvest like it's it's
ridiculous how you said it tedious it's
painful in a lot of cases your back gets
sore your fingers get sore hanging onto
the stems and you're like you can feel
it in your palm like it is it's it's
horrible it's horrible and i you know um
first thing you could do is just harvest
less plants that's number one you know
it's like do you really need this many
this is a big thing that i'm learning
i'm a perpetual gardener and i have had
a continuous garden going for
i don't know 10 plus years easily
and i have way too much way too much i'm
i i you know i it maybe it's a first
world problem but i'm throwing stuff
away left right and center because it's
either way too dry it's losing its color
it's been in the drawer forever it's
just it's no good you know even the
goats would need it so
you know ask yourself how many plants
you really need to harvest that's that
that would be the biggest question
because if you can get away with two
instead of four do the two that's number
one number two uh yeah i definitely get
sloppier you know when you first start
harvesting the the plants you're you're
trimming are just
you got so tight to the bud you're
showing them off to your buddies you're
excited and those are the best trimmed
buds you've ever seen in your life by
harvest four five six you don't even
care anymore you're just like it's good
yeah that one's good yep yep don't even
worry about it no i'm not even trimming
that one that was good so it's like it
you kind of get a little bit looser but
to
to to really maximize your your uh your
trimming time
make it fun um i i believe in trim
parties if you've got buddies or friends
or your wife or your husband and you
just want
to get a job done turn it into a party
kick on your favorite taylor swift song
get your favorite drinks have over some
friends get them trimmed make sure
you've got a nice smoke supply to keep
them happy and make the best of it um i
prefer to stand rather than sit because
i find standing just allows me to like
get a little bit loose and and and trim
um you know sitting over such a long
time can be a real pain in the ass a
good set of trimmers goes a long way and
i and and i mean that because uh you
know if uh
having to do this you know for four plus
hours is is a lot and if you don't have
a set of trimmers that auto opens you
know you don't want to use scissors
where you have to do both directions you
know you want to have a spring in there
um some people some people swear by
fiskus i personally just use whatever
ones that i can find at my local
hardware store for a fraction of the
price um just something that's going to
work with you you need a long pair and a
small pair
and yeah go ham make it fun that's my
best advice i know a lot of people use
the trim trays as well i'm not sure if
you use those or not but that actually
helps with the dry sift you know because
they have that screen and then as that
trims running across it
the trichomes are falling down onto that
bottom part and you can actually scrape
that up and use that so have you used
any of the trim trays or no no no i
haven't and i haven't used a bowl or
anything
um i i will i have like i use an
electric trimmer um those things for
doing big colas are great um very speedy
very fast or speedy and fast the same
thing but very efficient
cost wise oh you got to be careful which
ones you get because you can break bank
for some of these electric trimmers that
not necessary in terms of the price but
definitely and that's the downside of
using one of these screens that i used
was that uh there goes an electric
trimmer these buds are not as big as my
forearm you know they're they're a lot
smaller which made it
a little more tedious a little more time
consuming but i've been wanting to try
those bowl trimmers i heard a lot about
them i think ac infinity just dropped
one of them actually two different sizes
i believe i think there's like a 16 and
a 19 inch or something like that and uh
seems to make it much faster of a
process i just worry and which i think a
lot of people worry about is the quality
of the product that you get out of it so
interested no in the comments section
has anybody used any of those trim
machines or or bowl trimmers or anything
like that let us know let us know your
experience on it and if it's worth
picking up and using or not sweet so
let's get into curing next so uh
definitely an important process you can
get through your grow you get through
the
the harvest dry the bud washing all that
stuff get to the curing you could
completely mess it up right and throw it
away because you got mold appearing on
there so very very important process uh
is the home stretch there tell us how do
you go about curing
you said it it's so important you know
um that's also one of those learning
learning uh experience things that
you'll only get better with over time
and through harvests i've had to do it
right a few times and i've had to do it
wrong a few times to really understand
what the what your margin of error is
when it comes to
curing you know
i do say that you can take it off the
the
um the dry rack a little quicker and
have some play time in the cure
um
in terms of or trying to draw out that
dry
but if the more moist that you put those
buds in the jar if that makes any sense
the the more likely are you are to get
mold
and if if you are trying to put them in
a jar sooner
you know you've got to be very vigilant
in terms of trying to avoid that buildup
of moisture in your jars
i much rather through experience
over dry my my bud and put it in the jar
then then have it
more moist and put it in the jar if that
makes any sense um
i i often find that when i think i've
over dried my product when i put it in
the jar and give it a good 24 hours the
moisture is bad it's not back it's there
it's there it was never really gone it's
there and and you know you touch those
buds it's like oh oh they are kind of
sticking to each other in the in the jar
still you know that's good that's good
so
um generally speaking i use about i
think i should go bigger because my
harvests are typically a pound or larger
um but i should be using like vaults
in terms of those c vaults but i'm using
um the glass
kind of mason jars but one quart i've
been using those faithfully
fill those like a chip bag three
quarters of the way full seal it off
right on it put it in a cold or cool
dark area
in the basement um
typically in the exact same temperature
that i it was drying in you know there's
not much different there trying to keep
it in around that 60 62 percent is ideal
but again you're playing the plus minus
game any hydrometers that you use are
typically plus minus in their own right
so it's so tough to get that perfect
amount um i don't use
packs um like i.e bavita um mainly
because i feel like it takes a lot of my
vigilance out of the game like out of
the
uh
it takes my diligence
out of the out of the equation and i
feel like when you get this far
don't trust on a humidity pack to get
you through the burping phase okay i'm
not talking about a long-term storage
here i'm talking about those first
couple weeks after your harvest i don't
believe a bavita pack is is going to do
you any justice you're pushing 90
humidity in those jars sometimes
immediately after harvest that that
bavita packs just being inundated with
moisture it's not working i feel like
you want to
you know keep an eye as soon as you
harvest put them in the jars every 24
hours you're going to be burping
typically for about a week give or take
and these you can't take take any of
this for for just
you got to take it with a grain of salt
because every environment's a little bit
different but typically within the first
week i'm burping every day after that
it's typically every few days two or
three days just based on how much
moisture is being retained and then
after two three weeks four weeks it's
pretty well good for about once every
month to to be burped it's not unusual
to be
sitting in a jar for six eight ten
fifteen months so long term storage i do
believe in a bavita pack i do believe in
those moisture packs because they will
maintain that moisture in there for a
long term period i p i think people
often believe that if you just throw a
moisture packer pack in there it's gonna
take that 90 humidity and just bring it
down to 60 percent or if you've got 30
percent it's just going to bring it up
to 60 and that's
just the wrong wrong methodology for
those things we have a lot of newbies
watching this one here and uh you
definitely covered a lot of it in detail
container using temperature humidity
burping break down the details what
exactly how do you burp the jars it
comes down to where you are like how
long you let them dry out you know if
you've got
an incredible amount of moisture in
there you know you're there's a build up
of co2 there's a build up of moisture
there's a buildup of of of of of just
undesirable gases inside that jar as
it's trying to do its job
and it needs to be expelled if you've
got way too much moisture in there so
you're pushing 90 plus and that's not
unusual that's not unusual you need to
actually get those buds out of there i
in my opinion if you fill this jar up
three quarters of the way full and and
you start to look at the jar after a 24
hour period
those buds are stuck to each other you
you can i can shake the jar and i can
try to get those buds out of there but
they're stuck to each other so in order
to get them out and un fr and unstock to
free them you got to get them out of the
jar and i like to sometimes put them out
over top of like a pan or something or a
desk or a table or something clean and
just let them sit for about half hour 45
minutes until again the outsides of
those buds are similar to the work they
were when you you took them off the dry
rack they're crunchy on the outside
moist on the inside
sounds like a great candy commercial but
it's it's you're going to crush it you
know one of those buds unfortunately
isn't going to be survive is it going to
survive because it's going to be your
tester and you're going to just molest
it unfortunately and then you're going
to know you're going to know okay it's
ready to go back in the jar for another
12 24 hours where are you are you at the
beginning of the burp
if if so you're probably going to come
back in 12 hours best way to check on
your your your jar without actually
opening it was what i said there kind of
kind of shake it a little bit and if
those buds are kind of tumbling in there
on their own they're probably good for
like another you know
12 hours and then do it again you don't
have to go in there so often if the
moisture level isn't so high some people
use hydrometers but again it's it's plus
minus those things are plus minus i do i
do recommend using hydrometer it's just
don't rely on it it's it i i i i kind of
compare it to the analogy of being lost
in the woods with a gun
someone who's lost in the winds with a
gun is far less likely to survive than
somebody who gets lost in the woods
without a gun and that's because as a
we tend to become too competent in our
tools and we think that the gun what's
the gun going to do the gun can't get
water for you the gun can't get you know
it can't bring wildlife to you it you
know
it it's it's a tool and so if you rely
on these tools a i.e these boveda packs
or sorry i don't want to throw boveda
under the bus here these hydro packs and
these these hydrometers then you you're
you're you you can be i'm not saying
everyone but you can be less likely to
be more diligent and so just don't rely
on it so heavily a lot a lot of this can
be figured out by feel and by sight
that's all i'm trying to say i use those
little mini hygrometers
it has the not only the humidity but
also the temperature as well
and uh i fell into the chapter relying
on those 100 and a lot of people do rely
on 100
they can be accurate but the ones that i
was using unfortunately i had a couple
that were inaccurate and uh although it
said it was 62 rh which a lot of people
deem as the ideal percent unfortunately
mold appeared on the buds and i lost two
jars because it said 62 but actually
looking at the jars they were actually a
white fuzz like actual mold it was
pretty gross and so i threw those things
out because those ones weren't accurate
but no you bring up a great point is
like you might want to actually have
like another
measurement to kind of compare it to to
make sure that there's accurate don't
just trust it right out of the box that
it's going to be accurate test it first
to make sure because
you could spoil your harvest from it you
know and and just because it's accurate
on in june
doesn't mean it's going to be accurate
in august or may of the next year you
know and and that's just that's
something that you just need to take
into consideration you know there's
there's other methods you said there's
other methods use them and just because
it says 62 in the jar
that doesn't mean that it's not 75
between two buds in this little tiny
corner that's why i like to rotate the
jar get the buds to kind of tumble
inside move them about if i notice that
kind of two buds are stuck together
that's a great indicator that i need to
get in there and kind of just
get them unstuck
and and so yeah just be vigilant
vigilant is key for being if for curing
burping and drying and when are the buds
ready to consume
see that's the key is i also say that
you need product
to harvest product this is the thing and
i'd say it's so much better if i could
but the thing is is that it's like you
can't get to the end if you don't have
something to ingest yourself okay so
it's it it's it's very tough
to to sit there and watch this beautiful
plant just staring at you and and you
just want to eat
but you don't have anything right you
won't let it get there so the thing is
is you need to be in a good state to get
to a good harvest so when's a good time
to ingest it well when you need it
that's my first thing so once it's once
it's if you got through a dry period and
you got through a burp and you got you
got a cure of really any sorts
it
dive in don't go hungry with a fridge
full of food that's that's the first
thing i would say the second thing i
would say is that if you've if you've
got something to ingest while it is
doing its thing and you're okay you're
comfortable
two weeks
minimum
minimum and i think you're doing
yourself an injustice if you're going to
do it after two weeks if if two weeks
minimum
a cure
you can ingest it personally though if
you can wait a month
a month in the cure that that if you had
ingested it on two weeks versus the
month it's a world of difference i i
once read and and i live on bro science
i've got a third degree black bow uh the
uh the
i i believe that if with a proper cure
you can pull out the remaining
potential of that bud now everyone says
yeah of course curing does that but i
but i think a good cure a good cure goes
like a long way i think if you were to
put it on a scale and say like all your
efforts and work in the flower is going
to do this much to its it's it's smoke
ability you know the work you do in the
flower stage is going to do this much
compared to its smoke ability the the
amount you it does to in the first two
weeks of cure does this much to its
smoke ability but giving it a month
i think does that to its smoke ability
you know what i mean like that's so i'm
two weeks minimum but a month cure and
you're laughing you're laughing i agree
with that you know two weeks of the
minimum is when i'll touch it but i
usually have a stockpile kind of like
use so 30 days is really when i'm
testing it out for myself and that's uh
you know it's two weeks in it you taste
the the greenness or a lot of people say
chlorophyll
um and then after a month or so like
sometimes you can still taste it but
most of the time that that's gone so i
really feel like 30 days at the minimum
is usually when i'm testing it out and
get a much better flavor than two weeks
in you know so
yep so like i mentioned earlier there's
a lot of new folks listening in here i'm
sure there's a large handful of people
who haven't even gone through their
first harvest yet what other advice do
you have for somebody who is new to
these processes uh see again i'm not a
science guy i'm kind of a life guy
you need to make this system work for
you you need to make your harvest work
for you if you are new to it
um you know
you don't have to go overboard you don't
have to buy the 200 trimmers you don't
have to buy all the equipment you don't
need fancy
i don't want to throw any brands under
the bus here when i do this but it's
like you don't need any fancy curing
things you don't need any you can keep
this really simple and i think that's
the key i think that's the key because
this is your first time and a lot can go
wrong and i'm not trying to scare anyone
but when i when i was given my little
scale there the same thing can go
towards the like the
the amount of risk that's involved you
know and the later you get into the
process of harvesting the more risk is
involved in in things going wrong and
and all it takes is just a less of a
mistake and and things like you know um
over over simplifying or or over
complicating the process is one of those
things where it's like you you feel like
you need all the best things you need
the best um uh jars you need and and
that's not true that's not true that's
not true this is
it we do put a lot of weight on getting
it right
but there's a lot more ways to get it
right than there are to get it wrong
it's just the ways to get it wrong are
really easy you know it's not hard
but but anyways anyways as i contradict
myself the idea would be to make it fun
make it comfortable and make it work for
you you know incorporate people that you
trust and you love into the process i
think that's number one i think that'll
help make the process go a lot longer a
lot easier
because you can talk to somebody you can
you can enjoy the process with somebody
and it's it's just that much more
enjoyable um standing as i said like
when you when you harvest
standing and not sitting is huge
getting the right pair of trimmers for
you is huge
um just yeah yeah do your homework do
your homework just so today there's so
many more
resources on
the internet to
uh kind of relate to or kind of dive
into do it do it you don't have to
listen to me you know it's between the
two of us we have very different growth
styles in many different areas you've
tried out a million different ways than
i have you've got you've got guys like
rob cltv you know trey even between the
two of them they do things very
differently you've got guys like you
know um
high again you know they do things very
differently um you know mr canuck for
example does things very differently and
find find a routine that works for you
find something that works for you and
try to adapt it and if you're anything
like me you're going to take a little
bit of all of these people and you're
going to you're going to you're going to
make something of your own
and you're gonna you're gonna make that
famous and call it your own like you did
it yourself well said lots of good stuff
there
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future well uh first of
all uh thank you thank you for having me
on i really enjoy what you you are doing
with this with this platform and with
the with your shows and uh the amount of
information that this podcast has done
for the community is i think uh second
to none second to none the way you've
brought creators the way you brought
talent the way you've brought scientists
the way you've brought
technicians hobbyists together is is
incredible
and uh i applaud you for that and it's
an absolute honor to not only be the
first
or the second but at the most viewed but
the second time being on here it's it's
it's a lot of titles to hold for this so
i i appreciate it appreciate you
and uh for those watching um i i'm on
youtube as well you can find me at
pigeons420 it's on my hat um i'm on
twitch as well pigeons420 i'm everywhere
i'm pigeons420 um we've got the from the
stash podcast i do top buds live uh
monday wednesday fridays it's a morning
show we talk about everything and uh i'm
sure we're gonna get cancelled someday
you can find that over on twitch as well
at uh topbuzz live
and uh yeah i'm getting around when it
comes to the future i'm doing some
traveling um i i know these really two
other two cool guys that i do this
podcast with uh we do some traveling
together i got them coming to canada
depending on when you see this they may
or may not have already been here but
yeah the future is very bright for for
the pigeons 420 team and
a lot of that has to do with teaming up
with some great minds and i'm very
thankful for that and i'm very excited
to see where the future has in store for
me we'll definitely have a link to your
channel down in the youtube description
section below and then if you're on one
of the podcast platforms just search for
him he'll come up and if you didn't
catch on i'm actually part of a podcast
with him it's me
him not just us two but also rob from
cltv search from the stash podcast
that's on youtube as well as all the
podcast platforms as well
and uh yeah we have a blast over there
three different perspectives
and talk about all sorts of stuff so
definitely tune into that if you haven't
already if you enjoyed this episode
click that thumbs up button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend new garden
talk podcast episode and i would love
for you to tune in to future episodes
pigeons once again thank you so much for
coming onto the podcast today last
episode was a banger this one's another
banger and uh i am so thankful that you
came on again
thank you man it's been an honor to be
here and i can't wait to see and hear
what everybody thinks about this episode
i'm sure that i may or may not have said
something that a few people may or may
not disagree with so
i encourage some civil discussion in the
comment section and i can't wait to read
it and then also link the episode one we
did in the description section below so
if you guys want to head on over there
actually link it on the outro card of
this video as well so click on that and
hear us talk all about plant training so
another hot topic yes peace out everyone
see you in the next episode