welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
117 in this episode I interview Dr
aliceon Justice she has a PHD in plant
environmental science from Clemson
University she is also a consultant owns
the hemp mine and created the CRC which
is a science-based research group she
has advanced knowledge in post Harvest
production so drying curing and that's
what today's episode is about she talks
about some of the key information when
it comes to harvesting drying and curing
and she also talks about some studies
that have been done in those areas if
you want to see highlights of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube that channel is
dedicated to short bite-sized clips of
these episodes I actually did a poll on
my YouTube channel where this podcast
episode is posted to and 53% of the
people that responded weren't aware that
have another YouTube channel I call it
my main YouTube channel where I show off
the plants that I grow that channel has
over 130 videos from the past 7 years so
if you're not familiar with it I'll
leave a link down in the YouTube
description section below so you can
easily get to it and subscribe one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
electric sprayers with a 2 L capacity
and an adjustable nozzle that can go
from a strong jet to a fine mist spray
their sprayers are battery powered and
can be used for 3 hours on a full charge
no pumping required and it's a one
button operation click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their sprayers and the
discount code Mr Grow 15 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend I I've been using stash
blend for over a year now and it's
awesome one of the things that I really
like is that it saves me money it's a
whole bunch of different inputs in one
so I no longer have to go out there and
buy a silica bottle then a separate
seaweed bottle beneficial bacteria then
a separate one for microle fungi all of
that plus more is in this one blend go
to stash blend.com to learn more about
it and I also have a link down in the
YouTube description section below spider
farmer check out their 6 L Cool m t fire
which can be played placed inside the
grow tent or outside of it if placed
outside of your grow tent you can use
the included flexible hose which splits
into two to help distribute the humidity
evenly across the grow space also check
out their clip fan which oscillates and
has seven-speed settings to help
simulate the natural window doors it has
a 100° vertical manual oscillation and a
90° horizontal automatic oscillation
discount code Mr Grow 5 works on both
Amazon and the website spider- far.com
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Dr
Alison Justice how you doing today I'm
doing great glad to be here yeah thanks
for coming on appreciate it we met last
year at a conference uh had a good
conversation you actually knew you
before the conference very familiar with
your work I went through the Utah State
University the cultivation certificate
program and I know you have a couple
talks in there and uh one of them was on
post Harvest production the harvesting
drying and curing and that's really what
I want to get into today is you just
have so much experience in regards to
that and we've come so far in the past 5
years alone it's it's amazing what we've
uncovered so yeah I'm sure that you're
going to give us a bunch of insight and
I think uh a lot of my audience is going
to learn some things today that they
haven't known because I feel like a lot
of the stuff still isn't widespread as
much as it could be but before we get
deep into things can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening yeah so you know I
think I was I was born with it I was
born with green thumbs um my
grandparents my great grandparents their
parents everybody has been Farmers for
one thing or the other so uh yeah I I
was basically born in a greenhouse um we
grew trees uh be root ball and burlap um
we did patunas and pansies at one point
a little bit of everything um and so
because of that I swore I was never
going to go into plants when I was old
but here I am with a PhD in plant
science um I don't know it's just one of
those things when you're little you're
not going to do what your parents do but
you know I uh I I I loved it and I got
into it obviously um but I I got my PhD
from Clemson University and in plant
environmental science and um you know to
be honest I didn't know exactly wanted
what I wanted to do after graduation and
so um I did Consulting for a while with
Pest Management for green houses across
the US and started getting some calls
for medicinal plant
Consulting and so I took a few jobs and
loved it packed my stuff up and uh got a
job first but I packed my stuff up and
and moved to San Diego and stayed out
there for about 3 and 1 half years um
working for a vertical group uh which
was wonderful I got to learn everything
from SE to cell as they say it um um and
then decided I wanted to to do my own
thing and um you know have a little more
freedom to research what I wanted and do
what I wanted um and not be tied down by
um you know hitting a bottom line per se
so even though that is of course still
important um but you know research and
and commercial production is certainly a
a different world to live in so moved
back to South Carolina where um we've
been growing under the hemp program um
since since I guess
2018 and here we I own the hemp mine so
that's a a CBD company um we do
everything from breeding selling
genetics all the way to harvest and um
consumer goods and that sort of thing uh
but really what's near and dear to my
heart is the research aspect and um we
created the CRC the Cannabis research
Coalition with uh Dr fa at Clemson
University and so we've been running
that for about
uh about 3 years now and it's it's
really a three- tiered program I guess
you could call it one is more of a
membership model where you give money um
and what you receive back in return is
uh Early Access to research all the
nitty-gritty that may not be published
in a a peer- reviewed paper um
Sops access to talk to you know hear and
listen from some of the nation's top
Growers you know glass house um State
House etc etc and so just a place to get
together and talk about some of the
problems you're having um as far as
growing goes um we're also a contract
research organization and so if
somebody's having problems or if they
have a great product and they say you
know we've we've had as much internal
R&amp;D as possible um let's we need
somebody else to verify it cuz you know
how you know you can trust your own
research but if you're some trying to
buy a product you don't necessarily only
want to listen to internal research so
we're that third party non-biased um you
know nothing tied to to to support bias
which I know later you want to talk
about that in a little a little greater
detail which I'm happy to um and then of
course we do Consulting and Audits and
and things of that nature that's awesome
yeah you have so much going on and well
yeah clemon University Dr y Vos big name
there in regards to post Harvest
production as well I know he had a talk
at Utah State University you guys go
real real deep into it and a lot deeper
than I think the average homeg grower
goes into it being able to expose some
of the information here today I think is
going to be really valuable so let's
just get right into it let's get into uh
let's start with harvesting then we'll
get into drying and then curing so for
harvesting talking about the ideal time
to harvest a plant now it's mostly known
that when the tricomes are mostly cloudy
that's when they're at the highest
potency now some people like for it to
turn Amber where the inside canabo go
from THC to CBN is all of that still
true today is that still the ideal time
to harvest a plant you know you said
earlier
that you said earlier that in the last 5
years we've come a long way but the
deeper in I get the more I understand
how much I don't understand um so you
know I I'll give you what's known today
or at least what's theorized today um
because you know there's more than what
but any of us and any of our lifetimes
are going to figure out you know this is
certainly going to be something that's
done for hundreds of years um and and is
why this industry is so exciting for me
because if I were to study patunas or
poinsettas you know there's hundreds of
of of uh journals out there with great
information already so but yeah with
with harvesting I would say the most
important thing is to be delicate with
the plants um you know if you're in a
commercial setting a lot of times you're
rushed and hurry and you're just
throwing plants around you know every
time you touch a tricol it will bust um
for lack of better words so just being
as delicate as possible having it touch
as little things as possible um will
certainly keep your plant in a lot
better state but as far as when you know
what
color uh the Tricom
is you know I have found by you know by
being a breeder and seeing lots of
different varieties CBD CBG THC you know
seeing all of the varieties that are out
there that produce different cannaboids
I I've yet to find a a true consistency
of you know being able to say 10% Amber
perfect Harvest um it it it doesn't
happen the same way with every variety
so you know what what I always suggest
is if you have a new variety and a lot
of this is costly but this is this is
perfect we scenario okay you have a new
variety and the breeder says it's a 8we
plant at at we I mean the earlier you go
the better and you can graph it out and
see how you know your THC CBD whatever
it is um can progress and and where it
Peaks and where it starts to decline and
you can compare that to you know what it
looks like under the microscope and then
you have that to repeat from um but
testing is expensive and you know it's
not necessarily worth it for everyone
but I would just say repetition and
growing a
variety um and and a lot of it's
personal preference as well I mean I I
like mine to be on the earlier side
where they're more they're more clear um
and then there's some people that they
want it to be extremely Amber so a lot
of that's preference and um this is this
is simply Theory but I do not think the
Amber comes from the THC to CBN
conversion I think it could be uh some
sort of non-enzymatic Browning um like
other plants do when they ripen so
bananas and uh apples when you cut them
there's some uh en enzimatic Browning
happening um and so that's hope
hopefully something I'll get to dig into
this year um finding people to work with
that can test some of these more
nitty-gritty aspects of the plant has
has been pretty tough um and we finally
got um a university other than Clemson
that will test for carbohydrates and and
um the pieces that can lead you down
that road of starch to sugar conversion
and you know what I truly think is the
the guts to what is equating to a a good
cure got it yeah so it comes down to
personal preference I personally like
mostly cloudy with a little bit of Amber
I talked to so many people who are just
like oh 10% Amber 20% Amber but yeah at
the end of the day it comes down to
personal preference like you had said
you know if you're looking at your
tricomes and you're counting them it can
be tricky sometimes because are you
looking at the top ones where you know
the light is directly hitting them are
you looking at a a inside piece or a
lower Bud because all that can be
different throughout the plant too that
makes sense now you mentioned the starch
to sugar conversion which kind of
relates to the next question I have here
which is in regards to Flushing the
plants before Harvest now there have
been some studies that came out in
regards to FL flushing the plants before
Harvest whether or not it's beneficial
I've talked to many guests in the past I
like to bring this question up because
each person kind of has their own little
little tidbits on it little insight on
it and so I wanted to ask you this are
there any benefits to Flushing your
plants before harvesting it you know
thus far there's been a couple studies
out about it and you know I think the
only true solid takeaway we can have is
that if you stop fertilizing two weeks
prior to harvest there's no differences
in what's been tested so far and so that
really is Turpin
canabo yield um with I believe Mike's
work Mike from Clemson his work was
showing that if you go further than two
weeks of fertilizer restriction then
you're going to start losing some yield
which makes sense um but right at that
two we Mark you're not losing yield and
you're not losing any sort of potency um
so what that tells tell me is stop
wasting your fertilizer and you know
you're not having any negative from
doing it so why do it um
but again Theory and again again
something that this year we're going to
get done is looking at what else is
happening during that flushing process
um you know when you flush you see color
change you see um depending on how hard
and you know intense your flush is um
you'll see faster
ripening um and so it's my theory that
that is in fact what's happening is
you're cutting off the nutrients a lot
of times you're lowering the temperature
so the plant is being pushed into
maturation faster than it would be if it
were still getting all the nitrogen and
everything that um would be encouraging
it to stay um grow I say vegetatively
but I don't mean it being in this
vegetative form I just mean in bulk um
you're not pushing that nitrogen for
excess growth the plant thinks it's fall
they think oh no it's time to you know
close up shop and protect these seeds so
we need to ripen so I would expect I
suspect that flushing does help to push
maturation that then changes those
carbohydrates um from being starches to
sugars I also think there's some play in
that as well
um the starch the sugar conversion in
those I don't know probably first 5 days
or so of drying um because it is still
active um you know it's it's difficult
to to say when a plant is dead because
it depends on how you know it all
depends on how much water is in It
ultimately you know is this thing alive
or not due to the water and it due to
the water supporting some of the
enzymatic activities that can happen um
so I would expect you know those last
few weeks of growing and then those
first few weeks of of dry first couple
of weeks of drying to really be when
those changes are happening um and like
I said it's been a couple year Mission
trying to uh get the right testing
available for this plant specifically to
be able to check that that's really
interesting yeah ever since that study
came out by RX screen Technologies back
in 201 20 in regards it really showed no
difference between the two I actually
made a video on it and I talked about
how yeah well the same Viewpoint as you
it's like well you can save money on
fertilizer why feed the plant up until
the end if it's not doing anything
differently for you the respones I got
off of that was hilarious but now it
seems like the biggest argument is the
starch to sugar conversion and right now
we just don't have the data to back that
up and it's interesting that that's the
route that you're trying to go to
actively research and see if there is
anything there so looking forward to
seeing what comes out of there in the
future yeah it should be interesting now
what about giving the plants a period of
darkness before Harvest that's another
thing that folks do in order to try to
achieve a better result here are a
varying number of reasons why people do
it but 24 hours of darkness before
Harvest 48 Hours of darkness before
Harvest some people do even longer than
that is there any benefit at all to
giving your plants a period of darkness
before Harvest
uh you know again it's been one of those
things i' I've kind of sat on the fence
about um could see the the benefit of
why and again I I would lend it towards
being an act to encourage
maturation
um you know we're we're digging deeper
into trying to
understand what the the outer structure
of the the triome gland um you know how
it's composed what it's made out of and
what really encourages it to crack or
not
um and and a lot of that works with
canol um but you know I think there's
there's something to be found about it
it it strength um and with proper curing
and harvesting not disturbing it making
it stronger and more
encapsulated um you know it's always
been interesting when you go into
drawing rooms of large facilities you
know you just smell it a mile down the
road and if it's the day of of uh
Harvest or you know day after whatever
um and you can smell it and you know my
my thoughts always well if it's in my
nose it's not in the plant you know
there's TPS in the air and it's not like
they're continuing to make these turpins
and so you know at some point it's going
to be spent um and so if we're able to
preserve that triom head better you know
does that make your quality last longer
um that's something that that we're
digging deep to and it's hard I mean the
it's tiny it's tiny and so you know
learning the scanning electron uh
microscopy and and really digging into
that this past year and this year has
been an
eyeopener um and understanding again how
much we don't understand and being able
to see in detail that close cuz there
are there are some drawbacks from it too
as as cool as the pictures look look
it's also not the whole story yeah
that's crazy there's still a lot so many
people out there that prefer the
darkness before Harvest and they're kind
of blind in the fact on whether or not
it is beneficial so I guess that debate
is going to is going to be ongoing from
here I think so so any overall tips for
harvesting or anything we kind of need
to know about about harvesting before we
move on to drying and curing you know I
think I think for harvesting drying it's
is delicate you know you you've got to
think of even if it's 10 minutes where
you've placed it in the sun you know if
if we're talking about for smokable
flower um 10 minutes in the sun could do
a ton of damage so you know being being
fast at making your moves and you know
being delicate and consistent with
everything okay now let's move on to
drying talk to us about the goal of
drying really water activity is one of
the things that come to mind right away
so can you talk to us about you know
what water activity is and kind of the
overall goal of it and so on and so
forth yeah so you know drying is the
first thing that comes to mind is like
you said water activity for the point of
not
spoiling so we're getting the water out
just like we would any other Foods
raisins whatever it may be um getting it
down low enough to where um it does not
support proliferation of microbes um now
drying does not kill microbes um there's
lots of spores and bacteria that are
super hearty um and we can dry it down
to a crisp and those spores are still
going to be there so once it's
rehydrated they could take over um but
the point is to get that water activity
low enough to to not support other life
growing on it um and that's really the
difference between water activity and
moisture content you know they're
they're very related but the difference
there is um available water for microbes
to to uh persist in so goal KCK M from
WR is 6 water activity and that
prohibits the growth of moles and yeasts
and so on and so forth yes yep that is
today's goal okay now are there any
tools that Growers can purchase in order
to measure water activity yeah uh
moisture content meters are pretty
inexpensive but they are also very
damaging um to get a proper reading you
almost have to take a full bud and you
know uh squeeze it it as tight as you
can and then stick the prongs in um but
again then you're ruining a bud um and
that's not a great thing um the other
thing which is you know it's got it
drawbacks too is a water activity meter
um and they can be quite pricey
$1,000 on up you know $10,000 for a
really high-end one um so those aren't
my preference either um at least in the
hom grower space you know the it it's
Overkill um one thing I like to do is
put your plants in the drying room bring
it down to where you think it's just
about right and if you debut your
flowers put it in a jar and then have a
humidistat in the
jar once once you see the humidity level
stabilize that is your uh water activity
so your humidity then turns into the uh
water activity I mean you got to move
the decimal two points but um um
ultimately it's the same so if you have
a jar put a few buds in there and it
reads 70% humidity after it's leveled um
because there'll be a a time of
fluctuation uh for the moisture to
homogenize throughout but once you get
to that homogenized state if it reads
70% let's say then you're at a 7 water
activity and you you might want to keep
the lid open for a couple of days or
that sort of thing got it yeah I think
that's what a lot of hom Growers are
doing today some pretty straightforward
there really from what you're telling me
it's not really worth it to go and spend
money on a moisture meter a water
activity meter for the average hom
grower just putting the your buzz in the
jar and and getting that humidity down
you're safe at that point so for drying
conditions you know temperature humidity
what are the ideal dry conditions you
know I think the the traditional 6060
that everybody's been using for forever
um it works it works
Five Points either way also works um you
know I think being able to go slower on
the days it takes to fully remove a
certain amount of water um could is
beneficial for Turing retention uh
because the faster you're bringer
bringing that water out the faster you
potentially could be volatilizing your
tarping off too so um I think there's a
a nice medium point which 66 de it
achieves well um you know I think the
time will come where we start to
understand again how delicate these
tricomes are you know one thing that you
get when you're using very traditional
systems you know let's say a a mini
split and a
de when you're looking at tracking over
time even though your set points might
be
6060 you've got these these pieces of
equipment fighting each each other all
the time you've got the AC coming on
it's getting cooler but then the
humidity is also Rising because the
humidifier is off or the de is off and
then it switches places because then
it's you know then the de kicks on but
then that makes the room hot um so it's
this constant cycle of on and off where
you're also seeing these huge spikes up
and down um so I kind of like to think
of it like a balloon um um if you have a
balloon filled with helium and you go
outside and it's a um you know a humid
day versus a notum day the balloon will
will float and it will expand and
contract and um that's how I think of
the Tricom head is expanding and
Contracting um because of this
environment and at some point the
expanding and
Contracting will cause cracks and you
know these small cracks how much how
much Tarpin you know H how's the loss um
and so that's what I'm really
interesting interested in is taking a
step further than just seeing humidity
and temperature and understanding the
pressure that goes behind it um because
all of that is is wrapped around VPD and
um really understanding the internal
pressure of what's in that cell and the
the outside room pressure and not
causing those swings to be so intense so
stability is kind of more important than
the temperature and humidity and the gr
schem of things cuz like you had
mentioned going and a lot of these folks
that are drying in tents they're having
just that happen for me I have my
humidifer kick on fans are going around
sometimes I have exhaust fan come out
I'm exchanging the air but there's a lot
of swings happening you know and it
might be one or two degrees but those
one to two degrees could be rupturing
Tricom heads right exactly so overall
What would be the ideal length of dry in
number of days I've heard anywhere from
7 to 14 days I hear 5 to 10 days we know
the downsides of drying too quickly
versus trying too long and maybe you can
get into to that to begin and then let
us know what the ideal dry time day is
in yeah so I'd love to share with you
maybe you can squeeze into the talk um
it's a graph we put out where it looks
at Days 1 to 14 um it's looking at
humidity and temperature and and
correlates the the V PD and it shows you
know if you go out 14
days um it equates to this VPD and so on
and so it shows kind of right in the
middle there at 7 Days um if you are at
that 6060 Mark you should be able to
achieve it within 7 Days um it's a
really useful to Tool um but you know
obviously you can you can go further
than Le let's say you're at 60 60 and
you go eight days well each day you go
past you're bringing more and more water
out of that flow and you may think okay
well I can just rehydrate it at some
point um but we're starting to see a lot
of extreme rehydration can cause a lot
of Browning as well um and so being able
to pull it right at the right time and
having to dry it a little more is okay
but if you're having to really really
have to rehydrate it um you won't have
quite as great results so the goal is to
get it right where you want it right
when you pull it
from whatever drying environment you're
in now what about a 4day dry so I have
the canol I know you're familiar with
the citrol I've got one right back there
and I love it I've been using it for
over a year now real consistent dries
hands off as far as I'm not really
messing around with the equipment now
you know humidifier and fan and all that
stuff but I think in their normal
settings 60 8° F and a 54 D point which
I believe is 61% Rh I think it's a 4-day
dry period and then it transitions over
to curing cycle and that's the default
settings that's what they recommend is 4
days too quick of a dry um you know I
don't I don't think it's too quick um
you know again we're we're working
through all of these nitty-gritty
details um with canot trol
um I I think anywhere between that four
and 10day Mark is is okay um and again
but until we can
say you truly need 5 days at a water
activity of8 to convert the starches to
sugars because that is what makes for
the better smoke it's it's hard to to
say there's much difference in in 3 days
as long as you're not drying it out too
much which I know their product doesn't
do um I also know their product doesn't
have the extreme swings um that the
traditional equipment does that's that's
part of you know what their purpose is
to have extremely um
consistent pressure um you know
VPD so no I don't I don't think it's too
short and you know I don't I don't think
we'll be able to measure that until we
kind of backtrack to what is what is a
smooth smoke all right quantify that and
then backtrack from there to say all
right well 5 days would allow this
process to fully develop to equate to
the perfect smoke at the end um so you
know sometimes I feel silly not having
answers but as a researcher you're
told you know you're told to be okay
with not having answers CU that's your
job is to find the answers not guess the
answers that makes total sense now on
the other side you had mentioned 4 to 10
days and a lot of folks are are drying
for longer than that 14 plus days now I
heard from Dr James f one of the talks
that he had he said the same thing same
window I'm pretty sure was 4 to 10 days
he talks about some of the D the dangers
of drying longer than that can you get
into that what happens after 10 days
when you're still drying yeah yeah so
there's certain danger if if you're
going out longer than 10 or 14 days and
the reason that is is because any
microbe that you had in your grow you're
taking it with you into the drawing room
and the longer you have this Bud sitting
wet um the more potential you have for
Bettis growth and and P proliferation
all throughout the entire Bud um for the
most part in traditional drying scents
when you're drying out a large bud it's
the outside of that bud that's drying
first and then the inside side and so
that's why when I say put the buds in a
jar and and wait a day or so until it
levels out is because all of that
moisture that's in the interior of the
bud is then coming to the outside and it
it's it's
equalizing um and so if if you're
leaving the center of that bud at you
know 88 water activity or even higher
you know every minute is a second the
betrus or Fus serum or whatever you
might have um could could really take
over and and cause problems got it yeah
that's one thing that I don't even risk
I usually go around seven days sometimes
10 days at the max but if it's going on
Long longer than that I'm concerned and
I'm actually checking inside the buds
and looking for visual although that
could be there it can be microscopic
level it's more than just a naked eye
you know it could be there without us
even seeing it so scary so you've done a
lot of work with krol I know you've done
a study with them that's actually on the
website kroll.com resesarch if I
remember correctly real brief we I think
a lot of people looking for more details
in regards to that so can you break us
down what that study entailed I believe
it was the canol versus the traditional
6060 method there was I think 16% higher
tarpine content in the canol drying can
you talk to us about that yeah so that
that was first stab at you know really
trying to understand um their unit and
the flower it creates and and that sort
of thing
and so you know first stab is well let's
dry and cure at you know the two
different methods traditional and and
the canol
system and let's test what happens and
the problem they encountered and uh
problems we've seen other companies
encounter when testing tpin is that if
you don't have your own internal lab
there can be a lot of problems um and so
you know you think about a a dried
flower it's got 2% 4% whatever it may be
uh um by dry weight of Tarpin which is
yeah that's a small number if we're
looking at 100% 2% is very small um and
so if we're mailing samples even if you
overnight it with ice something's going
to happen and so any of effect that
could happen during transit or even if
it's just being drove somewhere anything
within Transit is going to affect the
turpine levels the other thing to think
about is you know there's lots of great
Labs out there but there's some that
will grab your samples and maybe
treatment one sits on the counter for an
hour maybe treatment two doesn't um and
so if we're looking at getting true
results on just
2% um that can cause a lot of problems a
lot of skewed errors and so the way we
overcame that is that U we work with a
lab katcha and I told them you know I
want to do the extraction at my lab and
then I want to send you the liquid
because the LI the solvent the solvent's
not going to lose turpins it's going to
be true to what exactly it was the
second I pull it from whatever treatment
is in um and so that's what we send to
the lab those are tested um and so we
can have very accurate results and then
of course have duplicates to uh to make
sure there's
no off off problems so that's how we did
the tpping testing and that's the only
thing that made me feel comfortable to
do tpping testing CU it's so
tricky um but yeah so getting results
back
from 7 Days traditionally drying and 7
Days in the
canol that's the results we got um the
other thing that you got to be super
careful about and and ask questions um
when you're looking at any study like
this is well what was what was the water
content because that can also skew the
numbers so for example if in the canol
it's a perfect Point 61 water activity
and in traditional drying uh let's say
it went down to 058 you know that might
not seem like a lot but in water weight
that will certainly certainly skew the
result so we made sure we had all of
those bases covered to where we're truly
just looking at uh the tping that the
plant produced um um compared to one to
the other and so that's the results we
got was 133% um across the board Tarpin
um each each individual tarpine there
was some you know skewed but overall
that certainly was the result okay now
is there a like a white paper that folks
can reference and and read more deeply
into it is it was a peer reviewed or
anything we're going to duplicate it um
so we had we had reps within the study
but we want to duplicate it again before
the final white paper mhm yeah it's good
to have a couple reps like that just cuz
you never know what could have went
wrong along the way and this is how you
catch any problems that you may have
exactly yeah that's one thing I
mentioned in uh handful of videos now is
science is repeatable you need to be
able to take that and repeat it over and
over and over again in order for it to
be fact EXA one study isn't just fact
right once study could say anything it
could be wrong it could have there could
have been something that went wrong with
it and then it might another study might
come out and it it's not repeated
results right so yeah I think you're
you're doing your due diligence doing
things right in regards to making sure
that it can be replicated and then uh
and then going from there so looking
forward to to reading the final paper
yeah yeah no it was it was great results
I was I was impressed I did make a video
on this actually and uh some viewers
were concerned they mentioned that was a
conflict of interest a little bit since
katrol paid for the research so could
you kind of explain how that works so
CRC you mentioned that you are the owner
of the CRC you did the research for
katrol katrol pays money towards the CRC
for the research to happen I understand
how some people can consider that a
conflict of interest but like in this
industry how difficult it is to get
funding and the barriers you face in
regards to this like there's no
Government funding for you guys versus
like other Industries like food and
beverage there's so much more Government
funding and towards scientists and
research velopment and all that stuff
can you kind of break that I know it a
little messy explanation there but can
you kind of break down how that all
works yeah yeah so funding is hard it's
it's extremely hard um you know USDA
likes to say that there are hemp grants
out there but they are not um they're
mainly for fiber and Seed production um
and so if we're talking
floral
research um there is nothing there as
far as the government goes so our
choices are donations
from anyone right anyone can donate um
and that's that's our our our general
donations is for our association and so
so that's for research that is not
coming requested by a company it's just
something that you know the Growers
might say ah rud AIDS we want x amount
of our funding this year to go towards
you looking at rude Aphid control
da um but then as I was saying earlier
another tier is um third party
validation and so krol says Hey I want
to do this study um we want you to
perform it and give us results and I say
that is great I will perform this study
um but in respect to their company I say
if if you don't get the results you want
then I'm just just going to keep my
mouth shut but if we get the results you
want you're you know I'll talk about the
work we've done um so there's no there's
no paying me for certain results there's
just respect
of use of results um and you know I
would just want to make it clear when
they pay for it it's not like I'm going
out and buying a new Volvo it's Volvo I
don't know where that came from new car
I don't know how i' buy a Volvo but um
you know this this pays for our research
the tests testing is extremely
expensive um and it supports Us in what
we're doing you know even though it is a
project for them the way I see it it's
really a project for the industry to
help to help to understand what's going
on I mean if they were paying me to give
results I would have probably went a
little higher than than 133% or
18% but um yeah so it's it's hard um and
I understand people say ah so and so
sponsoring this this test but um I mean
all you can do is trust me when I say we
you know the results we give is what
science gave us and we're not falsifying
anything you know just's put it this way
I've been back in South Carolina six
years now and for the first 3 years
we've funded our own research um and I
felt like I've not gotten anywhere
because it's been slower than you know
if you had some huge government grant
but you know the stuff we sell on our
consumer good side that supports
research um simply because I like doing
it and I want to do it and I know
there's you know there's thousands of
people out there that this will
certainly help not to mention the
patients who take advantage of the plant
science that's discovered um and how
that trickles down all the way but you
know the C CRC has been great for us it
brings in a little extra money um and
and helps us get down some of the
problems we're having um so can I say
it's not funded by someone no it's
funded by someone bunch of different
Growers different companies but I mean
all of our money personally or not has
to come from somewhere so um all I can
do is show the viewers and readers of
research you know throughout the over
the years of of the research we're
giving and and uh just keep giving good
results and and helping Farmers um
that's what we're trying to do I
appreciate you breaking that down yeah I
think there are a lot of people out
there just kind of ignorant of that fact
of how the research is funded and you
know where the money comes from I was
ignorant uh just a few months ago until
I actually sat down and did the research
and try to figure out that hey the
government isn't spending money towards
this industry like they are in other
Industries so it's a lot harder for
scientists to be able to conduct
research and that's why it's so slow you
know as far as doing the researching and
getting information out there it's just
there's no money here coming from the
government that's really funding it like
there are in other Industries so
appreciate you breaking that down for us
yeah and there there's no special
research class that we can get in to you
know have certain deductions
or help with testing costs I mean
cannaboids and tpin when test is 100
bucks and carbohydrate tests is $400 per
test so it's limit
um so we appreciate everyone that can
can help us out so we can't end the
drying section until we talk about
freeze drying a lot more and more people
are talking about freeze drying what is
freeze drying and is it really the
future uh I I've played with it a lot I
have
um in my opinion I think for bubble has
I think for any sort of concentrate
extraction that it's great and and it's
got a place now I've seen some companies
go out and buy millions of dollars of
equipment and freeze dryers just for
outdoor smokable flour and I tell you
the ROI is not there um so just to give
you an idea I have a freeze dryer and
it's just one of the you know small
2x three maybe Harvest rights um and
that is $3,500 with the pump and
everything um and it'll hold what a
pound and it takes 24 to 48 hours to run
the one pound so you can imagine um just
a two
lighter you know how how long and how
expensive that process is so from a
standpoint of Roi and making your money
back I can't see how that could be
feasible um from a flower standpoint it
keeps it the greenest I've ever seen um
but it's also very tricky to get the set
points just right um I've done it and
I've seen a lot of people do it where
you put it through the process and it's
you know just it's just
dust um but it it it keeps the plan
exactly how it is when you harvest it
let's just put it that way so if we are
finding that certain things like starch
sugar
conversions um other certain aspects
like that are important for that smoke
you're certainly not going to get it
with a freeze dryer um because again it
it pauses it in time you know any any
set starch that's there will be there at
the at the end of the freeze during
cycle wow so it could actually be a bad
thing it could be well interesting well
it's priced too high for me so I'm not
going to be doing any time soon I think
it's yeah for the average hom grower I
mean that that price is is crazy maybe
the the future it'll come down you know
there'll be competition more people
releasing freeze drying machines but uh
as of right now yeah I think it's kind
of price a little bit too high and too
lengthy of a process for the average
home grower agreed so moving on to
curing what is curing and what happens
during it so in my eyes curing is is not
just dry curing separated you know very
discrete separate times of treatment to
the flower uh it's really post Harvest
handling so
um it it all comes to go
together with looking at the changes
that are happening the the carbohydrate
status um it's going from a very wet
plant where changes are fast to a more
dry plant where the changes are slowing
down because the water's not there and
available to let those enzymatic
processes happen
um
and so in my mind it's it's a it's a
onef swoop um in order to prepare the
flower for use
um so you know people will say oh it's
for
um for sweating for um just very
generalized answers making the flower
better but you know again here I am in
my stance of that's my guess of of
carbohydrate change um but won't
necessarily be able to answer that 100%
confidence until next year I say next
year uh 123 25 we get on this talk again
and um I'm hoping we have very different
or actually I'm hoping we have the same
answers just with some data and details
behind it well we know that burping
there is things that are happening right
so burping a lot of folks know about
this basic method to where after it's
dried it's putting into a jar turkey bag
or Grove bags and they're actually
removing the lid of the jar and off
gassing has happened and I know there's
been studies I think it was Dr James fa
who is talking about the studies done
the off gasing the CO2 levels O2 levels
ethylene are you able to talk about any
of that yeah so ethylene is you know I
don't think it's looked at enough um and
I understand why it's very tricky to
measure uh but if you look at cuting so
poinsetta cuting that are shipped from
Guatemala to the us for our Christmas
poinsettas if you're thinking
about those pieces of plant um fruits
and vegetables there's so much money and
so many businesses that exist just to
control ethylene um because it is in
short a ripening
agent um we have been able to measure
ethylene and so we know that
ethylene uh the amount that's produced
is Extreme in growing and
drying not as much as when the plant has
dried out so during curing really um so
we know the levels are extremely high
but we don't know if that is a good
thing or if it is a bad thing um because
maybe we do want the plant to ripen
which then is doing all of its
conversions it needs to by having this
push of Ethylene
or is it beneficial actually to get down
to a certain drying point and then stop
the ethylene
production um because you don't want it
to go too far but again what are those
metric points along the graph that we
need to know here
stop um and so Dr F and I share an
ethylene sensor and it uh it's finicky
it's finicky you need a little bit of
humidity you don't zero it out properly
it throws crazy numbers so I feel like
it's been a boot camp just learning how
to use it properly um so that is is
going to be a a goal this year um we're
doing a study with a company that that H
that makes post Harvest let's just say I
can't announce who yet but curing
containers um and they're very excited
about the thought of ethylene and what
it could do or does but again it's just
an exploration experiment it's not we're
producing a product for them to
implement um and so to be H this goes
back to our our previous conversation is
you know a lot of the sponsorship money
is simply going towards exploration
because we don't know what the starting
points are yet to to alter that one way
or the other um so you know experiment
one is putting flour in different types
of containers and doing do measurements
and that gives you your
Baseline where uh after that you can say
all right well at day five let's jack up
the ethylene content and um see what
changes happened so yeah ethylene I
believe is um a very
important gas we need to take in account
um and and start to figure out and
hopefully again this is the year to do
it um but O2 and CO2 to is also very
important um you know it's I would
encourage you if you have a sensor and
as a home grower especially because if
you're using a mini
split um you're recirculating that air
and so even though you're recirculating
that air and you're adding your CO2
because your plants are taking the CO2
away what does that mean about your
ethylene are you also just compounding
your ethylene content since you're not
actually bringing in uh fresh sourced
air I was talking with a
grower uh probably within the past year
and he has a a dry room that went out of
commission so he had to use an old dry
an old growing room to dry in well
because it was a growing room he had a
CO2 sensor in there and the numbers that
the plants drying or producing which he
would never would have looked at the CO2
content if it had not and in him dry in
the grow room which measures it um and
the numbers were like well past what's
safe for a human to go in um and so you
know again I don't know what
that what does that equate to exactly I
don't know but when you have levels of
anything out of whack so extreme you
need to understand and be able to apply
apply optimization behind it and so it
it's just it's wild being in an industry
that we're still on many things
extraction you know especially on the
patient side patients understanding all
the different canabo everything at
exploration right now um so yeah it's
exciting but it's frustrating having to
repeat you don't know so many times but
none of us do right yeah still a lot to
learn still a lot to uncover and I agree
with you very exciting that's one of the
reasons why I like to be in this
industry you know I said in my videos
times in the past is doing the same
thing over and over again I mean that
gets boring to me being able to learn
new things un cover new things try new
ways to grow it's exciting it's fun for
me and so it makes a job more enjoyable
so yeah looking forward to seeing what
gets uncovered there in the future so
with so many different ways to cure or
store jars turkey bags Grove bags what
have you found to be the best method and
then are there any of those methods that
you would say aren't good to do and you
should avoid um you know it always comes
back to there's a there's a million ways
to skin a cat um and a lot of my work is
is really working with the the large
scale Growers who you know is looking at
every penny spent um so for example sake
even though stainless still is great and
it's easily cleanable and it doesn't
break like glass and it does a good job
you know would it be possible for a
commercial grower to go out and buy all
stainless steel containers for thousands
of pounds no probably not so you know a
lot of my time and work is spent looking
at those limitations of of really
commercializing on a large scale and
making the best call based from that um
now if I'm at home and I'm growing my
own and I'm putting it in my own you
know resource that's available there for
me and there's no
limitations I probably would use glass I
probably would use glass yeah I would
use
glass so that that's my short personal
answer um but that's not always the
answer for large production got it yeah
I know you hear through the grave Vine
of people being concerned about
microplastics you know so the turkey
bags Grove bags so on and so forth but
from what I'm understanding there's no
really research to back that up that's
just kind of a theory at this point so
it be interesting to see if anything
gets uncovered there you know that that
would be terrible if microplastics were
leaking in there and we're consuming
them and there always something to worry
about
yeah storage want to ask you one more
question in regards to storage so
storage temperature a lot of people
store in you know 60° Fahrenheit roughly
say the higher the temperature the more
Turin are going to volatize you're going
to lose it right but the lower the
temperature goes down I'm being told
it's okay A lot of people are storing in
a wine fridge that's about 50 60 deges
fahrenheit that's one of my preferred
ways to store some people in
refrigerators which is just above
freezing right uh typically what 33 to
maybe
44° F any concerns in storing in a wine
fridge or a refrigerator no I I think
that's the best the best move um I would
just be very certain that the container
seals properly you know whatever
container you're in is is sealed um cuz
even in a refrigerator even though it
would be slower it still can dry out um
if it's not maned properly so getting
your drying down your curing and then
holding um at the exact water activity
you want in the lower temperature yeah I
mean the the lower you can go the better
um but I know some people they don't
necessarily have a a full wine fridge
just for their their curing which would
be pretty cool do you have that I do
yeah I was using the wine fridge before
the canol oh okay cool yeah because you
know I live in Las Vegas and it's very
hot here and natural room temperature
it's I'm lucky to get 70° Fahrenheit
room temperature normally it's 75
sometimes 80° and I used to just store
it in those conditions and within 3
months Browning happening like those
higher temperatures really degrade the
product you know so uh once I switched
over to storing in the wine fridge and
yes I have them in sealed jars I also
did in the Grove bags made sure the
humidity was locked in at 60 to 62% but
putting it in that lower temperature
conserved them for a lot longer you know
and I didn't have any Browning you know
I could have it for a year and there's
no Browning happening so yeah I was a
big proponent of the wine fridge not for
drying I want to be clear on that some
people were trying drying in a wine
fridge katrol now it's just for drying
and curing I think one of the biggest
benefits of the canol is the drying a
lot of people think oh well I'll just
buy a wine fridge it's like well go
ahead and try to dry in a wine fridge
it's you know you're not going to get a
good result unless you do some sort of
alteration to it anyways yeah I am a
proponent of the wine fridge for storage
in particular and just wanted to kind of
pick your brain a little bit on storing
at 60° versus in a refrigerator at 40°
if there's any any big difference
between those two I think like you said
it's just the length of shelf stability
um the colder you keep it the slower any
of those degradation processes are and
um the longer it lasts
so yeah I think it all just matters of
how pick you are with perfection and and
wanting to keep it as green and and
really Longevity if you know you're
going to smoke at all in in a month then
maybe it's not
necessarily required to have your own
fridge for for that and it'll do just
fine in the in a you know temp tempature
control room um but yeah the the cooler
I would say the longer is really the
takeaway good to know couple more
questions for you one of them in regards
to any studies that have been done
recently in the past year or two that
have uh revealed some valuable
information that you feel like would be
valuable to the audience you know
there's there's a couple studies out of
ug that have I don't know if they've
been published yet but it was a post
Harvest study um and she was looking at
Tarpin and um and hemp at different
curing but you again going back to this
this all
exploration um hers was very dirty with
you know the barn hanging the the 6060
method was the the best representation
and then she was looking at some of the
Techni techniques she would do with uh
tobacco so you know fire curing and and
those sorts of things so you know
there's been some studies and some nice
generalizations we're able to conclude
from them but you know if you're looking
for extremely high quality smokable flow
at least I haven't seen it in the past
couple of years um cuz again a lot of it
has been on hemp with really the thought
being outdoor hemp that you're drying
fast for isolate production one exciting
thing we've gun um and about to start
phase one on which we could certainly
use your help on getting the word out on
this so um are you familiar with miabi
shields and um Riley um yes yep okay so
they're they're both phds and uh
basically PL plant chemistry they both
have a little bit different specialty in
each and so they now run the nonprofit
nap the network of applied pharmac
cognacy
and so we've we've been friends for a
while and been trying to find a way to
work together and so we've now figured
it out um we want to we want to do a
large pro project that's called this
we're calling it the science of smok
ability um
because basically everything from
flushing to the Joint being in your
hands is what we're looking at um and
really trying to put understand
around what means or what represents a
smooth
smoke what is it about the color of Ash
that
matters
um there's been people say that certain
smokes can make their tum tingly and go
Nom which I've never experienced that so
that one's going to be a little hard
harder to dig into but um some of these
generalities that everybody expects you
know I want my ash white I want it to be
smooth I want it cure for 5 months you
know we we really want to look at again
the the end point so consumer preference
and back it up to be able to say what's
doing what and so that's a lot to cover
um and so we're breaking it into phases
with phase one it's going to be pretty
easy pretty
straightforward you have flower it it's
all ground to the same um Micron size
it's all um packed to the same density
and it is all the same water
content um excuse me it's not the same
water content you've got different water
contents cuz we said all right well
that'll be the easiest is simply looking
at water content and so some with a a 04
6 and 08 so you've got a high you've got
a low and you've got what everybody says
is just right all right very easy to get
joints at three different contents like
that that send those out to the public
people that's interested in the in the
study and have it double blinded and
then the people say all right well this
SM smells the best this tastes the best
this smokes the best um you know we
we'll get super nitty-gritty into the uh
the patient discovery which thankfully
they've got experience on cuz I'm
usually just with the plant but they're
really good at connecting the plant and
the treatment with the person and and
how how to gather data from uh from a
person you know that's not something I
have specialty and um so that's where we
kind of all come together as a as a nice
group ranging from you know growing all
the way to to smoking so phase one water
content we're going to have CBD joints
and we'll be mailing them out and
getting test results back and and see
what's going on I mean the past 2 years
I've done dug so hard into tobacco
research it's it's been ridiculous but
um you know if you think about
cigarettes if you're smoker and you go
to one State versus the other or if it's
two years difference you're going to
expect that cigarette to be exactly the
same and you're going to be mad if it's
not um and so there's science and
there's repetition and there's there's a
lot that's going in to get that
cigarette exact um and that's what we
can do in cannabis you know we know we
know when good ones are good
um and there's Growers that can produce
good ones consistently but can
you how do you convert that to be able
to show other Growers this is what's
good um until you have data behind that
you can't so that is our goal is first
start with water content and then we'll
go on other things like uh certain
elements that can accumulate that causes
a bad smoke there's certain elements
that can accumulate that um that will
cause the Ash to break off faster than
others um so phase two will be um
elements cuz in
tobacco they go deep into you know even
the the government restricting certain
applications of certain fertilizers in
excess
because it will mess with the smoking
process super interesting I follow both
of them on social media and they're
always coming out with interesting
information speaking of social media
Let's uh let's wrap things up can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and what you have upcoming in the future
yeah absolutely so Instagram of course
we've got um dr. Justice uhor gross and
that's my Instagram and then of course
the CRC is just uh canis research
Alliance look us up there we've got
websites um easily googleable I won't
spell out all the long names the hit
mine is our CBD brand and
yeah follow us on basically all social
media platforms awesome and I'll
definitely have a link to her Instagram
down in the YouTube description section
below so you can easily navigate to that
and find her if I missed any questions
that you think that relate to harvesting
drying or curing drop them down in the
comment section below love reading
through the questions and maybe if
there's enough questions we can get her
back on and see if we can get some of
these questions answered so Dr Allison
thank you so much for coming on today I
appreciate it this has been uh this has
been a great talk and I think uh my
audience is going to get a lot of value
from it so thank you for your time today
and I hope you enjoy the rest of your
day yeah thanks for having me talk to
you soon peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode