what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching my extra channel here I
have the hlg 100 v2 LED grow light this
is a 3000 K color temperature
this unit has LM 301 B diodes and I'm
going to be doing a part test today for
this test I'm going to use the apogee MQ
500 power meter this meter measures a
certain range it measures from 389 90
meters to 692 nanometers plus or minus 5
nanometers measurements are in two ppfd
and this is just gonna give you a
general idea of what the power output is
for this grow light it's not meant to be
a 100% accurate test it's in a grow tent
so the reflective walls could throw
things off a bit and I have the grow
tent open so one side isn't even getting
the reflective walls but again this is
just for to give you guys a general idea
of what the power measurements are this
girl light has a flowering coverage area
of a two foot by two foot and this grow
10 is a 2 foot by 4 foot so I'm going to
keep the power meter on one side of the
tent I'm going to do three different
distances 12 inches away 18 inches away
and then 24 inches away just like all
the other power videos I will let the
measurements do the talking
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
I still have four potentially five more
part test videos coming at you those
will be released in the upcoming weeks
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave that that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]