welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into to the
Garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 164 in this episode I interview
soul brother he is an indoor Gardener
and is the winner of pimp migro season 1
he started out gardening with a severe
lack of equipment and after winning pin
my grow he now has it all he talks about
what his setup entailed and how he grew
his plants before versus how it is now
after winning the setup if you want to
see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
cloudray S9 oscillating fan this 9-in
fan features a redesigned build with
carbon steel gears and ip44 rating it
has 10 precise levels of fan speeds and
dynamic win modes which allow you to
recreate the natural flow of air so your
plants feel as if they're outside
there's more to it so click the link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about their cloudray S9
oscillating fan and the discount code Mr
Gro 15 works on both Amazon and they
website AC infiniti.com stash blend
stash blend is a 215 plant additive that
can be used with synthetic bottle
nutrients or in living soil systems
simply mix half teaspoon of stash blend
into a gallon of water then water your
plants with it ingredients include corn
steep liquor seaweed extract humic acid
beneficial bacteria silica and micro
risal fungi check it out at stash
blend.com Link in the description
section below and use to discount code
the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with soul brother how you doing today yo
yo how's it going doing good man thanks
for coming on to the podcast today you
are the winner of the AC infinti pimp
your grow season 1 and it's been a year
since you've actually had the new setup
from them and I'm really excited to sit
down with you today and really talk
about before when you had the barebones
basics almost nothing for grow equipment
to having it all you know a complete
setup Automation and all that stuff so
really looking forward to hearing about
your progress over the past year and uh
yeah it should be a good conversation oh
yeah I appreciate you actually uh
bringing me along and giving me a chance
to talk about everything and since a
year has been a lot since like the
process has changed so much though this
is going to be dope I can't believe it's
been a year man time has been flying
that's for sure it's weird bro super
weird
super weird but before we get too deep
into talking about things can you give
us an introduction tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah so um I go by so brother
the seeds um I'm originally from Los
Angeles
California uh I got into Garden
gardening um not really intentionally
I'll say my first time planning anything
at all was um probably about like uh
Elementary School ages um
just um with my grandmother
um I I was raised with like my cousins
my sisters my brothers all in like one
house my grandmother had a house that
was big enough to where like my mom or
anybody that would have
problems that needed like place to stay
we all go to my grandma's house and
everybody else was busy my my cousin's
like doing like they were dancing like
in Dan's Cruise like doing all this
stuff and I didn't know i' do none of
that so um most of my time I would spend
with my grandma like in the garden like
um just learning random things I didn't
even realize I was learning at the time
I was too busy into bugs and like rly
poliy and all that like I was already in
the dirt so she was like oh hand me this
hand me that and um I grew uh Keys like
I think they were snow PE the first
guack I went over there to Home Depot
grabbed one of the Burpee packs and
threw that along side of her actual
plant and uh yeah that was my first son
kind of sprout that's awesome and
getting into your gross style cckm
fromong you're indoor only I believe
you're in soil is that right and then
are you growing with Organic inputs or
synthetic so I'm going uh I'm growing
with Organic right now um my last round
I did uh try synthetic but it ended up
being like a syic mix that was not the
best idea um but um before that I was
organic so I was like I'm going back to
our G that was the best way for me I
feel like I was able to like
uh get more like leave like get more
time with my PL some in bed or anything
like that if uh I had any issues it
would give me a couple days to fix those
issues rather than like immediate same
day with Coco like if if you up it's
going to show you like today or tomorrow
and you only got the next day or the day
before to fix it if not you're done and
um that was just a little stressful for
me I I do want to learn down the line I
feel like um if you're growing Coco as a
beginner then um you got to do a lot
more education and a lot more like you
got to watch a lot more videos read a
lot more books byy as many books as you
can before you actually grow the plant
if I was to advise another beginner I'll
tell them to grow um in soil just
because it's going to give them time to
actually learn what they need to do and
um learn about Coco while you're growing
in soil and then go back to Coco yeah I
think each way has its own kind of
benefits and drawbacks right there are
so many like pros and cons to growing in
all these different methods and yeah it
kind of comes down to trying things out
like you mentioned and uh finding out
what works best for you yeah soil does
suck with like uh overwatering you can
overwater and it will kind of stay there
for a couple days um with Coco if you
over water is probably going to run out
and then you get kind of turn up the
heat or do whatever with your BPD to get
that water out soil you're going to get
PM if you try to do all
that um that's the only difference that
I've found I'm pretty sure there's a lot
more I got to learn down the line but um
right now I feel like soil was uh a
better thing for me I know based off of
like uh previously being into reptiles
and bugs and things like that I know
what just needs to go into uh soil to
keep it living so to keep other things
living um and it's just the easiest way
to go for me I hear you on that one for
sure so I want to warp back to your old
grow setup pretend like you're walking
into your grow room can you explain what
equipment you had back then how was set
up how many plants you were growing so
on and so forth so yeah when I
um previously I would say like a month
or two before the Pimp My grow
um before you guys all came out I was
like trying different things that I was
on offer up and I was on like Facebook
groups like getting different tents and
trying to they were all like T they
would have like holes in them a little
rip on the side or something like but uh
there's uh the room that you guys ended
up coming that had a couple plants in I
think if you go back to my YouTube uh
couple previous videos before that I had
uh huge 10 by10 I got from somebody on
offer of with no like uh uh I still had
the small light in there um there was no
intake fan there was no like fans moving
around the air and I kept walking in
that one room you guys came in to help
build out it pretty much you couldn't
even walk it was like you walk in barely
be able to crack the door and walked in
there and it was like 100° bro and I was
only able to do that for a couple days I
was like this is crazy there's no way
I'm going to be able to do this um this
is super cheap like almost can't tent so
I ended up taking that out and at that
time I had so many plants that uh it
just wasn't working out I didn't know
how to like control my VPD I didn't know
how to do any of that especially with
the stuff I had I was still trying but
um I I would I would watch videos I knew
what I was supposed to get Target wise
it just wasn't hitting from me things
and and areas and different type of tin
that wasn't marking so
um originally when you guys hit me up uh
Joe told me he was like yo this is this
is really dope you know I see everything
you're doing but
um we can't come when there's in all
these plants bro this has to be proper
and um I thought that was sick I was
like you know this is super dope um and
I ended up basically
uh making
um everything the way it it needed to be
to be like you know to have have a dope
show and um I I took so many plants to
my girlfriend's
house it it was wild like uh in in the
the big U-Haul boxes that you hang cloes
in I like packed those in and took all
my plants to my girlfriend's house and
by that time that I had to bring
everything back and everything it was
just everything was so dead and
everything was so bent over
and it was just it was wild a wild
time definitely a moment to remember
forever but it's such a crazy story yeah
I remember walking into your old setup
and you had the light how did you how
you it was on some sort of I'm trying to
think of what he even call that it was a
two two tripod post for like regular
lights I think like the uh I forgot the
brain but two regular
um soft light sticks tripods and a pole
across it for hanging backdrop and I had
a Viper Spectra 150 on one side and I
believe yeah I think two Viper specters
hanging on that it was just giving the
plants enough light to keep them alive
and it was open room at that point there
was no air exhausting out the room at
all it's kind of just like not even a
sealed room room um but yeah when you
guys came I was like on the verge of
like like my it was almost over from my
plans like almost over for my growing
career in general I didn't even know
that it could go any farther or go like
I had all these dreams and stuff but I
didn't know that I could keep going I
didn't know I was going to be afford to
keep going any of this stuff so when you
guys reach out and I actually like
uh not one I was like what the hell cuz
uh I originally seen the link one of my
friends sent sent a link and it was like
a video already made and I was like no
way I'm not there's no reason for me to
even sign up with and I signed up and
actually got hit up and I was like
there's no way I've never won anything
in my life this is a wild then these are
people I watch every at that point I was
watching your two channels from the
stash this channel um there's a guy
named John ker um grow your greens
that's like one of my favorite YouTubers
I was watching those three channels
um I don't know but that I I was doing
that all day long and growing and um so
I was trying to learn from basically all
those channels I felt like was that
would actually teach people to grow
different plants um fruits and you know
more things than the
normal Community would assume that
you're growing and um when I got a
chance to meet you guys that's why I was
so excited I was like yo Chris like you
have no idea but the I I respect it more
because there your knowled is uh
alongside with other plants yeah there
are so many different plants that you
can grow and I know people focus on one
or two different plants but uh yeah it's
exciting and they all bring in their own
unique challenges but yeah going back to
the the light yeah actually kind of
innovative having those on the softbox
tripods and then I guess that's the way
you're able to adjusted I remember you
didn't even have like light ratchets on
there I think it was just like no it was
two string and like other things that
would look like rope yeah it was like
the ghetto pulley system you definitely
had a lot of struggles there from the
lighting to no intake fan no ventilation
no oscillating fans it was wow and then
at the same time that that place was
like the building was like from the 80s
or 7s like filthy and
it was just it it was so hard to deal
with sorry to cut you off but that yeah
thank God I'm out of there heat issues
airflow issues man it was just not
optimal for growing I got to ask how did
this you know lack of equipment impact
plan Health yield overall growing
efficiency everything
um I would say I guess I'm going get
into later when you ask about the new
been try not to lean more towards that
right now but I would say it was just so
hot and like uh I'm learning now that
it's not really all about like uh as
much light intake as everybody is like
preaching on preaching on I understand
it but I'm believing airflow is way more
important way more important airf flow
getting rid of the air and bringing in
and keeping the freshest air if not the
air that that biome or whatever it is
whether it's for plants ants whatever it
is keep that air to or make fresh air in
that area you're going to have the best
thriving environment that you want
that's really the truth besides like
light light is going to like in every
environment needs their own light and
even like how they say the this is weird
but how they say the world spins like
our light is going to change for us
throughout our lifetime so so you can't
say that needs to stay like this 20 50
years later is going to be the rules are
going to change so it's just a lot
more a little Stoner thought but yeah
yeah cuz back then you weren't even
really controlling the environment right
temperature relative humidity CO2 air
circulation all of that was kind of like
I want say neglected right cuz you just
didn't have the equipment to do anything
right it was hope I I had a I had a
small 6 in like a AC Infinity fan that I
got from uh it's a girl named Coco Endor
on um Instagram and uh he actually was
the one that was like yo bro you should
just actually start growing like you
should make a YouTube you should make a
Instagram I was like why would I do that
like why would I show people gr like
that's
crazy and um he was actually growing
autos for years beforehand and I was
like I was working with him to learn
like different things like that um but
he actually was like yeah one of the
ones that told me yo you kind of know
what you're doing so do it you know that
little small intake fan that I had was
uh I didn't
understand why it wasn't working I
didn't have the can to it I didn't have
like it was
just and I was using it as a fan to blow
out uh the air from one side of the tent
at the bottom and I was leave the other
side open so it was just cleaning the
air at all times I thought that was
doing something but not at all was
making everything Snell way louder than
it need and plants look shitty complete
shambles I think is a a good way to
explain your grow setup but things have
changed man let's fast forward to your
new grow setup explain what your grow
room looks like now so now um currently
I have a
I um I have moved back to like with
family and things like that I have a 4x8
setup like behind me I have a 2X two the
propagation tent for um ceilings but
I've just been um working with the 4x8
and the 2x2 I still have um the
5x5 to work with here at this location
but the um other enser with my cousin um
Earl's blunt worth I've been trying to
like tell people about on Instagram ear
bunworth he's uh just getting into
growing and he's uh in Victorville
actually like the valley side of
California and same thing with like uh
chubs that's why I'm like really into
chubs because uh my cousin's son has
seizures like constantly sometimes every
day sometimes M I reach out for chub I
was like yo like that story everything
you're doing really inspired me kind of
help my cousin have him do something and
give him something to do and like his
son like so CH was like yeah if you want
like come through my crib sometime and I
still haven't been but that little thing
like people being actual real people I I
assume when I see like AI pictures or
like a a cartoon on the Instagram I just
I don't know why I assume all these
people are fake I think they're like not
real people and then I see people like
that chub has never had that chub has a
real picture but when I see people and I
hear real IC things is just reassure so
much for me bro it's crazy yeah there's
so many nice people in this community
that will literally take their shirt off
your back for you if needed and uh it's
really really cool to see yeah so yeah
from what I remember when the new setup
with AC Infinity I know you had
mentioned that you're no longer in that
location that we set up the grow room in
right yeah you're in a different
location but back then it was uh I think
you had two 4x8 a 5x5 and a 2x4 right
yes sir so you had a drying a dedicated
drying tent which I think you're using
as a 5x5 the two 4x8 were both for
growing plants and then the 2x4 was for
clones and and seedlings is that right
that's what I wanted to do but I ended
up growing so many like I would just pop
beans every week bro I I still have the
problem for sure like i' I'm saying I
have a 2X two and 4x8 but there's
there's beans in my bathroom there's
beans in in my closet like there's beans
anywhere I can fit it's wild like every
couple days I'm popping beans um that
was a problem with that um like I said I
have the two
4x8 and the 5x5 and the I forgot what
the other one size wasse but um I ended
up having two veg tints two and two
flower tints so there was a flower tint
that was ready to go there was a flower
tint that was like probably 2 3 weeks
after that and there was like jeans and
then there germ so everything was pretty
much on a 3 we
like pretty close cycle to be able to
flip and then um when I learned or um at
that point I kind of like uh got offers
when I thought was like a job
opportunity to move out of state and
like work in the um flower
business oh man this is going to be dope
and I was like whatever I got to do chop
everything down pack this up um I
actually let a male rock out in this
room and then cross to my female so when
I get to location I don't have to take
any um clones I don't have to like try
to like keep anything alive when I get
to my location I'm run everything and
something good and that's kind of what
ended up happening but I still have to
cut everything and flow a little bit
early probably like week seven week
eight like early eight so um yeah doing
all that and cutting everything down was
kind of like a buzz kill
but not getting that opportunity made me
realize and made me reach back out to
the family members like yo you need to
move back to LA like you need to move
back to what are you doing there nobody
there and I ended up moving back to Cali
and so much better like I see my family
every day like and I have the plants
growing in Vegas I was uh I had the
plants but every day like I only ate and
I only like I only did things like .1
miles away from where I was I was
watching everything at all times like if
people invited me somewhere I would pop
out for like 15 minutes and then they
like where he go I I was just paranoid I
I always thought someone was like trying
to you
know get what they had to get was while
yeah that was a bad area in Vegas where
you lived where we went that was like
right where the guy got his face a off
on the corner of really oh my gosh yeah
it was L that's terrible but overall
going to this new setup things it sounds
like things have gotten a lot easier for
you you know going from just an open
room to where you really don't have the
flexibility you didn't have the
flexibility to have plants and veg and
plants in flower two different light
cycles really is what I mean now you've
got all these different tents and you
can have them on different light cycles
different stages of growth can you name
some other ways that this new setup is
easier for for you um 100% for um
environment wise I'm actually really
learning like like I said I I've known a
little bit my whole life with like I
used to breed ball pythons different
things like that so with all those
things you have to like they only breed
in a certain temperature they only breed
with certain light like certain time of
the year kind of the same thing but I'm
learning um how to provide the perfect
atmosphere to where like the light and
the um the AC thing like 69 Pro will
kind of like it gauges you through how
to like change that so if your lights
are so hot and you just watered then you
should probably turn your intake fan up
that day and you just water you know
what I'm saying I mean just to get some
air out or what different things like
that like um I'm able to change that
instead of just work it at the same
exact level every time um I don't know
it does so much I can keep naming a
bunch of different things but even with
like
um I still plan on like going further
down like my breeding Lane and there's a
lot of different things like you cannot
have a human D at the end of like trying
to develop power you cannot have like um
different I have to have it in a whole
another area like the fact that I have
another light another tint and basically
a whole another you know grow I can take
to the other side and or family memb
house and still develop my um girl
that's amazing bro I would have never
even I would have thought maybe a couple
years down the line I'm going to do that
I have plans to do that I'm want to work
towards doing that but all those things
are like dreams so so now I actually
can't think like oh I have this project
at least I have the tools like I I know
where they are they're here with me or
they're with family members and I can
put those tools to work at any time
that's that's kind of amazing I did not
know that was POS yeah having that
controller that you mentioned definitely
definitely can make things a lot more
easier controlling the environment are
you using any equipment to control like
the relative humidity such as like a
humidifier or I imagine that you had to
use that in Vegas but now in California
are you using a dehumidifier now or or
still a humidifier not right now not
right now um let me see if I can
actually uh I'll stay here but I was
going to grab my controller to kind of
show but it it's kind of been like a 60
62 humidity and um a little bit high 70s
or like 75 uh temperature so I'm I'm
chilling I'm not worried about changing
that up pretty much it's been solid uh I
have the light level at uh
8 I haven't tried to push it up to
anything further than that they're on uh
week four maybe by the end I'll try to
push to 10 but still since I've had Evo
eights they're so strong I have not
tried to push 10 and running out the way
Joe did tell me he was like bro at 10
from from jump I was like what you're
wild bro but um yeah he said running my
10 bro I don't know wow yeah those
lights are super powerful the Evo series
I have the EVO 3 myself I have two Evo
3s and I have an EVO 6 and like you
mentioned the evo 8 you have a couple of
the evo8 right yeah so uh before I moved
I was running um I was running three at
one time pretty much on at 8 I didn't
realize it was like 3,000 watt lights
older building power builds doing me
like $1,100 almost that was wild I was
like yeah like after took the second um
month cycle of running that many I got
to figure this out I don't think it
takes this much
light but um yeah I ended up taking away
some lights and keeping the same amount
of
plants still checking like you know the
drop off but uh I feel like it was kind
of the same result could be wrong but
like it was kind of the same result with
uh the evo8 I feel like it just really
good yeah that is a really good light
powerful light I don't know anybody who
runs it at 100% I think most people run
it like 80% I know some people run it
50% 60% I'm talking flowering stage too
and of course you can dim it down even
more for the veg stage because you
certainly don't need to be at 100% when
you're in the seedlings for example
that's what I said I was like you trying
to kill my plants
bro but it does make a huge difference
having the optimal lighting you know the
lighting that you need for that grow
space in your old space you had those
Viper spectral wands and I don't even
think it was completely covering the
area as it should have been right so
like yeah no offense to like the company
at all I was just they have higher level
lights they have better you know I just
was using the bare minimum I was being
cheap want to offer up like 30 40 bucks
on 150 wat light and I wanted a couple
of those I feel like I could stretch
them out with the space
I don't advise any new grower to
actually try to maximize with the
minimum I think if you're growing with
the bare minimum you
should like you know go wild with that
minimum space and minimum equipment
instead of like uh overdoing it I was
definitely overdoing it I learned a lot
from what we're doing I learned how to
like you know when you're doing your
math I learned how to show my work [ __ ]
up and like go back and race it not do
that but shouldn't have to go through
those things for like at that Speed most
people will just quit growing for sure
how has plant health and yields changed
from your old setup to your new setup oh
man
um my plants are 10 times more healthy I
haven't really seen any um I haven't
seen many problems besides things that
either the plant is asking for or things
that I'm lacking on like uh CTIC
problems or nitrogen um I have a big
problem with adding in too much nitrogen
sometimes so I have I've had plants in
the um past get lock out I didn't even
know was lock out I was like oh this
plant is so pretty it's dark like this
is the darkest leaf plant ever like I
thought that was beautiful and I slowly
had to learn and like read more and
watch more and learn that that was
actually l out there's some plants there
it's dark naturally but that certain
color is lock out and I I didn't know
that so yeah I feel like that that was a
big thing for me I remember seeing your
gr room the old setup and walking in
there and seeing that's some struggling
plants there like you like you mentioned
earlier what and since then the pictures
you show online Instagram you can
clearly see a difference in there and
you know I hear a lot of people say that
you don't need all this equipment in
order to get healthy plants you probably
don't but it helps it helps out
tremendously having a controller that's
going to automate your environment for
example or or lighting that's going to
provide the sufficient amount of light
for the plants so maybe not having this
Top Line setup that you have now maybe
it's not a requirement but it's
certainly helpful in get in getting a
better result yeah having a Walmart
board versus a skateboard is not a
requirement you can still push down the
street you can uh
like I'm doing flip tricks right now
like this is way better but I don't know
I I just feel like uh if I could tell
anybody else with like a if they were to
get like a 150 watt or anything like
that get it use it but use it for veg
use it for germ don't even use it past a
week or two veg cuz it's not going to
like there's lights that'll literally
make your PL do what it should do after
a week after the second set of leaves it
could pretty much do
it I wouldn't use anything like that for
long I think it's good I think it's good
for germination how about your daily
routine how has that changed having from
basically no equipment to having top of
line equipment um it's a lot more
Stressless I don't know if that's a word
or
term but yeah um I I hand water so
that's a a thing that I still haven't
figured out um but other than that I I
feel like I can leave town for a couple
days I can leave town for like 2 3 days
if especially like you know growing in
soil you have a
2day in between watering most the time
especially with like the medium I'm
using I don't have to water every single
day now that I'm in flour I might have
to water every other day but um yeah I
feel like growing in soil and
with the controller you hook it up to
Wi-Fi so if you go to Disneyland and you
want to go to Florida to visit your
family or things like that I still look
at my stuff I still see what's going on
if you have anybody in town you can have
them go do what you see going on oh this
is going on hopefully I just to do this
work that's huge um before I was kind of
just like scrambling I felt like I was
the only one that could fit any problems
I couldn't go out of town I couldn't
like there's no way like nobody knows my
problems nobody knows what can be fixed
like now it's kind of like a I don't
want to say automated cuz there's like
the new like automated system but it
helps me control myself I have like I've
been saying this ter a lot with my
friend and I talk about a girl and it's
like full control no offense to like
companies growing Autos or anybody that
grows Autos but I don't personally right
now because I really like full
control um I want to know how many days
of veg I can go for I if plant just
decides to do what it wants to do I want
to know how many like if uh right now I
have one gallons in my tent I want to
know that I have this many one gallons
the bare minimum I'm always going to put
the bare minimum at developing uh 28 you
know at the
lowest 28 um at the weight of each one
gallon I'm just going to you know I'm
not going to high help if I know how
many I have and I know how many that
can develop then with the auto you could
never really calculate or predict those
things with um photo periods and having
a system that is controlled that word
control becomes so much more like you
can control every single thing that's
going on even when it comes to like
cutting clones you kind of can control
how many days going to take the Roots
come out well a little bit of it is hope
but if you know what you're doing you
can fully control it wow but having that
controller like you mentioned where you
can basically go into an app on your
phone and be able to not only see what
your conditions are but you can control
the different pieces of equipment
through there as well that's a game
changer yeah that's crazy I it felt the
same way when I went to like the AC
Infinity system using their App instead
of kind of being blind I spent so many
years without that and it is kind of
nervous leaving town because you don't
even know like you just hope that your
plants are going to be good to go you
hope that the the environment conditions
are going to be solid that the lighting
is going to turn on like it should and
turn off like it should you know so yeah
that's definitely a definitely a huge
game changer that's another thing I
forgot um before you you guys came I was
having a problem with um my lighting
like I um was using like the old like
spin wheel
timers and you know it happens I did it
wrong I was probably high but um I uh W
winded back my timer to where somehow it
was a couple more hours of light than it
should be it didn't turn off or it cut
back on and um Lally things were
starting to reveg everything had the
three uh branded everything like every n
it was wild but I wasn't able to catch
that because during those times it was
out I wasn't going to open that door I
was like there's no way I don't need to
go in there like up but um now that I
have the controller I don't really have
to worry about that I will say if you
are new to the controller at all and
you're setting up the controller by hand
I don't think anybody should do that you
need to use the app because there's like
the left and right right button
sometimes will change settings that you
don't even
notice and your lights might cut back on
and the only way to change that is in
the app I've had that happen to two
different people I've seen on Instagram
and I personally messaged them and
they're like yo thank you like this is
wild I I didn't know that was the thing
but yeah have the control over your app
it's so much easier to set up the
controller I completely agree with you
on that one versus trying to do it on
the actual controller so looking back at
you your Evolution from a struggling
grow room to a high-tech operation what
advice would you have for Growers
considering a similar upgrade my
personal
advice is really think about what you're
growing for really think about if you
just like there's nothing wrong with
people like house plants and different
flowers all that exists and I truly
believe that s 5% of our community are
men that are afraid to admit that they
want to just see something gr that's why
some people choose to grow Autos some
people veg for like a week some people
they just like to see something grow and
they don't want to they don't want to
grow no flower so I think that um I I
don't know I I I feel like we should put
more into growing more things than
just that
I hear you yeah getting the experience
with other plants can certainly be
beneficial some plants can be treated
the same but often times there are
little differences here and there and uh
yeah I went from starting growing
medicinal plants then vegetables leafy
greens I started out with peppers
tomatoes now I've got trees in my
backyard so uh I've just been kind of
continuing to move on and on and on and
learn more about the different plants
it's definitely uh definitely something
I enjoy a lot
how do you do that in Vegas well there
are a bunch of plants that bunch of
trees that can Thrive out here things
like figs pomegranate citrus trees they
actually really Thrive out here there's
some Apple varieties I I'm looking to
get a couple of those pears so um yeah
it can be done out here you're naming a
lot of stuff that I expected to be such
water consumers I didn't think was
postive um have you ever met John ker
col I don't know if I'm pronounce his
last name right but have you met him uh
grow grow Your Greens I actually ran
into him that MJ biscon probably like
three or four years ago now yes so I had
a conversation with him in person nice
guy that dude's cool that D's super good
so we have quite a few folks here that
are looking for genetics they're
shopping for genetics and they don't
really know what to get so I've been
asking folks that have been coming on
the podcast recently what genetics do
you like can you name maybe the top
three strains that you've grown and what
you've liked about them
top top three I would say um two I'm
going to feel in pretty quick just
because they were the first things I
grew that I was like wow this is this is
what is a difference you know I didn't
um give them the due diligence they
probably should have got but exotic
genetics and soire those are great I
really believe that like if you're
trying to get into growing like Exotics
or different things like different
flavor profiles then that's somebody you
should go to if you're looking into
breeding or if you're looking into
growing um different things that wasn't
like aren't exactly in the rules of what
like uh the way things should
go but you're looking for something
crazy that nobody is going to have I
think people should go through Masonic
that's my top three um Masonic smoker um
um the genetics and sire those are three
good Masonic is so reasonable on price
sometimes like $10 $25 for like
sometimes 40 beans and um the other two
they're a little pricey but I still
think all three years Super worth it
awesome all right well I appreciate you
sharing that information with us let's
wrap things up here can you tell
listeners how they can find you and what
you have upcoming in the future um yeah
so if you want to find me you can find
me at Instagram so brother the SE
um YouTube so the 420 or so the SE and
in the future I am working on uh podcast
right now I'm you know kind of writing
down the pre scripts or like pre
questions and reaching out to people I
feel like would fit best for my podcast
which is going to have to do with the
flower we all love and
um being paranoid you know being
paranoid and and different things like
that and people automatically like a lot
of people I reach out to they were like
what are you talking about you're going
to talk about um like being paranoid
things like that it's not going to be
necessarily what people are thinking
we're not going to talk about sometimes
we might talk about like Al or UFOs
things like that but I want to talk
about the paranoia and the plant we love
bringing a bag of soil home and you
might get something we all don't want
you know what I'm saying or like uh
really diving into become and a tester
for somebody that you're really
represented and something goes wrong
like there's so many things that can
happen that I feel like are vague and
people should talk about as we know what
he talks about and um there's ways to
talk about it without disrespect of
people I would love to do that that's
awesome man yeah I'm looking forward to
seeing what you come out with in the
future I'll definitely have a link to
Soul Brothers YouTube channel down in
the description section below and also
has a pinned comment so you can easily
get to it give him a subscription and
want to give a big thanks to the folks
that support on patreon
patreon.com mrgo it 100% of what is
donated through patreon goes right back
on the podcast the folks being scrolled
on the screen right now are in the
producer tier special thanks to you I'd
love to know in the comment section
below what questions do you have for
soul brother he's somebody who has
experience going from basically nothing
to having it all so definitely leave
some questions down in the comment
section below and maybe if you sometime
he'll pop in there and answer a few of
them oh yeah appreciate you for giving
me the chance to actually talk to
everyone and talk to you about things I
feel like I wanted to talk about and um
yeah this community is something
different I've uh working on music in my
life doing a bunch of different things
that involve uh outside communities that
you've never met and this is the nicest
uh most there's unsupportive but 80%
more supportive people this community in
any other
community thank you guys uh if you want
to reach out ask some questions like
Chris said um There's the link and or
you know spot down there where you
should come get it but yeah thank you
guys and um have a good day thanks so
much for sharing your journey man I
really was eager to hear about how
things have changed since going from
where you started to where you are now
and it's really awesome to hear the
success you've been having so thanks so
much for taking the time today to share
with all of us thank you bro um I
appreciate it and you have a good day
and hopefully you and the kiddo go watch
some TV and out all right everybody
peace out catch you in the next episode