what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you watch a mattress channel got a topic
video for you today
this one was requested by a viewer he
wants me to talk about par so in this
video I'm gonna talk about par I'll talk
about what the optimal power levels are
for growing plants and also talk about
PPF and ppfd which are measurements of
par so first off what is par par stands
for a photosynthetically active
radiation it's the energy that your
plants use in order to grow the light
emitted from the grill light are photons
think of them as little balls of energy
falling down onto your plant then of
course your plant takes those photons
and uses them for the photosynthesis
process so how much power does your
plants need there's a couple of
different measurements that you can look
at PPF is the first thing that you can
look at PP f stands for photosynthetic
photon flux basically what that is is
the total light output that it fix your
emits when growers are shopping for
grill lights and I have to get people
hit me up asking me which grow lights to
buy one of the things I recommend them
to look at is the PPF now there is such
thing as giving your plants too much
light and of course you don't want to be
in a situation when you're not giving
your plants enough light so making sure
the grill lights you're looking to buy
has enough PPF for that grow space is
important in my opinion so what are the
optimal PPF levels for growing plants
well it really varies depending on what
plant you're looking to grow the chart
I'm about to show you right now are the
optimal levels of for growing m.j plants
now if you're growing some other type of
plants such as like leafy greens lettuce
bok choy spinach things like that
you won't need as intense PPF levels
that I'm about to show so on the screen
right now I'm showing the PPF levels
which are optimal for MJ plants now I
got this list from Eric from LED grow
light depot this is actually part of
their LED buyers checklist and it's one
of the top things that are mentioned on
the checklist so as you can see here if
you're in a 5 foot by 5 foot area around
1,500 micro moles per second PPF is
sufficient for that grow space around
1100 to 1500 micro moles per second PPF
for a full 45 4-foot area around 600 to
800 50 micro moles per second PPF
is going to be sufficient for a 3 foot
by 3 foot area and around 275
- 375 micro moles per second PPF is
going to be good for a 2 foot by 2 foot
area these PPF numbers are just a
general guideline somebody may reply in
the comment section and say that they go
after different PPF numbers so just keep
that in mind so that's one of the things
you can look at when you're shopping for
an LED grow light now unfortunately not
all grow light listings are going to
have a PPS number some manufacturers
just don't post a PPF number if they do
bonus you have something to go by if not
then you're kind of out a lot there I
noticed that on LED grow light Depot
website most of the listings seem to
have a PPF number which is great LED
grow light Depot is one of the companies
that I recommend I actually have a link
down in the description section below
and they have some of the top lights
some of the best lights for growing MJ
plants now if you're trying to buy a
light off of Amazon most of those lights
unfortunately aren't gonna list PPF data
so for those listings that don't show
PPF data something else you can look at
is ppfd
instead a ppfd stands for photosynthetic
photon flux density and basically what
that is is a spot check it's gonna tell
you in a particular spot what is the
power output on the screen right now
show you what the optimal ppfd
measurements are for m.j plants and this
is going by the light that is actually
hitting your plants so the optimal
levels for seedlings clones and other
plants are between 200 and 400 ppfd and
the vegetation stage it's often one to
hit your plants with 400 to 600 ppfd and
the flowering stage 600 to 900 ppfd is
optimal now these numbers are without
supplementing co2 if you're
supplementing co2 in your grow room you
can increase these numbers you can go
for higher part numbers just like the
PPF numbers that I showed you these ppfd
numbers are just general guidelines
somebody might comment on this video and
say that they go after different ppfd
numbers so just keep that in mind now
there are a ton of other things that we
can talk about when we're talking about
lighting I do just want to keep this
video to par PPF ppfd
if there any other topics that you want
me to cover that relate to lighting let
me know in the comment section below
just to give you a quick update on
what's upcoming on this channel the next
video I'm gonna actually hit you with a
part test Ida
were recommend a particular grow light
that he wanted to see a part test done
on so I reached out to that company and
actually got them to Sevilla light so
that'll be coming up next and in the
video after that will be another Q&amp;A
video so if you haven't already hit that
subscribe button and click the bell to
be notified when I release a new video
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave that that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
[Music]