coming up on garden talk we are
continuing to add
diversity um as we build up these worm
bins
and then of course anything that's
organic matter that soil food web is
going to break that down into
carbon and carbon is basically like the
currency if you will of the soil food
web
you know if you're not monitoring the
temperatures you can basically ruin
maybe a couple weeks to a couple months
worth of work so that's very frustrating
when you first start out
he knows to poop and pee in the worm bin
so i have
probably 15 100 gallon worm bins
down in my basement i focus on
freeze-dried
corn and it has to be freeze-dried
that's how it still has the nutrients in
it non-gmo obviously organic and then
the main secret ingredient that i feel
when you're really
focusing on getting worms to breed other
than avocado tech
is focusing on
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 21.
in this episode i interview brian
wachsman brian is the host of the show
living soil conversations here on
youtube which oftentimes gets
10 to 20 000 views per episode he has
been gardening for 12 years
and focuses on educating the gardening
community from living soil systems
vermiculture beneficial insects and more
in this episode we talk about making
worm castings
and vermicompost by utilizing worm bins
we also get a little bit into beneficial
insects which can be in worm bins as
well as living soil systems
don't forget to click that thumbs up and
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already
if you're listening to this podcast on
apple podcast please leave a rating and
review
and if you're liking these episodes and
you want to support the podcast even
more
you can do that through patreon the link
is patreon.com
mr growit and if you're watching on
youtube i will link it down in the
description section below
before we get into the episode i'd like
to give a shout out to our sponsors
the first sponsor is spider farmer
spider farmer is now the exclusive led
grow light sponsor
for this podcast they make led grill
lights with quality components
and sell them at a lower price than
comparable fixtures on the market
i've been using their sf2000 led grid
light for several grows now
and have used their sf 4000 in the past
they also have
other style lights grow tents an inline
fan
and a carbon filter i will leave a link
to spider farmer down in the description
section below
and you can use discount code mr grow at
5 during checkout
for a discount on their products second
sponsor is dutch pro nutrients
dutch pro is a plant fertilizer company
that was established in amsterdam 30
years ago
and as of a few years ago their
nutrients are now available in the u.s
and several countries across the world
they have everything needed for proper
plant nutrition
from base nutrients ph regulators and
additives like silica
calmag and more i'll be using the
nutrients in showing my results on my
main youtube channel
in the upcoming months i'll leave a link
to their amazon store down in the
description section below
and you can use coupon code mrgrowit10dp
for discount on their products all right
now let's get to the episode
all right we are back garden talk
podcast today i am joined with brian
wassmann how are you doing today
i'm doing will sir appreciate the invite
yeah thanks for coming on
i'm super excited to have you on today
you know a lot about vermiculture
vermicomposting and that's really what
we're going to get into today so
i'm actually brand new to it i wanted to
get a worm bin going
i kind of have in my plans but i haven't
yet pulled the trigger yet there's some
research that i need to do before i go
about that
but hoping to learn some things from you
today that
will allow me to pull that trigger and
get going and
so my audience actually is more towards
the beginner slash
intermediate side of things and we
haven't covered that
topic at all on this channel so i'm
going to be learning right along with my
audience today
so excellent well you know it's really
all about building soil so it doesn't
really matter what you're farming
as long as you understand the soil food
web as long as you continue to educate
yourself on
how to build soil systems how to make
them become alive and thriving
that's really the end goal of whatever
you decide to farm
and so the one of the main secrets i'm
going to kind of talk about today and
you'll see for yourself
is that composting worms use um their
hermaphrodites and as soon as they touch
each other they want to reproduce
and once they really uh ball up like a
gumball effect
that creates what's known as biofilm so
they're going to create all that biofilm
and then once that
organic matter is broken down they're
going to continue through that soil
system
and basically you know start to build
and dig those dissolved oxygen channels
which is really what you're after when
you're a soil farmer gotcha
so before we get too deep into things
can you just tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening
yeah absolutely my name is brian
walksman i'm from
uh basically grew up in atlanta georgia
i feel like i
became a man in savannah georgia really
started to learn a lot about
just plants in general i was you know
trying to make a
small living for myself trying to do
things i got a
you know really it's almost like
whatever i want to try to do
that i feel like i can make money with i
focused on and at that time
online poker was really big so i got
really deep into that started to
be able to provide a a decent life for
myself
i moved to colorado continued to kind of
hone those skills
and then april 15 2011
uh the government shut all that down um
and so i
foolishly i guess thought that i was
going to do that for the rest of my life
um definitely it wasn't as it wasn't
glamorous or anything like that i didn't
have the skill set to be a glamorous
poker player but
um playing online and stuff allowed me
to at least work from home if you will
uh that kind of thing so when that was
taken away from me they also
froze the funds that you had in your
account so i had a full tilt account
an ultimate bet account like absolute
kind of same thing absolute poker
account
and when those were frozen i really had
no other skill set
i hadn't graduated from college or
anything so
the only really um you know where am i
going to go from here is when i started
to study soil sciences and that's when i
actually started to
learn about people like dr elaine ingham
from that i learned
about a guy named jeff lowenfels he's
wrote
you know three books that i feel like
you know your audience should definitely
view as like a blueprint for
understanding things
um and it's simple to remember teaming
with microbes teaming with nutrients and
teaming with fungi
i would personally recommend especially
if you're new to this uh to just read
the teaming with
microbes book then in my opinion read
the teaming with fungi book the third
book and then come back to his second
book
because that one for me as far as being
educated in georgia
that book was a little hard for me so i
felt like if you can understand concepts
and maybe see some more verbage
that you recognize that second book's
going to be a little bit easier
so yeah i was kind of forced into
understanding
our new path at least because yeah the
government literally shut it down on
tax day uh 2011. so let's start with
kind of the basics what is vermiculture
and what is vermont composting
so vermiculture is basically you know
you're going out of your way
to make sure that there really are no
mistakes so instead of
composting yourself what's also kind of
known as hot composting
vermiculture is a simple definition as
you're using composting worms to break
down organic matter
and one of the easiest ways to do that
is in my opinion using
four different composting worms i'm
going to get into that in a minute
but that really is kind of the basic and
then really get into vermic
from a cast which is worm castings
vermiculture all that kind of stuff to
me just really means that we're using
composting worms
in conjunction with other things in the
soil food web
uh springtail mites rogue beetles again
we're going to get into all that stuff
but we're using a
symbiotic relationship most things in
mother nature that
are beneficial are going to work in
harmony with one another
so as long as we understand creating
diversity
and we really focus on moving things
kind of more
towards as best we can especially in an
indoor environment to the old growth
forest
the easier it's going to be for us as a
farmer so pretty much
like the end goal for this process would
be to
obtain either vermicompost or like a
worm castings is that right and how much
can you like how long does this process
actually take
uh so when we're getting into the worm
castings that really is the the black
gold if you will
um when we're farming that's kind of the
stuff that can change
it's an inoculant in my opinion uh yes
it provides nutrients but that's not
necessarily what we're after
we're just after viewing it as an
inoculation
and so you know the large fields like if
you're a
major manufacturer of a warm farm you
know a million worms is probably doing
700 pounds of worm castings every single
day
to bring that down to scale for the you
know for the rest of us that are doing
this in our basements and that kind of
stuff
in the backyard you're going to need
about 2 000
of those composting worms and when i say
composting worms i'm usually referring
to red wigglers with these numbers
they have to be optimal conditions but
they're going to create about seven
pounds every month for you
so in my opinion you need to kind of
start with at least 2 000
again in optimal conditions they're
going to completely double their
population every 90 days
so that extra 1000 that you buy in my
opinion is worth it since it'll go to
basically two
four eight um and not you know with math
i feel like buying that extra thousand
if you
if you can get maybe four thousand uh to
start
that's really where i guess basically
it's how quickly are you wanting to
quote unquote by time
because once you've purchased composting
worms you're never going to have to
purchase those again as long as you uh
maintain the system
okay so to start the process really i
think starting with the container
you know like i mentioned a lot of my
growers a lot of the people who tuned in
to me are
more home growth side of things so i'm
assuming they're going to be working in
small containers i know you're probably
more of like a larger container type
thing
can you tell us like what container size
you use for it and then also what you
recommend
for someone who's new to use absolutely
and i i want to kind of set this
i feel like i've tried a variety of
different things when you google
they talk about how cheaply you can do
stuff with plastic tubs
i haven't had the success that you're
going to need
as a farmer if you're really trying to
create optimal
um goals with your composting uh worms
and that kind of stuff
you're going to need a fabric pot in my
opinion
so that i go you know i basically view
that as the stomach
that is the stomach of the soil food web
uh the reason why
we are building that up is because we
are trying to create what's known as the
rhizosphere it's just a fancy word for
where all those
uh roots and exudates are feeding that
soil system
um and to really have that um you know
be a thriving and
have it come alive and become thriving
you need to have plenty of oxygen
and so that's why i feel like fabric
pots are where it's at now
since i mentioned that it's a stomach i
would say that the minimal
um if you're going to do this in my
opinion correctly with the
the amount of volume that you're trying
to get then i would say that a 20 gallon
fabric pot
should be minimal that's easy to move
you know
relatively and as things start to build
up you can continue to inoculate
other pots and that kind of stuff so if
you wanted to
maybe have smaller pots i would just say
consider your 20 gallon as your mother
if you're really into this or you know
you're using this to
continue to improve your overall garden
then you're going to want to go to what
i have in my basement which is several
hundred gallon
pots and the reason that i'm doing that
is because i it takes a long time to
create
create those castings especially if you
start with two thousand worms
in a 100 gallon pot that's going to
probably take you a year before that
really starts to churn
so again it's how quickly do you want
things uh to take hold and if you have
time and you don't have a lot of money
that's where you know just understanding
and being proactive and
you know if you're if you're starting a
little project and you know that's three
months down the road this is something
that i always tell um
consulting clients as well as our
audience and that kind of thing is
be so proactive that the first thing you
do before you even start to
you know set up your tent or build your
your grow out
uh or or focus on your backyard farm
is to get that that worm bin going so
that you have your fresh
uh you know what went into worm castings
all right so for those that are new
they've got their 20 gallon container or
whatever size they're using
what's the starting material what do
they put in there to begin yeah so i
actually um
i wanted to make sure that i had this so
i have this in front of me so that you
guys can have a blueprint that i feel
like for a beginner
this is where it's at in my opinion
this has come from a lot of research
over the years
and again this is in my opinion very
basic so
this is something where you can start
out kind of see how your system
becomes alive and thriving and then you
can continue on and
try to understand more about natural
farming techniques or
biodynamic farming living soil you know
there's a variety of different like
tentacles that come
from that main octopus of organic
farming
and so when i would focus on this uh the
base that i personally like to do is i
like to get the lava rocks
that's something that i feel like you
know especially when you're building
these up this is something that's going
to
pretty much last forever so i take that
uh
lava rock again this is you know i'm
doing this cheap and basic
there's this stuff called pit moss if
money isn't an issue for you that
ethically is better than canadians
phagnum peat moss
but again that stuff is really cheap you
can actually get an organic if it comes
from canada
as far as i understand all of that is
organic um so
if you go to lowe's there's a bunch of
compressed bricks and that kind of stuff
that you can get for extremely cheap
like 11
12 bucks and that's going to last you
probably months
so i will take that canadian sphagnum
peat moss and then you kind of lightly
cover
all of that lava rock on that next layer
i'm i'm focusing on bri
kind of bringing back that old growth
forest again how do we
in a way kind of set the tone with that
i like to use that alaskan hummus
it doesn't really matter what brand just
using that older
alaskan humus and then i will again
drizzle that over
if again money isn't an object i might
buy two or three of those bags
um if you're just kind of starting out
one will get you by but again
it's time that's going to really get
everything churning um then i will
basically start with like a light food
layer for the
the worms that we're going to start to
build up so i focus on coral calcium for
that
i focus on freeze-dried corn and it has
to be freeze-dried that's how it still
has the nutrients in it
non-gmo obviously organic and then the
main secret ingredient that i feel when
you're really
focusing on getting worms to breed other
than avocado tech
is focusing on nutritional yeast so that
is a tried and true secret that i have
found
that just seems to be a cheap um
overall feed instead of having to buy
like the expensive worm chow and worm
food and that kind of stuff
in my opinion it's extremely overpriced
compared to
mixing up your own nutritional yeast
fried street freeze-dried corn
and then a little bit of that coral
calcium and again calcium is really
what's going to get those
composting worms to be able to reproduce
so then after i've laid that i missed
what's known as
sunshine in a bottle or it's a bio ag
product
full power again that's a tried and true
secret that i feel like to kind of get
everything going
that's a light mist again this is you
don't want to go overboard with this
kind of stuff especially when you're
starting things that you know
and setting things up so again just a
light mist with that
and then i will cover all of that again
with a little bit of that sphagnum peat
moss
and then my first worms come in which
are known as the alabama jumpers the
georgia jumpers
those are the ones that are going to be
deeper into that system they're going
for the most part to be able to stay
down into that system
these are fabulous also if you're really
trying to break things down
they go through clay like butter and
these are you know i would say i've only
been really playing around with these
for maybe a year and a half to two years
so it's still something new they are an
invasive species so
for people that are concerned about that
again we're just doing this in our warm
bins and you know
inside i wouldn't be releasing this
stuff outside
and then once everything starts to kind
of settle in
i would really focus to keep things
cheap around 300 to 500 of those
alabama georgia jumpers then i will add
the
pumice and the rice holes again i feel
like that is a tried and true secret
with perlite if you're adding stuff like
that or vermiculite or
god forbid vermiculite kind of stuff
especially perlite that's going to start
to float to the
to the top over time i feel like a lot
of the older
farmers older heads have known that from
experience so when you're using perlite
to me it's kind of silly because that
stuff's going to go up
if you're focused on you know building
beds building raised
raised beds especially or building these
worm bins that you know
you want to can you know hold on to for
years and years on
on end pearlite is silly so again it's
that pumice it's the rice holes that are
going to break that down
and then i'm going to add um what are
known as the european nightcrawlers or
the african nightcrawlers
those are a little bit different the
european night crawlers are a thicker
worm bigger worm
also because of that it feels like it's
a slower
worm for like breeding and that kind of
stuff in my experience
so i use those mainly to build larger
dissolved oxygen channels
so again probably about three to five
hundred of those
now with the african nightcrawlers
they're kind of like a nice little
hybrid between the red wigglers and the
european nightcrawlers
so i really focus on having the majority
of
kind of in that middle section of
african night crawlers over the
europeans
over the europeans just because of uh
the speed and everything that the
africans can kind of take off i feel
like it's more of like a
a sportier version of a composting worm
um and then once everything is kind of
building up and layering out
again i feel like a real secret is to
kind of go more to
leaves twigs sticks and if you put that
in the oven for 200 at 200 degrees for
around 20 minutes 30 minutes maybe to be
safe
you're going to kill anything that could
potentially be in there i have found
that
worms especially really like to break
down oak leaves and magnolia leaves
so that's something that i personally
will spend a little bit of money on
if i'm trying to speed things up it just
seems to be like another one of those
little secret sauce and then once those
magnolia leaves once the oak leaves are
starting to get in there
i will add kind of the basic stuff that
you've always heard
newspaper egg cartons kind of building
up
um the brown manure kind of thing tree
bark
and again this is kind of layering
things out but it doesn't have to be an
exact science
they're going to churn all this stuff
anyway so it's kind of silly to sit out
and
um you know and i encourage you guys to
make more than one
one of these like if you're going to do
a 20 gallon then make three 20 gallons
and kind of see how
wow these the processes are going to be
different for each one of those and then
if you continue to farm and you want to
improve your skill sets and then
you know one day you maybe get to a
large commercial level that's going to
really come in handy when you understand
how to improve a sluggish soil system
because you've been worn
warm farming for all these years and
then once that starts to take hold
again i will kind of just finish off and
and maybe about three to four inches of
that canadian sphagnum peat moss again
that's just a cheap
a cheap medium if you will to start to
build those things up and then of course
of course those composting worms in time
are going to break all of that down into
to castings and then at the top
is really the the secret sauce for just
life in general
you know most of the the the real action
that's going on
with the soil food web is probably
between the one inch to four inch range
and that's where
the red wigglers those are the
composting worms that most people have
probably heard of
anytime you google anything and it's
talking about composting worms
that's usually the variety that they're
talking about and
they're not as ferocious
you know as long as you maintain
population so again you don't want to
get crazy with this and if something for
whatever reason did get out of control
for the most part they will
self-regulate uh but it's it's pretty
easy to also
uh like i'll talk later with avocado
tech is to be able to get the worms to
come to a certain area and then just
take that avocado and put it into
and inoculate another soil bit and just
to go back on the the worms
for example you mentioned four different
types of worms right
somebody's brand new can they just get
away with just starting with red red
wigglers and just
doing that alone or what absolutely i
mean if they want to
kind of just experience this and again
it's you know pennies on the dollar you
want to see this for yourself
then the red wigglers are probably where
it's at because they're going to be the
hardiest worms
i personally have never had them escape
even in like a um
forgotten dusty basic past plastic bin
left in the corner
where uh some of the other ones because
they are larger
composting worms they're going to escape
that
when they when there's not a food source
anymore so that's one of the main things
again where i say focus on that fabric
pot
is because i've never had them escape
since i've been using fabric pots
okay so you touched on browns a little
bit i know from my understanding and
correct me if i'm wrong
they say that you should when you're
adding in inputs
have a balance of green and browns i've
heard 50 percent
as kind of the ratio of greens to browns
can you tell me
is that accurate and then also can you
give me some more examples of
greens and browns that people can add
absolutely
in my experience man i've noticed that
if i am just adding greens if i'm adding
something that is just greens
i'm going to have issues with that so
technically anytime
that i add greens i still add a little
bit of a filler of brown where
it's like newspaper or cardboard or
something like that
i just found from my own experience that
i have better success with that
i also don't feed the worm bins any kind
of like
real food or anything um i focus on like
i said that that food
chow that i was talking about and then
we um
we focus on also using lionhead rabbits
so we're using cold manures you can also
use alpaca manure that kind of stuff so
we're using cold composting
theory and with using the composting
worms and then we're also feeding with
cold manures as well
which is going to minimize for a new
farmer any kind of issues or
you know especially when you're
composting regular composting
sometimes you can get that you know if
you're not monitoring the
temperatures you can basically ruin
maybe a couple weeks to a couple months
worth of work
so that's very frustrating when you
first start out that's why i
you know anybody that's starting out
just composting in general that's why
i try to teach them how you start out
with vermicomposting because it's a lot
easier
and it's not as frustrating because
obviously they're not they're not making
mistakes
uh so again with the green manures we
really want to focus on
cover crops when we first started out i
felt like everybody was talking about
clovers
but we found that that attracts too many
bugs too many issues
so we use the dicondja which is
basically like
a um a cover crop of just plant material
right it's just kind of like protecting
the soil
again this is a shout out to a steve
cantwell of greenlife productions
he's really the the forefront of that
there are a lot of people
himself included that was talking about
always using a
clover a variety of different clovers
but
the new up-to-date version is that we're
gonna use that dicondra because it's not
going to
give us really any issues and there's
other ways to add nitrogen to the system
so we like to focus uh you know when
we're when we're building our worm bins
this is totally different than when
we're building our raised beds for
for other cultivation techniques uh so
um
you know usually some of the the plants
that i the medicinal plants that i like
you know we like to cultivate uh their
roots are actually going to go more of a
in a width pattern and they're going to
continue to go out
where when i'm focusing on building a
worm bins i want to use
dynamic accumulators i want those deeper
roots to go
deep down into that system especially if
i'm using 100 gallon or 200 gallon
fabric pot so it's a little bit
different uh you know if you're using a
20 gallon pot i don't think that dynamic
community accumulators are going to be
worthwhile
just because it's not really a bigger
deep enough
pot but if you are at the 100 200 gallon
ratio
that's where you get into like the
dandelions the chickweeds
uh the nettles uh the daikon radish
uh comfrey especially the bucking
comfrey
those are things that i feel like are
going to be game changers for you when
you start to see that
we are continuing to add diversity as we
build up these worm bins
and then of course anything that's
organic matter that soil food web is
going to break that down into
carbon and carbon is basically like the
currency if you will of the soil food
web
so the more exchanges that can go on
just the overall utopia that you're
trying to build
and i guess with greens to add with that
again coming back to like the avocado
tech
that's something else that i feel like
you know you want to make sure that
you're always adding organic avocados
and if you can i you know i like to we
have a
grocery store called sprouts here we
also have one name natural grocers
so you can go and talk to the produce
manager and say like hey what do you
guys
do with your organic avocados once
they've turned brown because that's
actually when you want to use those
um when you're using avocado tech and a
lot of those guys will sell them to you
for
you know maybe a quarter apiece maybe
less some of them will even give them to
you for free
the main stickler on that is again you
want to make sure that they're organic
and the way to always know that is the
the grocery stores will put a nine
before any other number as long as
organic so if you
walk into a grocery store and there's
avocados on the left and avocados on the
right
the one that has the nine before any
other numbers that's going to be your
organic choice
and i feel like as long as you maintain
that you're never going to add
potential issues to your soil system by
in my opinion going cheap
and it's really relatively inexpensive
you know when you're buying organic
avocados in general but for avocado tech
i think
if you're really trying to do it in the
right way you're trying to find avocados
that nobody was going to use
or you know your family uses it and then
you put it in there and that kind of
thing
so let's get a little bit deeper into
avocado tech because i know a lot of my
viewers are
newer like i mentioned and a lot of
people thought avocado tech what's that
can you uh could you explain what that
is and how you actually do that
yeah well there's actually two versions
of it so i want to give credit where
credit's due
i feel like our little crew in denver
colorado we have
uh avocado tech 1.0 and then there's a
gentleman named blue of green tank
and in my opinion he created uh avocado
tech 2.0
so what i'm teaching you guys today is
the basic stuff avocado tech 1.0
and then i encourage you to go check him
out on instagram he also has
been on several podcasts where he
discusses kind of taking this to the
next level
and using a variety of different things
than just avocados
but the basic avocado tech is simple
you're going to take
a pretty close to starting to rot uh
avocado so that's nice and easy to
manipulate
you're going to kind of push that
together like a baked potato
and you're going to cut an x into it
like a baked potato
pop open so that you see the fleshy part
you're going to take that fleshy part
and you're going to then
take it down and shimmy it down into
your living soil system
now i don't recommend doing avocado tech
until your system has become
kind of alive it doesn't necessarily
have to be thriving but you definitely
want
uh you know when you pull back that soil
to see those worms
to see those springtails and once you
see that with the naked eye
then you can implement this system uh
the reason i say that is if you leave an
avocado out there and there's not enough
composting worms to devour that in time
it could potentially uh be a nuisance
add fungus gnats and stuff so again
there's a
kind of like a balance with this a
goldilocks approach of knowing
when to add the avocado and you know if
they're not breaking it down quick
enough
when to remove the avocado so in optimal
conditions
what's going to happen is the composting
worms are going to start to
crawl up into that avocado they're
excited by the fats
they be more and more begin to
accumulate within that avocado
and then they begin to touch each other
like i mentioned at the beginning of
composting worms are hermaphrodites
meaning they're male and female so all
they really have to do is touch each
other
and then it's brown cow brown chicken
brown caltime and the reason why that's
going to the next level is because we're
able to get those to kind of
consolidate in one little area and that
starts to build up the biofilm that
starts to build up uh
in my opinion the real secret sauce of
what living soil is
and that's getting back to mother nature
so once those avocado starts to
break down and build up you're going to
since they all
started to reproduce you're going to see
just a pocket of these little white
when you first see them you might think
it's like an outbreak of a
non-beneficial
but they're extremely tiny little white
worms
you'll see them start to kind of be
around the area where that avocado
once was if you do have enough of a
system that's you know it's it would
definitely have to be
probably a year or two in they will
break down that avocado pit as well
if it's a newer system that's probably
not going to happen so i usually will
take those avocados
out maybe smash them and then apply a
top dressing
now that's to get composting worms
there's another version of this when
we're trying to get orbital mites
predatory mites we're trying to you know
against spend pennies on the dollar for
some of this stuff and so with that
we're going to take the same avocado but
instead of cutting it open like a baked
potato
we're going to cut that in half so now
you have two halves of the
avocado you're going to take that down
again shimmy it down into that soil
system and because it
has more air more exposure the
mites will actually take hold of that a
lot faster than the
composting worms so you will still get
composting worms when you use the
second method but it's not going to be
that gumball effect that you're after so
if you're really after building up the
composting worms then that first baked
baked potato style method that's the one
that you're going to want to use
and again that's going to work for red
wigglers european night crawlers african
night crawlers
and the georgia alabama jumpers so it
doesn't really necessarily matter
and again this is going to build up the
springtails the rogue beetles really
everything that's involved this is kind
of a little catalyst if you will
to spark up that life and you can put
these all over your soil systems or if
you're in a larger commercial facility i
mean you can put these all over your
raised beds
so that again if you're being proactive
you might be able to take 2 000 worms
and put them into each 4x4 bed
that you yourself have farmed over these
last three months
and save the owner operators you know a
ridiculous amount of money especially
when you're first starting to get things
up
shipping the worms is extremely costly
sometimes depending on where you are
it costs more to ship the worms than it
does the actual worms
so that uh prohibits a lot of this kind
of stuff and i encourage people to
you know you want to go out of your way
to be local i like peer-to-peer kind of
stuff especially if you're working to
try to get inoculants
shout out to marco is growing that's
another gentleman that i know that's
going out of his way to not only teach
about natural farming techniques
but is continuing to now breed
beneficials for the community as well
because unfortunately for a lot of that
stuff it's still extremely expensive
for the larger cultivator to be able to
farm with beneficials
effectively let's get a little deeper
into beneficials i think that's a great
segue to it
springtails rove beetles there's some
beneficial insects and as you mentioned
they're not known in your living soil
but
you're saying that they can be in your
worm bin as well right so
can you talk just a little bit about
springtails rogue beetles kind of
introduction to them and and how they're
beneficial and so on and so forth
absolutely so my first uh meeting with
springtails is i really didn't
understand what they were
i started to water you know day after
day week after week and i would notice
after a while some of the fabric pots
some of them had a little bit of that
snow that started to pop up
and then a lot of the ones uh would pop
up and it looked like kind of like
christmas morning over there
so i went to google i started to find
out what our springtail mites and i
would
i promise you the first probably two
pages when you google that
it's all about how to get rid of
springtails that they are a nuisance
so i personally freaked out i threw away
genetics that to this day
still kind of stinks not realizing that
you know what i've really done is kind
of over
populated the springtails so again in
moderation with things
uh but there wasn't channels like yours
you know there wasn't a mr grower where
i could just sit here and
take a few hours out of my day and
really learn dialed in things on how to
improve
uh for us back then it was just on
forums and sometimes you know
take you know you ask a question back
then it might take three four days for
somebody to give you an
answer uh so this is what's really cool
about digital media and that kind of
stuff and where it's taking is just
information in general
has gone through the roof and hats off
to the younger
younger guys the early 20 type
individuals because i feel like they're
going to really be the future and the
voice of a
living soil organic style movement
because they understand it from a to z
or at least they're starting to
for sure yeah i know when i first came
across springtails i was like what the
heck are these how do i get rid of them
you know and then realizing that they
were beneficial
from there um but you're not gonna see
that that's that's the real issue is you
gotta kind of uh
already know to look for that
information and again springtails are
just uh
organic decomposers they're just
breaking down organic matter in
conjunction
in conjunction in a symbiotic
relationship uh
with your composting worms and then what
i also like to
use especially in worm bins are what's
known as isopods or roly-polies
they basically kind of do the same thing
in springtails so those are two little
extra things
that you can have that are going to
really maintain your worm populations by
breaking down organic matter so that
there's enough food there's no reason
for those worms to escape
and then again it's once that system
becomes alive and thriving
there's really not really there's not
really that much you have to do to
maintain the system
other than feed it obviously watering
the system and every now and then using
maybe some avocado tech
but the beneficials what you're really
trying to do there is
inoculate and inoculate for cheap
especially with rove beetles
i personally like to use praying mantis
for the medicinal plants that i use
the beauty of that is you can buy little
egg sacs they usually come in
you know two or four when you hatch
those out it kind of becomes like an
apple alpha battle royale
so uh they'll be maybe 150 to 200 per
egg sac
they are going to basically start to eat
each other battle each other
the alphas will emerge the alphas that
come out of that will start to feed on
smaller insects
at that time they're brown so they're
working themselves
finding things to eliminate in that soil
system
as they start to mature they'll turn
pink
and for a moment there while they're
pink they're usually kind of the most
vulnerable so they'll
they'll also still be in the soil but
they'll they'll start to
get confidence to go up into the stock
and as they become an adult that's when
you'll see them either turn
brown or green or at least the ones that
i personally have
used there's super fancy ones like
orchid prang mantis but
you know for money-wise that's
definitely not something you'd be using
in your garden
but you know your basic praying mantis
once that turns green
uh they're kind of like watch dogs if
you will and so as long as they don't
get too close to each other
if they do get too close you can
literally pick them up and then just set
them on
another plant on the other side of the
garden other side of the room
and just keep things moving along the
the one
thing that i will say i used to help
keep them alive by using ladybugs
and i want to kind of set the tone for
that is ladybugs all of the ones that
you purchase at a garden center
those have all come from wild crafted
areas
so they also carry vectors and disease
and kind of that kind of stuff and you
it's not really what you think about at
first you think the ladybug is going to
be beneficial
but the reality is that you want to use
green lacewings
so all of us now that are cultivating
using beneficials focused on living soil
systems
we personally don't even use ladybugs
anymore so using a praying mantis again
you're going to have to use
probably something else to keep them
alive if you don't have major pest
issues
so maybe like a minute pirate bug or an
assassin bug
they will still kind of eat that so you
need to make sure that there's something
for the praying mantis to eat
because they will grow to a pretty large
length and
uh if if environment is well enough i've
had them
me personally live up to a year so again
it's
it's something that is pennies on the
dollar
for a up and up-and-coming farmer wow
yeah that's fascinating that's really
cool
and we're just kind of scratching the
surface here with the beneficial insects
i mean we would go on and on and on and
on
probably i'd do it a whole dedicated
episode to that that would be
awesome but yeah that that's really cool
that's that's cool that it's not only in
like living soil but also it's
fine if it's in your worm bins as well
it's just something that i learned today
so i didn't realize that
that was okay i thought it would just be
worms breaking it down and
you know obviously the microbes and
stuff like that but having all these
other beneficials in there
there's no harm in that so that's that's
pretty cool diversity is what's going to
keep
your soil system alive and healthy
whether that's
in the soil system or you know the the
beneficials that are protecting
the plant material and again real quick
there's something that was called the
hypeosis miles when i
first started out i believe they changed
it now to what's known as the skidimus
predatory mite but if you add that to
your soil system
it's relatively cheap and especially if
you're proactive let's say you
you added it a couple months uh before
you really started farming
that is something that is extremely
beneficial uh and
in my opinion something that is tried
and true for making sure that you don't
have
a pest and disease and with the good
also sometimes come with the bad right
fungus gnats are one of those things
that i think are pretty common when it
comes to like worm bins
you mentioned diversity is going to help
definitely help with the uh the fungus
gnat situation
they thrive in wet mediums right and
correct me if i'm wrong but you're going
to need to have moisture
in your bin at all times so that's where
the fungus and that's kind of come into
play
now that being a challenge what are some
of the things you can do to combat them
uh well one of the main issues coming
from fungus gnats
is that you're probably over watering
there's there's saturation there's
issues with compaction again that's
another reason why
you know you go out of your way to use
the four horsemen of composting worms so
that there's always dissolved oxygen
channels being built
but let's say that you do have a major
issue you have fungus gnats
so the first thing you want to kind of
do is well actually when you're starting
up you will always want to have the
yellow sticky traps
that is not to kill fungus gnats that is
literally just to start to
monitor so if you start to see fungus
gnats in one area of your
operation then you know that that needs
to be handled
so the sticky traps kind of are the
canary in the coal mine but that's
definitely not a
a way to eradicate like i had mentioned
everything is about being proactive with
the living soil system
so again there's that goldilocks
approach we have to keep a living soil
system
uh with a little bit more moisture than
you know the average
uh farmer that's used to using
synthetics
so how do we especially when i was first
crossing over
i was making a lot of mistakes i
obviously was over watering i was over
feeding that's why i had the
you know christmas morning of
springtails i definitely had fungus
gnats for probably two years when i
first started doing this stuff
and it's because i didn't know about uh
you know the schedule is hypiosis miles
or the rove beetle
uh the fact that you could use basically
mother nature to combat mother nature
when things start to
to pop off and again the fungus not
isn't necessarily anything that's going
to
unless it gets out of control it's it's
more of a vector
it's more of a nuisance so we want to
make sure that we just
don't have that issue and that's why i
encourage you guys as warm farmers
i know it sounds great to recycle your
vegetables and and your fruits and all
that kind of stuff but if you are new to
this more than likely
that is where your fungus net issues are
going to come from is that you're over
feeding your worm bins
uh and then that's overfeeding your worm
bins is
probably always going to happen for a
new worm farmer
so why even take that issue why create
that
environment basically a utopia for
fungus gnats is
overfed an over watered soil medium
gotcha one of the things that you
incorporate
you know in worm bins you touched on
earlier is rabbits
can you talk to us about the lionhead
rabbit absolutely so
um i've raised a variety of different
rabbits
and you know the goal at the end of the
day was trying to get them to pee
and poop in the worm bin so you could
have more of a closed-loop system
so i started off with dwarf white
rabbits i would have a couple of them
and i could never potty train them so
we built like a little cage above the
the worm bins and so they would eat and
then when they would poop it would kind
of fall down into the worm bins
but if i personally didn't really like
that i
i like to um interact with the animals
uh you know i have children that kind of
stuff so
it just never felt like the right way so
i tried to
start to research and find other uh
rabbits that
potentially could be a little bit
smarter and to my surprise there's a
rabbit that's called a lionhead rabbit i
actually have it right here i want to
show you guys
so this rabbit is extremely intelligent
you can potty train this rabbit so
he's allowed to go up and down my house
as he pleases just like a
well-trained dog he goes all the way up
to my bedroom my
kid's bedroom down into the basement and
he knows to poop and pee
in the worm bin so i have probably 15
100 gallon worm bins down in my basement
i
would imagine that's helped trained him
to potty train him
but having more than one seem to have
that process
extremely quick and now he's able to run
around
as he pleases go around poop as he
pleases i make sure that i'm feeding
organic food
and then when he's pooping into those
worm bins those worms are
like the night crawlers are coming up at
night to feed so again they're coming up
they're feeding on organic matter
they're feeding on
his name is rick ross the real red cross
so he's
feeding on his uh manure and then
they're coming back down
and basically you know kind of starting
to build
a real subway system if you will for all
of those composting worms and once it
seems like they understand that there
are
uh rabbit manure droppings at the top
everything just really starts to flow
and again this is a cold manure so if
you're a smaller farmer
this rabbit might cost you a hundred
bucks he's going to live for like four
or five years
and i assure you if you're a smaller
farmer you only need one of these little
guys
and you know he's a family pet you know
my children hang out with him like
when they're playing minecraft and that
kind of thing he'll just sit next to him
and they'll hit they'll pet him and that
kind of stuff so
again if you go out of your way to
research a few things
it really is cool to see nature as long
as you have an animal that's
intelligent enough to kind of make the
system work that's where i feel like
even in like an apartment if you lived
in an apartment you could still kind of
have a closed-loop
worm bin and system if you had one
little bunny that you potty trained and
a few pots and that kind of stuff
so again it's it's you know going out of
your way to to think about things and
find ways
uh to be more closed loop even if you
are a tent farmer or a basement farmer
or you're just
kind of growing at your backyard and
that kind of thing what are ways to
minimize
cost because when we first started
farming it that that part never mattered
how much it cost to
to farm the material it was just more
what was the price
at the end of the day well the reality
now is it's all about quality
it's all about medicine regardless of
your growing
tomatoes or other plants you know you
want new
medicinal value also in your your fruits
and your vegetables
i feel like that's the reason why today
you know
just human beings in general uh seem
incredibly pissed off and i feel like
this because a lot of us
are are suffering probably myself
included are suffering from a variety of
different um
deficiencies just like just like our
plants
kind of went on a tangent there but you
know i first when i first started to
notice
the overall health of using a living
soil system i started to get the praying
leaves
on the plants that i was growing i was
using kefir
using other calcium sources that's when
i started to
find out about kombucha's that's when i
started to use kefir
so again i want you guys to encourage
again your you know you're building that
soil system
focus it as a stomach and once you see
how healthy that becomes
i encourage you guys to maybe start
drinking kefir in the morning or have a
kombucha over a soda and start to see
your overall gut health
i could get you know we can get deeper
into that at some point as well but
there's something called autophagy
where basically your body is going to be
able to eat itself
break down those old folded proteins and
if you understand that process
i assure you your life will change if
you have gut issues if you just have
brain fog i personally had those issues
when i was a young man
and now understanding these things i not
a
you know once you understand that it's a
stomach whether it's in the soil system
or right here
uh your life can change dramatically in
your farming and just your overall
health in general wow that's that's very
interesting stuff there for sure
now let me ask you with a rabbit this is
a podcast platform as well
apple podcast spotify so they didn't get
to see that cute rabbit that you just
adorable by the way but um also
what i was going to ask is do you have
any pets along with it like i was
wondering how does it interact with dogs
cats because you said that rabbit's kind
of roaming your house
so no i don't have any cats or dogs
you know there would probably be an
issue with most dogs
unless you kind of have like a golden
retriever or something like that
i've seen that kind of work out uh so
yeah this would be
more if you're trying to figure things
out uh i can put him downstairs in the
basement and he can
you know has he basically has his own
little utopia so you could set it up
that way instead of letting him roam up
through the house the the reality is i
let him roam through the house
uh because my children enjoy it so he
can kind of
and you know these especially a lionhead
because they are so intelligent
they are social creatures so they want
to interact with you you
they want you to pet them you know i we
feed them a variety of things i mean
it's not just
uh hay or something like that he eats
organic
bok choy um carrots cucumbers
i mean you name it radishes so that
we can get that um complete basically
trying to
create that complete manure so that the
worms break that down and again
now we have a complete worm casting and
again that's the inoculant that's not
your
soil system if you just grew in worm
castings i assure you that your plants
would suffer
this is a a less is more type thing you
know a little goes a long way with this
and so when you do have
just 20 30 40 pounds of this stuff as a
smaller time farmer
pass yourself on the back you know
there's really no reason especially if
you're building up living soil systems
uh why you're going to have to go back
to that hydroponics store
you're now going to be able to go to the
grocery store and
and know specific nutrients that that
your soil system needs
makes sense that's really cool all right
i do want to flip it back
to something you talked about you
touched up about it a little bit which
is cover crops
now i didn't know you could have cover
crops in warm bins
that makes me wonder you know lighting
as well if the cover crops will be grown
there's gonna be some sort of lighting
can you talk about
cover crops and worm bins and like the
lighting requirements and so on and so
forth
yeah i would say there's probably not a
lot of people that use worm bins with a
cover crop
the most people that i see are using
like again those plastic tubs
or like a burlap sap
sack uh newspaper that kind of stuff
but the reality is is that you're trying
to build that rhizosphere whether i'm
building a worm bin or i'm building a
soil system in my raised beds
i'm trying to just get everything to
become alive and thriving
and so i need the roots to kind of
make sure that everything takes care of
itself especially with what's known as
exudates
so when we build up that root system
they're going to start
to communicate with the soil microbes on
what is needed
jeff lowenfeld's makes a a great example
of this for
someone that's new to this is it's like
your plants being able to say all right
tonight i would love to have a burger
but you know what tomorrow night i'd
love to have chinese food
or you know if it's more of like a you
understand farming it's more
hey i need a little bit more of nitrogen
i need a little more potassium i need a
little bit more
phosphorous calcium and so the plant
never has deficiencies whatsoever when
you're using a living soil system
and in my opinion man when we say living
soil system what we're really saying is
we're trying to grow with mother nature
indoors and since we um most of us are
forced to
cultivate indoors how do we
you know optimize that in the best way
that we can
and that's why i think living soil
systems are the future for
farming regardless is because it's using
mother nature
to create that as well as using mother
nature to combat
pest issues and the overall health of
your plant
there is an old school saying that you
know brix levels
for some some people believe that 12
percent or higher
sucking incense won't recognize that
that uh plant as food
i i don't know if you know those
percentages are exact but i
do know that if your garden is healthy
and there's almost you know the praying
leaves there's almost like this ah
when you first walk into your room you
are going to
hardly have any pest issues whatsoever
interesting yeah good stuff there
okay so starting from the beginning we
you know we talked about containers we
talked about the size
what to add in there to begin worms
beneficials we went through all that
stuff
now say somebody has all that stuff set
up right what's
like what's day-to-day tasks that they
do right so you wake up in the morning
you walk into your worm bin
what's like a maintenance types task
that you do on a day-to-day basis
this is extremely low maintenance so
again you know my focus would be to
build up that cover crop
and once you have a cover crop that's
going to kind of
protect that soil system but as well
kind of manage and regulate things
the reason why you never see you know
unless man has
intervened there's no bare soil in
nature and the reason for that is
anytime you start to see weeds it's just
trying mother nature's just trying to go
through that progression that cycle
so you know on the left hand side
usually when you look at charts it talks
about like very basic things
very beginning big bacteria that's
starting to form
and then as you go through the
progression and you get to more of the
old growth forest
that's where you'll see higher uh
bacteria to fungal ratios and so i feel
like
uh if you're really trying to grow
medicine you need to have a balance of
that as well so you need to have the
bacteria and you do need to have the
fungal aspects so that's why we're going
to add those
inputs but also grow the cover crop
because it kind of just protects
everything
you can chop and drop if things get out
of control like i said you can use a
lionhead rabbit that will come and munch
all of that cover crop that's starting
to come over your bins i assure you one
rabbit will mow down almost anything
that
you're trying to cultivate on a cover
crop basis
so i'm constantly reapplying seed
because
mr ross over there is is mowing it down
but he's providing such a valuable uh
fertilizer and cold manure
cold fertilizer uh that it's worth it to
me to spend you know
maybe five ten bucks and seed every few
months
uh to to make sure that that process is
as closed looped as it could be for
you know where we are and um and
in a home environment well we have gone
over quite a bit
in this episode i think it is jam-packed
full of good information so wrapping
things up how can listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future yeah so um you know on instagram
i've
gone out of my way like you have mr
growit and i try to educate you know
that's
one of the main things that uh we've
been doing we
we had live events in denver colorado
before anybody would ever
really give living soil guys the time of
day um and where it's progressed is now
we're on instagram so
my handle there is 303 organic cannabis
and if you want to learn more about kind
of what
we're talking about we have a show every
thursday it's called living soil
conversations it's on the future
cannabis project that's run by
peter you know and then of course we
have a
event 7 10 july 10th in tulsa oklahoma
with some of the brightest minds i feel
like maybe a personal friend of ours
a mutual personal friend uh keynote
speaker that we have chris is
brandon rust and then we also have marco
is growing
i'm going to also have another podcast
with him and our launch party is also on
july 10th so
i have a lot of things coming out
there's a lot of behind the
scenes kind of stuff and i honestly man
i really appreciate you
having me on your show when we first
started uh talking about podcasts people
would always mention you so you're
obviously doing something right bro
because a lot of people know about you
really wow that's that's pretty cool
that's awesome
but yeah i highly recommend you guys
check out his show
living soil conversations excellent show
long form content right
you're sitting down with experts for
hours on end talking with them getting
real deep on things
more of the intermediate slash advanced
type discussions
pushing everybody to the next level so
hats off to you for for doing that
you guys are doing a fantastic job over
there that's something i tune into
all the time pretty often to get
information as well
so i highly recommend you guys go over
there um subscribe check out his
show you said every thursday you're on
there every thursday at
11 mountain time 10 pacific awesome
cool all right well all right i will not
take up any more of your time thanks
again once again brian and i hope you
enjoy the rest of your day
appreciate it guys thanks a lot
[Music]
you