coming up on garden talk go ahead and
soak it in dechlorinated water that's
been ph at 5.5 to 5.7 i try to aim rate
at 5.7 that's kind of the sweet spot for
cocoa so if i'm in a seedling stage
looking for the 200 ppm i might make the
compost tea 300 ppm for indoor grows i
don't suggest anything bigger than a
seven gallon you're gonna get some
monstrous plants i generally try to tell
people one gallons three gallons and
five gallons are like really the best
size pots
you're going to get disheartened and
you're not going to want to grow and
you're not going to cultivate because
you're going to feel like you wasted a
whole bunch of money so less less less
less is more
let them brew let them really become
accessible i mean it's a night and day
difference when you feed compost teas
within two days your plants will look
completely different so that's my
favorite thing about organics
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 71. in this
episode i interview derek also known as
chronic he has been gardening for 13
years and grows a variety of plants such
as tomatoes lettuce herbs medicinal
varieties and more he makes his own
super soil and that's what he's going to
talk about in today's episode he also
touches upon compost teas ph ppm
container size and water sources thanks
to all of you support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring
zero cost for information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said i'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible
thanks to spider farmer for being a
sponsor a new grow light they released
here in 2022 is the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co280 grow
space and really want to maximize the
light intensity it has a 10 bar design
for an even light spread pulls 1000
watts from the wall and comes in at 2.9
micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is four feet
by four feet or five feet by five feet
use discount code mr groit5 to save on
all spider farmer products and i'll
leave a link in the video description
section below ac infiniti is a sponsor
of the podcast coupon code mr growit
will get you a discount on their
products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infinity down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
derek from homegrown world how you doing
today
good man thanks for having me how are
you doing
doing pretty good yeah thanks for coming
on i'm super excited about today's topic
we're going to talk all about super
soils and how to create them i think
a lot of people listening in on this a
lot of people garden in general wants to
make things more efficient wants to be
more hands-off the ability to mix up a
soil and then use that one batch
throughout the entire grow so you're
just basically watering in the entire
growth so i think that's a lot of
people's goals i think it's easier said
than done but today we're going to talk
all about that and how you do that and
so on and so forth but first can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yeah
absolutely so i'm an educator for
medicinal plant medicine as well as
various
mycology
forums that i help write guides for and
just in general i educate for
various plant and cultivation purposes
for the last two years i've done it on
youtube instagram and
um as well as my own podcast and
it's been a wonderful experience i've
grown up growing my own plants uh from
lettuce tomatoes to medicinal
mushrooms like shiitake or culinary
mushrooms like pink oysters to just so
many more plants that i'm a huge animal
and herb lover so i definitely gotta get
my own you know mints and peppermints
out of my garden for use in in the
kitchen so it's definitely been a
passion of mine for many years sweet and
then what's your style of gardening are
you indoors outdoors what medium are you
in are you organic could you grow
synthetic inputs and so on so forth so
i've touched uh on a little bit of all
of those i mainly do organic cultivation
with soils now but i've done pretty much
every type of cultivation but i prefer
organic
okay cool
let's get into the first question here
which is what is a supersoil
so zebra soil is essentially well that
phrase was coined by actually for many
people who don't know there was a grower
named subcool
that crafted a very
legendary
it's called a legacy mix actually now
because it's created a legacy for
himself
he unfortunately has passed away but
since then the dank company has kept
this recipe which is basically a
specific blended soil that has the
proper aeration nutrient mixture
acidity level whatever you're seeking as
an individual cultivator to be able to
grow your plant from start to finish
whether it be tomato plants lettuce
anything like that
without having to add nutrients or if
you have to add anything bare minimum of
maybe a topping of earthworm castings so
it's meant to pretty much be completely
uh sufficient with microbiology you know
generally they include
microbial life whether it's you know
some some
different mycorrhizae bacterials and
things like that so
the good stuff that you want in your
garden but it's a mixture that's just a
just a good nutrient blend for your
plants start to finish
yeah i've heard about the sub cools
super soil mix and there's a few other
popular ones out there have you used any
of those mixes or do you have kind of
your own
so i actually do my own blend i've used
coots before once or twice
i think i've used it once back on a farm
years ago in florida i can't guarantee
that but i have used it since then i
like their blend quite a bit
build the soil
sub cools
soil recipes and a few others are ones
that i really want to try
generally i just build my own and
they're very simple it's just with what
i have at my local gardening centers
that just make it affordable so when you
make this super soil talking about
medicinal plants in general there's a
balance of nutrition that has to happen
right so generally speaking a lot of
people notice that in the vegetation
stage the plant typically uptakes more
nitrogen and the flowering stage you've
got there up taking more of the
phosphorus and potassium right so
when you're making this super soil is
there a specific balance that you're
trying to achieve that will last you
throughout your entire throughout the
entire grill or like how does that work
since the plant has different
nutritional needs throughout the
different stages of growth
that's a wonderful question and that's
something that like pretty much every
super soil creator really has to
struggle with um you know dialing in
their recipes i go for the 132 ratio
just right off the gate for npk which is
a you know one ratio of nitrogen to
three ratios of potassium and
two ratios of phosphorus or i think i
got that backwards sorry um but uh
i try to go for that mixture and i try
to keep it simple now if i'm going to
play around and do like maybe two four
eight okay well i'm going to test it i'm
going to see how that runs with the
tomato plant just like how i'm going to
see it it runs with a medicinal plant
and those are the types of things you
have to look for when i tell people
to make their own recipes at home when
i'm looking for my ratio just simple 132
is the
simplistic um
way to make sure that you're not going
to burn your plants and you're going to
have quality enough food now also what
comes into play is ec and ppm when
you're talking about that as well so um
there's a little more variables into it
but 132 is about the ratio that i like
to to keep within
okay
we'll get deeper into the fertilizer and
the amendments that you're using in a
little bit here i know there's a lot of
new folks that are just mixing up soil
for the first time and i think one of
the easier ways for the purposes of
podcast of organization and try to
simplify the information that you're
about to say is is breaking it down into
your base whether it be like a peat or a
cocoa or something else
aeration after that and then kind of
talking about like compost and worm
castings and then the additional
fertilizers and amendments that you put
into it that's kind of really makes up
an entire super soil so starting with
the peat and cocoa are using either one
of those or is it something else that
you're using as a base to begin
so that's actually cocoa is the big one
that i use i just get cocoa blocks i
like there's a few companies i get them
from sometimes i'll just actually snag
the cocoa that's made for reptiles
because it's a little more cleaner
sometimes so it's actually a little
cheaper too
but if they don't have that my reptile
store in the blocks because they're
they're out or something i'll go with
like a rio coco or a um a uh uh just a
your in general uh pro mix coco just go
ahead and break it down or whatever um
but just a coconut husk or coconut
fibers really does good aeration um i i
do prefer sometimes i do prefer peat
moss in my mixes depending on what i'm
going to go ahead and add to it so if
it's going to be a more earthworm heavy
mix i'm going to go ahead and add a
little more peat moss to my mix i find
that it it holds a little more moisture
for the long term versus cocoa cocoa can
really let it out
earthworm castings really like to not
dry out as far as microbial life you
know going after them and things it's a
little more better when it's humid and
things like that so promotes better
bacteria so that's kind of the bases i
like to stick to i don't really stray
away from too many of those i like to
stick to my cocoa
not unfortunately not all cocoa is
created equal
you can get them in
several different ways right the brick
for example is very common to where it's
dried up in a brick and you have to
actually hydrate it first there's uh you
know some people do the rinsing and
buffering or you can get the bag stuff
let's get deeper into coco what do you
do to like prepare the cocoa to begin
okay so that's a that's a wonderful
question because a lot of people skip
this process and even when they tell me
it's like pre-ready or you know it's
been phd or whatever i still do this i
do this with all my cocoa just to make
sure so
first thing is is i go ahead and soak it
in dechlorinated water that's been ph at
5.5 to pop 5.7 i try to aim rate at 5.7
that's kind of the sweet spot for coco
when you're prepping it and i like to
add a kelp extract so i use germ genie
from the company i work with but you can
really use you know if you have a little
bit of kelp meal or any sort of kelp
extra extract you can put it in there
like a tea and basically just allow that
to kind of soak up the nutrients from
the kelp and use a bare minimum i'm
talking about maybe 100 ppm 200 ppm max
you don't really want much you just want
to soak it and allow some nutrients to
do that
you're going to leave that in there for
24 to 48 hours and generally after 48
hours i go ahead and ring it as long as
i'm getting to where it's squeezable out
to where it's just a few drops ringing
out that's the proper moisture you don't
want puddles and puddles of water i'm
talking just maybe you know just a
little puddle in your palm four or five
drops out you squeeze it it's good um
you make sure you drain the excess water
thoroughly and you basically allow i
usually do as a base um about five cups
if i'm mixing uh let's say a five gallon
uh bucket i'll do like five to six cups
of cocoa at the base and then i'll start
adding amendments and i'll usually do a
cup of cocoa every so so often just to
really make sure it's layered through
okay so that's the cocoa and then for
aeration let's talk about that a little
bit are you using any type of aeration
at all such as perlite humus uh or
anything like that pumice is something i
really like to get my hands on when um
the local garden center here has it
sometimes they don't have it so i'll
usually use perlite because it's a
little cheaper
gotcha and then what's the amount you
put in there with that five cups of
cocoa so if i'm doing five cups of cocoa
i usually try to do one to two cups of
perlite and then i'll stack about a cup
up so roughly about three cups to three
and a half cups total so five cups of
cocoa three cups of perlite nice
aeration then i'll do about two and a
half cups of earthworm castings to three
cups of earthworm castings throughout
make a really heavy mixture and then
basically since i don't have a composter
where i live i'm in an apartment i don't
want a compost to be all stinky um i go
ahead and add roots organic 707 blend
which is kind of like a nice even blend
that i like to add has a little bit of
everything in it has some uh
mycorrhizal fungi and then just for
myself i'll go ahead and hit it with a
shot of great white mico so that's kind
of like the blends i like to make
they're a little stronger
now what i'm making more for is uh for
strains that
um i don't plant my seedlings directly
in this mix so generally i use a happy
frog just a very very bare minimum um or
a rockwool cube or or just a cocoa pod
or something like that or a peat moss
pod and i'll get them started whatever
it is tomato plants lettuce plants um or
lettuce you know broccoli cabbage
anything it gets started elsewhere once
it's been adjusted and it can really
start up taking nutrients i like to
stick them into my mixes because they're
a little more hotter or just a little
more more nutrient heavy for the start
you mentioned use worm castings to use
any type of compost at all usually
people either use the worm castings or
the compost or some people will use both
so i don't have access to compost
currently i just use earthworm castings
so that's pretty much all i do it's just
the organic
earthworm castings i get from my local
garden center
we have a composter here in in my garage
but it doesn't get hot enough for it to
compost currently if i was using compost
i would back down on probably how much
earthworm castings i'm using i'd
probably increase uh just a little bit
more of the aeration so instead of
adding more perlite i'd probably add
some play sand to my mixture and just
kind of give it a little bit of a sand
through the mixture kind of i've noticed
that that's getting very popular and i
like seeing that
that that's also where i might think
about swapping the perlite for pumice if
i'm doing a more compost heavy mixture
so those are those are things you would
want to think think about if you do have
compost to access what you're using for
the specific uh aeration tools you know
play sand is a very great granular
tool to aerate some
more heavier or denser types of compost
so that's a yeah great question and then
how about fertilizer to begin i think
you kind of touched upon this but are
you adding like a blend of fertilizer or
you're doing individual amendments into
the soil mix
so it really just depends on how
what kind of gardening i want to do so
if i want a headache free hassle-free
gardening and i want to do mostly just
having to water just ph my water
dechlorinate it not worry about too much
i'm going to go ahead and make compost
teas once bi-weekly and i'm going to
make them um relatively so if i'm in a
seedling stage looking for the 200 ppm i
might make the compost tea 300 ppm why i
do that is because there's going to be
about 150 to 200 active ppms of of
activated uh nutrients accessible after
brewing the tea but then there's still
going to be some of the leftover
nutrients that haven't been completely
digested by the microbial life that we
added to that tea so you're still going
to have like a a leaching factor so i'll
feed my plants with a little bit of
higher ppm and then through the week
while i water them i kind of rid out
that excess 100 ppm that they're
digesting and then all of a sudden you
you see that your plants might show some
greenhouse burn which is for those who
don't know greenhouse burn it's
basically when people take up
plants at your local garden centers and
feed them immensely so that they can
ship them out to walmart or various
places and they're full of nutrients but
they're just burned on the tips but
they're not overly burned so that's kind
of like where i get my plants and then
from there it's just smooth sailing for
two or three weeks and then just the
compost tea you know
two three weeks you know every two or
three weeks and it's just smooth sailing
um if i'm adding amendments it's gonna
be a regiment so that's gonna be where
um i'm gonna go based off my ppm if i'm
starting at seedling stage i'm gonna
look for maybe just simple kelp extracts
or simple types of
feeds that are 100 ppm to 200 ppm i'll
just feed it with every feeding or feed
it with every every other watering and
that'll be that um all my early feeds
get ph to 5.7 to 5.9 um that's generally
the the range i like to go with it 5.9
is kind of my target range for the
vegetative for um
you know what they're up taking like you
said it's those uh micronutrients they
really like the calcium calcium the
magnesium the boron the manganese all
that fun stuff
so it just really depends on what your
nutrient line is and that's really vital
and that's why if you're doing a super
soil mix it's really good to kind of mix
it a little bit heavier that a not a
seedling but a juvenile you know a two
week old plant three week old plant can
go ahead and prosper in because then you
find yourself not having to buy
nutrients not having to buy a nutrient
line you can just go to your local
garden center and grab some earthworm
castings and throw you know a cup on top
mix it in and then just water if you
need more
food for your plants so i try to be just
simple compost teas and that's it
so you're not adding in any like bone
meal rock phosphate any epsom salts
anything like that at all you're just
doing the the cocoa with the perlite
with the worm castings with the 707 a
little bit of 707
soil you mentioned and then just doing
teas throughout the entire grow because
they get the teas get all the bone meal
the blood meal and all of that so i'll
go ahead and enrich the soil um because
i i like to make sure it's not too hot
for hot from the get-go because i found
when i was adding my bone meals my blood
meals my ratios were always changing
because i was finding that okay this one
type of plant likes this mix but the
next type doesn't early on so what i did
find better was just to make a very
not um
neutral super super oil but kind of a
neutral super soil mix that was happy
with all my plants that i could okay if
this strains of of lettuce like um you
know the purple head cabbage or or this
strain of you know lemongrass or
compared to my my um
my peppermints or my spearmints if
they're eating heavy okay i can feed
them more you know but if the the back
the back basil's not eating heavy or the
back um tomatoes aren't even eating
heavy okay i can back off i don't have
to feed them this compost tea so that's
kind of where i found my even mix is
just adding the things to adding my
excess nutrients or excess additives to
the compost tea let them brew let them
really become accessible and then you'll
see i mean it's a night and day
difference when you feed compost teas
within two days your plants will look
completely different so that's my
favorite thing about um organics let's
get deeper into compost teas so i know
some people have a recipe for the
vegetation stage and some people have a
recipe for the flower stage do you do
that as well or you just one recipe or
one tea type of tea throughout the whole
grow
oh i definitely change it up so it's uh
i'm a believer of changing up your ppm
range i'm a believer of changing up your
ph ranges um you know shifting ph ranges
are what's healthy for plants because
that happens in nature uh so
for my vegetative compost tea it's gonna
be around the you know if we're talking
about a a nice vegging plant
five weeks old four weeks old something
nice and hearty it's going to be around
the 500 to 650 ppm range maybe 700 max
um and that's going to give them a nice
boost but what that's going to be is and
what that's going to look like is
usually uh it's going to be one cup of
bat guano uh one and a half cups of
earthworm castings and then i go ahead
and add one cup of blood meal and then
half a cup of oh no a quarter cup of
bone meal
and that bone meal is in there just to
introduce some of that pk the earthworm
casting is about guano all of it has npk
throughout of it really um but it's just
the back guano and the uh the
uh earthworm casting is gonna be much
higher in nitrogen and the calcium and
magnesium and boron so i'm just gonna
let that steep for 24 to 48 hours i
generally hit it with some great white
mico or if i um my local garden center
has a brand called mike's m-y-k-e-s it's
a really great brand if you guys have it
in your garden centers it is actually a
very nice brand of mycorrhizae but you
always let it blend for about 24 hours
generally that's ready to go my flower
feeds gonna be uh one cup of bat guano
one cup of earthworm castings two cups
of bone meal and then i'm going to do a
quarter cup of blood meal so it's
basically going to be a pk heavy
uh
compost tea versus the
you know nitrogen heavy
vegetative okay and those ratios is that
for your standard five gallon bucket
with about four gallons of water
yes yeah it's for a five gallon bucket
um roughly i fill that thing to about
four point five gallons i'm not gonna
lie i fill it to the brim
and then are you diluting that tea down
with water or are you just giving it
directly to the plants
yeah so i'll actually take that tea and
i have a one gallon uh jug that you know
we have we go through milk so every so
often i'll clean my milk jugs and i'll
have a free jug
but i'll use a one gallon jug i'll fill
it up about halfway then i'll take
another free jug i have for my normal
water get dechlorinated water ph it
proper go ahead and pour it in kind of
dilute it half and half so it's 50
uh of a mix that way it goes longer
i make more most of my compost tea and
i'm able to off five gallons i'm able to
feed for you know almost a month and and
i can keep that key that tea brewing we
have a lid for ours that keeps it sealed
you know i go and check the smell i
check the uh the healthy uh bacteria on
top and make sure nothing's growing and
make sure it's all clean that's one
thing if you want to keep t for a long
time you don't want to keep it prolonged
if you don't have good aeration and and
proper temperatures because you can grow
bad bacteria really fast so that's that
is key so um generally the rts go with
how many plants um we usually run and
just vegetables and herbs and everything
our teas are gone in like a week
but we'll feed
you know i have 30 plus plants going
plus maybe 20 vegetables so we'll feed
all that in a week
so every week will be a new tea for them
basically
sometimes it'll be every second week
because if it is a heavier t it'll last
a lot longer gotcha okay on your initial
mix that you mix up are you aiming for a
specific ec
to begin
or bpm
is a little tough for me that's that's
still things i'm getting used to uh as
far as like you know i've never
i've had organic farmers tell me about
the electric electrical conductivity
with organic farming and saying like yo
if you're not reading current if your
plants aren't putting out electrical
currents you're not doing it right um so
that's
that's been the goal of mine to get
there i'm more so getting there by
measuring my ppm and making sure my ppms
are more accurate and on par
that was the big thing that i wasn't
doing when i was first making my teas is
i was just go ahead and jump in like two
cups of this three cups of that four
cups you know like just so much crap and
just doing over doing it and then i
checked my ppns and they'd be like my
run off my plant would be like 4000 ppm
and i'd be wondering why they were out
of range and all messed up so that's
where i started recently going okay you
know what i'm gonna do i'm gonna make my
teas a lot less so when i check my ppmit
okay my ppm might be a thousand but let
me go check it diluted okay now diluted
it's at 550 perfect i'm in range okay ph
ph is 6.0 perfect let's go ahead and
feed i check my runoff my runoffs are
now you know if it's i'm feeding 600 and
i have a super soil mix like we talked
about generally the runoff would be
about 750 800 and that's generally where
i want to be for a vegging plant that's
a really healthy amount of food for them
because right as they get into flowering
you're going to want to switch them over
and they're going to want that a
thousand range 1100 range 1200 range
i've had plants that love 1500 range so
you know it just completely depends on
what you have what's fruiting on your
plant tomatoes sometimes can take a lot
of nutrients but yeah i find measuring
my ppms have dialed me in much more than
than what i used to do
and then you touched a little bit about
ph your base soil is cocoa
and i know a lot of people don't aim for
a different ph in cocoa than they would
in soil what do you typically aim for
when it comes to ph in your super soil
so my ph and my super soil i try to keep
it at 6.0 6.1 it's really good to run
throughout the whole thing something you
have to remember if you're going to use
cocoa in any mix whatsoever you're going
to use plain cocoa growing cocoa
whatever you're doing cocoa cocoa holds
pk and will leech it later on in the
grow so you always have to remember okay
my cocoa is holding this pk that means
that my cocoa is holding on to a
ph range of around 6.3 to 6.7 because
that's roughly where
those nutrients lie and that's why our
plants absorb them best at the 6.0 to
6.5 range is because that's that
flowering fruiting stage for the acidic
and alkaline nutrients that flow in that
range so i generally think like okay
at 6.0 when one flower hits i'm going to
start raging it to 6.1 but i'm going to
back off and start watering those first
few weeks because i know my cocoa has
leech pk and generally the first two
weeks of
every time i switch to flour or i notice
fruiting happening on my plants i'll
i'll go ahead and just feed a very very
minimal water i usually won't compost
feed it'll just be like water and
molasses or water and kelp and i'll
notice that my ppms when i'm off the
runoff will continue to rise will keep
rising and then they'll just drop after
about a week or so because that leaching
has finally come out because they're
it's something with um
i don't know the science the true
science behind cocoa but i do know it's
something with uh those stages of cocoa
the fibrous breaks down of the plant um
something to do with coconut husk and
finally releasing the potassium and
phosphorus after so many weeks or
something like that it's based on how
much you feed
but generally the rule of thumb is
your cocoa generally can hold it on for
six to eight weeks after you fed that's
that's rule of thumb for most most cocoa
growers that have taught me anything
about cocoa
all right so you have your initial super
soil mix you have a clear plan of the
teas you're going to be doing in the
vegetation stage and the flower stage
let's talk about container size you know
i have people that are growing indoors
what container size would you recommend
for those folks and i also have folks
that are growing outdoors
is there a specific container size that
you have that you recommend for those
folks
absolutely so indoors you can get away
with pretty much plastic pot fabric pots
i don't know wood pots pvc pots whatever
you want to get uh grow in and get
makeshift with e um
and for indoor growers you always have
to take your grow tent or space or
height into consideration so
you one thing people always think you
know oh i have a two or uh six foot ten
i have six foot of growth space no you
really don't so you have to take in your
height of your pot then you have to take
in the distance from the ceiling to your
light and then the distance from the
light to your canopy so light to your
canopy has to always be at minimum 12
inches generally you want about 14 so
you don't burn your plants or bleach
your plants you get a really nice par
displacement and you can maximize your
light
12 inches is like when you're really
dialed in and everything so you always
have to calculate that distance so
whatever that distance in between so
let's say you have five feet of gross
speeds or or four feet of growth space
in between okay so you know that at two
feet you need to flip your plants to
flower or fruiting so that those plants
double and potentially don't outgrow
your space generally i even like to do
it a little shorter than two feet
because some plants will go 300 stretch
on you so you have to be careful
um
so with that height you got to take into
consideration what size grow tent or
what size pot you have for indoor grows
i don't suggest anything bigger than a
seven gallon you're going to get some
monstrous plants i generally try to tell
people one gallons three gallons and
five gallons are like really the best
size pots um if you have a smaller size
tents your one gallons and three gallons
can really do great your one gallons can
be perfect for vegetating and then you
can transplant to your three gallons to
for your your flour and your fruiting
stages and they can be you work wonders
um you know your five gallons you're
going to get into the much much much
larger plants which this is you're
talking about by four grow spaces five
by five grow spaces maybe a four by
eight grow space something that's larger
even a three by three um you just really
don't wanna
surpass your space like you're not gonna
throw a five gallon and a two by two by
four that's really too much so
just know your space i wouldn't suggest
anything past the five gallon if you
really want ease indoors um i always
suggest
more of a wider pot than a taller pot so
that you have more grow room and more
height to train your plants and then for
outdoors it really makes a difference
you don't want black plants or black
pots for your plants outdoors because of
the heat and you can burn your roots so
you generally want tan white or some
sort of reflective barrier for your pots
outdoors uh you want a lot of aeration
but you want a lot of moisture control
so what i what a lot of growers do
that i see is build grow boxes where
they're actually have individual pots
inside these grow boxes that'll be like
uh rings of sand so it'll be like a pot
of sand and then the the plant inside of
it and it's like a big grow box and the
roots can go out from underneath and
actually grow within the grow box but
there's a ring of sand around it that
the growers can go okay it's a hot day
i'm going to go pour cold water onto the
sand make sure the roots are cold
so you always have to think about
outdoors for temperature and for size
outdoors i mean it really depends you
could go 50 gallon grow pots you could
get 150 gallon grow pot you could do a a
whole you know planted in the ground and
then it's like a thousand gallon grow
pot so
um it really just depends on what your
space is
for
your general average greenhouse grower
if you're not trying to grow 20-foot
trees or 10-foot monsters
uh you would probably want something
around the 35 to 45 or 50-gallon marker
uh smart pots are really really handy
like i said tan tan makes a great color
for reflecting sun while also keeping in
heat for the nighttime temperatures so
that's that's some things to consider
when you're choosing your pots and i
believe you touched on paul on this in
the beginning of the episodes you
mentioned that you don't actually start
out in this super soul mix right i think
you said you like to use fox farm happy
frog for example to start your seedlings
in there so is that like just in a small
solo cup and you're planting it in
unhappy frog letting those plants grow
to a certain point and then
transplanting into your final container
or are you going from like a solo cup to
a one gallon then up to like a five
gallon for example
so generally i'll go solo cup one gallon
five gallon um but if it's like an
autoflower that i just want to go ahead
and
get them in their pot get them uh going
or if it's like a uh a tomato plant
where it's uh
it's something where you wanna get it in
a in a smaller viney
more growing straightforward and get
those little cherry tomatoes going maybe
it's a it's a strawberry plant and you
want your mini strawberries to grow more
of a bush in a box or something so it
depends on what i'm kind of doing if i
want something that's more quicker more
off going i want to get it instantly i
need them the medicinal qualities now or
whatever i'll keep them in small pots so
that'll be my one gallons and three
gallons and i'll just keep them in there
i'll let them get root bound and then
i'll go ahead and turn them over to the
flowering cycle or whatever requires of
them to go ahead and fruit um that way
their roots stay locked uh
the the hormone so
for those listening wondering how plants
even
flower fruit or produ produce fruiting
bodies it's ethylene it's a it's a
female flowering hormone and so whenever
the plants are root locked in most
species of plants
a self-preservation kind of signal goes
off so they're genetically a little
easier to produce ethylene with this is
why hermaphroditian kind of happens in
various species of plants
and that's why plants will seed out
themselves sometimes it's really cool so
for most medicinal plants if i want a
very fast response whether it's a
photoperiod cycle or not i'll go ahead
and keep them in a one gallon root lock
them and then if i really maybe i want
some a little bigger size to them you
know those first two weeks of flower
i'll i'll put them into uh a three
gallon and then they'll get a little
bigger they'll get a little bulkier but
they'll stay relatively smaller i can
keep them in a little uh um you know two
by two herb garden that i have going
with a little mars hydro or something
you know something small nothing crazy
so that's what i like to do now if i
want monsters if i want some really nice
trees really nice quality plants really
nice herbs whatever i'm doing it's gonna
go from the one gallon to a three gallon
proper feeding proper compost teas
training the whole what nine yards then
it's gonna go straight to a five gallon
uh one week before i go ahead and flip
under flour so the roots can actually uh
adjust
handle the shock and then properly
stretch out root bound and really get a
nice root system and i usually dust
those roots with uh mycorrhizae i go the
full nine yards and really try to make
sure
that
when they're going into those bigger
homes i'm doing them justice because
just because you put a plant in a bigger
pot doesn't mean it's going to get
bigger successfully there's still a lot
of uh
microbiology you know root science that
has to go into it what they're eating
and if they're
taking in all those things so i guess it
just depends on what i'm growing but
generally i like to stick at that three
gallon to five gallon marker three
gallons are my
my quick my quick medicine plants
okay and i probably should ask this
earlier but are you letting that soil
cook for a period of time some people
let it sit for a while to let the
microbes get to work start breaking down
some of those organic amendments and
then they'll plant into it whether that
be a week later two weeks later a month
later i've heard upwards of two months
later people after they mix two months
later them actually planting into that
super soil mix
your mix that you mentioned in this
podcast episode are you letting it cook
at all if so how long
so i'm not two months i'm not that that
you know patient crazy about it but yes
i do let it sit so i'll usually feed um
so if you can picture a little four by
four tent for those listening and you
have you know just a few rows of of grow
pots filled with soil imagine the back
row you know four pots filled with
plants the rest of them completely empty
i'll water all of them with compost give
them all food and i'll let those soils
cook just under the light in the
humidity and the temperatures and i'll
let them cook for about one to two weeks
and then i get to planting that way i
know the microbial life is active
there's some activated nutrients ready
for the plants and it's healthy and
going that makes sense
i want to dig into water source water
can certainly be a variable right uh you
can start with aurora water which has
little to no ppm distilled water
you've got rain water tap water i mean
my tap water comes in at 485 ppm so like
what are you using for a water source
and um do you have a recommended
like a different soil mix recommended
for somebody who's using hard water with
a high ppm versus somebody using ro
water
that's a very good question uh that's
one of the biggest questions i think i
get all the time is about water because
water can seriously mess up and grow uh
yeah so i use tap water luckily i'm in a
place in colorado where we have well
water that comes out roughly less than
50 ppm
it's a little high in ph so i have to
dechlorinate it you know just make sure
i ph ph it right but it's nice when i
was in florida i never used tap water it
was very harsh unless i had a water
softener and or some sort of you know
rain softener system or something like
that i was never using tap water so my
best recommendations for those people
who are using
um any sort of or living in areas where
it's harsh water and you don't want to
spend money on an ro system because ro
is the best reverse osmosis is the best
i think if i could have an arrow system
to pump all my water i totally would but
i get it it's not always affordable for
most people
so i would suggest
if you have to have to use tap water
get aquatic dechlorinators to at least
take the harsh chemicals and chlorine
out of the water
um it's very cheap it's it's literally
just a little couple drops in your water
and it goes a long way
and on top of it you're going to want to
use a mixture that is
generally
i'm talking maybe 150 ppms hot so you're
you're looking at like getting a very
heavy base of happy frog mixed with like
if not three quarters of cocoa and just
doing that as a mix with a little bit of
earthworm castings because your minerals
and all your your
stuff from your water is going to add
salts and various things that your
plants are actually going to feed or try
to eat
so
if you're not going to use distilled
water if you're not going to use
anything to rid those salts or clean
those salts or minerals or nutrients or
whatever's inside your water because
sometimes it's limestone in people's
water and it's super heavy limestone you
get limestone buildup in your soil and
that's an extremely um you know they
could combine some toxic fear plants
depending on what you're growing so
that's something to consider
um so with water problems if you have a
severe enough problem and you want to
cultivate your own garden medicine
whatever you're trying to do to be
self-sufficient i always tell people it
it is an investment to try to get a rain
softener system a water softener system
an ro system but really at the end of
the day the amount of headaches and
jumps and and and hoops you're gonna
have to go through
to try to just get
a successful harvest or plant or fruit
or flower or whatever you're trying to
get
with tap water it's it's very hard
you're gonna have a very hard time your
ph is usually all over the place the
problem with salts and minerals and
water is the leaching effect so cocoa
leaches and holds nutrients well when
you put salts in things and you have
salt build up eventually that salt does
break down and that salt will leach and
cause toxicities it'll it'll shoot your
plants out of range it'll cause your
ppms to go from you're sitting at 500
next thing you know you're at 2 000
because all these salts just leached
into the soil and they became bio
accessible and now your plants are
eating them and and now your plants are
absorbing them and now your plants are
also dropping them all up back into the
soil because it can't take anymore and
now your plants are just stuck in this
cocoon drowning of nutrients because
they that's what's happening with the
salt underneath the soil essentially i
mean there's much more into it i'm not a
scientist or a biologist but um
yeah i think we're
spending the money in an ro system or
bob gallons of distilled water man it
makes a difference i wouldn't use tap
water if it's too high i just that's
just my best suggestion um you really
water is everything for plants
collecting rainwater and filtering it
with a youtube how to filter you know
little gravel salt things that can make
a difference um you know so
yeah i wouldn't suggest tap water if
it's if it's a hard water like florida
georgia alabama or even pennsylvania new
york those i wouldn't suggest it i tried
to use my tap water for a grow and it
did not turn out good at all uh you know
like i mentioned 485 ppm that's
very high i think the epa approval is
like no higher than 500 so it's like
dancing the line on not being approved
by the epa
and it was that flint's level right
there that's not good
it uh it did not come up my my plans
didn't like it i invested in ro system
and i haven't looked back and i know
there's a lot of people out there that
say ro systems are a waste because
you're wasting water for every gallon of
ro water it's two or three times that
amount is coming out of the drain line
well you can actually take that water
from the drain line you can not hook it
up to your drain you can actually put it
into a bucket and use it for your
outdoor plants for example that's what a
lot of people commonly do they take that
water and they use it for something else
so that's one thing just to keep in mind
for anyone who is uh considering using
aura water but maybe not to go towards
it because of the fact they don't want
to waste the water but for someone like
me
i had to go to ro just because my
water that's accessible to me is just
not usable really for uh for the plants
that i'm growing
it just kills them it just doesn't do
anything good for your plants so yeah i
love your suggestions go to ro guys go
to it
so taking a step back and thinking about
everything that has to do with mixing
soils you know creating a super soil
what advice do you have for someone
who's new to mixing soils less is more
yeah don't overdo it just uh less is so
much more if you're if you're really
you're going down to your local grow
center this is all you need you know
i've talked to a bunch of different
cultivators kyle cushman eric branstad
um the dank duchess uh smoking with pod
all sorts of people and mr growitz now
getting to talk you know get to talk to
us so it's definitely been really great
but
i think every one of you guys
will always agree that less is more you
know just go ahead and do
bare minimum grab if you're not sure if
you want peat moss or cocoa okay go grab
a nice blend of soil go grab a little
bit of peat moss toss it in
go grab a little bone meal blood meal
toss a little in and leave it that don't
do anything crazy i'm talking to you
like half recipe of everything i i
decided to tell you test the waters just
do do less is more because when you go
extravag extravagant and go buying
everything and go spend your money on
all this and then your plants fail
you're going to get disheartened and
you're not going to want to grow and
you're not going to cultivate because
you're going to feel like you wasted a
whole bunch of money so less less less
less is more
definitely some good advice there so
wrapping things up how can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future well i am known as derrick
aka chronic from homegrown world you can
go check out at homegrown world on
instagram it has all the wonderful
information of where to find us what we
do what the company is uh what we're
about and what kind of seeds we have for
purchase that are top-notch quality and
all that fun stuff
mainly i do educational content so you
can check out my page there you guys can
always ask me questions i'm an open book
i know a lot of youtubers and various
faces are kind of hard to get a hold of
and it's kind of scary like should i
drop my question now guys drop your
question i'm happy to answer and uh it
was a it was an absolute pleasure to
come on this podcast man thank you so
much for having me yeah thanks for
coming on if you enjoyed this episode
click that thumbs up button trying to
get as many thumbs up as possible
youtube loves the thumbs up but they
recommend
videos that get a lot of thumbs up so
hit that thumbs up subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend i'm releasing a new
garden talk podcast episode and i'd love
for you to tune in to future episodes
derek once again thanks so much for
coming on to this podcast today i
definitely have a
new super soil to potentially try out in
the future uh thanks for revealing your
secrets there and i hope you enjoy the
rest of your day yeah it was a pleasure
man you as well take care peace out
everyone