coming up on garden talk the very top
two leaves that come out and pull those
off and allow that light to penetrate
down and they'll start to branch out by
themselves without that stunt period of
actually popping the top off
the second layer is for support the
first one is for yield i want that
canopy filled out i don't want to be
growing the floor
literally i'll make the top leaves of
the canopy kiss the bottom of that net
as soon as i bring them in i want to say
two but i'll even give it three anything
over a three gallon pot starts to become
wasteful in cocoa those are still
valuable i know they'd like to say cut
from the top but i haven't really seen
any difference from taking clones from
the top or the bottom i'll defoliate in
veg too if i see that it's getting too
thick and i want more branching i'll
defoliate in veg but those little silver
ones that you get out of beauty section
at like walmart or something i'm talking
about just one little snip they pop
right through that net like it's nothing
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 34. in this
episode i interviewed beast coast grower
he has been gardening for seven years
and he grows a variety of plants such as
berries peaches plums apples pears
medicinal herbs and many different types
of vegetables in this episode he talks a
little bit about his gross style and
then gets into something that he does
very often and very well the scrub
technique and he gets into very specific
detail on that topic thanks to all of
you who support this podcast through
patreon if you'd like to support you can
do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible
a big supporter of this podcast is dutch
pro they sponsor this podcast and i use
their nutrients i have been using their
base nutrients formulated specifically
for auro and soft water i also have been
using some of their additives like
calmag silica and their root stimulator
called take root they have a few other
additives on top of those and ph
regulators coupon code mr grow at 10dp
will get you a discount on their
products and i'll leave a link to their
amazon store down in the description
section below spider farmer they
sponsored this podcast and i use their
led grow lights spider farmer now has a
bar style series of led grow lights they
have the se 3000 a four bar fixture for
a three foot by three foot grow space
the se 5000 a six bar fixture for a four
foot by four foot grow space and the
sc7000 a six bar fixture for a five foot
by five foot grow space i will leave a
link to spider farmer down in the
description section below and you can
use discount code mr grow at five during
checkout for discount on their products
ac infiniti is a sponsor of the podcast
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infinity down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products
alright we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with beast coast grower how you doing
today
i'm all right how's everything
doing great man glad to have you on
board on today's episode we are going to
get deep into the scrug technique and
kind of using a trellis net plant
training we'll get into a little bit
about you and your growth setup i think
it's gonna be a really good episode
today i've had quite a few people ask me
about the scrub technique and i know
that's something you do very very well
so i'm excited for this one yeah me too
but before we kind of get into the
nitty-gritty of things can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
uh yes uh beast coast grower 420 the
main reason that i got into gardening is
because i'm vegan been vegan for a while
so it kind of made me want to go into
like growing my own foods which got me
into a lot of the the plant growing and
after that a friend of mine winded up
with cancer
and as he was recovering from the
chemotherapy i decided to start looking
up different herbs and medicinal plants
that would be good to help him in the
recovery process of the cancer and
that's how i stumbled across a lot of
the other plants that came along with it
but i've always been a nature person
always loved growing plants always like
to tap in but i would probably be called
the tree hugger
i'd be one of those guys i just
something about nature always called me
so that's what really pulled me into
wanting to grow that's pretty cool yeah
my dad just had lung cancer got
diagnosed with that and he was going
through radiation and chemotherapy and
he is doesn't smoke i mean he tried it
way back in the day he's older now he's
elderly
and
i somewhat convinced him to do it you
know i mentioned you know chemotherapy
one of the things is you get nauseous
sick after the fact
now i mentioned to him i'm like hey
that's one thing that cannabis helps you
with is the nausea it helps you go away
you feel better would you be willing to
try it he said yes now the thing is they
give you now with chemo a whole bunch of
different medication that offsets all
the side effects so he actually didn't
have any side effects from the chemo
which i thought was amazing it was crazy
wow so he never got a chance to try it
but cannabis kind of being you know
helpful on the cancer side of things in
various ways
you know yeah i'm glad you brought that
up because it is definitely helpful on
that avenue yes especially when it comes
to like appetite even because a lot of
people who go through that they really
lose their appetite so that's another
way to bring on the appetite i'm glad
medical science has gotten so good that
they have things that can counter the
effects of the radiation though yeah
yeah for sure and then before we started
talking you talked about how you grow a
whole variety of things i mean you're on
berries apples pears peaches plums all
sorts of vegetables so it's not just
those medicinal varieties you're growing
a lot of different things
yes heavy in a permaculture that's what
that's what originally pulled me was
people building their own food forest
and just giving back to nature so that
that called me as soon as i seen that
i'm like yeah i got to do this yeah
that's awesome
so are you an indoor grower outdoors do
you do both both both okay what's your
overall kind of gross style
um well for outdoor of course 100
organic i like to go right into the
ground it just makes life a lot easier
um on the indoor coco and then tell me a
little bit more about your indoor growth
setup you know what size growth space
are you working in what do you have for
lighting how's your ventilation run so
on and so forth okay so uh on the indoor
there's one room that is a
i say probably like an eight by
eight by like 18
roughly but i use about a four by 16 for
canopy space um one gallon pots of cocoa
on flood trays but instead of flooding
and draining there's a watering system
that sits inside of the tray loop around
just to get it pressurized and each tray
has its own watering system one minute a
day open flow water as soon as the
lights come on
um trellis of course uh double trellised
if necessary uh switched over to leds a
while back because leds are just
way more efficient didn't have to worry
about any heat when it came to those
summer runs anymore it just made life a
lot easier once i switched over to leds
so i try to keep it as simple as
possible 12 plants per tray one gallon
pots of cocoa open flow watering system
one minute a day
two minutes in the middle of flowers
sometimes if necessary because sometimes
around week four week five they'll tend
to drink a little bit more so that's
when i'll up the watering if necessary
but on open flow people got to remember
that it's it's a lot more water coming
out than those pressure regulated ones
that's given 0.3
whatever per hour so since mine is open
flow one minute is more than enough it
sounds like when you're working with a
large amount of plants this probably
much easier for you to have that hooked
up to automated systems like that yes
yes especially once you put the trellis
nets on because you can't really reach
in with a wand or anything in water it
just makes everything a hundred times
more difficult so much easier to get
them on that watering system early so
when the nets is set you're pretty much
free got it yeah that's a question i'm
going to ask you later on we'll get
deeper into it once we get into scrugg i
gotta ask do you typically grow from
seed or are you starting from clone most
of the time
uh most of the time the room will be
filled predominantly with clones but i
saved one tray and one of the rooms
specifically just for final hunting i've
always pheno hunted i pop new seeds as
soon as i'm done with the final hunt i'm
always looking for something new and i
want something of my own like it's good
to acquire the cuts that are available
to get those keeper cuts that other
people sourced out but sometimes i just
want my own fino and i might not like
the pheno that they chose to keep and
run with so i'd rather hunt through it
myself and see what i can find so
sometimes i'm starting from seed but
it's never going to be a full run from
seed predominantly the room will be uh
of the keeper stock of clones that i've
had okay yeah that was actually a viewer
question wanted to know about seed
versus clone that's one thing i don't
really ask the viewers much it's like
that's a great question might as well
start asking them because you know it
does make a difference in in some ways
it does some people say that seeds are
more vigorous than uh than the clones
are but it
it really comes down to technique what
do you what are you doing it for are you
just hunting for personal use is it just
something that you want to do or are you
involved in the industry do you have the
actual space to be able to do bigger
hunts so since i don't want to dedicate
a lot of space to hunting i just got one
four by four tray in the room that's
right by the door so you can monitor it
for any herms or anything as soon as you
walk in and that's normally the trade
that i'll dedicate to fino hunts oh okay
that's my
good way of going about doing it
okay so now that we have some of the
basics out of the way let's kind of dive
a little bit into plant training and
then we'll get into like the scrub
techniques so
what type of plant training do you
typically do are you doing topping any
low stress training super cropping
filming
what do you typically do um well from
the beginning water and solo cups as
soon as they start getting a bit tall i
do what what i label as the grandmaster
level topping technique where you just
take the very top two leaves that come
out and pull those off and allow that
light to penetrate down and they'll
start to branch out by themselves
without that stunt period of actually
popping the top off so they'll never
stop growing they'll just focus more on
branching from that point out so from
the moment they're in solo cups and i
see them start to go for that stretch i
start to periodically pull those top two
leaves off everything until you get that
wine glass shape that you're looking for
some people train for that some people
top for that but i don't like to keep to
stunt the plants and keep them short
they'll grow they'll grow wide enough
just by simply pulling those top two
leaves off now when it comes to plant
training
uh
they normally don't really get any
training until they get moved into the
flower room from from veg they're
compacted together because my veg space
is smaller than my flower space so i
have to compact them together and veg
and they kind of grow straight up minus
me pulling those top leaves but as soon
as they get into the flower room they
get one week of veg before they get
flipped and during that week is when the
net goes on and i start to fold them out
right then and there so i'll pull
everything from the bottoms that i feel
don't need to be there get them laid
under that net immediately and give them
a week to really fill that net out
before flip and then by that time you
could just let them go set that second
layer a net and they'll just grow right
into it
you won't have to really train into that
second layer let's talk about the scrub
technique in a little bit more detail so
net let's start with this that how big
of a net do you use i know you said you
were in a four foot your canopy was four
feet by 16 feet so you just run a net
all the way down or what all the way
down so they have these nets that you
can buy that come on like a like a spool
almost like a big like yarn thread thing
they come on a huge one and you could
just pull them out so yeah we uh in that
room 16 feet and some of the other rooms
there's 25 feet of trellis netting and
we just hook them up and get those
things set right away i was looking to
get uh those metal poles that you can uh
screw into the ground that can hold them
because one thing you'll notice is if
you're using pvc or something as a setup
for your trellis netting they they have
a tendency to bow in and i i don't like
having to deal with that so you got to
find a strong enough structure to be
able to attach the trellis too so you
don't have to worry about that happening
so you can get the full use out of the
trellis what are you attaching to the
trellis to now and how are you attaching
it
uh we i use screws and i i screwed two
by fours into each corner of where each
tray would be four feet wide on on both
ends and on one end i actually had to
brace it and actually make like a
how can i describe it it's like a two by
four that kind of locks on in each round
i could just unscrew it and pull it
right off
but that's what i have to use on the
other end because it doesn't have really
anything to brace to so just uh regular
screws hook them into the two by fours
and pulling that straight across
i try to do this before the plants get
too tall though because it gets more
hectic the bigger you let the plants get
because then you really got to start
weaving them through so you almost want
to get it to where they're just kissing
the bottom of the net
and then after that week they'll just
start to grow into it and all you got to
do is just move them out as they get
through those nets okay the screwing
into the board is interesting when i did
this grug when i i've done it a handful
of times probably uh
maybe a dozen times at the most and i
usually do it in grow tents
so what i usually use is zip ties and
i'll zip tie it to the side of the grow
tent poles so that's kind of another way
to go about it if any listeners are
wondering how to do it within a grow
tent and in that system you got
something more stable because that tent
is braced on each corner so you don't
have to worry about the tent blowing in
on you because it is built the way that
it's built so that's what i'm saying
when people gotta lay the net make sure
that you got something sturdy enough
that when you pull that net tight it
stays tight it doesn't wind up blowing
in the structure that you got for it
really good point so for the actual net
told you we're gonna get deep on this
one
is there a particular brand i don't know
if you mentioned the brand and you're
well from what you were explaining in
the type of net is it the polypropylene
type nets that you've got polyester
you've got nylon polypropylene you've
got chicken wire so there are different
options
polypropylene the plastic type uh no i'm
using the nylons nylon okay so it is
stretchy you you like the stretchyness
yes
compared to the plastic ones and the
plastic i don't i don't know what made
me stick with the nylon ones but
normally it's the nylon ones because
they come on the big spool they're just
easy to hook on roll it down hook it to
the other side cut it and you're good to
go yeah yeah i would think the
stretchiness would be beneficial i mean
it's been beneficial for me i know a lot
of people use this chicken wire and
that's more a fixed and you're really
not going to have to be able to bend it
at all have you used chicken wire at all
or no
i was also worried about if that wire
ever got wet or anything what what would
happen with it leaning on the stems like
i try to keep
wiring metal kind of away from the
plants because i i'm not saying it will
cause any issues but the the less risk
the better so i i try to stay away from
those kind of things
i know most people that are using those
they they reuse them right yeah yeah
they'll reuse them i got a fear of
reusing stuff like that because if it's
ever a problem powdery mildew bugs
anything
you you just inviting it right back into
each round every time that you do that
so with the nylon ones it's easy to just
pull them off after each round toss them
pull the next one on the next one good
point now on the trellis net i know
there are so many different ones out
there but the
trail set holes right the holes
are different sizes you know i think
there's three inches by three inches
four inches by four inches what size you
typically use the three and a half inch
uh three and a half inch i tried the
fives i tried everything else i feel
like the fives are more for support so
if i was going to use like the five inch
squares i would do that on a second
layer of net where i'm not exactly
trying to weave anything into place or
use it to fill out the canopy but when
it's time to to fill out the canopy i
want those three and a half inch square
so that way i can make sure that i got a
head in every square and that the canopy
is full but when you're using the five
inch ones it's going to be multiple tops
in each one and hopefully you can even
get it filled if you need to pull a
branch over it doesn't really snag the
right way that you want it to because
the squares are so big so on the first
layer of net it's always three and a
half inch but if i if i can't find any
more i don't mind using the five inch
squares on the second layer where it's
just more for support than it is for
actually weaving them through to fill
out the canopy
you bring up a great point with the
support side of things that's one thing
i was going to mention at some point is
you know some people use the trellis and
scrock technique because they want to
maximize yield other people they just
want it for plant support
which way do you do both for support and
yield or what do you kind of aim for
using the second layer is for support
the first one is for yield i want that
canopy filled out i don't want to be
growing the floor i don't want any light
hitting that floor if i could prevent it
because anything underneath that first
layer of net is getting lolly popped off
anyway so i don't i don't want any light
penetrating through there i just want a
full canopy from that first layer and
that up through that second one
so it's for yield for me now granted the
second layer is more for support because
you don't want them flopping over after
they get big but that that first layer
is strictly yield yield driven makes
sense and then you bring up a great
point just one echo what you said before
is the larger the square it seems like
it's the harder it is to kind of
manipulate the plan and keep plants
tucked under because the squares are so
big and yes you've got multiple shoots
coming out one square and
so yeah i mean i had this
i had this nylon one where it stretched
and as it stretched it to the growth
tent the holes would get bigger you know
what i mean so it just made it more
difficult yes i feel like
the size of squares i feel like is
pretty important
yes they start off as fives but once
they start to stretch they wind up even
bigger and if you're growing shorter
squatter plants like the strain
dependent um
those fives will really hurt you because
the shorter and squatter they are the
more you're going to want to train them
out to really get that penetration into
the inside and you cannot do that with
the fives gotcha now how many plants are
you putting per
i was going to say square foot but
really i mean you're
so maybe like a four foot by four foot
area how many plants do you typically
have in that like under the net 12 to 16
per 4x4 really strain dependent if i'm
doing something like ice cream cake i
would use 12 because they stretch about
200 percent once they hit flour so i
don't want to
load that in too heavy because then the
canopy would be two-packed now if i'm
running something that's a little less
vigorous i'll do 16 to make up for the
fact that during that stretch it's not
going to give me the same thing and
it'll work better to fill the canopy out
if i do 16
of that strain versus 12 of another
strain so 12 to 16 give or take and i
know you said you're in one gallon
containers small you're on an auto
watering system so that's very helpful
there to keep everything saturated or
else if you're not on an auto watering
system it's probably you know it can dry
out super quick yes and then you do a
lot more labor there and with the more
the higher plant count versus if you did
just do four plants for example right
you're looking at a shorter veg time too
so that's uh yes that's you're filling
up that space a lot quicker than you
would with less plants yes that was
worth pointing out there that was the
goal and when you're using cocoa i think
anything over
i want to say two but i'll even give it
three anything over a three gallon pot
starts to become wasteful in cocoa
gotcha
and so okay so you've got your 12 plants
roughly in that space i actually have
four four feet by 16 feet now what point
do you
you touched on this earlier i believe
what point you put up that first layer
of trellis that and then what is the
distance between the grow pod
and the net
it kind of depends on how big the plants
are when they go into the room
but usually i'll set that first net
literally i'll make the top leaves of
the canopy kiss the bottom of that net
as soon as i bring them in so i'll bring
the plants in and even if i need to i'll
cut them back just to make everything
even so if there's a couple branches
that are just reaching out on top of
everything else i'll just cut those
clean off just to even out the canopy
and i'll set the net right to the very
very top of it so it's usually about
maybe 18 inches from from pot to where
the first layer of trellis netting is
i typically do 18 inches too that's
that's about right you know might be 20
inches of time depending on plant growth
like you mentioned that's going to be a
determinant of it as well
yes so
when do you start
actually weaving the plants too now you
mentioned that you don't do any topping
okay traditional thing i mean i've read
some articles before we even started
talking here just kind of refresh my
memories and come up with some questions
traditional way is to top in between the
third and fifth notes so either third
note fourth note the fifth note and
allowing those lower branches to kind of
come up into the net and spread out now
you don't do that you do that other
technique that you mentioned and that
allows to grow the plants
so at what point are you kind of weaving
you said you added it in you've got the
net going right away so pretty much
right away is when you're starting to
weave as the plants are just growing or
what within that first week of them
being in the flower room even though
that first week is still veg they're in
the flower room but they're going to veg
for a week in that flower room and that
week is more than enough because i set
the net just above them so within that
first week of growth because there's way
more light now there's uh co2 now
there's so many other things now that
they're going to skyrocket the second
you get them into that that bigger room
so within that first week i'll have that
net fully filled out because i didn't
set it so high above where the plants
were that i have to wait for too much
growth any growth that comes in past the
point when they first get in there has
to get weaved through or it's gonna wind
up just being too tall and overshadowing
things in the corners
i try to keep the canopy as even as
possible like when i'm when i'm done
with a round i want to just be able to
scoop down and look at eye level and be
able to just see flat straight across if
if i can
yeah i know that is the goal for the
even canopy for scrub technique you know
using the trellis net does help a lot of
people call it the scrug net by the way
so same yes
it definitely helps keep that even
canopy
now
some folks what they'll do is you know
they let their plants grow up and then
they'll do a
lollipopping right they're removed to
lower growth
do you
do that
before your plants come into the net or
do you wait until a certain point that
the plants grow and then you'll do the
lollipopping
what i do is i wait for that week of veg
to be over
so once i bring them into that flower
room give them that week of veg see
exactly which branches will make it
through and which ones won't because
some branches i still won't pull off
even after that week of veg because i
know during the first three weeks of
stretch those will still make it so it's
kind of it's kind of it might hurt you
in the long run to pull some of those
off too early because they could have
winded up making it through and those
would have been great secondaries right
there and i i don't want to cut those
off i want to see what's going to make
it and what's not now granted there are
going to be some things that clean are
just not going to make it i'll take
those off before they even make it into
the flower room but there's some that
i'll leave and i'll just monitor for a
while until about week to a flower and
then if i know by then that you're not
going to make it i'll lollipop
everything that i know isn't going to
make it when running these kind of
setups you got to constantly have a
decent amount of clones ready to go
every single time so instead of pulling
those bottom ones off just a lollipop
and throw them out it'll be good to
that's where you can get a boatload of
clones from right from those bottoms
that you normally would have threw away
those those are still valuable i know
they like to say cut from the top but i
haven't really seen any difference from
taking clones from the top or the bottom
that's an efficient way to go about that
instead just pruning those and either
throwing away or throwing them in your
compost pile actually using them as
clones
now one more thing with the lollipopping
generally speaking some folks what they
do is they'll do
you know you mentioned about 18 inches
to the net from the pot
some people take
they'll use that as their guide and they
lollipop everything below that is that
what you do or do you
do more or less
uh
well since i uh
eventually once i got into it i started
to learn more about leaf stripping so it
really depends on how tall the plant get
will determine how much i pull off at
the bottom because i know once i leave
strip a lot of that light is going to be
able to penetrate now and things that
wouldn't have been valuable before now
have the opportunity of being valuable
so it once i leave strip i can kind of
get a good idea and that's normally
around like week two is when i start the
leaf stripping we too flower so once i
see what's going to make it and what's
not and what will be valuable and what
won't get any light no matter what
that's when i'll know what to exactly
pull off i don't like to pull anything
off before then because i know after the
leaf strip i'm going to expose a whole
bunch of branches on those bottoms to
light that they wouldn't have had prior
to that leaf strip so i have to kind of
wait to see how it plays out from there
and again it's strain dependent because
some strains all the branches stretch
when they hit flower and some strangers
mainly just the top ones that'll stretch
when they hit flowers so it kind of
comes down to what strain i'm running
will go based on what technique that i'm
gonna have to do and in some instances
yes everything from underneath that
first layer and that is gone because
it's stretched so far above it that
nothing down there is going to get no
light no matter how much leaf stripping
that i wind up doing so in some cases
jeff that is my god that first layer in
that anything underneath it under most
circumstances is gone
you bring up some really good points
there
so you mentioned when you start weaving
the plants underneath the trellis when
do you stop
doing the weaving and kind of let them
grow vertical from there
when i can't when i can't contain it
anymore when i come into the room and
there's so much growth after they've
been flipped into flower that no matter
what i would have to almost break a
branch in order to move it anywhere else
that's when i just have to let it go i
can't i can't really do much past that
point and most of the times all the
squares are filled in by then there's
really nowhere to put them past that
point once they flip in the flower so
worst come the worse if they start
getting too tall i can pull a branch
over through that second layer of neck
so i don't have to let it shoot straight
up i could kind of pull it off to the
side or something like that but i
normally stop as soon as i hit flower
because you just can't contain it
anymore there's so much growth going on
each day that i would have to pull the
branch back down and then over and now
i'm risking breaking branches and having
to move around and break other branches
from other plants i just i i don't like
to
i don't like to mess with them like that
i've learned my lesson from doing that
broke a lot of branches so basically
you're
correcting from wrong you're filling up
that first net
then flipping the flower
yes
okay and then you're kind of letting
them grow upwards and if you can
continue to tuck down you will
but for the most part you're kind of
letting him grow upwards and at some
point you're adding in a second layer of
trellis more for support right yes what
point you typically find that you're
adding in that second layer is it within
the first three weeks of that stretch
period first two weeks of flower or when
i already have the level set because
once you do round after round after
round you know where you're gonna flip
you know where they're pretty much gonna
end so i already have
two layers of hooks for that second
layer of net depending on how tall the
plant gets i have one layer if they're
going to stay a little bit more squat
but i got a second layer just in case
for those really tall ones because so
sometimes there's a huge gap in between
the first and second layer or net and
sometimes not so big but i have those
hooks already set in in the room so as
soon as i'm re i usually
since i know what strain i'm already
going to be running when i lay the first
net i'll lay the second one right away i
won't even have to wait for it and then
what's the distance between the first
net and the second net
probably about another 18 inches 18 20
inches roughly depending on the strain
because if i'm running something like
poly shore or ice cream cake
as soon as they hit flower they're
shooting for the moon like so
on strains like that it's going to be a
little bit bigger of a gap in between
the the canopy because they just go so
crazy if i set it lower i would wind up
having to put a third layer of trellis
and i don't like three layers i don't
like
yeah they can grow super quick and one
of the techniques that i do and i'm sure
if you do it at all is as i find shoots
are kind of outgrowing other shoots is
super cropping technique i don't know if
you do that at all or i guess my
question is how do you manage when some
of these plants are outgrowing others or
some of the branches are outgrowing
others within that same net usually i'll
just try to pull them out the way try to
get them over to the to the corners to
allow that light to get into the middles
and over to those other corners but
worst come to worst i will super crop
them that's that's when you pinch them
and let them fall over right
i have had to do that a couple of times
actually because they'll some some
plants just go for the gusto
they don't want to share no space with
nobody else around them so sometimes yes
i will have to go in and pinch them and
super crop them
sometimes i'm really scared to do it
because i've broken a lot of branches
like that but there's a technique to it
you got to be gentle you got to be soft
you can't go in there on your iron man
hear me roar you got
you got to kind of give them a nice
pinch and let them fall over naturally
so yes i have had the super crop before
and if necessary i'll do it as often as
i need to on any of the branches that
that needed gotcha yeah i actually went
so far one time to um this was kind of a
mistake things that i deem as a mistake
i still got a yield out of it but i let
the plant grow all the way up into the
net
and then flipped a flower and i
continued to tuck under that first net
it wasn't completely full so i was able
to still kind of tuck
continue to tuck added that second layer
in order to control the height i
actually topped
the plants at that point i know it's a
huge no-no to top the plants in front
but it totally yeah it was in the first
three weeks right so i think it was like
day seven and i topped the plants and
unfortunately it continued to stretch
for you know roughly another 10 to 14
days or something like that but the top
plant the shoots weren't really
really that big so like it wasn't there
wasn't buds on those branches and it was
just kind of a mistake there so yes i
know going forward i'm not gonna do any
topping i thought it might have been
beneficial i thought topping there might
have actually helped some of the lowers
on the other end fill up the remaining
part of the net
and i think it did but overall i don't
think it was it was worth it on that
avenue so yeah that's the reason that
worse come to worse i'll chop all taller
branches off a week before they make it
into that flower room for that last week
of edge before they flip that way i can
get the canopy as even as possible at
that point and anything else that's
coming in will roughly be on the same
wavelength as the rest of them because
if not man like you said you you'll wind
up needing to either top or do massive
super cropping later on in flower and i
try to leave the plants alone as much as
possible once they're in flower i don't
really like to bother them i like them
to let them focus on the development
that they're focused on at that point
that's a really good way to go about it
for sure that's i think is going to
actually help you know make things more
efficient you can help maximize yield do
you have any tips for maximizing the
scrog net i mean you already kind of
mentioned a couple things here and there
right how you run more additional plants
i'm sure that helps felt the growth the
scrug net do you have any other tips for
kind of how to maximize that crop net or
fill it up
either as quickly as possible or how to
maybe maneuver them so they're filled up
i'll say don't
don't rely on the fact that during
stretch that they're gonna fill that net
out
because sometimes just that main branch
will shoot straight up and you'll still
have gaps in the canopy so before you
flip it is good to give them just that
one week of veg underneath that net and
if you see that a week is going to be
too much
shave it down to four or five days uh
knock a day or two off of it if you see
like okay the canopy is exactly where i
want it right now it's fully filled up
the plants have already turned back up
and and they're they're looking back at
the at the light everything's good go
ahead and flip but make sure that the
net is pretty much filled out before you
even flip don't try to rely on that
stretch darn flip to fill the rest of
that net out the stems get thicker they
get a little bit more woody they get
harder to manipulate unless you're using
silica and stuff like that but to avoid
doing any of that just have them pretty
much ready before you even
flip them
yeah have them pretty much ready before
you even get ready to flip them fill
that net out as much as possible ahead
of time even if you're using less plants
that are bigger just make sure that you
fill it out as much as possible that's
good advice for sure now are you doing
any some folks what they'll do is
defoliation so they will let their
plants grow up into the scrog or
they'll basically let the vegetarian
plants out try to fill up all the
squares right then they'll let their
plants grow a little bit more then
they'll do a defoliation at some point
within the first three weeks of the
stretching phase do you do anything like
that at all did you defoliate at all if
so when
yes but uh from what i've noticed
the big defoliations like the the
massive ones where you go in and just
pull all of the leaves off the plant at
week three
i i didn't see it as
i didn't see it as necessary from doing
it after doing it a couple of times i
realized that if i just periodically
take a couple of handfuls of leaves out
of the room each day that i'm in there
by the time that i make it to the end of
flower i'm achieving the same results
the only difference is the plants don't
have to take the same amount of shock
they still have those leaves to store
energy they still got those leaves to be
able to do anything else that they need
to do with them so in the meantime i'm
really just pulling off the big gigantic
leaves on the top that are blocking any
light from getting into the canopy but
then later on once those leaves aren't
growing back anymore i'll start to go
through the mids and to the bottom
sections of the plant and pull a little
bit more here and there then by the time
i make it to the end of flower and i
have to cut them down there's not a
bunch of leaf material to have to go
through because some people harvest and
then they'll go through and cut all the
the water leaves off afterwards i i like
to already have that done by the time i
make it to the end and save yourself the
trouble of doing it all in one shot
because if you defoliate at day 21 and
you pull all of the leaves off by the
time you hit day 42 you got to do it
again
so i i figured why do it twice when i
could just periodically pull leaves here
and there the plants don't experience as
much stress and then by the end of the
round i achieved the same result as
people who had to do the two massive
ones i don't sometimes i'm limited on
time and i don't have time to be in
there four or five hours doing those
leaf strips but i got an hour to be in
there pulling off a lot of those big
leaves that are blocking the canopy so i
do defoliate but to an extent and i even
defoliate in veg and that's how i get
the structure that i want out of the
plant before i even get it in the flower
so i'll defoliate in veg too if i see
that it's getting too thick and i want
more branching i'll defoliate in veg so
you're continuing to pluck off leaves as
you see fit you know all through really
got it there's some people out there
that say that
if you continue to pluck off leaves
frequently like daily every couple days
and you're plucking off leaves and
you're stressing out to the plant to the
point where it become a hermaphrodite
and that's true or do you think it's bro
science
bro science i've never had that happen
to you never had that happen to me i
think you'd be more at risk
by defoliating all at once because it's
a huge shock imagine just having to take
your sweater off compared to getting
fully naked which one is more of a shock
to you
the the more of a shock is having to get
rid of everything than just having to
lose one thing here periodically at a
time so i think you're you're risking
the hermaphrodite trait more when you do
larger things that'll stress them out
more i don't think they notice a leaf or
two missing here and there because even
in nature uh maybe a deer will come
through and eat a leaf or maybe a
grasshopper nibble on the leaf so
they're not immune to losing a leaf here
and there the leaves died they'd suck
the nitrogen out of them they fall off
that that's more of a natural process
than one day a plant just wakes up at
all of its leaves are gone like i think
that would be way more stressful than
doing it periodically that's a good way
to think about it for sure now you
mentioned earlier you mentioned gml
grandmaster level
one of his techniques that he does now
i'm sure you're familiar with his
defoliation technique where he strips
those girls basically basically naked i
mean barely anything have you ever gone
that far yes that's what made that's how
i got into defoliating in the first
place i was following every method from
grandmaster level because i seen the
results that he was getting behind it so
i'm like man i gotta try this sofa for
maybe two or three years i defoliated
that same way i will come in at day 21
uh i usually do it a little earlier
maybe like day 18 and i will come
through and strip everything and then
lay the net and then i just found out it
makes my life so much more difficult
because i was i was knocking uh sights
off of the plants by trying to get the
net over it and all of this other stuff
the plants are way too big after they've
gone through that stretch to try to fold
them over now branches start breaking
pots get knocked over now you got a
plant in the corner that's kind of
leaning because it was too big by the
time you put the net on so
i realized that it may be a great method
and and his circumstances but in my
circumstances it works better to net him
early and just do small defoliations
throughout flower because i want the
same results that he got with uh with
that light penetration but i don't think
i need it all at once i think over time
i'm going to get the same results as him
i'm just going about it a different way
but i got that technique originally from
watching him i hadn't seen anybody do it
prior to him now afterwards you've seen
a whole bunch of people come out with
the defoliation technique and i think
the three of light book came out where
they kind of went into detail on it a
bit but uh grandmaster level was the
first person who i seen doing and i kind
of modeled it off off of his style
even my topping technique i modeled off
of his style because i noticed that
there's no stunting in the plants when
you just pull those top two leaves off
versus knocking that head off because
they have to stop and focus on making
those top two branches that you're
trying to force it to make compared to
just letting those side shoots become
tops afterwards different strokes for
different folks yeah there's so many
different ways to go about it because
some people need their plants to stay a
little shorter so it'd be better off for
them to actually top because they're not
going to stop growing with the method
that i'm talking about you'll pull those
top two leaves off and the plants not
going to stop growing it will shoot out
some more side branches but it will not
stop growing so if you need it to slow
down a little bit and focus more on
getting wide then yes you're going to
need to top
yeah there are a lot of ways to go about
it and this is one thing to remind the
audience is there is a lot of different
ways to go but there's so many different
techniques and for those of you that are
tuning in on a platform where you can
leave a comment i would love to know how
you do describe technique let us know
down in the comment section below
because there is just multiple ways to
go about it yes if you're listening in
you can actually read in the comments
and find out different ways to do it all
the people that are commenting and
sharing best practices i mean that's
really one of the reasons why i started
this podcast is to to really pick
people's brains on their style of
growing and how they go about do doing
things you know why they do their things
and hopefully it generates some ideas
for other people you know it's greatly
appreciated because for those people
coming in for the first time everybody
got different setups everybody got
different methods everybody got
different end results everybody got
different spaces and and requirements
and limits so it's good that you're
interviewing so many different people
that are doing it so many different ways
there there is going to be a way for
them to find a way to get it done no
matter what because of of the platform
that you've given so we appreciate the
hell out of it absolutely and people
should just have fun with it right i
mean yeah
don't beat yourself up if uh the scrub
technique doesn't go go your way the
first time you know you can just try
again you know yes i do have a couple
more questions for you
so we touched upon a little bit earlier
so when you've got that net up
it's very difficult to feed or water
underneath that net
training pruning that you need to do
underneath that net do you have any tips
for kind of getting under that net to
work do your work
yes uh for one get in shape
yeah because it's gonna take a lot of
crawling and reaching through crevices
and everything so you have to be in
shape to do something like that or pick
your tables up off of the floor so if
you have the ceiling height so you don't
have to do as much bending over to get
to everything because my setup used to
be on the floor
and man it used to be hectic trying to
get under there to do any kind of
lollipopping or anything so once i
lifted them up and got them on trays it
made life
a little bit easier but um
the the watering system is almost a must
if you're going to put a net on it if
you're not in like a four by four tent
where you can kind of reach to the back
with a wand or you don't have big enough
pots where you could reach in there with
a wand in that case yeah you might be
able to get away with putting the net on
and still having access to those plants
but when you're talking about a larger
number of plants over a longer amount of
space uh
you're gonna need a watering system at
that point to be able to at least have
the watering out the way so you can
focus more on the difficult stuff like
getting through that canopy and lollipop
and that's why i try to do a lot of it
before flower even starts so then by the
time i'm in that second week and i know
what's going to make it and what's not i
could just go in with scissors and cut
every branch off that's not going to
make it through that net so i don't
exactly have to go in and pull any
little leafs growing in or i already
took care of all of that only thing left
to do is see what branches are actually
going to make it through and what
branches won't and if they won't those
branches get cut right off good tips
yeah i know quite a few people who use
the wand that you mentioned they kind of
they're able to get in deeper there with
the wand i don't know how they connect
the actual watering if they're doing
hand watering if they're connecting it
in that way or not yeah i can see how
that would make things easier yes
if you got a smaller space and you could
reach to the back with that wand and
maybe you're using three or five gallon
pots or something
you got full access to the to the plant
still compared to
16 one gallon pots like you you're
knocking stuff over they're getting
hooked on the
hoses getting hooked on the watering
system that's down there as all sorts of
problems start happening snagged on
branches like best to just go ahead and
hook that watering system up so i guess
you can say if you don't have a watering
system it may be easier to run less
plants in that yes right yes
four plants and a four by four for
example you're only having a water crawl
under there and water four plants versus
12 plants or 16 plants however many you
do with the one gallon if i had to hand
water i would probably do nine three
gallon pots three three three per roll
and a four by four
uh scrog them out get em get em set up
nicely and that way i can still reach
through and a three gallon is a big
enough circumference that i don't have
to worry about knocking over too much
stuff compared to just a one gallon like
those
man
it's best to have the water in the
system if you're going to do those but
if i was in a bigger setup yeah i could
still get away with a wand easily and
running those slightly larger parts
running nine instead of four
another you know again you kind of you
should be filling up your growth space
quicker you know so yes the goals is to
fill up that growth space quick and flip
to flower quick you know running that
nine plants
would be
more beneficial than running four plants
because you're spending longer letting
those plants grow and train and so on
and so forth so fill up in pots with the
roots harvesting so this is one of those
things which can be kind of tricky right
if you your plants are stuck within
these nets
do you have any tips on kind of
harvesting getting them out of the nets
are you
chipping into are you clipping away
individual branches or are you cutting
through the net
are you just trying to rip things out
from underneath or how do you go about
it i gotta i gotta cut through it man
like the the second one's pretty easy
because they're not exactly weave
through it it's more just for support so
i can actually go in and just lift the
whole top net off roll it up and then
everything just starts to topple past
that point so you guys so that's when
you got to go in with the little mini
scissors uh here's a good technique for
you guys go to uh
like the women's makeup section and they
have these little silver scissors that i
think women use for i'm not sure if it's
for their eyebrows or whatever but they
got these like little silver scissors
those ones cut through the net so easily
compared to fiskars fiskars are designed
for trimming plants they're not designed
for cutting through nylon but those
little silver ones that you get out of
beauty section at like walmart or
something i'm talking about just one
little sniff they pop right through that
net like it's nothing so i'll cut each
plant out in a circle and then try to
just i'll keep pulling at the net and
cutting and it'll just keep coming out
like a string until i got the whole net
out chop the whole plant hole hang it on
the hanger move it out the way on to the
next one but yes i have to i have to cut
the trellis netting out and sometimes
you get lazy and don't want to cut it
all out so you'll just cut the circle
cut the plant hang it and it'll still
have the net on it all the way through
until trim time yeah
yeah i've done that before for sure i've
also tried to you know rip rip the
plants out out from under the net and uh
that just i mean
buds get torn off trichomes get crushed
all that stuff you're looking to trade
afterwards and you're just like hey man
[Laughter]
now have you ever measured yield when
doing the scrog technique
measure and what measurements
yeah like dry yield you know what i mean
so like have you ever filled up like a
four foot by four for space or whatever
and kind of measure the yield you got
out of that you know everything would be
a yield per square foot or what do you
typically get i normally do yield per
light and are by tray because each light
covers a tray so i normally do it by
tray i'm not good at the square footage
and all of that that's
it gets a little bit too technical for
me but um
normally per 4x4 string dependent
anywhere between two and two point six
two and two point six pounds yep nice
nice and what are you using for i know
you mentioned led
uh up there the scissors right there so
if you're on youtube you can see the
scissors those little
these are the ones that you need to cut
through the trellis netting like it's
nothing
okay all right and then you touched upon
that you're using leds but what brand
what model leds are using to get that
yield
well um
i have one raymatix h8mr4 is similar to
a bar style comes in and strips that's a
thousand watt led so that one i've hit
the of course the biggest numbers on is
underneath that one but mainly hlg
everything okay and then are you
supplementing co2 in that growth space
too or no uh you know what last round i
hit my biggest harvest to date
room wise with no co2
but i'd normally yes i would use a co2
burner because the burner comes in handy
because come winter time i need heat
so one of the great ways to add heat
since the leds don't throw any heat out
is the co2 burner so you heard it here
first folks co2 does nothing for your
plants let's just get this joke
i think it's i think it's still up in
the air because they do so well outdoor
at a natural 350 to 400 ppms of
unlimited co2 and then indoor we're
pumping up with 1500 and
they're still getting bigger outdoor so
i'm i'm wondering how much of a
difference does the co2 actually make
now this run i'm gonna run co2 again and
i'm gonna see how much changes and how
much benefit the co2 has versus last
round not using it with the exact same
setup so i almost get to do a side by
side with co2 and without co2 and if the
increase is so minimal then it just
won't be worth it you almost better off
doing an intake outtake at that point
got it yeah i'd be interested to hear
your findings on that one um i do know
that there have been quite a few studies
in the past i mean we've been growing
for so long and stuff like that i think
the general consensus is that pumping
co2 in there and getting your level
stable you see a significant difference
in yield now let's you know let's put it
to the test right go ahead yes and try
it out and see what happens you know
yeah and i'm not saying if it makes a
difference for you and something else i
never went with the standard everybody
else went with the 1500 or 1250 ppms of
co2 i literally just want to double what
the ambient is because i feel like
there's going to be a cap out at so at
some point because this plant isn't
designed to take in this level of co2 it
has never been designed to take in this
level of co2 so double ambient to me is
more than enough so if ambient is around
350 to 400 then 800 750 should be more
than enough for them i think once you
start hitting over a thousand you're not
going to see much difference between 800
and 1500
save yourself some co2 okay and then you
also got a factor in the lower minimum
right which is basically you can you can
pump up 1500 co2 but if you don't have
your temperature humidity nutrition dial
then it's going to operate that at that
lower level that minimum level right so
it all needs to be in sync
so yeah so wrapping things up how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future
uh yes they could either find me on
beastcoastgrove420 on youtube
beastcoastgrow420 on ig or the green
table podcast on youtube
um and for the future um we got some new
setups coming some new rooms coming um
a lot more soil talk for people because
i'm learning that a lot more people are
going towards the organic methods but
they're usually buying and bringing in
pots and everything because they don't
know how to repair the native soil that
they have to be able to use the ground
that's already given to them so i'm
going to focus a little bit more on
trying to get people to
repair the natural soils that they have
to be able to use those versus having to
spend the money to buy these super soils
and make them and throwing them away
each season or composting them or
whatever no i'm going to show you how to
make the ground that you have good
enough for you to pop anything into it
and it'll start growing right away um i
also want to do more
production talk for people for the
people that are looking in to get to
more of the production side of things i
want to be able to show people a more
efficient way of of scaling up from from
where you were because most people are
focused on scaling up so as you start to
scale up i'm i'd like to go over the
problems that you could have and the
easiest ways around them so that's
mainly the goal moving into the future
helping people sounds like you got a lot
of good valuable information coming up
in the future so i'm definitely
definitely looking forward to tuning in
on that one you do have a youtube
channel which i will link down in the
description section below for sure so
head on over there give him a sub and
then also the green table podcast so
that's something i tune in from time to
time
sometimes i think you do it on what's
sunday nights right sundays 9 p.m
eastern
sunday's 9 p.m
i tune in sometimes and you know
sometimes i'm like just really stressed
and i think i bet message you about this
one there was one time i was so super
stressed turned it on
and the chill vibe that you guys have i
mean you're so casual you're laid back
you understand that there's so many
different ways to do it
it just it it took away some of my
anxiety you know what i mean so if you
guys like those those chill style
podcasts where people aren't you know
people more open-minded and understand
that there's so many different ways to
go about it and different techniques and
sharing best practices all that stuff
you know i definitely recommend giving
his podcast a try and i'll link the
channel down in the description section
below as well thank you well beast coast
grow this has been awesome thank you so
much for coming onto the podcast today
folks if you enjoyed this click that
thumbs up button
also if you are on apple podcasts leave
a rating and review and then if you
haven't subscribed to the youtube
channel for some reason hit that
subscribe button i try to release videos
uh
every single
saturday or sunday depending on if susan
approves of the video or not um
that's when the video comes out the
podcast episode on youtube and then
shortly after it's on all of podcast
platforms so whether in apple spotify
amazon
i heart there's so many different ones
out there so let's take a look at the
world
on them
well beast coast once again thank you so
much and i hope you enjoy the rest of
your day yes thank you for having me
peace everybody peace
[Music]
you