you have to adjust the pH at all that's
a common thing that people look at when
using synthetic nutrients is they'll mix
it up in their nutrient solution and
then they'll adjust the pH what does
your pH come out to before and and then
what do you adjust it to before I adjust
it it's usually around 68 7 and I try to
get that down to 6 58 6 around there 5.8
or 6.0 what do you use to adjust down uh
just the G
General Hydroponics pH Down got it I
believe that's a phosphoric acid but I'm
not 100% sure but yeah those acids are
very commonly used in order to adjust
the PH down now with the Organics are
you phing at all like are you monitoring
the pH
whether not at all that's thing about it
yeah I mean I know I can but the plant's
been showing me that she's doing good
and she's she's fine she's happy so I
don't think I need a change anything on
that side right now that's another way
that it makes things easier is you don't
have to adjust the pH at least in your
particular case I'm not sure you know
we'll talk about water here in a minute
but your initial water source is
certainly going to tell you whether or
not you need to do that pH adjustment
some people comes out of their tap at 8
pH or higher and like I have to adjust a
pH or else I come across problems but if
you're tap water or your filtered Oro
whatever water source you're using if it
falls within that you know 6 to seven
range roughly sometimes it can be up to
7.5 pH people swear that they add that
in and they don't do any sort of pH
adjustments and their plants are fine
yeah when when I check mine out the tap
it's at 7 but I still like I let uh I
let my reservoirs air overnight I'll
stick a AirStone in the in the water let
that sit for at least 24 hours before I
give it to any of my PLS yeah that's
also said to help eliminate some of that
chlorine that's in there all that extra
stuff that you don't want to give yeah
yeah depending on your water local water
source it uses either chlorine or
chloramine although if chloramine is
included that's one thing that people
really have to be aware of is that isn't
something that is just going to if you
have it sit overnight it disappears it's
more of a stable molecule versus the
chlorine a lot of people just let it sit
overnight some people let it sit and
have an AirStone in there like you do
some people put it in light they said
that helps with it dissipating well my
first 6 months when I started growing I
was buying water so I was just buying
the still water every day and that was
getting expensive after a while man so I
started testing with my tab water and
the plants didn't really give me too
much of a reaction to everything normal
the same so I just stuck with
that man I can only imagine yeah I had a
buddy who lived locally he was buying
water every time he was buying reverse
osmosis and it adds up I personally
think over time it's going to be worth
it to buy a system that you can actually
install like under underneath their
kitchen sink for example cuz they're
pretty small and uh a lot of these are
now a 1:1 ratio before a lot of the old
systems are 1 to three so what do I mean
by that it's basically for every one
gallon of RO water that you get out of
the the system there three gallons would
be wasted yeah now like I mentioned it's
a one to one so for every one gallon you
get only one gallon is wasted and so um
yeah buying that which is uh 200 250
bucks roughly for that particular system
I'm talking about the one to1 system it
can certainly save you money over the
long run versus going and buying either
reverse osmosis or just Ste it' be very
very costly doing that Avenue yeah I'm
definitely looking into getting
something different and picking up a
system for the house so I don't have to
worry about the lot anymore go to the
full episode by clicking the outro card
here or click the link in the
description section below catch you in
the next video