coming up on Garden talk once you end up
with branches that are too skinny that
are in the middle still cuz some
genetics like to do that you want to
lollipop those as much as possible
you're going to get more production
vertically some people don't find it to
be a pretty looking sight but if you do
it just right lollipop and maintenance
your plants you'll get more production
that way vertical and it's all about a
leveled canopy and that's where topping
will help you out you just making sure
you're nothing you're not letting
anything
get like this you don't you don't want
something low and something High my
first trellis is simply to train the
plant the second trellis is to support
the middle branches and the third trus
is to uh support the upper part of the
branches it's nice to be able to create
that beautiful art and train a plant the
way you see them being trained but not
put that much physical labor into
it what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr it and
you're tuned into to the Garden Talk
podcast this episode number 98 in this
episode I interview Josh but many of you
know him as baby Grilla he has been
gardening for 9 years and is the creator
of the web trellis he talks all about
different plant training techniques and
how to maximize yield using them if you
gain value from these podcast episodes
please click the like button and also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already that way you can be notified
when new episodes are released if you'd
like to support even more visit
various rewards set up for those of you
who support and you can pledge any
amount that you'd like 100% of the money
pledged through patreon goes right back
into the podcast it helps this podcast
keep going so thank you so much for your
support there before we get into it I
want to acknowledge that one of my goals
for this podcast is to bring free
gardening information of all plants to
the general public that being said I'd
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who help make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode their clip on oscillating
fan is awesome I've been using their
6-in version but they also have a 9-in
version it's easy to clip on the side of
my grow tent and has 10 different speeds
which makes it easy to control air
circulation they do have a
nonoscillating version of this clipon
fan as well it also connects to their
smart controller 69 so you can control
the fans and other AC Infinity equipment
through their app from your smartphone
the discount code Mr Grow 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com thank thanks to spider
Farmer for being a sponsor check out
their new sf600 grow shelves both the
metal stand and plant trays are included
each shelf is the perfect size for an SF
600 LED grow light and two 10in x 20in
heat mats it's also on Wheels so it's
portable and has dual locking casters
use discount code Mr Grow 5 to save 8%
on their website or 5% on Amazon I'll
leave links in the video description
section
below and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I'm joined
with Josh but some of you know him as
baby Grilla how you doing today I'm good
I'm good how's it going to how's it
going Mr Grow just want to say hi to you
and I appreciate you for letting me on
the show and um I want to say what's up
to the whole Mr Grow fan yeah thanks for
coming on appreciate it today we're
going to talk about maximizing yield
with plant training so there are so many
different ways to train plants and if
you do things right you can absolutely
increase the overall yield but before we
get deep into that let's do an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah so um I I was really
active as a kid and I used to like
really be into sports and uh the one
that took its toll on me the most was
basketball after a few like wear and
tear on my ankles I um I said I found
that this medicine helped me deal with
the pain a lot better than um you know
other things so after while I um you
know I started to take advantage of the
the
opportunity uh in 2010 they started uh
um well they didn't start that's when I
heard about it the
program um the medical plant program LIC
so that's when I got my started getting
my hands dirty that's awesome so before
we get deep into training plants one of
the things you had mention when I sent
you over the initial list of questions
is you had mentioned that the plant
needs to be healthy and you wanted to
talk about plant Health First talk to us
about plant Health why is that so
important before you start training
plants so um you know before before we
talk about uh plant training I'd like to
obviously talk about um plant health
because without a healthy plant you
really can't do anything um although
like a lot of people that are starting
off I realize people pop seeds and they
have really healthy plants cuz they
haven't gotten any viruses or any kind
of um bugs yet but so people that
probably for the most part have a clone
where maybe there's a virus in there or
some kind of uh pathogens or or even
even like it's good to start off with
bugs and make sure you don't have bugs
and why your plant sick and most
importantly the worst one is when you're
uh when your when your stems get purple
it's really hard to train your plants so
like if you have purple stems in
vegetation not in flower because those
are two different things usually if you
put the light Too Close flower you'll
get like uh the the the the plant itself
will try to what they call uh like shade
itself so it turns purple and that's
fine in flower but in vegetation if that
happens and it's coming from a
deficiency then you have to try to
correct it and that's where you start
digging I I like to start off making
sure I don't have bugs that I can't see
but usually I'm really dig you know like
very Vigilant on um in my garden making
sure I don't have that and once I find
out if I find out I have like something
in my root roots or anything like that I
usually start off with like
um I'll start off with 3 G per gallon of
uh peroxide I use um sanidate which is
more concentrated so it's probably a
more concentrated dosage than you would
get out of
peroxide with that said though uh I'll
I'll also use um a little bit of dish
soap and um that seems to like really
help me out like in the root system but
what happens is I wipe out a lot of my
um my built up colonies of like microbes
microfungi whatever is in there that I
took me so long to build up then I have
to kind of like reinoculate and get
everything back in the output like
usually I like to use uh amino acids
fobic acid and uh humic acid all at the
same time which is you know it's in the
recharge so that's kind of like a little
bit of a cheat code but if I want to get
more of it I'll just get it separately
and I'll add it in there all in the same
day I'll put microbes everything right
back
in and um after I see that I don't have
any bugs or anything what I'll do is the
next step I'll take is I'll actually add
magnesium and if you're if you're
already using Epsom salt and you're
already using a magnesium I I recommend
to use a little more
magnesium and I also recommend to use uh
phosphorus sep SE in raw form usually
like if you if you buy like a product
like raw for example uh raw mpk they'll
already have it in the uh you know they
have it in raw form so you could just go
buy it it's just real easy to have it in
raw form add a little more of those two
things which is uh the Magnesium I
mentioned and the phosphorus and that
kind of covers you um and you know for
the sake of having purple stems along
with the fact that you do have to make
sure that your environment is correct
once you get your environment correct
and go over those two three things that
I just mentioned that's like my process
of elimination when it comes to purple
stems what exactly is the issue with
purple stems though you hear people say
it's zinc you hear some people say it's
phosphorus you hear some people say it's
magnesium you hear people say that it's
for cold
temperatures is it one of the things and
not the other or is it a combination of
things or what my answer to that is
usually when I start to spot purple
stems it'll be like after I transplant
it and um maybe like left the lights at
and all the way 100%
intensity um I'll notice the purple St
that's almost me creating it but if I
could be on top of it and I could like
lower my my percentage to around 30 40%
for the first 5 days uh it kind of helps
me ease my way into the the process cuz
I notice more purple stems with
LEDs and um I think it has a lot to do
with the fact that the lights are
flickering at a faster rate than your
traditional
HPS now with all that said there's other
ways to create purple stems um like if
it gets too cold obviously you're going
to get purple stems and you know I I
really talk about it a lot when I'm
around other Growers and and they they
they like they like man what's your your
problem with purple stems but if you
have purple stems you just can't train
your plants if you're if that's what
you're trying to do is train your plants
yeah the stems become more harder and
less like malleable and you can't really
bend them as well I mean I totally agree
with you on that one and it seems like
it doesn't girth up like your branches
don't thicken up after they they if you
can correct the problem you'll start to
see these green lines coming through and
then the green lines almost like uh come
out and then push out the
purple and eventually you'll see purple
lines if you corrected the problem you
know like if you did a good job at
correcting it and you got it on time but
there's been times where I've where I've
gotten purple stems and like the plants
almost never recovered from it and
there's been times where you just go
into flower and they almost like fix
themselves right away because sometimes
they say don't put a you know like a a
sick plant in the
flower and which I don't I don't
recommend to do it but there's been
times where my plant's been sick and
just the 12 hours of resting and maybe
something in the formula because they're
get more phosphorus right away it just
corrects
it you know I don't recommend it but I I
actually recommend to get your
environment under
control you get you go through them
three things that I brought up and and
and that's a good way to kind of go
about correcting the the purple stems
okay so say the plant is healthy someone
is ready for training let's start with
one of the most common methods of
training which is low stress training
talk to us what is low stress training
when do you do low low stress training
and how do you do low stress training
order to maximize yield so one thing I
do want to be clear on is that um you
don't need to necessarily do these these
these uh practices that we're talking
about and like to it's not the only way
to get maximum production if you have
like a tent and the law says you can
grow 12 plants then you could
just basically what we're trying to do
is create what a a a sea of green and it
doesn't matter how you do it or how I do
it it just matters that I fill it and I
make it look the same
so basically this this strategy that
we're
um that that I'm practicing is for like
micro Growers where they've they've kind
of set certain laws and in that they
kind of uh they made it to where you
can't really mass-produce it you so so
like some people micro grows will make
the best out of the 24 some people even
the 12 plants they have so that's why
people do this and and with that said
um so what happens is when you when you
when you only have so many plants to
work with you got a 4x4 you got a you
know 6x6 and you're trying to train
plants and you only have four because
that's what you want to
do what happens is when you all the oxin
which are the hormones of that plant are
at the top of the plant and when you
pull these plants out and if you do it
properly with the right pruning the
middle branches are going to grow up and
when people are scrogging which is the
difference is that that's not what
they're looking to do they're looking to
kind of do more branches to where um
you're kind of focusing a little
different when you're when you're doing
the LST grow and you're trying to grow a
perfect Bush of a
plant so um to uh to to kind of shed a
little more light on that LST is when
you um when you pull the main branch
down or a couple main branch anes you
distribute the the plant energy towards
the middle of the plant and it um like I
said with the rate lollipopping and and
defoliation you can get colas in the
middle cuz that's basically what a lot
of people want to do they don't want to
end up with the smaller buds but um very
important another thing I like to
mention is it's important
to not train the skinnier not so thick
branches that are in the middle but but
to train only the big thick branches
that were kind of like the ones that
were too tall you move those out and um
once you end up with branches that are
too skinny that are in the middle still
cuz some genetics like to do that you
want to lollipop those as much as
possible and leave it alone and if not
if if it shows you it has enough
potential to do something that maybe top
it but really lollipopping is like one
of the things that's more important than
anything when it comes to Growing
because um if I if you gave me one style
to grow right now and I only had one way
to do it it' just be a bunch of plants
and I lollipop them it's so it really
comes down to plant maintenance and uh
plant Health we'll get into lollipopping
in a little bit here that is uh one of
the questions on the list here a little
bit later I think one of the biggest
mistakes that new Growers make that are
just starting to train is pulling that
initial Branch down and you mentioned
you talked about like the hormones and
if you don't actually pull that Branch
down so it's lower than the other
branches then that main branch that you
just pulled down is going to still
continue to dominate and uh you know
sometimes when the plant is Young you
can't actually pull that Branch all the
way down to be lower sometimes you just
need to do a slight Bend to begin but
eventually you want to get that main top
down lower than some of the other
branches so the plant will then Focus
its growth on those other branches it
happens time and time again with with me
it can be tricky it's not always easy to
do but I fig I'd mention that one yeah
I'd like to also add to that and uh
where I would want to add is on top of
what you said um sometimes you tie a
branch down and it's not tied um you
know good enough and now this branch is
is like coming up and now it's just it
almost like it just doesn't look right
if you could really hold that Branch
there that's that's very important to be
able to really firmly whatever trellis
unit you have if you could just firmly
hold it there and not allow it to come
back up cuz it's just it's not what you
were what you were aiming for when you
started everything so speaking of I
started using the training Clips in
order to then train them on train them
later and I noticed that uh a good
friend of mine you know he he he
basically told me this would happen
years ago and I never tried it but I
wanted to do it for for
R&amp;D and uh when I put the clips on it
took them off did everything
right I went to open them up again I
went to basically train the the plant
again and it snapped so I noticed that
um you know when you do that you're
creating that that Barky area where it
gets like a knuckle sometimes and even
almost like a super crop style and when
you go to train it again it's impossible
so just kind of talking from like my
experience and and and basically how far
I've gotten so far I realized that uh
it's not a good idea to to get that that
bark on there at that shorter area if
you're not aiming for a small little
plant if you're aiming to get like a
bigger plant and you want to be able to
train it or manipulate it um you can
never retrain it after you already got
that knuckle on it so it just makes it
that much harder so going back to the
LST it's it's all right to low stress
train and kind of pull the plant around
and do what you want to do with it but
um your once you once you put the
training clip or you do any kind of
tying down and creating that little
knuckle at the bottom training Clips
there's some people who probably don't
know what that is can you just clarify
what exactly you mean by the training
Clips are they just the standard garden
clips so you talking about the ones that
actually attach to the actual stem yeah
I just started like kind of like doing
research with them cuz I wanted to
implement it in my garden um and I don't
know the exact name of them but they're
the ones that everybody's 3D printing
now you you put it in there and it just
kind of is in there you know there's
Different Strokes with different folks
it depends who you are and what you're
trying to do that's a perfect um
strategy for somebody that's not going
to train the plant
again cuz like you know I as far as my
my uh product testing went that's that's
what I tried to do and um it just it
didn't didn't work the way I wanted it
to I've never used those trading clips
that you mentioned whether it goes
directly on the branches usually I'm
actually clipping it onto the side of
the grow pot just a regular Garden clip
and then using uh just regular Garden
ties like two bucks at your local
gardening store and using those to tie
down the branches to the side of the
growt definitely a different technique
there there's so many different ways to
go about it are you tying the branches
down to the side of the grow POD at all
or you just using the training Clips so
that wasn't that like I said that was um
just kind of like a a trial that I did
just to see how everything would work
out um obviously you know I use the
umbrellas and uh what I do it's a custom
trellis that I design that um it's not
it's not very given it doesn't give it
doesn't give back and once you open it
it's firm it holds and whatever I'm
trying to train stays the way I want it
to to go so um basically I was just
trying to like see if I could um trade
my plants a little lower at a lower
point because if you could get away with
using the way I thought of if I could
tie two or three branches down and it
make a difference a little
shorter I just wanted to see what that
would do and you know I just didn't I
didn't like the way it worked out for
me now with with that said um when it
comes to training a plant tying the
plant down like you just said uh couple
of my friends found that they they like
using like kind of like a more firm
trellis because of the fact that
sometimes when you when you pull a
branch down you'll have it down you know
and a recalibrate it's like what I like
to call it when it recalibrates comes
back up towards the
light sometimes these taller plants the
like branches just go like this way on
you for no reason and it's just not as
uh organized that's why I
um I still got to get you to try one of
my trist units Yeah you mentioned
umbrella and I'm sure that sparked a lot
of people's interest I'm sure there's a
lot of people that haven't even heard of
it can you talk to us about uh it's
actually your product right you created
this it looks like an umbrella it's a
trellis net talk to us about that so
yeah I got uh 5 years ago just I kept um
basically uh kind of like lollipop in my
plant speaking I know we're going to get
there but um so when I was training uh
this plant called Gorilla Glue that
everybody had in like 2015 you know
that's when I got it and um I kind of
like been growing it ever since
um so what was happening is this plant
grew perfect and when I would lollipop
it it just it looked like the reflection
of an umbrella
so um basically I I um I just didn't
want to do like your traditional PVC
when you're not using it usually like
you can't really uh detach or retract it
or anything like that it wasn't easy to
store cuz like I tried it a couple times
and I didn't like how it would just be
not easy to store basically
so I want to do something different and
I seen this umbrella reflection coming
out of the you know what I was looking
at and that's when I decided to pull the
trigger on it and you know 5 years later
now I I've really really
um I really got it to the point where
it's it's a really good formula I wait
till my plants are about 10 in tall and
what happens is I'll top it right around
there the branches will come out and
I'll have two perfect branches and
because this genetic called uh wiie
Pebbles that capulator the breeder
actually made it's an exclusive genetic
nobody really got
has access to it but uh I got it that's
a whole another story and
um these this plant grows very very
vertical it just grows very stretchy it
grows like a like a like a solid diesel
that I grew in the past like really tall
and um I would get I would hand it out
to people and they'd be like I give up I
don't want this plant anymore that's it
and I be like what're like I can't get
it to produce I mean you top this plant
and it just instead of like it like the
will glue we would top it and the
branches would just kind of like grow
like that and it just be like this
perfect Bush after you top it this plant
you would top it and then you just have
another Branch right on the side of it
it wouldn't even and then it just be the
same amount of branches it had just all
going up and and it wouldn't really fill
anything in so um I didn't understand
what anybody was talking about cuz I was
working on this product when I got this
genetic so when I hand out my product to
people and they're like oh this produce
me so much more flour and this that and
the other and I wish I would have got it
earlier and like I wish I would have you
know just listen to you two years ago
I'm like relax you got it that's all
that
matters point is they're like this
actually makes more production like I
really get more production out of it but
like I said I've been using it so long I
don't realize anything anymore I just
keep you know using my
formula so after 10 in once once the
plant gets really stretchy because it's
a stretchy plant and I'm actually
forcing this plant to look bushy so what
happens is you get those two branches
then the other two are going to follow
and even in some cases if you don't get
the trellis on it early enough it's very
forgiving cuz what'll happen is um first
off it's a it's a portable trellis it's
just it's basically uh designed just for
the the single plant and what happens is
if if you don't get the trellis on it
early enough and you don't startop
training it early enough you can go
ahead and let it just get tall and kind
of out of control on you and then when
you get this trellis on it if you if
you've train trained the branches
outward and there's still like a a foot
or two of like this plant just going up
again now I decided where if the plant
is healthy again back to the healthy
part because if it's not healthy there's
no way you're going to pull this off if
you got purple
stems once this Branch goes back up I
then pull it back down and all the
satellites that were going off of it now
all like just kind kind of
like Get
recalibrated and literally the energy
leaves that that that the upper po of
this this branch that I pull over the
energy like you go back like a week or
two later and that thing's done it just
kind of goes up like 6 or seven Ines and
that's all you're getting out of it but
then you could get
nine eight eight eight to even 10
branches just going off of that one that
are like it just it puts that main
branch to shame what like the way the
oxin get distributed to the all the way
the the branches furthest away from the
one you just pulled is going to be the
thickest brus and then they're all going
to be just gorgeous branches going up
and you can just create your own canopy
when when you uh when you're in control
of of your Ghana like that and you know
when it's an art and you're trying to
grow craft flower you know it's it just
it's it's it's a beautiful thing to
watch it feels like an art and it gives
you more time to
you know clean broom you know mop your
your garden make sure it's clean because
you're more efficient you're you're not
spending time grabbing a piece of rope
tying it down grabbing a piece of rope
tying it down that's okay for the guy
with four plants in a in a tent but when
you're a micro grow and you got you're
like basically a caregiver for a few
people and you're you're growing on a
larger scale then even if it's a
basement you know what I mean like it's
it's nice to be able
to create that beautiful art and train a
plant the way you see them being trained
but not put that much physical labor
into
it that's what that's what basically why
I did it it looks like an interesting
concept and definitely something I want
to try out in the future uh because I do
find myself growing those tall plants
and not wanting to tie down as much
these days as I used to and I I think
just putting that umbrella chalice in
and being able to spread it out it seems
like it would be a little bit easier
than doing all those ties like you
mentioned now my my question is I do
want to I do want to butt in on that I
if you could hold your thought on that
so I I you're saying that you don't like
training your plants and basically what
happens is they go vertical and I love
vertical growth like that's actually
where I get my production from is once I
plant um train the plants to grow
horizontal um I Then I then pretty much
just leave them alone
and really it just it just looks like a
bunch of small plants on the side of
each other so there's nothing wrong
we're growing plants that just go
straight up if that's if that's what
you're happy with and you know how to
you have the right light that penetrates
down to that lower canopy you're going
to get more production vertically and uh
some people don't find it to be a pretty
looking site but if you do it just right
lollipop improving your maintenance your
plants you'll get um you get more
production that way vertical yeah I
sorry I wasn't bashing it or anything
like that of just it's just people get
really uh you know when it comes to
Growing it's people want to fight with
you and like that's why I like I like uh
platforms like yours and it' be awesome
if I can come on like other platforms
and just have like a a nice civil debate
with people on um these conversations
and nobody has to punch nobody in the
face yeah exactly but what I was saying
is basically like just the time
consuming that it takes to to tie down
plants so not so much disliking the
shape but more so like the time spend to
to tie things out but I still do it um
anyways back to my question was about
the umbrella's trellis I just want to
know like what are the dimensions of it
like are you like when you put the
trellis in are you just shoving it down
into the soil like a steak like you
typically do with a steak how far down
does it go into the soil like how does
that work so um basically I I basically
been working on two different bases or
STS um and what it is is one is I kind
of make them custom to whoever like say
like you reach out to me you're like
look I got this situation going on and a
lot of times I will consult with people
and try to tell them what are you trying
to do how many plants are you trying to
have and you do want to commit to this
style because um you know once you buy
these you're kind of committed to that
style so what I do is uh I have
umbrellas all the way from 2 feet all
the way to like
4T and I recently started making them
Square uh the stands go in the soil and
they made about 13 in out they they're
really made to go into like 20 gallon
pots the ones I make for myself and
and local Growers but I make them
smaller for anybody for whatever they're
trying to do and um I make them like a
little shorter than the pot so that like
there's like 4 in of give so that uh so
that because I realized to put it
actually in the
soil I got I got more results so I had
to go back to that I was kind of like
putting it out and over and I was like
you know what I'm going to just make
sure that there's an inch if you could
just get an inch of soil over that thing
I mean those roots anchor it and then
that's it and usually the best time to
use it is on transplant so you know
you're going to transplant your plants
then that's a good opportunity to put
the stand in cuz it's just a stand so
what happens is uh you don't have to use
the umbrellas right away you can kind of
just get that stand in there and then
worry about that later and another
reason why there are different tears to
it is so that if you want to put a
two-footer still make it through the
door you can and you know go to your uh
you know flower room with it and not
have any
uh you know like uh a plant that can't
make it through a door I just had a
brain F I don't know
why but I didn't I didn't want to run
into
like having
a not be able to grab my plant from here
and move it over there basically so that
there was um you know that's why I came
up with that and then then once you get
into flower room if you want to put a
bigger umbrella on it you don't have to
worry about um you know space
restrictions through a door or anything
like that you could pull this other
umbrella out that's actually way bigger
put it on or if it's even if it's not
it's just I made it that way for uh
people to have more options and be able
to be more uh mobile more access to
every side of that room say your
electrician needs to get in your
electrical panels on the other side of
the room you could just pot the seas in
like 2 minutes you know and you throw
the second tier on whenever you want you
throw the third tier fourth tier you can
just keep going with tiar
and like I said that's where vertical
production comes from where it um and I
have to give a shout out to uh to cron
Don gross cron under uh CH h r o n
eore don gross because um he inspired me
between him and um the northern scr
Northern scroger taught me some
techniques on how to kind of like make
sure you don't um tangle the wrong
branches like when you're opening it up
it's one thing to focus on that but
don't let the branch get like Tangled
under the trellis get the right branches
to go up again so uh got to give him a
shout out we would have conversations
all the time and he would tell me how
ugly the big plants are he doesn't like
them at all but it's it's all good well
it sounds awesome I'm definitely going
to check out your channel again or your
Instagram page I should say and I think
you have a website and stuff like that
I'll definitely link your Instagram down
in the YouTube description section below
so those folks that are tuning in on
this can click on your Instagram check
it out they can see the umbrella trellis
in action and uh yeah let's move on to
lollipopping you mentioned that a couple
different times some people consider
this form of training other people
consider it a form of pruning whatever
way you think of it well we'll uh we'll
still cover it here today because it can
definitely be very beneficial when it
comes to helping to maximize yield talk
to us about lollipopping what is it and
how do you go about it so so lollipop
and is pruning it's just the word that I
think if you ask me on uh you know my my
Outlook on it I think it's just a word
that we we
used to describe
pruning because that's basically what it
is you're pruning the plant and um
so nowadays uh pruning is very important
because you just don't want to be
sitting there trimming little
flowers so um if you don't want to it's
it's almost like uh you know cry now
laugh later because you're not going to
be sitting there killing yourself later
on when it's time to trim if you
lollipop just right also it frees up
microclimates um from happening where
bugs can hide and mold can be
created and all these issues can happen
inside there cuz you're looking at your
thermostat in the room and it says 60
but is it really 60 you know so it's
going to help you uh stay away from
issues it's going to help air flow it's
going to help in my opinion the quality
of your flow like like when when my I
don't I don't run into like quality
problems and I think that has a little
bit to do with it that's a that's a part
in the fact that I grow quality yeah
when I do lollipopping I usually do the
lower third sometimes the lower fourth I
think a lot of people make the mistake
of going too high up when they're
lollipopping and uh ends up stunting the
growth of the plant you know they do it
right before stretch and they don't get
the stretch that they think they're
going to get then all of a sudden they
they
have poor production straightforward so
I think another thing I want to talk
about with the lollipop and is uh sorry
to cut you off but um so I do it four
times a veg I I want to say a plant gets
about four defoliations of vegetation it
gets about 3 to four in flower and uh
speaking of like shock on the plant we
never do too much at one time we kind of
um try to do so much at a time and the
reason why I do more late in flower too
like about 21 days to like you know that
that that 20 to 30 day period I I still
get in there because then you really
start seeing these little flowers that
just aren't going to make the cut and
it's really important for me to have
quality flowers so I just take off the
little tiny flowers that just H they're
not going to turn into
anything so we go all the way until like
day 30 got it that makes sense yeah last
time I will actually do the ly popping
is uh typically it's around day 21 in
flour but even like during flow you can
get some stuff kind of growing down
there so I usually kind of maintain that
continue to kind of pluck off those
little buds that are growing down on the
lowers even into flowering just to make
sure that uh don't end up with that
popcorn lury stuff at the end of the
grow so topping let's get into that I
there's quite a few people who do
topping and there are so many different
ways to go about it I mean when I first
started out I was letting the plant grow
to the fifth node then top and down to
the third then I was you know next time
around let the plant grow up to the
fifth node top at that fifth node and
let those lower branches grow up there's
a bunch of different ways to go about it
what do you do for topping um so I had a
friend who would like always just top
top top top top and not do plant
maintenance I'd be like dude like take
care of the plants he got like really
just gun hole with the whole topping um
as far as topping goes with me I weigh
10 in let the plant create the Y
structure that I like to
um you know my
terminology it creates that y let it
open it up once that happens um
sometimes the plant don't grow perfect
and even so there'll be like one branch
that just like outows a canopy later on
like early veg late flow I'll come in
I'll top that one but another you know
like usually when it's like late in veg
I'll start to try to flatten my canopy
out so I just come in and find the
tallest Branch top it then I'll wait
until another plant another Branch
passes the canopy and then come and top
it but it's more of a for me it's more
of like a place and time for it I
completely agree I have I usually grow a
variety of different cultivars and often
times I'll get that one cultivar that
just grows slower it stays squater and
then this other one uh just happens to
just have longer inter nodes grow faster
so like those ones I'll top more often
and allow my other plants that are
growing slower or stand squater to kind
of catch up a little bit because often
times they growing in one grow tent and
I have to flip that whole tent of flower
at once so just kind of utilizing
training on some plants to control the
height while the other plants catch up
is is certainly beneficial and Topping
does you know it can certainly if you're
doing topping and low stress training
you can certainly manipulate the plant
and train the plant to be more of a
wider structure have more main colas
coming up and can certainly increase
your overall yield so I'm definitely
glad we covered topping because that is
uh one of the main high stress trading
techniques that a lot of people use in
order to try to increase yield yep and
it's all about a leveled canopy and
that's where toping will help you out
you're just making sure you're nothing
you're not letting anything
get like this you don't you don't want
something low and something High yep if
you do get branches one get low one get
high one thing I usually do is
particularly in flower when I can't do
any other type of training is super
cropping to bend that Branch down and
allow the other ones to to catch up do
you do any super cooping at all can you
talk about what that is and when you
usually do it if you do it yeah I'm
happy you brought that up because uh I I
don't really use it because um you know
like I said earlier once you get that
knuckle um and flower it's okay to get
it because um you're not really trying
to train it after that um I don't do uh
super crabbing because I'm not in a low
sealing
situation uh I noticed that after I
super crop it the the the branch no
longer wants a stretch and that's where
I get my production from where um these
new genetics they kind of just like grow
stretchy and they Stack Up far apart
from each other those are the genetics I
love so I actually don't like my plant
to do that so I don't do super croing
that's the experience I have with it got
it yeah know uh pigeons 420 I don't know
if you know who he is I'm on a podcast
with him you do he uh funny guy he super
CRS every single branch which I thought
was just super interesting and when it's
young as well because he wants to build
up that strength in the branches so uh
you know there's so many different ways
to go about it I personally only super
crop in like in flowering the first
three weeks when I have that stretch
period and one of the branches or or
some of the branches get up and grow
over the other ones I'll supercrop those
ones only in order to try to maintain
that even in that situation it really
does I've done it before I'm not a
master at it but I've done it and um a
friend of mine does it as well and I go
by I look at his grow and I like it you
know it works great for the the
application he's in yeah he's in a he's
in a tent so I get it and like you said
there's certain branches that you know
you kind of want to do to get it to all
just be that level canopy yeah it can
make sense for many different
applications let's get into defoliation
this is another thing where some people
consider it training other people
consider it a form of pruning uh either
way a lot of people claim that it does
increase yield so figured we get into
that today do you do any type of
defoliation at all if so when do you do
it uh I do well when I do when I say I'm
doing uh lollipop and I'm pretty much uh
defoliating um I mean I know they're
both different because um sometimes you
go with a focus that you're going to
lollipop and prune and defol
sometimes could just be you going like
into your flower room usually is where I
would defoliate and just take leaves off
where they
so what I was taught a long time ago and
this is kind of a technique I still use
I I grow these kind of like big plants
so I'll try to create a circle of light
penetration and I'll pick off a leaf
that's on this side a leaf that's on
this side another one this way and this
way and I'll just go in a circle
defoliating I'll focus on that one
little area and once it looks like
there's light penetrating to the bottom
I'll move on to another Circle p and
I'll just start doing that I'll go in a
circle with taking leaves off and that
allows that penetration all the way down
huh okay are you only doing that in veg
or you doing that in flour as well some
people do it in late flour as well yeah
I do that mainly in flour mainly in
flower to allow the light to get in
there I don't I I can't think of a time
that I'm defoliating in and not
lollipopping when I'm doing it any other
time so if I'm in veg I'm just either
when I'm lollipopping I am defoliating
those things can definitely go hand
inand that's for sure speaking of uh
people you said people use it as a
training technique and I've noticed that
uh I think Beast Coast does it as well
he learned it from uh the Master grandm
Level Grand Master Level he learned that
if you take these leaves off at the top
these big leaves that actually trains
the plant too so that's pretty pretty
cool little technique that I you know I
just learned just watching people but
that's that's a cool little uh thing one
of the things I like to do is really
focus on defoliating like the center
like in the middle of the canopy going
down in and kind of leaving those outer
ones mostly mostly towards like the
bottom of the plant the the outer around
I like to leave those big bottom leaves
there often times because that could and
I call it the skirt method actually cuz
it kind of looks like a skirt in a sense
um the reason why is because if you're
coming across a deficiency right things
happen right the nutrition things could
get out of balance in the medium and you
could start seeing signs of deficiency
that helps right to be able to see that
happening because if you take off the
leaves well then you you kind of screwed
in that sense because then you you you
don't really see the deficiency as well
as if you had those lowers so I fig I'd
mentioned the skirt technique is kind of
leaving those lowers as an indicator so
you could see if you're seeing a
deficiency or not I had a friend of mine
that just told me not to leave the skirt
there cuz I used to and ever since then
I just stopped doing it so there's no
Rhyme or Reason but I don't leave the
skirt there yeah I mean what are you
talking about vegetation or flour I
usually do the defoliation in like veg
before flipping the flower and then I'll
keep it and you leave the skirt on yep
and then I'll keep it into flower uh the
first 3 weeks I usually defoliate I'll
look to defoliate on day s day 14 and
day 2 want but often times it doesn't
need to be defoliated that often
genetics is going to depend on it of
course uh but yeah I'll leave that that
skirt all the way through there I don't
I don't you know never really saw harm
in leaving that skirt the only thing if
there's a lack of air flow then yeah
you're going to I'm going to pull off
the leaves there but other than that
I'll just leave those bottom leaves
there you leave them all the way through
too huh yep So Different Strokes for
different folks no I mean I like I said
I don't do it but there not a rhyme a
reason why I don't do it all right well
uh we covered quite a few I think the
only thing we didn't really cover was
fing and I think if remember correctly
last time we spoke you don't do any type
of fimming right no I don't do fine cuz
uh I'm just not something I ever got
into plus um it kind of creates more
branches and I'm not too crazy about
more branches in that in in certain
scenarios okay are there any other PL
training techniques that we didn't cover
that you'd like to talk about no I think
uh we pretty much covered everything
like I said I just uh usually pull my
plants out but if if I uh if I'm
slacking and my plants get Too Tall I'll
usually come back and wrap it around the
outside which
is you know basically covered that so I
think I think we're pretty good as far
as
uh PL training nice I appreciate you
coming on to the podcast and revealing
your training techniques just want to I
think if I could shed light on anything
it would be that um my first trellis is
is simply to train the plant the second
trellis is to support the middle
branches and the third plant I mean uh
trellis is to uh support the upper part
of the
branches so you know to anybody out
there that can like you know I encourage
you to try it both
ways really I encourage you to not train
them after after you trained them the
first time but if you want to do an
experiment go ahead and you'll see that
um it just works a lot better when you
just let the plant just go up after
that that's how you get the the colas if
you keep just training and training
branches you end up with skinnier
branches and then you end up with
skinnier flow oh smaller smaller flowers
I've made that mistake before uh you
know continuing to train all the way
till stretch was done and all of a
sudden I have these uh this real small
flat plant which uh doesn't really grow
up much and the buds are just kind of
all Consolidated and a yeah it's and
then sometimes you got to Branch hand
then you got this one here and then it's
like you trained this one again and now
you're just shading another one so it's
like you got to kind of like pick when
when's enough is enough on the training
the topping with all of that good advice
any other advice for maybe beginners who
are just training for the first
time just to find a good uh seed bank or
genetic Bank uh you know somewhere you
could get some good reliable
seeds um pretty much start off there uh
get your environment under control uh
tent is the best way to go about that
cuz it retains everything a lot better
than just trying to start off in a room
that's going to not have uh any it's not
going to be able to retain as well so
you know a tent's very
efficient um make sure not to water too
much cuz everybody makes that mistake
when it comes to cloning don't at fill
the thing up with water actually just
leave a little bit at the bottom to
where the roots actually have to go
searching for it
um and just uh if you're using LEDs make
sure to keep you you could go as high as
like
87 and keep your humidity as high as up
to 65 and you'll be fine if you could
stay under that uh VPD for those LEDs
you you do a lot better um HPS wasn't it
it's not as uh it's a little more
forgiven because of uh I guess uh they
say that the uh the HPS actually create
heat so for you to for you to use a LED
you have to kind of like run your room a
little hotter to kind of buffer that
whole difference
so those few things I think are very
important making sure you cuz the Clones
are very important of course the um your
environment for your plants is very
important humidity is very important
when they're small you could do them
things and and and you get off to a good
start all right good stuff so wrapping
things up how can the listeners find you
and do you have anything up coming in
the future that you want to talk about
pretty much uh nothing coming up in the
future I just uh been just working on
this project that I've been working on
since forever now um the web trellis
which is uh an idea that I patented and
um trying to get it out there just so
people could see it use it kind of like
grow with
uh you know use use the uh the web
trailer style in their
Garden uh um it's always just you know
it's an option and
um I'm on Instagram as umbrella trellist
and uh my backup is uh the web
trellis
um I'm going to actually uh that's
pretty much it just going to be on there
and um I am going to build
my uh different different um social
platforms up cuz right now it's
basically only Facebook and IG but
moving forward maybe even um get my
YouTube channel
going start growing some tomato plants
or something and really start like
crushing it and showing people how uh
you get some really good production
horizontal too it's not all just
vertical awesome well like I mentioned
earlier in the episode I'll definitely
have a link to Josh's Instagram down in
the YouTube description section below if
you're on one of the podcast file forms
just search for them you'll find them if
you enjoyed this episode click that
Thumbs Up Button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend I'm releasing a new
Garden Talk podcast and I would love for
you to tune in to future episodes Josh
once again thanks for coming on this has
been uh it's been pretty insightful I
always like talking about plant training
because there are just so many different
ways to do to go about it and hearing
your way to go about it which is
different from my way which is different
than a lot of other people's ways is is
interesting and there's definitely some
takeaways here so thank you for coming
on to the podcast today appreciate it
awesome all right peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode