coming up on garden talk if you're at
5.8 you have access to everything your
plant has access to everything that's
one of the things i love about hybrid
hydroponics and deep water culture is
that i mix it and i have full control
and i know what's happening cracky is a
fantastic growing method but it's
limited for certain plants changing the
reservoir that advice is anywhere from
weekly to every two weeks
when i fill up my hydro buckets i always
fill them up one to two inches
below the bottom of the net pot it's not
for advanced growers it's for new
growers is because it takes the grower
out of the equation how many times have
you ever over watered a plant or
underwatered a plant when you grow in
deep water culture that doesn't exist
there's no watering
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 36. in this
episode i interview mitchell from
visionary hydroponics he has been
gardening for seven years and he's the
creator of the hydro bucket a deep water
culture hydroponic system he talks all
about deep water culture dwc and
recirculating deep water culture or dwc
this has been a highly requested topic
from you the listeners so i'm super
excited to bring you this one today
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com mr growit before we get into
it i want to acknowledge that one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring zero
cost for information about gardening all
plants to the general public that being
said i'd like to thank the sponsors of
this podcast who helped make that goal
possible spider farmer is a sponsor of
the podcast coupon code mr growit5 will
get you a discount on their products
they're most known for their led grow
lights but they also have other products
such as grow tents inline fans and
carbon filters i've used their sf 1000
sf 2000 and sf 4000 led grill lights in
the past and i got some great results
with them i will leave a link to spider
farmers amazon store down in the
description section below and don't
forget to use coupon code mr grow at 5
for discount on their products
big shout out to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast ac infiniti is
well known to produce high quality
products and provide excellent customer
service they have the thickest grow tent
on the market today
in line fans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
growit during checkout for a discount on
their products thanks to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro
products are now available in several
countries across the world for those of
you that don't know dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that has base
nutrients additives and ph regulators
they have different formulas of base
nutrients for if you're in soil or if
you're in hydro or cocoa they also
formulate their base nutrients for if
you're using hard water or if using ro
or soft water i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code
mrgrow10dp for a discount on their
products
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with mitchell from visionary hydroponics
how you doing today
i'm doing well as uh thank you for
having me yeah thanks for coming on uh
my voice is a bit raspy so i kind of
apologize to the listeners in advance i
was in a very smoky environment over the
weekend and it just got to me so i lost
my voice and a little bit raspy here
hopefully you guys can stick through it
luckily i'm not gonna be doing most of
the talking mitchell's gonna be doing
most of the talking today which is a
good thing we're gonna be talking all
about hydroponics
so this is a highly requested topic i've
had so many people over the past
30 something episodes that i've done so
far just dwc wwc rwc rwc hydroponics so
we're going to get into that today
actually got a most of these questions
came from me but i did have quite a few
people submitting questions through
instagram so thank you to everyone who
had submitted questions in through
instagram a lot of great questions that
you guys submitted in and this episode
is going to be awesome because i think
we cover so much in detail to all of you
that wanted this dwc episode i think
you're going to like this one a lot so i
personally don't grow in dwc or any type
of hydroponics i have my concerns
my reasons for not doing it which i
think will address today which we'll go
over maybe they aren't actually
legitimate concerns and i'm just
overthinking things but yeah we'll get
on to that later on into the episode but
first can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening sure uh first off thanks for
having me so much i you know i really
appreciate
people who bring
knowledge to
to uh uh people to grow at home to grow
in different ways to grow different
things
we're in an opportunity in the world now
that
yeah i mean a lot of opportunities are
opening up for us so uh thanks for
having me on and and just you know
sharing all the knowledge and what you
do
um so
i got into gardening uh a few years ago
it was pre-legalization you know i've
always grown plants i've always had
house plants but i just kind of let
house plants i keep them alive i don't
grow them so much but pre-legalization
in canada
when legalization was announced i
immediately knew i was going to grow
medical plants i've always wanted to
i've always had a uh
a thing there so
i went out and i bought the grow bible
and i started reading and
i came on to deepwater culture
and so two years before legalization i
just started growing deep water culture
in my basement getting familiar with it
growing tomatoes peppers cucumbers
anything that i could so i knew when
legalization happened
you know i had some experience and i was
just gonna roll with it and and that's
what happened yeah and i've been growing
ever since awesome so we'll get into
that deeper hydroponics in particular so
you said deep water culture a lot of
people call it dwc what is dwc and then
there's also rdwc can you talk to us
about those two things
sure yeah so the difference is is that
it's one style of hydroponics
hydroponics there's lots of different
styles deep water culture and
recirculating deep water culture are the
two
is what we're talking about and a deep
water culture
is essentially a plant that is in some
sort of medium suspended above
a solution and then that solution
contains just the roots there's nothing
else down there except for roots and
nutrient solution and air stone
being and oxygenating the air and and
and that's all
and then how what separates a deep water
culture
from recirculating deep water culture is
exactly that is a recirculating system
if it's just deep water culture it's
just one container and there's no pumps
or anything nothing's moving it's deep
water culture if it's a recirculating
deep water culture it's still deep water
culture same principles apply except now
there's water moving typically to an
external reservoir and there's reasons
and
i mean differences between having and
pluses and minuses of having an external
reservoir versus simply just having
everything contained in one uh
container okay that makes sense and now
what equipment is needed you said for
dwc it's just kind of a bucket in itself
i'm sure you need like a net pot within
the net pot there is a medium can you
talk to us like in detail about what the
different pieces of equipment are needed
for those setups yeah absolutely so
for deep water culture you're going to
need a few basic things you're going to
need
a
bucket
something to
hold your your fluid you're going to
need something to hold your plant and
your medium and you're going to need an
air pump an air stone
and an airline and
and that's it that really is all that
you need uh of course then you need your
nutrients and all the other stuff but um
those are the basics and you can really
get into deep water culture uh for it's
quite an affordable thing
to get into but it's a little bit
intimidating um i think everybody can
can speak to that right so and so within
those net pots you can put different
types of mediums right you can do the
clay pellets clay balls right hydroton
or you can do cocoa can you do soil can
you do perlite can you do different
types of medium within that net pot or
does it have to be a certain type
right yeah so uh so typically what you
need for deep water culture is you
you're suspending your plant above your
nutrient solution right your nutrient
solution below is just roots just just
uh aerated
solution and i would say you know about
two-thirds of your plant is submersed in
that that's your consumption selection
of your roots your upper portion of your
roots is enclosed in a net pot some form
of apparatus some people call them the
top hat those are the ones that are
large that contain the structure that
holds the medium so that is either going
to be
hydroton which is the clay pellets it
could be
rock wool uh that that's an inert medium
that's up there as well
you could technically use
anything to hold the plant above in the
net pot
but you don't want to be making your
solution dirty if you're using cocoa or
you're using soil or anything like that
it can be done but it's not
ideal it doesn't work well it's best to
keep everything really nice and clean
and uh um go with the inert mediums okay
gotcha yeah that makes sense i even
think about that it could dirty the
water if you're using something like
soil right just drips down in there so
that right that's
balls and stuff like that because that
doesn't really drip down into in there
or anything so
right and that's one of the things is
getting away from i found getting away
to not introduce soil every time i've
tried to introduce oil or or cocoa
just for the experience in my garden i i
find other things come accompany with it
you know when you're just dealing with
rockwool and you're doing with hydroton
or
an apparatus say that doesn't use medium
at all uh
you you now don't have to you're not
introducing any organic uh critters
right there's there's there's there's
nothing alive coming into your garden
it's all washable and uh
the pests are really uh easier to
control uh in that matter
gotcha now you mentioned air stones so
that's one way of doing you know you
have air stones within the bucket it is
oxygen that water that's key that's
gonna one one thing that's gonna help
prevent you know something like root rot
you know what i mean lithium i think
it's called is is the actual name of the
the bacteria in there that that causes
the harm there's also the kratky method
which i believe is just there's no air
stones right correct me if i'm wrong the
roots are just sitting in the bucket so
you can actually get away with not using
air stones at all can you talk to us
about the differences between the two
like kind of the pros and cons of air
stones versus the kratky method yeah
definitely so kraki is a fantastic
growing method but it's limited for
certain plants
the principle of kratky method is that
you can mix a nutrient solution
and
you could put your plant
in your medium in your lid and then put
that lid in your mixed solution in a in
a container and then there's no
oxygenation there's no disturbance
there's no ph balancing there's no
addition of anything what you mix and
what you put into that container is
going to
have everything the plant needs to get
it to harvest so that's really cool but
it's only applies to certain things your
leafy vegetables
and nothing that has to have a
transition in its nutrient
regime so if you have a plant that needs
vegetative nutrients and then has to
switch to bloom nutrients exclusively
and has different nutrients that is
changing
for a fact
that's not gonna work with kraki because
you're obviously working that and
something that's a a very long uh um and
uses you know intense amount of
nutrients and stuff is not gonna work
for kratky but it is cool there is ways
to use it for
different plants and uh um
also with uh you know cloning medical
plants it's uh there's some neat things
to do with kratky so okay gotcha now one
of the top questions i had through
instagram was can you grow organically
using dwc
right
and that is
i would love to be able to grow in a
pure organic sense you know that is just
something that people it's a big box to
check for a lot of people that's the
one thing that allows people to really
get into living soil and and organics
and and just pursue that
i'm testing some nutrients right now
some fertilizers and they are an organic
line um
but
again i'm just testing that right now
i don't use it
because i found with organics even
introducing organic amenities
you risk the run or you don't risk i
mean you have accumulation is what it is
you have
you have you have to think of your water
solution that you have as your deep
water culture solution and you have your
roots and
everything in there
and when you have
organics that are physical compounds
that are in there
you have to be careful how many things
you add that create
uh
you know sticky into the water right
that film that could you can only handle
so much and then at a certain point
but i don't know understand all the
science but any time i've tried it it's
just you get an accumulation of gunk you
get a uh uh and and that goes in the
opposite direction of when you don't
it's just nice and clean and white right
you know everything that's happening
that's one of the things i love about
hybrid hydroponics and deep water
culture is that i mix it and i have full
control and i know what's happening
organics
i'm working on it i i think in year in
years to come
and who knows maybe very shortly there
there will be some great organic
products that work really really well
that's around the corner but right now
for ease of use especially for new
growers i stick to you know some
semi-organic stuff
that's just fully dissolvable so it's
all about dissolvable right okay that
makes sense and just kind of talking
more about nutrients i know like some
organic lines they're
very thick you mentioned sticky they're
gonna clog the actual lines of the
hydroponic system right so
are there any can you talk about some
nutrient lines maybe that you recommend
that won't actually clog the lines
yes uh
if we're talking about and we're talking
about a recirculating system
specifically right and here's here's you
know the
again going back to the difference
between recirculating deep water culture
and deep water culture deep water
culture has its advantages because
there's nothing to
there's nothing moving there's no pumps
happening in your house there's no
external reservoir with lines and
pressure
and
crevices and cleaning in between grows
it's just a bucket right that's the
hydro bucket that's why that's why we
we made it it's kind of getting away
from that recirculating system so you
don't have accumulation you have it all
right in front of you available
to
interact with um and and
and this i think may lend to
more
you know going down that line of
organics and uh
using stuff that is a little more gunky
because you can you can manage it on an
individual basis per plant right
and you have access down in front of the
roots you can actually see the roots
as per design of the hydro bucket and
the deep water culture vessel that it is
but
right now i use crop salts
anything that is a
you know any liquid will work well
you know
like so many people i started off with
gh3 part
right
and then a lot of people start there and
they start going up to maybe some nice
expensive stuff like advanced nutrients
uh
you know they work great you you
there's so many great nutrients out
there uh canadian companies american
companies uh european companies uh but
also then you can get into some nice dry
nutrients where for new users it's very
nice and economical where you get a
couple sacks they're going to last you a
year
and you just don't have to measure
multiple things per when you're mixing
up your solution you just get to go
so many grams of a so many grams of b
and you're done and that's the same
throughout your grow you just dilute it
with water
so
the big thing with nutrients
it really doesn't matter which one you
choose as long as it's fully dissolvable
that's what you're looking for it
dissolves 100 percent
and there's it just looks like a nice
clean water after maybe there can be
color i mean some of many of them
manufacturers use color um and again
that can stain your roots and
make people think oh no my roots are
brown or orange or whatever but
you know if you just choose a nice white
fully dissolvable nutrient line then
you'll just always be impressed with how
they look thinking you use liquid or
powder as long as it's fully dissolvable
and then you're just kind of dumping
them into your dwc system with the
existing water that's already in there
or you're putting into a bucket diluting
it down then dumping that bucket of
water into your dwc system right
yeah i mean so so so you know i treat
our rdwc and dwc there's a couple things
that i've come across uh over the years
especially now that i have hydro buckets
in my garden
you know i
the whole reason
that i created
the hydro bucket was
uh because i here's here's what happened
with my with with growing um
is that i started growing like a lot of
people i chose deep water culture
because i heard
of how
how awesome it is i it worked for me
that i could grow in my basement i could
be clean right there's no there's no
coming and going with soil and mixing
and stuff i didn't have room for that uh
i could grow my four medical plants and
deep water culture worked for me so
i went out like anyone i'm i'm i'm a
home grower and i don't want to just go
out and spend lots of money and this is
one of the challenges of deep water
culture
and hydroponics in general is if you
wanted to enter hydroponics
there's a pretty good price tag to that
right especially a recirculating system
you're either going to spend quite a bit
of money on a recirculating system or
you're going to go a diy road
and so that's what i did is i went the
diy route uh i this is one of the very
first buckets that i made i went and got
the bucket for five bucks i drilled the
thing i got the grommet you know uh but
a lot of people
are we're talking about a diy people
versus growing people right and not
everybody has a drill not everybody has
all these things so so deep water
culture has kind of been overlooked um
for that reason right
but what happened was
after going into getting this i found
i have to lift my plants
i have to i have to jeopardize yield
every time
i have to change this nutrient solution
i have to lift a big tomato plant or or
a pepper plant or cucumber plant uh and
and and it's a bit of a disaster to be
able to get into here
so what do you do
to solve that is you go to a circulating
system
you hook up plumbing to your buckets so
you have an external reservoir outside
of your tent outside of your environment
so now you can service
all of your nutrient solution that's
going through all four plants from your
external reservoir
right and and that that that works well
because now you can scrog your plants
you don't have to worry about
a loss of harvest because you never have
to lift the top anymore to access for
fluid changes
or anything right it's all
controlled in the external reservoir
so that's what i did
is is i grew in a recirculating system
but then
i just found that that i was still using
all diy stuff and there wasn't uh
there's just there had to be something
better than just a pail than a bucket
and so that's uh yeah so that's so
that's when we made the hydro bucket
right that's why we made the hydro
bucket and we and we made access to it
and so essentially what what this did
was
we want access to the to the growing
container
and we don't want to lift the top so we
put a reservoir outside of the tent
so we've just moved the reservoir and
attached it right onto the hydro bucket
right i mean so now with a hydro bucket
we don't need plumbing we don't need an
external reservoir outside the tent
let's just put another tent beside that
tent right
because
now
we can have our plants on top and they
can be scrogged they never have to be
lifted they're treated just like a dirt
plant you never have to disturb it
and you have access just like you have
an external reservoir but it's on the
side so there's a lot of benefits
to doing this and getting into
just skipping the recirculating system
for those that are listening and don't
see the actual visual he held up just
your normal at first he held up your
normal five gallon bucket they'd get
from like home depot or lowe's and it
kind of had a kind of a pipe attachment
to the side and then he showed up his
hydro bucket which are products that he
created and it kind of has like a lip
this is kind of the best way for that i
can think to explain unless you have a
different words to explain that lip but
it gives you a way to access
the inside without really you're not
really having to remove a top at all
right you can kind of just kind of get
in there without having to lift up the
plant like you had mentioned so yeah
that's it it allows you to
uh
access
the reservoir solution get in there and
check your ph because here's the thing
if you're growing in
a bucket
how do you test your ph in your
reservoir you know in a convenient and
and functional way because because you
have to keep
you have to test your ph and you have to
check
keep the parameters of your nutrient
solution in check just like your
environment right it's everything it's
it's about when you're growing plants if
you give them the right environment they
will grow well and there's two
environments there's your
root environment of your plant whether
you're soil or cocoa or hydro it doesn't
matter you still have a temperature and
a water and
you're managing that environment and
you're managing your plant environment
that's your light and your humidity and
your temperature so
we have to manage that we need an easy
way to get into our
solution and check it
we need to be able to remove fluid from
it and put new fluid in
so when we when when you're only using a
five gallon
bucket or a diy job
it's very difficult to get in there you
have to disturb that top you have to
lift it and move it and it can be done
but it's not really very convenient
with the hydro bucket
the externally the external reservoir
that is fluidly coupled sharing the same
walls and bottom
is one way to explain it it is a five
gallon bucket with
more space added
and that external reservoir on the side
has a lower access point
so you can see your roots you can see
inside you can see what's happening
and you can access it comfortably you
can drop a hose in there you can use a
water pitcher you can use your put your
ph pens and your ec pens in there and
test on a regular basis all without ever
touching your plant so
ever lifting it so essentially you know
we we made recirculating
systems without all the pumps and
pressure that's pretty cool yeah viewer
question was you know if you're not
doing our dwc and you don't have the
hydro bucket right you're with the
typical five gallon bucket what's the
easiest way to remove the water from the
buckets you know i use
a pony pony pump anyway uh when when
when you get into hydroponics there's a
certain thing few things that you need
that you're just going to make your life
really nice
and going to help you i mean
just just grow in a way that's
i say let the pumps do the work
you know don't you don't you don't you
don't have to lift anything anymore and
this is just well suited for certain
people certain growth styles certain
ages i mean there's a lot of people who
can't carry big bags of whatever in and
out of their house up and down stairs so
hydroponics allows you to plug a pump in
and let it do all the lifting and so
yeah i love a pony pump with a small end
that you just drop in uh
and it sucks it out and then you can uh
add to your
uh
your your vessel your water vessels
again right to top everything up um but
it's it's more than just the ad and
removing um with a pony pump okay gotcha
let's flip it up let's talk about water
so
water why did i say it like that water
water
let's talk about water what is the type
of water that's ideal to use for this
you know the best results that i've had
are reverse osmosis water
ro water
it's just it's just costly to create all
oral water um
you know you you have to you need an ro
system and
there is some waste involved
uh with it
um
it works the best but it's not required
i don't use ro water uh
[Music]
again i found my best results were
coming from it but i couldn't grow at
the
level at the size the size of my garden
i just couldn't keep up with that amount
i'm still a home grower and i'm not
ready to spend a few thousand dollars on
the massive ro system that's out of
reach for me right now uh so so i'm just
uh i'm using tap water and i'm sure to
aerate it it comes from it's a municipal
water source i put it in a thousand
liter tote
so it sits there has the the chance to
off gas
and then that that's where i start so
i have good results with it results will
be better if you do use reverse osmosis
water when you say off gas are you
talking specifically about chlorine
exactly you're going to have chlorine um
and you're going to just
um you have that smell to the water when
you get obviously it's treated right out
of the facility when it comes out of
your tap you know for it is here so once
you leave it sit for a week uh or you
put a bare stone in there you can smell
that that smell goes away and
um you know it's just
something that you can do to
the and there are other small there are
some some products that exist out there
at our local store hardware store there
is a
i couldn't tell you what it is but it
was a fairly affordable product that
changed tap water made tap water
suitable for
plants and animals
um so
i'm sure it's something that busts up
the uh
the
the chlorine bond and maybe just helps
it
dissipate from the water
because really i think that's what we're
trying to do is we don't want
water that is going to kill live things
that's all we're really looking for
what's in the water
is important
you know if you have a water source that
is
400 parts per million that's what it's
starting at well that's a problem
because it contains a lot of stuff
already right reverse osmosis you take
everything else you're starting at zero
so this is why it works so much better
is you have all the space
in your water your water is essentially
empty consider consider your water is
your your your obviously your fluid but
it's what you're delivering to your
plant as your your battery so when you
start at zero or you start at 50 uh
parts per million you can
let's say you're building it up to 1 000
parts per million for your plants that's
1 000 parts per million that you have
full control over
if you're starting at 400 you have all
kinds of stuff in there you might
already have high levels of magnesium
and calcium or who knows what so when
you're just adding your three part or
your nutrients to 400
you don't you know it's it's it's
problematic most tap water you know most
people you're gonna be one to two
hundred
and that's fine uh as long as it's not
actively killing everything it comes in
contact with like chlorine does right
it's meant so to keep to harbor any
beneficials so your water's not alive
well we want our water to be alive
we don't want it to be dead so
we want our water to a lot be to come
and either ro out the chlorine and the
stuff that kills
beneficials in the water or we want it
to aerate it and just get that chlorine
out of it and then it's just water
so we do need to get the chlorine out of
it because you know chlorine kills off
beneficial microbes it also kills off
the bad microbes right
hydroponics a sterile environment
anyways and we don't really rely on that
beneficial bacteria to uptake nutrients
at the roots so on and so forth or what
right well so there's two ways to grow
um
we're not we don't necessarily keep it i
don't grow in a sterile environment i
know there are
other companies that do it very well do
it very well but that lends to
the big hydroponic recirculating systems
that that are in the industry
you know they're
at an industrial standard where you have
what how many how many plants hooked up
how many vessels to your recirculating
system 10 20 50 right you know you can't
afford
contamination anywhere period uh and a
lot of the uh regulations don't allow
for it i mean you have to prove that you
can grow here in canada where where you
you're not going to jeopardize
a large crop of plants
uh with something so being sterile on
that level in a recirculating system
is extremely important i think but not
necessary
the how i grow
is
with a live environment i
don't sterilize i start with water again
i'll start with with with uh um
you know i start with my aerated tap
water that's been sitting in my my
thousand liter tote and then i'll mix
that into a hundred liters um and that
does one of my flower rooms that'll do
you know five six seven eight nine about
eight eight or nine hydro buckets is one
of my flowers so i'll mix 100 liters at
a time and
my my starting point i start sterile and
and that is true just to make sure the
water going in and there's there's
nothing harboring in there so i start
with a
uh
silic silicic acid uh or a
like a
magnesium sulfite
and so
what that does is there's some benefits
there for the plant but it also
puts a ph spike and makes it quite
off the scale and and and not you know
great for anything to be in um so that's
where we always start in that direction
and then you add your your nutrients to
that once the nutrients are in there
uh then i will bring the ph into balance
once the ph is in balance then i'll add
some microbes i'll add microbial mass
and i'll add some
hydrozyme
root enzymes so these are living things
so you want to make sure your ph is in
check and it's a not a hostile
environment otherwise you're just
they're just going to get fried right
so once i add those then i put those
then i feed out of that thousand liters
or 100 liters and i just pump into my
hydro buckets and they that is their
feed for the week
okay gotcha that was actually a question
was can you use beneficial microbes and
dwc and you just answered that yes you
can yeah yeah
that's cool right now what about the
water level what should the water level
be within the system the water level is
important
definitely but it's more important in a
recirculating system
in the recirculating system
you want that water level to never go
above a certain level so that's two to
three inches below the bottom of your
net pot
right and basically what we're looking
at it is
the your the top portion of the plant
has to breathe this is the whole dry out
principle of of drying out plants right
is it has to dry out from the top down
because that top third is really where
the root
the plants
have a different process than the uptake
portion that's the below
so two to three inches below
always from the bottom of the net pot
you don't go above that in a
recirculating system
if you're in a deep water culture
then you can
and i say that just because not on not
on on good garden practice not on
regular practice when i fill up my hydro
buckets i always fill them up to about
what again one to two inches
below the bottom of the net pot
and then but sometimes i'm going away
and it's not a static environment i know
that that fluid level is going down it's
going down pretty drastically in certain
times in in the grow cycle
with with uh uptake of different plants
so
i know that
if i want an extra day
then i will fill it up right to the
bottom of the net pot i'll get that
extra two inches in there
why not because i know the plant is
going to say oh i'm kind of drowning
but
but it has no choice it it though that
fluid is moving through it um
and in a day it's down to one or two
inches and then it's within uh two or
three more days it's down to uh uh only
two or three inches left in the bottom
of the hydro bucket and then it requires
service again one of the general advice
that you hear every so often is talk
about changing the reservoir every so
often you hear about it should be done
every seven days some people say you can
do it 10 days everybody says you can do
14 days you can do it so how often
should the reservoir actually be changed
right so again this is this is uh this
is this is a broad area of it depending
on how you're doing things for home
growers right we don't want to you no
one wants to waste a lot of water i mean
that's a very valuable resource so we're
always trying to conserve everything we
can
and when i did grow in a recirculating
system
and i had that larger external reservoir
i found it
i was more grudging to change that
solution because there was more of it
the whole principle of recirculating is
you're using volume to
move i mean the volume volume is what's
moving through all the uh
additional lines to move it through the
tent and then back into the
reservoir so you need x amount of volume
that is nutrient solution that is just
there simply mixed to make things move
where
in a sm in the same single bucket you
only mix what you're going to use and it
sits there
so one to two weeks is when you should
change your reservoir if you're sterile
then
uh um
you know there it there's more to it uh
you want new new you you want to change
it but it's more of a system of how to
grow it's understanding
uh a a recipe in which to
uh
when to add nutrients when to add water
when to pump it out and i say every
single week
and the reason why i say that is it
allows you
to refresh your plant put everything
back
into
parameters
that they want to be in
uh and then
at the end of the week completely flush
your plant
and get it ready for the week again
if that makes sense and i can go into
detail on that i do online on our on our
ig page with some videos but um i'm
happy to talk about that here as well
yeah i mean they can they can always
visit the ig page to learn more about it
in detail and we've got quite a few
questions here to continue on to so if
you want to learn more details about
that in particular what's your instagram
it's vish it's hydro bucket uh or
visionary hydroponics we can be found on
instagram yeah and that's where we post
a lot of uh videos on i call it the week
in the garden where i show
why i where how i pump out and what i do
for my seven days in the garden that
repeats each week okay cool
ph
let's talk about ph ph is another hot
topic
you know there's a general range that
people can stay within 4ph that's the ph
of the water solution can you talk to us
about ph what's the ideal range and so
on and so forth yeah so ph is everything
ph is availability so
if you're many people have seen the the
the scales uh uh essentially if you
are at your your range is 5.5
to 6.5 in hydroponics in deep water
culture hydroponics okay let's just to
be clear because cocoa is hydroponics as
well and those are not the same ph
ranges so deep water culture hydroponics
year 5.5 to 6.5 if you're in that range
your plant is not
going to be stressed it has availability
to move water and function and
availability to certain uh uh
uh nutrients so
if it it
5.8 is ideal if you're at 5.8 you have
access to everything your plant has
access to everything if it goes below
5.8 you're going you're not going to
have access to
the stuff that is at the higher end of
this of the scale at 6.5 just like if
you go to 6.5 you're not going to have
access to the stuff that's below 5.8 so
you can float around i mean your plants
the plants know what to do they don't
have to just be
right there and if they're not there oh
no if it's 5.5 to 6.5 it's good and we
keep it in range as long as it's in
range for four days then you have the
ability to uh uh
you know check it and adjust it every
four days but you have to keep your ph
in range number one what are some of the
best ways to stabilize the ph from my
understanding if you have air stones in
there your ph could is more prone to
drift so what are some of the best ways
that you can stabilize ph
um you know i hear this
often is that it causes
drift and
um
you know
air stones in deep water culture they're
just part of deep water culture they're
always in there um and i don't always
fight with with ph drift i think it's a
combination of
having nutrient solution that is well
dissolved
having a happy environment
um
and
not an environment that's too dynamic i
found i had more ph swing when i was in
a recirculating system because i would
have multiple plants i would have
multiple nooks and crannies different
things pulling it just seemed like a
more dynamic environment
i find
when growing in individual deep water
culture hydro buckets um
i can stabilize it quite quickly if i
really
want to
because i have that nice access on the
front of the hydro bucket so
i can
i can i just use ph down really is what
i do i found by using magnesium sulfate
or sulfite uh
when i when i before i when i start my
mix of my fluid and then i bring that
high ph down
to 5.8 before i add my beneficials
i find those two
additives seem to
stabilize
with a good
soluble
uh solution right a good soluble
fertilizer it has to be well so because
because that's part of the problem i'm
finding with certain uh
things is if the salute if the solution
is dynamic and it's not fully dissolved
and you mix it and then you put it in
with your plant
now it's even more dynamic because the
plant is up taking water the
concentration of your solution could be
it could be concentrating but if not
everything is dissolved
you have
an addition to your fluid that's
happening so when you balance it
once
maybe it's just the air is creating a
good environment to dissolve what hasn't
been dissolved yet and so that la that
that that
addition of dissolved particles into the
water
needs more balancing
if that makes sense yeah it does for
sure yeah yeah because i can really i
can really balance my water and
it's good it's once i once i make my
notes and i get my you know if it's a
straight if it's a plant that i'm used
to growing um
and i i i dial it in and i know
the ph is
in range i won't even check it for four
days let alone balance it each day right
it's just about using
your
uh
paying attention to stuff and and uh
i really think uh dissolving things well
gotcha now with ph a lot of people talk
about another measurement ppm or ec what
should the ppm or ec range be during the
different stages of growth right so
light um you know like so many people
when we grow growers like to just push
push push and we're encouraged by
so many packages by
nutrient manufacturers but this isn't
necessarily uh i think it's a
misunderstanding
um
you can
you want to be
in a vegetative state uh you know in
small plants and hydroponics you you're
you're only they don't need much you
know leafy greens uh
they're just after a bit of nitrogen
that is really what they're after they
don't have massive root systems um
so you're under 400 parts per million
500 parts per million that that does a
lot for seedlings and clones
under
once you're into a vegetative state
where you're growing a plant that you
really want it to get going um you can
go from you know uh
if it's if it's bigger what if it's
bigger than a football a basketball then
then i think you can push something at
that point uh
if it's going to go from a basketball to
you know two to three times its size
then that's a plant that could probably
start getting up towards to a thousand
parts per million
of vegetative nutrients if you're
switching your plant to a bloom nutrient
at that point
um you can go anywhere from a thousand
to fifteen hundred parts per million
the fifteen hundred parts per million
that's on the
the manufacturer's bottle that's for
people who enrich
so
they are correct in telling us
1 000 to 1500 but you have to understand
that your plants need more when they're
in a co2 environment they're going to
use more so that is what that reading is
for most people what i recommend when
you start using a nutrient line is you
start at half whatever they say
go half and um
it's it's easy to
give your plants a little bit more
uh
than than the other way but uh for the
most part
if you're around a thousand for biggest
plants whether you're in veg or bloom
you're gonna you're gonna be in a good
space okay and then talking about water
temperature the water temperature is too
low you can run into problems
temperature's too high you could run
into problems what should the
temperature be of the water right so the
temperature should be
68 to 72
fahrenheit
is what we're looking that's that's kind
of the ideal range it can be
lower it could be
anywhere
down to below 64 you're going to get
you're going to have slower growth once
you get below 64 degrees and once you
get above
76 degrees
you're really risking
uh competition uh in there and the
reason for that is dissolved oxygen
when you have cold water it holds oxygen
so that oxygen the water is full of
oxygen it's it's very
uh it's a very uh happy safe environment
for
for good microbes and and not for bad
things
and as the water gets hotter and hotter
there's just not that much oxygen in it
that's why air stones are really
important to get them in there and just
bubble bubble bubble in a and keep that
that water cool
but yeah
you can be anywhere from
64 i'll say to
78 on the very high side of things um
but i recommend again
not a sterile system if you're doing
this you're going to look you're going
to want to do enzymes
and and certain
additives to your
your grow because that
these enzymes inhibit the ability for
root rot and things to come into your
your zone so
that's important right you're not going
to get the same yield if you're growing
at 78 but you're not going to lose your
plants to root rot there's a big
difference there you're still going to
have a yield and for some of us
maybe your summer yield is is
you don't have as big of a yield in the
summer because it's hot and then you're
going to rely on your bigger yields in
the winter right so okay yeah that's
actually my main concern the reason why
i haven't done dwc is controlling water
temp i mean my natural you know house is
like 80 degrees so that's what my water
temp would potentially be
now when you get into the high temps you
talked about you know root rot is one of
the main things that people get when
they're running into the high temps
you mentioned enzymes as a way to kind
of help deal with that is there anything
else that you can use to deal with root
rot i mean i think hydrogen peroxide is
something i've heard in the past is that
true or
you know i i
i think it's about
not having a practice that doesn't allow
it in the first place
right and this is this is where
uh you know we get into the conversation
of why i just never went back to
recirculating systems
i was sure i was going to you know i
made a recirculating system then i made
a hydro bucket then i got the hydra
buckets in my garden and i said i got to
hook this these things up and i just
never did i just put another tent and
put more hydro buckets and then another
10 to put more hydro buckets because
the hydra bucket allows me to control
temperature and not use a chiller 24 7.
and and and and
why that is is is that you add
on the first day of the week
and then
you add in your
ideal temperature of water right so this
is different than a a recirculating
system if you were to add 68 degree
water in a recirculating system
it's going to go up
it's pumping water you have multiple you
have one pump for sure and it's pumping
through a heat exchanger essentially
it's going through tubes that are in
your hot environment
and then it's going into your
your
vessels your
your plant containers and then it's
draining out a drain line back to your
external reservoir
where it's picked up heat it's done its
job
so people will need a chiller because
that water cannot go down it cannot stay
at the same temperature it has to go up
so we'll start we go from 68 and we
start going up
with a hydro bucket and the single deep
water culture grow environment
you can sidestep that
so you can start with 68 degree water in
a single deep water culture hydro bucket
and then
in four days
from when you first added your ideal
solution
your parameters have been getting out of
out of check your your parts per million
him getting out of check your your your
ph and your temperature they all been
sliding away from optimum but every four
days you get to top it up with cold
water
so
again you know it every four days we get
to make it perfect
you don't get to do that with a
recirculating system you just have to
make it
good i mean you have to keep it ideal
i you know they kick on and off but
you're using more water and you're
picking up more heat whereas a hydro
bucket you're really not adding any heat
in a in a in an individual
container right and so this allows us to
i i still have a chiller but i only use
my chiller for an hour
pre-mix just to get my temperature of my
solution to where i want it and that's
only for three months a year
the rest of the year i use a heater
because my water's too cold
right so so if i was in a recirculating
system though i'd be using my chiller
all the time i would never i'd rarely
use a heater
i would i would always be using the
chiller so that's just the difference
it's it's trying to portray the
difference of
of getting your optimum
temperature
your optimum ph your optimum parts per
million and then put it in your deep
water culture environment
and it's good for four days
mix up some some nice cold water
get it in there it's good for another
four days right we don't need a chiller
uh we may even be able to manage this of
just cold water out of your tap depends
where you live right so
this always allows us to
keep that temperature in check
so
gotcha let's get deeper into chiller
because there was actually a lot of
questions in regards to chillers can you
talk to us about you know how many watts
is a typical chiller i know it can get
very expensive like you said if you're
running a rdwc and you're running that
chiller 24 7 well it can be pretty
expensive there and it might not be
worth it for you so how many watts is a
typical chiller how much does it cost
and how do you calculate the size of the
water chill you need for your system
right so
a water chiller you need a water chiller
if you're going to get a water chiller
you need a chiller and you need a pump
to circulate that chiller they don't
come with their own pump so you need a
secondary pump as well and that's i mean
that's hydroponics there's pumps here
and there especially if it's
recirculating
they're
the ones here in canada they're based on
horsepower uh but that equates what i'm
looking at to you know anywhere from two
to four hundred watts
you know i think is what you're gonna
you're gonna have for a water chiller so
you know that's another light
right you know if that's running on a
regular basis to keep uh more fluid
uh at a
smaller temperature that's that that
could be another light that could be
another plant um
so
uh water chillers
are
necessary well i don't know if they're
necessary water temperature control is
necessary whether it's a heater or a
water temperature but a lot of people
think just because you say deep water
culture that you must have uh a chiller
right and and and it's going to be an
additional cost and it's going to be all
these additional things and that's where
i say
you know rethink
individual deep water culture buckets
because we get to turn that that that
that chiller off
we get to we get to save money in in a
lot of ways when getting away from a
recirculating system
now with the chiller will nutrient salts
impact the life of a chiller that's one
of the viewer
i i
you know i i i think like anything
whether it's your pony pump or your
anything you want to flush everything
out
regardless right so
um
how you do that in a recirculating
system yeah i mean
um
i would say if you want your chiller to
last a long time
uh you should probably disconnect it
every once in a while uh and and clean
it
you know once or twice a week just to i
i don't know yeah i don't know
it's definitely not going to be
great to have an internal
system that never gets clean that has a
stalled accumulation you're gonna have
to do something okay and you mentioned
the words flush i want to talk about
flushing the plant at the end of the
cycle so highly controversial topic for
sure some people say you should flush
your plants which is basically you know
in a hydroponic system
is you're you're removing the nutrient
solution out of the system and just
having plain water in there for a period
of time whether it be five days some
people say seven days some people say 14
days what's your take on flushing do you
recommend people to to flush at the end
of their cycle yeah
in my experience i've had the best
results um in
a well-rounded
feeding program that ends
with pure water
so we can call that a flush
or
i think it's more important to put it
this way
if you were to just
pound nutrients into a plant
and then simply flush it for two weeks
you're not going to get the same result
as someone who
fed it properly for the first three
weeks
transition to something that was more
appropriate for the next three weeks
and then for the final two weeks
had another product
and then
for that last week
went to just water
that is that process
is what gives a nice smooth clean
product at the end
with no bitterness or bad tastes or or
anything like that
it's not so simple as just a straight up
flush at the end that's the magic trick
in my opinion there are some things that
i that that i can say about that time
though which could confuse people
or just just make it more uh just not
clear is
those last couple weeks if you're think
about a tomato
think about a a nectarine that gets to
ripen on the tree that gets to ripen on
the plant when you walk up to something
and you pick it off and it's been ripe
tree ripened and you pick it off and it
doesn't have to ripen on the way it
doesn't have to cure and ripe
you know it's it's really got to stay on
as long as possible
[Music]
there's something to be said with
certain strains and how you grow in
allowing your plant to mature when it's
not under pressure you know it it it
only can do what it can do at certain
stages so pounding it with nutrients and
then just giving it a flush at the end
isn't isn't isn't going to do it
[Music]
you draw it out properly through all the
the portions of it but then
if you don't flush versus you flush
for me it's more of a ripening process
right you you you you could have that
week or two um that that just creates um
that speak people sp speak to a smoother
flavor or this and that um i don't know
flavor something that i was going to
bring up next i mean there's some people
who swear by
growing in soil growing organically that
the flavor is going to be much better
than growing hydroponically you know and
then there's hydroponic growers that say
you're going to get the best flavor in
the world growing hydroponics
what's your take on that hydro flavor
growing hydroponically the flavor versus
growing in soil the flavor you get i
wish i could
experience both on a side-by-side basis
because i love science and i love
knowing
the truth the truth that i do know is if
you are hydro and you crush it
you're gonna blow doors off people are
gonna say wow that's amazing if you're
in living soil and you crush it people
are going to go wow that's amazing you
know that that's what's going to happen
in my personal experience
when you're in living soil
um
you know i i've had some living soil uh
uh
stuff that
has just been so flavorful and and such
a great experience
but and i think it translates when
you're straight up after
um
you know not oils and stuff but uh
you know organic product
that's a nice way to grow but but
there's
there's also the components when you're
talking about hydroponics you have full
control
right we're talking about a couple
things where you know you got a couple
topics there it happens leaving it to
nature or taking full control or you
know
hydroponics we have full control so we
can really make it do exactly what i
want it to we can give it everything it
needs this is what i like to say i like
to give it everything it needs to give
let it do what it wants to do at its
full potential and that's kind of a
similar
you know mantra of of organic soil
um what i do know for sure is we grow
for
what's on the organics
not the organics we specifically have
strains that are for
uh washing that and so we know that the
expression of what we do
and what we create as our final product
is
fantastic and i'll put that up against
anybody growing in anything
that being said if someone has done
their best to grow some amazing organic
product for consumption
um
you know
there may be something to make that
better yeah in flower but i can't speak
to it right i i i really think it's um
it's a big conversation and i say it's
about what works best for the individual
for growing if if if you grow and you
grow what grows well for you and and you
have a good successful product in the
end
that's a success and it doesn't matter
what what you used right and the top
growers in the different categories are
all going to have a wow product
every one of them right so
it really until the science comes out
until i could
have more information
um
you know i'm going to say
grow it all
well said
so we have a lot of new folks that tune
into my channel and they're either just
starting out in dwc or they're about to
start out in dwc what advice do you have
for someone who is brand new to growing
hydroponically
don't be intimidated with it and do it
um go out and get a single hydro bucket
you know this is the thing is people
people are intimidated by hydroponics
rightfully so they think that they need
a chiller they think they need a diy and
a drill or they think they need pumps
and pressure and they're going to flood
their house there's so many things that
turn people off hydroponics
and then say
or it's a price tag you know all those
things disappear if you just have 1500
bucks you could take roll into a fifteen
hundred dollars and and it's real simple
and you're gonna crush it so i tell
people get the we have a product that
allows you to just try hydroponics
without a big bill right you can get
into a hydro bucket net pot uh uh
hydroton you know airstone air pump
there's packages for under a hundred
dollars you take it home and you get to
just try deep water culture and why i
say it's not for advanced growers it's
for
new growers is because it takes the
grower out of the equation
how many times have you ever over
watered a plant or underwatered a plant
when you grow in deep water culture
that doesn't exist there's no watering
you literally fill it up you mix it
fill it up and it's good it has
everything it needs that's why deep
water culture grows so fast deep water
culture will grow in vegetative state
30 faster
so that's a significant difference when
you're talking about dollars and cents
on large scales when you're talking
about production is 30 faster is that an
extra crop
there's a lot of things that happen with
uh uh with that but
why i think deep waterculture works
really really well for new growers is
that you it's you get to mix it
you get to put it in
and then it just has what it needs
you're not gonna water and you're going
to have lifestyle as well that was a big
thing for me you're going to be able to
leave for a couple days and come back
and your plants just sitting there
growing and you can you can conveniently
check the parts per million the
temperature and the
the
uh
ph
and if it's good you're good for another
couple days you just leave and when it
comes back so it has everything it needs
you are just there to give it what it
needs and when you do that
it goes
crazy deep water culture grows like
nothing else
so you just have to manage yourself so
just don't be intimidated just get a get
get your gear and try one plant
i hear there's no going back
great stuff for sure yeah you the way
you said it there and what you've said
so far within this episode i mean you
you make me a little bit more confident
to try it out you know what i mean like
i mentioned that i did have concerns i
think most of them have kind of been
addressed at least the way you explain
it with the hydro bucket in particular
not running the rdwc with the reservoir
and how it is can be a little bit more
beneficial in some ways just doing dwc
with the hydro buckets so i might have
to give it a try just might have to do
that so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future oh thank you yeah
um so we have uh you can find us on
facebook on youtube on ig most of the
stuff in the garden i is
ig is is my main platform that's where i
share and then we get that from there on
to facebook and then we are
uh you know trying to give the youtube
some more love um
but uh yeah that's it we have a website
visionaryhydro.ca
uh we're gonna be updating our website
it's uh uh uh it could be polished it's
not great but uh we're available uh
for purchase on our website we're
available for purchase on amazon and
lots of retailers around
and
we are trying to make a presence
everywhere we can
toronto lift
expo coming up
we're going to have that if we can make
it down to vegas we will
we don't know if this is going to be the
year for that
but then next year definitely we're
going to be looking at doing more
[Music]
you know all the big trade shows if we
can
and uh any cups or anything like that
next year um you know we hope to attend
all of those in in big fashion
awesome good stuff there well i will
provide a link to mitchell's channel
down in the description section below if
you enjoyed this video click that thumbs
up button i know there's a lot of things
that we didn't get to there's some
questions i had to skip over did we miss
anything let us know down in the comment
section below and do you have any tips
or tricks what's your style what do you
do to kind of make the process a little
bit easier let us know down in the
comment section below if you haven't
already subscribe to the channel release
new episodes every single weekend
usually it's on saturdays sometimes it's
on sundays if you're listening in an
apple podcast please leave a rating and
review creeping up towards 200 ratings
and reviews so if we can get there by
the end of the year i would be stoked
thank you to everyone who has left over
rating and review so far mitchell thank
you so much for coming on to the channel
today coming on to this episode there's
a lot of people that are really going to
benefit from from this information so
thank you so much for your time and i
hope you enjoy the rest of your day yeah
thank you for having me it's been an
absolute pleasure i can sit around and
talk growing
all day and i just really appreciate the
opportunity to connect with you and
another grower so
awesome all right have a good one