coming up on garden talk let's say
you're doing bottled nutrients and you
would have your part a and your part b
and your part a is for veg and then your
part b is for flour well our part a is
fermented plant juice and our part b is
fermented fruit juice this is oriental
herbal nutrient it's used for plants
animals and humans too ohn helps get rid
of pathogens diseases ailments this
could help boost your immune system
fermented plant juice is a rich enzyme
solution made out of beneficial
biochemicals inside of the plant
and you let it soak and ferment for so
many days and then you strain out the
shells and then what you have left over
is water soluble calcium soil is filled
with life and as a regenerative farmer
all you're doing is maintaining that
life
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 57. in this
episode i interview green's goddess she
has been gardening for eight years and
grows a variety of plants such as
vegetables house plants herbs and
medicinal varieties in this episode she
talks about a handful of k f methods
which stands for korean natural farming
she also talks about composting bokashi
and reveals a high fungal tea recipe
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
call possible thanks to mars hydro for
sponsoring this episode they have two
different size heat mats 10 by 20.75
inches and 48 by 20.75 inches and you
can get them with or without a digital
thermostat so you can really dial in the
temperature they also have grill bags
all of the grow bags are made of high
quality thick fabric and have a handle
for easy maneuvering they have a ton of
other products too such as grow tents
grow lights ventilation systems and more
check out their website at mars
hydro.com and you could use the discount
code mr growit for discount on any of
their products
big shout out to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast ac infiniti is
well known to produce high quality
products and provide excellent customer
service they have the thickest grow tent
on the market today
in line fans with a controller that can
automatically turn on and off according
to specific set points they have
seedling mats trimmers drying racks and
several other products that you can use
in your garden i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and you can use discount code mr
grow it during checkout for a discount
on their products a big supporter of
this podcast is dutch pro they sponsor
this podcast and i use their nutrients i
have been using their base nutrients
formulated specifically for auro and
soft water i also have been using some
of their additives like calmag silica
and their root stimulator called take
root they have a few other additives on
top of those and ph regulators coupon
code mrgrowit10dp
will get you a discount on their
products and i'll leave a link to their
amazon store down in the description
section below
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
julie aka greens goddess how you doing
today
i'm doing amazing chris how are you
doing today
i'm doing good good thanks for asking
i'm excited to talk to you today
we had a live stream that we did uh not
too long ago
and i was on twitch
and it was very very successful lots of
people loved the information that you
gave
uh we had a lot of people in the chat
that were really thankful that you came
on board and
spit some knowledge so figured i'd have
you on here garden talk and let's get
deeper into things
nice let's do it so today we're going to
talk about a handful of kmf methods
and then we're also going to get into
composting which may help many of you
work towards a closed loop operation
right
but before we get into those things
let's do an introduction can you tell us
a little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
yeah um my name's julie uh also known as
green's goddess on instagram um
i at home i like uh gardening and
growing a lot of different plants
um
herbs vegetables fruits whatever name it
i like growing it i've been having a lot
of fun doing it and it's just very
therapeutic i've found
um one thing i love doing is is digging
into
natural farming because i want to be
able to grow plants organically
and i think just microbials and stuff
like that are extremely important in our
lives i'm glad that your uh listeners on
our last chat wanted to have me back
thank you very much for letting me be
here it's it's an honor thank you
um another thing i do is i run um luna
gardens
my website is lunagardens.co and i just
help educate people about
plant medicine and how it helps people
heal
so i'm really like involved in the plant
world and how
natural plants can be used to help
people heal from a variety of ailments
and conditions and just
everyday modern sickness even even just
boosting your immune system if we all
ate more organic plants and spent more
time out in nature and the sunshine and
fresh air it could it could help all of
us heal a lot
so i'm i'm totally into stuff like that
totally into the natural way of doing
things with you which is cool because
more sustainable way to do things it
arguably a cheaper way to do things
yep yes
exactly
so there's so many benefits to going
that route
now when we talk about k f in particular
don't assume my audience knows what that
is can you talk about like what is knf
and what inputs do you do
so um k f stands for korean natural
farming
um everything that i have ever learned
about k f i i learned it online by
watching chris trump's youtube videos
and uh you can even check out his
website christtrump.com he's got a lot
of really great information on there
about
what type of inputs you want to use at
what certain times and how you can make
your own inputs
uh that's one of the things i've done um
to kind of like help save money by
making your own inputs to put back into
your garden um there's some things i
have out here that i have made um not
this one ohn
this is oriental herbal nutrient it's
used for plants animals and humans too
it could um ohn helps to like get rid of
pathogens diseases ailments this could
help boost your immune system you could
take a little bit of this every day
i can't open the jar right now because
it it's made with sugar in the
fermentation process and i got some on
the lid and it's stuck
but um
it's really great stuff
humans can take just a little bit every
day to help boost their immune system
you put like about four mils of this
into a gallon of water and water your
plants with it just once in a while
maybe once every couple of weeks or
maybe once a month to help boost their
immune system also if like for your cats
for example or your plants or if you
have livestock you could give just a
little bit of this into the water and
it'll help boost their immune system
so how do you make that how do you go
about making that right there
if you've seen the video he uses big
jugs and i've done the same thing so
i've made
so much i would recommend anyone doing
this at home to try to go with smaller
jugs and smaller amounts but um you take
uh ingredients like angelic root
cinnamon
ginger
garlic
and um i i used turmeric too not
everybody uses turmeric in their ohn
recipe but i've used it in mine because
he had recommended it on his youtube
page when or his youtube video and he
made it at the time so i added it into
mine because i did exactly as he did and
uh turmeric is really great for your
heart and your blood anyways so why not
add it in with the rest of your ohn
this is something that's been used for
centuries
um just as a tonic to help people feel
better but it can also be given to like
plants and animals to help their boost
their immune system help them feel
better as well
so um
some of the ingredients are dry you you
rehydrate them by letting them soak in
beer and you can taste uh the different
beers and people's different ohns like i
have used ipa beer a friend um my friend
matt mile high gardener he had used um
stout
which actually tastes much better than
mine
and uh so the other ingredients once
you're done hydrating those ingredients
you move on to the next step which is to
put all the ingredients into a big jar
of alcohol
and you let that sit for it takes a long
time um
like
i forgot how long it took me but it was
over a month i remember i wrote all the
dates down but i went in there every
single day and stirred those jars every
day to mix the ingredients around
um and then you strain it through a
strainer then you put the ingredients
back in and then you fill the jar back
up a third of the way and then you add
more alcohol to the jar
and then you let that sit for another
um i think two weeks or something if you
want more details you gotta check out
his youtube page because it'll have all
the information
and then do you dilute it down before
giving your plants and how often do you
give to the plants
so um this is in this way it's straight
uh alcohol
uh and you would give it like just four
mils
four milliliters per gallon of water
and you don't need to give it to your
plants often maybe if you gave it to
them once a week once every other week
would be fine foliar spraying is great
too
um later on i'll talk about um the
maintenance solution because this is
something that you would mix three
different ingredients
so ohn would be your first ingredient
your second ingredient is fermented
plant juice i've made that fermented
plant juice is usually made out of uh
fresh uh roots not roots the fresh
shoots that's the word i'm thinking of
fermented plant juices um it's a rich
enzyme solution made out of um
beneficial biochemicals inside of the
plant
so when you take a a
fresh like say in your backyard you got
weeds and you got a lot of things
growing fast
you go out there early in the morning
and you harvest all of the tips
you put the tips into a big bucket and
you mix it with equal weights of
raw brown sugar
and you mix it together then you take it
in like a jar
you take it in like a jar about this
size and you smash it all down so that
it's all compressed together and then
you put like a breathable lid on top and
you leave it in a cool dark area for
about two weeks depending on the plant
material some plants break down a lot
faster than other plants but basically
through that osmotic pressure and
fermentation the sugar starts eating
away at the plant and it starts
releasing
all of this great chemical compound in a
liquid form and then you strain off and
you collect the liquid form
and you could use that liquid form same
thing as um
pohn about four mils per gallon
so there's two different things that
fermented plant the fermented plant
juice is made out of like fresh leaves
fresh tips greens so you're using that
to
as an input for your veg side of things
to help your plants grow fast in their
veg stage
there's another thing called fermented
fruit juice
i made this one nope
fermented fruit juice this is made out
of
fruits
like with the fruits you're
getting out all of the
nutrients and and chemical compounds in
those fruits that are letting your
plants know it's time to make more fruit
so same process you cut up your fruits
you mix it in with equal weights of raw
brown sugar you
put push it in a in a jar with a
breathable lid and you give it like a
couple of weeks for the fermentation
process to do its thing and then you
strain it out and you keep the liquid
the liquid uh for fermented
uh fermented fruit juice
that's about eight mils when you're in
flour
so um
fermented plant juice ohn and brown rice
vinegar
um you could make it if you want i just
buy this
off of amazon it's brown rice vinegar
this has so many great um
qualities just this alone how helpful it
is for your plants
um it's basically like
a cleanser
so
that
brown rice vinegar plus ohn plus
fermented plant juice is all added
together to make a maintenance solution
so when you you could order these
products by the way off of somebody that
you know like
who's making them there's a lot of
people making k f products and selling
them so if you don't want to make it
yourself but you want to give it a try
totally buy it off of them this is my um
k f maintenance solution it's those
three ingredients ohn fermented plant
juice and brown rice vinegar mixed
together so if i wanted to give my
plants a boost i'd give them just a
little bit of this 20 mils per gallon
uh soil drench or foliar spray is fine
just a little bit you don't need to
overdo it how often do you do the
maintenance solution
if i was
so you i don't think that you need to do
it if you're foliar spraying and also
doing a soil drench then
maybe one or the other
if you're doing it just once a week it's
fine
uh when you go on a flower you don't
want to foliar spray anymore you want to
put it in the soil once a week is fine
once every other week is fine too
also i've made water-soluble calcium
well actually sorry before we move on to
that i did have question about
the
fermented plant juice so just to kind of
quick recap
four milliliters per gallon for the
fermented plant juice
and that is going to mostly be veg human
during the vegetation stage and then the
fruit
fermented juice
fermented fruit juice would be used
during flower
that's eight milliliters per gallon
so you can use them individually or you
can make that
um
maintenance solution that you spoke
about right so you can do either or
right
yeah
um the maintenance solution that i've
made is only with the fermented plant
juice
so okay gotcha
not the fermented fruit juice that does
kind of get a bit confusing
that makes sense you could totally use
just fermented um fruit juice
with a water and just water that to your
plants
the ohn and uh is is kind of used
sparingly
same thing with the uh brown rice
vinegar just a little bit you don't need
to add it all the time but it's
definitely beneficial to have it in
there
so let's say you're doing bottled
nutrients and you would have your part a
and your part b and your part a is for
veg and then your part b is for flour
well our part a is fermented plant juice
and our part b is fermented fruit juice
there's also um
you could use all sorts of types of
different fruits to make the fermented
fruit juice i heard you should probably
stay away from citric fruits
and
pineapple
but
my friend that does fermented plant
extracts makes this fermented pumpkin
so if you didn't want to make it
yourself you could buy it off of
somebody else
and then same thing this one's like the
comfrey
this one you would use in veg this one i
would use in flour
so
you get things from building soil don't
you
oh yeah yep definitely uh
juice or
i have not now that's something i've
been i've been wanting to do so i think
maybe this year i'll definitely
experiment with fermented juices
absolutely
yeah what was that other thing that you
were going to show behind you i'll see
i'll cut you off before i cut you off
that's okay
water soluble calcium
this is made with um
your eggs you collect all of your
eggshells preferably organic and see if
you're doing your own regenerative
farming and you had chickens you would
just use your own chicken eggshells the
best
um but what you do is you collect
eggshells and you crush them up and then
you cook them preferably outdoors on a
pan until they get like nice and brown
and then you put them into like one of
these containers of brown rice vinegar
and you let it soak and ferment for so
many days and then you strain out the
shells and then what you have left over
is water soluble calcium
available to be taken up to the plants
love it they'll take it immediately
you mentioned the egg shell should be
laid out
and that you should potentially cook it
outside
so you wouldn't recommend that they do
it inside in like the oven for example
well like on your stove top you could if
you wanted to um for a lot of people it
creates a nasty odor so they just prefer
to do it outside is all uh
i did mine outside so
i just grabbed a um
one of those cast iron pans
and went outside and
mixed it all around you've got to keep
mixing it so it's nice and brown and
so if you don't clean out your egg
shells they do kind of have this white
fluffy stuff that needs to be cooked off
you don't want that stuff
in your solution
just the eggshell itself not any part of
the embryo or yolk or anything i was
going to say is there a specific ratio
of eggshells to vinegar
um
yes 1 10 egg shells
and the other nine tenths to brown rice
vinegar
okay
and um
that one you would apply a little bit
when you first transition your plants
about four mils per gallon later on in
flower when they start
producing
um then you would put um
eight mils per gallon gotcha yeah good
information there i know uh there's
quite a few people who want to ditch the
bottle of calmag and this is the way to
do it right because you're getting
calcium through the eggshells through
this process
so i'm glad you shared that today
there's there's other easier ways to add
in um magnesium like um epsom salt
so
but the the funny thing is everyone's
always saying more calmag when something
goes wrong and it could possibly be a
lockout of another nutrient not that
you're missing that nutrient just that
you added too much of one thing and you
gotta lock out of something else
happen to me
absolutely yeah i mean the running joke
is just add more calmag and it's like
well what type of cal mag is it military
calmag
is there a medical grade calmag
what was that one uh skit that people
would say like i have a disease and the
only cure is more calmag
there's so many memes out there so funny
i know
so the other stuff um
water-soluble calcium
and
i already showed you my bloom for a
minute
sea salt
sea salt is one of the ingredients one
of the k f minerals um and just a little
bit
uh
throughout the
whole growth cycle uh i wrote down here
one to two grams of sea salt per liter
of water once you measure it out in your
hand then you know how much goes in and
i put it in my water and i let it
swirl around and i put that in
um
this is fish amino acid
i got this off of a friend from
neverwinter farms
this is his faa he's got a buddy that uh
is a fisherman so he goes to his friend
all the time to get fish off of him
he loves fish i'm not a big fan of fish
myself so i would i don't want to go out
there and
go fishing
so if you love fishing but uh let's say
you come home and you're eating up some
parts and you've got a whole bunch of
heads and tails left over or whatever
you're not eating
you take all your fish same thing that
you do with the rest of the inputs equal
weights of brown sugar put it in a
bucket shove it down
um let it ferment for a long time fish
amino acid takes a long long long time
to ferment
um but this could be used um all
throughout the growth of your plants a
little bit more uh
during the beginning of your plants
because they need a little bit more of
that nitrogen
not so much towards the end this has a
lot of
nitrogen rich
nutrients and enzymes and stuff like
that in it
and like for example if i couldn't make
it myself you could always buy it off of
somebody else
this is conscience natural inputs before
i started making my own k f inputs i was
getting his just to test the waters and
to see if i liked it or not
and then after that some things are easy
to get the salt's easy to get the brown
rice vinegar is easy to get you could
get this
it's easy to buy it and just give it a
try
if you wanted to grow organically
so these are the k f inputs that i have
been messing around with i i really love
it i don't know if it's because i just
love making things so much
but i just have a good time making all
these inputs
fermented plant juice is my favorite it
took me so many tries before i got it
right doing fermented
plant juice with leaves
but that depends on which leaves you're
buying some of them break down really
easily and some of them don't and it's a
learning process you learn along the way
sometimes just got to jump in and get
your hands wet
i also wanted to get into that a little
bit leaf mold right i know you spoke
about it a little bit on the live stream
i think it's value added to speak about
it here as well can you talk to us about
leaf mold and how you get that
this mold is what happens when um you're
like out like under a tree or in the
forest or something like that and all
the branches and all the leaves and
everything that may have grown and then
died and then grown and then died they
all start to collect and they are what
is making up your soil
it's all mulch
so that's another thing why mulch is one
of my favorite things to have around
it's great when it can help keep your
soil moist
uh but even better is the breaking down
of the mulch just because the leaf is
dead doesn't mean that it lost the
nutrients that were inside of it it's
still stored in there
as it breaks down and mulch as it
becomes a leaf mold is when things like
um
fungi and bacteria and other
microorganisms start coming in and
decomposing and breaking it all down for
you now when they come in to decompose
and break down those are the guys that
are feeding your plants roots the
nutrients that came out of that mulch
so
one reason why we always say to chop and
drop it if you're if you're cutting it
off just leave it on the ground or on
your bed whatever setup you got
and just kind of let nature do the rest
as long as you've got a a healthy dose
of microbials
fungi
bacteria
nematodes protozoa worms just things
breaking down that matter for you they
do all the work so that you don't have
to
so leaf mold there's a few things you
could do to go out to the forest to
collect it and bring it back
you could um to don
jadon's way of
of grabbing uh microorganisms and
bringing them back into your garden is
to go out
and dig preferably under like something
where you've seen a tree that has fallen
down and a lot of dead material has
already decomposed and new life has
already grown on top of it if you dig
underneath that that's where you could
find all the fungi and all the mycelium
and that's where you know that you got a
good
network of leaf mold soil down there
like it's hardly recognizable anymore it
sort of looks like soil but technically
it's not soil but what is soil made up
of you know it's made up of
mulch that's been decomposed time after
time after time after time
and so you grab a handful of that and
you could bring it back home and you can
make um jadon microbial solution
and
sort of the same thing as a compost tea
where that you're giving it some carbs
to feed it like a baked potato a little
bit of that sea salt in the bottom of
the bucket
and
you let it sit in the middle of the
bucket for a few days depending on the
temperature
and there'll be a ring around the edge
when the microbes are ready it's like a
i think that that might be an outcome of
yeast or something some type of
action is happening in there that causes
that ring of bubbles to happen and once
you have that ring it's a perfect
opportunity you got to use it
immediately
you take that big bucket of five gallons
you mix it in with maybe another 20 30
gallons of water and you apply that to
all of your plants to introduce all
those microbials into your plants
into the soil
another way to do it like the korean
natural farming way they call it uh imo
which stands for indigenous
microorganisms
their way of doing it is by having some
slightly cooked rice in a box and then
you go out to the forest and then you
dig to till you find that area where you
see a lot of mycelium the leaf molds
you hardly recognize the material that's
in there anymore but you can tell that
there is a lot of great fungal life down
there
you put your collection box on top of
that and then you kind of not bury it
but cover it up so it's safe from
like bugs and critters or maybe other
people walking by wondering what a box
is doing there
uh leave that for a few days and that
also depends on the temperature you're
supposed to be able to take collections
any time of year including the winter
time
but um me personally i'm having a really
hard time doing a winter collection
right now because all the places i have
tried haven't turned out to be so
successful
but um you can't give up just because it
doesn't work out the first time you know
you got to keep trying
but um
when you have a good successful
collection a lot of fungi is growing on
top of your rice like a nice white puffy
cloud some colors are okay a little bit
a little bit of mix is okay too much of
any one color is not okay
um then
you take that collection you bring it
back home with your moldy rice
and
you mix it equal weights with brown
like brown sugar raw brown sugar
and you let that sit in a jar to ferment
that becomes shelf stable so if you
wanted to do several collections you
have all your little jars your shelf
stable jars once they've been mixed with
the uh brown sugar
then um
there's there's several processes like
imo1 and imo2 and imo3 so these are all
the different steps
um the next step when you have your
collection is to mix it in water with
some other things
i haven't gotten this far yet you mix it
in water with some other
stuff like a little bit of labs and i
believe a little bit of the ohn
and
i think sugar i'm not sure if you're
adding more sugar to that concoction or
not you're brewing it around kind of
like a tea and then you're
using it to water like malted barley and
wood chips
and stuff like that
um then that creates like this
pile that could get really hot so you've
got to keep turning it every once in a
while to make sure it doesn't get too
hot you want to increase its temperature
but not get above a certain temperature
and
eventually what happens after you know
you've turned it enough times and it
cooked and it's cooling down and now
it's completely finished you could use
that finished product
to sprinkle around your garden
or you could use it as a tea and it's a
liquid imo
but that is a really amazing way to
introduce microorganisms into your soil
and you've got to let your
microorganisms do all the work for you
you don't have to
continuously add all these ingredients
when your soil is hooked up and it's got
plenty of microorganisms
fungi bacteria
nematodes worms anthropods
microanthropods
um protozoa all sorts of cool stuff soil
is is filled with life
and
as a regenerative farmer all you're
doing is maintaining that life
it blows my mind how many practices
there are out there that you can do
in order to
grow these plants right um so many
different ways to do it i'm sure a lot
of these viewers that are or listeners
that are tuning into this
their minds are blown because they're so
used to just growing with bottles or
just growing organically using just a
blend that they top dress in or are
initially amended in the medium then top
dress throughout the grow
but using these other methods
um
you can get away with not doing any of
those top dressings
of blends you know not using them at all
or using bottle nutrients at all you
know k f is is
another way to go about it you know and
you can have great success with k f so
absolutely
if you want to learn more about k f
you've got to talk to um chris trump
i already reached out to him and told
him about the show today and i said can
i um have mr growit reach out to you so
that you could come on and talk to his
learners he said yes absolutely it's
okay thank you oh thanks for the hookup
there yeah i've heard his name so much
and uh
he is somebody who i i would love to
have on the podcast because his
knowledge
is just extensive uh when it comes to
that and so um yeah thanks for thanks
for hooking it up there
absolutely he knows he knows way more
about knife than i do
um and i'm i'm just very fortunate i had
the pleasure of having him over and
showed in my garden and he said to me um
you're doing too much and you need to
back off so i was like
it didn't it didn't comprehend to me
until after some time that i have
learned that
the thing about bottle nutrients is you
feel like you have to constantly be
adding something but when you're growing
organically you don't have to constantly
be adding stuff it's all right there for
you you're just maintaining
you know so that's what that's what
makes it real easy for me
well said
let's uh let's flip it up let's talk
about composting so i know that's a
topic that you wanted to get into today
i do a little bit of composting myself i
do very composting so i have just a
small i think it's like 20 something
gallon bin uh in my garage
it's winter time right now so
everything's cold and everything's
moving pretty slow but hey i've got
something going i'm sure once the
springtime and summertime uh comes along
and the temperature heats up a little
bit there's going to be a lot more
activity
in my bin
but this is something that
it's often said that every home grower
should be doing is composting
and there's so many different ways to
compost right
so vermicomposting what i just explained
is just one way of doing it you could
have a regular compost pile even
outdoors
that's another way to go about it you
want to talk to us about composting like
what you do what you know about it so on
and so forth so um i'm doing some
composting myself i haven't i haven't
reached the point where i've had
my own finished compost product yet if
you can do a composting where you're at
absolutely go for it not everybody has
that opportunity because like let's say
you live in an apartment or something
like that if you needed to buy compost
online you absolutely could same thing
with like vermicompost and worm castings
i just highly recommend that if you are
going to be purchasing it from somebody
else
right now during the winter time is the
perfect time to go ahead and place that
order because of the temperatures are so
cold this time of year if you try doing
it during the summer time you don't know
how long that bag has been sitting out
in the sun for so all those great
microorganisms that maybe were once
thriving in there the majority of them
are dead by the time it even gets to
your place
so just something to consider when
composting if you're buying it off of
somebody else purchase it during the
winter time bring it back to your area
store it in a nice dark cool place i
like having my compost in um in a bin
with the lid on it one thing that i've
noticed just leaving my bag out in my
garden is it definitely attracts a lot
of gnats and flies
so for me i roll it up tightly put a
clip on it and then i put it in a bin
that's locked
if there is a time it's usually during
the summertime that these that more
little fungus flies or nats start coming
in and i notice them on my
compost i'll put up one of those yellow
sticky traps and just lay it directly on
my compost bag and then put the lid on
it and seal it for like two weeks and
don't even touch it every single one of
those flies comes out hits that sticky
trap and doesn't go anywhere after that
so that totally works to try to keep
that population down if you notice that
same thing like with your vermicompost
bin sometimes you open it and if one it
only takes one little fly to get in
there and mess things up for you i hate
it when it happens i have my um
vermicompost bin indoors i just started
that
um
it's just a plastic tote some holes
poked all around the top and all around
the bottom
i filled it up with uh well i had an old
10 gallon pot that i was using so i just
used that i put in a whole bunch of
plant material to give it time to die
out i added in a handful of bokashi to
give it the plant material to break down
and then some kitchen food scraps
what else do worms also like um oatmeal
cornmeal stuff like that added in like a
little treat um half of an avocado
uh preferably a slightly you know rotten
uh
when it's mushier they get in there
quicker i've noticed if i put in a fresh
avocado they're not going anywhere near
it because uh maybe it's too hard for
them to break it down
but um if you want to speed up your worm
population that's the easy way to do it
one thing i uh vermicompost is really
amazing but it is high in bacteria
that's just something to consider
depending on which types of plants
you're growing because um
annuals things like that usually like
really high bacteria environment and
soil to grow in and typically trees
shrubs or your perennials
usually like more of a fungi dominant
soil to grow in so also it has a ratio
of bacteria to fungi
your annuals like more bacteria and your
perennials like more fungi
but vermicompost is really awesome it's
got a lot of bacteria and the worm
castings are coated with polysaccharides
and carbohydrates and simple proteins so
vermicompost is really rich in nutrients
uh it can help retain moisture and it
helps
the soil like soil structure
and conditioning of soil it too
might be able to help get rid of some
pathogens
anytime anyone is mixing up new soil
that they want to start a new garden in
you should add vermicompost which is
worm castings and regular compost
like cow manure mix it in with um i
always like native soil because of the
sand silt and clay that's involved you
need that for cation exchange
and so i like mixing the compost in with
that and then putting a topsoil on top
and then waiting about two weeks and
then putting your plants into that
topsoil area when they're ready they'll
go after that compost and they'll just
be sitting there waiting for them
um
vermicompost is a really
easy way
to take care of um
getting rid of kitchen scraps or stuff
like that it's nice to use it for tea if
you want to give it to your plants
regular composting can take a bit longer
there's hot composting and then there's
cold composting
hot composting um it's it's ready pretty
quickly
it gets really hot and it really cooks
and you gotta you gotta turn it and mix
it so that way what was in the center is
now on the outside and what was on the
outside is now in the center to even it
out
um
anything about
composting or the soil food web i would
highly recommend
checking out dr elaine ingham's videos
she goes into so much detail that is her
jam she loves talking about the soil
food web and composting and even um
lowensville the guy that wrote this book
he uh took her course and got into um
composting in the soil food web with her
and highly recommends checking her out
as well
um
i like doing
cold composting it's what i'm doing
myself or i call it the lazy compost
that's where you're just kind of putting
like a layer of browns in and a layer of
greens and when you got
kitchen scraps you put it on there if
you've got um
specific type of manures
uh this year i have used uh aged horse
manure
along with and i layered it like a
lasagna so browns include anything
that's dead like dead leaves dead weeds
um cardboard paper
some things
can be decomposed really quickly
your trash that's mainly um
paper material
uh then you got your greens which
basically means anything alive like
plants that were alive um food food that
you had ate in your kitchen scraps poop
i guess that's considered a green
greens offer more nitrogen
and browns offer more carbon
and so this is why i like to do a nice
layer of both when i'm doing my cold
composting because
and i sprinkle a handful of bokashi on
on it to get it you know rocking and
rolling a little bit faster but uh i
just sit there and and leave it be
outside and i don't have to mess that i
don't have to turn it too much
i don't have to do anything but um wait
for time and it'll just
like break itself down to the point that
you now have this really rich brown
material that's kind of like most of
it is unrecognizable you wouldn't have
been able to tell really what went into
it
you could use that compost same way you
could you could use vermicompost you
could sprinkle it uh around your garden
beds like put it on top
as long as it's a few inches away from
the stem of any of your plants
or you can make a compost tea that's one
of my favorite ways to do it because
if you only have so much compost you
really want it to spread and last a long
time so using just a handfuls and making
a tea out of it and you can apply it
you could apply it often but i
personally only do tea once a week
and um even like with indoors on the
beds that i have i'm slowly starting to
back off of that because i've been doing
compost teas for so long in these beds
they're like good they don't need any
more you don't need to keep on
reapplying it but this is this is a bed
there's so much to learn about growing
in a bed versus growing outdoors in the
ground where it's a lot easier in a bed
you have this controlled environment
once you put things in there it doesn't
leave
and
whereas outdoors it could kind of
you know go somewhere else and you know
go to the next soil or somewhere else or
deeper into the ground
so you've got to be very careful not to
add not to overdo it with the compost
um a really light tea once a week is
fine if you are reusing your soil
watch out after doing it for
so many
runs or so many years
um if you're doing it in a bed outdoors
probably not that big of a deal
but some people have applied top
amendments and some people have watered
with compost and after so many years
their soil is just so enriched with
microbial life that they don't need to
do anything other than to keep it wet so
that's where that magic happens
where you've already done so much to
your soil now it's totally hooked up and
you don't need to do anything else to it
other than just keep it moist
compost is really awesome compost and
vermicompost super simple easy ways to
put nutrients and microbials back into
your soil and let the microbials do all
the work for you you don't need to do it
when i started my vermicompost bin it's
very similar to what what you explained
right so you got the bin poke holes in
the bottom i actually have a screen on
the inside so things don't escape out
those holes in the bottom holes around
the top as well
and then to start it i did a
pretty standard a lot of people do this
is the brick of cocoa
mixed with some shredded paper or some
people use shredded cardboard as well
so mixing that all together
adding in
worms so buying worms from uncle jim's
worm farm
i bought the red wigglers and i bought
the european nightcrawlers so
diversity
is what i was aiming for there um and
then adding in your your inputs the
greens and and brown so normally for
greens what i'll add is
i'll add in
just any kind of leftover salad stuff
that isn't eaten um anything real green
vegetables uh goes in the bin
um i also add in eggshells
and i add in a lot of coffee grounds as
well so those are kind of the main
things that come to mind that i
typically add in the bin and typically i
do it on a weekly basis
so i know a lot of people wondering
frequency how often should you be adding
stuff in there you can actually get to a
point where you put too much in there
right so like too much food for the
worms it can go anaerobic it can have a
lot of you know gnats flying around or
pests flying around and so it can really
turn into a bad environment if you
aren't doing anything right doing things
right which is something that that i
quickly learned i had a nap problem for
a while but um i ended up balancing
things out i feel like and getting more
aeration down there and the moisture
level correct and all that stuff
and now i feel like things are going
pretty good there so but normally i'll
add stuff in on a weekly basis
and i'll kind of rotate around on the
different sections of the bin right so
like you know maybe the top right corner
i'll do one week then the next week i'll
go to the bottom or you know right
corner and then i'll kind of rotate
around by the time i get back down to
that corner that i started in it's
usually broken down at that point um and
then i'm able to add in more in that
area but i had it for about four months
so far
um
and so i don't feel like i'm able to
take things from that bin yet and use it
for anything i think it takes uh longer
than that
um i know some people say they don't
even start pulling stuff out of there
until like a year into it so i'm not
sure what your take on that is if it's
like six months or a year or when you
start using
so much activity like you're saying this
time of year it's a lot colder so they
might not be working so fast because
they're not moving a whole lot versus
during the summer time when they're
warmer they are working a lot faster so
they are going through and and
composting everything for you a lot
quicker
um
the other trick i think we were talking
about this last time we did our show was
um instead of just you could just put
your food scraps in there but instead of
doing that you could also put them in a
blender so that they're already broken
down and extremely available to all the
worms
microbial life because it's not just
worms that make up that worm then it's
it's the fungi and the bacterium and
other things breaking it down and then
the worms come and eat that
like i said with the avocado they the
worms did not want to touch a nice fresh
um hard avocado they wanted it to be
partially starting to like turn brown
a little bit rotten
um they don't like citrus stuff i've
heard they don't like the orange peels
or lemon peels or anything like that
they won't eat it or go near it
um
i always like throwing in apples and
stuff like that um i like cornmeal it
just it's funny i've watched so many
videos on uh vermicomposting and there's
this sweet english lady that loved her
worm bin and would go on about all these
treats she was giving her worms she goes
i love to get new treats like the
cornmeal
and i think about that every time i go
to open up my worm bin when it's time to
give them a little food i'm like give me
a little corn meal
but it's fun like it's fun to make it um
it does take a while until you can
actually reap the rewards of the verma
compost bin
but um
once you do have it going and you get it
and you understand it and then you can
kind of keep like maybe two bins like
maybe this bin is ready to be harvested
a little bit out of while this bin is
working
you know and that's just a super super
easy way to put more
micronutrients and microbial life back
into your soil that's readily available
to your plants
absolutely it's a step towards closed
loop operation so for sure and then the
same thing with the outdoor composting
in the cold compost pile worms will make
their way up there so that outdoor
compost pile also has worm doodoos in it
also so you are totally good to use that
you don't if you're outdoors you don't
need both the outdoor pile and a warm
bin i use my worm bed for the indoor
stuff
bokashi is like also fermented organic
matter it's extremely extremely easy
it's it's it's a lot like the whole imo
process
except for with bokashi
um they use it they buy that bottle of
em1
from terragenix
and they take that
they put it in a big old five gallon
bucket of water with a little bit of
molasses and stir it up real nicely then
they use that water to soak
malted bran
or malted barley sorry they use that
water to soak malted barley
and then um you let that sit and firm it
in a plastic baggie for like two weeks
and then after that you take it out and
then you let it dry out
it takes a few days and you turn it so
often but once it's completely dry you
now have like
bokashi that could be put in a bag or a
shelf stable you could buy bokashi this
is from kashi blend
and uh let me show you what it looks
like on the inside bokashi is another
really amazing great tool that you could
use the same way as like other
composting you could
put it on top of your
soil you could put it right next to your
plants it'll help
it'll help increase the microbial
population it'll help with fungi it'll
help with the bacteria
um it puts a lot of nutrients
and enzymes and whatnot back into
your soil see this is what bokashi looks
like
okay yeah i use grow kashi which is a
brand of it i believe um
yeah
by uh this one's by growing organic
so this one has the rice bran
uh
[Music]
a lot of other wheat bran and insect
frass molasses and then the em but they
put other stuff in here like um biochar
and uh high nitrogen amino acids so with
the with the compost and the bokashi
once you have enough you don't need to
keep reapplying it and so it's just
something to look you you don't need to
do too much just a little bit is good
enough
and i love personally love using this
book flashy if you've seen a lot of
people showing off their soils and you
see the little uh fungi little mycelium
growing and they say man ever since i
put that bokashi down that's exactly
what they're talking about
you can make a compost tea
this is um this is a recipe that i
wanted to give your viewers
with the compost tea
you basically get um
and you can buy compost or worm castings
from your local grow store or online um
just be careful about it not being out
in the sun and or direct sunlight or
getting too hot
but this recipe is really awesome you
get um one cup of oli mountain compost
a half a cup of worm castings
you get a handful of bokashi
you mix all that together along with
two tablespoons of oatmeal flour
and
one tablespoon of rock phosphate
oh yeah two tablespoons of barley but i
use gnarly barley from clackamas coop
and you mix all that together you get a
little bit wet i put this up on my
instagram page today just to show
everybody the recipe and how to make it
i make it all the time you mix it
together you get a little bit moist then
you put it in a container with a cover
on but not all the way on just slightly
on top
and
you wait for about three days it's got
to be in a warm but dark location so
that the fungi on it can grow
so i made this three days ago so i could
show you guys
usually if you're storing this i i leave
the lid like that
so that way a little bit of air could
get in the lid's not completely sealed
and this is what happens three days
later
oh okay you see this nice museum when
you go out to the forest and you're
trying to get a collection
of um indigenous microorganisms this is
what you're looking for
you could make it yourself it's not the
same i personally prefer just
all sorts of a variety a diverse variety
of different things
but this see how like nice and soft this
is it kind of smells like apple cider
vinegar
i call it uh santa's beard
also in that um teaming with microbes
book he shows you uh how you can make
this this recipe i got off my friend
random nicole 420
so it's kind of like a cake
and what i would do um when it's time
see that oh okay breaking it right open
there yeah wow
when it's time i put this in a in a tea
bag and i make a tea out of this
this will create a
fungi rich compost and this is good for
plants that love fungi
you could feed this tea to any of your
plants because fungi life lasts for so
long as long as you maintain
maintain it that's so funny
that's so cool
i'm definitely gonna have to take that
recipe and try it out i will send it to
you but i'm telling you it's the coolest
thing ever if you could if you make this
and i've tried a few different ways to
get it right you know
just cold and dark
i mean i wouldn't eat this but it does
smell really good it reminds me of like
fruit or apple cider vinegar as long as
it smells good it's good to work with if
if it starts smelling really nasty or
funky then it's no good
and nice thing about bokashi one of the
things that it does is it helps to get
rid of all that smell
funky smells of anything and it helps
them to break down faster
this has created a lot of
fungi life a lot of bacteria
there's a lot of great things in here
that i could use
and put in my um
my tea and then this tea i give to my
plants about once a week until i notice
that my plants have had too much by
checking out their leaves then i start
backing off that's all so i wanted to
share that recipe with you guys i hope
you guys can make it and give it a try
and if you find any way to make this
any more white then what i can do then
please share your recipe with me i'd
love to see it
awesome i'll definitely have to try that
out that's uh that's really cool i love
how there's so many different ways to to
go about you know feeding these plants
or
you know providing care for these plants
it's uh
you know we talked about so many things
that are like
your non-traditional way of growing yeah
and it just it opens up your mind and it
uh it makes things fun it really does
so it does seem traditional but that's
the funny thing isn't it
it is very traditional why did we switch
from our traditional simple ways of
farming to go to this new thing that
said we had to go out and buy nutrients
from bottles i could go into details but
i'm not gonna it's just it's
regenerative farming is what i'm getting
into right now i'm not like i'm not
totally deep you know into it
i am who am i kidding
but i'm super thankful to have you on
here today wrapping things up how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future um you can
find me on instagram greensgodus
um in the future let's see right now i'm
getting into some bubble hash
because i'm still processing things from
the freezer from outdoor season
and um soon as the weather starts
warming up i'm going to be working on uh
my yard because
i got all these seeds from neverwinter
farms and now i gotta grow all this food
so
that's one thing that i'm gonna be
working on a lot more of these imo
collections
and uh just
just watering my yard my backyard with
that to hook up the soil to get it ready
for me to start planting food in that's
what i'd really like to look forward to
this coming up season is is making a lot
more plants making a lot more healthy
food you know plants are medicine you
know i want to help people heal and i i
don't i don't think people should pay a
arm and a leg for like some apples you
know apples should taste good
so
i'll definitely have a link to your
instagram down in the youtube
description section below um so people
can tune in to your channel to your
content
and uh yeah if you enjoyed this video
click that thumbs up button on youtube
follow or subscribe on one of the either
youtube or one of the podcast platforms
because every single week releasing
these garden talk podcast episodes
julie thank you so much for coming on to
the podcast today this has been uh this
has been awesome this is really cool you
opened up my mind and i think a lot of
my audience is really going to open up
their mind as well so thank you for
sharing thank you thank you very much
thank you everybody for watching
[Music]
you