welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr growt and you're tuned
to the Garden Talk podcast this episode
number 169 in this episode I interview
Preston Smith he has been gardening for
15 years and has a wealth of knowledge
when it comes to Natural farming which
is the focus of today's discussion
Preston shares insights to his current
Farm practices and dives into topics
such as increasing soil organic matter
composting leaf mold jadam microbial
solution and much more if you want to
see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said I
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make that goal
possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
cloudray Gen 2 oscill clip fan their
nextg clip fan has been re-engineered to
provide a long lasting motor and
customizable air flow for all stages of
your plant's growth cycle it features 10
speeds and 10 Dynamic win modes to
simulate outdoor air flow in links with
U controllers for Wi-Fi app control
click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about their CL cloudray clip fans and
the discount code Mr Gro 15 works on
both Amazon and the website AC
infiniti.com stash blend several
additives in one blend so you no longer
have to buy individual bottles check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash spider farmer
check out their dwc Hydroponics grow
system each bucket has a 7g capacity
made from corrosion resistant material
the Triangular cover design makes adding
nutrients and measuring pH levels easy
it has a water level indicator so you
can see when you need to refill it
includes an 8 W air pump has a top drip
design and comes with air stones to
oxygenate the water more information is
linked in the description section below
and discount code Mr Grow 5 works on
both Amazon and their website spider-
far.com and we are back and I'm join
with Preston Smith how you doing today
doing well thanks good to be here Chris
happy to have you on you're requested by
I don't know who it is sometimes I get
requests in the comment section like you
got to have Preston Smith on he is so
knowledgeable when it comes to knf jadam
just natural farming in particular and
applying it not just on a small scale
but a medium or a larger scale and I'm
eager to kind of dig into learn more
about you what you've been doing on your
farm recently and really some of the
techniques that you go through in order
to grow your plants but first can we do
an introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah sure well thanks for
having me super stoked to be here and
share with all your listeners uh these
are topics I'm super passionate about um
my start in
agriculture really regenerative more as
a lifestyle really than just an
occupation or anything else um I would
say that started
um back in about 2008 2009 I had kind of
a a past life as a draftsman I worked a
desk job um worked for an architectural
firm so was really into kind of systems
thinking and coming up with blueprints
well for those that remember that year
um there was there was a collapse of the
economy the construction industry was
really bad I found myself without a
career and at the time it was kind of um
you know it was a a tragedy but you know
turned out to be a course correction in
my life for me a window of opportunity
to basically Venture into a completely
new field and occupation literally a
field um and you know long story
short you know there back then there was
this feeling of like wow like the
economy collapsed um what do I do now um
and so it just felt really like this is
you know these systems in society are
not working they're collapsing and so
how do we live like more regeneratively
more
sustainably uh more in tune with nature
and that really put me on the path and
so I had the opportunity to move out to
Humble County California in
2011 uh my sister lived out there her
and her husband they had a family out
there and um specifically my
brother-in-law offered me an opportunity
to come and work with medicinal plants
uh get a job on a farm out there and so
I took that opportunity and that really
started a whole kind of um chapter of
Awakening in my life you might say um
that led me into you know wild crafting
uh spending a lot of time in the forest
uh I took some herbalism courses and
learned a lot um
you know found myself living in the Lost
Coast for a season uh in Humble County
and lived in an army tent so lived off
grid so you're kind of forced to like
learn how to be
sustainable and you know live off the
land and that kind of settings so wild
crafting foraging for mushrooms plants
using medicinal
trees um so that was all kind of um
within the permaculture realm so it kind
of led me down that rabbit hole which
led me into you know Korean natural
farming uh and just the whole
regenerative farming in general is is a
large broad umbrella I mean there's so
many different methodologies even under
regenerative farming and so I've never
felt married to any one of those uh so
for me it's always been looking for like
the principles behind them all and
Universal languages
because I'm sure you've noticed and a
lot lot of your listeners have noticed
like within Korean natural farming
there's all these acronyms within
biodynamics you have all these acronyms
within Copic Agro forestry they use a
lot of terminology and permaculture has
its own
terminology you know so and then you get
into the soil food web and microbiology
and so it could be all really complex
but if we're distilling it down into
principles it it kind of makes it a lot
easier to approach and we can can we can
see where the there's overlaps instead
of differences instead of language that
is creating Division and in technical
kind of groupy you know areas where
we're siloing information it becomes way
more inclusive that
way so that's kind of in a
nutshell um you know went down that
rabbit hole that took me up into
Oregon um you know Consulting for farms
in you know medic
um settings in hemp Fields uh you know
did 10 acres of hemp with Korean naturo
farming in jadam using some permaculture
techniques you know along the way I've
worked in indoors green houses
Outdoors um from you know a five lighter
in my garage to like I said 10 ACR in um
in Oregon um so kind of a vast array of
different uh settings that I got to
practice and and learn from all of these
different uh you know settings that's so
cool it sounds like you've gotten a lot
of experience over the past 15 years
doing all sorts of things and yeah I can
totally relate to what you mean by
confusing with all the different
acronyms I think that a lot of my
audience kind of falls in the Trap oh
what's this that and then they they get
so frustrated because they don't really
know and then they just don't do things
one of the things I noticed to that with
your YouTube channel you make things
real easy with the explanation and I'm
excited for this episode because we're
going to go through a lot of things that
I'm sure that my audience is confused on
and you'll be able to explain them in a
a beginner friendly manner that people
will be able to to understand so yeah
I'd love to get into that awesome cool
maybe let's start with your farm can you
kind of give us a rundown of what you've
been doing recently on your farm
absolutely um yeah so I kind of
explained the history of kind of going
up through the Pacific Northwest uh but
uh as fate would have it it kind of
landed me back in Southern California
where I'm originally from uh
specifically North County San
Diego uh I'm in a basically a Zone 9B
10A um so we're in a tropical kind of
subtropical we we get some freezes but
not a lot so we're able to grow a lot of
uh tropical fruit here which is
extremely exciting to me I've lived in
more temperate climates my whole life so
this was was a huge opportunity like 3
years ago moving down here I've just
kind of done a deep dive into more
tropical subtropical plants and fruits
and So currently um you know I've been
establishing some different food forests
which has really become my passion is
polyculture Food Forest uh and currently
this year I'm working on a really
exciting project it's 22 Acres uh in
North County San Diego so it's primarily
its history is an avocado Orchard uh I
would say probably roughly like eight 8
Acres of that is planted with avocados
there's quite a few different citrus
trees um it's also been used as a flower
market Garden so things like purple
Pride uh some of these high value
flowers from market so we're trying to
run with kind of what's already here but
we're also um prepping for Copic gagro
forestry planting on about half an acre
so we've been sourcing a lot of fruit
trees for that um plants that we can
grow here like mangoes even like um you
know longan we just picked up some
longans
yesterday uh papaya you know uh cherya
we have several cherya trees that are
well established on the property which
is a fruit I absolutely love so I've
just really fell in love with you know a
lot of these tropical fruits and and
it's just a vast kind of rabbit hole of
of uh fruit that I wasn't even
introduced to until a few years ago and
so that's my current project we're also
uh implementing more of a traditional
kind of Market Garden so we are
incorporating you know annuals in with
perennial systems and kind of
experimenting with both of those so
offering kind of a a wide array of you
know different um poly cultures that's
so cool that sounds like you got so much
going on there in your recent YouTube
video one thing I noticed that you're
doing is you've increased the organic
matter in your soil and you've also
added a cover crop those are kind of
like the first steps that you've been
doing can you talk to us about some
sustainable ways to increase the organic
matter in soil yeah well I mean what you
just mentioned is probably my favorite
way of adding organic matter um you know
a lot of what permaculture and Copic
Agro
forestry um the methodology there is
more looking for things that are
directly in your ecosystem so looking
for materials that we can use for
creating biomass composting um I like to
use a lot of cover crops as you
mentioned so you know Clover Alfalfa
between those two you have you know nit
nitrogen
fixation um you also have you know
phosphorus uh like Alfalfa has an
affinity um for phosphorus mobilizing so
between those two um you're really doing
a lot of improvement with the soil um
I'm a noil farmer but you know sometimes
we have to do a hard reset to you know
create a new planting or switch out a
crop or something so that's the only
time I will ever recommend really a till
because it's so damaging to the soil but
if it's it's already
compacted um you have erosion going on
you have you know a system like a
monoculture system you want to swap out
you know then the tilling really makes
sense so for me that first succession
because really with copics we we're
thinking about the successional planting
you know that Clover might just be there
for the beginning to help you know
create that biomask get the nitrogen
fixation really going in the soil get
the exudates really pump pumping down in
as photosynthesis is is pumping you know
pushing a lot of those sugars down into
the soil which is teamed with you know
knf and jadam when we're putting imos
and jadam microbial solution in the soil
and now we're really building up the
life in the soil along with that biomass
and getting that nutrient cycling really
pumping so I mean that's probably my
favorite way to build up the fertility
in the soil uh the
biomass um and organic matter is really
growing those cover crops and um we can
get more into you know support plants
and um you know companion planting um
but right off the bat I'd say get to
know the legume family um nitrogen
fixing family fabas uh I always say they
call it fabas because it's fabulous in
in the sense that these plants uh are
just amazing in a lot of them are fast
Growers vigorous Growers and and again
they're nitrogen fixers so taking that
atmospheric nitrogen you know the ryia
bacteria that is symbiotically growing
with a lot of these uh legumes is is
offering Us free nitrogen so we're we're
producing our own fertilizer in sichu on
site we don't have to go to uh our
neighbors or our grow store down the
street or you know so you can practice
organic farming in a very unsustainable
way you know what I mean when we get
into into regenerative and even copics
now we're looking at directly in our
close vicinity so trying to do things in
sichu on site from animals to um you
know plants that were growing for those
fertilizers makes sense it must be a big
cost savings going that route as well I
can only imagine the amount of money
you're saving from doing it the all
natural way versus going on buying
synthetic nutrients for example which a
lot of farms are still du to this day
where they're buying chemical
fertilizers they're adding it onto the
land and they're killing off their
microbial population and they're just
you know they're kind of in a rut to
where they're they're relying on these
chemical fertilizers in order to grow
the crops year after year when really
they can go the alternative route which
is the allnatural route and use
resources from your land that's free and
then grow plants with that so exactly
yeah now one of the things that you I
saw in your video is that you added down
compost and I think a lot of viewers are
using compost there different types of
compost out there I'd like to know what
type of compost do you recommend and why
yeah so you know along with what I was
saying was I like to do things in sichu
and really create my own amendments my
own um inputs my own fertilizers my own
compost um but it really depends on the
scale and the timing I mean you know the
context kind of drives everything so
there really isn't uh
uh kind of cookie cutter method that I
use it's really all context driven um so
for this context you know we we didn't
have much organic matter in the soil
here at the farm that I'm currently at
so we had a lot of decomposed Granite
sand um so we made the call to Source
some omry organic certified compost till
that into the soil I mean really it's
about a 5year headstone start if you
think about like being able to grow
biomass chop and drop it get it all to
break down we're really giving ourselves
about 5 years by tilling in you know
good quality compost into the soil from
where we would be if we're just trying
to build that up you know say with uh
top dressing and and again you know
using mulches and cover crops so um so
yeah that's what we decided to do here
um we did um didn't produce all this
compost and make it myself to begin with
uh we brought it in from from a local
company uh it was Cal RoR and um you
know got a test on that because one
thing I'd say about compost is we really
need to trust the source because
whatever those animals are eating you
know is ultimately going to end up in
your finished compost and a lot of these
herbicides uh you know and different
chemicals can make it through the
digestive tract of of cows of cattle of
livestock and uh we want to make sure
that doesn't get into our our compost
either it's certainly true when they say
not all compost is created equal
100% well I mean I I did take elain
Ingram's uh course and and she has a
very specific method biocomplete compost
so you know I mean because as you said
not all composts is created equal I go
to some of the uh you know landscape
supplies around here and what they're
selling is compost is essentially like
you know wood chips and like sand and
I'm like where's the organic matter in
this this isn't compost so yeah that's
that's kind of a that that term I would
use that you know with a lot of caution
and take it with a grain of salt you
know grain of sand literally so what can
viewers look for when they're going out
to purchase compost some compost does
come in a bag some are just kind of out
in the lot is there something a
particular should be looking for in the
compost and also do you recommend
testing of the compost before purchase
so if you can get like a small sample
test it make sure everything is good and
then go ahead and do a large purchase
yeah well I mean I would always
recommend
organic um you know I was at the grow
store yesterday we were sourcing some uh
fruit trees for the Orchard and um I was
looking at
um a
biodynamic uh compost so I mean you know
that those are things I would look for
you know obviously
organic um
and yeah the testing is really important
so usually if you're um interested in
getting a test result you can typically
you know email or get a hold of somebody
in the company to get a test result now
sometimes the problem with that is that
they are you know only required to test
so often so you know the batch of
compost that you got might not be the
same test result as a previous batch
that was made so they kind of um that
can get tricky but but the uh company
that we use uh I talk directly to they
have a a PhD you know agronomist that
works for their company and um you know
he was able to I was able to talk to him
directly on the phone and he offered a
really cool guy offered me the test
results and you know showed you know
uh negligent really uh amounts of any
kind of you know harmful uh glyphosate
or or anything else so yeah I would
highly recommend you know trying to get
a test uh if you can talk to the highest
uh quality control person in that
company you can just to kind of Ensure
and and get to know like what you know
get to know what our our our Foods food
was eating or like our plant's food what
its food was eating you know what I mean
get to know that um kind of um down the
line where those sources are coming from
really important that's some good advice
now you mentioned the word biodynamic
and I have quite a few folks that are
beginners here that's probably the first
time they're even hearing of that word
can you break it down for us what is
that yeah that's that's a whole Rabbit
Hole in and of itself uh I don't claim
to be an expert but I have studied a
little bit into it uh biodynamics was
created by a gentleman named Rudolph
Steiner and he's a really interesting
character in history um he wasn't a
farmer per se he was more um kind of the
way I describe him is a a very
esoteric kind of uh guy that used
astrology that used uh it it's it's
really it it's it its core I would say
it's Alchemy applied to Agriculture and
so you know this was in the early 1900s
and and you know people came to Rudolph
Steiner because he was just such a a
powerful figure in his community on all
topics they asked him for a specific way
of of farming and so he came up with
biodynamics as an alternative to
Conventional farming uh and so
biodynamics the short answer is that was
what he came up with it it encompasses
astrological
alignments um you know and there's a
series of different inputs some of them
actually some somei similar to Korean
natural farming I mean for example one
uh
bd500 is horn manure and so um what you
do is you take manure you would put that
in a horn uh traditionally and put that
underground for the winter and so to me
what that is is it's a you know
microbial inoculant by the time you dig
that up after a season after a winter
you now have it completely inoculated
with the soil microbiome of that land
and and then you take that and you go
around and spray that and kind of spread
it but it it it works in
homeopathic uh ways um some of them are
kind of hard to explain by
reductionistic science so it kind of
gets more into some esoteric Realms
that's wild I had never heard of that I
didn't even know that was a thing that's
so cool to hear now one other thing that
I noticed that you do is leaf mold
utilize leaf mold can you talk to us
what is leaf mold what are the benefits
how do you create it how do you apply it
so on and so forth yeah so leaf mold um
is really uh a passionate topic um it's
really my go-to to really create the
foundation of fertility and soil and so
it's it's really the decomposition of
leaves from deciduous trees and so um
primarily the fungi that is symbiotic um
sometimes not always symbiotic I mean
there's a whole Consortium of different
fungus and bacteria I but specifically
it's more the fungi that creates this
aggregate through a slow you could call
it um you know you could call it a
composting process um because the the
leaves are decomposing Slowly by the
fungi that's really eating the lious
material and creating this beautiful
soil aggregate uh meaning like big
clumps of uh this these leaves that are
being literally Digest Ed by the fungi
um and you just see these big webs big
chunk of white
melal um humus in the top soil and you
know so this is used in Korean natural
farming and jadam as a primary means of
uh an inoculant for U growing you know
IMO cultures for creating jadal
microbial
solution um and so the important thing
to note is that it's a Consortium we're
not looking for a specific type of
fungus or whatever and um you know
whenever I've talked to kind of mushroom
Growers about IMO they're always like
Curious so what mushroom are you going
for and it doesn't necessarily work that
way we want the Consortium we are
mimicking nature and so we want that
diversity uh I think you had Chris Trump
on the podcast and um he was talking
about those DNA tests that were done
over 400 100 different species of fungi
over 800 you know bacteria found in some
of this you know this was uh IMO
cultures cultured from leaf mold but
that's what we're looking for is really
the diversity there's power and
diversity and a big approach for me in
in how I practice agriculture is kind of
trying to create these diverse systems
these self-regulating systems by
bringing in the healthy
cultures the diversity and kind of
letting nature figure that out for
itself um obviously like I've trained in
some uh microscopy too so I can look
down under a microscope and kind of look
for the players involved but you know
you don't have to be a scientist uh or
even use know how to use a microscope to
be really successful at culturing imos
and and using them very effectively uh
in your Gardens and on your farm that's
one thing about culturing on your own is
the diversity is going
far superior far more than if you're
buying some of these microbial inoculum
products on the market I'm not making a
claim they should never use never do
that and that they don't work or
anything like that but you're going to
get much more diversity going this
allnatural farming route and kind of
culturing your own absolutely 100% you
know and I'm not I'm not going to knock
some of these uh commercial inoculant
like I use some of them back in the day
and you know specifically to your
audience that you know grows indoors um
I did grow grow uh an indoor back in the
day where I was using imos from outside
bringing those in but that's a careful
process um you know if you're doing a
big scale commercial operation um
obviously you got to be careful when
you're doing that to really build up the
right diversity so I think that you know
indoors might make a little more sense
for some of these different uh microbial
inoculant that you can buy kind of bugs
in a jug so to speak they certainly like
have some efficacy but um you know I I
would use IMO over over those all day
long and and here's one big uh
difference between some of these bugs in
a jug versus like imos imos are cultured
out in nature versus cultured in a
laboratory and there's a big difference
between microbes that are cultured in a
community where there's you know
competition and there's so much
diversity that all these players are
getting involved I mean only the
literally survive whereas in a in a lab
where you're creating like a monoculture
in a sterile environment those cultures
don't have the competition they don't
have um that diversity in nature um
which is really kind of what drives um
the power and and strength of a lot of
these microorganisms in in in my opinion
so I'm not going to say that these these
store bought inoculant don't have a
place but uh you know for me like I
don't I don't buy anything
um except for like a culture that I'm
buying to reculture for example I take
um El rudai uh it's a strain of
lactobacillus uh it was originally found
in uh Mother's breast milk and uh so
it's a probiotic and it it's um there's
a lot of new studies on you know uh
lactobacillus rud ey and so I buy the
culture for that to take as a probiotic
and I reculture that as a yogurt to take
for myself so you know and you can do
the same with these you know uh these
microbes for applying to you know plants
and agriculture that's awesome so it
sounds like there's multiple ways to
kind of get to the Finish Line oh 100%
yeah but for me it all really starts
with the leaf mold I mean there's a lot
of lactobacillus like everywhere on our
skin in the air we can culture that as
well which you know Labs is is a great
uh companion in uh really great for
decomposing organic matter in the soil
too but uh you also get a lot of that in
your your IMO cultures so yeah I'm sure
there's got to be some risks and
mistakes that can happen when you're
creating your own IMO can you get into
that yeah I mean it's definitely uh you
know a specific process for sure and um
I after about 10 years of making IMO
piles my process has kind of changed a
little bit
um and I can speak to that however um
what I would say to your original
question is um I would say uh the
temperatures that you hold you know your
IMO pile when you're culturing is really
important you don't want to be you know
culturing higher than about 130 fahit
and that window between 120 and 130 is
is pretty optimal to maintain that uh
during the process which means you'll be
turning the pile quite a bit um on the
on the flip side of that you don't want
to um disturb the pile too much like
there is a balance like you don't want
to come in and just turn your pile to
where it works a lot like a fire when
you're starting a fire like you don't
want to extinguish that fire too fast
like you really want the the microbes to
start eating that food supply which is
you know basically Millrun so oats
barley Wheats any of those will work you
Mill that down the carbohydrates fats
proteins available are going to become a
food source um and so yeah I mean I I
would say that um having that optimal
temperature that goldilock zone is
really
important and um you know making sure it
doesn't get too wet too Anor robic if
you got you know uh ammonia smells
coming off of your pile that's a red
flag so yeah there there is kind kind of
a a goldilock Zone kind of sweet spot
that you want to stay between when
culturing your your imos that's good
advice I appreciate you uh bring that
down for us so folks are aware you
mentioned you've been creating IMO for
10 years and you've kind of adjusted the
way you've been doing over the years
would you be willing to kind of break
down what steps you currently do to
create IMO yeah absolutely so um I'll
just tell this this quick story because
this is how I came to the Cur process of
of how my process has changed a little
bit um I was uh blessed with the
opportunity to uh you know train
directly with the Cho family uh Master
hanq Cho who recently passed away rest
in peace Master
Hano uh also his son uh young s Cho and
their family uh jadam Sona and um
basically uh was part of a group that
helped to promote a tour around the
whole United States with the The Cho
family and so I toured with the Cho
family and um you know so we had a an
Airbnb out in uh DC to do an event at
Firebird Farms out there an amazing
farm and uh we had a workshop out there
and so one night I was hanging out with
um cultivating Classics who makes these
awesome shirts check them out makes gear
IMO gear and and um so he was helping
with the tour and we were sitting with
uh choyang song and um all having a
beverage of choice and basically um he
told me the story of kind of how IMO
came to be so Master chose original way
for culturing you know IMO and that was
going through the process of imo1 two
you know into three and four and so one
for listeners that don't know I think
it's been explained on here uh maybe by
previous guests but you basically use a
cold like you cook rice and you go out
and you place it in you know healthy
forests with microbiomes or those
healthy ecosystems near you and you
would culture the the
fungi in that environment the indigenous
microorganisms bring that back mix it
one to one with a brown sugar then you
would have imo2 in a jar now imo2 is
really cool because this is like you
know a cryogenic freeze of that specific
year that time of year which that
fluctuates throughout the year so you
literally have a library of that
microbiology from that very moment and
you can keep a whole library of these Im
o2s so that is one really cool thing
about imo2 from there you can take the
IMO Collections and best practice is
really to take several of those to grow
on a substrate you you know Millrun
reculture that that gives you imo3 and
then you would add native soil reculture
it again to make im4 you can take that a
step further into IMO 5 by adding I like
to do seaweed so a nitrogen Source you
could use um manures for this but I5 is
basically if you get to that uh stage
which which is a long process to get
there um that is your like super
Amendment you literally don't really
have to add much more than IM5 if you
get there okay so that being said
simplifying the process what Yong sang
Cho told me was that his father
originally y sang CH or um Cho um hucho
excuse me he originally uh would take
leaf mold and directly culture that on a
substrate and make you know what we
consider
imo3 um and then what happened is there
putting together some books and it was
kind of uh uh Master Cho's daughter was
helping with the recipe writing and you
know there was there was a decision made
at some point to basically use the extra
steps of imo1 collecting in a rice box
adding it to sugar and then creating
imo3 which which adds a lot of steps so
you can do those extra steps if you like
but I kind of just used the leaf mold
straight to the substrate now um I think
this is also a lot more uh kind of
approachable for people the more
accessible and approachable and kind of
less steps involved I find um people
naturally stick with it a little more uh
so uh the other thing that I do is
instead of I love to Mill down all of my
grains myself rather than just buying a
mill run from a Feed Supply because we
can really we have more control of the
the food sources uh the degree in which
we're uh Milling that grain down to make
available those carbohydrates uh the
fats and everything that that grain has
inside all the constituents that these
microbes can feed on so um what I do is
I'll Mill my own grains um which kind of
came from a practice I used to brew a
lot of beer back in the day and so that
was kind of I had these Mills around and
started using it for that um but what I
started doing was um using some whole
grain in my pile so not Milling all of
that but actually leaving some of the
whole grain in there and then I noticed
that grain would germinate and Sprout so
I'd have these Sprouts within my pile
and then I thought wow this is something
because now I can actually you know a
lot of people might be familiar with
like um you know sprouted teas for you
know those enzymes and hormones that you
get from from doing these sprouted teas
and so that's kind of where my thinking
started going with this was well if we
have some of those Sprouts growing in
the mix too you know now we're
increasing like the enzymes and you know
everything else
um that comes along with you know
germination and so we're in you know
adding that to this pile too and now we
really have a super powerful inoculant
either go broadcast or to take further
into uh a liquid Imo um like Chris Trump
kind of originally did I know there's
tons of folks here that are listening in
that uh that do the process and hearing
somebody who's done it for 10 years how
they do it is certainly valuable so
thanks for breaking that down for us
you're welcome I also explain that a lot
more detail kind of on my YouTube
channel if anybody wants to watch any of
those videos sweet yeah I'll definitely
have a link to Preston's YouTube channel
down in the description section below so
people can easily get to it now another
potential option that can do is jadam
microbial solution JMS can you break
that down for us what is it exactly and
kind of how does it differ from IMO
that's a good question um
so JMS is sort of a a simplified version
for replacing IMO that young sing of
jadam came up with uh he felt like
there's too many kind of steps involved
I think if we take those couple steps
out it makes it a lot more approachable
um but you know you can you can culture
JMS incredibly quick so basically with
potatoes uh and sea salt right and so um
it's nearly free to brew and you still
use leaf mold only you're doing it in a
culture of water so it's it's um not air
rated uh so for the most part you know
anerobic
however not completely Anor robic um it
is recommended to really Splash when
you're when you're um cooking the
potatoes down you essentially make like
mashed potatoes and
then you know you can blend that up and
so it's very available starches uh and
then along with the trace mineral
complex that you get from sea salt now
you have this incredible food source for
these
microorganisms and as you steep that in
a
bucket you know you really want to get
it agitated so you're splashing a lot of
oxygen into the mix so even though it's
not completely like an aerated compost
tea with a bubbler rolling um it's not a
Vortex or anything like that you still
it's not a lot of people think that
might be just completely Anor robic and
that's not the case we still get some
aerobic culture in there um I would say
it's a little more Anor robic so we
might be getting more uh facultative
culture than than uh say what you'd get
with the the imos so I have seen that um
so there is a little bit of a difference
and and so to kind of explain the
difference in how I would use IMO a
little bit differently than JMS even
though they're pretty much
interchangeable when I'm first uh
establishing um a new grow say I have
like really uh you know compacted soil
and maybe got some erosion going on JMS
is amazing for that soaking in jmss CU
you really want to soak that in like
deep down young sing always says J jaw
which means like deep down and uh into
the soil and they can survive in
conditions without oxygen so that's
really good at like breaking up hard
compacted clay you know rock um sand and
so I would start with the
JMS first for that situation then I
would come come back start mulching more
and then um before getting ready for a
planting I would be adding the imos
directly you like before my plantings
during my plantings and after and that's
kind of dealing more with the aerobic
cultures that are in the top you know 4
Ines of the top soil so that's kind of
how I differentiate those sounds like
it's a lot easier to do JMS and would be
to do the IMO process I mean with you
mentioned potatoes and sea salt that's
something that lot of people just have
in their cupboard there so they can
easily kind of get started creating
their own JMS solution is there a
specific type of potato that's better
than other like rusted potatoes versus
sweet potato is there any differences at
all there um it's an interesting
question it's really like what has the
most starches cuz that's really you know
what the food source is that we're
getting from potatoes this gets into
kind of a really interesting area of
optimizing your JMS and so let's say
you're growing strawberries uh you could
create a JMS by putting potatoes or
strictly strawberries into that and now
you're optimizing your microorganisms
for that specific crop so this gets into
a a really interesting kind of uh area
of of application and research um you
know tailoring these microorganisms for
the specific crop so I haven't seen a
huge difference I have used like sweet
po potatoes before um I would say by
adding different food sources you are
you know
potentially and I've seen this under a
microscope you are culturing you know
different strains um largely they're
going to be similar based on you know uh
samples that were taken from the same
environment um but this also gets to um
jadam and I guess you could say knf as
well typically you want to be culturing
in the same exact environment that
you're growing in because those
microorganisms are optimized for those
conditions there's a reason why when I
go collect leaf mold under an oak tree
that's a 50-year-old oak oak tree on
this property there's a reason why
they're there because they went through
the whole process of you know Evolution
and adapting in in you know all of those
different variables from the temperature
humidity um the moisture you
know all those different VAR Ables these
microbes made it through and have
adapted and acclimated for literally
thousands of years so they're optimized
for that environment and so that is
where you want to be doing your liquid
fertilizers your composting your
JMS um you want to put those barrels
right next to the fields you're growing
in that makes total sense now in regards
to application rate probably majority of
the folks out of tuning in are indoor
Growers and uh JMS what would you say is
an appropriate application rate when
should they apply should it be you know
every week should it be every other week
once a month once a grow can you give us
some information in regards to that
stuff sure yeah I mean it's um you know
it's variable for sure it kind of
depends on your situation if we're
talking about an indoor uh it might be a
really good time to condition uh before
let's say you're um you know prepping
for a new planting and you just added a
new soil mix a new blend you're getting
the structure and your your soil uh a
living soil system you know going jmss
is great for that initial inoculation
and kind of jump starting that whole
process it's going to help start
breaking down all the compost and
organic matter in the soil um so that
would be a good time to apply it when
you're just getting started and just
starting to build you know that soil
food web um I would use it more often so
maybe once a week you know for the first
couple of months uh from that point on
you know you might do it every uh month
or so and then once you really get it um
those cultures really
established um you don't have to apply
that often I'd say maybe you know every
succession of your planting I might do
another application at that point maybe
just one um but uh yeah so more up front
when you're first developing the soil
food web oh and so you're point about
you know application rates um 1 to 30 is
a common rate I mean so a lot of these
um you know kind of um applications work
a little differently than say like a
salt-based fertilizer where we get
really specific on the application dose
I mean we can stay within the
recommended ranges um which is always
good but it's it's not like you don't
have to get too worried about like okay
I did this one at like you know 50 Parts
as opposed to to 30 parts um you might
go with a more uh concentrated you know
form of the JMS when you're first
establishing it for example we had a
really compacted area outside here um
where we're doing the cop Copic rows on
half an acre
and um what I did is I just soaked it in
with water and then I applied jmss
straight onto the field but I did soak
it down first with water um but the the
common rate is one part JMS to 30 parts
decoronated filtered water that would be
a pretty common
application um you could go all the way
to like 1 to 100 um and if you're
soaking in first you could be applying
JMS straight I'd be a little more
careful doing that because it's it's uh
it's pretty loaded with uh a lot of
microbiology okay and then only as a
soil drench or do people use it as a
fold spray as well jmss more so as a a
soil drench um you yeah you could fuler
spray it but I feel uh a lot of those um
kind of facultative Anor robes I mean
they could they'll live in the phosphere
as well as the the risos sphere so yeah
you're going to get um you know some
benefits from foler spraying as well if
you have uh say you have some powdery
mildew um you know JMS could be good for
combating that um just like you know IMO
limo tea is also good for that awesome
all right what other simple inputs can
indoor Growers make at home using either
kitchen straps or easily sourced
materials I would say fermented plant
juices um which we use sugar to
osmotically extract all the constituents
out of plants usually just the uh growth
tips that have most of the growth
hormones in the plant um you know the
oxin gibberelic acid is what we're going
for as well as some of the
constituents um you know in that plant
so um basically harvesting vigorous
weeds that grow around your house you
can utilize those or your farm you can
utilize those for a fertilizer to make
uh a fpj fermented plant juice or if you
go the jadam method you just throw it in
water and so I kind of around like
everything in jadam you just like throw
it in water and purify it um you know
obviously there's more to the system
than that um you know and as mentioned I
think by previous guests you know the
the IMO cultures are 80% of knf and
jadam these other inputs that we make
are kind of just additives little extras
they also mimic like exudates with the
the soil content I think that's a lot of
what um fpj
is doing uh so yeah other inputs we
could make um if you have eggshells you
can make water soluble calcium if you
have bones you can make Cal fos uh those
are made with extractions of of vinegar
um so you know those are are really
great to make as well uh what else do we
have um brown rice vinegar is another
input in Korean natural farming uh I do
culture some of my own brown rice
vinegar um that gets a little involved
that's a three-step fermentation process
so um that's a little bit more involved
in you know um Master Cho doesn't really
teach never really taught brv for the
most part that that I'm aware of so uh
kind of found those recipes on my own
but uh yeah those would be some good
ones you can you can make I also do a
lot of uh vermac composting with kitchen
scraps I have worm Tower right outside
my kitchen door so I just toss a lot of
my food scraps in there give it to the
worms awesome yeah it gives the audience
some options they can uh do some
Googling and and research anything that
interests them and they can learn more
how to do that process absolutely now
how about for Pest Control a lot of
people want to really go the allnatural
route when it comes to controlling pests
or preventing pests what are some best
knf or jadam Pest Control solutions for
indoor garden yeah that's a great
question question so uh with the knf
side it's um there's not a whole lot of
pesticides that we make in the k&amp;f
system it's more preventative measures
and those preventative measures are
really built in the diversity that we're
building first of all in the soil with
the the
microbiome and so we're building a lot
of resistance on our plants with the
higher bricks level um that is created
through these cultures of of IMO um and
then we can use like you know bio
remediation like uh Labs is a good one
to com combat like uh mildew and things
like that um in the phosphere even in
the soil and then jadam has a lot more
to offer on the side of like you know
our our uh pesticides so jadam teaches
how to make a Horticultural soap a
wedding agent and then with that you can
team that soap with many different uh
herbal uh
extractions uh to I mean the this guy is
the limit with different um extractions
that you can use with the Horticultural
soap one of my favorites when I was in
Hol County was using the California bay
laurel um introduced that to the Natural
farming Community years ago uh because I
was studying herbalism and found that
the Native Americans of that region use
the the bay laurel which has this really
fragrance super high uh essential oil
content in the leaves it's just very
powerful um and the Native Americans
would take and they would um they would
protect some of like the egg corn meal
they were making they would surround it
with the bay laurel to keep pests away
and I was like reading about that like
oh that could be used in jadam as a
pesticide and so I started distilling uh
bayoro leaves and found that um yeah the
uh essal oils like have are are great
for you know aphids they really really
effective on aphids um successfully took
care of a huge infestation of um aphids
on a hemp crop in in Oregon and uh had a
lot of other friends doing pretty large
scale stuff using the bay laurel with a
lot of uh you know um positive results I
mean basically within like 99% of the
community of aphids was destroyed in two
applications that's super interesting to
me bay laurel is actually it's around
here a lot and I was considering putting
in as like privacy bushes so I didn't
realize that they could have other uses
for me so that's that's really exciting
to me yeah absolutely it's it's a it's
amazing uh tree up in Oregon it's um
Oregon
Myrtlewood and um they they have a
different name my ex-girlfriend who was
an herbalist used to joke around with me
um no it's Oregon or murwood and I'd say
no it's California bayoro and we were
both
right so I imagine all of these things
when it comes to Natural farming a lot
of folks they're afraid that they're
going to make mistakes and I'd like to
go over some of the common mistakes that
new Growers make when trying to
implement some of these permaculture
techniques can you break it down for us
maybe some of the things maybe top two
or three that come to your mind of
mistakes that new folks make and how
they can be avoided or corrected well
the biggest one that comes to mind for
me is you know living soil systems
regenerative farming systems that were
uh emulating natural processes you know
they take time and so I know we kind of
live in an instant gratification modern
culture and I would say that's probably
one of the biggest ones is that we need
to be patient and enjoy the process uh
it's okay to learn through our our
failures our mistakes and uh those just
make us better the next times around and
so I would say that's probably one of
the biggest ones um you know it's it's
the old story of uh the moral of the the
tortoise in the hair you know it's
better to be uh slow and effective and
efficient than you know fast and Hasty
and so I think with the the regenerative
farming methods um you know take the
tortoise's example there and uh be
patient with the process and um
other
mistakes uh the companion plants are a
big one when it comes to
permaculture and Copic Agro forestry um
that was a big one for me was learning
how important the companion plants are
to you know um to that system because
those are more systems approaches we're
looking more ecology rather than just
like a monoculture uh we're focused on
the system so really focusing more on
the system and those support plants and
how important they are to cycle you know
nutrients into the system not just
looking at you know our Target crop um
we're literally growing our own you know
fertilizers uh with Copic Agro forestry
it's it's more of a principle based
method than an input-based method yeah I
I'm sure we can get much much deeper
into so many different aspects of things
cover crops companion planting mulch
layers and Tropic Agro foresty I'd like
to invite you back on for a part two at
some point in the future if you'd be
willing to get into some of these things
deeper coming up towards the end of the
podcast here so I'd like to wrap things
up but yeah if you're down for a part
two at some point in the future I not
only me would enjoy it but my I know my
audience would enjoy it as well
absolutely I would love to yeah I mean
we didn't really touch on uh copics and
and there's so much there it's it's it's
an incredible uh way to to farm and I
think it does have some application
uh in in indoors too looking at plant
consortiums and uh you know those uh
those intervals that we can plant in so
I'd love to come back awesome to a plan
for that okay let's wrap things up here
can you tell the listeners how they can
find you and is there anything upcoming
in the future that you want to talk
about yeah sure um I am Rogue uh
regenerative agriculture on YouTube I
have an Instagram um Rogue
regeneration and then my website is
rogal farming.com there's some
information and I try to keep that
update with kind of current projects I
do offer some canf inputs um you know I
I don't my goal isn't to be a fertilizer
salesman at all my labels say you know
make your own first and supplement
second so I I don't often sometimes I'm
slow to even get those orders out and it
and it's really seasonal but I do offer
some of those on on the website and then
also uh Life Source farm.net is a is the
farm that I currently work at we're
launching uh a new platform to sell our
produce that's regeneratively harvested
um we'll have avocado boxes available
very soon and and much more so that's
where you can find me awesome I'll
definitely have a link to Preston's
YouTube channel down in the YouTube
description section below and if you
have any questions in regards this or if
you want to let us know what inputs you
use let us know down in the comments
section below below the people being
scrolled on the screen right now are on
the producer tier on patreon special
thanks to you
patreon.com Mr Grow 100% of what is
donated through there goes right back on
the podcast so thank you so much for
your contribution Preston once again
thanks so much for coming on just
hearing a what seems like a small piece
of your knowledge has been very valuable
to me and I'm sure it's very valuable to
my audience as well so thank you so much
for taking the time to sit down with me
today uh speak for an hour absolutely
privilege to be here Chris thanks for
the opportunity can't wait to talk some
more all right we'll leave it at that
thanks so much I'll catch youall in the
next episode peace out