what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
today I got a discussion video for you
let's talk about plant training there
are so many different things you can do
when it comes to training plants in this
video I'm not only going to tell you
what I do when I train my plants but I'm
bringing a guest into this discussion
pigeons for 20 he is a youtuber with
over 74 thousand subscribers and he has
over 800 grow videos on his channel and
he's been doing YouTube since I believe
the beginning of 2016 if you go to his
channel which I'll link down in the
description section below you'll see he
does a ton of different plant training
techniques if you like these types of
discussion videos please hit that thumbs
up button that's an indication to
whether or not I should make more of
these videos and yeah let's get into the
discussion all right got pigeons here
how are you dude man I'm I'm doing well
thank you for having me I'm really
excited to talk to you it's been overdue
conversation I guess I'd say it's the
first time we've ever actually done a
video chat like this and you know we've
both been doing YouTube videos for over
three you know three four years now
alright five years and dude I'm super
psyched thanks for coming on today well
as I said thanks for having me man but
more importantly thank you for for being
kind of kind of a shining light in the
community when it comes to bringing the
community together and and getting
getting getting the best out of us I saw
the the show that you did with Rob and I
really enjoyed the conversation I
thought you guys really brought the best
out of each other when it came to the
conversation pulling out ideas and and I
think this is this is a this is a good
Avenue for the content so I'm really
excited thanks for having me
cool yeah no problem let's talk about
plant training so for plant training so
you know I really wanted to bring you
into this discussion because I've been
on your channel and I see a lot you do a
lot of different type of plant training
techniques and you know today you can
talk about that I don't think we're
going to talk about all to plant
training techniques that are out there
but definitely the most common so low
stress training topping if we can get
into it maybe do a little super cropping
or filming things like that there are
other things other ways to do it we
probably won't get into it all in this
video so just to give you viewers a
heads up on that one
let's start off with arguably the most
common which is low stress training so
first off what is low stress training
right so low stress training is really
bending down and or tying down branches
in order to allow other branches to grow
up and you know be even with that canopy
is kind of the basic definition of it
what's your definition of it is it kind
of the same thing there after yeah
absolutely absolutely low stress
training trying not to create anything
that's going to prolong the plant's life
and and stress will certainly prolong
the plant's life so just gentle bending
be tying down is a great way to put it
talking of even of just a tucking of
leaves I think is a low stress training
so yeah just just anything that's
hands-on that's not creating too much
stress for the plant in general why low
stress train was the point of low stress
training so I think I do believe the
most common reason for low stair saying
is to increase the yield so I've read on
websites that it's up to a 40% increase
in yield just from doing low stress
training what do you think what do you
think the reasons are for doing less
stress training well that that that
exactly at trying to create the most out
of your plant when I when I first
started growing I remember when I would
look into a a package of seeds and on
the back it would give you the strain
the contents of the Kanab but then it
would give you a time frame and an
average yield and I was looking at
numbers that that looked so unobtainable
you know we're talking 500 grams 300
grams of some some number that went
along with those those those those beans
and I tried to figure out how on earth
you're gonna be able to maximize your
those numbers how do you get those
numbers and the best way to do that is
to to try to pull the most out of the
plant ensure that you're gonna expose
more possible tops to get buds from and
and you can you can certainly do that
with low stress training so yeah
to maximize the yield that you're gonna
get out of the plant by maximizing the
size and potential of that plant
when do you usually start low stress
training honestly it starts really early
when I'm when I'm describing this to a
new grower I'm gonna tell someone to
wait till the third node it's kind of a
rule of thumb but the reality of it is
your plant is going is going through
stresses almost immediately you know
you're trying to minimize the amount of
stress that a seedling goes through but
you can certainly start flexing
well well after the first node as soon
as you start to see some kind of sprout
coming out after your original what are
those first leaves called called Laden
yes the first node after that typically
you can start to give it a little bend
get a little bit of of hands on to start
to beef in that stem so I'll go as early
as the first node after the first node
got it for me you know it really depends
on growth it depends on my schedule
right sometimes I'm not available to
start low stress training that dead
early but yeah starting early I
typically like to wait till the third to
fifth node and then I'll start bending
the main branch down from there now
sometimes you know it really depends on
growth as well because some like indica
strains for example gonna be real
naturally squat if it's more of a
stretchy strain like a sativa stretchy
strain like an OG or something like that
at the third node the things already you
know 7 to 10 inches tall potentially so
doing it at the third node you know is
always a potential as well so for me it
really depends on growth I guess I guess
that's a good point it really depends on
the the sex of seed as well if you if
you if you don't know your your your sex
training that early might not make as
much sense you know your you might be
putting in too much effort for something
that might not be going the full
distance you know you might not have a
female so if I'm if I'm running regular
seeds typically I'm actually gonna start
training a little bit later but then it
kind of goes hand-in-hand with the more
training
you're gonna you're almost gonna see
signs of sex sooner based on stress kind
of anecdotal them through my own
experience but
if I knew I had a regular seed and sorry
sorry-sorry a feminized seed I am going
to put stress on that plant that seed a
lot sooner than something that I didn't
know hmm
the outcome of interesting I actually
went to your channel and I saw a video
directly it relates to this is when to
start training I think you had a
chaplain that you did know training on
and it was like close to three feet
maybe two feet three feet and had a new
man handle the thing and it was just
straight up and then you manhandled it
and literally brought it in like a swirl
coming around how did that turn out
right so you had a little three feet and
then just manhandle it bent it like
crazy and then wrapped it all around and
then can you talk a little bit about
that yeah essentially you mentioned it
earlier when you said when it came down
to schedule growing your plants relies
heavily on your schedule if you're there
then you know they're gonna benefit a
little more a little bit more than if
you're not there
this particular plant got yeah I think
it was even upwards of four feet high
and this was sheer ignorance I just let
it get the best of me I kept I kept
doing other things you know you get a if
you have a full flower room you know
it's easy to let the veg room kind of
kind of kind of get a little bit behind
where it should be and and that's what
happened in this case and this girl in
fact it was a I believe was it was new
dog was that was the strain it it it got
way to I unmanageable but I knew through
experience that this wasn't something to
be worried about I knew that I could
bring this to a size manageable
something that I could deal with and my
first my first response was to bend it
in half take take take take that four
feet and turn it into two feet because
at least now I'm I'm an indoor growers
so I can I don't have the sky the sky is
not the limit for me so I decided to
manipulate that stem and at four feet
we're talking about a stem that's
already almost in maybe an inch inch and
a half thick already and with no
training and I decided to just really
manipulate that stem get it nice
loose and I just as you really started
to break that membrane you could it
almost starts she started to just fall
over on her own and then it was just a
matter of just getting her down tying
her to the pot and ensuring that all
that undergrowth was gonna start coming
upwards and as a matter of fact I still
have the refer to it as the antlers of
the the stem that was the new dog I
trimmed it up and it still sits in a
back room in the house because I I'm so
attached to that one I'm not ready to
get rid of her I'm trying to think if I
should lock her up and put her up as
like a trophy on top of the garden or
something you know all right yes she's
right right she yielded she yielded
wonderfully III I don't I I didn't weigh
my harvest but we got quite a few jars
off of off of vekar I'd say in and
around that half that 3/4 of a of a pea
you know so it was a good it was a good
it was good haul I was a happy camper so
I was beneficial for you so would you
say that there's no it's never too late
to start low stress tree no no
absolutely not never too late you know
absolutely not you you can go hands-on
at any time and in fact even when you're
in flower I would still suggest going
hands-on for at least the first few
weeks to ensure that you know well the
plants using up those starches and those
sugars and and and enjoying that stretch
that it's not gonna become too uneven
that you're having some some some
flowers that are closer to the light and
some that aren't you know so no it's
never too late never too late the plant
should be just the way you want it
before you put it into flour and and if
that means you need to train it at week
8 12 or 15 and in veg then get you got
to get her done you got to get her done
I did that one time where I bent a
French down when it was similar
situation I think it was as as big as
what you mentioned it was very unstable
to planning at being very unstable and
that's mainstem still continued to be
the main stem and had the largest bud
and thing was just flopping all over the
place did that happen with with yours or
no no no once like once you once I bent
her over it was it was it was imperative
that I gave those other stems
is my here I am this is much this is the
technique I use on the stems I roll them
through my fingers I do this all the
time I walk through the garden in the
mornings and and and roll all these
little stems through my fingers
I must roll you know upwards of a
hundred stems in the morning as I just
come through the garden with my coffee
and the idea was with that particular
girl once she was flipped over was to
just manipulate all those shoots all
those tops to ensure that none of them
got left behind but then I did you got
it we have to remember that sometimes
not every top is going to be a potential
bud you've got to just get rid of
something you've got a creeper clean
you've got to keep your canopy fresh
open and and and and available for to
take in fresh air and if you're keeping
every single top you're gonna have some
buds that are huge some that are small
and and it's just it's important to just
ya get get hands-on on all of those
individual buds so that they all get
that that that strength that they need
got it I'll link that video in the
description section below so for anybody
who wants to see that it I definitely
recommend you click on that video and
check it out because it's it's a pretty
crazy eye I was blown away with what you
did but a lot of fun it was a lot of fun
and and yeah it the story of the new dog
that one I remember that she was a good
one that was a good one it was a lot of
fun cool
ok so low stress training so what
exactly do you do so I'll start so you
know I'll typically do that initial
first Bend when it's on you know roughly
its fifth node right like I said it
depends on growth and I'll bend that
down and then really it normally only
really takes what like a week ten days
maybe two weeks before you have to
actually bend down other branches as
well so for me I'm continually bending
down branches and tying them down and as
you know a new main chute kind of comes
up and dominates I'll bend that down and
you know I'm constantly tying things
down you're just trying to creep to make
the canopy even at all times and I'll
continue to do that all the way up
really into flowering and then that
three-week stretch I'll still continue
to do less stress training I'll still
continue to pull down those branches
tied
down in order to try to keep an even
canopy and I found that really that
first three weeks when you flip the
flowering when the plant is still
stretching is kind of like the hardest
in my opinion to still control and
create even canopy feel like it's a lot
easier when the plant is in veg just
because you get I mean a plant can grow
while like two inches overnight or
something like that like that's right so
yeah it's a little bit harder to control
my opinion but that's kind of when I
stop is really after that stretch now
what do you do how long do you do
low stress train and when you stop it
I'm very similar in terms of the
starting starting early with that
initial been I don't do like I have but
I try to refrain from tying down or or
pinning down now i i do i do take coat
hangers metal coat hangers and i and ice
and i cut them up so that you can keep
the metal pins and i can put those to
use as pins for the for the shoots to
kind of keep them towards the soil but
generally i feel as if if you can get in
there every day every second day let's
be real and and twist and bend those
tops you're gonna turn a very small stem
into a very thick stem very very quickly
when you do pin them down there's still
that same effect but i do feel as if you
can every time a top rises up and
sometimes it can only take three hours
four hours maybe maybe a little bit
longer they from going in from a flat
bend to being straight up again if you
can get back in there and keep bending
that down i think that's far more
beneficial than you know tying it down
leaving it coming back tying down
leaving it coming back you know but but
that would be more that would that's
just i guess more my technique than
anything else
I certainly utilize both techniques when
it comes to pinning and or bending when
it comes to your schedule this whole
at-home virus this 2020 has allowed me
to do a lot more in garden work than I
have ever been able to do so I'm kind of
learning these little little techniques
over the last few months that I didn't
necessarily know before but when it
comes to as early as training yeah that
initial Bend
typically it's hands-on
bend it down still twisting and there's
that that finger thing yeah still
twisting each stem and just just making
sure that each stem from going straight
up at the the end of my visit
looks like something stepped on it she I
don't want any tops pointing the sky to
the sky when I leave the flower room
after a good low stress training in the
morning because then I feel like I've
gotten I've gotten I've gotten
everything taken care of so yeah as
early as I can hands on and then same
thing not three weeks and you're right
it is the hardest because you're growing
in the veg room over the course of well
my case is three plus months of vegging
whereas you're seeing growth over three
months you can see a month's worth of
growth in just a couple days in the
flower room and if and if you're not
click on the hands on next thing you
know you've got you've got nine inches
in between your flower points or in
between your but your bud sites so yeah
I totally agree in terms of that three
weeks is just as important or more
important to ensure that you can
maintain all that hard work that you put
in at throughout the rest of the flower
room so I totally agree the the last
time I'm training you know you're still
you're still tucking leaves and and
trying to trying to separate buds you
don't want any buds stuck together so I
still think that that in some sense is
low stress training just to ensure that
these buds they're there in their own
isolated environment you don't have two
buds that are stuck too close together
you don't have a leaf that you know say
drooped right on top of a bud personally
I would not remove that leaf I think
that's a high stress training I would I
would just tuck that leaf underneath
that bud so that there's no moisture or
any any trapped air inside that kick
there that bond cutter you bring up a
good point with the hand bending you
know I use ties I mentioned how I use
ties but there have been grows where I
all I did was ham bending so I go in
there and just use my hand and you know
you have to do it like two or three
times a day
but hand bending down and continuing to
bend down and you'll see those other
branches come up and I've done plants
several grows where I just do hand
bending and no ties whatsoever so it is
still possible to do low stressed
hanging without actually using ties
what do you use for ties when you use
ties should you use coat hangers coat
hangers and I think that's a that's a
underutilized
item in our households now granted metal
coat hangers are kind of going out with
with the times and we're more of the
plastic coat hangers now granted I'm
sure you could like you could manipulate
a plastic coat hanger and do the same
thing but metal coat hangers have really
got me through because it's like I find
these things everywhere I've got
hundreds of metal coat hangers now they
don't last forever they do corrode and
they do eventually go bad but you know
just just to cut a coat hanger you cut
the the bottom in the middle and you cut
the top you just take the two sides you
can even take the little the hook and
cut that off and use that as a hook as
well however I I primarily use either
they're they're like mechanic's ties
there are like pipe ties or something
they're like a they're like a twist tie
but they're rubber and my viewers have
told me they're like they're a
mechanic's twist tie of sorts okay and
or garden wire typically like just a
twist tie a roll of twist tie and aside
from that ma'am that's it in my hands
yeah that's that's most of I use those
garden ties I think it's like two bucks
at your local gardening roll of them
right yeah for the whole like a green
yeah yep yep and you can just take off
those ties and reuse them so exactly
exactly but I mostly use that and when I
tie the branch what I do is I'll wrap
that tie around like a loop like a
double wrap but I won't actually like
twist the ties together because as that
branch grows thicker the way I do it
could I'm just continuing wrap it it'll
unravel on its own right so it doesn't
like choke up the stem I don't know if
I'm explaining that clearly enough but
just kind of wrapping it around twice
and then as it expands well then it's
unraveling the tie now you have to
adjust every now and then but just a
small tip so people don't choke out
there there and you totally will that's
a group that's a great tip I still choke
out my plants because it's like you'll
forget about a tie you know what I mean
you'll you'll come in make sure I'm
moving ties all the time but you know as
the plant gets larger and the more tight
put down you're gonna forget one and and
so wrapping them that's a good idea
that's a good idea I've choked out
plants too way too many times
yeah and then sew on fabric pots I think
common thing that beginners might be
wondering is how do I tie this down to a
fabric pot and what I usually do is I'll
take like a bobby pin and I'll pierce
the side of the fabric pot and then you
know close off that bobby pin and then
take that twist tie and then attach it
to the bobby pin just I do for fabric
pots I'd see some things with velcro
that actually wrap all the way around
the the fabric pod then you take the
velcro and go up and bring the branches
down if I have a link to that I know
coop med uses that shoutout to ku
Matty's a grower if I can find the link
to that I'll link that down below and
then for plastic pots I usually use
those binder clips just really when you
do a most are strangest whatever you can
find okay that's it I use I use e paper
clips yeah around a fabric pot okay
paper clips around it and then I just
tie to the paper clip same idea whatever
you can find yeah I know some people
drill holes in the plastic pots I mean
whatever you want to do right so
whatever whatever you have available
really what about you and anything else
to add kind of for that no that's it I'm
an exclusively fabric pots I don't use
anything aside from a fabric art and
it's been that way for years so I don't
know anything different but yeah it's
the the paper clip but the paper clip in
you're gonna put about you'll see it in
that new dog video actually as a matter
of fact if some if anyone checked the
description after the after the video I
there was probably twenty some paper
clips all the way around that pot and I
just tied now the downside of course as
the plant gets stronger and they are
incredibly strong they will pull the
paper clips out of the fabric pot so you
got to be yeah you got to be vigilant
you have to be vigilant anything else
for low stress training I think it's
necessary I think it's necessary IIIi
don't avoid it get hands-on and and and
manipulate your your plants to increase
yield it's a necessary it's a necessary
you can really forty percent I think if
they if that's the statistic that's I
think that's an under statement in terms
of the amount of yield you'll increase
by doing training
I think it's upwards of you know seventy
percent in some cases but yeah
get hands-on dulo training I wouldn't
say I disagree I was as necessary like
as a new grower you don't have to do low
stress training but it's extremely
emotional yeah good point that's a good
point good point
cool topping let's talk about topping so
okay so topping what is topping topping
really just straight basically is just
pinching off or cutting off a piece of
the plant usually it's that main stem
that comes off and then what happens
from there is it'll kind of split into
two and it will have two tops right it's
like kind of your definition of it as
well or uh yeah and not only are you in
like it you're promoting on undergrowth
as well you remove a top you're gonna
get two tops and then you're gonna see
an excess amount of energy promoted to
the undergrowth of the plant as well
great boy yes great point so for me I
usually top I usually wait until it's
like on its fifth node then I'll top
down - well actually I'm sorry there's
so there's two ways to kind of top is
the pinching method and then there's
also the the cutting method where I like
to call it a hard top is where you're
actually taking you know trimmers and
trimming off the stem I've done both
techniques you know the pinching off is
super easy just take your hands and
pinch off I kind of like to do the the
hard top where I cutting
usually when I'm pinching I'll just wait
and then pinch at that fifth node if I'm
doing a hard top you know I'll hard I'll
wait till it's fifth node and hard top
down to the third node for me
similar to LST it depends on growth
right a real stretchy strain I'm going
to do a hard top down because I might
have other plants in the garden which
are slower growers and so trying to kind
of create keep that canopy even between
all the plants so as far as you know
when I top how I top it really kind of
depends on growth what about you you
know when I first started training
topping is something that I did all the
time as I've become more efficient in my
growing I don't top at all anymore
I just I Bend I just bend I find bending
does a very similar has a very similar
Nikken earths are a very similar effect
when it comes to promoting undergrowth
and and creating strong stems I just
yeah once you start training your plants
you start to you to like the I find when
you're not training a plant the energy
is focused at the top of the plant I
don't think there's anything new about
that the energy goes up when you start
bending that plant the energy is now
being delivered to more than just the
the top of the plant
wait you're now seeing a promotion of
growth and that under growth or the
other anything other than the top I
think that's a very similar effect that
when you have a topping is you remove
the top you then have two tops but then
you have a promotion of undergrowth now
III yeah I've just not found topping to
be as beneficial anymore when it comes
to training I just bending has a very
similar effect and I end up when it
comes to being say two and a half to
three months in two veg I'm removing
tops at this point because I have too
many not because I want more I've got
way I have way too many so it's through
training you're gonna be removing tops
just just just to keep a clean canopy so
if that's the same thing I'm not
entirely sure but yeah not not much of a
topper anymore yeah I mean you bring up
a great point right so topping is HST
high-stress training right so it's a
high-stress train technique you're doing
physical damage to the plants so really
you know if you're cutting off the top
of the plant plants gonna use some of
that energy for recovery right so it
could you know slow down the growth and
most likely gonna slow down the growth a
little bit right like a day or two
whatever it takes to recover so bending
down arguably just doing LST I give Lee
isn't gonna slow down that growth right
so just revert faster your vegetables at
you that's right
but yeah I'll top I'll do a combination
of topping and low stress training so
maybe you know top down I'll top the
fifth node for example and then I'll
Bend all those branches down and then
just to low stress training for the
remainder of the time so some plants I'm
just doing that one top one top of the
fifth node and then spreading out all
those lower branches I've done other
techniques where I top-down like I said
wait till the fifth no top down to the
third node and I'll remove the first
node leave the second node
there's so many different things you can
do right so I've really recommend people
to kind of experiment with with topping
and low stirring all these different
training techniques that we talked about
because there's so many different ways
to do it but yeah I've done both I like
to top and also I've done multiple tops
so I do that first initial top then I
wait a week or so and then do another
top of those tops and then kind of wait
till those branches develop so
topping so I get you know eat Maine coal
is coming up or I could top a third time
we get 16 Maine coal is coming up I've
done as much as thirty thirty-two
Maine Cola is coming up on plants so
there's just so many ways to do it and I
definitely recommend people to kind of
experiment with that that's true it you
have experimenting is key experimenting
is key regardless of what you hear from
from myself or or yourself is that
you're gonna find a way that works for
you by by blending a bunch of the
techniques I I did the same thing I
started by doing a bunch of topping I
thought it was the best way to go top
and get all the tops and then I and then
when people asked how many times do you
top I ended up only topping two times I
would do the initial top and then maybe
one more top after that but to emen and
then just kind of weaned out too I find
I was getting a similar technique which
is the bending so that's it experiment
get your hands dirty these plants are
resilient it's wonderful that we can
discuss a low stress training and a high
stress training you know that's that's
pretty special so so so get your hands
dirty get your hands on and and and
maximize the yield maximize the
potential and you could literally if you
just have one of those plants where it's
just growing straight up and really
you're not getting much side branching
at all if you're a beginner and you're
kind of worried about you know doing a
topping you could literally just do that
one top and that plant is gonna Bush out
you don't have to do any additional
training on top of that and the plant is
gonna push out just from one initial
topping and no additional training that
feeling in your heart of insecurity and
unknowing that the unknown of what's
gonna happen when you type that's normal
that's normal
you're gonna get over it and it's gonna
be okay because I'm sure it happened to
you on the first time that you eat
someone told you to chop the top of your
plant off you're like what
yeah it's gonna be okay and that feeling
deep down is normal I just yeah I want
that to be new and anything else on
topping there's not much else - all
right no I think that's it pretty
straightforward pretty straightforward
yeah
how about FEMEN have you ever done
filming yeah I think on like
inadvertently when you try to top and
I'll let you two actually describe the
acronym and what it is but because a lot
of people you have the idea of what
filming is and what it stands for don't
actually go hand in hand people have no
idea I know I didn't when I said when I
learned the technique but I think yeah
inadvertently you end up en up filming
went often when you're topping and and
it's it's it's a very similar technique
but you haven't completely removed the
initial talk so there there's there's a
little bit of life there to keep going
and in terms of the energy that's being
being provided but yeah I've certainly
practiced it one of the same things but
topping though it's it just kind of gone
by the wayside with time got it
yeah so it's so FEM our filming phim
stands for I missed that's actually what
it stands for Google if you don't
believe me
really the name comes from somebody
trying to top but when they pinched off
the top they missed so they didn't
actually top off entirely so they just
pinched that top growth and what
happened instead of just splitting out
in two different directions it went to
four different directions I believe I've
actually finden went off three different
directions so you know just cutting off
not actually like pinching off the
entire top but just kind of pinching off
almost the entire top it could lead to
it's hard to get accurate actually I
feel like it's hard to especially I it
so small
yeah it's hard to get that perfect spot
to where it's gonna split out into four
different branches of stages - but yeah
I've done it accidentally - I thought
I'd topped right and then it turned out
to be a film which was it's kind of cool
I don't know but I hard over to miss
it's almost harder to miss than it is to
get it right I don't like to get to get
that right miss so that it gives you
those tops those extra tops it's almost
harder to get it wrong than it is to get
it right
so that now if ma femme isn't something
I often practice to be honest but I
would love to hear from the viewers how
many of you guys try to film on purpose
let us know down in the comments section
below and let us know like when you try
to film as well good question there's so
many different ways to do it right
you know what note do you like to film
at and to get the best result from so
anything on that anything else one
filming no you nailed it man you know
that not something I heard at practice
myself but again something to experiment
with that there's so many different
techniques and I think that's the joy of
being a gardener in 2020 is that people
are trying everything now and you can
almost go and check someone out who's
doing it you know and you'll find
someone and then pick up some techniques
have you ever heard of no technique
plant training you know never heard of
that no technique no you'd have to
explain because maybe it's not as simple
as it sounds
yeah so I came across the Sun on the
website that was talking about it all it
is is basically taking that main branch
bending it down 90 degrees and that's a
no other training on top of that so just
taking that initial initial branch
bending down 90 degrees and then of
course the lower branches of stuff are
gonna grow up so I thought that was
pretty interesting it's something
actually when I was looking at some
training websites or websites talking
about training right before you know
we're talking here today I came across
the Hat and I was curious to know if you
had ever heard of that because it's
something that I really hadn't heard
that before and I don't really know
anybody who just bends it down 90
degrees right and I be I'm sorry go
ahead but you know that is another form
of training I I would be I don't know I
like I just cuz I've never tried it you
can't knock it not in this industry but
initially I think the first been
fantastic but I feel like those under
branches still needs some sort of
attention in order to give you that
maximization or maximized potential of
the the plant now now I'll be curious
though are you bending it at three nodes
are you bending it at three feet yeah
I'd be curious because maybe at three
feet if you bend that over those those
branches are a little farther along but
I'ma be assuming pretty stretch
yeah techniques learn something every
day he's exciting okay what about super
cropping let's move on to super coughing
do you want to explain I know I've seen
that on your channel before do you want
to explain what that is do you want me
to uh yeah go ahead go ahead keep
consistent and I'll go with your your
definition ok so super cropping is
really just I guess you're kind of
breaking that outer layer of the plants
you know the what cell membrane or
whatever you want to call it and kind of
flop and making it flop over so some
people do that normally I typically do
it when it's during that three-week
stretch period and I'm having trouble
controlling the stretch or if I want to
kind of keep that canopy even in some
sense I'll go ahead and I'll just like
you were doing it right there kind of
manipulating that breaking off that
outer layer and then flopping it down
and then as the things flop down it
allows the lower branches to kind of
catch up and that thing will you know
it'll pop back up nope that branch is
gonna pop back up yeah I mean kind of a
poor definition but that's kind of no
that's really that's really it and
honestly if there is a technique that I
follow the most it's super cropping it's
it's exactly that now some some mate
might argue that it's it's just the main
branch that you're super cropping and
and and sure if that's the definition of
super cropping would be the main branch
then sure sure yeah I certainly exercise
that as well but the manipulation of the
cell membrane and someone in the
comments can tell us what that there's a
name I know it is
but anyways when you break that cell
membrane I guess it could be argued to
that that is high stress training yeah
for sure and and that is that is a
practice that I think needs to be
utilized in the garden or at least if
you want to get the numbers to which
that you're that particular seed can or
that strain can Hart harvest then super
cropping is where you're gonna get that
I feel that the manipulation of the stem
is what seriously reinforces the
structure which then supports the the
flower at the very end the bigger the
strong
that stem is the more the more dense the
speck they go hand-in-hand if you've got
limp loose light stems you're gonna have
loose light limp
flowers it's it's literally hand in hand
the stronger the plant is in veg the
stronger the plant's gonna be in flower
environment a excluded kind of thing you
know what I mean variables excluded but
super cropping is is is is the technique
that I'd like to utilize the most every
single day I come in the garden and
manipulate my my my plants during veg
and then less manipulation of it during
the stretch more of just anytime you
want to bend the stem you can't just
come into your flower room and just bend
it over you need to manipulate it now
how much you want that bent in flower I
don't want that I don't want it to lay
flat in most cases I just needed to come
down in inches rather than to come flat
so super cropping great technique and
and when I utilize almost the entirety
of the girl so I only utilize it when I
need to kind of create that even canopy
and I feel like low stirring isn't an
option anymore because maybe it's like
that Center branch in the middle and
it's like well I can't really pull it
down with the other branches I Supercop
are you saying you do super copying in
order to strengthen the stems yeah
everybody every step Wow
when I come in if you've watched a
time-lapse on my video although all the
plants start or even a training all the
plants start very high up they're all
very perky pointed to the words the
light that's when I will come in and in
in in you know I'd say it's like a 60-40
in terms of bending and twisting
I want those like once you bend those
main when you start bending your plants
you're gonna find very quickly that
there's gonna be stronger ones stronger
stems on the outside just just through
through nature itself without the
training and you're gonna have weaker
ones in the middle going through the
middle the middle branches is where I'm
exercising that technique the most to
make sure that they're gonna keep up
with the outer branches so that I'm
gonna have similar buds throughout the
entirety of the plant yeah I think yeah
I would say yes so
when do you start super coughing the
moment I'm gonna make that first Bend if
it would the moment I'm gonna bend it in
veg would be the moment I start to super
crop you're gonna start to manipulate
that stem try to I don't know if
breaking is the right way to describe it
all the time if if super cropping is the
technique of breaking the stem you know
you can hear it snapping I don't think I
do that all the time but the idea of you
know stretching that membrane and
manipulating enough that it falls over
is is more of the technique that I
follow but breaking it is just another
way of getting it done yeah so when do
you stop it then when when's the last
time you super crop really typically
like if it's going like it'll be late
veg because typically I've got by the by
the time I'm sending the flower I've
created the canopy that I bet I'm happy
with so then I'm sending it to flower
at that point when it comes to keeping
the canopy even I it's more of just a
light manipulation of the stem so I
would I would say it's still within the
first couple weeks of a flower still
still trying to make sure because like I
said by the time your flower in your
plant your stems are really thick
they're very heavy and and and and
they've they've almost built up like a
not a bark but like um just an outer
core and if you were to come up to that
that branch and just try to back to get
it to go flat with the rest of the
canopy it's gonna snap in half and
you're gonna lose it without taping it
back together so you're gonna have to
kind of kind of rub it in your fingers
just to get that that that bent that
stem to bend down a little bit so first
couple weeks of flower do you have a
tutorial video on your channel that I
can link oh yes okay I'll link
description section below for for
everybody out here so during that three
week stretch for a period and flower you
you really don't do I'm super copping no
no I wouldn't I wouldn't say to the
extent that I am in veg every day no no
okay no because I'm hoping by the time
I've sent it to flower all of the
effects that I've done in veg are enough
that those stems are good like they're
tight they're built they're robust
they're strong any any bending that goes
and flour is just merely to keep the
canopy flat all even you might even tie
down still in flour to make sure that
it's but I know I wouldn't say that I
continue super cropping in flour okay as
intense as intense there's that's as
Canadian answer as you're gonna get
right there I think I went both ways
three times and arguably I mean somebody
could could probably comment and say you
don't want to be sort of high stress
training in flour right I'm you can but
I give Lee training yeah your your plan
would then focusing on that repair
process instead of the blood formation
process so I try to avoid doing any type
of high stress training techniques like
that or topping in the flowering stage
but I do do it just to try to create
that can be even as like a lot you've
gotta do what you got to do keep that
canopy even because that's what's gonna
reward you in the long run
and I found I need to do it whenever I
do like a trellis and try to like do
like a screw to scrub technique you know
I find like during that three-week
stretch period in flower it I don't have
the chance to bend down it anymore to
get under the netting anymore so I'll
you know I'll super cry so that's just
another another time I do it anything
else on super cropping don't be afraid
don't be afraid it's another one of
those techniques as you're it's very
aggressive it's very hands-on these
plants are resilient and it's almost
it's almost the more abuse at the right
time is is he's gonna reward you they
can handle it they can handle it well I
think we've covered a lot in this video
man this was good this was a lot of fun
yeah yeah good stuff so thank you so
much pigeons for coming on to my channel
and discussing training techniques I
think that this is definitely some good
information again for the people viewing
this and I've got beginners I've got
veterans that are viewing this there's
so many different ways to do it just
experiment and yeah I just try to have
fun with it
right that's the key have fun because
there's already enough stresses let
alone though in the world there's enough
stresses in the garden that'll keep you
preoccupied we don't need to we don't
need to create any more unnecessary
stress have fun
relax and it's it's quite the experience
and anything that you experience through
this grow is going to seriously help you
in the next grill so get your hands
dirty and Chris I want to thank you for
having me as I said at the beginning
your this this this form of interview
this kind of content is is a shining
light for our community and I look
forward to seeing seeing what else and
who else you can have have over and and
the information you can pull from them
much needed and I want to hear from I
want to hear from in the comments to you
know whether you agree or disagree what
are your techniques because like I said
we've been here for almost an hour forty
some minutes but it's like we haven't
even scratched the surface we haven't
even scratched the surface in terms of
of the techniques and the numbers of
ways of getting it done so absolutely
more content for the future yep and yeah
another question if the viewers is who
would you like me to kind of have a
discussion with next right so I talked
with Rob from CL TV we've got pigeons
here I want to get more growers involved
in these types of conversations because
there's just there's so many different
perceptions on ways to do things it's
going to generate ideas for people right
so let me know who you want to see on
this channel in the future and I will
leave a link to pigeons channel down in
the description section below thank you
very much any final words no thanks for
having me a lot of fun I appreciate it
and I look forward to seeing the success
of your channel and it's been an honor
being being a colleague of yours bro
thank you I really appreciate you coming
on all right take care of him thanks
guys
[Music]
you