coming up on garden talk with the more
experience you kind of see how your
plant tries to get away from the light
like you can see the light stress with
proper experiences we're trying to say
go about 300 for seedling between three
and six hundred and veg and between six
and like 900 in flower they saved my
butt a couple times telling me about a
power outage it's not just at home where
you'll get notifications you could be
absolutely anywhere main lining is one
of my most favorite ways to grow i just
enjoy getting all that energy to the top
of the plants do your tucking until the
end of week one now that could change
obviously if you're going with like a
more sativa strain i would probably tuck
until like maybe the end of week two
like i have no one to impress either to
you you have no one to impress just
throw your herb and have fun doing it
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned in to the garden talk
podcast this episode number 52. in this
episode i interview rose of green he has
been gardening for 20 years and grows
plants such as carrots tomatoes
cucumbers and medicinal varieties in
this episode we get into lighting
environment and plant training thanks to
all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible big shout out to dutch pro
for sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is
a plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products a big
supporter of this podcast is ac infiniti
they sponsor this podcast and i use
their products ac infinity now has
gardening tools and accessories such as
heavy duty fabric grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow it during
checkout for a discount on their
products spider farmer is a sponsor of
the podcast coupon code mr growit5 will
get you a discount on their products
they're most known for their led grow
lights but they also have other products
such as grow tents inline fans and
carbon filters i've used their sf 1000
sf 2000 and sf 4000 led grill lights in
the past and i got some great results
with them i will leave a link to spider
farmers amazon store down in the
description section below and don't
forget to use coupon code mr growit5 for
discount on their products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with rose
of green how you doing today good good
how are you doing
doing good good thanks for asking today
we're going to get into a whole bunch of
things lighting we're going to get into
environment and plant training which a
lot of people say that those three
things are some of the main keys to
success in your garden right so lots of
things to talk about there
first though let's do an introduction
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening yeah so i'm from a small town
northern ontario canada
and i've been gardening since i was like
five six years old
my grandmother had a real huge area a
real huge garden where she uh grew like
flowers and plants and stuff
which she would make like bouquets and
stuff and then uh
sell them to like people who are having
weddings and funerals and just things
like that so uh
pretty much since i was just a little
one i've been in the garden uh growing
something so and now you've gotten up to
the point where you have a youtube
channel now and you're sharing your
garden with the world on the internet
you actually have almost 40 000 people
following you right 40 000 subscribers
on youtube alone i'm not sure what your
instagram numbers are any of your other
social media but you've got quite a big
following there and looking through your
videos actually have your channel open
right now on the side here you're
showing your garden all the way through
all the different growth cycles from
seedling veg flower harvest strike here
all that stuff you're covering there you
even do like q a videos and all that
stuff so i'll definitely be sure to link
that down in the description section
below for those of you tuning on youtube
so you can visit this channel and see
what he's got and subscribe to him also
if you are on one of the podcast
platforms just search his name rosa
green will come up let's start with
lighting what grow lights are you
currently using
i use uh the mars hydro fc 6500 is one
of my main lights
and then i use uh a couple of the sp
3000s and then i just put in an fc 8000
uh into one of my four by fours
uh i know i'll get a little pushback
with that people think it's overkill for
me to be running uh 8 000 watt light in
a 4x4 but i just run it dimmed at like
50 60 percent uh just because i have
that much power
uh in the tent it doesn't mean that i'm
using it all so
uh
that's that's basically what i'm using
do you say 8 000 watts or sorry 800 watt
it's all right that's good 8 000 yeah
that is an overkill
burning down the house
that's enough that's enough watts for
multiple rooms in your house right
oh yeah i'm running the manufacturer
facility there
yeah mars hydro they have some good
lights for sure yeah they've come uh
it's come a real long way like uh
honestly a few years ago i probably
wouldn't have touched them but uh over
the years they're really you can see
they're really starting to pick things
up they're uh
they're making
good quality lighting and fairly cheap
for like people getting into it and
stuff i find anyway and uh honestly i
found their customer service to get a
little bit better i am sponsored by them
so obviously i'm gonna get top of the
line customer service
but uh my subscribers i noticed are not
complaining to me about their customer
service so much anymore it's like they
step their level up a little bit and i'm
actually like
before i i wouldn't be proud to say i
was working with mars hydro and today i
could actually say i am
i am proud to be working with them like
yeah i remember their blurples back in
the day i mean 2015 14 2015 and they
were selling those lights all the way up
until like 2019 i think they still are
i'm not sure if they are but yeah yeah i
think they took them down i think they
have everything seriously yeah yeah i've
given them that feedback i'm like why
are you selling all day lights like well
they sell it's like
i noticed uh
viper spectra companies still selling
those on amazon uh the purple ones
are they really yeah they actually have
a new light though which i'm actually
getting my hands on it they're sending
me over one it's a bar style light and i
was impressed with the specs i think
actually by the time this episode is
released i don't think they're going to
have the light released so i'm not going
to talk too deep into it but they're
another company that's come a long way
in regards to the fixture like the
quality wise build of the fixture good
stuff these days for sure yeah i i've
always liked that company they do have
quality stuff like they're called
quantum boards they're all quality you
could tell that they take care of their
stuff and uh that new light you're
talking about yeah people are gonna be
uh impressed with that i got the the
download details on that thing a couple
months ago and it does sound like it's
going to be a pretty good light
that and they do have others coming on
the way to that i won't really speak of
yeah
i'm running the so i have three grow
lights right now i have a 4x4 tent where
i'm running two lights i'm running the
es 300 v3 by the green sunshine company
on one side and then the sf 2000 led
grill light by spider farmer on the
other side i personally grow you know
all different cultivars within the tent
and so
for me i personally like to run two
lights in there so i can have different
light distances as needed as some grow
taller than the other so that's what i'm
currently running and then i have a 2x4
tent which has a es180 v3 by the green
sunshine company and all those lights
i've really gotten some good results off
of but you have to run them dimmed right
there's
these grow lights these days a lot of
them are
more powerful than needed you know and
the problem is there's a lot of new
growers they want to run on the max they
think they're they're helping their
plants more when they're running them on
full power when in reality a lot of
these new lights you can dim them down
and actually run them dimmed for the
entire grow right yeah exactly like uh
that's uh that's what i i i tell people
like when people question me on the show
or on my video sorry uh they say well
what should i run my light at and i will
answer them well first i need to know
like what kind of light you have uh
because they're all so different
nowadays from the quantum style to the
bar lights uh like you might have to run
a different wattage but not only that is
they're so efficient nowadays that you
i don't even know how you would go by
gram
for water anything anymore or go by buy
per watt because they're just so
efficient you're either cranking them up
or
or you don't need to crank them up it's
either one way or the other so uh when
people ask me
uh
how do i run my light it's like check to
check the manufacturer what they
recommend
or uh do a quick google search to see uh
see if you could find your answer there
or you could just watch your plants
altogether like we used to do uh
back in the day before parameters and
stuff and uh you just watch your plant
for like your tips turning down the
talking like the light stress how your
planet is like trying to shrivel its way
it's just trying to get away from that
light uh you could see it uh with a
little bit of uh
education or something the word that i'm
trying to use uh anyway you just see it
the more you grow the more you'll see
signs of it trying to get away from the
light and stuff like that yeah it
definitely comes down to experience i
think is what you're trying to
experience
but i don't know
but uh yeah with the more experience you
kind of see how your light or how your
plant tries to get away from the light
like you can see the light stress with
proper experience that's what i'm trying
to say yeah
so the light energy coming down is
photons you know a lot of people refer
to as kind of like pictured as balls of
energy coming down like rain onto your
plant right you you increase the amount
of density increasing amount of rain or
photons that's coming down onto the
plant now people refer to that you know
par photosynthetically active radiation
are you aiming for a specific amount of
par or dli
yeah uh
dli i i truly i typically try to run
around uh 40 dli at all times but uh
what i'm again when i'm trying to
explain it to new growers and stuff i'll
i'll be a little more uh
lenient with my words and i'll tell them
like go about 300 for uh seedling
between three and six hundred and veg
and uh between six and like 900 in
flower um i try to stay away from
telling them hey crank it to uh 1250 and
flower because i don't want to see
anybody burn their plants up
honestly if you're seeing like uh
deficiencies or
or something like that chances are it's
too much light you're giving them so
much light that they're trying to take
up their nutrients more so then you're
getting that burn
so uh yeah i try to just
be a little more lenient with
the ppfd levels that i tell people to
use but for myself yeah i'm around a dli
of around 40. sometimes i will push it
depending on strain uh ambient co2 is
usually around four or five hundred but
i'm in my house it's usually around 750
so uh i'll be able to play around with
my uh ppfd a little bit sometimes i'll
get it up to around 1200 uh 1250 but for
the most part i'm maxed out around 10.50
in flower i think there's some good
general ranges that you mentioned before
for for beginners or somebody who isn't
quite aware of it because that'll
that'll help you kind of kind of like in
safe ranges i'd say exactly not a lot of
folks they're not going to have the par
meter in order to kind of measure it
right you could you go and buy one of
these par meters apogee has ones there's
a spot on par meter there's several
different measurement tools now that you
can use to measure the amount of par
that that your light puts out and then
you kind of adjust your light distance
that way if you don't have one of those
and you don't want to spend the money on
one of those you could always what i
usually tell folks is
check out the park chart that the
manufacturer puts on the grow light
listing right so usually you know most
companies i think just about every
company now is putting a par chart on
there it's going to be basically an
overview snapshot
of the different part numbers in ppfd
that shows you at the different like
distances so you kind of refer to that
chart and then adjust your light
distance that way i think that's that's
usually what i tell folks that are
beginning but yeah those ranges you
mentioned are pretty spot on in my
opinion i know you have the pulse pro
how do you like that i do i've actually
i got four of them and uh i like them
quite a bit i uh
i'll be a little honest with you i did
start off using them for uh vpd but
without having a sealed room it's so
difficult to keep that vpd
day in day out
right head on uh hitting the nail on the
head type deal it's hard to do without a
sealed room so i just keep it as close
as i can to the vpd and i go from there
but uh they're a real cool unit like uh
now you could actually get a
somewhat basic ppfd reading with them
that's awesome you can see your spectrum
uh most leds are going full spectrum
nowadays anyway
uh but uh yeah i i really like them they
saved my butt a couple times telling me
about a power outage so uh it's not just
at home where you'll get notifications
you could be absolutely anywhere i could
be across the country
or and or in a different country and
still be able to get that reading so
uh not to uh
totally try to advertise for them but uh
they are a real awesome unit
uh i find anyway yeah i was curious
about the pulse pro in particular
because it does have co2 readings and
also has the the par meter on it built
in
you know so you can check what the par
is and adjust your light distance
according to that now some people might
get sticker shock once they see that the
price is five hundred dollars right sure
you know and i had sticker shock at
first
but you know somebody commented on one
of my videos and like think about it
though right you're getting a par meter
within it
you know that alone the apogee sells for
like 525 alone so you're getting a par
meter you're getting the co2
measurements obviously the temperature
and humidity and you're getting the the
ability to have it sent to your
smartphone if something's out of range
right so you're getting those
notifications when needed if things are
out of range i have the pulse one
need to get the pulse pro i think i
think that's my next one of my next
purchases for sure yeah they're pretty
cool and uh yeah you touch on the price
of like a
parameter well that's the same thing for
like a co2 meter a good co2 meter you're
not finding under 100 bucks for like a
good one you know
so
yeah
actually the price isn't bad if you
actually think about everything that's
in it it would be nice to see them
cheaper but
it is what it is right yep
so what temperature do you typically aim
for
uh
so in veg i'll usually be around uh 28
degrees celsius i think that's like 82
83 maybe fahrenheit
and veg i'm usually around there and
then as i get into flour i like to cool
things down a bit i'll i'll usually run
around 25 degrees during the day maybe
22 degrees at night
and that's the same thing for veg at
night i go down to about 24 degrees
celsius so
when i talk i'm talking in celsius
and yeah anyway i find in flour uh it's
better off to go by like how true nature
uh goes it usually cools down in the
fall so uh not only that i find it
tightens up your buds and stuff if you
run it a little cooler in flower
i'm not sure if you notice that but it's
just something that i picked up on over
the years
and uh yeah so i always try to run a
little cooler and flour and uh warmer
and veg you bring up a really really
good point as far as the increased
temperatures and veg and then reducing
it in flour what so first off i need to
have a uh i need to learn celsius
because i
i'm stuck in the the freedom units as uh
as uh pigeons often calls it yeah maybe
if i have a key right here i can see
okay if he's talking this this is that
you know and it's like quickly refer to
it i usually aim for you know around 80
82 degrees fahrenheit in the vegetation
stage and oftentimes i'm running that
throughout flowering now i'm currently
in school a lot of people know that i'm
in school for cultivation and one of the
studies that was brought to my attention
through this school
is that they studied the optimal
temperature what is the opportunity
temperature and they're doing pretty
much what you're doing they're seeing
that high increased photosynthesis with
the higher temps you know assuming that
the vpd is dialed in co2 is dialed in
right so they're going after the high
photosynthesis during veg a little bit
into flower as well however towards the
end of flower they're finding a if you
stay at that high temps they're seeing
that more area blood structure
foxtelling can potentially occur and
also loss of terpenes they're
evaporating so their recommendation what
they found in the study is that if
you're lowering in those temps a little
bit towards the end of flowering maybe
weeks five six and beyond i'm just
gradually lowering them you can conserve
some of those terpenes and it should
result in more tighter uh bud sites like
you had mentioned that that you often
see now of course that's going to depend
on genetics and stuff like that but i
thought i was worthy mentioning here
because uh something i learned recently
so now how about uh relative humidity
what are you typically aiming for there
i uh in veg i try to shoot for 65. but
it's hard to get that here in the winter
even using like
a humidifier so i always try to keep it
around at least 50 to 65 in uh veg
sometimes i can't always get there and
it's somewhere around 45 and i just got
the humidifiers pumped but uh for the
most part if it is around 55 i'm happy
and then in flower i shoot for around 50
percent so uh 50 of flour just seems to
it's always worked for me i've done it
like that for a few years now and uh
uh
it's what i prefer gotcha so there are
some general ranges that folks stick by
you know there's a lot of you know if
you're a bare bones beginner just
starting out you just want to get
through your grow
40 to 60 is kind of the general range
that the plant is going to grow it's
going to be fine you're going to get a
yield out of it right but dialing things
in which is kind of what we're talking
about here you know vpd you know we
talked about that a little while ago
right so
when your temperature changes according
to vpd your humidity should kind of
change as well right it should kind of
change with it really comes down to the
stomata opening and being able to to
intake that co2
specific rate right so i personally do
aim for
vpd i find that i can actually naturally
fall within that range just by the way
my room is set up so
oftentimes when i'm running that 80 82
degrees i think vpd calls for
turning remember off top my head
like 55 to 60 something 62 percent or
something like that and of course
see the confusing thing is there's so
many different vpd charts online so if
you were to search vpd chart you would
get so many different results i think a
lot of people go after pulse
their reference guides but then there's
different guides according to
the difference in leaf surface
temperature which makes things even more
confusing so
generally speaking usually it's like
minus one degree on the leaf surface
temperature so what your canopy
temperature is for example
your leaf surface temperature is usually
you know one degree less now lighting is
going to turn in is going to be an
impact of that right if you're hid
lighting you're going to have the ir
come down and heat those leaves a little
bit more than led so there is just so
many variables when it comes to humidity
in my opinion you know but yeah general
ranges are certainly these general
ranges that folks can go by just to get
to the grow right
yep so do you supplement co2 at all
uh no i uh
i used to do like uh the own
uh i would make my own like milk jugs
full of uh
uh
the sugar and yeast and try and do co2
like that and uh honestly that would
work if i didn't use an exhaust van if i
was able to keep it cool enough
inside a tent with an air conditioner
and not exhausted out it would work but
if you're running any sort of exhaust
fan even just into a lung room it it
really doesn't help all that much you
really need to get that bottle hooked up
if you want to take the advantage of co2
i find uh even with um i don't want to
throw them under the bus or anything but
like the tnb naturals
i really don't find that works it's
basically the same thing that i made if
you're doing any exhausting at all
you're not going to get any benefits
from that
whatsoever i've tried it all i've had a
bunch of co2 meters
that i purchased to try it all
i wish i made more videos on it to tell
you the truth uh just so some people
weren't wasting their money on things
um because as soon as that fan comes on
you're pretty much euchred uh you lose
that co2
i agree i mean if you're exhausting you
know 24 7 like some people have their
airline fans on the entire time i do use
the tnb naturals i do have the canister
for tme naturals i've have a co2 monitor
as well which i've taken measurements
and it's built up past 1000 at some
points you know what i mean but i wasn't
exhausting 24 7. i was doing
intermittent exhausting right so i have
the ac infinity inline fan which is
hooked up to controller and i have set
points you know so if it goes over a
certain temperature it'll kick on
remove that hot air and then it will
turn off and same thing with humidity if
humidity rises too high
reaches that set point it'll turn off
and then
turn on exhaust and then turn off when
when it's below that set point so i feel
like in that case you can definitely get
away with like the co2 canisters and
stuff i also have the exhale 365 bags i
just started using that last month
and things are working out pretty good
so far with that the whole thing got
inoculated within a couple weeks so i
was a little bit surprised on that one
it's my first time using it but i
haven't done the co2 measurements on
that just yet but i do know a lot of
people that are running those with
success and they mentioned that they're
they're increasing their co2 levels
quite a bit with the bags and also with
the canisters but yeah i agree if you're
exhausting 24 7
probably don't want to spend the money
on co2 since that's probably just being
sucked out to grow space yeah
yeah exactly so exactly if you got your
fan off why not right and i haven't even
tried out those mushroom bags yet so uh
that might be something i try next just
to give it a shot see how it works
for sure for sure now what are you doing
for like air circulation and air
exchange oh i'm i'm hooked on ac
infinity everything pretty much so yeah
i i got their new fans early uh i don't
think the other ones come out until like
april or march or something
they do have fans on their website now
but that is just for the non-oscillating
ones
but what i do mostly is i run uh the ac
infinity fans or any other six inch fan
i used to have i'll typically have three
in each four by four tent uh i'll have
one like on the floor and then i'll have
one on a close pole to me and then one
on a fire pole i always like to tell
people
that uh airflow is key it's i cannot
praise that enough uh you want good air
flow you want air blowing around and
then i use of course uh the six inch
exhaust fan uh that i always change my
air in my tent uh when it's on the off
setting it's really at about two
the number two setting so it's always a
bit of airflow and uh it's usually up
around eight percent uh or setting
number eight uh exhausting during the
day in order to keep that temperature
down and flower or i could go to like
the sixth setting in veg or something
but uh for the most part i use ac
infinity uh everything for my indoor
indoor grow
i can't even say they've really come a
long way because they've always been
uh pretty much top-notch right like
they're fans it seems like everything
that they put out is just uh they're
hitting the nail on the head so yeah i
completely agree they've definitely
changed the game quite a bit uh you know
when it comes to their fans i mean that
was a major game changer with it hooked
up to the controller they didn't have
set points you know for temperature and
humidity now they've got that
oscillating fan that you mentioned i
told them because i i work with them too
i said send me over four of them so i
got four of them now
and i've been using those and my i like
to put at least two per grow tent in
case one were to die out because i've
had that happen before where i had one
of my inline fans die and i only had one
in the tent at the time so there was all
that stagnant air and it led to bud rot
and i had to throw away some colas that
encountered bud ra which was a freaking
disaster that's on my channel people can
can watch that and laugh at me there but
yeah ac infinity i i do the same thing
with
trying to get air flow below the plants
and also try to get air flow above the
plants as well kind of like through the
canopy i feel like it'll kind of work
its way down below the plants up through
the canopy and then of course if your
inline fan conducting is connected to
like the top part well then you're
you're getting that exhaust there and of
course having the rectangle intake vents
open like on your if you're using guru
tent for example is certainly key right
let's get into plant training next um so
what do you typically do for plant
training do you do anything like topping
lst super cropping anything like that
yeah i uh
i do a lot of main lining so i obviously
i do a lot of topping and uh
bending and low stress training so
uh main lining is one of my most
favorite ways to grow
so
so yeah i i just enjoy getting all that
energy to the top of the plants and uh
just dealing with uh big buds and colas
instead of little popcorn buds
and stuff so uh pretty much uh
any video you see of mine i will have a
mainline plant uh either here or there
uh in one of my tents but uh
but yeah anyway uh basically i i do it
all uh some some super cropping i will
do depending on uh if i get a a branch
maybe two too long that i wanna flatten
out the canopy or something i might
super crop or on my outdoor i will do
some super cropping i actually super
crop a couple of them real hard
last spring
and just to make all the other tops come
up so
i basically do it all when it comes to
training can you explain the main lining
process in more detail for those that
don't know what it is i mean from my
understanding you're letting it grow to
a certain node then you're topping then
you're letting those ones grow to a
certain node then you're topping again
can you explain in detail like how you
go about doing the main lining process
yeah so uh basically uh it's what you
just said you let it grow up to like uh
maybe the fourth node um you want your
plant to be like eight inches tall and
then you take off like uh four inches
right away or something you take it down
to like the fourth node you don't have
to do it that way you do lose a little
bit of bench time that way but i really
prefer to do that so that you get
stronger branching but once you top it
the first time
you top it you spread those branches
apart a little bit and then you remove
all the other bottom branches so then
you got your two mains coming out like
that
so then your next time you top these two
mains so you do uh two toppings you top
one on your right right on your left and
then uh
so then you got your four tops and four
mains coming off that with everything
else below removed so uh
then you would top your third time so
then you get eight tops so every time
you top you're pretty much doubling your
tops the amount of tops you have
uh i typically stop around eight
i am going to be doing one on this next
series i'm going to be doing one plant
to uh 16 tops
but um you would go uh like uh two tops
four tops eight tops
16 32
64.
there was one person who commented on my
uh channel saying that they did 120
some tops 128 tops so i wanted him to
send me pictures but he didn't reply
back to me after i replied to him so i
was interested in seeing that
would have been quite wild so
uh picking that up i might actually do
that this spring on an outdoor plant i
might do one with a ridiculous amount of
tops
but uh
sorry for the short version of how you
main line it's basically what you do is
you continue to top until you get as
many tops as you want
and then uh
anyway when you mainline
like i said before all of your
bud focuses to the top and
us instead of a bunch of branches
everywhere yeah because you're still
kind of doing that lollipop technique
where you're taking off the lower third
or lower fourth some people do and then
that helps focus it on top i think
mainlining the theory behind it
is that and i don't think anybody can
prove this
is that if you have equal distance
from the stock
to the colas then it's evenly
transporting nutrients up to the
branches right so like
if you look at the main line how it's
actually done all the branches are are
even right the the same exact distance
to where your colors start right i did a
little bit of a variation of main lining
basically what i did was i let it grow
to the fifth node
top down to the third node
left the second node branching
and removed i think i removed the first
node branching so basically right off
the bat i was able to have four branches
right off the bat you know now they're
not evenly branched the branches aren't
evenly distributed or whatever you want
to call it like but i found like it was
a little bit of a shortcut to the main
lining process and then i did do a top
so it's eight eight tops or eight main
colas
16 main colas topped again 32 bank colas
so 32 was the most i ever done
i personally felt like it was a little
bit of overkill for my situation because
i was trying to keep the plant at two
foot by two foot space so having 32 tops
on a plant i think i was in a three
gallon container too i felt like you
know i didn't get much of a stretch once
flipping over the flowers the plant was
small and you know because when you top
and you have all these different
branches
when you do that flip to flower and it
starts that stretching period well you
don't just have a few branches stretch
you have more branches stretching so
you're not really going to get as much
of a stretch most of the time right
generally speaking but yeah eight main
tops is typically what i go for
sometimes 16 main tops for me kind of
growing each plant a two foot by two
foot space so that's what i found works
well for me but i feel like there are so
many different ways to kind of go about
it and i always tell people to
experiment right try things out see what
you can do have fun with it so yeah
that's the thing with it right like uh
mainlining it puts you
you're so much hands on and i really
like uh i really enjoy training plants
and uh growing the plants it's not just
all about yield or how fast i could turn
over a grow it's like i enjoy the
training and doing what i do it's like i
don't want to rush it and get it all
knocked out in a couple weeks like uh i
will get a lot of people will comment to
be like oh that takes way too long it's
like in all reality uh main lining only
adds a week on to what i regular veg
anyway so like i regularly veg about
five weeks uh i'll go six weeks with the
main line right like it doesn't add all
that much more time
but uh it's what i enjoy to do if i
wanted to just knock them out of the
park i would just fill the tent with uh
six plants uh every time i grew and do
no training and just grow them fast
right
so
uh yeah being hands-on with your plants
is one of the most uh fun ways to do it
i find so that's what i'll continue to
do absolutely
i've seen you had some amazing success
with the scrub technique can you explain
your process there
yeah i got i've done a couple scrogs i
think this is one of the first ones i've
ever actually done on my channel
but uh
for the most part
i would have enjoyed to start off with
like two plants but i didn't know until
later on that i was going to be doing a
scrog so i did it with four plants kind
of happy i did that anyway because it
filled the canopy a little bit more
but i went from seed so it was up in the
air of like what kind of phenols i was
gonna get so i was a little worried
about that
but i ended up making it work
what i'll do is for hybrid strains i
will just keep tucking my branches under
uh i don't usually weave my branches
through because it's a to harvest
oh sorry what my language are but that's
all good painting
harvest that so what i'll do is i'll
just tuck all the branches right
underneath and they're all pushing up on
the scrog so then they gain their
support that way so uh then you just end
up with a bunch of tops
and uh you'll be good to go i'm in week
five now so if there's anyone interested
in seeing how
good scraw goes uh feel free to go check
out my channel because i'm just in week
five now we still have a few weeks of
that left to go
uh for most viewers it's the most
exciting part because we're starting to
put on all the bud
so uh that's uh it's bitties by soulfire
gardens and it's a real nice strain with
a real potent smell to it i'm really
excited about
so follow up question i have for you is
like some people swear that you should
do one top first and then it allows the
lower branches to come out and then
spread into that scrub net a little bit
easier and then also some people swear
by a certain height from the grow pot
then that should be a certain height
above that do you do a topping and then
what is your distance from grill pot to
net yeah uh you're right there uh i like
to leave a distance about a foot
so i'll get my plants to grow about a
foot and then i'll toss toss them
underneath the scrog or i'll put the
scrog down and then i'll start to train
from there
really doesn't look like you're getting
much out of it the first couple weeks it
just looks like a plant bent over but
it seems to be one of my
a better way to do it
and uh so i'm just trying to remember
the second part to your question
oh no i don't talk so uh no i don't uh
i didn't top this time anyway uh next
time maybe i will i switch it up here
and there but for the most part no i
just bent it over let all those branches
come up and then uh continue to bend
them over and underneath uh the scrog
okay
and then when actually went to your i
saw this on your instagram is that
you're using
not your traditional scrub net it looks
like it's like a clear plastic and
they're not actually squares can you
talk to us about what you're using there
yeah i found that online so uh
usually when i use like scrog netting
i can't even say usually because i don't
do it all that often really to tell you
truth i've done it a few times now but
uh usually i want like uh smaller
squares i find it's easier to train with
like smaller squares like three inch
squares
uh so what i was doing is i was looking
for something that i could hook up to my
uh
gorilla grow tent the high cfm kit
i don't know if you know those bars that
go across in your uh
tent that helps for the sectional sides
anyway i was looking for uh i was
looking for a scrog to attach that and i
came across that other scroll online uh
it's called the p-scrog i forget the
name of the website but uh that's what
i'm using there now
and uh that's the plastic one i'm real
happy with that it came with like uh the
poles and uh it was easy to put together
reusable washable and i don't have to
worry about uh
trying to untangle a messy net
gotcha and then are you just doing one
net or some people do like two layers
some people do three layers
yeah so that's what i i do right like uh
i just do the one layer because what
i'll do is i will uh
i'll tuck until
up to uh the first week of flowers over
so that that's enough stability when
those all those tops come up and put
your buds there you're gonna get nice
sized colas they're gonna end up far
away from away from your light
i don't know i just find it ends up
perfect if you do your talking until the
end of week one now that could change
obviously if you're going with like a
more sativa strain i would probably tuck
until like maybe the end of week two uh
really i would just watch that plant and
see how it starts out stretching since i
flip it from 1212 and i would just judge
it from there but for the most part for
like your indicas and your hybrids
i suggest training them keep tucking
them until your first week of flower is
over
and then you won't need that second
screen to support your buds okay that's
good to know
how about defoliation you know a lot of
people group this in
to plant training
some people call it pruning method right
do you do any sort of defoliation if so
what's your process for that
so yeah if i'm uh if i'm just growing my
plants normally say give them one
topping or whatever i will do uh i'll do
a good default maybe around a week
four and a half five of uh veg just to
keep all the airflow going make sure
that all the bud sites and uh
branches are gonna get light to them
mostly for air flow i'm all about the
airflow
and then yeah so uh later on in flower
about week three i will do another heavy
default depending on how i grew them
with the main lines you don't really
need a default all that much because
you're defauling as you go
but uh but yeah when i do a default i
sometimes i'll strip them right down uh
depending on like the cultivar or i'll
uh i'll be a little more easier on and
then just select which ones i want uh
with autos i will tuck most of time and
just do selective defoliation i don't
like to go real crazy with autos
i learned my lesson with them a couple
times from going too hard on them so for
the most part i'll just tuck and
remove the ones that absolutely need to
be moved
uh then sorry for uh then for in flower
on photo periods like i said i'll do a
strip in like week three
but continuing out in flower all i'll do
then is i'll just uh again i'll select
uh certain leaves that are blocking bud
sites that i'll remove the rest of the
way through flour and now you mentioned
super cropping you do that sometimes
when did you say that you typically do
it uh well i i don't do it all that
often but i will do it like if i get a
branch getting out of hand getting
taller than the other ones then i'll
super crop it just to bring it down and
have it with uh
flat note the canopy or on my outdoor
grows uh
when i'm starting out outdoors sometimes
i'll just give it a hardcore super crop
break that thing right in half we'll
bend it right in half
so that all the other bottom branches
come up to uh start filling
start filling like the fencing that i
put around my plants
outdoors so
sometimes i do it sometimes i won't
again it just depends
yeah i think the only time i really do
super cropping is when
you know i've flipped the plants to
flowering and i'm having trouble
controlling the stretch right because
some of these phenos they're just going
to stretch
way beyond your expectation right i had
a phenol frozen fuel
by squealing genetics shut off thc titan
it stretched three times the amount
it was in vegetation stage so i was like
blown away i almost ran out of height
and yeah that in particular if i was
running out of height or you know maybe
i'm doing the scrub technique or
whatever and some branches are higher
than others that's when i'll do the
super cropping technique for the most
part i know pigeons he does super
cropping he swears by this
every single one of his branches and
when they're small and he swears by it
and he has a lot of success doing that
so it's something i haven't tried yet
but i've been wanting to try i think
maybe this round next time around i'm
gonna have to try to super drop every
every branch and see if it can build up
some strength see if it actually does
work or not yeah i find if uh with your
branches if you like mess around with
them right make them feel like they're
out in nature
uh bend them around and stuff just to
strengthen them up i find that beefs
them up a bit that and some good silica
but i've never super cropped every
single branch no
yeah it's definitely a unique technique
that's for sure yeah he's always had a
pretty unique way of growing like his
training's always been pretty heavy
ever since like i started watching him
maybe like four years ago
uh
yeah he's always uh he always did some
real heavy training i know that lost a
lot of those videos were lost i think
when he lost his channel
but uh yeah he used to have a real lot
of uh good training episodes on there so
we covered a lot in this episode you
know we went over lighting went over
environment we went over plant training
what advice do you have for new growers
and we went over so much information
there are some folks that are brand new
that just starting that might consider
this
overwhelming to hear this type of
information
a lot of people just want to keep it
simple
what advice do you have for people who
are just starting out
have fun with it don't let it stress you
out at all uh and if you plan on
starting like a youtube channel don't
stress about that either like uh your
subscribers will come but uh for the
most part do not stress about growing
it's all gonna come with you uh watch a
lot of videos uh try to only like do one
thing at a time
uh don't try to uh
show a master gardener or have a master
garden try to like grow that one plant
first see how you can do with that and
then upscale i say start with the basics
get a
a good light is always key of course uh
then you could need some fans and stuff
but just start with the basics uh start
with like a basic nutrient line as well
and uh just take it easy don't get
stressed out don't get mad at yourself
and uh you're not growing to impress
anyone else it's another thing i try to
tell people like i have no one to
impress either to you you have no one to
impress just throw your herb and have
fun doing it well said
well said for sure so wrapping things up
how can listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future i uh
well i have my youtube channel rose of
green that's my main one then i have a
backup channel uh it's more or less of a
it's called rog growtek uh it's where i
show off like lights and fans i just do
reviews of products on there
and then of course i have my instagram
rose of green 420
and uh something new that i'm doing is
uh
i've been dabbling in the breeding for
the last couple years and uh i'm going
to be releasing a strain here shortly in
the next
month or so
it's called rewind it's a cross of uh
granddaddy purple and og kush breath
so uh you can check that out uh go to
just follow my channel along and i'll
show you where you can find them because
i can't really spit it out on here
without uh youtube getting angry
that cultivar you mentioned is it a f1
f2
3 what is it so i brought it to enough
too
i
i found a really nice granddaddy purple
a couple years ago so i've used that in
a couple of good crosses
uh and then i found a real nice og kush
breath so i made the cross there
and then uh again i found a couple nice
sister and brother so i turned it into
an f2 and then i just made uh the
feminized version of it i made some s1
so i'm going to be releasing the regular
seeds and the feminized seeds together
awesome good stuff there
well i will definitely have a link to
rose of green channel down in the
description section below if you're
watching on youtube of course if you're
on one of the podcast platforms just
search his name rosa green it'll pop up
first thing right off the bat if you
enjoyed this video click that thumbs up
button
if you haven't already subscribe to the
channel i release these card and talk
episodes every single week and if you're
on one of the podcast platforms
particularly apple podcasts please leave
a rating and review we're coming up i
think we're so close to getting 200
ratings and reviews so if you're on
apple podcast please take a minute let's
reach that goal of 200. i would greatly
appreciate it
well this was awesome this was really
really fun talk we covered a lot thank
you for your time today this is this is
cool hey man i appreciate you asking me
to come on this is uh my first uh
first interview or uh working with any
other uh
influencer so it's kind of cool to even
come on in the first place so i want to
thank you for that
yeah no problem well i will leave it at
that and i hope you enjoy the rest of
your day peace out everyone
[Music]
you