welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into the
garden Talk podcast this episode number
147 in this episode I interview autopot
he has been gardening for 6 years and is
well known for growing massive Auto
flower plants some yielding well over a
pound and that's what we're going to get
into in today's episode I pick his brain
to find out exactly what he does in
order to grow these massive Autos if you
want to see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said I
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make that goal
possible thanks DEC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode
check out their ion frame LED grill
lights which have the latest Samsung Evo
LEDs these grill lights include a
schedule controller that features 10
brightness levels dimming and a sunrise
sunset feature click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their ion frame LED
grow lights and the discount code Mr
Grow 15 works on both Amazon and their
website AC infinity.com stash blend
stash blend consists of several
ingredients in one so you know no longer
have to buy individual bottles it
includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash spider farmer
check out their new dehumidifier it's
equipped with duct design for grow tents
sensor probes Monitor and display
real-time humidity levels with
adjustable Target settings it has a
built-in drainage pipe for continuous
drainage adjustable speeds 12-hour
customized timing function and a
security protection lock more
information is linked in the description
section below and discount code Mr Grow
5 works on both Amazon and the website
spider-
far.com and we are back and I'm joined
with Lynn from autopot how you doing
today pretty good pretty good how are
you doing pretty good thanks for coming
on to the podcast today today we're
going to talk all about growing Auto
flowers and if anybody's been to your
Instagram before they know you've grow
some massive Auto flowers and uh I
actually had at least one person I think
it was more than one person reach out to
me like you got to get him on the
podcast we've got to find out what he's
doing to these Auto flowers because they
are just massive and uh I can't wait to
pick your brain a little bit and find
out how you do things but first can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yeah
absolutely my name is Lyn um you know I
started growing plants six years ago so
since uh Canada legalized it was always
a dream of mine uh to be able to uh grow
my own plants so um six years of
experience you know and I I've tried a
bunch of stuff but what I'm doing right
now seems to work really well um what
else can I say yeah so ly I'm based in
uh Yellow Knife which is in Northern
Canada and um you know I like to I like
to show some tidbits photos and videos
from from life up here because it's a
really small population very big
territory so it's kind of nice to be
able to have a platform to also show
some stuff that we do up North that's so
cool yeah when we linked up before
actually recording we kind of want to
meet first do a little face meet he
talked about the Northwest Territory and
it instantly reminded me of the show
alone and I was actually wearing the
shirt at the time and you said you were
familiar with it is they go up there and
there's a whole bunch of people they
drop off like 10 people in the middle of
nowhere and they got to survive it out
and uh watching that show they're
catching these massive fish and I look
at your Instagram you've got these
massive fish that you catch so it is
exciting I would love to do that
sometime yeah the alone show I think I
want to say there's two or maybe three
seasons that were filmed up here and
actually um on the same Lake that we
live on it's just on a different arm on
the East arm of it and I've flown on top
of the location of where it was filmed
because as part of my work I you know
sometimes take a lot of helicopters and
planes and stuff like that and working
with these helicopter Pilots they're
like yeah like we were working on the
show and this is where one guy was
dropped off and this other guy was over
here so it is literally the same Blake
and as you know there's giant fish out
there it's insane that's incredible yeah
it's my dream to actually go out and and
catch a fish like that I mean 20 30
Pounders like that's that's insane
that's really really cool record lake
trout like I think the the record the
ultimate record was conette up here like
65 pounds something like that insane
looking fish that's incredible that's
incredible yeah I'm a huge fan of the
show I watched every season except for I
still need to watch the alone Australia
and then there's alone UK I need to
watch those ones but uh no it was really
cool to see that you've been up there
you live up there yes and uh it's it's a
whole different environment up there
really yeah yeah this town has uh I want
to say 20,000 people but it's very
transient you know people come and go uh
they come with a three four five years
plan sometimes they leave sometimes they
say like me I've been here for 14 years
now I'm originally from uh Montreal
Quebec which is like in Eastern Canada
but it's been yeah close to 15 years
that I've been up here it's been it's
been a good time I gota ask where did
your name come from autopot that's a
cool name yeah you know I I started
posting um some of the plants some of
the some of the plants that I was
growing on Reddit and then people are
like man these plants are huge so I'm
like yeah I think you're right just
looking around on the subreddit like a
the flowers and be like yeah like my
plants are are significant like what's
going on so then I decided to uh post my
girls on Instagram and uh I can't do
what I do without this watering system
called autopot so in my mind
you know I had to come with a really
good handle um it took me about I want
to say like five days I was browsing
different names and stuff like that and
then I'm like autopot autopot what ends
with autopot that people can like
remember right so I'm like aut autopot
amus that's a good one because uh the
hippo hippopotamus is is an aquatic
animal it lives in the water and the
autopod is a bottom wicking system which
is basically Hydroponics you know so I'm
like man those two together would be
awesome and then there's the word Auto
for like automatic autoflowering and
there's the word p so it all it all
worked out together and then I came up
with the Zan helped me design the logo
so it all worked out yeah that's clever
clever and easy to remember I really
like that name that's what I was going
for but it took about five days of
brainstorming with my friends with
myself and then I thought it was a good
one it was a catchy one you know yeah
for sure so getting into autoflowers I
think appropriate where to begin is
genetics genetics genetics yeah start
off with bad genetics you could have a
bad result right start off with good
genetics well your chances of having a
good result is a lot higher what are
some of the biggest yielding autof
flowers that you've grown and are there
any specific strains that you recommend
to get big yields so I'll talk I'll talk
out of experience because obviously you
know I can only grow so many plants at
once um so I'll talk out of experience
so my biggest yielder plant so far were
from three breeders so we got Mesto we
got a night ow by Jazz and then speedrun
with Ben um so my latest run which
harvested in uh January that was a
26.6 ounce Auto
Autoflower so and then the second would
be a 21 a half Ripley OG by Mesto and a
19 o plant by Nal again which was the
purple straw
popsicle so yeah they're all over a
pound and I seem to be able to reproduce
that pretty much every grow now I have
one uh ongoing right now which should be
over a pound as well so pound a oflow is
not Out Of Reach for most of everyone as
long as they know what they're doing 10
15 years ago it was out of the reach but
I think the genetics have been uh bred
to get higher yields so was the
26.6 O plant that you had was that the
largest yield bu one you've ever had
yeah yeah 26.6 I that was just last run
so I haven't I haven't beat that yet no
it's an incredible plant she was close
to six feet tall and four plants in a
5x5 and she was busting out of the it
was really really big plants yeah and
it's uh I don't use a trellis I probably
should I like to have my plants mobile
cuz I pick them up I bring them outside
for
defoliation uh to remove some some stems
that kind of stuff uh to take some
photos if I put a trailers if everything
is more immobile in the T then right so
I can't do what I want to do but at this
point in time I think it could be it
could be a good idea understood let's
get deeper into the equipment you use I
know you're growing indoors can you
describe the equipment setup that you
have in your indoor garden yeah I
mean it's really similar I'm going to
say to what everyone uses some people
use some higher Tech
equipment than me you know I'm sure
you're aware of those AC Infinity tents
that everything is you plug it in and it
adjusts the VPD the relative humidity
the temperature for you almost if you if
you have the
hardware I don't do that I'm uh I'm
analog I have uh sensors um at canopy
level that tells me what the temperature
and the relative humidity is but then I
also run a dehumidifier and a humidifier
depending on what my VPD tells me to do
uh for the most part but everything is
uh I do everything by hand I just look
at my data and I'll adjust it um and
then the autopot obviously is a big part
of my grow and I've used um I want to
say most of their system you know so I'm
I'm I'm an affiliate with them so they
they do help me out with some of the
equipment so I do run the 3.9 gallon
plastic I ran um
fabric pots as well and then the bigger
6.6 gallon plastic so they have
different sizes for um most of the time
the substrate that you're willing to use
with it and also fans everybody got fans
and I have multiple lights man like I've
learned the hard way I went from you
know Mars Hydro blurple I had t5s you
know I have uh the CMH uh 315 and now I
run LEDs but but uh some of these were
sponsored and some I bought out of
pocket so I still use the hlg qb96
there's are old school uh do-it-yourself
type lights that you assemble yourself
it was meant for like to do-it-yourself
crowd but I don't think it it it took on
all that much but it's a great light I
use four of those and it shoots on Max
probably like 650 watts and I still use
those lights up to now uh cuz they're so
small so I can really use one up to four
lights depending on the wattage I'm
looking for
but in the big 5x5 it's a photon Tech um
XD 1,00 watt I don't run it on Max
that's uh that's too much for a 5x5 so
at the most I'll use 750 watt for the
5x5 okay and so for the 4 hld DIY and
the photon Tech you have in your other
tent do you have like a par meter are
you like measuring the amount of light
that the plant is receiving or just kind
of going off of kind of the
manufacturer's recommendation
um I want to say I used to I don't have
a par meter everyone think it's really
crazy I have a photon meter um I think
it's Dr Dr Meen Dr Meter sorry and uh on
the hlg website way back then you there
was a calculation you could do to divide
um the Lux that came out of it divided
by 66 and it gave you an approximate
ppfd so I did do that for a while but
now that I know my grow and my my grow
tent and grow area so well I don't
really measure
anymore and I know it sounds crazy
people ask me all the time like hey
what's your ppfd targets what's your da
I'm like I don't I don't really do that
anymore but I I used to you know I I
went deep into it like looking into all
the information for ppfd DLI Lux all
that stuff you know and it's really
confusing I'll be honest for a lot of
people that start looking into the light
metrics extremely confusing stuff right
but I did do it yeah yeah that can be uh
super confusing to uh look at all the
numbers and not really know what you're
doing especially for a folk somebody who
is newer I know some people who reach
out to me all the time with questions on
lighting but uh yeah I guess it is a
little surprising it probably is a
little surprising for some people to
hear that you're not really dialing the
lights since you're having these massive
yields you know what I mean the how
about CO2 are you adding in CO2 that's
another thing that people add in order
to try to get a higher yield are you
supplementing CO2 at all or no typically
I am not though I have tried it and you
know what funny enough um now that you
mentioned that my previous girl with
like record level yield um I was
implementing
C2 typically am not I had a mother earth
uh bucket that's connected to a fan and
I would shoot see through at the bottom
and as the air gets sucked by my exhaust
fan it would climb up through the plants
right some people do the up down like
they have like those little um fungus
bags I don't know what they're called
and then they put it above the canopy
but this uh this bucket it was right on
the floor and it would it would it would
exhaust CO2 and I had like a I have a
CO2 meter so it actually did work but I
think it's only good for like uh six
months so I ran out and I I don't have
the top up uh for CO2 okay yeah I just
looked that up right now you talking
about the mother nature CO2 generator
the 5 L kit yeah that's correct it was
sent to to me by by autopot thanks
autopot and it seemed to work I yielded
it a lot last run um that was that was
two tents right a 5x5 and a 4X4 and the
total yield for eight plants was 110
ounces wow I wouldn't want to be in that
trim
jail we can talk about
that so the autopot system it's pretty
commonly known these days but how did
you find out about the autopod system
and can you walk us through the setup I
know we have a lot of new folks on here
that don't really know what the system
is how it works talk to us about that
okay so I have probably four years of
experience with a system now pretty much
every day I use it right um so my when I
first started growing I did hand feeding
I had two plants in soil two plants in
Coco my first grow 2018 right and um the
cocoa plants won hands down that contest
like my yield the plants were happy
um the plants produce more and I can't
say for like you know the tpine profiles
all that but to me at a time yield was
very important and also how easy the
grow was going to be um so long story
short for roughly two years I decide to
run coconut uh Coco core right and
that's hand feeding and hand feeding
cocoa is something else like you can't
hand feed um once a day typically in veg
or you can do two three times a day in
flour they'll take it all it's extremely
hard to overwater a plan in Cocoa like
you really have to I don't know if it's
possible um possible I've done it
possible I've done it y can you tell me
about it because I tried I'm like
watering them like two runoff 10 15%
runoff daily three four times a day
right but that comes to with the
inconvenience of having to first of all
do it and second uh you have to deal
with a runoff if you don't have a proper
system you have to go in there with a
shot back or something and that takes a
lot of effort it takes a lot of noise
and after you know two years of doing
that I'm over it like this is so much
work there has to be a solution and
browsing the internet I Came Upon
autopot um it's a bottom wicking system
it's basically a if you use the right
substract it is a form of hydrop
and um it worked my first grow with it I
grew the most incredible plants and it
was so easy you basically have to top
water a few days or after a while you
just add your nutrient mix to the
reservoir and then the plant basically
feed themselves so the way it works is
you have a tray and uh within the tray
there's a key part of the system it's
called the aquavalve and the aquavalve
will fill the tray uh with the the plant
in it with roughly an inch worth of
water and then a stop and it works by
ways of vacuum and gravity so there's no
power involved at this point and once
the plant drink down the whole inch of
water in the tray the aquavalve will
break the seal from the vacuum and it's
going to refill it back to one inch
that's it that's it you do not have to
hand water anymore just the first few
days but after that from the rest of the
grow you don't have to hand water and
you just add your nutrient mix if you're
using coconut to the reservoir and then
there's no runoff to deal with either so
typically because of the reservoir
system you can leave for a week five six
seven days at a time and the plants will
keep drinking as long as the reservoir
has nutrient water in it so what I do
when I go on a 7day work trip or a
vacation or something I'll F the
reservoir to its limit and I'll even
have another 5 gallon bucket beside it
for a neighbor to dump it in as it gets
low so that extends how long you can
leave so it's it's an amazing system and
you grow the most incredible plants on
coconut and it's uh I love it I just
can't go back you know because
previously if I wanted to go on vacation
my partner would have to go and feed
once two three times a day and Shop back
the nutrient the the runoff water so for
me it's uh it makes so much sense for a
homeg grower that's really busy to have
like kids um or that have like a a very
busy work schedule or they want to go to
the gym you don't have to think about
your plans just mix it dump it in you're
done you know so I've been using it for
the better parts so four years now and
it's it works so good it had to be as
part of my Instagram handle I love the
autopot system I have it as well I uh
actually I stopped using it probably
like a year or two ago just because I I
switched the blue mats but man every run
I had with that thing was great and I
really do need to just wipe the dust off
it and get it back in motion because it
is a fantastic system now I want to ask
you about what size Reservoir do you
have it connected to and are you since
it's a gravity fed system yeah are you
having the reservoir up a certain height
yeah I think the manual recommends um at
least 6 in on above the tray so I have
mine like on on a mil crate um and I'll
use one 13g reservoir per two plants and
uh comes midf flowering they drink
really fast right really really fast at
first like oh not much is happening and
by the time you're an early to midflower
it's incredible how fast they drink
which makes me think a lot of people are
probably underwatering their plants in
Cocoa they just they're just not aware
of how much they can drink these plants
is incredible and um yeah it's uh it's
amazing I literally I cannot go back um
um oh and they have multiple products
they have there's the tray to grow that
I use in the 4x4 and that one's
incredible it's just one aquavalve and
it's like a a plastic tray roughly 3
feet long with a wicking mat on it so
you can grow many different ways with it
you know I've tried um man the previous
girl I I tried two fabric bags two
gallon just to see I want to keep my
plant small I'm like I'm going to use
something small two gallon two Auto
flowers uh well one in each obviously
and they were both close to a
pound in two gallon cocoa just sitting
on top of this tray with one aquavalve
and I I legit started from scratch I
didn't even top water once nothing it
just put it there and then it just grows
right it's it's un it's amazing yeah
it's such a great system and so you
correct me if I'm wrong you said you
have cocoa in it and you just been Coco
the entire time or have you tried soil
uh I've tried soil my first grow and
just uh just this current grow I was
chatting with Jeremy at builda I'm like
hey man I'd like to try some living soil
it looks awesome it's dope just water in
the reservoir right so he shipped me up
uh some builda 3.0 with some amendments
same thing I grew I grew oh my God I
just harvest the Same expeditus by night
oh that was 17 ooun and uh what's the
other one the speedrun frosty cherios F3
that came at 12 in living soil um just
water in the rest and that's my first
living soil grow ever and I'm like this
is incredible I didn't do anything I
just added top water in the reservoir no
phing nothing so I don't have a lot of
experience with it but I feel I need a
couple more ons to have a really good
feeling for the reimen M how much
nutrient is left in the soil because to
me it's kind of like maging like with
with when you're mixing uh salt you're
measuring everything so every point in
time you know what goes into the system
because you purposely mixed it right but
with soil say you have two three grows
through living soil like how much is
left in there how much do you need to re
amend to me it's kind of a a mystery
right so that that that part that's not
quantifiable it's kind of cool but it's
like magic man I I love it yeah it's
completely different from Coco so you're
mostly growing in Coco now are you
adding in any Iration like some people
add in like per Life for example and
along with aration do you add any type
of amendments at all or you do an
assault based system for nutrients so
I'm I believe okay so this this is the
thing autopot a lot of people try to
copy me but they they need to have
basically the same setup as me for it to
work so a lot of people will try 100%
coconut cor like I do and they may have
issues because of the lack of ariation
so here's what I do I have the air doome
which is part of the autopot ecosystem
as as well as the air base at the bottom
of my pot and the air doome is connected
to an air pump so it adds oxygen at the
PO at the bottom of each pot that is
sitting within the tray right without
that aerodome you might run the risk of
suffocating or even overwatering your
plants so I've I've seen that happen so
uh I'm 100% cocoa fella a lot of people
uh would be would do just fine with some
added perlite in the mix like 50% or 30%
but I don't personally do that and then
what do you run for nutrients oh man
I've ran a variety of stuff kind of
similar to you you know uh being in this
field on on Instagram there's a lot of
company that that reaches out to you and
I'm like yeah I'll try some stuff so
I've tried a variety of nutrients you
know uh from Athena to Canada to Mills
uh and I'm using right now a dried
powder line by Green Planet nutrients
called H te line it's brand new and um
it it's different in the sense that you
know a lot of people claim that um when
you buy a bottle nutrient most of it is
water so you're going to end up buying
more and more bottles and it weighs a
lot right so I'm like why don't I try a
different line um that's more DED salt
based I'm not sure if that's the right
terminology and it's seems to work so
basically you have your uh Reservoir
whatever how many guns you want to mix
in then you add your salt you mix it up
and then you pH to your Target and then
you're done and it's quite economical
because a bag of such powder nutrients
lasts for so many gallons you can mix so
much right but that's also the the very
scary thing about growing with Coco is
you you have to be able to um mix the
nutrients
properly which takes some practice but
you can you can learn anyone can learn
yeah the powder based ones are just so
convenient like you mentioned it goes
goes a long way and yeah I mean when
you're growing with the bottled
nutrients a lot of it is water you know
a large percentage I heard upwards of
98% of it being water yeah the powdered
form can definitely take you a little
bit further depending on which lineup
you're using so are you starting the
reservoir in like a low EC or I'm not
sure if you use EC or PPM starting low
and then kind of working your way up
throughout the grow or how do you do the
feedings yeah um what you say is correct
um I will start at a lower concentration
I use EC so I have like a it's called a
blue lab trunion I'm not sure if that's
how it's it's it's it's set because I'm
pretty French um the truncheon uh comes
out in two PPM formats a different scale
and there's also the EC scale so I use
the EC one because then you have to
think about the different scales that
are out there um all start pretty high a
lot of people people are they're quite
surprised when I tell them how high I
start my seedings we're talking 2.1 2.2
EC right off the bat the plant is like
just spr this big I'm like two
2.2 but you know plants being plants you
it's not just about the EC level the the
light needs to be at the right wattage
or di or ppf if you want as well and the
temperature and the relative humidity
everything needs to be right into for
the plant to be able to uptake that kind
of EC right else uh if you run like a
really small light you know like 25
watts because it's a Seedling and you
feed something 2.2 they're going to burn
they can't they can't process
it so personally I start them strong
right off the bat it's because these are
um I grow only autof flowers you know
and autof flowers being autof flowers um
to get big plants like I do you need to
perfect it needs to be perfect the veg
needs to be on point if the veg is not
on point and something happens to the
plant early on it will Fast flow on you
and if you have your plant you know this
big starting to flower it's only going
to end up being this big right so you
need it needs to be on point from day
one so that's the only tricky thing
about autoflowers yeah for those folks
listening on a podcast platforms he
mentioned this size to this side he was
do about 8 inches down up to 12 inches
or two feet at the max really yeah
that stunt that happens within the first
20 days any sort of deficiency really
holds back the plant I've had a handful
of autof flowers where it's like there's
this little bit of stunt and it totally
ruins the stretch and it and the overall
because it goes into flower like you
mentioned and then just starts flowering
and the stretch stops and all of a
sudden you're stuck with that size plant
no matter what throughout the rest of
flowering so it can be tricky yeah and
it I think it's going to be a little eye
opening for folks to realize that you
start with that high of EC and the
seeding stage now are you keeping that
for a period of time and then upping it
even further like in flowering for
example like what do you what do you
typically go up to um I want to say the
peak EC for me would be midflower so in
autoflow assuming for me a harvest is
typically day 90 plus or minus a week so
we're talking in the in the day 70s from
Sprout is roughly where my EC is on Max
so I'll be hitting close to like 2.8 2.9
EC so basic basically my range from 22
28 29 is what I typically do and as you
progress towards Harvest uh it lowers
back again towards the you know 2.3 2
2.4 it doesn't need to be crazy specific
but that's roughly it's roughly what I
do so midf flowering 2.8 and then a lot
of light that's your max light I'm
running 750 watts in the 5x5 and the 4x4
I'm close to 650 okay so load nutrients
are lowering towards the end of
flowering there and I take it you're not
doing any sort of like flushing of the
medium prior to harvest no I I don't do
that there's a lot of
misconception uh about it you know what
I don't know what's true or not but to
me it makes zero sense to flush out your
nutrients towards the last they're still
they're still living they still need
nutrients to grow um but they don't
uptake nearly as much so for the for the
purpose of like cost savings I'll lower
the EC but they're still growing I don't
see why you know in the Coco itself is
there's nothing and if you're you're
just flushing everything you're going to
mess up with the pH of the substr in
there as well and here's the other thing
I reuse my Coco so I don't want to strip
everything that's in there and have like
crazy pH spikes because I added just
plain water or pH water you reuse the
Coco huh can you talk to us about how
you actually go about reusing are you
flushing that all out and then starting
fresh you just continuing on what you
left off with the nutrients so yeah no I
I'll pretty much start I'll have the
same regime from day one whether it's
new coco or reuse Coco um it's really
easy I'll just dump all my plants uh all
the containers into an action Packer or
something similar I'll let it dry and
then I'll remove all the roots with a
tennis racket or a squash racket so
there's no more roots and I'll fill my
pots and I'll give it a go again but
here's the one thing uh that people
don't really know or maybe they don't
know but they will know out but there is
some nutrient uh salt buildup in the
autopot system so that does happen
because it's bottom wicking and uh the
actual nutrients salt will um slowly
migrate to the top of the pot so people
will notice when they're growing autop
poot with cocoa there's always a bit of
like white stuff on top of the substrate
and that's basically salt builded up uh
so that does happen and but you won't
see many roots up at the surface it's
mostly happens way down where the air
doome and the water update actually
happens so it doesn't really hurt the
plant but something I've learned the
hard way the top of the cocoa has really
loose cocoa and it's white and it's uh
crusty somewhat do not use that cocoa to
start a Seedling you will burn the hell
out of them and I've done that you know
I was uh mixing some new cocoa mine
comes as brick because I live so remote
I don't order the big expended bags
because it's more expensive for shipping
so I'll buy like the compressed brick I
ran out of it and I'm like oh I just
need a bit more cocoa to fill the sings
Cups right so I grabbed some of the top
loose soil of an old grow and I burnt
the hell out of everything everything so
always start seedling with fresh Coco
like fresh fresh fresh good advice you
know I know there are some people
probably a little bit surprised that
you're reusing it over and over again
having success other people are a little
bit surprised that you're not actually
doing a full flush of the medium to
where you're trying to get back to to
really say zero PPM but like basically
no nutrition in there and then kind of
adding in your 2.2 EC or whatever
whatever you want to start with to begin
so um yeah it's cool interesting to hear
that your way of going about it and so
how many runs in a row has it been with
this batch of cocoa that you had oh man
like I I never stopped so that's like
four five six years six years worth of
cocoa eventually as you pull the roots
out you know and then sometimes I'll
I'll purposely Chuck like first 4 in of
like salt buildup away So eventually I
need to buy some more and keep cycling
but for the most part uh some of the
original Coco I bought six years ago is
still is still running in there so in a
way it's very economical right because I
don't I don't really waste my Coco it
goes right back to work as soon as I can
and this thing Coco is so inert man I've
had Coco sitting in the action Packer
outside all winter all fall uh sorry all
spring until until I is thought enough
that I can use it again and boom it
right it goes right back into my grow
that stuff is so inert nothing grows in
it there's no algae there's no mushrooms
nothing it's good to go right away I
love the medium so much and the specific
one that I buy doesn't really compress
nearly as other brands that you can buy
and I I'll let it know I buy canac Coco
bricks which is the same as the
Professional Plus but it's in a brick
format and it's been uh
pre-buffering again um um as you expend
it can is a big name and known for their
high quality products so that's good
stuff there let's get into plant
training next what do you typically do
for plant training if any on the autof
flowers I love this topic um man you
know when you browse Reddit or Instagram
and then you see people like bending the
plants out of shape from like is this
good bending and it's like they eight
and they're they're bending the plants
out of shape because supposedly it
yields more and all that um I've tried
it I I've tried it you know I I tried
training I tried those little 90s band
stuff um nowadays I I don't do any
training I don't do any training I don't
do any training and uh I let the plan
expresss as as they are and it doesn't
seem like my yields suffer at all you
know and I did topping too I tried all
that it doesn't to me it doesn't I don't
see any benefit so I don't really do it
anymore to be honest you know and I like
to I like to provide as limited stress
as I can to these all flowers and veg
you know so most of what I do comes
after the flowering stretch so we're
we're going to say like day uh 50s when
the stretch is over that's when I'll go
in there and start stressing them up
because they already they're already
almost a full size you know I'm trying
really hard not to stunt them is what I
do I'm in the same camp as you where I
do little to no training on autof
flowers you I've tried topping in the
past and it just hasn't been a good
result and versus when I don't top you
know now I do do low stress training and
bend down the branches and stuff like
that I do like doing that in order to
shape the plant and make sure it fits
within my grow space but that's it
really just the low stress train I'm not
doing any topping not doing any super
cropping no fimming no nothing like that
so and yeah seems like the more hands
off you are with that the less stunt and
growth and the higher the bigger the
plant the bigger the yield you can get
off of it I'm a big fan of leaf tucking
so what I'll do is under when you have
like a a newish plant you'll have your
plant like this and there's going to be
your sub branches on the side and
typically there's a giant leaf on top of
it that kind of restricts uh direct
light to the the growth the lateral
growth so what I'll do is I'll grab that
fan leaf and I'll tuck it under the
growth so the growth is exposed a direct
light and what I find is that these side
uh these side shoots are able to grow
nearly as tall as the main so most of my
plants do not have that Christmas sheet
Christmas tree shape where it's like a
big really big tall Cola and then some
lateral Branch like this most of mine
are somewhat even perhaps not exactly as
tall as the main but they're able to
grow pretty tall and that's kind of what
I'm looking for but um I don't do a lot
of uh training because I'm not trying to
yield um let's say more I yield enough
for what I'm trying to do and say
there's some popcorn or smaller buds it
just goes to the hash bow there's no
waste at the end of the day you know so
it doesn't really hurt my feelings that
some of the buds are smaller down there
it doesn't doesn't hurt me it goes into
hash B make some hash out of it so
you're not spending a whole bunch of
time doing lollipopping or stripping
that lower part and really trying to get
rid of that fluff or lar you just like
oh well my know using it elsewhere uh no
that's not true I I I do I do lollipop
quite rarely but you know there's like
some people care about the tops right
and then growing mids apparently it's
very uh it's almost like a bad word like
oh look at your mids but I don't
understand why people feel like that
once it's in your hand and it's cured
you cannot tell the difference between
you know especially when you cut them
down to like you know nug size I'm quite
happy partaking in the mid so I don't I
don't understand that so so there's like
uh mids and tops and then the super
super low stuff like say one foot and
below that gets that gets cut I I'll
I'll prune all that quite happily it
doesn't take much time at
all but I guess what I'm trying to say
is like once you have a finished product
whether it's like mids or tops or
whatever it's it's all fair play for me
I'm I'm quite having I'm quite happy uh
partaking in it yeah and Ian the yields
that you are putting out is massive you
know over a pound per plant that's
definitely something to talk about and
I've got to ask you about your Harvest
process first of all when do you like to
harvest these Autoflower plants and what
is your process for harvesting you know
walk us through a detail like the
cutting down process all the way to
getting into drying okay um for me
personally I'm about 75% about the butt
look there's a certain look to a flower
when it's ready that I'm looking for um
the cxis needs to be plump you know when
they're in midflower you can see them
all they're all nice and and shimmery
but there's a c certain plump look that
I'm looking for that tells me the plant
is ready uh the stigmas are for the most
part orange and kind of retracted not
too many of the the newest flowers
forming on top of it and finally about
25% is is based on uh triol ripness so I
look for 0% clear um the vast majority
milky SP by me and some Amber as well
but not just the top buds you have to
look at the mid the bottom have a feel
for the whole plant whether it's ready
or not so it's combination of all that
um but having growing in the same way
the same strategy for so long again it's
it's also based on days so if we're
closing on day 90 I'm looking a lot more
closely at my buds for for Harvest okay
and then I believe you cut the plant at
the base if I remember correctly at
least I seen you in your Instagram you
love to hold that up uh the whole plant
hole and get some good pictures I I love
those picks are you then cutting
individual branches and hanging them or
are you just hanging the plant whole
yeah I I cut uh branches sometimes the
plants are huge right so it needs to be
a manageable size and I sadly do not
have a dedicated room for drying so I'll
use my grow room for drying but outside
of tent and I've got like lines set up
everywhere and I'll hang I'll hang the
plants by branches and the whole idea
here is I don't want buds to touch each
other for uh mold purposes right so I'll
have a room full of like individual
branches all cut up and strung up
together in my room and uh in terms of
drying strategy I aim for 6060 but
that's kind of hard it's kind of hard
for me to get I'm hoping to get you know
10 12 days but sometimes it's faster
than that sometimes I have to get in
there um before I even hit 10 days
because I'm scared of overdrying which
is where you you lose uh tpes if they're
too dry right so um for me anyways I
look for a smaller branch and if it
almost snaps apps I'm about there and
when I usually um jar them or back them
I'm looking for above 62 relative
humidity in that bag if it's below 55
I'm losing tpin so I want to be in the
high to
mid-60s you know so I'd rather trim
faster um than L let them hang for like
10 14 days and they're just overdried
and so you're putting them in bags and
aiming for above 60% like you mentioned
RH I used to jar them and that takes so
much effort I'm sure you're aware of the
growth bags yeah oh yeah so I use growth
I use one pound growth bags now for most
of my work because the B the the jars
are insane you have to open them daily
for like a week and it's just so much
effort right so I've been using growth
bags for possibly the last two years now
and it it works fine it looks great grow
bags are a game changer yeah because you
don't have to do that burping process
like you have to do with jars it just uh
it's able to escape that bag by itself
now are you heat sealing it as well I
know said people swear by heat sealing
it versus just the regular seal what are
you doing uh lately I have not but I
have heat sealed and to be honest I
haven't really found lots of differences
between heat sealing the bag or actually
just not doing it you know but for some
of uh if I have overdried some buds I'll
put a bito pack in they're 62% as well
and then what size bags you I'm assuming
bigger bags which size Grove bags I
think they're I think they're pound bags
or half a pound bags if I can't remember
yeah those Grove bags are are awesome
I've been using the um canol which is
the system that yeah pretty good system
very expensive though I mean I can't
recommend anybody go buy it because it's
just so much money it's so much money I
think it's 1600 I was talking to someone
yesterday I think he got like 14 or
1,600 USD which is close to like 2,000
can he I'm like man and I need I would
need like three of
those you know so I'm like I don't know
if I'm going to go that route I'm I'm
not rich like that you know yeah it's a
lot of money but I wish I had one yeah
it it does make things a lot more easier
because you just cut up the branches
individually place them in there and
then it dries and cures dries and cures
yeah so dries it's going to bring you
right down to that 60 62% whatever you
kind of set it to and then you have that
shelf stable and it just stays at that
it's awesome but uh I can't say I
recommend it just because of the the
price it's just it's just so much money
you know pricey but I want one so
bad so that's Harvest dry and cure for
you I want to get into common
misconceptions about
autoflowers there there's just like
anything in life there's uh pros and
cons right
so I I like them a lot um I get the
yield that I'm looking for um the
product itself is great THC level is
great I sent a bunch for testing one
came out as like 298 or something like
that you know um but here's one big
misconception and it's relevant to the
fact that it's easy for
beginners autof flowers are harder for
beginners because you not you lose the
ability to uh veg for as long as you
want and you lose the ability to flower
when you think they're ready to be
flowered right so they are not better
beginners you can grow a plant but will
you be happy with the yield and the end
product possibly not if you're brand new
in the game right I agree with you 1,00%
on that one for those exact
reasons yeah um but I I I focus on aut
of flowers because exactly for reason
because people grow really really small
all the flowers and I'm out there
showing that it doesn't need to be that
way if you are dialed in like I am you
can grow really really big plants and
and just be like hey look at this plant
anyone grown in 90 days um an one
benefit for for example is they can grow
under 24 and0 you do not need to rest
which is another misconception people
are like everything needs to rest in
life I'll give them two hours of
Darkness because they need to rest I'm
like that's not true you're kind of
losing the benefit of outer flowers
these guys can express themselves they
can grow under 24 and0 so as long as you
give them as much light as they can
possibly take they will grow huge right
they don't need that Darkness at all I
live in the subarctic in the summertime
there's no Darkness you know there's and
that's where these plants come from for
the first place rumors has it I don't
know if it's true that uh the creator of
autof fliers grabbed these genetics from
rud rales plant out of Russia in
Northern Russia where it is similar
environment as me where in the
summertime is really short and there's a
lot of light and it's not the season
that will dictate whether you need to
procreate or not it's like
time you know we got to go now because
there's not much time left so um yeah so
those those are the two big ones um is
it true that photo period um have better
genetics than autofs 100% photo period
have been readed for so much longer so
they're way ahead of the curve in terms
of genetics potency and turpine profiles
all that right but with all these new
breeders coming up doing some proper
work they're catching up really fast So
eventually you're going to see some
autof fers with some crazy t on number
if that's what they're breeding for and
also a very interesting tpping profile
you know the same expeditus that I'm
growing right now has like a a sweet
beet SL carrots tpine profile that comes
from you know a land RAC train AF call
zal so there's some really cool stuff
going on out there so I'm I'm quite
happy growing them in the future going
going for you're inspiring me to get
back into autoflowers to be honest with
you I took a little break from
autoflowers but the takeaways in this
episode is autopot system three things I
want to say you know for me uh part of
My Success quality genetics cocoa core
um and autopots those three combined is
a really really solid start you know um
we can talk about white label genetics
or strains if you want but what I would
advise is to buy straight from the
Breeders if you can if not there are
thirdparty um websites or seat banks
that can provide the same genetics but
if you go on Google and you type best
auto flowering strains a lot of sketchy
stuff comes up and I cannot advocate for
that because genetics is the base of it
all you need to know you need to procure
seeds from a known breeder someone that
you know is behind the scene actually
thinking about the breeding and
selecting the plants and doing the
Crossing not just hype from a company
that you don't even know who the breeder
is you know I completely agree any other
advice for beginners that maybe somebody
who's just getting started growing Auto
flowers any takeaways that they could
have yeah that that's that's a really
tough one a lot of beginners even myself
like years ago you would go on on Reddit
and then you would look for information
and there is an insane amount of um
misinformation out there you know even
stuff like we talked about like
flushing and training and light
schedules and that kind of stuff there
is so much bad info um I would advocate
for kind of like following someone kind
of like yourself that can provide the
proper information and just follow it to
a te you know because if you listen to
like too many people are reading too
much information from who knows what
you're going to end up with terrible
advice so I'd follow to I'd probably
suggest to find a good source and then
follow that and that should be
sufficient to get um some really nice
flowers good advice and I think for
autof flowers the best person to follow
is autop potimus ever heard of
him I do a good job you know and uh I've
been doing this for a while and I'm I'm
happy showing the process people know
it's just not a fluke I've been doing
this for many years you know and I show
the process from like seedlings all the
way to harvest right
yeah for sure I mean I spoke about your
Instagram a couple different times and
it's it's incredible really really great
results to see in there awesome pictures
and big fish too you even threw some
fish photos in there was Prett cool to
see yeah we like her fishing up here for
sure awesome last question I'll hit you
with oh actually second to last question
future of autof flowers what do you see
as the future for autof flowers from a
breeding and a cultivation aspect the
first thing I want to say is um all the
flowers are great for for many things um
bitc con is you can't clone them say you
have like a really cool plant and you
want to keep growing over and over
because it was so awesome that's one of
the biggest thing uh is you cannot keep
a mother plant all the flower uh it's
just going to flower on you and then you
can't clone it you can't do nothing like
that however um you can collect
seeds so I do that a lot of people do
that and that's a super cool aspect of
it there's a lot of strains that are in
demand and sometimes they come and go
and uh I see people collecting an insane
amount of cool genetics so I I really
really actually like that you know
trading seeds with people it's a it's a
big hobby of mine uh but in the future I
can only see um the genetics progress
and potentially get better and better um
each time you know bigger plants uh
faster Harvest maybe cooler
tpin um and more stability as well um so
there's a there's a lot of like Hy uh
photo pared strain as well that can be
bred into autoflowering so I'm looking
forward to some of those you know
there's some strains that I've only
known as photo period and I'm just
waiting for the time when it's it's
grown Autos as well so people will have
like a lot of choices in the future as
well right awesome well there is more
that we could talk about but we're going
to wrap things up here can you tell the
listeners how they could find you and
what you have upcoming in the future
yeah so I'm active on on Reddit I I
browse certain subreddits for sure but
I'm mainly my main my main spot is on
Instagram I think the link was going to
be down below so you can you can hit on
that and see what I do uh but something
I want to mention is I'm partnering it
with I'm partnering with autopot USA to
um have a master class and this master
class is basically
me teaching what I know what I do really
well I'm not going to teach something I
don't understand so basically I'll be um
what we're thinking is I'll be teaching
over a weekend all the information
everything that I do from A to Z and
then we're going to have a grow along
with the class um on set on a specific
date and I'll come in we're going to
have everyone in the chat room a Discord
Channel I'll come in and I'll I'll
provide advice um on the grow so
everyone can grow just the safe same as
me with a lot of hands-on experience so
we're hoping to launch this uh in Winter
2024 that's exciting I'll definitely
have a link to autopot Us's Channel down
in the YouTube description section below
and if you're on one of the podcast
platforms listening in just search for
them you'll find them we'll come right
up there shout out to all the folks that
support on patreon those in the producer
tier are being scrolled on the screen
right now special thanks to you but
anyone who donates through patreon it
goes 100% right back into the podcast
everything from the edor fees to the
cost for the platform here to the cost
to get on to the podcast platform so all
of that is covered through patreon thank
you so much for those folks that
contribute through patreon Lynn thanks
so much for coming on to the podcast
this was great like I mentioned there's
a lot more that could be said I don't
even think we got into environment right
we could have been a whole conversation
about that and you know there it's not
just growing with salt-based nutrients
but people are doing it with Organics as
well so there are so many different ways
you can grow autoflowers
I think we could potentially continue on
the conversation in the future
absolutely if you'd like to if the folks
demand a part two if you want a part two
let us know down in the comment section
below and also let us know in the
comment section what do you do that's
special when growing autof flowers is
there particular light spectrum that
you're going after amount of light
medium so on and so forth so drop it all
down in the comment section below I'd
love to read through it and uh yeah
we'll leave it at that thanks so much
for coming out to the podcast and hope
you enjoy the rest of your day thank you
my pleasure peace out everyone catch you
in the next episode