coming up on garden talk
before when i first got into autoflowers
i was all about hps lights i absolutely
love them i did try some leds back in
the day and i really didn't really like
the quality of buds that i was getting
nowadays i've switched completely over
100 to leds and i probably never looking
back to hps it's a completely different
ball game when you do it outside times
to finish are definitely not the same
once you start going over 86 or up to
90s the autoflowers definitely take a
little bit of a hit and
they
will not grow as fast the autoflowers
are very sensitive to nutrients they can
get overfed very easily well actually
depends on the genetics too that is one
of the best ways to get like nice solid
hard dense
rock hard buds
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 20. in
this episode i talk with dr otto flower
he is a fellow youtuber with over 53 000
subscribers and his videos have over 4.3
million views combined he has been
gardening for 13 years and he grows a
variety of plants tomatoes herbs peas
carrots lettuce and medicinal plants he
is most known for growing autoflower
plants hence his name so in this episode
i pick his brain to find out how he
grows autoflowers and also how he
maximizes yield when growing autoflowers
i release these podcast episodes on a
weekly basis so be sure to hit the
subscribe button if you haven't already
and if you're listening on apple
podcasts please leave a rating and
review i do have a patreon page for
those of you who would like to support
in that way the link is patreon.com
mr growit and there are various tiers on
there with different offerings before we
get into the episode i'd like to give a
quick shout out to our sponsor dutch pro
nutrients dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for 30 years now they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world i'll be using their base
nutrients which are formulated
specifically by water type for example
their two-part soil rosso bottles are
specifically designed for when using
reverse osmosis or soft water they also
have base feeds for if you're in hydro
as well i'll leave a link to their
amazon store down in the description
section below and you can use coupon
code mrgrowit10dp
for a discount on their products all
right now let's get into the episode
okay we are here with dr autoflower
welcome to the podcast man how you doing
hey thanks thanks for having me on chris
uh yeah it's uh good to be here i've
been watching you guys for a while and
uh it's good to be on the show thanks
for having me on
yeah i think we first found out they
made each other back in like 2015-ish or
2016-ish
i think both channels
and uh
man this youtube journey has been crazy
huh
yeah to say the least um
yeah
turned into an actual full-time career
and it looks like it has for you so
it's it's crazy how far we came to uh
i was going to tell you about like back
in the day because i i you told me like
you started 2015
back in the day in like
2010 2011 that was back in like poop in
the bucket days where people tell each
other oh yeah you can poop in a bucket
or
pee on your plants like there was some
crazy information out there but
yeah we definitely come a long way
so for those that don't know who you are
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening
uh yeah uh
my channel actually i had a channel
before and i just deleted it and started
a new one that was dr autoflower i
started that back in 2011.
uh
some would say i'm one of the originals
but uh i think the more the the real
original started like as soon as youtube
started back in like 2005 2006 and uh
yeah like i first started pretty much
back in the day
my ex-girlfriend her dad had a really
nice setup
and he said yeah you can just grow some
plants and see how it works for you and
gave me some seeds i had no idea what
those seeds were
and it actually was a
type of autoflower they i had no idea
what i was growing back then
and they just started flowering out of
nowhere and i was like what's going on
it doesn't make sense and i i thought
they were just
just regular plants just doing the thing
but i
noticed like hey these are actually
forming some decent buds what's going on
here i have it on
20 hours of light so i did some research
and
turns out they were autoflower i don't i
don't think they're actually full
autoflower but
they were autoflower for sure and that's
what kind of led me on the journey of
autoflowers
and i started doing tons of research
back then probably the best source of
information was on forums
and i was just like a complete sponge of
knowledge and i was just super addicted
to like just wanting to learn and
research as much as possible
so i was learning from everyone else
who's been growing them for the past
back then it was only like
a few years when they were actually good
quality
uh but yeah learned a lot from the
forums and then i
thought wouldn't that be a good idea to
kind of
give back to the universe or whatever
and just like put all that information i
learned but online on youtube
in an easier
form of you know information
and uh
in a different i guess medium or
whatever
but uh yeah i
i had no idea this could lead to a
career
uh back then and
yeah it's
pretty crazy how far we've come
so
yeah that's how i kind of got started
with autoflowers and
from there i just
wanted to learn more and uh
produce more content so
yeah here we are today
that's awesome yeah before we started
recording uh he had mentioned that he's
been gardening for 13 years
and you know you grow a variety of
different plants right so tomatoes herbs
you mentioned peas carrots
lettuce on top of the medicinal so um
lots of experience across multiple types
of plants which is pretty cool so yeah
yeah like i was telling uh mr growit
here uh
the soil i use now if i instead of just
throwing it out after
my use uh indoors i'll just move it to
my outdoors because that's where i use
all my uh regular plastic pots i i've
moved over to like air pots and smart
pots so all my olds my old plastic pots
that'll that's what i grow my uh outdoor
vegetables and that kind of stuff with
so yeah it keeps me keeps me busy and a
little fun thing to do because i do live
in an apartment so growing here is a
little bit different i can't just go you
know grow in the soil here
don't have that many options so yeah
that is what i like to do nice nice
so in this episode in particular i'd
like to talk all about
maximizing yield on all the flowers
right so how do you grow huge autoflower
plants and you have a track record of
growing big autoflower plants that may
not have seen your videos so you've been
doing it for years and years and years
so i figured you'd be a great person to
come on to the podcast today and and
talk about your style of doing it so
we've got a list of questions here uh
i've given those to you ahead of time
for those viewers that don't know uh the
guests are given a list of questions in
advance so they can kind of get an idea
for what's going to be asked
and so we'll go through each thing we'll
go through nutrition we'll go through
lighting we'll go through environment
all these different factors that impact
yield
let's start with medium
so what medium do you usually grow in
are you in soil cocoa are you doing
hydro
what do you do for that
i've pretty much done everything other
than hydro
um
so i've used like kind of you know not
the best just regular bag soil and stuff
i've used soil from our
over at my farm my family farms it's
like compost pretty much
so i've used that
um
but i've
i've pretty much gone
and like stayed with um
pro-mix hp that's the most
you know abundant
good soil i have around everything else
is you know kind of mediocre compared
i have gone higher cocoa
and uh
i've used low quality cocoa really
didn't like that had bad results
really got kind of turned off from it
uh but i had also awesome results by
mixing
two parts pro mix and one part cocoa
like good quality high quality cocoa
i really really enjoyed growing with
that
but
uh because hydro stores aren't really
you know
close to me uh it's just much easier to
stick with pro-mix i have awesome
results with it
why fix what's not broken so i just kind
of stay with them and uh have awesome
results are you know gotcha and so that
pro-mix hp
uh that's the one that comes with
mycorrhizae right are you adding
anything else in are you amending sort
of amending anything else and to begin
with
no like while when i was doing organic
um i've grown grown with guy green and i
forget the other one but
uh that's the only time i've ever added
stuff into the soil
um
pretty much now i use all advanced
nutrients
for my nutrients so i don't really need
to
to have
additives i find
so i i pretty much keep it like before i
was i don't know i'd get
really technical with all my growing i
uh like i would
add some stuff at the beginning i forget
what it did i i can't it's been so long
since i don't even remember what i was
adding back then
but i kind of keep it with the kiss
method keep it simple stupid
just the easier the better and if it
works don't fix it kind of thing yeah i
mean you can still maximize yield with
simple techniques right a lot of people
yeah
yeah a lot of people do try to um do
more than they need to do
yeah you know micromanaging in a sense
so
um okay cool
and then what drill pot size do you
usually start in and what type of pot do
you use plastic fabric air uh for a
while there i was using three gallon but
i have now switched over to five gallon
i really like it um that's probably the
max i like to go i've gone bigger like
10 gallon pots and it just seems like
you're doing too much work for
not that much big of a difference with
all the flowers
so
yeah i i always recommend five gallon
three three gallons good too
if you don't have all that room or you
don't want to use so much soil uh but
for me
i
like to stick with five gallon
okay and are those the
air pots or the plastic pots i'm sorry i
don't know those are
i kind of do a mix uh sometimes i do air
pods sometimes i do smart pots air pots
are a little annoying to work with
because water can just like run out the
sides super easy and stuff and then you
gotta suck up all the water that runs
off into your catcher
but i would say
yeah i really enjoy going with smart
pots now uh it just seems like you get
better growth all around especially
compared to like my old plastic bots so
yeah definitely recommend those yeah i
mean it helps you know you do need
oxygen down in that root zone and that
does help with growth you know that's
one of the reasons why a lot of people
go with cocoa because it adds a adds
that air into the the root zone so
pro pro-mix is a light
lighter medium when you compare to soil
too yeah you're going to get that air in
there and that along with the
either air pots or the fabric pots
that's going to help with aeration
that's going to help with with overall
growth so yeah if i did have access to
some good high quality cocoa if i didn't
have to order online pay for shipping
all that i definitely would use it
because you do get more air you do have
to water a little bit sooner
but
you get a bit better results than just
using uh pro mix hp so yeah i would
definitely recommend
uh a mix
if if someone else was interested in
getting into like my kind of
uh style medium and stuff definitely a
mix is good gotcha and then one of the
most debated
pieces of this is
starting in the final container there's
people out there who
argue that you need to you should start
in the final container right so you had
mentioned three gallon grill pots five
gallon grill pots
a lot of people say plant that seed
directly into that medium avoid the
transplanting process is what they're
trying to do
because if you're starting in the small
solo cup for example and transplanting
up there is that risk of transplant
shock happening slowed growth happening
with autoflowers during a limited life
right so if you have any um stunning
growth for the first 30 days or so or
any any point of grow actually it could
negatively impact yield most likely it's
gonna negatively impact yield um now do
you start in the final container or are
you
transferring a person yeah like you said
nothing's like written in stone right
like i have seen some decent grows very
good grows that have been transplanted
it can be done it's just like you said
like there is that chance and it the
chance is pretty high that you're going
to stunt the growth
so
i personally started directly in the pot
don't mess with it starting five gallon
if you're going to do three gallons
start in three gallon but just keep it
as that and uh
yeah you're way less likely to get risk
of
shock or anything
but one caveat is um
i've seen that um
growing outdoors
it's it i i think it's fine you you can
actually can have better results i found
like i've tried both i've tried planning
directly in the ground
and
just uh dixie cups
one week old and then transplant them
but i definitely noticed that the ones
planted directly outside didn't fare as
well for like up here in canada i get
some cold nights so it kind of hurt them
i would suspect
but once they had some
you know they were taken off a bit they
could actually handle it so
i actually
had pretty decent results when
transplanting outside because it seems
like it's a completely different ball
game when you do it outside times to
finish are definitely not the same
a 60 day strain will not
especially where i am it will not finish
in 60 days
but they can get way bigger than normal
they they have a huge root mass area if
you just plant them directly in the
ground some good soil their roots get
gigantic and i've i've grown like
probably the biggest autoflowers i've
ever grown and i transplant them but
they didn't finish so i didn't really
you know
get the uh you know cream of the cropper
or whatever
a good harvest but uh
definitely grew some massive mass of
plants
so
did it stunt it
i don't think so i think it was more
environmental issues that i had to deal
with but it just seems like outdoor
they can handle transplant more because
planted directly
they don't have the best start i would
say gotcha gotcha and there's going to
be people that comment on this video and
they're going to say i transplant autos
every time and i don't have any stunt
growth that's a myth the whole
transplanting slows down growth and
stuff so uh either way if you're new to
autoflowers maybe try both and see which
one you like that's what i say it is
definitely an experiment like everything
you should see as an experiment if you
want try one plant directly the other
one transplant if it's the same genetics
if you get awesome results still then do
what's easy for you that's what i say
and if you're gonna go the transplant
route maybe you know when you do that
transplant a common technique is a
sprinkle mycorrhizal fungi on the roots
as they're doing the transplant so that
way it's basically like an extension of
the root so the fungi extends the roots
helps the nutrient uptake yeah and some
people swear by that that people are
like oh i start in the small cup so i
can do that sprinkle of the mycorrhizae
and then they go into their final pot
yeah and then it just blows up from
there so
there are so many different ways to kind
of go about that for sure yeah yeah find
what works best for you and stick with
it yup now how about water what type of
water are you typically using when you
grow auto flowers tap rain distilled uh
yeah like i have used uh when doing it
outdoors i have used rain and seemed to
work really good
but here in my apartment building i do
just just water i don't
i don't purify it or whatever i don't
really have a setup for that i would i
would love to if i had my own house
get something set up like that but uh
yeah just straight tap water let it sit
out for a day
decor decolonize and uh
yeah
pretty much uh
i don't really ph it or anything
uh well actually i do ph it just a
little bit
just so it gets close to like the
7.0 ph mark and then i use ph perfect so
i don't really worry about ph but yeah
just straight old tap water settle for a
day okay cool and then kind of getting
into the nutrition side of things you
mentioned for nutrients using advanced
nutrients is that typically what you use
when you're trying to maximize yield
with autoflowers is the advanced
nutrient lineup uh yeah like i i've used
a lot of nutrients before i've had also
awesome results with remo's nutrients
shout out to remo
but
yeah i've kind of just switched to
because i noticed before a lot of my
issues if i did have issues was normally
from ph
issues just imbalances
and it just got annoying chasing the ph
because my ph here can get pretty high
and it's just annoying to deal with so
once switching to ph perfect i
kind of stopped having ph problems and
yeah getting awesome results still and
good quality bud so i'm happy with it
and uh
keeping it simple and
yeah still getting awesome results so
i'm pretty pretty pretty happy with it
and you mentioned you're just using the
base nutrients for advanced nutrients i
think they have a couple different bases
right they have like a grill and uh
which ones are you using i actually
don't use the base nutrients i
found a pretty decent uh
kind of
what you would call it a grow schedule
feeding schedule or whatever online and
it uses the uh was it the scentsy bloom
because the scentsy bloom is really it's
got like enough
uh
nitrogen that can last the whole grow
so a lot of people have shown like you
can just get awesome results just using
that the whole way through
uh
and yeah
plants seem to love it they don't get
super
they don't like run out of nitrogen
halfway through the the flower cycle so
it's definitely
a good all-around nutrient to use i'd
say and i'm looking at it right now so
there's scentsy grow looks like there's
two bottles for scentsy grow and then
there's scentsy blooms sensei bloom is
the only one to use yeah those a and b
wow yeah okay
and are you following a feeding chart
off of their website
no the one i follow i forget what it's
called
um
but if you search scentsy bloom
uh schedule autoflower it should pop up
it's on a form there but it's pretty
much um
it's i think it's more less than half of
what they recommend or maybe even one
third of that
but yeah it's definitely much less than
they recommend for their regular plants
and
it seems to do you know it's it's on the
level of like almost being too much
sometimes so i even go like a little bit
less
so
like let's say the beginning of feeding
during veg my very first feeding i'd
probably give um
like 1.5 milliliters
of each a and b
or
two milliliters depending on how the
plants are looking but yeah it's pretty
small because they i think they
recommend five milliliters when you
first start
something like that so yeah it is a bit
bit less
okay and then you're not using any
additives on top of that at all any
using any sugars like or any microbial
inoculants or anything i'm using voodoo
juice b52
uh
what is it rhino skin
that kind of helps with the
strengthening of the stalks and stuff i
go
intermittently with the cow mag big buds
and the
the sugar stuff though i i forget what's
called but it has the sugars bud candy
or something like that yeah but yeah
that's pretty much what i use and then
during flower i switch over to the
their flowering additives and then i
kind of take out the
the veg additives and switch it up a
little bit but yeah i think i might have
to do a a video on that on my channel
kind of explain exactly what i use for
the entire growth for autoflowers so
yeah i might have to come up with that
yeah i think that would be very helpful
for sure um yeah so you use some
additives there's definitely some sugar
in there and like microbes in there
beneficial bacteria and stuff like that
in those bottles that you mentioned so
awesome you're getting yeah the full
nutrition there from
advanced nutrients for sure
and then you said you don't with the ph
nutrients has ph perfect they're
i think it's patented technology or
something that
really when you mix i don't know how it
works
i i asked them how
because my my water can get up to like
9.1 ph wow so pretty high yeah like it's
kind of annoying to deal with so i asked
them like hey
my ph is really high does this work for
mine and they said uh the best thing i
could do is get it down to
7.0 around that
and just
you know just do that the regular
uh nutrients and
pretty much the way it goes is you add
the
the main like if you're using scentsy
bloom you'd use use uh put sensitive
bloom in first and then all the
additives
um
but what i do now is i found out
uh i i use the
tnb up and down
the the crystals
uh so
i just found out how much i need for 7.0
i can pretty much eyeball it now just
take a little scoop put in there
boom done
and uh
very simple i don't even use a ph pen
anymore there's no point
uh just do that mix up the nutrients
never had a problem yet pretty much
okay so you are monitoring the ph going
in
some people what they'll do is monitor
the ph of the medium as well whether
that be a runoff test or a slurry test
did you do anything like that at all or
just
i used to but now i keep things so
simple now like it works i'm not having
issues i don't see any ph issues pretty
much anymore so
i kind of pretty much just stopped doing
that it's just
it takes more time up and
i'd rather keep it as
simple as possible in the garden now
gotcha gotcha makes sense now how about
some people monitor the ppm or the ec
of it to know get an idea of how much
nutrients are going into their medium
do you
monitor the ec or ppm kind of going in
after you create that mix or coming out
at all or no
i used to
but like i said keeping kiss method
super simple um
i just don't anymore i feed the whole
way through
um that's why i keep it a little bit
less than what they recommend on the
advanced nutrients like calculator you
can put in how much water you're using
and like what growth cycle you're in
they'll tell you how much to use i
usually use like
two thirds of that
and i use it throughout the whole grow
and when i get to about week six or
seven start with the flush flush
everything out make sure it's all nice
and clear and
bud's awesome tastes good smoke's
awesome don't have any black ash so okay
so there's nutrition kind of just went
over what you do for that let's switch
it up and talk about lighting so
arguably one of the most if not the most
important thing when you're talking
about yield is
is lighting and getting that energy down
onto the plant if you don't have the
optimal amount of energy
it could yield could definitely be
sacrificed right if you're not giving
enough par
enough of that radiation uh down onto
the plant or too much could harm the
plant you know you get a light burn it
can slow down growth as well so what are
you typically using what are you using
for lighting in order to maximize yield
good point on uh talking about the like
burning like too much light some people
just think oh more light more lights in
there the better
no uh that's why i always recommend
people get a par meter or a lux meter
and learn how to convert it from lux to
par
uh it is definitely needed
uh before when i first got into
autoflowers i was all about hps lights i
absolutely love them
i did try some leds back in the day and
i really didn't really like the quality
of buds that i was getting
uh nowadays i've switched completely
over 100 to leds and i
probably never looking back to hps
um
yeah i use optic leds i use the bar
lighting bar lighting seems to become
super popular lately the last two years
or so
many companies are switching over that
and
the results i'm getting are
better than what i was getting on hps i
would say
buds are super dense and thick
uh not getting any
weird stretching and stuff back like
you'd get back in the day
um
the terpenes are even better than hps i
would say
but yeah i'm super happy since switching
all the way over to leds and uh yeah
pretty happy with the results i get all
the time
leds have come so far over the years i
mean if we had this conversation back in
2015-ish
uh there would be debatable right
there's a huge debate
uh you'd have led grow lights coming out
that are less efficient than hps
so you have these these people
advertising their lights saying that
it's more energy efficient when it's
actually less energy efficient it was
really bad back in the day when when
leds first kind of came on the market
so days of the blurble
yep days of the the targeted light
spectrum with the the blues and the reds
only and eliminating those greens and
you just see purple and oh man wouldn't
i strain
yes exactly exactly like uh
i remember back in the day
when
hps was the main thing there were people
they would come on and they would want
to like do like grow battles and stuff
and hey let's do a competition all
i think i can beat you with leds and you
use hps and
there was no competition really like it
was it was not a competition back in
2012. now 10 years later nine years
later it's
there's no competition comparing hps to
leds now like the energy you save
the heat you like uh
you don't have to deal with all the heat
and stuff
and the light spread is just has gotten
so damn good that it just doesn't make
sense to go with hps anymore yep
i agree you still get good results off
of it but um of course definitely more
efficient better light spread with the
leds and so on and so forth now is there
a specific amount of par
that you aim for during this different
stages of growth when you're looking to
maximize yield like i know you said you
have a par meter there are some general
ranges out there which i've mentioned on
my channel many many times of general
ranges that people can aim for during
the different stages of growth do you
look at that and aim for a certain
amount
oh yeah of course definitely i if anyone
asks i always recommend them
pretty simple like i said before if you
don't have a par meter they're expensive
they're like 500 800 i think here in
canada i think 500 or 600 in america or
something like that so they're pricey uh
but a lux meter you can get for like
forty dollars or something like that and
there's a simple conversion you can do
to get par pretty much
uh but yeah i recommend um
for autoflowers it's pretty similar to
for veg plants i would see the first
first three weeks would be what you
would give for veg so i would start at
200 par
and slowly ramp up to about
550 600 par
at the end of uh
veg there once it starts flowering
and during the first week of flower i'll
probably slowly go from
600 slowly go up until about i would say
week 5.5 or 6
like slowly ramp up to about
900 850 something like that
that's where i usually see the best
results
but it's it is a slow ramp up and uh
that that is the nice thing about having
a par meter you can actually check every
day say okay it's because your plants
are growing too so you don't always have
to just lower the lights
so as long as they're you're keeping
your par and it's slowly going up i
think you're doing awesome
and uh
that is one of the best ways to get like
nice solid hard dense
rock hard buds and knowing your par is
very important i say
it's super important especially if
you're giving a lot of people don't
realize that they're giving the like or
their plants too much
i've had that issue before when i wasn't
using my par meter i was just
cranking up the light and then oh
i go check and my par is at like
600 700 during veg and i'm just like oh
yeah i'm frying my plants this isn't
good
so yeah definitely something i recommend
people look into gotcha gotcha and then
the higher light levels is pretty much
the same in line to what i aim for right
i'm going
you know 900 max really for flowering is
typically what i go for now if you're
supplementing co2
you can go higher than that in most
cases are you supplementing co2 at all
right now or no uh i was using uh the
kind of like the mushroom bags i forgot
what co2 bags or whatever uh i was
cranking up the leds a little bit more i
was going up to like 950
1000 i didn't notice
light burn really uh they were
i think
if someone asked me like how much does
it actually help i would say
maybe five percent better growth i i
don't i don't see it as like a huge
amount but if i actually had a real co2
setup yeah i would definitely be going
higher um i've heard of people going up
to like uh 1200
uh par or sometimes even higher than
that um but i don't have a
uh co2 set up like that so i haven't
really got into it um i do grow pretty
much right next to our bedroom pretty
much so i don't really want co2 all
throughout the house and stuff so
yeah maybe one day when we have
something separate um i would like to
get into co2 a bit more gotcha so are
you still using mushroom bags or not
anymore uh no i i kind of stopped um
made me think like is
is this releasing spores throughout the
house or something like that or
i don't know i didn't really see a huge
huge difference
to
make me want to go spend you know i
think they're around like 60 70
bag or something like that a little
pricey so yeah i
just thought might as well just not do
it this time gotcha and then when you're
not supplementing since you're not
supplementing co2 air exchange is going
to be super important right because
if you're not exchanging the air the
plants are just eating up that co2 and
the grow tent or grow room whatever
you're in yeah what do you typically do
for air exchange normally i got the
window just wide open fans blowing all
in the outdoor air but this year i'm a
little worried about that because i did
end up with mites
last year so i was super angry about
that
but this year i think i might have to
set up a
portable ac unit just so it's sucking in
the air i don't have the window wide
open for bugs to come in
so i think that's probably my best bet
but i do also grow with my my tent doors
just wide open
um i don't really tend to close them all
the time
um
yeah i just feel like the air movement
is just much better when you have it
wide open like that fans blowing
everything around got the uh in intake
fans uh sucking it out but i don't take
my intake fans and put it out the door
because i'm an apartment building
building i don't want people seeing a
bunch of tubes going to the window and
stuff and them wondering what that's all
about so
yeah i keep it pretty low-key um
i would like to have a more proper setup
for
moving air out but here's what it is for
right now
gotcha are you running into any
temperature issues the way you're doing
that or what's the temperature you
usually aim for
uh
[Music]
well going with leds i normally would
want it around like 80
80 fahrenheit to about 85 is tops i
would like to have it at uh and that's
the canopy temperature yeah canopy yeah
pretty much
try to keep it at that
it does get a little
hard to do sometimes in the
you know dead of
dead of summer or whatever so like it's
gets a little intense
uh because i am an apartment building so
it does get a little hot in here so that
makes me think i should probably get a
ac unit just for
that one month so it doesn't affect the
crop or anything but uh normally during
winter time i don't really have any
issues with keeping the temperatures
down um
during the winter it kind of helps heat
my place so that's that's the nice thing
um
but yeah try to keep in those
temperatures once you start going over
86 or up to 90s the autoflowers
definitely take a little bit of a hit
and
they
will
not grow as fast i would say yeah i used
to go up to 85 87 actually is kind of
what i maxed out at and some cultivars
were able to take it
other cultivars you'd see that stress
come on
so i've
brought it down a notch usually now i'm
actually aiming for typically leaf
surface temperature to be like 80 to 82
degrees and depending on the cultivar um
most of them will be able to take that
and uh and that means that the canopy
temperature usually is a little bit
higher than the leaf surface temperature
it's usually you know two three four
degrees potentially depending on the
light you're using and how much it's
radiating down on there you know the
amount of ir comes into it we talked
about we get into a whole discussion
about hps versus led just as the amount
of heat that comes down but
we won't get into that but um yeah okay
that makes sense for for temperature now
what about
humidity
uh what do you typically aim for for
humidity through the different stages of
growth uh
really i just try to keep it as low as
possible i just i don't mess with the i
i know it's better like the uh what is
it called the the chart the mac vpd
like i i have
tried to go buy that but
i really
don't want
high humidity at all not like none lower
the humidity for me is the better
because
i have had issues with mold in the past
and this this is during wintertime
winter time is super important for me to
like have
as little as humidity as possible i have
dehumidifiers
trying to keep it as low as possible
because when you're running four tenths
it can get kind of high in one room
um
but
yeah i've had issues with mold in the
past where
here in canada it gets so cold that the
humidity will start
creating ice on the windows
and then start dripping down and stuff
and dripping down your window and if you
get too much of that stuff it can be
really bad ruin
all the wooden stuff onto the windows so
i
really don't like humidity at all
anymore and try to stay away from it
do i see much of a difference with
growing
not really um compared to when i've had
it i like
really
perfect humidity i haven't noticed that
much of a difference so
i just try to keep it simple
if it's low humidity and it's doing good
why not
just keep it at that and not have to
worry about molds when you say low
humidity what percentage around is that
here
it's normally around 40
something like that okay so not critical
no not there's some places where it's
like 20 i just really don't want it to
go up to like 50 55 60 that's when i
started getting worried and i can start
seeing condensation on the windows
summertime i don't have to worry about
that but i'd rather just have a set up i
don't have to like mess with every
winter and summer that makes sense and
vpd you know as it it is optimal as we
all know you know science has proven
that that
vpd is out if somebody who doesn't know
about vpd you can search that and find
out a lot more details on that is a good
article from pulse
pulse monitor they have a good article
about vpd what it actually is what the
different ranges you should aim for
during the different stages of growth
there's charts that you can go by
i've been going after v i've been
chasing after vpd for the past several
grows
and
you know there definitely seems to be a
little bit different in growth i would
say from my experience as far as mostly
about like quality blood structure i
feel like as i'm running low humidity
like i struggle here i live in the
desert oh yeah very dry here we're
looking at 20 natural humidity
30 natural humidity so if i don't have
humidifiers pumping things up there
you know pumping that humidity up and
getting high i do see impact with growth
in bud structure um that's just kind of
my experience but 40 isn't isn't
critically low and no
it's not true from my experience there
isn't a big difference between um you
know 30 i'm sorry there is not a big
difference between 40 and like 50 for
example
and when you talk about optimal vpd
specifically in the flowering stage you
know if you're running the what
78 to 82 degree range
you know the high 50s i think i believe
is the green range for it yeah just on
the cusp i think but
it works it gets me by um
yeah like it's it does get really uh
like like dry like that here too like
sometimes outdoor humidity is probably
like the same as yours
especially during winter time but
indoors when i got you know
16 pots five gallon pots full of water
and stuff right it does help
make the humidity in there and uh
keeps it pretty stable i'd say so yeah
all right so let's switch it up let's
talk about plant training techniques so
um arguably one of those things that can
impact yield a ton
i mean there's some websites out there
that say low stress training alone is
going to increase yield by 40 percent oh
yeah particularly with autoflowers
you know a lot of people do plant
training techniques because they want to
maximize yield right um so what plant
training techniques do you typically do
for autoflowers uh right off the bat i
start doing leaf tucking
so just tucking the leaves in any of the
big fan leaves that you can see that
kind of can tuck in between the lower
branches coming out so you can give
those lower branches a light it really
helps
yeah i would say the more low stress
training the better
some people get really into it really
just tie them down every place they can
and the more you can do it the better
your results are going to be the more
light that can penetrate through to the
lower branches and uh it's it's it's
definitely going to help
i've done it where i just don't do any
training at all compared to when i do
lots of training lots of training always
produces better results i completely
agree with you i've grown um now i know
when you're growing from seed there's
different phenos different growth blah
blah blah
but uh you know growing
the same cultivar
i had 10 different plants actually same
tender from phenos same strain or
cultivar
and some i did low stress training on
some i just grew naturally
and the ones i grew naturally i believe
it was uh
let's see a yield range from like three
and a half ounces up to i think five
ounces and then the low storage chain
ones always produce more than that up to
eight ounces wow yeah from low stress
training off off of an auto
and that was i think the highest yield i
ever got off of an auto was eight ounces
and that was with low stress training
um now what about topping that's one of
the debatable
topics on this is people say no high
stress training techniques at all should
be done
for autos or else you're gonna
negatively impact yield
topping you know is one of those things
that are high stress training techniques
do you
top auto power plants did you avoid that
or what uh
normally i just avoid that i'm not big
into topping at all
even for photo periods
i
more prefer super cropping but for
autoflowers i just
just don't do it i actually have been
thinking about just trying just for a
little experiment make a video put it on
my channel and just show people what's
the difference use the same genetics
but normally
it would take
what five six maybe seven days to
recover from that
which your autoflower could be using to
produce get like more branches getting
bigger instead of just trying to heal
so
normally i would tell
a beginner or some just get into
autoflowers don't top just stick with
low stress chaining
and
but if you're getting more advanced and
you want to just try it out
like we were talking about before
different genetics can handle it better
it seems like
i've seen some amazing grows people
topped it and had awesome results
i've also seen people top and get bad
results so it kind of really depends
depends on how you're growing them to
depends how big these plants are getting
like are you growing a small little
plant that's not going to get more
bigger than a foot and a half or are you
growing a plant that's normally can get
up to
four feet because there's the super
autos that get really big and then
smaller autos that say really small so
i it kind of depends but me personally i
just don't do it i low stress train
enough that it
pre creates a like a decent bush and a
nice canopy right but like you said like
when you grow just let it do its thing
and stuff
the
plant will normally grow up like a
christmas tree you'll get some really
nice buds on top the first you know
one third of it the rest are kind of you
know not that greatest of quality of
buds
so when you have a nice canopy and
you've got way more top buds all getting
the good light
it comes out better i'd say yeah i've
topped autos handful of autos in the
past and obviously i've grown plants why
i haven't topped them and
just every time it's been
more yield off of the non-topped plants
that's just my experience and there's
going to be people in the comments again
that say they top autos every time and
it doesn't impact growth
you know maybe i just need to experiment
more but
i'm pretty sure i've like accidentally
topped some too
the results came out good but that the
question is would have would have it
been better if you just
not topped it at all and just low stress
chained until you got a nice big canopy
that's uh you know all nice and even i
would say a better big canopy is
going to give you better results i would
say yep highly debatable product on
topping autoflowers versus non-topping
autoflowers i'd love to know in the
comments below
for those that are growing autos do you
top them let me know your experience
doing that cool
and you talked a little bit about
pulling the branches out do you do
anything for like plant support you know
scrub technique anything like that in
order when you're growing your autos or
no not really like
my autos compared to my photo periods
because i i grow my photo periods a bit
bigger uh my autoflowers seem to be very
sturdy i never really need to like
tie them up or anything or have uh
stakes
tie them steaks or whatever or do the
scrog nets
uh yeah autoflowers
the ones i grow uh seem to do really
good with without so yeah okay
so
that being said we kind of went over a
lot we went over nutrition went over
lighting over environment
all for autos and kind of talk about
things that
that you do in order to maximize yield
right so everything being said and every
all your experience growing autoflowers
what advice do you have for people who
are new to growing autoflowers and what
advice you have for people who are
trying to maximize yield with
autoflowers one of the most important
things is start with good genetics of
course
stick with some reputable brands um
the thing with autoflowers is you can
get some not so reputable reputable
brands and they may not actually be full
autoflowers i've had that lots in the
past where you've grown it and it's not
actually autoflowering and then you have
to switch it to 12 and 12 light just to
get the flower
you kind of know that those genetics
aren't really you know stable
uh so i always recommend mephisto
uh always had great result results with
them and uh
like we were talking about in the past
or in the start there uh start i
recommend people start in the past
they're gonna finish in so three gallons
or five gallons
uh i recommend that they use a good
medium
a lot of people just use
i don't know some some people just go
the the hardware store and get some just
random dirt i don't recommend it i
recommend getting something good quality
at least some pro mix
some good quality cocoa or you know
there's some other stuff out there
but definitely stick with some quality
medium
and when you're feeding nutrients it's
don't go by what they're actually
telling you to go on the bottom the
bottle uh the instructions it's normally
at least half or even one third of what
they're telling you to use
and because autoflowers are very
sensitive to nutrients they can get
overfed very easily it seems like well
actually depends on the genetics too
but yeah that uh
keep your power good make sure you're
not giving them too much par or too
little par and uh
yeah just try to not stress them as much
as possible if they're not stressed they
can just take off and do the thing and
you'll get some awesome results if you
stress them too much you mess with them
too much so you can kind of
kind of stunt the stunt your results
really good advice there yeah you
touched on a lot of pieces that are
really important when it comes to autos
for sure yeah so how can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future
uh you can find me over at the dr
autoflower channel there on youtube or
dr our flower on instagram those are the
best places to see me uh things i got
coming up i have a new season started
right now um
we are
i'm just starting some new autoflowers
right away getting them planted here
today uh and
yeah i got some photo periods going too
i do grow a lot of frodo periods and
mix it up with the autoflowers
i like to do pheno hunts
so can't really do that with autoflowers
as you know as well
so that's why i kind of stick with
photo periods if i'm doing phenol hunts
but yeah you can find me over there and
got a new season new content coming out
so yeah cool i will link dr autoflowers
channel down in the description section
below for those of you watching on
youtube or i mean if you're tuning in on
one of the podcast platforms just search
on youtube dr autoflower and his channel
will pop up so lots of good stuff right
there
well dr flower thank you so much for
coming on to the podcast today
thanks for having me on and i hope you
enjoy the rest of your day
you too man have a good one cheers
[Music]
you