coming up on garden talk i typically
lean more towards liquid cultures just
because i can store them in my fridge
for quite a bit of time and slants or
even just in a in a jar actually popcorn
is one of my favorite go-to's just
because of availability it's very very
easy to find some organic popcorn and
you can boil that up and sterilize it
that is a really important factor you
want to make sure that you're just using
enough to saturate and mix between the
grains but not actually create puddles
anywhere
if you see any green i would just ditch
the jar don't even open it get your bag
whatever it is as it spreads very
aggressively don't get disheartened
you're gonna see a lot of contamination
but once you actually get to the
mushrooms it makes it all worthwhile and
you get some awesome food and some just
some nutrient dense goodness
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 75. in this
episode interview corey from htg supply
he has many years experience growing
gourmet mushrooms and that's what we're
going to get into today there's
definitely a more beginner friendly
episode talking about the steps to grow
mushrooms from the equipment all the way
through harvest thanks to all of you who
support this podcast through patreon if
you'd like to support you can do so by
going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to mars hydro for
sponsoring this episode they recently
launched new all-in-one grow kits they
have a new 3x3 kit and 4x4 kit under
their regular grow kits then they also
have new thermostat control kits for 2x2
2x4 and 4x4 all kits come with a grow
tent grow light ventilation system a
timer trellis net grow bags and a
thermometer hygrometer check out their
website at mars hydro.com they'll have
sales on these kits every now and then
and you can use the discount code mr
growit for a discount on any of their
products gorilla grow 10. check out
their carbon filters to help get clean
contaminate-free air the filters remove
odor pathogens disease-causing spores
contaminants dust and bacteria from the
air they use a two inch thick layer of
coconut carbon which is the most
eco-friendly and sustainable source of
carbon it has a significantly higher
density of micropores compared to other
forms of activated carbon this results
in it being 50 more effective at
absorbing odors and contaminants go to
the website grow strong industries.com
and use discount code mr growit for 15
off ac infiniti is sponsoring this
episode they have two different series
led grow lights the ion board and the
ion grid the ion board fixtures are
board style and use samsung lm301b
diodes while the ion grid series has an
open center design and uses samsung lm
301h diodes i'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow lights and
you can use discount code mr growit if
you're buying off their website
acnfinity.com that discount code works
for all ac infinity items or discount
code mr growit15 if you're buying off
amazon
and we're back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
corey from htg supply how you doing
today
pretty good man about yourself
i'm doing great great thanks for asking
today we're going to talk all about how
to grow gourmet mushrooms so lion's mane
shiitake oyster rishi portobello turkey
tail the list goes on there is lots of
medicinal value when it comes to
mushrooms so i figured it'd be a great
to have somebody on the podcast today
that has many years experience
cultivating them so we're going to talk
about how to cultivate mushrooms so
really excited for this one but first
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and kind of how you got into
gardening yeah definitely man uh so
pretty much since i was just a young kid
my family members my mom and grandma
have always had a pretty big plot garden
uh raised in the midwest where just
about everybody is related to a farmer
in some way shape or form
uh and it's very therapeutic for me uh
just quieting down in the garden and and
focusing so uh all that being able to
tie into a hobby that i could feed
myself
it was just bound to be it was like i
was made for it and then when did
mushrooms come in like how long have you
been cultivating them and what made you
get into them uh specifically about
seven years ago um
i was at a restaurant and i pretty much
really didn't like mushrooms that much
at the time
and i had a really awesome mushroom dish
and it was mostly oysters there was also
some shiitake
diced into it
but it was just really really good and
blew my mind because i thought i hated
mushrooms
and then once i
you know dived deeper in and seen how
many different mushroom options there
were i realized i was just eating gross
mushrooms rather than having really good
quality ones
uh then you know realize that it was a
plant and it was you know essentially
something that you could grow yourself
and uh
so then i went ahead and learned how to
grow it awesome and then what type of
mushrooms have you cultivated in the
past and what are some of your favorite
mushrooms to cultivate
i've done pretty much uh oysters
piopinis lions maine shiitakes
chestnuts trumpets
right now my favorite is the black pearl
king oyster it's a hybrid trumpet oyster
it's really really good it gets really
thick and meaty and you're able to
really do a lot of
meat uh like mock meat dishes with it
it's really really good nice nice i know
there are several different ways to
cultivate mushrooms it really depends on
the type that you are looking to
cultivate there are different tools and
equipment that you need to grow
mushrooms
what are some of the tools and equipment
that are needed talk about container
substrate light so on and so forth
yeah yeah so uh it's it's pretty uh
straightforward you'll need somewhere to
create spawn in
uh i.e like a bag or a jar something
like that
and then you'll also need a pressure
cooker that would be pretty important
that's for your sterilization and uh
pasteurization
uh then you're also going to need
somewhere to actually grow the mushrooms
in like a fruiting chamber or a martha
tent or even a mono tub there's a lot of
different ways you can grow mushrooms i
have quite a few customers here at my
hydroponics store that use entire four
by four or ten by ten grow tents
to turn into a giant fruiting chamber
then past that you'll need
you know a lot a lot of isopropyl
alcohol that's probably the thing you're
going to go through the most
sterilization is key when growing
mushrooms
very small led light or a t5 fluorescent
or at a minimum even like a small rope
light
those work out really well
um
and then you're gonna need your
substrate itself uh i typically like to
roll towards masters mix
the masters mix is a 50 50 blend of uh
soy whole and uh oak so they take uh
pellets of the compressed oak and
pellets of the soy hole and mix it at a
50 50 rate and that's really what the
mushrooms these gourmet mushrooms really
want is a heavy
wood latent substrate gotcha and then
you can either start with
spore syringes or liquid cultures can
you talk to us about the differences
between those two maybe talk about the
pros and cons to each of them yeah
definitely
uh so they both have really good value
in mycology uh
typically your commercial
spore syringes will be a little more
broad
spectrum of uh spores inside of them
meaning that it's gonna be more than
just one uh fruiting body or mushroom
cap that the spores came from
meaning your gene pool will be very wide
in phenotypic expression
you'll get you know big ones small ones
short fat ones you'll get all these
different sizes whereas
typically with a liquid culture it's
done from a specific mushroom if it if
that's how i like to do it you can get
multi-spored liquid cultures
they just tend to not grow as well than
a single single strain liquid culture
liquid culture is definitely a lot
faster because you're essentially
starting with
a liquid suspended mycelium rather than
the spores
which if you think of the spores
more like a seed
in layman's terms
that's what's going to grow the mycelium
and the mycelium would be considered
like the roots of the mushroom
so it's you're running with already
pre-germinated uh roots essentially
versus starting from spore which you
have to germinate and create that
mycelium so you just get a lot
faster colonization rate
and typically a lot less contamination
because those
commercial spore syringes
coming from multiple mushrooms there's a
lot more chance for contaminants to be
inside those four syringes
yeah both are really really good
i typically lean to
more towards
liquid cultures just because they i can
store them in my fridge for quite a bit
of time
in slants or even just in a in a jar
they really really work well for having
a lot of
mushroom seed on hand so to speak and
kind of keep them in my fridge a couple
different strains in there different
times and i can kind of rotate in and
out
that's uh pretty cool when you have the
liquid cultures whereas the spore
syringes
i think of it just like spores and water
uh
if you leave them in there too long they
can't germinate inside the syringe and
uh if there was a contaminant in there
those contaminants are gonna grow inside
your spores wrench
um
yeah uh most most cultivators though
tend to tend to lean towards the uh
liquid cultures for sure i actually have
one grow under my belt i ended up buying
a
kit so it has a kit with all the tools
and equipment in it
and from my understanding they sell the
spores separately so most of the time
you have to find a source for the spores
i actually started with the spore
syringe i've never done liquid culture
before so just the spore syringe and
then the kit together and i was able to
have everything i needed in order to to
completely grow first thing i remember
having to do is like they had
had the sport syringe and then it was
the inoculation so i had a it was a
mason jar and it came with corn kernels
in it
and and there was sealed up top and
there was a way for you to stick the
syringe in through the top and then
inoculate those corn kernels
what do you typically inoculate the
spores into
i actually popcorn is one of my favorite
go-to's just because of availability
it's very very easy to find some organic
popcorn and
you can boil that up and sterilize it
and use that another really common one
is uh rye grain berries uh another one a
couple of my friends like to just use
oats just just plain oats
millet's another really popular one uh
really
all depends on preference i find
uh and your technique
if you if you don't have a pressure
cooker uh you might only be able to use
uh millet or something like that
just because
the smaller seeds you don't have to get
as hot to
to sterilize
so
yeah yeah a couple different uh grain
options but just about any grain will
work if it has starch inside of it it's
a really good option
i would say availability would determine
which one you want to use but uh just
about anyone can go to the store and
pick up some popcorn and uh actually
works pretty well all right and then i
remember putting i think i put like
three milliliters
within that container size which had to
have been like a quart size mason jar
that was like probably halfway full of
the kernels put like three milliliters
in there is that pretty standard for all
types of mushrooms or does it really
depend on the the type the variety of
mushroom for how much spores you want to
put in there
so i would say it's more relative to how
much spawn you have inside the container
so if you had like a three pound bag you
know of spawn you would need anywhere
from five to even eight mils or cc's of
that uh spore syringe into it but these
smaller containers you can definitely do
you know one cc three cc's
but what you run into
uh with
with that could be an issue where you're
using too much of these uh
spore syringe and actually put too much
moisture into the jar
so
that is a really important factor you
want to make sure that you're just using
a enough to
saturate and mix between the grains but
not actually create puddles anywhere
that's good advice there and then like i
mentioned i don't have any experience
with the liquid cultures how would you
go about like the inoculation process
with the the liquid cultures
yeah so there's a couple different ways
you can do it my go-to way is just good
old carro syrup uh just like corn syrup
uh the unflavored is the best uh lately
i've only been able to find like vanilla
flavored uh definitely try to get
unflavored corn syrup
or any uh carbohydrate will do well you
know you could use molasses if you
wanted uh some people will use cane
sugar coconut sugar
uh
coconut water
but i do prefer just water and uh some
carrot syrup uh and then what you do is
you'll uh cook that up to uh
sterilization temperatures
for about 15 minutes in your pressure
cooker about 15 psi
um
then once that's been sterilized you can
then let it cool down to room
temperature and then you will inoculate
your
spore syringe or your liquid culture
into the the broth that you've made
and then ideally you'll want to put it
on like a magnetic stirrer with a little
stirring uh device inside the jar but at
a minimum you can just hand stir it
maybe once or twice a day
and then after about 10 10 to about 20
days depending on the temperature of the
water you'll start to see that mycelium
grow in the jar
and then you can literally just pull it
up with a syringe and inoculate whatever
you like with it okay and then after
you've done the inoculation process into
your grain or whatever you're using what
conditions should that be
in you know is there a certain
temperature that yeah that should sit in
in order for growth to occur
yeah definitely your inoculation
temperature is going to be roughly
anywhere from about 75 74 all the way up
to about 82 degrees
warmer the faster but also
some contaminants do grow at warmer
temperatures
so i find that a little bit lower into
the 78 uh 77 range is really fine for me
and it really gives me a pretty
aggressive mycelium growth
but you'll go you know into
from your
jar let's say like you had in your kit
once that's been fully inoculated and
colonized and you see a lot of clean
white mycelium in there and then you
would dump that grain out in a
sterilized environment
i ideally like a in front of a laminar
flow hood
or
at a minimum like an upside down glove
box
which is just a box that you take you
cut some holes in the side of it so you
can reach your arms inside of it and it
gives you still air
and that still air will make it so
you're not getting a whole lot of
contaminants and you can spray a lot of
alcohol in there before you open up your
jar and then you'll pour that into your
substrate bag
uh or your substrate tub or whatever
you're growing in your your vessel
you're gonna fruit in yeah i used a grow
tent and kind of use that as the place
to sterilize so i had a little table
within a grow 10 and like use lysol and
wiped everything around with isopropyl
alcohol and just tried to sterilize it's
really important because it can go bad
right you can have uh you can completely
ruin everything if you don't sterilize
yeah and so that's super super important
i think i aimed for about 78 degrees
fahrenheit as i was aiming for and i got
some good growth
and uh in the court mason jar was about
i think it was about halfway full of the
kernels i think it took like
60 days maybe or something like that to
fully inoculate so what's the time frame
i mean i'm sure it's dependent on a few
different things but like how long
should it take to like fully inoculate
yeah so depending on what type of
mushroom it is is definitely going to
greatly affect the inoculate or the
colonization speed but typically most
gourmet mushrooms are going to be
anywhere from about 10 to about 30 days
and all those streams are going to fall
right inside of there some of uh
other mushrooms might take uh
anywhere from about 14 to seven days uh
for full colonization depending on grain
as well like the popcorn we were talking
about one of its caveats is it tends to
colonize a little bit slower just
because it has a harder outer shell and
its surface areas a little bit greater
versus like your millet which very very
small seed kind of like bird seed if you
if you've ever had a bird before it's
the really really small seed in that
seed mix
uh and that seed being very small uh
will be taken over by that mycelium very
quick and it'll penetrate into the seed
and consume it
all right and then after they have
inoculated
what should they look out for like each
day you know what are there signs of of
good growth happening and what signs of
bad growth happening
yeah so uh you'll see the the mycelium
uh start growing and from wherever it
does grow it almost seems like it's a
random point in the jar that'll start
growing but from there it'll kind of
nucleate outwards from these points
you'll have
you know multiple points inside the jar
which will have this spherical or
cylindrical growth rate away from it
and you want to see a nice run of that
mycelium daily you might some mycelium
you might see inches some you might see
centimeters
but what you want to see is that even
growth rate and stretching and consuming
those grains and what you want to look
out for is contaminants
anything that is in a really nice white
healthy
clean looking mycelium
is going to be considered a contaminant
unless it's a metabolite
metabolites are kind of an amber
brownish liquid
uh consider those guys like a waste of
the mycelium it's going to be uh
in layman's terms mushroom poop and pee
it's uh it consumes uh the food source
and uh releases that uh that exudate of
metabolite and uh it's actually uh
antiseptic i believe uh so it's uh
pretty sterile on itself at nature
but the contaminants that you're going
to want to look for are mostly
trichoderma
either that or cobweb mold
trichoderma is going to be a very very
green mold
also
parts of it can be gray and even white
but green is really the main thing
you're going to want to look out for if
you see any green
i would just ditch the jar don't even
open it get your bag whatever it is as
it spreads very aggressively and it can
sporulate inside your grow space and be
very hard to get out but yeah just
really looking for those uh small
growths in mycelium and checking for
contaminants
uh and
patience what about blue mold is that a
thing uh blue mold
like growing on the mycelium itself or
on the actual food yeah i mean you see
that often like with the compost for
example if you're composting and this is
like a blue type of mold that occurs is
that that ever happened on the mushroom
side of things when you're growing
mushrooms or no there's hundreds of blue
molds but a lot of
blue is typically
uh bruising of a particular type of
mycelium
usually active mushrooms will have a
bluish hue there are a lot of other
mushrooms that have the same bluish
bruising to it
but the most common ones are active
mushrooms there are definitely blue
molds not super common inside grains
though you'll see more green
molds pink molds
you'll also see
very very common is bacillus
or wet spot is what it's considered in
the mycelium world
and that looks very very like brown and
slimy uh just looks very gross
uh almost like snot and brown is growing
on your uh your grains there and once
that happens that's another you know i'd
consider that just toss it out
one thing with with mushroom growing and
mycology if you're getting into it
don't be disheartened by failure or
contamination i wouldn't even consider
contamination a failure
i would consider that a learning point
you know most contamination
can be tracked back to poor technique
uh and what i mean by that is like your
sterilization process or how much did
you use iso did you clean your tools in
between transfers uh did you make sure
your room was sterilized or even worse
was the
culture you were using contaminated from
the beginning so there's going to be
quite a few failures and
complete loss i've lost whole
growth tents just full of
gourmet mushrooms
due to quite a few different things and
it just happens happens to everyone
so don't get disheartened you're going
to see a lot of contamination but once
you actually get to the mushrooms it
makes it all worthwhile and you get some
awesome food and some
just some nutrient-dense goodness
that makes sense
so let's say the person is successful
right and they they fully inoculated
their jar or their grain is fully
inoculated they're ready to change over
to the substrate
what do you use for a substrate i
particularly like to use masters mix for
the gourmet mushrooms
which is that 50 50 blend of the oak and
soy hole pellets
but a lot of
saffrophilic mushrooms which are
mushrooms that
eat decaying waste and matter
and those types of mushrooms really like
to grow on
a multitude of different substrates most
common vermiculite and coconut uh
coir mixed together with some sort of
manure or even a worm casting
but for the gourmet mushrooms
it is most common
a
oat or a hole of some kind with a heavy
amount of wood and there's lots of
different blends but i particularly like
the masters mix from mushroom media
online
really really awesome stuff i'm actually
working on getting it in my store
but
you can take a couple scoops to the
desired amount of weight you want to
have and add x amount of water
and you have all the substrate you need
pretty cool stuff nice i have to check
out that blend sounds like a good one oh
yeah the one that i used i have it right
here it's a two pound bag pasteurized it
was dehydrated elephant and horse manure
vermiculite and gypsum does that sound
like a pretty decent substrate is there
anything that worthy of calling out
there that maybe be a pro or a con not
necessarily that all seems pretty all
right other than it being elephant uh
and i'm certain that's a great you know
dung source
i would only consider like its
availability i think it might be a
little hard to get elephant poop on the
regular unless you live by a zoo
and the zoo you know was willing to give
it away then definitely go for that
stuff
but with any poop or manure or dung you
want to make sure that it's properly
composted and aged
because with a lot of comp or a lot of
dung and manure if it isn't properly
composted and aged
it can pass on salmonella
quite a few other food borne illnesses
so you want to really make sure that
you're getting manure from
a farmer who knows what he's doing and
has aged his product properly and
contaminants will come too so
good to know yeah that's really good to
know okay so at what point do you
actually
transfer what you've inoculated to the
substrate and how do you do it and feel
free to break it down in details you
know what i mean even down to the nitty
gritty details of putting on the gloves
to make sure
that uh you know everything's clean and
sterile and all that stuff okay well
i'll start by saying uh i'll get the
repetitive part out just in between
every step insert the step where you
spray down all the surfaces your hands
your tools and everything
with isopropyl alcohol unless you are
using a alcohol flame for needle
sterilization
then you do not want to be spraying
alcohol
because then it's flammable and that
will that won't turn out well
but insert
alcohol sprays everywhere
but you'll definitely want to glove up
a glove box if you don't have a laminar
flow hood uh and we'll just go with the
glove box option because not everybody
has a laminar flow hood they're pretty
big and pricey and bulky but just about
everyone can make a glove box so you're
going to take the top of your glove box
off and you're going to put all of your
work inside of it
and then you're going to close your
glove box and by work i mean all of your
petri dishes or spore syringes or your
bags or tubs or whatever you're working
on inside this clean space
spray with alcohol you might have forgot
already
then we're going to
open our mycelium or our spawn or
whatever we're using
inside the sterile environment and dump
it into the substrate mix now your
substrate mix might be in a big tub it
might be in a box
it might be in a small
bag mix it up inside of there you can
get very large glove boxes like
i think they're about like 32 or so
gallons the big rubber made totes with
they're all clear plastic i recommend
the largest one you can find that way
you have a very large workspace and
you're not confined to this little shoe
box
um
but yeah uh sterilized sterilized
sterilized
and then you're gonna actually pull that
mycelium out and place it into your
substrate break it up really fine and
mix it thoroughly into it
and then you're going to cover your
inoculated substrate
from the light and you're also going to
want to seal the co2 in so if you have
any
breathing ports on the side of your mono
tub or
a
filter patch on the side of your
mushroom bag there's a certain way you
can fold that patch over so it's not
just dumping out all the co2 and then
the mono tubs you can just put tape on
your
side holes on the mono tube there
to trap that co2 in and then you're
going to let it sit for about 10 to
about 30 days for that substrate to
fully colonize
just like our little jar did it'll
completely turn nice and white like a
big old brick
and then once we get to there
we can start going into our fruiting
initiation you mentioned clear tub
now i actually use a clear tub as well
it's like a i want to say it's probably
maybe 18 inches long by maybe about 10
inches wide so it's a height maybe uh
maybe a foot tall right it's a real
small tub it's you know i'm just going
personally for myself but
one thing that i was advised was to use
like i have like a clear like a black
plastic liner that you know you
sterilize and then put in there
and that helps with uh helps reduce
i'm terrible with the terminology i
don't know if it's called pinning or
something like that but basically these
it'll start to fruit underneath
the whole substrate kind of come off the
sides and just not like fruit naturally
out from the top do you recommend uh
doing something like that or i mean you
mentioned clear containers black
container would that prevent that from
happening uh yeah so if you went ahead
and like let's say that tote you have
where you normally put your uh your
plastic if you went and painted that
same length black or even covered it
with black tape that would effectively
do the same thing but i actually prefer
that plastic bag a little bit better
because you'll
sometimes get separation from your
mycelium block off of the side of the
plastic wall and the bag will actually
grab that mycelium block and really help
with moisture retention
and prevent that side pinning you're
talking about where you got those pesky
little mushrooms on the side that
you just can't get to or it's a pain to
get to them
and they just they're just not
aesthetically pleasing okay that's good
good tips there so you mentioned it's
going to take you know roughly 10 days
maybe even longer for
that substrate to be kind of completely
inoculated red is going to turn out to
be this white brick when do you
introduce light
you know what light should be added and
when should you add it
so you really don't need any light until
you're ready to fruit the mycelium block
or brick and that light really you don't
need a whole lot of it a lot of
misconception about lights and mushrooms
is that you need this big old powerful
light when you really all you need is
enough light to direct the mushrooms
which way to grow you know if you had a
150 watt led light versus you know a 50
watt t5 led light you're not going to
grow more mushrooms with the bigger
light
the the smaller light will do just fine
and almost the same exact job so i tend
to go with the really low dose low end
of the spectrum with your lights
uh literally a desk lamp if that's all
you have you can utilize that and
that'll be more than enough
rope lights are pretty efficient as well
at that
but don't need a whole lot of light and
then it's going to be a 12 hour cycle
very similar to most fruiting and
flowering plants
and that will
that mixed with fresh air exchange
which is going to be your co2 and fresh
air transfer from your actual fruiting
chamber
that with the 12 hour light cycle will
initiate your fruiting
fruiting conditions
okay so for the first two weeks or so
you are going to be under no light at
all and then once you add the light 12
hour light cycle that's when it's going
to start to fruit and you said there
should be exchange happening can you
talk a little bit more in detail about
the actual exchange that happens as far
as air the co2
yeah so you want to have a fresh air
exchange and and what that means is you
want to expel the co2 out of the grow
chamber or the fruiting chamber or
wherever you're fruiting at
because the mycelium will continually
make and produce co2 and if there's too
much co2 prevalent you'll get really
tall and leggy and stretchy mushrooms
that sometimes can't even stand up on
their own and they just look really
misshapen
and it's hard to get a nice good even
canopy flush of mushrooms
or even just get your mushrooms to get a
good yield off on
so
a couple different things you can do for
your fresh air exchange is if you're in
a mono tub which most most people
growing uh saphrophilic mushrooms are in
a mono tub
you'll have your holes on the side of it
typically
two on each side so right above your
soil line about three to six inches
above where your your substrate line
will be is where you'll want these holes
and then you want to think of co2
like water the way it fills up the rooms
it's going to fill from the bottom up
it's heavier than air
so you'll place your
holes
right above where your canopy would be
for your mushrooms so that way it'll
flow out
and then the fresh air exchange will be
going through
a little piece of polyfill or a filter
patch at 0.2 or 0.5 micron
i prefer the poly fill which is uh
really just the stuff you find inside
pillows you can get it at craft stores
and
join fabrics and all kinds of places
like that
uh
yeah you just pop that inside of the
hole so all the air going through is
filtered no contaminants are making it
through there
nothing but co2 and oxygen
and then another little step you can do
is open your uh tote daily and fan it
out but that typically will lead to and
you opening the door to more
contaminants
so i tend to not fan as much and try to
focus on having a proper fresh air
exchange with the holes placed properly
on the tub so that way it doesn't allow
the tub to fill up to
a really high level of co2
and like a an exhaust span on your tent
will help as well if you haven't you're
inside of one of those tents
uh fresh air exhausting out gotcha and
then mushrooms will start to grow you
can clearly see them at what point do
you harvest those mushrooms
yeah so depending on what kind of
mushroom it is uh if it's a gilled
mushroom or
i'm going to try to stick with more
layman's terms or like a polypore
mushroom which one has
gills and one doesn't if you're growing
the type of mushroom that has gills
you're going to want to wait for that
veil to break off and the veil is right
below the cap
and it's like this almost like a skirt
that connects completely around the edge
of the cap to the bottom of the stem and
as that mushroom opens up kind of like a
umbrella would it tends to pop that
little veil that connects and then that
mushroom pops open you can see those
gills
typically you'll want to get it right as
or right before that veil is bursting
and that's perfect time to harvest and
if you're growing poly pores
or oyster mushrooms or anything like
that
you'll want to wait until
the mushroom has opened up and the
bottom of it goes from curling down
towards where your stem is from curling
up it'll kind of it'll kind of look like
the bottom
it's a hard way explain like if you've
ever seen a blue whale where it holds
its neck up it has those big grates on
on its neck
you'll see that and it's almost like the
whale tilts its head up after looking
down it's really what it looks like to
me
and that's when your oyster mushrooms
are ready to go
but typically before they drop spores
if they're dropping spores really
heavily you've kind of went a little bit
past that window of when it's perfect
harvest
yeah the one i had this the veils opened
up and spores were released and i know
if you are
looking to do multiple flushes
basically if your spo if the veil opens
up and the spores get released it kind
of prevents more fruiting from happening
if i'm not mistaken and so like
i was always told harvest right before
the veil actually opens up to prevent
the spores from actually kind of getting
all over the rest of the substrate and
preventing those that fruiting from
happening
yeah definitely
those spores once they dump
if they're left there for long they can
start to contaminate uh you'll also
start to get new mycelium growing
because it is a a new mushroom
essentially uh so those new mushrooms
growing on top of that old mycelium you
might have a clash
where definitely it would it would halt
that that fruiting and kind of shift its
gear over to i'm being attacked by this
this outside external mushroom
uh and switch from its fruiting and yeah
you get some really weird stuff
happening and so when you go to actually
pick the mushrooms what's your preferred
technique i mean are you just going down
there with your hand and kind of
pinching it at the bottom and twisting
and pulling off or using you know
trimmers to kind of get in there and
prune at the very bottom of the base of
the mushroom or how do you do it yeah so
if i'm growing in a monotube i prefer to
actually grab that little piece of
plastic you were talking about and
actually pull the whole block out of the
tub and place it on a big old table and
i'll just take a pair of scissors and
right above the mycelium line just cut
like you would you're trimming the grass
or something cut all those down as low
as you can as close as you can
and then for those wood-loving mushrooms
most of the gourmets
i actually do those by hand and you just
kind of place your hand right up
underneath where the mycelium and the
fruiting body reach each other and then
you just kind of kind of jostle it left
to right and it'll just kind of pop
right off the whole mushroom and that's
how i like to do those ones and then
after you pick the mushrooms a lot of
people they'll do is they'll dry it i
know it depends on the variety and so on
and so forth but
talk to us about like the drying process
how long does that take do you just lay
it out on a paper towel for example or
should you be
doing something else with it
yeah there's a bunch of different ways
you can do it
i prefer the the dehydrator method it's
very quick and efficient
you'll set your dehydrator on on the
lowest setting some of them nowadays
even have a mushroom setting or
a nuts and fruits and berries whatever
the lowest temperature is
and then that could take anywhere from a
day to two days depending on how big the
mushroom is
or you can also air dry them just like
you would any other herbs or plants
um
let's say if you've ever done like basil
or oregano or thyme uh you get some of
those large drying nets and you can just
lay them out on the nets
for about 7 days sometimes 14 days
depending on the humidity and the
temperature in the room yeah yeah pretty
straightforward stuff but you will
definitely lose about 80 sometimes 90
percent of your mushroom weight to water
so when you when you're drying out and
you got this big hefty crazy full net
you come back in 10 to 14 days and it's
it's light and fluffy
it's like styrofoam almost makes sense
yeah there's some medicinal plants that
are grown and when they do the drying
process they lose about the same amount
of weight right like 75 80 percent of
the weight is actually water weight to
begin so you know they'll dry it and
then they'll they'll weigh it after the
fact and and see all the the damage that
has been done as far as like the amount
of moisture that has been lost there but
uh yeah very similar there i was gonna
say uh once they're dry
uh as long as they're stored in a you
know airtight container uh
i would say indefinitely they're they're
pretty much good and definitely as long
as they're not re-uh hydrated uh
you can really really long-term store
some mushrooms as long as they're
properly dried and uh stored in an
airtight container okay so we were like
a traditional plastic baggie you know
sandwich bag you would avoid that all
together huh
i wouldn't yeah i would avoid the
plastic bags uh unless you're
you might be able to do
like a skunk bag or like a grove bag but
i wouldn't do like a sandwich bag you'd
want it to be specifically uh or like a
food service mylar bag
you could definitely do one of those or
like a glass or steel
receptacle like a c-vault or a big glass
mason jar or something like that all
right cool
so i have lots of beginners tuning into
this podcast and i'm sure there's some
people that are either just starting
growing mushrooms or they're about to
start growing mushrooms taking a step
back and
looking at the entire process what
advice do you have for someone who's new
to growing mushrooms um it might sound
cliche but you know have fun with it it
is a hobby at the end of the day and
hobbies should be fun you know you
should be having fun while you're
learning this
and then i'll take it back to what i
said earlier where
uh contaminants are mostly in my opinion
from just a poor technique uh so all
that means is you might have just did
something wrong and that means you can
go back and fix it and do it right the
next time
so don't be disheartened
from failure and have lots of fun
and then my final one would be
kind of what you did as i'd recommend to
start with a kit
if you're really on the fence about it
there's a lot of companies that sell
kits
my company included
htgsupply.com we have quite a few
different little mushroom starter kits
on there they're mostly just substrate
that you'd add uh mycelium to like you
were saying you did
um but yeah just get a kit and have some
fun
sweet have to check out those kits i i'm
in need of another one because i ran out
of substrate and the uh the grain so
i'll have to uh shop through your
website next time around yeah contact uh
get a hold of me we'll set you up with
something awesome all right so wrapping
things up how can the listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future um
you guys can get find me through
htgsupply.com
or you can just come down into my local
store if you're in the illinois area
we're located at 4460
44th street in rock island illinois
and we have just about everything you
could need from gardening to mushroom
cultivation and then coming up soon
we have lots and lots of free classes
that our at our store you can check
those out through our website as well
we do
monthly free classes as well as free
monthly giveaways here in the store so
definitely come through and check us out
and one thing we don't charge for is uh
knowledge and information sweet we'll
definitely have a link to your website
down in the youtube description section
below if you're listening on one of the
podcast platforms just search for it
you'll find it in the search results and
i'd love to know in the comments section
what questions do you have in regards to
growing mushrooms i think this is a good
brief overview for beginners i myself am
a beginner when it comes to mushrooms
like i mentioned earlier probably missed
a lot of things so i'd love to know what
did i miss and what questions you have
in regards to growing mushrooms let us
know down in the comment section below
if you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend i release a new garden
talk podcast episode and i would love
for you to tune in to future episodes
corey thanks so much for coming on and
uh talking about how to grow mushrooms
this is something brand new to the
channel nobody's ever come onto the
podcast and talked about growing
mushrooms before so you are the first
thank you so much for spilling your
knowledge today hey i appreciate you man
uh i feel honored to have be on the show
and uh look forward to watching more of
your episodes
thanks so much peace out everyone see
you in the next episode