coming up on Garden talk the scrog
technique means utilizing and maximizing
my light and the space of my grow area I
like to use masonry 22 because it does
sometimes have that wax coating and it's
tough and it's nice and thin so those
are the three that I use to string up
the actual frame they're gonna get
bigger right at your screen level which
you don't really want because they're
not up as full as the light so there's
going to be a lot of little node sites
that you want to defoliate in your
flower defoliation so I want to talk
sooner so that means that my hole sizing
is going to be a little bit smaller so I
can talk sooner
you're definitely gonna probably yield a
bit more scrogging than you would
typically off a normal kind of plant but
only because you're going to be growing
top dense colas on your screen and every
bud you have is going to be a top Colo
that has density to it
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 86. in this
episode I interview Northern scrogger he
has been gardening for 20 years and is
well known for being a scrogger and
that's what we're going to get into in
today's episode he talks all about how
he does the scrog technique in detail
thanks to all of you who support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com Mr Grow it before we get
into it I want to acknowledge that one
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
zero cost for information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said I like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible
spider farmer is sponsoring this episode
spider farmer is doing a big sale for
Amazon Prime days this month October
11th and October 12th all spider farmer
products in their Amazon store will be
discounted and you can use my discount
code Mr grud5 for an additional percent
off they have LED grow lights grow tents
grow tent kits ventilation systems and
more search for spider Farmer on Amazon
and don't forget to use the discount
code Mr Grow at 5 for a discount on
their products AC Infinity is sponsoring
this episode their clip-on oscillating
fan is now released I've been using
their six inch version for over six
months now and I absolutely love it it's
easy to clip on the side of my grow tent
and it has 10 different speeds which
makes it easy to control air circulation
they do also have non-oscillating
versions of these clip-on fans these
fans are currently in high demand when
they sell out of the fans which I expect
them to often you can pre-order them for
the next release you can also use
discount code Mr Grow it if you're
buying off their website EC infinity.com
that discount code works for all AC
Infinity items or discount code Mr Grow
at 15 if you're buying off Amazon
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Troy
also known as Northern scrogger how you
doing today
yes thank you so much for having me here
one I'm doing good thanks for asking
yeah I'm glad you decided to come on you
actually reached out to me first
although I had many people reach out to
me and request that you come on they've
seen what you're doing over on your
YouTube channel and Instagram and just
really blown away at what you do in the
garden and that's kind of what we're
going to get into today is your style of
plant training more particular what
you're well known for is the scrugg
technique we're gonna really get deep
into it and what I mean by that is I
want to get into the Nitty Gritty
details of it so we'll ask some of those
deep detail-oriented questions so people
can learn your Technique and potentially
implement it in their Garden perfect I'm
excited to talk about it but I just want
to First say
um I appreciate that everything that you
do for our community Chris
um I've actually watched your videos on
YouTube went like quite a few years ago
I learned a lot from you man and um just
some all you little garden talk shows I
watch them and I learn a lot so I just I
just want to say thank you to me or from
me and a lot lot of people that probably
don't get to do this and talk to you and
say thank you like this so I appreciate
what you do first of all
yeah let's do this I'm ready now thanks
for your positive words yeah it's it's
positive words like that positive
feedback that really are fuel for us
content creators to keep going right if
we have people that are gaining value
from our content we're going to keep
spending our time making the content so
thanks for uh your positive words no
worries you deserve it how about an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah up for sure well
um what happened to me was I was
introducing at a very young age my
family actually used so I got I grew up
like knowing it seeing it a lot
um so when I was actually younger
probably about eight years old maybe 10
years old I followed my parents out to
the garage where I wasn't supposed to go
and I stumbled into like a kind of a
grow up just like what you see back here
it was just a white plastic sheets and I
opened up the plastic sheets and I saw a
few a few medicinal plants sitting there
and like that just kind of
that you first it was shocking but it
was really kind of cool to see right
so um
since then as I grew up in life I became
one interested in in this and uh
my mom started showing me a few little
tips and I was younger about how to grow
this product and uh and she was a
stronger kind of cool right so that one
taught me how to strong as I got older I
threw a few little of my own tips into
it and uh and things just took off from
there I just kept on stronging ever
since then I don't really grow anything
else uh naturally I'm the stronger so
yeah that's just I just called myself
other and stronger because I live in
Canada and uh in a little bit of the
northern region of Canada I'm not quite
north of Canada but we call ourselves
Northern Canada so I call myself an
order in scrogger that's so cool and now
you have a YouTube channel you have a
pretty big Following over there and
Instagram how'd you get into wanting to
produce content well yeah that's pretty
neat what happened to me was
during our covid when covet first came
out everyone kind of got laid off from
their jobs and I was one of them but I
always had a scrog going I I was always
a scrogger so that's when I was like you
know what I'm going to start showing my
strongs on Facebook groups I'm just
going to show my scrogs and I'm gonna
add a little tip to help people learn
how to scrog
and so I did that well one tip and that
one tip kind of blew up and a lot of
people liked it and a lot of people ask
me for more so like a week later I took
another picture of my grow and I was
like this is another tip this is when
you should talk and and like I added
that tip and that kind of blew up and
then people started telling me like you
should make your own group on Facebook
your own group so then I created my own
group called strongers which is my hat
here and that's on Facebook
um and then then I got told by people
that make an Instagram so I created an
Instagram called Northern instructor and
since then that that got deleted and I
have a new one called the northern
scragger on Instagram but but really
what happened was the initial Facebook
reactions was got me thinking like wow I
could really help a lot of people in
this technique and I should just keep
pushing and try to become good at it
good at creating content to help help
new Growers and help even experience
Growers they want to learn how to strug
that's awesome that's really really cool
so are you just an indoor grower or you
also do outdoors are you organic or
synthetic are you in soil cocoa Hydro
yeah I used to uh I used to do outdoor
grows but um once it became legalized
more so in Canada
I got right into the indoor girls like
steadily
um I like the indoor grows more because
I can control my environment the outdoor
grows I always like you do good but I
feel like later on in the season the
environment changes sometimes it's too
too humid for the for the like what the
plant needs stay late in flower and
you're not like high humidity and it's
pouring rain every day like I just got
sick outdoor growing so I just took it
right to the indoor and I am a synthetic
grower
um right now I use future Harvest
nutrients for all my satanic growing and
uh I want to learn how to organic grow I
just I just don't like the bug aspect of
it like sometimes there's a lot of bugs
with organic growing I know some bugs
are good bugs but I just I'm just not
there yet with wine bugs to be in my
space I just like uh
I'm just I'm good with synthetic right
now and I honestly feel that fans don't
tell the difference from like organic to
synthetic so I know there's a lot of
difference in like all the bottles you
have on the time it takes to mix the
nutrients like I get that part of it and
that is a that's a huge deal it's time
saving right there so
there's so many ponds or pros and cons
to each but I do gotta get into it and
destroy it and like expand my knowledge
that makes sense yeah outdoors in
particular it's a whole different
Battlefield right now luckily the plant
that we're growing that we all know and
love is a very resilient and it's going
to be able to adapt but yeah it's it has
its own unique challenges indoor versus
outdoor and organic for synthetic and
all that stuff but definitely like to
hear about you know what the guests
growth style is because uh yeah I can
definitely help lead the conversation
and I guess to start really basic
question I do have beginners that tune
into this podcast as well so when we say
scrog what is the scrub technique in my
mind well a lot of people mind the straw
technique is called like the screen of
green so this screen behind me would be
just full of colas eventually
um but really in my mind the scrog
technique means utilizing and maximizing
my light and the space of my grow area
so I'll build my screen the size of my
grow space that will work my light so if
I have a 5x5 flowering footprint light
I'll build a 5x5 screen and I'll
maximize that screen by filling it full
of colas as much as possible and then
I'll maximize my light to feed all of
these colas at the same height as each
other with a full canopy uh so really
that that's that's what strong is in my
mind is maximizing my light and my space
okay and then you answer my next
question which is what size net do you
use you just mentioned if you're in a
5x5 space that net size is going to be
five feet by five feet same thing with
the smaller spaces I assume that you
grow in your the lights coverage area
will be the size of the net is that
correct yeah
yes what you want to aim for but if you
have a screen that's like say four by
four screens you're only a four by four
ten I can still use lights that are
capable of a five by five stays in a
four by four tent you just don't have to
have it like turned up all the way or
dialed up all the way so so yeah like
that goes with each other
um
I just definitely wouldn't build the
screen much bigger than five by five
because most of our lights that we use
these days are a five by five footprint
uh you can you can't find much more than
that right now with the LED world
so um that's that's pretty much like
yeah you just gotta just kind of gotta
not use your head but just think about
your footprint of your light and the
size of the screen that you want to
build that's that's the main that's
that's really like what it is that makes
sense and then in these nets right
trellis net is often used there are
different size trellis Nets as far as
like the holes
what size holes do you go for I mean I
think there's three inches I think it's
four inches there might be some other
sizes as well but like what size holes
do you prefer in your net
in my net see I don't buy
trellis met I build my own screen
um so what I do is I build my own
screens anywhere from 2.5 inches to 3.5
inches and why I do that is because if I
go any smaller than 2.5 inches then
sometimes when your plants grow the nose
spacing gets tight and if you have a two
inch hole space then your nose will get
trapped and as your plant gets more into
flour those nose faces become Buds and
that's when they get fat and they expend
and if they're all stuck underneath the
screen that only has two inch hole
spacing you're going to get problems
like pm and mildew and no air move
basically because you're just you're
growing a real tight carpet so I like to
use like say 2.5 to 3.5 because now I
can like have space for each node to
grow up through a separate hole on my
screen
it's easier to talk when your holes are
a little bit smaller compared to say a
four inch hole size because if you have
four inch hole size then you gotta wait
for your branch to grow up at least four
inches before you can tuck it underneath
again
I don't really want my branches to grow
four inches because by that time they
are going to get a little bit thicker
they are going to develop more of their
nose lights are going to start thinking
like they're on a vertical growth path
instead of being on a horizontal dive
horizontal that I want
so I want to talk sooner so that means
that my whole sizing is going to be a
little bit smaller so I can talk sooner
so also why I tie my own strings on my
strong frames is for harvesting purposes
I like to cut my string when I harvest
and if I was to buy them every time
they're not cheap well they are
relatively cheap but not cheap in a way
right people want to kind of wrestle
their screen off and save that screen
for the next run
what I do is it's cheap so I'll just cut
down two sides of my frame and then I
just pull the twine it it just slides
right out perfectly whatever I use just
slides right out and the plant doesn't
just fall down it kind of just kind of
like mushrooms and just sits there ready
for me to chop it at the base
so so yeah I kind of went in a little
bit detail there but yeah the screen
hole sizing is just like 2.5 3.5 that's
my preference and that's what I would
use and I I build my own and I have
videos on YouTube on how to build your
own and it's really really easy and it
takes 10 minutes to string one of these
frames up once you have the frame built
understood yeah thanks for explaining
the pros and cons for the different
sizes I wasn't you know some of these
things you don't think of like another
reason why I like to string my own
scrogs strings
when I talk a branch I can actually grab
this one the twine that I use and I can
slide it with my fingers a little bit
and I can tuck that Branch under Slide
the twine and it'll hold the branch with
like one of the one of the fan leaves
will hold that twine and I can let go
and it'll sit there if you buy if you
buy a store-bought twine you can't slide
that position it at all it is it's there
like you can't move it over you can't
slide it this way so that's that's
another good tip right there it's like I
do move my screen around sometimes to
pull it closer when I talk so like I can
make it reach that's a good tip right
that I want to throw in that's a good
call out so using twine that you
purchased I assume from a local store or
online can you talk to us about like the
actual building of the frame by using
PVC what size PVC how are you actually
fixing the twine to the PVC so on and so
forth you talk about like the build of
it yeah so what I do is I use three
quarter inch PVC
and then and then I buy uh these little
tees that are called three-way tees but
what I advise new Growers is to buy
four-way pvcts that just gives you
another extension on the top if you ever
need a second trellis okay so what I do
is I build these screens three quarter
inch PVC and then whatever I want my
bowl sizing to be is I run
screws down the top of my screen three
inches right now all my screens are
three inch hole spacing so every three
inches I'll put a black mark then I just
get top tap drilling screws and I just
screw in every black mark that tapes it
pie takes me like to build a five by
five screen it'll probably take a good
like one hour it takes some time but you
have it forever and when you're not
using this Frame I can just take it all
apart into pieces and I can I can like
wrap it up in tape in a nice little neat
little bundle and I can store it
somewhere for when I want to start over
again I just pull it out put it all
together do my twine again which takes a
few minutes and then I'm ready to rock
so
I like to use twine I like to use
masonry rope and I like to use hemp
twine but there's a difference between a
lot of them if you're going to use a
twine you want to try to get a wax coat
of twine because the hairs Fray off it
and you'll have a bunch of like fraying
hairs on your on when you take pictures
you see a bunch of hairs on your twine
exposed if you use hemp twine it also
frays so you have a bunch of hair
exposed like fraying hairs off the twine
but hemp point is not bad because it's
biodegradable and you can actually
probably even smoke a little bit how big
it gets caught in there
um I I like to use masonry 22 because it
does sometimes have that wax coating and
it's tough and it's nice and thin so
those are the three that I use to string
off the string up the actual frame
that's good to know good good
information there now how many plants
are you doing underneath the net there
are you doing a a plant per square foot
or like how do you go about it yeah so I
like to do what I like to have at least
two by like two feet by two feet square
feet for one plant so if I'm like doing
a five by five strong I'll probably grow
like four plants under it
um if I'm doing like a like a like a two
by two strong frame because there is two
you can grow one plant under a nice two
by two frame and one plant it works
perfect or if I had a four by four frame
I'd probably do like two or maybe three
plants
so I decided to keep like yeah like two
foot area kind of for one plant at least
because I do veg for only like I know
people think I veg for a long time but I
really do only veg for two months from a
Seedling so really it takes a ceiling to
take off it takes out about three weeks
just for a ceiling to really start to
take off right that's three weeks right
there and then I'm then I'm talking
underneath this screen for like a month
and a little bit then flipping oh God
that makes sense and what would you say
the measurement is between the top of
the grill pot and the screen
yeah that's another good question what I
what I this is just what I do I'm just
going to tell you things that I do so
the way that the way that I strong is I
like to keep my screens six to eight
inches off the top of my pot I don't go
any more than eight and I really don't
even go eight anymore I just recommend
that is the maximum height and I only
say eight inches for like the elderly
people or people that like have to
really get under there and work on their
plants have really big arms you want a
little bit more space under there but I
like to go six inches that's my spot so
I like to keep my screen low as possible
because that's going to shorten my veg
time got it yeah I've actually heard as
high as 18 inches from the top of the
pot six inches actually the lowest I've
heard but it it makes sense you know
because exactly what you just said it
you can reduce the amount of veg time
you have your your real squat to the
actual net and uh yeah that's that's
it's good to know I get I can go into a
little bit of that if you want me to a
little bit why I keep my screens low
yeah sure and actually another question
would be when do you start the training
are you just bending branches down are
you doing any topping first or filming
first and then starting to get into the
screen or what yeah so good what I do is
um first I have my cups and or my plants
in like a solo cup
I wait about two weeks two weeks and a
couple days ish I put them in my five
gallon pot
and then I'm going to let them be in
that five gallon pot for like maybe one
a day twos one or two days just to like
kind of recuperate from a transplant
right just give them a couple days
soon as that plant is like enough for me
to start tying onto I'm going to start
training it
I might not top it right away I'm first
I'm going to bend it over I'm going to
put a little tie on its bottom stock and
keep the main stem coming from my soil
keep that straight then I'm going to tie
off to the top and I'm gonna I'm gonna
bend the top as I as I keep the main
stem firm and straight because a lot of
people a lot of people miss that step
they just tie from the top and their
whole plant comes on a lean now you're
like ripping the roots around you don't
see it but you're really like hurting
the bottom of the plant there so like
you really want to tie off this bottom
of your plant and then tie down
then yeah and then after I do after I do
that I will
keep on training that plan all the
individual branches that start growing
up I'll tie them to the sides of my pot
I'll do that for the first month of the
plant's growth so even from seedling
right for the first month I'm just tying
down the branches once I transplant it
and then after one month I put my
screens on and I get my plants all ready
for the screen and I just and I untie
all the branches from the pot and I let
the plant just kind of push off into the
screen
and then I continued tucking it for
another month so that this is where I
keep my screens low because my screen is
only six inches off the top of the pod
so that happened the plant will reach
that six inches real fast usually within
a month of growth it's up six inches
high
that now I'm not I'm not waiting for it
to be 18 inches high I'm using every
node on that plant even the first note
on that plant that most people trim off
in defoliation they trim off the first
few nose so they can expose the top of
their plant well I'm using every note on
my plant so I'll start training every
node all around my Branch all around my
screen for another month
and then that's when I will flip the
flower I always split the flour on two
months no matter what because I figured
out I'm strugging for a long time and
the size of screens that I use but we
just talked about how much I have for
per plant two feet by two feet per plant
I know that in two months it's it's
pretty much time for me to flip and I'm
going to continue tucking for that first
two weeks of me flipping the flowers so
during the flower stretch I'm still
tucking my branches underneath my screen
that's that's one of my main tips of
scrogging is keep on talking during the
flowering stretch now are you waiting to
flip the flower until every single one
of those squares is full or you like 95
full and then you do the flip to flower
or what no what I do is
I just I flip I flip at no matter what
at two months but I have um like I've I
figured out that like
it only takes two months to fill that
size of the screen that I use if I had a
big big screen with one plant I could
have veg for longer and try to fill more
of the screen up
you don't run you don't want to run out
of space on your screens because if you
run out of space on your screen then
you're gonna have runoff branches that
are taller than other branches on your
screen and now you're not maximizing
your light anymore because you got to
work your light to the top of that
runoff Branch you can't work it on the
whole canopy anymore so I I try to have
a little bit of space on my screen still
when I'm when I'm going to harvest I
want to see the edges still exposed
because I don't aim to fill my screen
and I don't aim for yield I aim for
Quality I'm here for quality over
quantity so that's why I do the two
month veg
um to fill up each hole in the screen is
actually really easy you're probably
gonna have two two bun sites purple the
way that I scrog so against against
really it gets really packed in a
certain way like but that's why you want
to have the three inch hole spacing
because if you don't have the three inch
roller spacing your three and a half
you're not going to fit two nodes two
Bud sites in that hole
to get too cramped with two of them
right
so yeah that's why I say three to the
three to four inch or three to or sorry
2.5 3.5 inch hole size on your screens
you mentioned some branches coming up
and and kind of outgrowing some of the
other branches in the net how do you
manage that is there things that you can
do in order to kind of control the
height like I know some people will do a
super copping for example so they'll
super crop that Branch allow the other
branches to grow up what do you
typically do for when when some of those
branches grow out of control and they'll
grow the other branches well typically
what I do is I tend I honestly I keep up
on my screen I'm usually there and I'm
working it every other day and I'm
talking branches so like I don't
normally have that many runoffs but if I
was to go away for say a while and I
came home and it was there was a lot of
runoffs I would like do the super crop
technique I like kind of pinch that
Branch stunt it a little bit if I was
still in like say vegetation I would
maybe top that Branch low and then start
talking the nodes that come off come off
where I topped it I start talking them
again and start working them into my
screen but yeah if I'm in if I'm in late
flower and and I have a runoff in late
flower then I you just kind of just
gotta ride it out there's not much you
can do in late fireworks you're not
going to Super crop that Branch it
because that could stress the plant out
too much you're not going to top it and
leave flowers so that that's that's in
my mind I'd be like oh I kind of messed
up on this drug because I let it get
away from me I've had that loss I've had
plans
they just keep on stretching in
flowering I'm like holy like it's just
it's just crazy girl you know but for
the most part I like to keep up on it
another thing is in late flour you'll
notice on your screens that sometimes
the center of the screen is pushing up
more so it looks like it looks more like
higher on a canopy than everywhere else
what I would do is go underneath my
screen and I'll just tie a piece of
string to at the actual string of the
frame and I'll pull it down and I'll tie
it to a weight as I look at my canopy
I'll pull it down so it's level again
and then I'll tie it a weight on and
I'll hold it there so I'll because like
once you use the screen like this you
can pull your screen down your whole
canopy will actually Flex up and down as
you pull on the screen so I'll pull on
my screen until it's perfectly level
again tie it off and then now I'm
maximizing my light again interesting
yeah the reason why I ask I know you
mentioned that you tuck for the first
week of flower and then after that
you're kind of letting the the branches
grow up so like as generally said that
the plant stretches for 21 days after
flipping the light cycle now of course
that's gonna depend on some factors
genetics what light cycle you actually
on and so on and so forth but uh that 14
days is what I was kind of mentioning is
like if you have branches growing out of
control within that 14 days what do you
do and you pretty much answered it there
so so at what point do you add a second
layer of a trellis you mentioned that
you have your net set so you can and add
in a second layer when would you add in
the second layer what would the distance
be between the first layer and the
second layer
so if I was the kind of stronger that y
EP you're strong and there's a lot of a
lot of Growers out there that like to
have that for sure
I would um what what they like to do is
like they like to fill their four their
first screen full and veg so they keep
on talking until everything is
completely full on that screen and then
they flip the flower once it's all full
and then they stopped tucking so that's
what that's the difference that I don't
do is I always keep talking when I
switch the flower they don't keep
talking they now let their plant their
buds rise up or their colas their
branches start rising up
but at this time now they're too like
from the from the training that they've
had you're gonna get a lot of skinnier
branches you're not going to get a lot
of those thick firm branches because you
keep on talking in your branches right
so the ones that are coming up now if
the screen are kind of flimsy they're
not as like strong and sturdy so you're
gonna have to add a second cellist for
support so I would recommend it to be
around like say six to eight inches off
your second screen once you flip the
flat once you flip because they're
probably going to be around they say
12 inch colas all together so if you're
sitting around eight inches you're going
to be supporting that pretty good
but I I sometimes like doing that
because if you don't have a lot of good
air movement within that Center canopy
and you don't have a lot of good light
penetration that's penetrating on those
inner buds
then I just feel like sometimes it's a
waste and like you're not now you're not
now you're not growing like nice pure
colas off the screen you're actually
just throwing branches with like with
like Buds and then like a stick and then
a bud down here maybe a bud but all the
buds are getting less like quality as
you go down
so
there is pros and cons to everything and
everyone has their technique and like I
appreciate all of them really I it's
just in my mind I just I just I just
don't see why why a lot of guys would
like to or girls would like to do the
double decker strong just just for the
reason of like exfoliating the center of
it and keeping it clean for the airflow
and quality of the light to penetrate
and stuff like that
got it I've made the mistake of talking
for too long before I took for like the
first 14 days and uh after that I didn't
get much stretch and so like that was a
that was a mistake because then
everything's kind of flat in your buds
are like mixed in within the net and
it's like what the heck I did this wrong
so like yeah that seven day Mark that
you do is probably something I'm going
to be doing in the future it seems like
it's a sweet spot you know you don't get
too much stretch to where it grows out
of control and you need that second
layer but you know you just got the 14
days of stretch and then um you know
those buds will hopefully be able will
be even across the canopy and be able to
stay up on their own without that second
layer exactly I aim for a six to eight
inch rollers off the top of the screen
so if you have an eight inch Cola it's
gonna support itself that's not going to
flop over that as long as you have fans
and your space blowing them around like
not blowing the hardcore but as long as
you have air movement always moving them
and dancing your branches around they're
gonna get they're gonna get strong if
you don't have air movement they're just
growing in a like a still environment
and nothing's moving they're gonna get
heavy and then they're gonna fall you
need to build the muscle and that's by
moving wind right and another thing is
like you just said I mean when you
scrubbed and you talk for so long
what happens is yeah you're going to get
a bunch of those little buds on there
but the way that I do it is that you'll
see all the all like the little branches
coming up then you'll see you'll notice
the ones that are caught and you can
snip them off you can snip off certain
nodes that you can tell aren't going to
make it up to the screen and so that
that's not like that's another thing if
you want to talk about exfoliating like
I get into exfoliating and I sniff off
all those that's what I actually was
going to ask you next is do you do any
sort of defoliating and adding into that
would be having that net there it can be
difficult to kind of get underneath the
net to water the plants or kind of
hovering over the net I know you can see
your setup you can actually have walk
all the way around but there's a lot of
people in grow tents and so do you have
any tips on defoliating under and above
the net and as well as watering and
feeding underneath the net yeah for sure
so what you can do is
if you're if you're someone that is not
good at bending down and getting
underneath the screen and like just
working in like on the ground basically
you can build a platform scroll kind of
like what I have behind me here you can
build it on like a table
and build it to your height where you're
comfortable to like you got you can like
you can build them as high as you want
as long as you have a good ceiling
distance right so you can build it
almost your height I high level I've
helped a lot of people in wheelchairs
build strong frames they can't stand up
so what what they do is they'll build it
to their eye level and they can just
stand there and reach in and work on
their plants just by sitting here and
reaching in
um
I use like a watering wand to water my
plants nowadays I just stick a little
wand in there and I can just water them
easily but I used to use a little bucket
like a little like a little yeah like a
little um jug
kind of like this truck right here
actually a jug just like this and I
would just water my plants just like
that
so it takes time doing that
and now I don't have the time just to
hand water like that so I have a cool
little water wand and they're a dime a
dozen these days you can find a water
wand but I got Canadian Tire or Home
Depot or whatever wherever your like
local places to shop you can buy them
everywhere now
um so yeah for defoliating is like
like I like to defoliate two major times
so one week before I flip my plants to
flower I will defoliate below my screen
everything below my screen
um all the leaves that are weighed
talked under there they're gone I'm
stripping all my all my stems that are
being stripped there if they haven't
made the top of this screen yet
and then after that I wait a week before
I flip the flower so I do it one week
before the flower exfoliate a lot of a
lot of stuff under my canopy that I wait
a week let them heal let them heal from
that defoliation because it does stress
them out a little bit once they get back
in their groove I flip the flower and on
day 19 I do another major defoliation on
day 19 of flower I clean up everything
below my screen one more time because it
all comes back
so I'll do another major cleanup and
that's my two defoliations but during my
second defoliation I'll look up in my
screen and you'll see nodes on the
bottom of branches that you scrog that
are trying to wrap around the branch to
reach the light but those ones just
aren't going to quite make it you're
gonna have to snip off a few of them
because they're gonna get they're gonna
get like like I just said they're gonna
get bigger right at your screen level
which you don't really want because
they're not up as full as the light so
there's going to be a lot of little node
sites that you want to defoliate in your
uh in your flower defoliation okay so
you're sacrificing some of those
branches that aren't going to make it up
and grow the six to eight inches above
the net which is kind of your ideal
height yes now are you doing any
defoliation so people do it towards the
end of flowering they'll do one last one
so like you can get down and ripen the
buds for example are you doing anything
around like day 45 I think is a common
day where people do a defoliation before
Harvest nothing major but I do remove
fan leaves here and there if there's a
big fan Leaf blocking a nice Bud site I
will sometimes take that fan Leaf off or
sometimes I even like just take like a
fingerling off a fan Leaf I won't remove
the whole Leaf I'll just snip off like
let's say the middle finger of that leaf
because sometimes it's just just a leaf
that's rubbing on a bud site or covering
a bud site and I'll take off just that
little tingling of it
um yeah that's that's something I do is
I do walk around and remove fan leaves
here and there tuck them under my screen
if I can tuck a fan Leaf I'll tuck it
under my screen before I remove it
uh yeah so there's always those little
once in a while pluck a fan Leaf here
and there but nothing major I just did
two major defoliations one week before
and 19 days after I flip okay and I want
to back up for a second because I don't
have a question that should have been
asked a little while ago which is
positioning the plant underneath the net
now you mentioned that you typically run
four plants underneath the net but you
also mentioned that when you're you're
training you're letting that plant grow
up right and then you're doing that one
Bend towards the side are you
positioning the plant directly
underneath like the center of the net I
don't know how to explain this like you
know what I mean like are you
positioning towards more like towards
the corner so that plant can grow
upwards towards the center yeah you're
you're getting you're getting close
there so I should I should have
elaborated a bit more of when I taught
my plants that I do top my plants once
okay when I do when I do bend that main
top over
eventually I'll get to that top say
after I transplant it a couple weeks
after I transplant it I'll top that main
stock that's growing I won't top that
means I won't top it to create two new
tops because those tops they're already
there I'm not creating two new tops
they're just two nodes below that top
right but now I'm going to what I'm
going to do now by topping is those two
new nodes or nodes that are exposed are
now going to grow and they're not going
to be as firm and stiff as the top that
I just topped off right because that
main stock is always going to be thicker
than the side branches that are coming
off it the main one is always going to
be thick so I top that main one just so
I could have flexibility and work the
two new branches into my straw so when
you were when you said I top and direct
that top somewhere I don't do that
because eventually that becomes two and
they split off in their own Direction
but what I do is I position my plants
under my frame so they have enough space
to come up and turn into a mushroom and
I try to keep it so they have enough
space on every side of each other of
like the plant so against my frame here
it has to have enough space here as it
does on this side of my frame beside
this plant here
so I see that mistake a lot in my in my
scrubbers group people positioning their
plants on the side of their frame so
when the plant grows up they have all
this room to tuck over here but now
they're already running out of space
here because they position their plant
too far into the corner so you
definitely want to give your plants room
to become like a mushroom that's what
you got a vision in your head is that
plant becoming a mushroom
and it's a lot about like future
business visualization really like when
you when it comes to scrubbing you got a
picture like when it's going to be in
the end and yeah you gotta think of a
big mushroom happening that's a good way
to put it yeah I never heard anybody say
it like that but it makes sense and you
can visualize once you say mushroom you
can certainly visualize how it'll be
yeah
now harvesting you already said one tip
which I think is fantastic which is you
cut the twine and then you basically
just pull out the twine and then are you
just cutting from the base to harvest
are you cutting individual branches a
lot of people get caught up because
they're using Nets and uh things get
intertwined you know and it's difficult
to remove the branch because you got the
net there so um backing up do you have
any like just general advice for
harvesting yeah the way I honestly
Harvest is I what I said is like yeah I
cut all the twine on just two sides of
my frame I pull it all out and then I do
I cut right from the base of my plan
and then I cut individual branches from
the main stalk of the branch I'll just
start cutting big branches off
because I now I want to like open up my
plant as much as possible when I when
you scrog that you're always like kind
of close together you're still gonna get
air movement but it's not like
it's real dense I want to get air
movement happening everywhere around
these around my buds now so yeah I cut
them into like just nice big individual
branches hang them all in the side of
tent or inside a nice room
and I'd let them hang just just like
that individually so I don't hang I
don't hang just big scrog plants I
definitely
a little bit how long do you drive for
and what are your drying conditions
temperature and humidity
I like to keep my temperature anywhere
from like say 60 to
4 degrees Fahrenheit and anywhere from
like say 60 to like or I should say like
from 58 to 63 degrees or percent
humidity
so and I'll let them hang up in there as
long as I keep those conditions in that
environment they can sit there for as
long as they want to
because pretty much they're going to be
carrying themselves in those conditions
after I like like first I'll okay I
should go back a little bit like when I
do Harvest I take off the big fan leaves
right away so I'll break down into
individual branches take off those big
huge fan leaves that I don't want but
I'll leave like the little sugar leaves
is what people call them the sugar
leaves I'll leave them on there and then
I hang all the branches and then I go
back about
I'll go back like say eight days nine
days later and I'll do another dry trim
just trim off all my branches
and I'll I'm usually like I have a nice
environment that I dry in so I'm not in
a tent I go right up into my space I can
sit there at a desk so I just keep on
hanging them and I let my let my plants
cure in the environment that I hang them
to dry in right after harvest you
letting them cure so you're you're going
through the dry period but then they're
just continuing it on through the Cure
how long are they caring for and when
you put them into containers yeah so
like I'll hang them I'll let them hang
up there for like
I've had them hang up there for like
over two months before like as long as
it's dark and it's it's at the right
conditions I'll let them sit up there
for as long as they want until I need
that space and then I'll jar them up but
particularly what I want to do is I'll
leave them in there like if I had like
if I had to like get going I leave them
in there for at least say 14 days
hanging up there drying in the dark and
then I would jar them and then I would
burp them every single day for at least
say probably half an hour and I would
get the humidity packs to put in my jars
at like probably like 60 humidity just
to keep it safe in there
but yeah like I always found that it
works out just to keep them in my space
so they keep nice and cold and a nice
humidity and daycare in there for me
just like that okay got it have you ever
tried using those uh Grove bags
I've used the Grove bags before too
uh
I I do like them
but I honestly like I do prefer the jar
method if I was to pick a method I'd
probably go back to the jar method I
didn't do the grilled bags quite 100
you're supposed to do it you're supposed
to like uh heat seal the top of the rim
like of the bag and I didn't I didn't do
that state that step so I can't really
like
give my opinion on them fully but um I I
did I did like them I know that they
they probably did their job but I might
have left them in the bag too long it's
not something that you want to leave in
there for a very extended long period of
time you want to let them kind of cure
and then take them out of that bag and
put them into like jars or something
that was my that was my experience but
like I said I didn't heat seal the bag
so that might have messed it up that's
interesting yeah you actually just got
the Grove bags that's funny I was I
forget what video I was I think it was
on the from the stash podcast because I
have another podcast and we we talked
about it and the comments would just
flooded with people that are like jars
are outdated this is 2022. everyone use
good Grove bags and I was like what the
heck are these grilled bags so I went
and bought some and I just started using
them so I didn't really have an opinion
on them yet but it sounds like a game
changer I mean supposedly you you put
your dried bud in there and then it it
cures itself it gets no burping you
don't need to burp it all apparently and
that kind of cures in the bag you don't
even need to open up the bag or anything
so um yeah I'm definitely gonna have to
try that out a little bit more I'm using
a storage right now and I want to see
particularly I live in a very dry
climate and I want to see if it's
sucking up the humidity some people had
said that they live in dry climates and
they're humidity at you know their blood
turns crumbles up over time so I want to
prevent obviously prevent that from
happening but yeah I just wanted to get
your opinion on the on the Grove bag
since they seem to be a hot product here
in 2022. yeah they are did you uh did
you heat seal the top of your bag
no I just just sealed up the bag with
the and then put it into max in my wine
fridge I have it set to 60 degrees and
actually I did put a packet there I put
some uh those humidity packs in some of
them and I put the I didn't put the unit
packs in other ones so I'm going to kind
of see the difference on that as well
yeah well I did I actually talked to the
girl big like the manufacturers like
right at the company themselves I met I
met some guy at some conference and he
told me that he highly recommends that
you need to heat seal that top of those
rims it even says that you have to heat
seal those for them to work the way that
they are designed to or else they will
not that dry air end in the bag
so you need like you need to heat if you
want to really do a proper test you got
to heat seal it and what he said to me
was use your girlfriend's hair
straightener and just go and just clamp
it on the bag and just warm it up a
little bit and it'll stay tight I'm like
okay man like I'll try it my next round
but I'm not gonna go do that now but
yeah he said he he said you got to heat
seal them or it's not going to do what
you think it's going to do
oh man I didn't know that yeah so I was
doing it wrong but uh let's get back to
the scrog I do have like one more
question and then we can kind of wrap
things up yield a lot of people are
trying to do this drug technique
specifically specifically for yield
purposes have you ever measured yield
when doing the scog technique like do
you have like a yield per square foot or
anything like that like
to measure yield when I was younger when
I was actually growing it for the reason
of
quantity
but um ever since probably say like the
last 10 years I don't even I don't even
weigh my Harvest anymore but what I can
say is like I used to always use a five
by five screen and I used to always roll
four plants under it and I typically
would get say like
eight ounces per plant on a two-month
veg
so I'd be like over a pound per pound
per run on my five by five frame I would
always get over a pound per run
out of four plants over a two-month veg
so like the longer that you veg the
bigger your yield will be but in my mind
nowadays
the bigger your yield the less your
quality because I just feel like the
bigger the plant is and the bigger the
buds are the less quality is there I
always now I find that my smaller plants
are actually more potent and more
powerful and more dense and they just
smoke a lot better compared to my big
huge plants that yield like say 15
ounces per plant like yeah that's
amazing but look at like it just doesn't
smoke that nice it just feels like it
just got like just fed a lot and like
it's just not as nice as my little
plants that that only veg for two months
that you know what I mean like that's
just where I came to now so but with
that being said like you're definitely
gonna probably yield a bit more strong
than you would typically off a normal
kind of plant but only because you're
going to be growing top dense colas on
your screen and every bud you have is
going to be a top Colo that has density
to it a lot of plants a lot of ways that
people grow is they'll have a lot of Bud
but a lot of those lower buds are not
going to be dense and they're not going
to be that much quality to it because
it's going to be fluffy mud
uh so yeah I just find that with the way
that I strong I have about 70 top
collars per plant that's the average 70
top colas and they're all about like say
around six to eight inches tall and
they're all dense and and yeah I
definitely yield a lot off one plant
but I don't measure it anymore I'm not
I'm not there to do that I'm there just
to just enjoy it myself and my family
really I agree that there's definitely a
balance between yield and quality and if
we pack up for a second quality is so
subjective right equality to me can be
different to you to the next grower to
the next grow so some people might think
that non-dense buds are quality
that could be quality to them right the
area stuff that might be quality to them
and they might say the dent stuff isn't
good quality you know so it's really
really subjective is what I found
because in the comment section it's just
people debate about it all day long on
what's quality and what's not quality
and it's just it's funny yeah like some
people love flowers that foxtail with
like so much box tails on them they love
that they see the trichome production on
the foxtail but like I wouldn't like I
don't like foxtails so much I like a
nice indicate density flower compared to
like a sativa Fox tailing plant so like
yeah you're right like everyone has
their own preference even in styles that
they grow
um everyone everyone has preferences in
every way they do things in life so and
they all work really everything works as
long as it works for you absolutely and
just like today talking about the scrog
technique I mean this is just one way to
go about it it's your style of doing it
there could be a whole bunch of other
people that do it differently than the
way you do it and it's not really a
right or wrong right there's just it's a
different way to do it and that actually
brings up a question for the folks
tuning into this do you do this drug
technique let me know in the comments
how do you do it do you do it the same
way that Troy does it or do you do it
differently I'd love to hear your
techniques down in the comment section
below is there any other things about
the scrog technique that we missed or do
you have any general advice for new
gardeners
um well for yeah for new gardeners one
thing that I always try to tell every
one of them is don't over water your
seedlings like when you first start
growing that's one of the main things
that people mess up on is just over
watering their plants
plants don't need to be over watered
they need oxygen so your little plants
let those pots dry out before you add
more water to them that's that's a
that's a really important step for a new
grower because I've that's what I
stumbled upon when I first started a
long time ago and everyone I teach they
stumbled upon that as well they drown
their plants basically they need oxygen
and uh and for the straw technique the
only thing that I can advise people with
if you want to try this out is to build
your frames of on a platform or even on
the ground if you're comfortable but you
need to build it to make yourself have
accessibility around it and able to work
on your frame so if you're you're in a
if you're in a 4x4 tent and it only has
one door in that tent you might not want
to scrog the way I do because you're
going to need to get to the side of it
and you might need to get behind it a
lot of tents have two doors so that
works or you can buy tents like I have I
have tents that have like it has one
main door and then two side doors that
come that flap down so you can work on
each sides or the front you need to be
able to access at least three sides of
your straw that's that's important for
anyone who wants to get into this and
you want to make your screen size
comfortable for you to work on with your
hands and water good tips so wrapping
things up how can the listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future well right now I
have something really exciting happening
actually
I started something called strong School
happening so that's on YouTube on my
YouTube channel I have a little series
that I is going to call to be called
scrog School I've already done two
episodes of it
and right now it's going to start
getting in the interesting times because
I'll be transplanting coming up now and
start doing the training so every
Thursday at seven o'clock P.M Eastern
Standard time I go live in this room and
I have cameras positioned everywhere in
this room uh the high definition cameras
and we just sit here and be like teach
how to how to scrog I teach you I show
you how to do it with my hands uh so
yeah that's Grog school
um
the Instagram or my Facebook page called
subscribers you can find me there
there's a lot of good starters on that
page if you're interested in strong just
go over to Facebook type in strogers a
group will come up we have 65 000
members in there and uh and they all
love it they're all be like post grogs
every day all day
so yeah that's that's my two major spots
Instagram I'm like the northern stronger
on there if you want to see my pictures
of scrogs I'm all about strong so yeah I
eat breathe and sleep strong
definitely sounds like you have some
exciting things upcoming the future I'll
definitely have a link to your YouTube
channel down in the YouTube description
section Below on this video and then if
you're tuning on one of the podcast
platforms just search from you'll find
them if you enjoyed this episode click
that Thumbs Up Button also subscribe to
the channel if you haven't already every
single weekend I release a new Garden
Talk podcast episode and I would love
for you to tune in to future episodes
Troy thanks so much for coming on this
has been a cool talk I appreciate you
revealing your techniques to the
audience and uh I hope some people
tuning in here will uh head on over to
your channel And subscribe to you and
and start watching your content because
you have some really really good content
over there Chris thank you so much I
really appreciate you doing this for me
and um
yeah like just thank you so much and
everyone for watching like I appreciate
you watching us and and yeah I hope you
enjoy the strong technique and keep
watching this guy man because he is
definitely going to teach you the ways
of life and the ways of growing and I
appreciate you Chris thank you so much
man thank you too all right peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode