welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned into the guard
Talk podcast this episode number 114 in
this episode I interview Sly AKA Loco he
has been gardening for 6 years and he
grows indoors he has experienced growing
with synthetic as well as organic inputs
and one main focus for him is growing
large plants and that's what we're going
to get into today he breaks it down for
us his style of growing large plants we
go over lighting environment conditions
Plant Nutrition plant training and so
much more if you want to see highlights
of these Garden Talk podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube
there you'll find short bite-sized clips
of these episodes I also have a
gardening Channel which has over 130
videos of plants that I've grown I'll
link that channel down in the YouTube
description section below one of my
goals for the this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode their clip on oscillating
fan is awesome I've been using their
6-in version but they also have a 9in
version it's easy to clip on the side of
my grow tent and has 10 different speeds
which makes it easy to control your
circulation they do have a
nonoscillating version of this clipon
fan as well it also connects to their
smart controller 69 so you can control
the fans and other AC Infinity equipment
through their app from your smartphone
the discount code Mr Grow 15 works on
both Amazon and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend I've been using
stash blend for over a year now and it's
awesome one of the things that I really
like is that it saves me money it's a
whole bunch of different inputs in one
so I no longer have to go out there and
buy a silica bottle then a separate
seaweed bottle beneficial bacteria then
a separate one for micro brazle fungi
all of that plus more is in this one
blend go to stash blend.com to learn
more about it and I also have a link
down in the YouTube description section
below and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with Sly AKA Loco how you doing today
pretty good brother how you doing good
good everybody loves my horn oh man yeah
you always do that on your Instagram
show that's how I know you through
Instagram uh you actually had me in your
show before canac convos uh I'm actually
going to be on there again soon uh in
March sometime if I remember correctly
or maybe it's February I can't remember
it's on my calendar but you have some
great content on Instagram that's where
I mostly know you from I know before we
started recording you said you have a
YouTube as well but um yeah how about
you just start off by just telling us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening all right well my
name is uh Sly AKA Loco as everybody
should know um I have been growing about
6 years now I started with a friend
friend actually came by and he gave me a
plant and I decided that I wanted to
grow that plant out and so I went
outside and I grew it out it was pretty
fun and yeah I the way I got started was
kind of a little crazy too cuz for those
who don't know I had gotten sick I was a
big drug user and alcoholic long time
ago in my former life and then I had
cotton swine
flu um H1N1 virus which was kind of
weird because nobody around me caught it
only I did um and I was in a coma for 3
weeks uh they flew me to Portland OR I'm
I'm originally from Washington but they
flew me over to Portland cuz I was the
only place with the EO machine um and
yeah I was in aoma for 3 weeks and I saw
a lot of visions and a lot of stuff that
when I came out of akoma I left my old
life behind I stopped doing drugs and I
just concentrated on on you know the
plant that we all
and yeah and ever since then I've been
just flourishing just loving life going
better has just been amazing man that's
wild I'm glad to hear that you recover
from that that's pretty pretty crazy you
don't hear about people anybody like
I've never heard of anybody getting that
and then being in a coma for three weeks
being know the comeback and the
adversity you had and overcoming the
other things I mean that's that's
incredible man I'm happy for you thank
you thank you yeah it took a while man I
had to learn how to walk again and
everything geez but I did it I I came
out the other side I was 400 lbs at that
time too so I uh lost 170 pounds in
like under a
year um and yeah everything ever since I
stopped
drinking and just moved to the plant
that we all love it has been just
amazing everything has switched my life
has changed I've been more positive and
yeah it's just been really good man
loving life that's awesome man I'm
really glad to hear that so you're an
indoor grower correct me if I'm wrong
what size grow space are you in and kind
of how many plants are you growing um
right now I just took a little size or I
checked the size of my room and it's
about 10 by 20 um and I have two tents
in there I have two 4x4 tents also a
little one uh 2x two tent too that is
for my clones um and yeah that's what I
have in there pretty nice side I think
it's pretty good also I have a sink in
there which not a lot of people have not
a lot of people have sinks in their
rooms and so I think I feel like it
makes it a lot easier to flush to water
you know go about the daily stuff that
you need to do with your plants W that
makes make it so much easier dude when
I'm between grows like if I have to like
wash out grow pots for example like
doing in a bathtub you know bending over
and like man I my back hurts after a
while after sitting there scrubbing and
I've been doing things outside and still
you're kind of bending over and stuff
having a sink would be really nice I
wish I had wish I had a sink yeah that's
what a lot of people tell me they always
tell me that I'm very lucky to have a
sink there and that um I think it is too
because when I have to take my plants
into the tub um cuz back in the day I
would flush in the tub for some reason I
don't know why oh because my plants were
too big so they were too big to go in
the sink so I had to take them out to
the tub and that was a hassle and so I
definitely felt for people who have to
move their plants out into a a uh tub or
something like that into a area where
they can get
wet um and you that would be a lot
harder I really would not like that and
I feel also that if you have trellises
in your tent um you wouldn't be able to
take the plant out and you know do
whatever you have to do so that would
have been another problem yeah for me I
typically grow smaller plants a little
bit easier to transport from the tent to
a tub for example back when I flushed I
kind of switched over to Organics so I'm
not really doing flushes as much anymore
uh if ever usually it was just with
synthetic nutrients but uh yeah I mostly
just grow small plants sometimes medium
plants you on the other hand grow large
plants and that's what we're going to
talk about today really is growing large
plants indoors I think it's a topic that
we haven't really covered in depth
before and I'm glad when we first talked
about well hey what should we talk about
this time around you had said hey I grow
large plants indoors perfect perfect
topic let's base it around that let's
get deep into your style of growing
larger plants indoors so the first
question I got for you is are you going
after like certain genetics that are
like deemed high yielders for example or
have like a certain morphology like
anything in the listing description
that's going to say hey this is going to
be good for growing the large plants
indoors no actually I don't I um just go
with whatever genetics I can get
whatever genetics come around I'm very C
curious curious person so I want to see
if I can take a plant that is supposed
to be small and see if I can make it a
bigger plant which in turn would mean
that I have to do a longer veg time
right and that's one thing that I
usually do is I will start off in like a
one gallon right pot and then transfer I
feel like transferring is one of the
reasons why my plants get too so big is
because I transfer a lot I'll transfer
from a 1 gallon to a 3 gallon from a 3
gallon to its final thing is a 5 gallon
usually if I did go a little bit above a
5 gallon if I went to a s gallon the
plant would be massive just massive any
every time that I've done a 7 gon plant
it's just been incredibly big all the
way up to the top I can't move you know
the light up any higher um I just have
to start training and start bringing the
branches down in turn I'm probably going
a little bit too fast there for that but
um yeah they're just big plants man very
big plants I think it's the the longer
veg is what I do CU I usually veg for
about at least minimum seven weeks
minimum got it now for the genetics can
you name off maybe a couple different
plants that you've grown it could be
recently it could be at any point where
you feel like hey these ones were easy
to kind of you know they grew pretty
fast they grew large quickly without the
longer veg time maybe or is there
anything that kind of comes to mind that
you're like oh this is good for a large
Plant yeah the there's one that a lot of
people know is gg4 um that one is
usually a big plant very big one um I
also had a blue fire that was a massive
plant I didn't have to do a long I
didn't have to do a long veg or anything
with that one it just grew big it was a
big one um also this last one that I was
doing was the Triple Crown Triple Crown
was a big one too I didn't actually have
to do too much to it had a long stretch
on it too when I switched to flower it
was very big so I don't really go
looking for any other the big genetics I
just come across what I come across and
I'll just grow it out that makes sense
now what are you using for lighting it's
arguably one of the most contributing
factors to growth right is the the light
energy so you're indoors what are you
useing for grow lights so for the grow
lights I have a high Photon flood hpf
4000 that's what I'm going right now I
am sponsored by them also by the way uh
very good company I suggest people to go
check them out uh it's a bar style
LED um has the Red Spectrum it's a full
spectrum like and I also have the spider
farmer
se5000 is in my other 4x4 and I only
keep those at about 60% okay now you
chasing after a certain par for those
that don't know I have have quite a few
beginners that kind of tuned into this
par photosynthetic active radiation
there's a couple different measurements
ppf which is kind of the total light
output of a fixture ppfd which is kind
of a spot check in basic terms are you
aiming for a certain
ppfd um I'm not actually I don't have a
part tester or ppf uh I think it might
be on the AC controller no no actually I
don't though I just roll with it and I
read the plants the plants will kind of
tell me if the light is too intense you
know how they start to get the past to
HS or something like that um that's when
I know to turn down the light so I
basically read the the read the plants
and then what about CO2 it's another
thing that really can contribute to a
lot faster plant growth right do you run
CO2 at all um I don't well I do now I
haven't in the past in the past I just
let uh just let the plants grow with the
lights the water but I started adding
CO2 recently um I have this product
that's called
it's the VIP Plantation CO2 maker um
he's a guy on Instagram he makes a
little uh concoction which I think it's
just yeast and sugar or something like
that and water put six cups of water
shake it up and just hang it up in your
tent and it gives you your plants of CO2
how long does it last and do you need to
like refresh it every couple weeks or
something or what yeah it only lasts two
weeks and then he gives you a package
you get one container that's already
made so you just or that's ready to go
you just the water mix it up and then
it'll work but then it also comes with
another package for the next two weeks
so one of those packages lasts two weeks
and then you got to refresh it take it
out wash it add the other packet add
some more water and then boom and I have
about two six I have about eight weeks
of packaging there to use but I think
that would be perfect for a veg so
what's the total cost on that do you
happen to know how much the packages
cost and kind of how much you're
spending per run yeah the whole set up
that it was about $30 to have them ship
it out and everything so it was about
the same price that I see at the grow
stores so but his is a little bit bigger
and it lasts a little bit longer you get
an extra couple weeks on there for that
$30 so I felt that that was play that
was the way that I wanted to go and I've
developed a a reputation or a rapport
with him so you know he hooked it up a
little bit more too so nice now you have
a CO2 monitor where you're kind of
monitoring things and dialing in with
that type of setup with CO2 you don't
have as much control as you would with
like a tank for example do you have a
monitor are you able to see like what it
goes up to and and what the low point is
and stuff I don't have a monitor yet I'm
actually very new to the CO2 so I don't
have a monitor I wouldn't even know what
I'm looking for I uh I'm very new very
green to this one I got to start doing a
little bit more research so I can figure
out how you know cuz I think it's in
ppms right yep PPM some people go up to
like you know 14,500 PPM at the max I
naturally for me well naturally outside
it's what like 400 450 PPM naturally
outdoors if you're indoors us exhaling
and I have a three-month old daughter
she's exhaling CO2 I have two cats
they're exhaling CO2 every time I go on
my tent it's at like 700 so it's always
elevated a little bit now for me I have
an exhaust and I'm pulling air out and
the fresh air that's coming in is from
my house so for me I just I don't even
run CO2 anymore I used to run the um
mushroom bags for a little while I did
see some increase in it but there's some
kind of inconsistencies I ran the tnb
naturals before again same thing where
it's just kind of up and down up and
down no real stable result and then just
finding out you know for me I'm just a
small home grower I grow these small
plants just myself six to 12 plants Max
is usually what I'm running in that
range I personally don't really need to
run CO2 but I can see for the folks you
know somebody like yourself who's
looking to grow large plants CO2 can
certainly be beneficial so yeah I was
just curious on that one yeah and that's
one thing that I've been trying to keep
an eye on is trying to see if it really
does work if it's giving my plants the
more faster grow the bigger grow um all
that and I feel that it is I feel that
they are growing uh faster bigger which
is always good you know I really like a
a nice big plant to go on the veg what
the way I feel is that FEG is the
pregame to the game you know the game is
when you go into flower and that's
that's the Super Bowl so you want to be
very ready before you put that plant
into the flower stage absolutely yeah I
mean kind of rule of thumb is the plant
to be the half the size you want
generally because you're going to expect
some stretch to happen even after
flipping the light cycle and for the
plant to be healthy right so like a lot
of people won't flip the flow unless
their plant is fully healthy if they
seen any sorts of deficiencies or
anything they won't flip now of course
with autof flowers you're kind of so
there because yeah it's on a timeline
right so if you come across deficiency
well you just got to roll with the
punches in a sense and just take it but
with photo periods you you kind of have
that control right you could keep it in
veg for a little bit longer get it
healthy again and then be able to flip
the flour from there so that's one the
reason that I don't really mess with
autof flowers is because I like the the
the control to being able to change it
into flower when I'm ready when I feel
that the plant is ready which is kind of
you know kind of a little messed up to
say it like that but it's when I feel
that the plant is going to be able to
give me the best buds is when I want to
send it into flower you know I don't
want you turning on you know small and
then giving me little buds I need big
buds and so um yeah that's what that's
probably why I don't mess with auto
flowers I hear you I've grown about
probably two dozen close to three dozen
autof flowers now and I got some good
results I do like them once in a while
but for the most part I do prefer having
that control over the photo period you
know being able to keep it in veg for as
long as I want so I can shape the plant
the way I want it then be able to flip
over the flower when I'm ready so that's
just personal preference there now what
about like temperature and humidity what
are you usually aiming for for that so
for TS I have been um messing with TS a
little bit because I've been sitting
here I'm a very experimental person so I
like to go around and check and see okay
how do they work at a 72 73° 75 and now
right now I'm at 78° with about 50 to
60% humidity which some people would say
it's kind of low cuz in my room in my
little room you would think that it'd be
easier to control the temperatures but
it's not okay summertime it gets really
hot winter time it gets really cold so I
have to either turn up the heater more
or the air conditioner which I put a air
a portable air conditioner in there
during the summertime because over here
on the West side or on the east side of
Washington
is not like the West Side okay the West
Side you got uh more calmer temperature
70 80° is the hottest maybe 90° is the
hottest it'll get over there it gets 10
and something over here on the regular
every summer so over here and there's
zero humidity I think you deal with this
too cuz being where you're at um you
have to add humidity in and so we'll get
a humidifier but then on the same time
since I'm in a small little room if I
have so many plants going it puts the
humidity through the roof so then I'd
have to turn on the
dehumidifier right and then turning on
the dehumidifier then I have to is going
to add a little bit of heat so then I
got to turn up the air conditioner so
I'm constantly fighting with
temperatures in my little grow room
balancing that environment easier said
than done I mean that's a something when
I first started growing 14 years ago
indoors and I was like yeah it should be
easy to control you know I get my HPS
put the HPS in there put my plants in
there right away and all of a sudden the
skyrocketed with temp with heat I was
like what the heck so then I have to get
an exhaust have the exhaust and the
exhaust running all times and all of a
sudden the heat is still high it's like
what the heck then you have to add
Cooling and it's it's a balancing act
for sure is your heater and humidifier
and all that stuff that's in your lung
room I assume which is the room that
your grow tents are in and you
controlling that air and so that way any
air coming into the tents are of the
proper R and temperature yes that's what
that's the way I try to keep it to where
the outside temps are better or you know
a little bit more dialed in the inside
temps but I do have the the AC Infinity
controller on the tent on one of my AC
Infinity tents and that controller does
tell me you know the TS the humidity and
everything in one of them but the other
tent I don't have that so I'm just
freestyling and I kind of assume that
it's in the right same thing as the
other tank cuz I mean it's the same
environment but you know you really want
to be on top of that and I just just
been slacking on that veg tent a little
bit so you mentioned 78° F and 50 to 60%
R is that for the vegetation stage or
the flowering stage or both uh for about
both okay got it so you're running that
the whole way through yeah cuz I would
like I would like my uh my my humidity
to go a little bit no actually cuz I
like that point in flour because I'm
very uh paranoid about getting
mold and getting you know just mold I'm
very paranoid about that that's why I
try to keep the humidity very low in the
room because I don't want to build up
mold behind the walls which is
possibility in growing which some people
need to know out there is if you are
growing into a if you're growing in an a
complex or apartment complex or
something that's what they are worried
about they're worried about you getting
the humidity so high and mold growing
behind the wall and nobody wants that so
make sure that your humidity is low in
your room but in your tent in your tent
you want high humidity so it's a little
balance there that you got to figure out
I've heard of like gr operations people
have converted their entire house and
the way they got busted is they see the
condensation on the windows so like
neighbors and stuff we see the
condensation build up and that's too
high of humidity right in there and so
yeah good that stuff could definitely
cause mold to happen now me I often get
people commenting on my videos when they
see my setup because I have it in I have
a 9x12 bedroom and have a couple tents
in there right now have a 4x4 and a 2x4
I've had other size tents in there in
the past but my exhaust is coming from
the tent up into my attic now I have
okay ventilation into the attic as well
right so it goes completely out but I've
had so many people like hey you
shouldn't do that cuz that'll mold up
your your attic valid point very very
valid point if you're just dumping high
humidity in there depending on you know
what the temperature is and stuff like
that it could actually cause mold to
happen on your roof there on the inside
panels I've seen pictures of that and it
looks like just a complete nightmare I
live in a very dry climate I have to say
that in every single episode every
single one of my main Channel videos
every single one of my podcast episodes
I live in a dry climate so even if I
dump stuff up up there it's usually not
high enough to cause mold but those
living in a high humidity area they're
dumping stuff into their attic they high
likelihood of mold happening there and
for my understanding that can be very
very cost so I mention that one yeah and
it only takes one Spore guys one Spore
of mold and it will just blow up and
it'll just reproduce and reproduce and
sometimes in the worst case scenario you
don't know that it's happening and you
don't know that it's happening until you
start getting sick
so everybody please be on top of that
make sure that you're not getting mold
in places that you can't see absolutely
so we talked about your grow room we
talked about lighting we talked about
environment condition conditions let's
see what else impacts the size of the
plant we we didn't talk about soil are
you in soil cocoa Hydro if you're in
soil what's in your mix I am using a uh
Happy Frog soil so I just recently
switched to organic um amendments so
that I can build my soil so now I'm
using the same soil instead because I
used to just go uh Ed soil throw it in
out in like my yard and I'd have this
big pile of used soil that I wasn't just
reusing again you know and I just go get
another bag well I recently since
watching you guys uh decided that I can
re or I learned that I could reuse the
soil so I'm like oh okay well I've been
wasting a lot of money so now I'm going
to go over there get all that soil and
so I went and ran got
a a 26 gallon bin that I put my soil in
and now I am mixing them with a GU green
dry amendments so I buil that with some
worm casting
and some micro Riser I throw that into
the soil and I just been letting that
sit there and cook for it's been a
couple couple months now and
everything's going great I I before that
I was a synthetic nutrient person though
and I would just yeah like I said I
would just throw out my soil but now I'm
reusing the soil and I'm starting to go
Organics and I really digging it it's a
lot easier too you don't have to feed so
much that's a synthetic one nutrients
okay so you got Gaia green as kind of
your base nutrition then some warm
castings and micro risal fungi have you
been re reusing your soil for several
grows now or or what this has been it's
been about I would say about 6
months no almost a year I've been doing
that wow that's pretty good time flies
when you're having
fun but yeah I just been uh using
reusing that soil and just mixing the
amendments in and doing that for as of
late and it's working with me and so how
do you do the feedings throughout
because eventually when you do that
initial
amending the nutrients are going to
deplete unless you're loading it up
there so it's like a super soil you
don't have to do any feedings but I
imagine since you're growing larger
plants you're vegging for a little bit
longer there you're probably doing top
dressings throughout how do you
typically do your top dressings and also
do you know what ratios you do of like
diag green and stuff like how much you
tablespoon per gallon or yeah I do a
little bit more than a tablespoon I
about 3 tablespoons per gallon is what I
try to do I am uh I try to load it up as
much as possible because I getting a
little lazy and I don't want to be in
there every day and mixing soils and
stuff like that so I'll put about 3
tablespoons per gallon um put it on the
top soil mix it in and then just water
and be doing that every couple weeks and
recently also when I start to see
problems if I start to see a little bit
of deficiencies or something I'll make a
brew and I started doing the Brews that
was pretty cool I did not know like
going into that that you wanted to see
the bubbles when you make a brew for
those who don't know if you're putting
in uh your uh organic nutrients into
your water or a cheesecloth or something
like that that you put it to keep it a
little bit keep the water a little bit
cleaner because that's something that I
didn't know that would happen uh the
first time I just threw everything in a
bucket and I turned on the AirStone and
I said left it there and I was like okay
but I didn't even cover it so now I
cover them and I started getting that
life the bubbles and everything that you
see on the top um that you're looking
for um and I really like those I really
dig it how do you brew your tea what's
in there is it just worm castings or is
there some Gaia Green in there as well
and how long do you usually like Brew
for yeah I put the ga green uh 444 I
think that's the allpurpose
or is that I think it's the All Purpose
yeah yeah that's put the allp purpose
and I put the flower in it in it and uh
the worm casting I put in with a little
bit of bone meal um and some kelp too
that I do have from another company I
have some of that A friend gave it to me
so I started adding that into the Brew
um I wanted to try molasses but I'm not
too sure about how much molasses what
kind of molasses cuz I heard that you're
not supposed to use sweetened
molasses I think I'm not too sure about
that one but unsulfured is the one you
want to Target is no preservatives in
there so a lot of people do black strap
molasses cuz a little bit easier to mix
in if you mix it into kind of warmer
water that'll actually mix into the
water better than if it was it was
cooler water but yeah unsulfured black
strap is okay pretty much the most
common okay so I do that and I stick it
into my bucket with some water and
AirStone and I brew it for about 3
days um some people say the longer the
Brew the long the better it is but I
haven't really experimented too much on
how much is a long like too long of a
brew U but I feel like 3 days is pretty
good yeah then I know long bruise can
things can go anerobic bad pathogens
that happen so you can definitely mess
up with tea I've done it before or I've
fed my plants tea and they were not
happy at all so okay so how long was a
how how long is too long I usually just
do 24 hours that's me some people do 36
hours I've heard of some people doing 48
hours at the max I haven't heard anybody
going 3 days so that was a new one new
one for me so I could probably I'm no
master when it comes to uh when it comes
to Brewing compost teas but I've done
done them several dozen times in the
past don't do them as much anymore I
usually just water and compost for
example but yeah I usually do it when I
need to either I'm I'm going organic and
need to resolve a deficiency or if I'm
just looking to boost up the microbial
population in order to have some more
decomposition in the in the medium
faster decomposition you know yeah I'm
going to cut back on that I'll try two
days and we'll see how that goes one day
I one day works sometimes I just forget
about it sometimes I'll set it and I'll
walk out and I'll just come back a
couple days later and be like oh no the
plants oh no the
brew and then I got to do what I got to
do and get it in
there that happens man we lives are busy
busy busy do you dilute the tea now when
you create the tea you brew it now are
you diluting it in water at any Ratio or
anything are you just feeding that
solution directly to the plants yeah I
just feed that solution directly to the
plants I uh yeah I know I haven't
deluded it or anything I haven't thought
of
that the plants so far they're loving it
so far I haven't had any problems be
size pest is the only thing that I've
been dealing with in my girl room okay
got it so the te's are working out for
you so that's good to hear yeah now I
want to flip it back to the nutrients
now you said you've been doing Organics
for about 6 months now before that you
were doing doing synthetics so I kind of
want to dive a little bit into
synthetics we have a lot of people that
listen to here that use synthetics
particularly when growing large plants
they want their Precision feeding they
want everything to be soluble in order
to try to help get faster growth what
were you using for synthetic nutrients
and how were you going about your
feedings uh for the synthetic nutrients
when I first started I was using uh
General
Hydroponics um and then I had made the
switch over to Dutch Pro nutrients from
you guys were but that was back in the
day when we were you guys were
collaborating with them and I really
like those nutrients because the general
hydroponic was already phed so soon as
you added it to your water your water
would be at 6.2 and so 6.2 6.5 whatever
whatever up pH at
um and it was easier so you just mix it
f your plants boom there you go and so I
did that for a while but then I started
getting deficiencies and deficiencies
started plaguing me all the time so then
I made the switch to Organics which I
feel is working better for me at the
time right now but I will every once in
a while still throw some synthetic in if
I need to if I'm just like hey this
plant needs an nitrogen right now right
now here boom just throw some nitrogen
on some uh veg General hydroponic feed
so the Sanic approach yeah yeah there
you go that's what it is some people
swear by that they and I've done it
several times in the past you know start
out with the organic medium to begin
there's organic nutrients in there then
adding in some synthetics along with top
dressing of organic amendments and yeah
getting through grows like that that's
some my best Grows Where I combine the
two so yeah and I really don't feel that
you have to go one or the other I feel
like the grow it's your grow if you feel
like you want to add some synthetics in
there go for it man it's you know it's
your thing you can do whatever you want
there is no set science to this nobody's
ever said hey man you got to do it this
way or else you know well there are
people who will say that but you know
they there's some people who will try to
make you do what they want you know or
grow how they want but I feel that you
need to experience this you need to uh
experiment you need to see find out what
works for you the best yeah I completely
agree and yeah there's nothing worse
than a backseat grower somebody that
comes in and tells you how to grow your
plants oh
man feedback like we need to do this
this this this now change this and then
do this and it's like dude what okay
that's the way you do it but like I want
to do it a little bit different you know
I have my own style let me let me do
what I'm doing you know I'll ask you for
help if I want it you know it's funny
yeah there was one guy uh yeah exactly
how you said that I'll ask you for help
if I want it right there was one guy out
there on Instagram who was uh he sent me
a message and was like dude you need to
do this this this and I was like all
right bro I was like yeah I already did
that and he just took total offense to
it and was like I've been growing 40
years you need to you need to like or he
sent me a video too was like shaking his
pants what do you think I don't know
what I'm talking about I'm like bro
that's not what I said I just said that
I did that already damn but I could
totally understand too so some people I
could see how some people are so
passionate about the way that they grow
you know and they they some people deep
down they're just trying to help and
they don't like being told that they're
not doing right which I think they're
getting defensive you know they have
that
inner insecurities or whatever it is and
they just feel like Tash hour was easier
thing than to sit there and talk to
somebody and actually be like okay man
my bad I was tripping because I have
insecurities you know that's just so
hard for some people to say yeah I can
totally I totally get what you mean by
that for sure I want to bring it back to
container size and type for a minute now
you mentioned you start out in one
gallons then you go to three then you go
to Five you've tried to go to 7 gallons
before but you felt like that was a
little bit too much is that when you
were growing with Organics or synthetics
and then also those plastic pots or
fabric pots or what so that was when I
was doing all of it actually I still do
synthetic and organic in that same way
um and I use fabric pots I tried some
plastic 1gallon pots but I just feel
like they're not getting the air into
the root system the way that fabric pots
do and I really like I understand that
some people like the way that the root
system bounces around and starts to curl
around with the plastic but I don't I
like the root system to be able to
because I feel that that leaves room for
root rot if the roots are bouncing
around they're getting tangled up too
much right so that's why I only use
fabric pots ever since I've been started
growing I just did fabric pots it's
easier I like the way that they um like
they could soak up water from the
outside like say say you got fungus
gnats
and you want to start watering on the
bottom you know it's easier for the
fabric pots for them to soak up the
water uh and also I
like that the root system supposedly
when the root system goes out and it
hits the fabric it doesn't bounce around
it just stops right there and it starts
to get bigger and bigger and so uh the
root system is very healthy in there I
think it's healthier with fabric pots
yeah they're different and I I did the
one gallon to three gallon to 5 gallon
to S gallon one of my other friends he
does like I don't even know I think like
a 20-gallon or something pot in his
plants and I was like bro you are a
Savage if I did that my plants would be
the size of the
house Different Strokes for different
folks yeah there are so many different
ways to go about it some people use
plastic some people use fabric some
people hate plastic love Fabric and vice
versa so me I do like the plastic pots
to begin but I did switch over to the
Grassroots fabric pots the living soil
fabric Poss with the liner because uh
one thing I learned from Tyler over at
Grassroots big shout out to him is he
had mentioned that you know it's really
not natural for when you're grow with
the living soil or Organics having the
medium dryo from all sides so they
created one with a liner in the middle
of the pot basically like from I think
it's like 2 in up and upward so it's a
little bit of Iration on the bottom more
than you'd get in a plastic pot but it
it prevents all the sides from drying
out to dries up from the top down
naturally like it kind of does in nature
so those are the ones I've been I've
been really digging but Different
Strokes for different folks some people
certainly get away with just doing uh
Organics with fabric pots so yeah and I
uh just recently started washing my pots
um I went and bought new pots every time
so when I first started growing I was
wasting a lot of money I feel like I
didn't reuse my soil I didn't rewash my
pots I you know I just went and got new
stuff and after a while it started
adding up that money adds up so uh
recently just started washing the pots
and I feel like it works as long as you
run them through two times boom
everything comes out nice and clean and
you can just reuse it absolutely yeah
reuse where you can and save money yeah
so when you transplant are you doing
anything special like some people what
they'll do is they'll sprinkle micro
risal fungi on the roots during
transplant I like to do that I also like
to put a scoop of worm castings in the
bottom of the hole I personally feel
like that helps with growth prevents the
transplant shock quote transplant shock
that that you can get sometimes if you
disturb the roots too much it kind of
just looks like the plant's slowing down
a little bit before it bounces back
typically when I'm I'm sprinkling
microle fungi and then adding in the
scoop of worm castings to the bottom of
the hole growth just seems to continue
on without any sort of stunt do you do
anything during transplant like that or
or what I do actually I do exactly what
you do I uh transplant and I put the
micro RIS it on the root system and put
a little bit of worm casting on the
bottom too cuz I feel like it's just
that makes sense um to put that right
there while you're transplanting I mean
you have it all open you might as well
get it to the to the root system while
it's open I also when I do I do break
the bottom of the uh the root system up
I break that open just a little bit you
want to be careful though when you're
transplanting you want to make sure that
your soil is very dry because if it's
not as dry for me at least um when I go
to transfer the soil will fall apart Off
The Roots if it's wet so the drier it is
the more you pull it out and it'll stay
in one spot and then you can drop it
into the thing if it's a little bit wet
it'll fall apart and that's when I have
trouble with my transplants and then
you'll get the shock and everything like
that to happen but when it's really dry
I don't see any shock and yeah I just
put a little bit of microa and some worm
casting on there cool let's get into the
meat and potatoes of this whole talk
right I think the rest of the things
that we're going to be talking about
really contributes to larger plants
right so first off how long do you veg
the plants for so my veg I veg for a
long time I will read the plant as I
like to say which is making sure that's
big enough I want to say it's about 7
weeks is how long I veg for maybe even
eight some sometimes uh but in that veg
time I'm
topping and I'm uh training like crazy
czy so like I said earlier I sit there
and it's like the pregame you know
getting the plant ready for the Super
Bowl so the long veg is something that I
really stand by cuz I want my plants to
be very healthy very ready to go into
this flower stage and produce the
biggest um flowers that I can okay so a
7 week veg on that then you flip out of
flow I don't know if I asked you or if
you mentioned how many plant is that for
like one plant in a full by4 or how many
plants are you putting in that full by4
that you mentioned you have oh um what I
would do is I I usually stick it to
about three plants in a 4x4 that I uh
because I find that four is just too big
the way that I grow my plants grow so
big that they Bush out really big and so
when I'm starting
to cuz I uh do the technique from pigees
420 where I break the membrane on the
stem right and I'll break the membrane
and I'll set the plant down I'll super
crop it right is that what it's called
yes so I'll just be super cropping on
top of topping so I really train this
plant to go out because it gets very
bushy so by the time that I put it into
the 4x4 t0 I can only fit three plants
in before they start to because it looks
like H you know you got a lot of room
but once they start to flower wow these
plants start to fill the whole tent out
and then there's no room for you to get
in and so I always always have to have
room for myself to be able to get in to
get into the B bottom of it to clean up
the bottom uh stems or you know do all
the maintenance everything got it so
three plants and you're trying to fill
it wall to wall so how tall are they
typically before flipping so you've got
you know from the ground up about a foot
for the grill pot how tall is it before
you kind of flipping CU you got space
constraints too right so you're doing
your training you're doing the the
topping low stress training super
cropping and then it you're you're
shaping it the way you want it to ma CU
out has grow space and then how tall is
it really before flipping to flower I'd
say about 2 feet over the one foot pot
so it'll be about 3T Al together um and
then you got to en count you got to take
in count that there is that stretch
going to happen to a flowers so you know
you got to be ready for that one that's
one thing that I have to deal with a lot
is growing big plants you have to be
ready
for the stretch to happen and you have
to be ready for how much room you're
going to have from the light and the
plant because you don't want the plant
touching the light but when growing big
plants it's going to happen sometimes it
definitely happens man I've had so many
plants outgrow and come up into light
you know I went on vacation one time
came back and the plants were grown into
the light yeah luckily I was able to
just prune off some branches and I was
good to go but it certainly can be a
problem where it kind of over grows the
grow space so knowing when to flip
making sure you're not overing your
plants to where all of a sudden you're
running into high constraints and you
have to prune when you don't want to
prune and so on and so forth so knowing
exactly when to flip and how bit how
long to your plants are super super key
so one thing that I've ran into also is
because I have a Perpetual grow so I
have a bunch of you know stages I got my
veg tent I got my flour tent I got my
clone tent I got my drying tent right
well if these tents aren't perfectly syn
then sometimes you're going to have to
veg for longer and the veg t than you
would want to and so that that happens a
lot more often than I would like it to
happen um and so in turn what happens is
when I move it to the flower tent we
have the plat touching the lights and
you're going to have to prune it and one
thing that I've noticed that freaked me
out the first time that I saw it was the
leaf touching the I think it's the red
diode um that gives you the Red Spectrum
it'll burn it'll burn the plant and it's
burnt and so you want to be careful for
that guys just be out there keep an eye
on it just make sure that if a leaf is
hitting the light it will burn in uh
prune it down if you have to um it will
will stunt the plant a little bit but I
feel like it'll be okay in the long run
how about pruning techniques like
lollipopping or defoliation are you
doing those things at all and when yes I
I love the lollipop and default like I'm
in there defaulting all like crazy
because the rule that I feel like is you
want all the energy to go up to these
colas right so you don't want to waste
too much energy down here with these
popcorn buds that are just going to be
if you're hand trimming they're just
hard to trim nobody likes to waste time
on the on the popcorn buds when you're
hand trimming um so in return
lollipop so I go in there and I
defoliate and I lollipop like crazy so I
will just
leave I'll just be looking for colas my
my my my goal is to get the big colas I
want I want these fat just beautiful
looking ones so um yeah I lollipop and I
train like crazy and do you do that in
veg before flip well in particular maybe
break down one by one for lollipopping
are you only doing an AEG before
flipping with flour are you also
lollipopping in flour at some point or
throughout flour I do it I in flower
also I do it in veg I get the plant look
in the way that I really like which is
lollip popped and topped and super
cropped right so she's throughout those
seven weeks she's going to be looking
very nice before I put her in the flow
now when I put her in the flower there's
going to be these these Bud sites that
are going to show up on the bottom that
a lot of Growers you know what I'm
talking about you'll have that one
little nug just sticking out on the
bottom stand that's just like really
developing and it looks nice but it's
taking an energy away from the top so
it's got to go and so yeah you just go
down there and just be picking off
whatever's uh on the bottom I try to
make it about a foot from the pot
nothing from under there just completely
stripped and all the stems are up here
in turn what happens in that time though
is you will get flopp this is a coin a
term that I I want a coin but it's the
flage it's a real big problem and that
is your you know your buds get too big
and they just start flopping over and
when they start flopping over that's
when you need a trer
or what I use is the yo-yo hangers use
those those are really nice they just
hang up on the top of your tent and just
come down and you just hook it onto your
bud and it'll hold it up and another
product that I've used is the umbrella
trellis now have you heard of this one I
had the owner on here oh episode before
huh good good yeah uh the umbrella Tris
man that's one product that I'm STI
standing by if you learn how to use it I
didn't know how to use it as well so I
asked uh the owner the maker and he
showed me what he does in his grow and I
was like oh now that's how it's supposed
to look it looked very beautiful if you
put two trellises on there then you have
the ability to take out the plant out of
the uh spot or wherever that you have
and you still have be able to hold the
nugs up and everything so the umbrella
trellis is really cool invention I like
that one some people don't like it but I
do that's pretty cool yeah I was going
to ask you about support for the plants
and you mentioned trellis net and the
yo-yos and stuff my next question is if
you're just using a regular trellis net
are you doing just one layer or you
doing multiple layers I actually have
only done trellising maybe three times
and there was one time I did one layer
and then one time I did the two layers
uh but like I said I need to have room
for me to get into the girl room so or
into the grow tent I can't fit in under
a trer
get under there and have to water
because I'm still hand watering too and
uh even though I do have a blue mat
system that I need to hook up and get
going uh which I had a question for you
on that but we'll ask that later uh yeah
trellises have never been my deal I I've
never really liked trellises I just
can't get over the fact that I can't get
in there and then when the plant is done
that you have to be able to get that
trellis off the butts and it's so hard
and back in the day when I was doing
more synthetic nutrients I would have to
flush a lot more often than not right
well I mean a lot of times having a
flush inside of a tent and move that
plant out is just while it's strapped
down to a trellis is just crazy crazy
impossible I I don't like it and so yeah
I don't really like trellises too much
fair enough now there's a lot of people
listening in here that are homeg Growers
maybe they're newer and they want to
grow large plants indoors what advice do
you have for those folks that are kind
of just getting started growing large
plants indoors um the advice that I
would give them would be to do a large a
longer veg the longer veg time will give
you a bigger plant and flower and yeah
you just got to be be patient too you
got to be patient with it because I know
you want to get it into the flower tent
you want to you know get a flower in and
get all the the good excitement out of
it but it's better to have the I like to
put it in child kind of you want your
child nice and healthy right before you
go set him into football or something
like that right so that's the way I put
it try to get that the veg is the most
important thing to me I think if the veg
is nice and good and perfect then you
shouldn't you should just be able to
flow right through flour but we all know
that that's not what really happens
sometimes sometimes a flour you know
problems arise and you're just going to
have to deal with that but
if you have a real long veg you'll have
a real big plant speaking of problems
what problems have you run into and how
did you resolve them oh man oh man what
are we talking on problems you mean like
best or just anything that's going to
prevent you from growing large plants or
hinders from large Plant development
what you're trying to you know your end
goal there the problems that I have one
thing in growing big plants is you're
going to you're going to lose a lot of
room uh these plants take up a lot of
room they take up a lot of water they
take up a lot of nutrients you're going
to start be getting a lot of
deficiencies because the bigger the
plant the more they're going to want
energy they need more more uh nutrients
to create this energy to keep them
healthy to keep them thick and um you
know wantan to live so yeah they're
going to be having more deficiencies is
one thing that I've noticed that happens
to me a lot um also the flage when
you're growing big plants you're going
to have that flop
so be ready to put a trellis on there or
yo-yo hangers or something to hold up
those big buds because those buds are
going to get really big and they're
going to start hanging another thing
it's guys just room because you're not
going to be able to put I mean you could
put nine plants in there and try to grow
nine big plants but you're just going to
be having too many things grabb together
not enough air circulation because
there's going to just be too much uh
foliation in there uh yeah so that's why
I keep it to about three plants at a
time some people might want to do more
more power to you but yeah big plants
you're going to be ready for flopp this
one flopping is something that happens
to be a lot some people might want to do
less than three plants right some people
some people like to do just one plant
right in the middle of their full by4
and veget for that long period and put
it into a trellis for example is there a
specific reason why you do three plants
instead of like one plant just oh no
I've done one plant before I've done one
plant in a sgon pot and that was a
massive plant massive it took up like it
might have been three plants in one like
yeah I've done that before and people if
you follow me on Instagram you've seen
that plant that plant was huge I feel
like it beat me up it was almost like
Little Shop of hores it was like feed me
SE
more so I was a little intimidated by
this plant because they get really big
man and one thing that I've noticed that
if anybody is grown Outdoors they know
that Outdoors they can get huge cuz I
did that one time I wanted to experiment
and I was like well I grow really big
plants indoors so let's see what happens
if I put it outdoor and so I took one of
my strains that I cloned out and that
had been doing indoors and I put it
outdoors and Jesus Lord it was huge
brother oh my God two plants I had out
there and they just took up a lot of
space and I had to deal with flage which
is one thing that I'm always dealing
with but they came out good and I just
wanted to see how big it would get and
that was in a 30 gallon pot so yeah that
was pretty fun nice experience right
there and i' very I highly recommend
everybody to
experiment experiment with everything
see how big you could get your PL see if
it's if it's something that you're into
to if you're something that you can
handle if you can't handle it keep them
smaller easy I think that's some really
good advice man is there anything else
we need to cover I'm trying to think
here when it relates to growing large
plants indoors we covered lighting
environment we got soil
nutrition training we did almost
everything here right anything else you
can think of that we should talk about
for large plants growing them indoors no
not really I was just going to say
patience patience is one thing that is a
key in growing in general um you're
going to have to have patience for this
if you want to have the best product or
the
best you know the best product that you
could produce because you're you're
putting in all your time in this and you
don't want to put all your time in for
nothing right you want to have also one
thing I wanted to point out is I want to
have everybody out there not not to
stress too much about it because I I I
try to nurture a lot of new Growers and
I tell them like don't stress about it
you're supposed to be having fun let's
have fun on this uh don't take it too
seriously because as long as you gain
that knowledge you could always do it
again if something goes wrong your plant
dies or whatever you can always plant
another seed and you could give it
another shot and so just keep up with it
man that's the advice I have for people
keep with it and don't give up and have
fun well said well I appreciate you
coming on today man this has been uh
this has been cool to hear about how you
do it how you grow large plants indoors
tell the listeners how they can find you
and what you have upcoming in the future
um everybody can find me on Instagram uh
Sly AKA logo but that is
sore
akore logo um go check me out over there
that's where I'm most prominent at uh I
upload almost every other day I do
content and I have a show on there
called canac convos which is my podcast
SL live and we have a bunch of guests
that are from the Community I've had
pigeons for 20 I've had Mr Grow right
here I've had Rob the whole from the
from the stash crew I've had even some
famous rappers i' had zigzag from MB
Riders I've had a lot of people on there
and it's going pretty good I really like
it and I want everybody to come check us
out because we got some more people
coming booked for couple months now and
it's going to be some good shows also I
have a YouTube too my YouTube I'm not
too prominent on because we keep getting
age restricted I show plants and stuff
like that so I got a little turned off
by YouTube but I don't think it about
starting come back and post a little
couple more videos it's an uphel battle
with YouTube man so frustrating at times
I totally understand how uh how you feel
sometimes I don't see why when we're
just all going to like stop fighting it
YouTube this is going to it's going to
happen it's going to be federally legal
and it's just going to be like it's not
worth the fight I I feel can't wait for
that day to happen well thanks so much
much for coming on I'll definitely have
links to s's Instagram and YouTube down
in the YouTube description section below
so you can easily navigate to his
Instagram or YouTube and give him a
follow or a subscription and tune into
his content I want to give a thanks to
all the folks that follow me on patreon
so if you're a supporter on patreon
thank you so much that's something that
helps keep this show going I appreciate
contributions there if those folks that
are listening in and aren't aware of the
patreon
patreon.com you go there there's various
te
that you can enter and you get access to
mostly early releases so you're able to
actually listen to these podcast
episodes early before they release to
the public which is kind of one of the
main perks uh and then of course you can
get access to my book audio book and so
on and so forth so I'll have that linked
down in the YouTube description section
below as well so once again thanks for
coming on man I totally appreciate it
can't wait to come on your show once
again and hope you enjoy the rest of
your day thank you sir thank you for
having me on I I really uh appreciate
you giving me your time and having me on
you're welcome all right everyone peace
out catch you in the next episode