coming up on Garden talk in a two by two
you know that's 16 tops give or take so
if I can if I can get 16 Tops on one
plant and they all have about five to
seven nodes that's a perfect canopy to
start flour with I come home to happy
healthy plants when I have Organics when
I'm dealing with synthetics I tend to do
something wrong or I over feed or
something goes wrong and then I end up
with issues I want to keep a quicker
cycle if I can but you know I also want
to have the most yield I can get out of
that space so if I have to veg a little
longer I will worry about it the next
run man I think that's my best bet is to
keep my my stress levels down because
it's very easy when you're passionate
about these plants to let it get to you
and stress you out but I think that the
happier I am the happier my plants
generally are
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 93. in this
episode I interview two by two Gorilla
Glue he has been gardening for three
years and he grows in a you guessed it
two by two grow space he focuses on
maximizing that grow space in order to
achieve the highest yield possible and
that's what we're going to talk about in
today's episode if you gain value from
these podcast episodes please click the
like button and also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already that way
you can be notified when new episodes
are released if you'd like to support
even more visit patreon.com Mr grew it
there are various rewards set up for
those that support and you can pledge
any amount that you like 100 of the
money pledged through patreon goes right
back on the podcast it helps keep this
podcast going so thank you so much for
your support there before we get into it
I want to acknowledge that one of my
goals for this podcast is to bring free
gardening information of all plants to
the general public that being said I
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode that helped make that goal
possible thanks to grow strong
Industries for sponsoring this episode
they have kind LED grow lights which
allow you to control the veg and flower
spectrums independently allowing you to
maximize quality and yield and they also
have Lotus nutrients a nutrient line
developed by Growers for Growers to
completely replace the typical 9 to 12
Bottle recipe with an easy to use
three-part system to see their products
in action check out their first ever
grow strong grow off go to their website
growstrong industries.com linked below
and use the discount code Mr Grow it for
15 off thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode their clip-on
oscillating fan is awesome I've been
using their six inch version but they
also have a 9-inch version it's easy to
clip on the side of my grow tent and has
10 different speeds which makes it easy
to control air circulation they do have
a non-oscillating version of this
clip-on fan as well it also connects to
their smart controller 69 so you can
control the fans and other AC Infinity
equipment through their app from your
smartphone the discount code Mr grodd15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infinity.com
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I'm joined with Vince
but most of you know him as two by two
Gorilla Glue how you doing today doing
very good Chris how about yourself man
doing good good appreciate you coming on
today uh well looks like I have a
visitor over here my cat Max likes to
jump up
so uh yeah we're just going to keep on
recording I'm going to let him settle
down and then we'll continue on with
this episode so
so you grow in a smaller grow space two
feet by two feet grow space to be exact
and you maximize that space which helps
of course maximize yield now training
the plants to fill up the space is a
given but there's a lot more to it so in
this episode I'd like to get into your
way of maximizing yield in a small space
but first can you tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening definitely
um so I've been gardening medicinal
plants since 2019 so about 3 or four
years now
my first real experience with gardening
in general was you know four or five six
years old at my grandparents house they
had a nice backyard lots of cool plants
growing and I remember having an apricot
tree back there that I just broke a
branch off of and stuck in the ground
and you know let it do its thing and
eventually we were getting fruits off of
it which is you know very cool to see
and so ever since then I've always kind
of had a interest in Plants that's
awesome so let's start off by talking
about your current growth setup now I
know you're in a two foot by two foot
grow tent correct me if I'm wrong there
can you tell me a little bit about your
setup like what brand grow tent what
lighting are you using other equipment
you know so and so forth definitely so
I'm in uh it's technically it's a 26
inch by 26 inch by 55 inch grow tent the
brand is called one deal
um pretty standard grow tent my
lighting I have a Viper Spectra
p1500s 150 watt LED
um
yeah so far as my other stuff in there I
have an AC Infinity T8 fan which is uh
the one with the controller which is
it's definitely overkill for such a
small space but I I bought it for a
larger tent that I have that I'm still
waiting to set up but I just keep it at
a lower setting and it does great for
that space yeah the TA that's that's the
big boy there a lot of people using that
in like large like four by eights or ten
by tens things have full rooms that's
exactly what I was what I got it for was
a 4x8 Vivo Sun tent that I'm just
waiting to set up at the moment that
makes sense yeah I think in the two by
two what would you typically run maybe
like a an ideal world like a four inch
setup or what I would say uh four inch
is ideal
um anything else is going to be a little
bit Overkill I I always like to say that
uh it's okay to have a little more fan
than you need but if you have a little
less you're still going to be fine like
before I have the AC Infinity I was just
using like small little desk fans you
just now you stick them in the vent and
just have it pulling some air in pulling
some air out and you know as long as you
have air exchange I think you you're
okay yeah absolutely now are you growing
autoflowers or photo periods at the
moment I have not done any auto flower
work I've only worked with photo periods
um a lot of flowers are cool though
um I think just a little more
unpredictable but for the most part I
think it's it's cool like I wouldn't
mind having an Autoflower run under my
belt eventually I'm doing an Autoflower
run right now and uh I mean I I heard a
long time ago that they were recommended
for beginners and a different
conversation here but I got to disagree
with that there's uh they could be
tricky in some areas especially if you
have that stunned growth within the
first 20 or 30 days I mean you could
really stunt a plant and then end up
with a real small Autoflower so anyways
so photo periods is what you're growing
now are you in soil or cocoa are you
doing a hydroponic system or what uh my
current run is in kogo pure Coco No
perlite or anything
um the run before this I was in uh Roots
big or big Roots was the soil brand uh
it's just a super soil mix but really
enjoyed that uh in terms of the systems
I mean I like all systems I think
they're all fun to work with it's just a
matter of budget and just how much time
you have to invest into you know your
your grow did you start with the brick
of cocoa or was it a bagged cocoa that's
already kind of pre-rinsed and all that
stuff
yes it was a bagged cocoa the brand is
Mother Earth Coco
um yeah I think that like you're saying
you know before before I go for a brick
if I can find a bag of you know cheaper
kind of less expensive bagged cocoa I'd
probably go with that over any of the
the bricked options but you know there
are some pretty cool options out there
for the bricks as well like I like the
they come in almost like a puck with uh
with the bag attached and you just kind
of fill it and then I think floor
effects does it and maybe some other
companies too but I like that idea I've
mostly used the bricks and uh you know
it's it's good for like shipping
purposes but one of the bricks I had
from some brand I don't remember the
name of it like super salty like even
after rinsing and buffering it still had
problems with my plants but I have this
other brand which I can't think of this
name either that I got off of Amazon
pretty recently and no issues I just did
I didn't even rinse more buffer because
I'm doing some sort of uh testing I've
got going on here but didn't rinse or
buffer and I had no issues so it's kind
of a hit or miss with the bricks in my
experience but uh but yeah a lot of
people do tend to go towards the bagged
stuff since it is typically already
pre-rinsed and buffered and so on and so
forth definitely definitely now what
size grow pots do you use and type grow
pots you can fabric a plastic or what uh
current run I'm in one gallon plastic
pots so they're they say one gallon it's
a seven inch tall pot I feel like it's a
little bit less than a gallon but like I
would call it a one gallon pot and one
what are you using for fertilizer I
could imagine you're probably not doing
Organics probably doing uh you have like
a synthetic lineup to choosing yes so
for this run I'm using Mills
um I've used plenty of other bottled
nutrients
um you know slow release dry amendments
Organics uh
they all work at the end of the day when
we use them properly but uh it's I would
say for me I kind of prefer Organics
over the bottled nutrients if I'm gonna
pick between the two just the ease of
use along with just you know kind of
feeling better about it at the end of
the day I come I come home to happy
healthy plants when I have Organics when
I'm dealing with synthetics I tend to do
something wrong or I over feed or if
something goes wrong and then I end up
with issues but um that's on me more
than the nutrient company you know I'd
say the nutrients themselves are great
it's just uh for ease of use Organics is
what I kind of really like to do more so
the Mills line up the juicy grain now is
it tell us a little bit more about it is
it there's like an A and B for veg and a
and b for flour and then is there
additives that you're using as well
right so uh there's only an A and A B
and use the same A and B for veg and for
flower just for flour you would increase
the ppms of that
um there's a few different additives
like they have a silica additive called
vitalize it's a monocacylic acid so it's
you know you know it's good stuff it's
going to be ready for the plants to use
right away
um they have a veg additive it's called
start R
this nitrogen huge nitrogen boost kind
of lean the NPK towards veg and then in
flour for
the first two or three weeks you're
using the start are still and then after
that you would switch over to their C4
for the next three weeks or so and then
the final three weeks you're using
um an additive called ultimate PK which
is just a huge phosphorous potassium
boost just right at the end right when
they need it
but yeah that's pretty much all the
bottles they have for it okay so they
have a feeding chart that you're
following but I assume you're doing like
a reduced dosage throughout or you're
doing a full dose
um so the way they have their feed chart
set up they have a light mix medium mix
and a heavier mix for this run I went
with the light feed mix and pretty much
went issue free for almost the whole
grow I would say around week four or
five when I switched over to their C4 I
started having some problems I think
that it was a probably
a phosphorus toxicity which led to a
magnesium deficiency in some of the
plants just like it was just too much
light
the main problem for me in this tent was
nine plants and a two by two is just
it's too many plants for me personally
like I just wanted to see what would
happen more than anything else but I
think that I would have done much better
if it would have been just one or two
plants in the same space in the same
time versus doing nine plants you know
you have to keep nine different plants
healthy and happy versus keeping one or
two plants healthy and happy in the same
space you know I just end up with an
easier time I was going to ask you how
many plants were in that nine one gallon
containers in a two by two that's what
you're doing right now yeah insane right
it's uh wow it was uh it was a little
bit of an overzealous challenge now I've
always kind of tried to keep it to one
plant per square foot is the max I
really want to do but I thought you know
I've seen places I've worked for do it
this way where they'll throw you know
this many in such a small space and I
just wanted to see what would happen and
sure enough I ran into some problems you
know just because you just
having nine smaller plants there's just
no way I can get them to take that much
light in the same way that I could if it
was one plant right because you figure
if you have
nine plants with four branches each of
those four branches can only take a
certain amount of light versus having
one plant with 36 branches now all 36 of
those branches can absorb all of that
light so I'll end up with a better
overall final product I would think yeah
it definitely comes with its own set of
challenges running more smaller plants
in that grow Space versus one or two
larger plants in that gross base I think
there's pros and cons to both in my
opinion I think one of the things is
kind of getting into the grotent water
right I don't know if you have an auto
watering system or if you're doing hand
watering it's a hand water system uh I
have a little little cup that I would
just kind of reach in there luckily it's
a small 10 so my arms can reach back
there and I keep the bottoms of my
plants pretty well pruned so I don't
have to worry about breaking any
branches down there but it's definitely
an ordeal and it's gotten me to think
man if I would have had an auto watering
system I probably would had a lot easier
time there but once again I think that
if I was going to do any kind of
automatic system in there it'd probably
either be living organic soil with some
blue mat drippers or an auto pot you
know and at that point I can really only
do one plant in there so that might be
for the next Rhonda or even a flood
drain would be a potential for that yeah
yeah so that's what you're doing right
now you said it's an experiment what's
kind of your ideal State like what have
you done before have you done just one
or two plants in there before like what
in your opinion is the ideal state for
maximizing yield would you just do one
plant would you do a couple plants or
what for maximizing a yield I think that
one plant like I was saying is probably
my best route simply just because I can
have one large healthy plant absorb a
lot more light a lot more nutrients and
probably cycle through water faster than
I could having nine different plants and
you know you know each plant's an
individuals so you're gonna have a
problem on this one and you're not gonna
have a problem on this one and you end
up having to adjust the feed that way or
you can just not worry about it and let
the round finish and try and just learn
from that but I think for me next round
one plant's going to be a lot better in
terms of overall yield because the way I
I gauge my yield is the shape of my
canopy the the cubic dimensions of it
right I want about two vertical feet and
then the entire area of my grow tent
filled for for maximizing my yield right
like if I have a two by two space so I
need
what is that eight square feet or eight
cubic feet of canopy space so I can do
that with nine plants and I could do
that with one plant it just depends on
you know obviously if the one plant
might take a little longer to veg that
amount of time but I think it's worth it
if I have only one tent right if I only
have 110 then I'm only vegging in and
flowering in that same space so if I
have a separate space to veg that one
plant for even if right now my current
veg setup is just a single T5 light that
I have underneath my desk and I just
throw plants under there just to you
know keep them alive and growing a
little bit at a time while I have my
flowering tent up and running okay so
one plant in a two by two and then what
would be the ideal pot size for that for
ideal pot size I mean
I would say for a two by two
I don't really want to put anything
larger than a two gallon in there
because I mean I know with a three
gallon I could probably fill I don't
know maybe a three by three or a four by
four with a single plant given the right
amount of time and and whatnot and
once again you know going back to you
know my current setup I've got nine
plants in there nine one gallon pots
that's nine gallons of media right if I
have one two gallon pot that's two
gallons of media it's not two gallons of
media is gonna obviously dry out a lot
faster than nine gallons of media and
it's also going to put a lot less stress
on my exhaust system right the fans
aren't going to have to pull as much
moisture out of the air if there isn't
as much moisture being dumped into the
room through the soil
so I I would say for me like like I said
the the next round I have is going to be
just one single Gorilla Glue plant and I
have it in a two gallon pot right now I
just threw it in maybe a week ago
um my current run is going to be chopped
on Monday or Tuesday so hopefully by
that time this plant that I have ready
to go will only need to be vegged for
you know a few days or so before I can
flip it to flowers that way you know I
want to keep a quicker cycle if I can
but you know I also want to have the
most yield I can get out of that space
so if I have to veg a little longer I
will yeah I think individual goals
definitely come into play I mean there's
so many different ways to go about this
you had mentioned it you would go with a
two gallon one two gallon plant in that
two by two space I know people who are
running you know five gallon one five
gallon net space one seven gallon that
space one ten gallon that space you're
doing the synthetics I know there's
people who's running Organics so there
are so many different ways you can kind
of go about it when it comes to pot size
media inputs so on and so forth so yeah
it's really interesting to hear your
your experience there and what you would
say is ideal for that one the other
thing I didn't ask about was sugar is it
using any sugars like a lot of people
use molasses or any microbial inoculants
or any other inputs uh so far as sugars
or middle acids nothing like that at the
moment
um even when I was doing the Organics I
I didn't do any kind of compost teas or
anything like that not opposed I just uh
I'm in an apartment so it's kind of
harder for me to have a tea Brewer set
up or you know anything like that but um
yeah it's all good stuff especially you
know if you're in Organics you know you
can add some sugars and just feed your
microbes keep the you know turnover rate
going
um as far as my cryrobial inoculants
that I'm using I'm using uh
stream gardening mycos it's the water
soluble one
I really only use it to kind of like
flush my media
like as in almost like a transition
you know like if I was about to flip the
flower and it's like I didn't know I was
feeding a bunch of veg nutrients I might
hit it with some mycos plain water
before it flips that way it's like I get
most of that you know excess nitrogen
out and can start with the flowering
nutrients but
then again you know some people say you
know or I guess it's proven now that the
plant wants nitrogen maybe for the first
three weeks or so so it's probably less
beneficial than I would think but yeah I
like to use microbes and you know
especially in Organics you know it's
pretty much that's what you need in
Organics you know you gotta have the
worker bees in there breaking down the
Organics and just feeding the plant it's
a beautiful cycle yep very true
okay so we talked about your grow tent
setup we talked about what you use for
inputs talk about pot size uh I guess
one thing I didn't ask about was like
transplanting are you just planting
directly into those one gallon
containers or are you starting in like a
solo cup and then transplanting up like
how do you do your transplants and then
after that we'll get into trainings you
know what you do for plant training okay
um so far as transplants go
um the current run I had started out in
small uh eight ounce styrofoam cups
they're very small right I really wish I
would have started them in Solo cups I
probably would have ran into less issues
with a larger pop there
um the way I go about transplanting is
uh I kind of like to look at the plant
from the top down and if I can still see
any of the soil then I'm I'm not ready
to transplant but if I can't see the pot
or the cup at all then I know it's
probably ready for it so you transplant
up you get to your final container what
do you do for trainings when do you do
the trainings and then when you stop the
trainings that you do okay so for
training
um I would say this in an earlier
part of the grow you know if we're in
the Solo Cup I'm pretty much just
topping with occasionally I might do
some super cropping I might bend a
branch if it's really tall and lanky
um
for veg mostly just low stress training
or you know scrog I might use the net to
kind of keep my branches low and wide I
really want my plant to be as low and as
wide as I can possibly get it before I
flour it
um
topping works really well for that just
because you know you can decide how many
branches do I want each plant or my
current plant to have in general right
I want to have one top with about seven
nodes in each of my trellis holes in a
two by two you know that's 16 tops give
or take so if I can if I can get 16 Tops
on one plant and they all have about
five to seven nodes that's a perfect
canopy to start flour with in my opinion
so you're trying to get up to those 16
different tops or or branches to fill up
each one of those individual holes on
the trellis net when do you put up the
trellis nut like how many days are you
vegging for and when you like put up the
trellis nut and then what is the height
from the trellis net to the like the top
of the grill pot well
in terms of the height of the trellis
net I mean that's going to depend on on
your space right in my situation with
the 55 inches of vertical space right I
have about five inches at the top was
where my light is and it has to be hung
a certain distance from the canopy so
I'd say about 15 inches from the from
the light to the canopy and I want about
two feet of canopy which leaves me with
like about I don't know four and a half
inches of of leg that I can have when I
have seven inch tall pots so so vertical
space is what I'm always fighting in
such a small space
um
so my trellis net uh
I kind of I for this current run I
played with it right so I started it out
low at about 10 and a half inches
because I knew okay this is as high as I
want my legs to be so I just made sure
that before I flipped none of the
branches were really going above the net
I just wanted to keep it all even and
then once I had the full area filled the
full two by two fold I let them stretch
up a little bit to get some vertical
length right because I wanted
some canopy to start with about you know
six or seven inches of canopy to start
with
and so once I flipped I just moved the
net up above the plants so that they
would have to grow and stretch up into
it again and that worked out pretty good
um
like I said you know they stretch mostly
during the first three weeks so during
those first three weeks man they're
stretching about an inch a day just you
know I started out with a 10 and a half
inch tall plant and right now they're
sitting just under 36 inches
you know so I mean it was pretty close
um the main thing I like to do too is
once I'm done with that first initial
three weeks I like to take you know some
kind of tie and tie any runaway tops or
taller branches I like to tie them
directly to the net just to where
they're even with the other you know
colas in the canopies that way you know
I want the most even canopy I can get so
that we don't have any one bud pulling
more light than the other or shading out
the others if I can avoid that got it so
after flipping the flower that stretch
period you know two three weeks you're
probably making constant adjustments to
make sure some of the tops aren't
dominating others right right right if
you see one that's you know going up
here and this other one's over here you
might pull this one to the next trellis
hole over just to lower it a little bit
trying to keep it as even as possible
but you know life happens sometimes it
gets away from us all but it's gonna be
okay because even if you get one random
top that's you know way taller than the
others that's where our friends super
cropping comes in and we can just bend
and break if we need to we never want to
but if we have to we will that makes
sense now defoliating or lollipopping do
you do either one of those things 100 I
do both
um so far as lollipopping goes I really
like to only do it in week one of flower
just to kind of initiate that stretch
I'll I'll lollipop pretty aggressively
usually like I'll go almost to the top
node top three nodes Max
and uh I've noticed you know that's it's
kind of like the plants like ah what's
attacking me down here I better grow up
here and it really just induces that
stretch you know and that's that's what
I'm looking for in flower generally I I
like to start with a smaller plant and
finish with a medium-sized plant versus
starting with a medium-sized plant and
finishing with you know I don't want my
tops to be too close to the light that
makes sense I know there are quite a few
folks that are just tuning in on podcast
platforms and even the folks that are on
YouTube you're trying to get a visual of
how you do things but you do have an
Instagram which I'll be sure to link
down in the YouTube description section
below and then folks can go there and
click on there and actually see what
your setup is how you do it because uh
you've got a ton of pictures on there
that clearly show exactly what you're
talking about so I figured I'd mention
that one right now okay so you've done
your lollipopping defoliating you've got
your plants in the net spread out
maximizing the stretches done and after
that's just flowering just kind of
getting through the flowering period
just feeding as you need to watering as
you need to and so on and so forth right
right uh I forgot to say about uh
defoliation so
um there's a book I'm sure you've heard
of it uh three of light and they do uh
they do defoliation day 21 day 42 and
I've kind of tried it and it's worked
very well for me so I I always do those
defoliation days I do just like they say
I take off every single fan leaf larger
fan Leaf especially uh anything blocking
the light I really just want to maximize
light penetration through you know the
certain amount of canopy that I have you
know if I only have two feet of canopy
to work with I got to make sure I have a
light that will penetrate that two feet
that way my bottoms aren't looking as
bad as they could you know I've had it
happen where you know you don't get any
light down here and you end up with the
Fluffy popcorn bud and but you know at
the end of the day we want the good
tasty sticky colas that you get at the
top yeah absolutely I think with the
method that you explained especially
when doing lollipopping you get rid of a
lot of that lar fret and uh you know the
the from the net upwards is usually hard
buds that's the goal that's the goal
I want to take it back and bring it back
to water what are you using for a water
source
ah so like I said I'm in an apartment so
my my tap water is it's okay it's like
240 something ppms pretty high so um
normally I would never ever use anything
like that I have before and you know you
get mixed results
um
currently I'm going across the street I
have a Rite Aid and they have a little
water dispensing machine out there so
for like two bucks I get a five gallon
bottle and I've checked the ppms and
we're like 12 to 5 to 12 ppms which is
like nothing so it's very very clean uh
so that's what I'm using for water right
now yeah that's the reverse osmosis
technology is yeah because I have the
same thing there's water stations you
get and it's about the same PPM very
very low right do you monitor the pH of
the medium at all or your initial water
source if so what do you aim for
um so far as the media goes uh currently
I'm not monitoring it I don't I don't
check my runoff or I have a meter that
checks it but it's kind of hit and miss
you know uh I do monitor it whenever I
water or feed
um
the way I kind of do it is I'll check
the ppms of the plain water before I add
any nutrients and then each bottle that
I add I check the ppms and the pH
afterwards just to kind of see how it
affects it
um
but yeah yeah I monitor it but uh I'm
not super concerned with it like I'm
more concerned with the EC PPM or TDS
over the pH now the pH to me is more
important than like a true hydroponic
system where you know if you're in if
you reach are constantly suspended in
the water or constantly being having
water run over them then pH is probably
more more important because you know
that really affects how much nutrients
you're going to be able to uptake
whereas in a media situation I feel like
you end up
not having to worry about pH as much
just because the plants produce those
exudates that can adjust the environment
accordingly to what the plant wants so
if I just keep it in range you know
within I usually aim for five eight to
six two for my for cocoa at least in
Organics I don't I don't check pH or
worry about it at all because I know
that there's stuff in the soil that's
pretty much going to adjust the pH to
what it needs to be at anyways but for
Cocoa I know it's a little more
important so I try and just make sure
that when it's about to get watered in
it's got to be five eight
temperature is important to like I don't
want it to be too cold like any colder
than 68 degrees is too cold and any
warmer than 80 degrees is probably a
little too warm so I usually try and
keep it 70 to 75 degrees
um and obviously like I'm saying EC is
more important to me than pH uh I really
try and monitor
what I'm putting in and at what times
right you know you can't I can't feed a
plant that's you know smaller you know
like a fresh clone I can't feed it the
same way that I would feed a plant
that's you know a week away from being
chopped down so you know you got to know
what you're feeding that so on Coco 5 8
5.8 to 6.2 pH going in ignore the runoff
and then for PPM or EC are you doing are
you monitoring the runoff for that or is
it just what you're putting in like what
your nutrient mixes that you're putting
in yeah I only monitor it going in like
the only time I'm ever going to check my
runoff is if I'm having a problem really
if I'm if I'm noticing one plant has
some sort of you know burn or or just a
look to it I'll I might check the the
runoff to that but normally if I have
any kind of nutrient burn I'm just going
to flush that plant just for that week
I'll just not give it any nutrients just
hit it with some plain pH water or even
that and sometimes that's a good time to
use a microbe you know if you have some
mycose and you know you have a plant
that's struggling you can hit it with
some mycose and it might help eat up
whatever built up salts are in the media
to you know hopefully get it back on
track you mentioned the feeding chart
that you follow earlier do you know
offhand what the ECS are going in
uh not the EC offhand
um
I know that for my my most recent
feeding I gave them a very light dose it
was like 300 ppms that was my final
feeding and my next watering here should
be
tomorrow or maybe tonight
it's going to be just plain water I do
flush
forced habit I don't know you know we've
heard both ways that it's beneficial or
non-beneficial I like to do it I just
noticed that it really does help with uh
kind of bringing out some color along
with just you know peace of mind I just
it might not work that way where it's
you know I know I'm not flushing
anything out of the plant but if the
plant doesn't have anything else to eat
it's going to start eating itself which
is you know senescence I'm trying to
push that towards the end of flower so
so we talked about plant training we
talked about nutrition to very important
things when it comes to maximizing yield
let's get into environment that
certainly can impact the amount of yield
that you get you know if your
environment temperature humidity CO2 are
in a whack you could see a significant
stunt growth so let's break it down one
by one what temperature do you typically
aim for
for temperature uh in my grow tent and I
I like to keep it under 80 above 70 if I
can
um I've had it go up you know 86 in
there and you don't have a lot of
problems as long as you're you know kind
of closer to the beginning of flower or
in veg but towards the end of flower I
do like to keep it a little cooler
um right now I have it aimed for 70 to
75 degrees
um I don't have an AC in there obviously
it's a two by two so I just use my my
Apartments Central AC and that does
enough to where I keep it pretty cool in
there and don't have to worry too much
about the temps and then humidity what
do you typically aim for for RH
uh for veg uh as high as I can get it in
there I like to keep it pretty high you
know 70 to 60 is pretty ideal for me in
terms of veg uh for flour uh
I'll keep it 60 to 50 is about where I
want it anywhere in that range is
usually pretty safe
and then when I chop the plant I try and
keep the 60 and 60 60
percent humidity and 60 degrees if I can
but um a little warmer than that's
obviously not a huge issue but just uh
in that range is good for me so if I'm
remembering correctly I'm pretty sure
what you mentioned as far as temperature
humidity Falls within the the ideal VPD
range right you've got the the green I
know how much you know about VPD but uh
you've got the green optimal range for
VPD then you've got the yellow which is
kind of like the tolerance range for VPD
and then the red which is kind of out of
range and I think what you mentioned uh
lines up with the optimal range or at
least in the tolerance range so you're
probably getting some really good plant
growth there uh and certainly staying
within that VPD range I mean that's
going to help maximize growth right it's
going to help maximize your overall
yield definitely vpu is very important
um I know that obviously if your
environment you're if your environment's
off at all you know it can throw off the
way your plant eats which if your
plant's not eating all the food that
you're getting it you could have a
buildup in your medium which could have
you know lead to more problems in the
cation exchange right so it really is
important and environment's key
um
the better environment that you can
create for the plant the better plant
growth you'll get but that doesn't mean
that we can't get decent plant growth
out of them less than ideal situation
you know the plants are very resilient
and they can you know do things to their
environment to affect what they need but
there is a limit right you know you can
definitely kill a plant with uh you know
a bad environment I've done it where you
know you let the tent get a little too
warm or you know when I first got into
this I didn't know like that you should
have a fan exhausting the air out you
know I just threw a light in there and
just hoped it would be fine but I was
like oh it's a T5 it won't do anything
bad I'm not going to burn my plants but
you can burn your plants with c5s if you
don't have any air exchange I'll
guarantee you that I fried the crap out
of seedlings before when I first started
growing because I read on a forum the
more light the better which was not true
at all especially with an HID grow light
uh burnt the crap out and completely
kill them so it's like
um no
yeah that's the thing that's what they
say you know every uh every piece of
equipment works as long as you use it
correctly but it's very easy to misuse
any piece right you know you can do have
the most perfect environment but then
you know if you're overfeeding or you're
over watering or you're you know you're
topped at the wrong time or something
and now the plant has to recover longer
you know you can run into problems any
Any Which Way But
I think the best thing to do is to
remember hey I'm only going to be with
this plant for 90 days max right so like
as long if I have a problem with this
plant hey I just kind of let it go
unless it's something I can fix now if
not then just worry about it the next
run man I think that's my best bet is to
keep my my stress levels down because
it's very easy when you're passionate
about these plants to let it get to you
and stress you out but I I think that
the happier I am the happier my plants
generally are for some reason so well
said
CO2 one of those things where it's just
study after study after study proving
that increased levels of CO2 helps
increase biomass are you doing anything
to supplement CO2 in the environment at
all or no
uh
not necessarily as I was saying I do use
microbes and microbes breathe out CO2 so
to some level I guess there's a little
bit of CO2 supplementation through that
but as far as like uh you know the
canisters or the mushroom bags or
anything I haven't done that in that
space I might do it in the 4x8 next but
for right now I'm not and I'm not
supplementing any CO2 but it is
definitely you know you're going to get
more yield when you when you use a CO2 I
feel like there's only two real things
that I can say that would increase your
yield for sure and that's CO2 and a
might a light mover light mover uh even
in a two by two no I wouldn't use it in
a two by two for my four by eight I was
thinking about throwing a thousand watt
onto a light mover so that way I can
cover both four by four spaces with that
one light and I might be able to pull
you know more yield from one light in
there than I would if I was to throw two
600 watts in there or something
interesting how about pest prevention we
haven't talked about that yet a lot of
people will do things to prevent pests
from invading your grow space What do
you do uh personally I've used a few
different things
um for Organics I really like insect
grass
just kind of helps to keep your plant
you know the cell walls get more strong
so they're less likely to be attacked
along with just kind of uh the chitin in
there kind of triggers a response in the
plant to make it so that their defenses
are up so that's kind of like a
preventative uh if I'm dealing with
Organics uh in terms of synthetics I
really only use one product it's called
plant therapy
um
I think it's got like
some kind of rubbing alcohol and other
mix in it I don't know what's in it but
I once again I really only use that if I
see like damage like if I see thrip
damage or you know for some reason see a
bug in there I'll spray them that day
but I I try not to ever spray and flour
and I really will only do it once in veg
just to kind of you know peace of mind
be like I just want to make sure hey I
didn't see anything but I just want to
have a clean slate when I go in flower
so I don't have to deal with it in flour
if you had any like major infestations
would say like fungus gnats or spider
mites or anything that you had to battle
uh luckily in this 2x2 not yet I haven't
had any major issues
um
I've had problems in the past with you
know fungus gnats white flies
um and some of the places I've worked at
I've dealt with aphids or root aphids
and you know broad mites rusted mites
I've dealt with a lot of different
things along with pathogens like pm and
you know bud rot and all that but um
yeah in my in my personal grow here at
home now my plants are usually pretty
sturdy and once they go into flower and
I'm on the second story so it's like I
don't have to worry about the things
crawling into our house that way it's
less likely so luckily I've I've been
pretty pretty bug free in my tent lately
so that's good to hear what other
problems have you come across when
growing in such a small space and what
did you do to fix those problems uh uh
small space problems really comes down
to when we were talking about
environment and um
I think that's one of the things that
I've learned from dealing with nine
plants in the one space is that you have
to water them all right and so putting a
lot of extra humidity and moisture into
the room and your fan is going to have
to exhaust all of that so sometimes I've
had less than ideal humidity ranges in
there where it'll be you know a little
bit out of the range I like but
my usual fix is just open the tent let
some fresh air get in there and it
usually works pretty good but
one of the other problems too of a small
space obviously is the height
restriction you know like I was looking
at uh this gorilla glue or Gorilla Grow
Tent that was uh I think it's a two by
two and a half but it's like seven feet
tall or something so I feel like
something like that I would have way
less problems with height issues you
know because in this current row if I
could have let the plants get just a
little bit taller I probably would have
gotten a much better yield and they
probably would have been a lot healthier
but because I had to flip it before it
hits that certain height I ended up you
know having to deal with a smaller plant
but
other than that I would say you know two
by two space is great for if you're just
a single home home grower you're only
growing for yourself I think that you
know four to five ounces every 90 days
is a pretty good deal if you're you know
buying it at the store and stuff you
know you're spending what like 100 bucks
on an ounce or something you know you
figure but two by two tent setups like
400 bucks if you get the you know the
whole kit or something
you know one cycle and you pretty much
paid for your whole whole tent right
there and you know and then every
Harvest after that's just you know more
more tree so you definitely get your
money's worth growing your own
uh heat issues have you had any of those
that I feel like that's like the number
one problem I feel like people growing
in small spaces is they put these LED
grow lights in there which some people
put more more powerful than what they
need and then then running into heat
issues has that occur to you at all or
like is your central air conditioner
that you mentioned that you're using is
that just completely mitigated
uh it's definitely an issue
um if I run the light that I have now at
100 the hottest it really gets is like
86. I mean that's deal withable but if I
didn't have that ventilation system that
checks the environment constantly with
the little sensor like and I just had to
rely on me being there then it's then
it's more of an issue but that AC
Infinity fan you know it makes
everything so easy in terms of managing
your environment that way with Temp and
humidity
um so far as lighting in in the space
goes uh
I I know that I've seen you know some of
my favorite YouTubers do it where
they'll throw a much more powerful light
than the space can really take and I've
seen good things come from it I've also
seen bad things come from it so I mean I
guess it's like
you know roll the dice if you want but
you know don't don't be mad if something
bad happens right like uh
I don't know even 150 watts seems like a
little bit too much light for the two by
two space uh I kind of almost wish I
would have gone with the smaller model
and just done 100 Watts I probably would
have maybe ran into less issues but I
was a little overzealous I was like I've
got two extra inches to work with on
either end I should be fine but
you know we'll see you next next run
when I only do the one plan I want to
see if I can get it to take the full 150
watts no problem and if I do that then I
know I'll probably be okay but got it so
I think we covered quite a bit of things
that impact yield the only thing we
really didn't talk about was the
genetics right as number one uh you know
get high yielding genetics to begin and
that's going to help contribute towards
a higher yield overall you know
especially in a two by two grow space
but uh is there any other advice or
anything you can think of for those
folks that are trying to maximize yield
into two by two space
uh yeah I would say the main thing for
me
uh just knowing your space right knowing
how much height you have to deal with in
terms of how how high is my light able
to go in this space
uh how far away do I have to keep that
light from the canopy and then I will
like I said I want about two cubic feet
of canopy at any one time
to get the maximum yield I would say
right the most you can really do is
three feet three cubic feet of canopy
space but any more than that and I feel
like he might end up burning your tops
trying to light up the bottom and I
don't want to do that
so I tend to just try and keep it in
that two foot of canopy range with maybe
one to one and a half feet of leg to
support it
um so that that's my plant that I want
right that's like the ideal plant shape
and size or canopy shape and size that I
want for any space so I just recreate
that in a two by two space you know if
uh if you're in a three by three you
know you want 18 cubic feet if you're in
a four by four you want 32 cubic feet of
canopy and that should be the about
where you want it if you want to get
your maximum yield all right good stuff
so let's wrap things up tell us how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future I don't know
well you can find me on Instagram right
now that's my main social media Outlet I
also have a YouTube I don't really have
a lot of content it's more of just a
video log at this moment
I would like to do you know more videos
like this in the future just you know I
like I like to say it like this you know
the only thing I like doing more than
growing medicinal plants is talking
about growing medicinal plants so I mean
something like this is awesome just
getting to talk to other people about
it's always a joy
so uh I don't know I'm just gonna keep
letting it happen uh hopefully social
media will do well for me and I can make
some good connections and just keep
talking to people about this and
yeah just excited for the future awesome
well like I mentioned earlier in the
episode I will have a link to Vince's
Instagram down in the YouTube
description section below and also link
your channel your YouTube channel if
you'd like I can link that down there as
well so people can navigate to your
channel And subscribe to your channel
awesome thank you so much if you enjoyed
this episode click that thumbs up also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single weekend I'm
releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode and I'd love for you to tune
into future episodes Vince thanks so
much for coming on this has been cool to
talk about growing in a 2x2 and
maximizing the space so I haven't grown
a 2x2 but I do plan to eventually grow
in a two by two right now I'm growing in
a two by four and a four by four but a
lot of the things that we mentioned
today that you mentioned today can be
taken and put into larger growth spaces
as well so I think this is not only
valuable to those smokes growing in
small growth spaces but a lot of it does
go towards larger growth spaces
definitely yeah you gotta be able to
scale it up if you can now absolutely
alright peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode thank you Chris have a
good one man