coming up on Garden talk my soil is the
most important thing to me if I don't
have good solo I don't have good crops
so I treat my soil extremely well and
try to help it be as nutritious as
possible my tomato plant roots will feed
on the microbes from the cover crop
plantings are still the roots are still
on the ground they may be dead but
there's there's still life down there
eating and surviving and helping each
other out so I'm a huge huge cover crop
fan I'm building my soil legitimately
every single year because I'm adding
more castings more sort of cover
cropping like it just gets better and
the yields go up and I mean we know our
mechanic we know our doctor we know the
got Footlocker that sells our shoes by
name but we don't know who put who grows
the food that we put in our body and
most of all our kids body that's just
back ass words to me
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 99. in this
episode I interview Michael Bell he runs
a half acre garden and supplies his
local community with his harvests he
talks all about his garden how he grows
his plants and how you can emulate what
he does and make great money doing it if
you gain value from these podcast
episodes please click the like button
and also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already that way you can be
notified when new episodes are released
if you'd like to support even more you
can do so by going to patreon.com Mr
growit there are various rewards set up
for those that support and you could
pledge any amount that you'd like 100 of
the money pledged so patreon goes right
back into the podcast it helps this
podcast keep going so thank you so much
for your support there before we get
into it I want to acknowledge that one
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
free gardening information of all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode episode who helped make
that goal possible thanks to AC Infinity
for sponsoring this episode their grow
10 kits are incredible you get their eye
on board LED grow light their grow tent
which is currently the thickest on the
market the ventilation system clip-on
fan and their controller 69 to control
it all you also get their fabric pots
trellis nut plant ties and Tremors
definitely a good price for all that you
get in the kit I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow tank kits
and the discount code Mr Grodd 15 works
on both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Michael Bell how you doing today
I'm good man thanks for having me thanks
for coming on so you have a very large
garden and you actually grow plants for
your local community and you make money
while doing it when you reach out to me
and ask to be on the podcast I was
inspired I commend you for what you're
doing and for you wanting to come on and
spread your message to inspire others
we're going to dive into the details of
your garden and how you go about making
money from it but first let's do an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening
yeah
um I own Dallas half acre Farm it's a uh
a little less than a half acre a piece
of property right outside of Dallas
Texas I don't live on the property it's
just strictly by farm and where I raise
a few chickens and quail and you know
it's a miniature farm is what I call it
just a farm scaled down to a half acre
and I've been doing it seven years
starting in January will be my seventh
year and I grow seasonal vegetables for
uh families and people in my
neighborhood and at businesses and that
I know you know anyone that wants to buy
buy them I'll sell them to them I don't
do farmers markets
um it's directly I don't do restaurants
or grocery stores it's directly to the
families and the people that that I know
that want to buy
um so seasonal vegetables is like right
now going into the fall here in Dallas
winter it's a
salad mix kale carrots uh small onions
um you know about the size of a quarter
or a golf ball and a lot of people eat
them for the greens instead of the
actual onions so
um then I've got a little bit of
cilantro left and just anything that you
think of during the winter I grow that
and then come spring I move into uh
salads I grow salad year round here in
Texas so I can do that pretty easily and
then I do tomatoes peppers
you know a little bit of cantaloupe if I
have the space just stuff that you think
of in a seasonal Garden I just make it a
little bit bigger and then I'm able to
sell it okay pretty straightforward and
so you have different plants that you go
for different times of the year yep yep
it's all seasonal
um like I don't grow carrots in the
middle of the summer because it's it's
they don't taste as good
um I don't grow tomatoes during the
winter because obviously the frost and
the freeze here in Texas kills them so
it's just basic what you would think of
a backyard garden except there's a few
techniques I do to increase my yield
and
um
overall profitability so I imagine the
folks that are looking to do this as
well determining a place to grow the
plants how do you determine if the space
you are looking to plant in receives
enough sunlight uh it's just observation
um but I picked that when I picked my
property that I bought now I went out
there four or five times just to see
where the sun was at different times of
the day
obviously here in Texas you know the
summers are brutal it's 110 for weeks
you know between 100 110 for four to
five six weeks on end so
in my context I want uh Evening Shade so
if I can get that morning sun up to
three or four o'clock and then I've got
a nice tree line or something off to the
to the west to give me some Shade that's
perfect but yeah you are correct you
need as much sunlight as possible for
the growth but depending on your area
you know if I'm in
Minnesota I don't really care if I'm
have a West shade or not because it
doesn't get that hot there I just want
maximum sunlight so you got to take in
the contexture your temperature
and your amount of sunlight got it talk
to us a little bit deeper about your
half acre that you're gardening on I
believe you're growing all in beds
correct me from on there and then what
plants do you have kind of growing where
so aggro
um I grow actually growing 330 foot long
14 foot wide caterpillar tunnels
um they're seven foot six in the middle
and they're shaped like a tunnel and
they're they're made out of poles that
are bent into a tunnel shape every five
feet and it's got eight mil plastic on
it and during the winter I can close
everything down and hold in that heat
um during the summer I can raise the
plastic up a good five or six feet on
the side and then take the end walls
down so I've got good airflow going
every which direction
so that allows me to plant
summer crops earlier because in Texas we
usually get a frost around Easter
well I plant my tomatoes spring break so
I plant them three or four weeks earlier
than what I could is if I didn't have my
tunnels
and then in the fall I just lost all my
tomato plants last week because it got
down to the low 30s you know for five or
six hours a night four nights in a row
and it just shocked them whereas last
year
I had tomatoes selling at Christmas
because we never got that cold
so some years I could have them for a
long time some years like this year it
was just kind of a free deal with with
getting that cold snap real early but it
does you know growing in the tunnels
helped tremendously it also protects
them from the rain which you think
you know plants don't need protection
from the rain but when you're growing
lettuce and even Tomatoes what happens
is in the summer here in Texas you'll
get a thunderstorm and it'll rain a
quarter of an inch and an hour later
it's 105 again and the humidity is 95
and it's pure hell on Earth
and those leaves on that lettuce are wet
and it's 95 degrees you get a fungus
and you lose everything
whereas grow underneath my tunnels that
plastic protects it they don't get wet
everything stays dry
and so it helps Regard in regards to
that quite a bit so
now that you understand the context of
the tunnels
um yes I grow in raised beds about six
to eight inches tall because my soil is
so bad it's literally clay it's like
concrete during the summer and swamp
during the fall in the winter because
it's so wet so I just bought
a bunch of one by six uh Cedar boards
and made beds that are three foot wide
and 50 foot long inside my tunnels and
gave me a little walkway every 50 foot
to get in and out of the tunnels
and fill them up with compost and my uh
amendments that I put in there depending
on what exact plant I'm putting in there
with them and off the go I don't till I
don't know if you've ever heard of the
phrase no-till so I'm like no-till I
never till my soil
it helps with the fertility and in Texas
it gets so dry it helps retain moisture
so that helps a ton and
um it's just easier my soul never gets
compacted I don't walk on my beds so
they never get compacted
um my bands are three foot wide so I
don't have to walk on my beds to harvest
anything I can get everything from one
side
and then I can walk around and do
everything on the other side and reach
to the middle when I go from both sides
so my soil
my soil is the most important thing to
me if I don't have good soil I don't
have good crops so I treat my soil
extremely well and try to help it be as
nutritious as possible I definitely want
to get deeper into this soil and how you
do the amending and so on and so forth
but I do want to ask about the tunnels
first specifically how much does it cost
to build out those tunnels there's a
company there's several companies
there's uh two main companies that you
can get them from one is Farmer's friend
and it says farmers friendlc.com and
then there's another uh company called
bootstrap farmer and they both sell to
small-scale Farmers like about me and
they just send you the kit you put it
together they got a 10 minute video both
of them have 10 minute videos on how to
do it
um they're really easy to put together I
can put one up in about four hours by
myself I don't recommend it but
most of the that I do I have to do
by myself so
um it is possible and I'll be honest
with you I haven't got a quote on a
tunnel in a couple years because I don't
need any more but I think I'm 50 Footers
around twelve hundred dollars
so it's not going to break the bank but
it's definitely something you should be
serious about before you go spend the
money but they do last an extremely long
time like I've had the same plastic now
going on Seven Seasons
I'll probably have to replace it after
this season but it's paid for itself
very very easily yeah it sounds like it
can be extremely valuable and pretty
much needed for somebody like you where
you have those swings in the environment
like you mentioned yeah absolutely
um I that's a everyone that I talked to
about this I ask them are you serious or
you just want to try it and if they say
I just want to try it out I said okay
wait till spring
you know try it for three or four months
and then if you love it spend the money
and buy you a tunnel but if you're dead
serious right now spend your money on a
tunnel first and then you know buy the
other stuff that you think you need
because you just can't grow year round
without the tunnels and if you're trying
to make money doing this you can't take
off four months out of the year and not
grow anything that makes sense so
preparing the soil for planting a lot of
people will amend the soil with
fertilizer to begin I know you mentioned
your organic no-till what do you do to
the soil in order to prepare for
planting so first thing I take into
account is what am I planting if I'm
planting tomatoes in this three foot
wide bed
um
I'm going to put in
different amendments that I'm going to
do if I'm going to put in lettuce so if
I grow a lot of salad mix on my farm so
if I'm just doing salad mix the most
important thing is nitrogen and the
organic forms of nitrogen that I prefer
to use on that farm is soybean meal
you can get a box of it for 20 bucks I
think there's five pounds in it and a
box lasts me
got four or five months so I mean that
amendment's really cheap and I just
literally just sprinkle it all over the
bed before I plant and then kind of rake
it into the soil
so that's a big one but the most
important amendment that I use is worm
castings and for those of you that don't
know what worm castings are they're warm
this warm poop and it sounds gross
but it's not
um there's a guy down in plantersville
Texas down by Houston and he's pretty
much the smartest man alive when it
comes to worm castings like we all have
our own Hobby and his Hobbies worms and
making the most nutritious worm castings
there is in in the world like he has
other
worm castings tested he'll bind with his
own money test them just to make sure
his are still higher grade than everyone
else's
and he he loves it he's a wealth of
knowledge and I buy a thousand pounds
from him twice a year
and
what I do is usually a five gallon
bucket
every 15 feet
so like uh on a 50-foot bed I'll put
three three and a half five gallon
buckets which is about I don't know 60
70 pounds worth of worm casting into
that bed and then just rake it in like I
do the soybean mail
so the worm castings if you're anywhere
close to Houston like Louisiana Oklahoma
Arkansas to Mexico is worth the drive
down there you buy a thousand pound bag
big old tote sack he puts it in the back
of your truck with a
with a tractor and you drive off with it
and you go home and unload it however
you want to unload it but they're by far
the best I've actually done accidental
tests without fat tomatoes
um I dig a hole of course and then I put
worm castings and some organic
fertilizer in there and uh sometimes I
forget
to put the worm castings in the hole
well two weeks later I can go back and I
can see I didn't put worm castings
in that one because that tomato plant's
two two feet shorter than all my other
tomato plants I mean there's a massive
difference and it's all because of the
quality and I've done every test that I
can do
by myself just to try it out and every
time
they proved to be the best and I really
can't talk about them enough yeah I use
worm cars things in my garden for my
medicinal plants and makes a huge
difference definitely makes a huge
difference it's got the microbes on
there as well which will help break down
any other organic matter that you add
into the medium so yeah can't speak
enough about worm castings that's for
sure now are you starting these plants
indoors and then letting them grow for a
little while maybe under a grow light
and then transferring them to your
outdoor Garden or you just planting
directly into your outdoor beds no I uh
I start indoors I have a tub shed in my
backyard because my wife
um was getting really pissed because I
have so many lettuce plants and
everything growing in my house so I
splurged and bought me a 10 by 10 Tough
Shed and insulated it and I've got a six
four foot wide six foot tall grow racks
from Lowe's that has some LED lights
that I start everything from indoors I
mean obviously root crops carrots beets
radishes though those get started direct
seeded
but most everything else is transplanted
lettuce tomatoes
you know some of the grains like red
Russian Kerala charred I'll just direct
so into the ground but probably 75
percent of my farm is uh started in my
Tough Shed or my backyard and then
you know depending on the date how many
days it is since I planted them I uh
transplant them into my farm I was going
to ask what how long did you let them
grow indoors before you transplant
Outdoors
um it switches back it depends on the
plant you know obviously Tomatoes I
usually start you know around Christmas
and I'll transplant March 1st because I
like really big tomato plants
um so you know that's a good 12 weeks
whereas lettuce is 21 to 24 days
um
so it just depends on the crop like I
said salad is usually 21 to 24 days
maybe 26 but anything over 26 tends to
get too big and when I transplant it it
goes into kind of a shock and I lose the
bigger leaves anyway so I actually lose
Time by letting the plants get bigger
got it now when you do plant them into
your outdoor Garden forgot to ask are
you using any cover crops like some
folks will use cover crops and grow
along with their plants or some folks
will do cover crops between grows do you
do any of that at all or no
oh yeah yeah I'm a huge cover crop fan
um I don't know if you've heard of Gabe
brown but he's a regenerative farmer up
in North Dakota or South Dakota and he's
got five principals for soil health and
I follow all five of those you know
religiously
um
just to try to increase my soil and
cover crop is
you know so does two of the five things
it always has a root in the ground so
during the winter like in my tomato I
caught my tomato tunnel that's where I
grow most of my tomatoes right now it's
covered in a 13 seeded winter
uh grass cover crop it's about three
four inches high now and then in the
spring around the end of February March
1st I'll uh
I'll tarp it kill it real good and then
I'll pull the that dead grass back dig a
hole plant my tomato plants right into
the
to the dead cover crop and that cover
crop acts as a mulch
for uh my tomatoes all summer which
helps with retained moisture you know my
tomato plant roots will feed on the
microbes from the cover crop plantings
are still the roots are still in the
ground they may be dead but there's
there's still life down there eating and
surviving and helping each other out
so I'm a huge huge cover crop fan most
layers do you use any of those
um yeah so I can't use cover crops on my
lettuce beds because
the cover crop tends to not die
perfectly so when I go to harvest
lettuce I've got
you know wheat grass or hairy veg
whatever my cover crop was grown inside
my lettuce and it makes it so tedious to
sit there and pick out every little
thing so instead of doing using a cover
crop on my uh
let us Bears I use wood chips there's a
there's a place two miles from my farm
that sells a pickup load for 10 bucks
so I go down there quite often and get
wood chips and
put them everywhere so how much mulch of
wood chip especially during the summer
because it just keeps the ground cooler
and moisture retention and all of that
there's so many benefits to mulching so
it sounds like you're getting everything
just about locally huh everything is
local except the worm castings but yeah
everything else is is local and
I mean it's my compost is three miles
away wood chips is two miles away my
house is four miles away so I mean it's
pretty easy that's the way to do it so
you've started your plants indoors
you've grown them to a certain point you
transfer them to your outdoor beds that
are amended with the fertilizer that it
needs for that particular type of plant
as the plant's growing what type of
organic inputs are you adding in
throughout the grow and when do you add
them so lettuce I don't the grains I
don't add anything after I because they
grow so fast like I'll transplant them
in at 24 25 days and during the spring
fall and summer when the days are a
little bit longer you get more sunlight
I'll Harvest that day 50. so they're
literally in the ground three to four
weeks before I harvest them so lettuce
isn't a big deal
dear uh the other plants the fruit
bearing plants tomatoes peppers zucchini
stuff like that I found this stuff at my
local Nursery here and they get it from
somewhere I don't know they don't make
it but it's got like that guano molasses
I mean there's a list of like 20
different things that are completely
organic that they figured out some
combination to put together and it comes
in a gallon jug and then you dilute
dilute that into a spray bottle
and about once every two to three weeks
also I'll spend a few hours and go
through seven or eight gallons of
my after I diluted seven or eight
gallons maybe a half a jug and and water
you know deep water that stuff into the
ground and you can tell three to four
days later
there's more blooms they're healthier
they're Greener they're darker
um if they're really struggling I'll do
it once a week and then maybe back off
to every two to three weeks yeah I just
go about observation
but that is a great amendment to have
I'm really lucky to have found it it is
25 for a gallon and I would probably use
three gallons for the whole year you
mentioned watering I want to ask you
about that next how do you go about
watering I mean you have such a huge
area that you have a garden on what's
your watering routine
uh that's drip tape everything's on drip
deep uh drip tape from drip Depot comes
with a kit
um so what I I have you know 14 foot
wide tunnels so I have uh a 15 foot I
call it the main hose a 15 foot strip of
main hose that goes across the length of
the bed
that has a water hose hook up to it
and each bed depending on what I grow
like lettuce I can get four rows of
lettuce and a three foot bed
so I've got four drip lines that the
lettuce is planted right next to every
dripping meter which is
um eight inches apart
so
if there's a jumping meter there's a
lettuce plant right next to it and at
the end of the hose out of the main hose
where the drip tape connects
has a I don't know what you want to call
it a faucet nozzle that you can turn
that specific line off or on so if I
decide to grow something that's not
every eight inches or I don't have four
beds I just turn that drip line off
and turn the drip line on if I'm growing
tomatoes per se I don't need four lines
of water if I've got one row of tomatoes
and it's it's all on drip I mean it's
you just turn it on and the biggest
thing is observation knowing when to
water and when not to water and you know
how long the water and you know other
than just observation you just turn it
on you must be saving a ton of labor
hours by having that automated watering
system there I imagine some people are
listening to this and they're like wow
it's a massive space he must be spending
all day long in your garden just
managing your plants whether it be
feeding or watering or so on and so
forth how often do you spend in your
garden each day
um
four hours
four to five hours now I could spend
more but I have a family
um and I don't think I even told you
this I'm actually a full-time teacher
um I found this farming thing seven
years ago and I didn't know how it was
gonna go I was like you know what I'm
gonna try it fell in love with it I
actually figured out I'm pretty good at
it and it makes pretty good money but
now I'm too close to retirement from
teaching so the way teachers work in
Texas you work
24 25 years and then you get a
percentage of your salary for the rest
of your life for retirement
so I'm like literally eight years away
and then I get three thousand dollars a
month for the rest of my life so I'm not
gonna you know leave doing that when I'm
this close so I actually Farm part-time
I tell everybody I'm a full-time farmer
and a part-time teacher because that's
the way I feel because I do so much
stuff at the farm and that I should do
so much stuff at school for my farm like
during lunch I'm planting seed trays on
my conference period I'm on the phone
talking to people or scheduling pickups
or deliveries or you know whatever so I
work from 4 30 in the morning to seven
o'clock in the morning at the farm then
I go to school and then at night or on
the weekends I'll get in another
you know a few hours here and there
averages out to four to five hours a day
yeah I think I read in one of your other
interviews like in the caption or
whatever that you're a PE teacher yep I
teach uh elementary PE K through five
that's funny my uh brother-in-law is
also a PE teacher so yeah it's not bad I
mean everybody's like oh that's the
easiest job ever and I said come and
spend eight hours with 300 screaming
kids I mean yeah I don't have to grade
papers and listen you know do lesson
plans too much but I have 300 screaming
kids for eight hours a day
so it's not all rainbows and sunshine uh
getting back onto plants I did want to
actually talk about pest prevention now
you have such a large space that you're
gardening on and I can imagine that
sometimes you have to deal with pests
what do you do to prevent pests from
occurring and have you ever had like any
infestations that you had to battle that
you can talk about so
my Arts I have two arch nemesis and if I
was God for a day I would destroy them
forever and they never walk the planet
again but they're um
this type of worm
it's actually a moth it's what a moth is
before it transforms into a moth it's
just a worm and it gets down in the
middle of your lettuce
and they like it there because it's
usually moist
dry you know moist warm or cool during
the summer it's cooled in the summer and
they just eat your plants from the good
lettuce from the inside out and you
don't know that it's there
until half your lettuce is gone
and so during spring and fall is the
worst so during the Spring of the Fall
I'm literally digging
pretty much in every lettuce plant
looking for one because if there's one
three days later there'll be thousands
so it's one of those things you you want
to stay on top of and they have this
I hate using it it's completely organic
you can spray it in your mouth it tastes
I actually did it just to make sure
tastes like crap but and it doesn't kill
the the worm what it actually does is
it makes the worm's mouth too sticky to
open up and then it starves to death
so it's not like a pesticide it's more
like a glue but it's completely safe for
people so that's the only spray that I
use and then the other pest that I fight
continuously with is hornworms
for tomato plants you know the big fat
green worms that have the horns sticking
out they will destroy a tomato plant
in two days I mean I had a real bad
um in the middle of October I lost
30 of my tomatoes to hornworms but the
the weather conditions were perfect
um for them and now the way you can't
even spray anything for them you
literally have to just sit there and
pick them off
um luckily they're not that hard to find
you can get a black light
and they glow in the dark
so they have a very fluorescent color at
night so
sometimes I take my kids out there and
say Here's a dollar for everyone that
you find
or something
I mean but those are the two that I have
everything else
I've learned if you
create spaces for
the pest Predators they take care of
them
if that makes sense so like Gabe Brown I
mentioned earlier he said that he heard
a scientist say there's 1700 beneficial
plants for everyone pest so I'm sorry
1700 beneficial insects for one pest but
you have to give them the environment to
thrive in for them to go search so
that's why mono crop is so bad for
farming because there's no place for the
good pass to live so like in the middle
of my bed
I might have a three foot raised box on
top of my raised bed that's just got
flowers in it Salvia and marigolds and
you know different stuff and it looks
completely insane because it's right in
the middle of zucchini but the stuff
that eats the squash bugs which is
usually a bad problem for people with
you know zucchini and squash they but
those good insects live in that flower
little group of flowers right there you
know cover crops are the same way
not mowing your cover crop gives those
beneficial insects a home to live when
you need them so it's pretty much
companion planting as well that you're
utilizing is there any other companion
plants that you have besides the ones
you just mentioned it's not so many it's
so much companion planting it's what
fits in that empty spot in the ground
that I can grow and make money off of
while like when Tomatoes get my tomatoes
get up to 10 feet tall
have you ever heard of lean and lower no
I haven't it's when your tomato plants
get so damn tall you can't reach the top
of them so I trellis my tomato plants on
one one string straight up and when they
get so tall you unravel some string at
the top and you lower them and they lean
like this and then they start to grow up
again well all this space down here
there's nothing there because I pruned
that because to keep fungus and disease
and stuff off the tomato plants so I'll
go in I'll plant radishes or beets or
lettuce or whatever I can think of that
I know I can sell then I need that you
know need to get in the ground I'll
plant underneath
those tomato plants for example
so it it doesn't hurt anything but I
don't know if it if you call it
companion planting it's more like
make money planting understood yeah so
let's say you've gone through the entire
Grill process you didn't deal with any
pests that took away your crop
harvesting let's get into that how do
you go about harvesting and what do you
typically get for yields
um it depends on what it is
um you know salad I sell in a Ziploc one
gallon Ziploc bag
it's not the most process you know I get
DMS all the time you're losing too much
money buying Ziploc bags you should use
the Uline one gallon bags with this tie
but my customers like the Ziploc bags
you know so I'll spend an extra 10 cents
and so anyway I'm getting off on a
tangent so
like the Ziploc bag is six heads of
lettuce and I sell it for five bucks
that just just to give you an idea
um and but I plant four rows every eight
inches so like I could get into the math
until you you know real door numbers but
just on basis
I can on a 50 foot bed I'll make 500
every eight weeks
on average you know during the summer
it's every six weeks during the fall and
the winter it's 10 to 12 weeks because
stuff just doesn't grow as fast
but it's very easy to get five crops
five to six crops of lettuce out of one
bed in a 12 month time period
and you can usually get about 500 for
that bed so now you can do the math
uh tomatoes
you know it just depends on the crop I
could spend an hour telling you about it
but I the easiest way I can tell you is
once you're set up it's so much profit
margin is so high you can't even imagine
because you're not
I mean the worm castings you pay for the
seeds cheap as hell the main thing is
your time
and I tell people all the time I don't
even know what to like pay myself hourly
wage because I would do it for free
like if I never made another Dom I'd
still Farm just the way I do now just
because I love it but the profit margins
are insane when you start
when you when you can quit buying stuff
like you want to buy another tunnel you
don't have to make more beds you don't
have to do this you don't have to do
that once you get your farm into a
machine
it's probably 80 profit margin that's
incredible I mean it takes a while to
get it to that point but when you do you
as long as you don't do something stupid
and or you know tornado hits or
something and screws everything up it's
just a machine it's a well-oiled machine
you do boom boom boom wait three weeks
and then do it all over again you know
it's it's simple especially once you get
that soil right like the first time you
use the soil is one thing but year after
year after year as that soil is getting
better and better and better with all
the microbes in there and the nutrition
that's in there you got to be getting
better and better crops each year in the
limits that I have that I put in they
don't get used every year like the
soybean meal I can dig down in there and
I can see soybean meal from
a year ago like it just has it's a
yellow color
so that's still there
you know the worm castings are still
there so it's it's all the you know if I
put triple 10 fertilizer which isn't
organic and I'd never use it but if I
did
that should be gone in a month
or less and then and my soil is fried
from all the from too much nitrogen and
phosphorus and all that so when you say
it actually gets better I'm building my
soil legitimately every single year
because I'm adding more castings more so
cover cropping like it just gets better
and the yields go up and
it makes your plants stronger it fights
off disease and bugs and so it's more
than just yield that you know that
you're counting on you're saving money
by not having to buy more stuff yeah
that makes sense so after you've grown
the plant and harvested them I mean you
talk you talked a little bit about this
in the beginning but how do you go about
selling the produce that you've grown so
I'm different from
probably every other farmer that does
what I do I don't do farmers markets
um I'm glad they're there for Farmers
but I hate them look I want my I have
all my products sold before I harvest it
um I have a list actually that right
there is my customer list
and that's my that's what I go off of if
you look like I have week a and week B
so I have two weeks
um
and week a I delivered this group of
people week B I delivered to this group
of people and they're like why do you
have two weeks
because most people can't eat or don't
want to eat all that produce in one week
and then boom have it again on Sunday
you know there's only so much zucchini
you can eat during the summer
but if they eat it one week and then
they do something else the next week by
Friday or Saturday that next week
they're like oh Mike's bringing me that
his basket tomorrow I call it a basket
you know that basket has salad zucchini
Tomatoes beets
green beans in it you know and so
they're ready for it so it's kind of
like that I was saying keep them wanting
more
and I have a few customers that I sell
to every single week I maybe
I think I got two people up there that I
still do every single week because
they're vegetarians
and I'm happy you know they're happy
they love it and it works out great but
if you ever start people out there if
you ever start
at least consider doing two different
weeks of customers
just so because I always wanted customer
to say I can't wait to get your stuff as
opposed to oh crap you're bringing me
more stuff you know that's you want to
be wanted not like a hassle how did you
find the customers to begin with and
then how do you like do the
communication with them is it through
like an email list or is it all
individual or what it's a
there's not a whole lot of communication
anymore because they know
like they know I'm going to drop it off
at this time like I live in a
subdivision and a little town outside of
Dallas and there's 600 homes in my
subdivision and it's you know a fairly
well-off community and so
they know on Sunday evening I'm bringing
in bringing in their stuff
and I just drive around drop off the
baskets you know in my neighborhood and
then a lot of my customers are teachers
um teachers anyone that's starting
that's thinking about doing this
teachers will be very best customer you
could ever have if you're selling salad
mix because they only get 30 minutes for
lunch
they don't have time to heat anything up
really
more than likely they're trying to lose
a few pounds or at least eat healthier
so salad's the best tell them they have
a fruit salad on Monday
they can have egg white salads on
Tuesday tuna salad on Wednesday chicken
salad on Thursday and a nut salad on
Friday
it's five completely solids you take it
to them on Monday
it's literally the easiest sell in the
world and if you know
teachers are great anywhere that there's
a lot of people hospitals like I
delivered to One hospital because
there's like 10 nurses that buy from me
they're all in the
I went blank Navy Ward pregnancy gonna
have babies
Dawn that that shot that uh
floor
what's that called oh my God what is it
I'll put you on the spot now
but anyway you know what I'm talking
about yeah yeah yeah so and nurses are
always busy you know they're just like
teachers they got 30 minutes if that so
they want something quick healthy fast
tasty and I always Harvest Sunday
morning a harvest Sunday night of the
liver
or Monday morning I deliver so it's
literally 24 hours and old at the most
as opposed to
you buy salad at the grocery store and
everyone's like why is my salad going by
it's only day three it's not day three
it's day 12.
because it is harvested in California
packaged in California SAT on a
warehouse before he got shipped to where
we're you know to Dallas from California
sit in the back of Walmart
day eight or nine it finally got on the
Shelf day nine or ten you bought it day
12 it's earned that's just the way our
supply system works which is completely
stupid whereas if you buy mine
it was 24 hours old
or not in your mind anyone that grows
local
is 24 hours old I've had people put it
in the back of their fridge and their
kids put stuff in front of it and then
they pull it out and it's been two weeks
and they eat it it's as fresh as it was
the day I gave it to them the freshness
is unmatched I uh locally here I have
green life produce and uh yeah getting
it right from right after harvest I'm
getting it probably within 24 hours and
it's delicious better than anything I've
ever bought from a store my teachers
didn't want to put a crack in my salad
to tell them that I'm a crack dealer I
accidentally actually put crack in there
because it's so addicting
so I got to ask for your half acre
Garden that you're growing plants on how
many customers are you supplying during
the summer when stuff grows so much
faster
um
I can do 40 a week pretty easy
you know and that that's 40 you know
baskets
um yeah in a basket like I said is
usually 15 to 20 bucks
and it's
just to give people an idea of the math
I chose five dollars for salad and 250
for everything else
so like tomatoes are 250 which is too
cheap it should be 350. but then I also
charge 250 for Beats which is too much
but it averages out and then it's just
simple and I've never had anyone
complain
about money most people actually
if I tell them this week it's 15 bucks
they usually just give me 20.
you know because I also delivered to
their door
I when I started I said you know what
Amazon just bought Whole Foods
Amazon's going to be delivering stuff
now they got covet hit Walmart started
delivering so I was like I have to
deliver too so I changed my focus around
of marketing and started marketing
really close to my house or my school or
my work so literally everybody that I
sell to
I could be there within they're probably
within a mile of my house or my school
it works really well that way I can
imagine it's super rewarding supplying
the folks around you with the food oh
it's I've had people cry
and not not because it was so good
because like one lady her husband worked
for TruGreen for 25 years and now has
Parkinson's disease and you know
obviously nobody can prove it but she
swears it was because of working for
True Green and she doesn't want to feed
her grandkids that come over
you know stuff from the supermarket
because even if it says organic at the
supermarket
it's not or the organic label's been so
watered down that's why I'm not
certified organic they can kiss my ass
like I I have absolutely no respect for
that organic label anymore because it's
the lobbyist has said you know what this
we can slide this in here I mean
Hydroponics or aquaponics is certified
organic please tell me how that can be
organic when all you use is chemicals to
feed the plant
like it doesn't make sense so
um that's my soapbox like if you want to
piss me off bring up organic labeling
and not I'll get a little far away but
but back to the whole thing was the lady
like Lily cried she's like I've been
looking for this for so long I can't
grow anything and I just want to know
I'm feeding my grandkids something
because I don't want them to end up like
my husband
and literally she's like just got tears
coming down around and that was
super rewarding and I've got people to
be like oh you've got to try my I'm the
salad guy like if somebody meets me that
nose of my salad they're like you're the
salad guy
yeah I'm I'm a salad guy that's me I
guess but yeah it's super rewarding it's
inspiring and you know what we just went
over in this episode how you do it I
think a lot of people are going to enjoy
listening to your story and it in
realize that it's possible you know I
think a lot of people
think about Urban gardening and think
about supplying people locally and they
think that it's gonna cost a bunch of
money to get started they think it's
going to cost it's gonna be a ton of
time doing this and what you just
explained there that's not the case you
get started cheaply now courses
Investments with the tunnel and stuff
over time but that'll pay for itself it
sounds very very possible the way that
you're doing it and I'm really glad that
you decided to come on here and share
your story I do have a few more
questions for you one of them is a
question that you actually wanted me to
ask you which is why do you think Urban
farming is going to be important in the
future I mean covid taught us so much
and now with the war in you know
overseas and
basically everything's just Fallen apart
that's it's some I mean the supply chain
is such a joke and the fact that we have
to go to Whole Foods or sprouts
and I don't know how many people do this
but I look and see where stuff comes
from and why in the hell we buy beets
that are grown in Mexico
um as an example because I just saw a
label the other day it said made in
Mexico on a beat it blows my mind the
amount of everyone's worried about the
climate change why are we spending so
much money on diesel and exhaust
shipping beads from Mexico or even
California to Texas
I mean California is a whole nother
podcast in itself the damn place of the
desert we decided to make California the
capital of AG in the United States and
it's a freaking desert and now we're
paying the price because there's no
water dog pushers are running dry it's
quit raining the Lake Mead is at the
slowest level in history
and we get something like 80 percent of
our lettuce from California
it doesn't make sense
um
so all that to say Urban AG
checks the boxes of so many things the
customers are literally next door
and if you want to get
in into details about other things like
grocery stores dying for local produce
and I don't mean Kroger Tom Thumb and
Albertsons those places are impossible
but like organic food stores are
starting to pop up everywhere they would
love to have an urban farm two miles
down the road and be like yeah try my
salad mix I get it from a bike two miles
down the road it's just a great story
people love buying local
I mean we know our mechanic
we know our doctor
we know the got Footlocker that sells
our shoes by name but we don't know who
put who grows the food that we put in
our body and most of all our kids body
that's just back ass words to me
so I really just want people to
understand
going forward in the next five years and
Warren Buffett said this
and he said lawyers and doctors were the
people that made the money in the past
and they will continue to make the money
but moving forward farmers
will be included into that category in
the future
and I really believe that I mean Warren
Buffett's not wrong about too many
things well you like the guy or not he's
not wrong very often
So and I've seen it I mean I've lived it
for six years now and
the amount of money you can make is
ridiculous once you figure things out
and the best thing about figuring it out
is there's YouTube
there's a guy named Curtis Stone and
I'll make this real quick there's a guy
named Curtis Stone he's known as the
Urban Farmer and he's the one that made
this type of farming popular he's in
Canada he farms and in Canada in his
town they have it's an old town so they
have big yards like third of an acre
yards
quarter acre yards and he farmed nine
people's backyard along with his the
exact same way I'm doing mine
and he made 150 000 a year every year
for like 10 years so he started vlogging
and he vlogged every day for 365 days
like a little 20 minute this is what I'm
doing today
and showed you how to do it and that's
where I learned about salad mix
and you know greens and all that and the
business side of it so literally you
have a free course to learn how to learn
like learn how to grow commercially on
YouTube
now you have Instagram and I will stay
up 48 hours in a row helping people get
started just send me a DM and say how do
I start
and I will reply back questions
I'm going to teach PE I get bored here's
three balls go play and I'll be in here
like I don't I don't mind I I live and
breathe this stuff and I want to help as
many people get started as I can that's
really kind for you to do that you might
regret your decision after this no I I I
I really won't it's almost like paying
it for it because I would not be where I
am and have the happiness that I have if
it would have been for Curtis start his
YouTube videos and there's you know jm48
you can look him up too if you're
interested in them there's just a ton of
people out there that's doing what I'm
doing now on YouTube I just don't have
the time
or as you figure it out trying to set
this up the technology ability to figure
it out yeah it's not easy but uh you
know what you're doing is is really
great so so thank you for that one last
thing would be is there any other advice
that you want to give folks looking to
do the same thing as you just start and
don't worry about killing everything
like I killed so much stuff I look back
and I'm like God I was an idiot but I
learned I mean experience is the
greatest teacher
but again luckily for you you don't have
to just learn from experience only like
you can DM me you can watch the Youtube
videos you can do all these other things
to learn how to start
and
there's so much money to be made if
you're 50 right now and hate your job
and you're going to retire in two years
but you need a little extra income this
is the absolute perfect job for you and
you gotta love growing stuff and get
your hands dirty you know
but there's nothing better than waking
up and you know going to your farm at
seven o'clock in the morning and
literally hearing the birds chirping
watch the sun come up half my post on
Instagram Rose is the sun coming up over
the horizon and I don't know why he
posted it because it's literally the
same pictures but is there something
about it that's just it just brings you
back to
to the world that we live in as opposed
to cubicle and traffic and all that
other crap so let's wrap things up how
can the listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future
um Instagram's probably the best it's
Dallas half acre Farm
um
that's the easy way to shoot me a DM
comment you know hey I dm'd you because
sometimes if we don't follow each other
it goes to a separate account in my
inbox and it's kind of a pain to find
sometimes so just let me know
um you can email me
embell971 Yahoo if you don't do
Instagram I give you my phone number but
my wife would get pretty pissed about
that one but after we email I'll
definitely give you my phone number
and um so those are the three I don't do
YouTube yet I want to I just don't
have the capability brain wise it's too
full of plant to add in technology
to but uh hopefully one day I'll be able
to but those are the three easiest ways
to or two easy ways to contact me and
and don't hesitate to do it okay you
said do this so I'm doing it I won't
ever get mad okay well I'll definitely
have a link to your Instagram down in
the YouTube description section below
and if you're listening to know one of
the podcast platforms just search for
them you'll find them if you enjoyed
this episode click that Thumbs Up Button
also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already every single weekend I'm
releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode and I'd love for you to tune
into future episodes like once again
thanks for coming on this has been
awesome definitely a very uh inspiring
story some really good takeaways here we
learned how you do your process how you
sell your produce and and make a living
from it really and you've really set
people up for success in the future that
they can take what you're doing and
emulate it and Supply their local
community so that's a big deal I think
it's a strong message and once again
thanks for coming on hey thanks give me
the platform man I appreciate your time
take care everyone catch you next
episode Peace