coming up on garden talk when you use
phosphorus that is impure you already
see that what you put in into your
fertilizers is not 100 available to your
plants over application of phosphorus is
definitely a problem both indoors as
well as with big agriculture it's crazy
to hear how many myths there are and
also like how many myths are spread by
some really big companies in the
industry potassium is crucial in both
veg as well as flour and it is actually
the only element that is not part of an
organelle in most of the binding when it
comes to fertilizers it is being done
through a mixture of pressure heat and a
catalyzer all has to do with filtration
processes how clean is the raw material
that you use
as nutrients manufacturers and brains we
should be open and transparent about
what's inside the products
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 44. in this
episode i interview rico from dutch pro
nutrients he talks all about how
nutrients are sourced and some forms of
nutrients that should be avoided we
aren't able to get into all of the
nutrients used by plants but we do get
into a small chunk of them i'm sure that
we'll have a part two of this in the
future thanks to all of you who support
this podcast or patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com mr grellit before we get
into it i want to acknowledge that one
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
zero costs for information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said i'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible a big
supporter of this podcast is ac infiniti
they sponsor this podcast and i use
their products ac infinity now has
gardening tools and accessories such as
heavy duty fabric grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr growit during
checkout for a discount on their
products big shout out to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is a
plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products spider farmer
is a sponsor of the podcast coupon code
mr growit5 will get you a discount on
their products they're most known for
their led grow lights but they also have
other products such as grow tents inline
fans and carbon filters i've used their
sf 1000 sf 2000 and sf 4000 led grill
lights in the past and i got some great
results with them i will leave a link to
spider farmers amazon store down in the
description section below and don't
forget to use coupon code mr grow at
five for discount on their products
okay we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with rico
from dutch pro nutrients how you doing
today
good man actually i'm excited for the
show
and obviously christmas is coming up
soon so uh we already put up the
christmas trees here in the office i'm
ready what about you chris nice nice
ready super excited for this episode
today we're going to get into how
nutrients are sourced
so really the goal is for listeners to
be able to look at the back of their
bottle and recognize some of the
different nutrients that are shown there
it can be confusing for some be aware
that some of the forums are actually
we should avoid because that they are
actually harmful to the environment so
we're going to go over that today
dutch pro you've been a sponsor of this
podcast i just want to thank you for
doing that you know being able to
provide this information to the general
public that they can access for free
you've sponsored that so thank you yeah
and thank you chris
um
you know i mean we both you know share
try to share as much knowledge as we can
and it's a lot of hard work
and you know you give the platform to
people actually to go to and it's crazy
how many people hit me up and be like oh
i've seen you you know at guard and talk
we've missed to grow it or whenever my
trade shows they mention your name and
we even had the situation a couple
months ago where someone came up to me
be like oh can you let chris know to do
an episode about this and this i don't
know if you remember
um and then i called job right and that
i mean he's a fan honestly and he was so
happy chris so thank you as well for
actually offering that platform to uh a
lot of growers it's pretty pretty cool
and i listen to it as well you know i'm
a fan of your show as well
that is really cool that's awesome
well first thing we do on this podcast
is introduction so can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and kind of
how you got into gardening
yeah definitely so in this case we go
back to the 80s i wasn't around then i'm
going to be honest but uh my dad he
started the dutch pro nutrient company
and he was a grower himself in amsterdam
and him and his business partner
actually um started to look into
nutrients to better you know like how to
grow
uh how to make sure your plants grow
bigger um you know have better yields
etc so that basically started late 70s
early 80s and then at 85
they really got heavily into it and then
early 90s that's when they came up with
the desperate nutrient line
and then from that moment on you know
they just grew out the company
so in this case when i come into play is
literally the moment i was born
the moment i was born i grew up you know
in between plants um my dad you know
telling me about it but i must say he
never really
pushed me in any way to do something
with it
but
as i just grew older and i saw more and
more and i read up about it myself more
and more i just thought it was so cool
and i think plants are so um undervalued
by a lot of people in this world
and so i really decided you know to
stick with it and
because i was so excited about it and i
just yeah things went automatic and
normal and
a pretty good sized company here in
europe i shall say we have our own
factory and stuff and then i branched it
out to the us
so that's where i come into play really
is the u.s side of things
um yeah that's been a cool cool journey
to be honest that's awesome that's a
really cool story so let's hop into the
actual elements some of these elements
some of these nutrients that are for
plant growth we're not going to be able
to get through all of them today you
know there are 17 essential nutrients
for the plants i think there's a few
here that we're going to go over that
aren't actually an essential element but
are useful for plants as well so we'll
get through as many as we can today and
then maybe in the future
if the audience demands it we will get
into a part two we can go over more of
it let's start with nitrogen so talk to
us about nitrogen you know how is it
beneficial for the plant maybe just do a
quick run through of that
maybe get into the nitrogen cycle and
kind of how it's sourced
yeah no definitely and nitrogen i think
is the most
well-known element as well so it's
pretty cool that we can actually start
off with that one
but yeah basically what nitrogen does is
it's like one of the building blocks to
create amino acids
and amino acids in turn is one of the
building blocks to create enzymes or
proteins you know enzymes proteins is
the same thing
and enzymes are pretty cool because you
need them for nutrient transportation
they you know like speed up the
processes inside the plant and honestly
without enzymes a plant just can't
function but again it all starts with
the building block which is nitrogen
and then furthermore nitrogen is one of
the
molecules that is needed to create a
chlorophyll molecule
and chlorophyll is needed to create the
green pigment which actually is able to
attract and use light energy for
photosynthesis
so nitrogen i think is a really cool
element it's like i said one of the more
well-known elements
and what is also cool to know about
nitrogen inside the plant it's a mobile
element so for those of you guys that
want to know like hey
where do i find the nitrogen deficiency
look at the older leaves the one at the
bottom because nitrogen is mobile so it
goes wherever it's needed the most which
is in this case the younger leaves
but the problem with nitrogen is it is a
very difficult element to attract
from nature
i should say and
for most of the time actually till like
early 1900s
all nitrogen that was used by plants and
to grow crops and everything literally
came through the um
nitrification
from bacteria and fungi inside the soil
and one of the discussions that i
sometimes have with people you know and
especially people that um want to go
back to back to you know to the old days
where they want to use bacteria fungi to
actually give like organic nutrients to
the plant which by the way guys i'm not
against organic nutrients not at all but
like i said one of the discussions i
have is with
with the amount of people we have right
now we're currently at 7.8 billion
people is it still doable actually to
feed the whole world if we actually use
the methods from back in the old days
and i literally give them examples chris
and i don't know if you know that but go
back three four hundred years in time
it was not
actually crazy to think of that
sometimes ten to fifteen percent of a
population in europe would literally die
off because there wasn't enough food
around you know because of a miss
harvest or because climate
uh you know wasn't playing its part so
yield wise there wasn't just literally
enough
food actually to feed all the people so
that is one of the things that whenever
i talk you know with people about
synthetic nutrients i always think about
you know tell them like think about can
we feed the whole world and we were 7.8
billion that is 5.8 billion more is back
in the 1900s um
yeah can we actually produce enough in
an organic way now coming back to what
you said the nitrogen cycle
caused like a nitrogenous difficult
element to fix it right
so normally the nitrogen cycle goes you
have plants that die off decay you could
plot of animals that
you know
in this case actually do the big thing
if you know what i mean and um the brown
part
i don't know if you want to say
yeah and and then the bacteria and fungi
i mean they start to work right so the
nitrogen actually in all the plant
animal matter that's being left behind
they actually first turn it into ammonia
and then from ammonia actually being
turned into ammonium and ammonium is
already one of the forms that plants can
use
and from that moment on it goes from
ammonium
to nitrates and then to nitrate which is
again another
second form of nitrate nitrogen that can
be used by plants
now in this case
like i said
the germans actually figured out a way
to speed up the process and to actually
fixate nitrogen so we could mass produce
ammonium and nitrate which again are two
directly available forms
and this goes through the harbor
bosch process
and i'm sure a lot of people actually
already heard of it somehow
but the process process basically goes
as follows
so first of all
what you see in the air like literally
like 80 of it is nitrogen nitrogen um
yeah like i said nitrogen with an n and
then two
and then a part of it is oxygen but most
of it is nitrogen so basically what's
being done is air is being withdrawn
and then methane is basically being put
into this chamber
heated and we literally talk about crazy
heat guys we talk about 750-930
what is being brought together a crazy
amount of pressure again we talk about
like a hundred bar which is crazy
and then basically what is being done
is it goes through like four processes
four different types of
process where methane
the air heat pressure
and in this case also
[Music]
when i say air actually being put
together and a catalyzer and in this
case they often use a catalyzer which is
iron actually is able to bind the
molecules together so it is able to do
bind the nitrogen
with the hydrogen molecules
because if you talk about ammonium which
is the first
directly available form
the molecular structure guys is nh4
which is one nitrogen
for hydrogen
now if you talk about nitrate which is
the second available form
it's one nitrogen
it's
an oxygen and then it's an it's a
negative ion so it's negative three
basically but it all starts first with
ammonium
and why isn't important that we first
start off with ammonium because there's
a second process involved to create
nitric acid
now
chris whenever you look at like a bottle
right of liquid nutrients you turn it
around and you look at like the sources
because
companies young
fertilizers we do need to state our
sources
you often see when it comes to nitrogen
like a calcium nitrate
magnesium nitrate but also nitric acid
right
and um
you you agreed to that right chris those
are like um
recognizable terms what i said right the
calcium those are common
very average yeah pretty common
nitric acid what did you say urea is
another one
urea is another one which is in this
case like a cheap form of nitrogen it's
literally one of the cheapest forms you
can get out there
it's also the one that is not the best
available to plant to be honest because
it's such an
organic product and
it's easy to over apply i should say
and if we can skip it a little bit
that's also because you were talking in
the beginning about bad forms right of
raw materials
and
often what is the case if you look like
big egg
is the quality of fertilizer that they
use
now you have to think you know like
those big agricultural farms that grow
crop or soil or whatever
i mean they don't really get the most
out of their pricing if you know what i
mean so they're easily turned towards
input materials that are kind that are
low quality obviously the price needs to
be low so it's often low quality
materials as well that they use
and unfortunately because
they don't really have such a good
profit structure it's difficult for them
to implement technology
to really analyze what their plants need
so it's easy for them to over apply
fertilizers
and a big problem what you see in the
gulf of mexico and i don't know if you
heard about it chris is eutrophication
and it's basically the over
up application of fertilizers
and
when you get over application and it
washes out of the fields into the rivers
and eventually into the oceans
why is that such a big problem well
basically and it's funny enough the
problem is is that
algae
they grow so phenomenally well when more
nitrogen actually you know ends up in in
this case the gulf of mexico
so it is not literally that it
kills because it's there's too much
nitrogen and algae in the plants they
just don't know what to do with it it's
literally that the algae just grow way
too fast
and what we have here at least i mean
i'm currently in the netherlands guys
what we have here is those little side
canals right
and it's very easy to just literally
only see green on the water from the
algaes
and basically what happens is that the
algaes block sunlight it blocks the
sunlight for the plants
below the water
and those plants those water plants are
crucial for for creating oxygen inside
the water which in this case all animals
need even underwater
so when algae actually blocks
getting sunlight directly to the plants
underneath
eventually you literally turn off the
oxygen
input into the water so that's when all
the animals all the fish everything dies
because there isn't enough oxygen in the
water so eutrophication
in this case literally means you have
too many algae growing from the over
application of fertilizers by big egg
and therefore
not enough oxygen is being left in the
water anymore or produced and then all
the
plants as well as animals under the
algae dies off
so personally i love technology i think
also indoor screens if you because i see
a lot of grow facilities right in the
grow facilities and the technology that
some of those facilities put in i think
is amazing to see
and also reduces actually the over
application of nutrients
now going back actually to the sourcing
of how in this case nitrogen is fixated
the ammonium that we first talked
is actually used in the osmo process to
create nitric acid
and nitric acid guys you often see it
with a ph
down
you often see that
companies use a form of nitric acid
to lower the ph in someone's nutrient
reservoir and basically with the oswald
process it's kind of similar to the
hubba bush
they don't use methane or anything like
that but what they do use
is the ammonium let it go to multiple
processes of
heat which is eventually the start with
a high heat and a lower down they add
water in there as well along the process
and by doing that they create an
environment under pressure that the
water and the ammonium
actually bind together and that
eventually at the end of the line
creates nitric acid
now important for you guys to know is
the filtration processes i mean there
are multiple plants
and what i mean with plants like
factories all over the world that
produce in this case
nitrogen
with the harbor bosch process
but
basically all the elements that we use
no matter if it comes from like rock air
animal plant matter you know what people
call organic it's still all organic i
mean
there is no 100 pure form of anything on
this planet so even with these
chemical sourcing as people would call
it there are still filtration processes
that needs to be involved to create
priorities
and as we move along chris towards
phosphorus for example
phosphorus is an element guys that is
very easily
able to bind with heavy metals heavy
metal like an iron heavy metal like an
aluminum something like that
and
when you use phosphorus that is impure
for example you already see that what
you put in into your fertilizers is not
100 available to your plants
and one of the things that we need to do
chris as a fertilizer brand if we want
to be registered in the u.s
is we need to test all our products for
heavy metals
and if the heavy metals for example
testing
turns positive or in this case it's a
negative thing of course because you hit
a certain amount of heavy metals your
fertilizers are not allowed to be sold
on the market because it is a danger to
both plant as well as you for human
consumption
and in the case of phosphorus you also
reduce actually
the quality of the material because it
is not available to the plant again
and
so like i said let's just move on to
phosphorus to be honest chris because i
think we have said everything about
nitrogen yeah so transitioning over to
phosphorus that's another thing really
that contributes to these toxic algae
blooms you mentioned that with nitrogen
same thing with phosphorus same exact
thing over fertilization runoffs into
these lakes ponds toxic algae blooms so
that's a big reason why a lot of people
don't use some of these
and you know it's kind of frowned upon
to use some of these in outdoor
environments particularly for runoff
into the lakes and streams and so on and
so forth but yeah let's get into
phosphorus a little bit deeper so how is
it beneficial to the plant how's it
sourced you know what form does dutch
pro use why yeah so on and so forth
it's good i think phosphorus is a really
interesting one
uh because of the history as well you
know like it's funny but like
if you look like sourcing it also
evolved over time you know often how
people did it back in the days and we
come especially potassium i think is a
very cool one
um
but yeah let's start off with phosphorus
first i hope you can see i'm very
excited about it you know so sometimes
i'm like okay
you know straighten up rico just one by
one
but yeah phosphorus so basically
phosphorus is a crucial element
in especially energy production
and
uh
a quick you know quick notes about what
happens
you got adp which stands for adenosine
diphosphate or d-phosphates
and adp needs to be transformed
to atp it's adenosine triphosphate
and with the adp you got two phosphates
involved and with the energy molecule
atp you got three molecules involved
so you need to apply phosphorus to your
plants in order to actually create these
energy molecules
and funny enough
all living
um
animals and plants they use the same
source of energy atp i think it's
amazing
um
you know like how efficient sometimes
literally you know the world can be i
mean it's so efficient guys that
literally we all use it you know we all
use the same form of energy which is
called atp
and what is happening
with atp is the bond eventually is being
broken up again
and when that happens that's when the
energy is released
to fulfill all the processes that
happens in both a human
as well as animals as well as implants
now
furthermore um phosphorus is also an
activator of enzymes and roots love it
as well roots grow really really well
under phosphorus
i mean multiple things like calcium as
well roots love calcium as well guys we
come to it later
one of the things that i just think is
funny chris when you look at fertilizers
is the over application of phosphorus
you know
people talk about the pk 1314 or they
talk about like a 5234 you know what i
mean
and it's like more phosphorus for like
flower development and by development
and
yes it is important don't get me wrong
100 this
but if you look at nature and if you
look at the resources
and i show people that they're like wow
i didn't think you know that that was
the case
and what i showed them is actually
plants don't need that much phosphorus
as people really think that they need
it's crazy you know a lot of people they
talk about nitrogen that you shouldn't
use any flour well first of all guys
i would say try it try using you know
a product that has no nitrogen during
flour and you will see yourself what
happens i understand why people want to
cut it down that's 100 sure but i hear
some people talk about don't use any
nitrogen at all i'm like okay i guess no
amino acid production i guess
chlorophyll production is going to be
down as well you know
good luck with that but yeah phosphorus
is all is often an over applied element
and like i said it's easy to bind with
heavy metals in the substrate
so most of what they apply chris
literally just resides in the soil in
the substrate itself
and there are a couple ways that you can
use to increase efficiency nutrient
uptake
um like umicrophobic acids microbes
um but still over application of
phosphorus is definitely a problem in
the world both indoors as well as with
big agriculture
interesting if we go back to history
actually is that it was already
discovered in
the 1600s
and again i don't know why it has always
been by german it's crazy how often
we're going to see the germans involved
in agriculture
it's crazy but uh it was actually
already discovered chris in 1669
actually and funny enough you just
mentioned urea it has to deal with urine
so literally what happened is when you
actually distilled urine
a white salt was being left behind and
that was the first phosphorus to be
honest it was very flammable gloat in
the dark so whenever you see something
glow in the dark right like a bowling
alley or whatever they also use some
form of phosphorus in there
and funny thing enough i don't know do
you know where the name comes from chris
no it actually means like
miraculous bear bearer of light huh
interesting i didn't know that another
question for you
and obviously i did my research before
guys know that i know everything right
before but
so it's uh it's not a diamond
know-it-all or anything like that guys
but uh
funny enough do you know how many
gallons actually of urine it took to
create like 60 grams of phosphorus no
how many gallons 290 gallons to produce
60 grams of phosphorus
that's crazy that's a lot
of e-collection out there
so i mean obviously that wasn't a
source that we could use to use in any
type of
application actually
and funny enough
after that the
largest source up until
end of the 19th century was actually the
the bones and also guano you know bones
of animals
um yeah
and because there's a lot of like
phosphate found inside bones and also
with guano you know there's a good
amount of phosphates found as well
um yeah so funny enough the whole world
turned actually towards um the bones
because calcium phosphates were found in
there and then um
actually like i said you also know in
guano itself but then at one point
because more and more
synthetic fertilizers were actually used
and demanded for especially towards the
end of the 19th century that they needed
to find a different source because
literally at one point everything was
already basically used and it just
couldn't keep up with the demand
and
one of the reasons why synthetic
fertilizers were so popular at the end
of the 19th century had to do with
justice from liebeck
and i think you talked about it chris
before in a different episode
with one of your um
you know other people actually but for
those of you that didn't see that
specific episode so justice von leybig
is basically a german scientist again
always in german
that discovered those 17 elements that
the plant need to grow and develop
themselves so the mpks the calcium the
sulfur the magnesium et cetera
and
interestingly interestingly that
happened around 1850 1860
so after that that's really because you
finally discovered hey this is what we
need to do to actually grow
really good crops and in a consistent
way that's when the whole synthetic
industry basically came to life and then
what happened because like i said at one
point
the demand actually over uh exceeded the
supply and that's when i turned to
phosphate rocks
and i don't know if you you heard about
that chris oh very common yeah rock
phosphate is used very commonly it's
it's a number one source there isn't
uh well i shouldn't say there isn't i
know there are some really big companies
working on a different source of
phosphorus it's still an experimental
phase
and the reason why is because they
literally think that with the demand
that we currently have that the world is
going to run out of the phosphorus in
like 40 to 50 years
which is going to be a problem
especially if at that time we're
probably going to be with 9 to 10
billion people
you know we all need to be fat we are
all hungry multiple times a day and
phosphorus is honestly crucial in that
supply
but yeah rock phosphates indeed
is where
the majority of the phosphorus comes
from and basically what happens with
those rock phosphates i don't know if
you know what an electric arc is chris
no i don't so it's basically like a
like i see this like a big furnace and
it's also like how to make steel and
steel is also being made by extreme heat
and an electric arc you can see it is
like you got like three of these
pins so you got like three of these pins
right
and they all actually um like
electricity electricity goes through it
and they basically connect with each
other through electricity
and because by doing so
an extreme heat is basically produced
and when phosphate rocks actually are
being put in there and they're actually
mixed with in this case a product it's
called coke c-o-k-e it's not the coke
that comes from colombia in this case
guys but it's a natural product
it actually mixes with each other and
then element of phosphorus is actually
created an element of phosphorus is like
a pure form of phosphorus that can be
actually further amended
and in this case what they do actually
is
they distill it and then actually they
burn it with air to produce phosphorus
pentoxide
and then the phosphorus pentoxide in
this case is being dissolved in water
and that creates phosphoric acid
and phosphoric acid is another um
frequently used form in fertilizers it
is also used we actually we use
phosphoric acid in our ph minus bloom
version because we got two different
bloom versions you know all about it
because you've got the bottles of
honeycrisp
oh yeah yeah phosphoric acid very
commonly used in ph down products and
often says that it kills off microbes
which uh is a myth you know people think
that they're adjusting the ph
you know using ph up or ph down and
that's wiping out the whole mythical
population which is is false it's one of
the common myths that you hear true
and it's it's crazy to hear how many
myths there are and also like how many
myths are spread by some really big
companies in the industry and often what
kills like the microbes is literally the
ph
you know when it's too low basically
everything below ph4 guys
then is when most bacteria can grow they
can't grow in that environment but when
you use phosphoric acid on its own you
mix it with water and everything the ph
will never get below ph4 so just like
you said it doesn't kill
anything at all
that's also one of the reasons why
fertilizers liquid fertilizers often
have a pretty low ph on its own
it also has to do actually with the
longevity of the product you know to
keep it in good condition because one of
the last things that we want when you
sell your fertilizers is the bacteria
can grow inside a bottle
um and literally the bottle with
nutrients creates you know is like a
bottle of like a positive portion polish
now poison that you know plants want to
use to grow big and heavy and you know
what i mean
so um
yeah if you just look at places for
example like channel build life wants to
grow every single where so what like i
said one of the things we have to do as
far as liquid fertilizers
uh you know like manufacturers we need
to keep the ph low to keep the microps
out initially
um
yeah that's like a little bit of a side
note what we use
because that is also like one of the
questions i think you want to know chris
like what does detroit use
we use a mixture actually so we use like
indeed phosphoric acid
we also use something called
monopotassium of our mono potassium
phosphorus
as well
yeah it honestly has to do with like
creating the right mixtures the right
ratios
for some of the products we personally
only use the minimum of a food grade
product we always first look at like the
heavy metal analysis of
you know the supplies that we get in
because we only want to ensure that what
we sell to you guys it's also like the
highest quality that we can offer and
still offer the best price quality ratio
because that is also important obviously
so that's personally what we use gotcha
lots of information about these elements
more than i expected
sorry man like i said i
yeah i'm just excited about it it's okay
it's great great information for sure
let's move on though let's go into
potassium so similar to the other
elements you know how is it beneficial
to the plant how is it sourced and then
kind of what form does dutch pro use and
are there any forms that we should avoid
yeah no definitely that's a
couple good questions though
one thing one side note why i'm so
excited about it chris i was in la a
couple weeks ago and i was actually with
a friend of mine who grows and he we got
in the store and obviously there's so
many brands to choose from he's like
rico he's like to be honest he's like i
don't understand nutrients he's like i
look at the bottle i look at the back i
see all those you know sources he's like
i don't understand what does it do what
does it mean how is it actually being
sourced and then i have to think about
this podcast obviously and i was like
okay i really wanna you know make sure
that
i tell like the full picture full story
that definitely double triggered me
but yeah potassium so potassium is
crucial in both veg as well as flour and
it is actually the only element that is
not part of an organelle
and basically what it does is it is
crucial for nutrients transportation
and it is also crucial for um
the regulation of co2 through the
stomata through the leaves
and there's something called like a
potassium pump
and i'm not gonna go too deep into it
right now because it's about sourcing
but basically what you have to realize
and understand about potassium is it
literally regulates the inflow and
outflow of elements from cell a to b
or at least plays a crucial part of it
potassium also activates enzymes
and like i said enzymes are used also
for nutrient transportation but also to
speed up a variety of processes inside a
plant
uh yeah and like some potassium is just
crucial both during veg as well as flour
the name i think is very interesting
potassium which is obviously a lighter
name but it's also frequently called
potash so basically with potash how it
really started is just
by burning wood you know and and the ash
literally that was being left behind
um places in a pot and potassium is very
water soluble i think it's one of the
most water soluble elements actually in
this world
and
basically by mixing it with water and
then filtering it
you get like the potassium was being
left behind
and initially actually it wasn't even
used as a fertilizer funny enough
it was eventually used as a fertilizer
because they had so much of it and they
had no clue what to do with it and it
was like you know what let's just
use it as a fertilizer and see what
happens as an experiment
but up in that point it was actually
used for soap production
mainly yeah potassium was actually used
as like a soap so basically what they
would do to make um soap back in the
days was use like fat from like a pig or
whatever
and then actually mix it with water and
then potassium and if you mix it up
that's literally how they created the
the first soaps
and funny enough
um
a lot of the trees and forests that were
cut down in europe back in the days
was actually to create potassium
and something very cool i think is the
first u.s patent
like
in history
was actually because of potassium as
well it was actually an improvement of
how to filter potassium to offer a more
cleaner source of potassium first patent
ever in the us history was about
potassium
and then we go actually back to the 18th
century and it was signed by george
washington himself so i thought it was
pretty cool as well
uh but yeah a lot of like trees were cut
down actually because of it and it was
literally like one of the uh
biggest sources up until like the 19th
century
and the 19th century actually like i
said so many trees were cut down like
the forests were cut down in europe then
forests were cut down in the u.s
as well
because of potassium production
and then
what happened then is they found
protection really deep
into the ground and it was literally an
average they would find it like over 4
000 feet deep which is obviously crazy
deep and it also brought a lot of risks
with them to actually mine
the potassium so accidents would happen
it wasn't uncommon you know that like
gas and oil was actually sitting pretty
close at that
depth as well so some accidents happen
with that
but eventually what i did and i thought
it's so simple chris and it is so smart
and still works so well that it's still
being used up till today
they use the water solubility in the
their advantage
so if you guys google there's an amazing
video out there on youtube it's about
potassium mining in utah
like two hours southeast from salt lake
city
and literally what they do
is they drill a hole to the source of
potassium
they
pour water in there
they literally you know give potassium
time to dissolve in water they just pump
it out at the other side through a
different hole
then they literally create these lakes
which they treat with
a mixture of copper sulfate to actually
keep the bacteria and fungi away
and they literally just wait they let it
evape
they literally let the water evape out
of those lakes and what is being left
behind is just a thick layer of
potassium and that is literally how most
of the potassium nowadays is still
sourced
it's an efficient way
um
and yeah it's so easy actually wow
that's super fascinating yeah
honestly chris uh it's a very um
interesting video as well to watch for
all for everyone in your audience
because you see those lakes and those
lakes actually they change the color of
the water changes color because of the
copper sulfates and because of the uh
different evaporation stages that they
are in and then
the potassium you know after the
potassium is sourced
it is easy to bind and most of the
binding when it comes to fertilizers
it is being done through a mixture of
pressure
heat
and a catalyzer you know like an iron
iron for example or another metal
that is literally the the basic would
you which you need to understand of how
elements are attached to each other like
a potassium sulfate
or you know like when you look at the
back of a bottle you see potassium
sulfate or you see
mono-potassium phosphate for example
or g calcium nitrates and like i said
those elements i mean they need to be
binded together through some form of
process
and that often goes through heat
pressure and catalyzation as well
now we use a mixture so we use for
example potassium sulfate we use mono
potassium phosphates
yeah we use a couple of varieties of
potassium
as well is there any forms that we
should avoid good one good one um
are a couple forms that you should avoid
well
yes and no i would say and it all has to
do again with the filtration part
there's something that you can't see
from a label unfortunately
and it's also a little bit the strong
point obviously of the brands you know
like the raw materials that they use the
quality of the raw materials but it all
has to do with filtration processes you
know how clean is the raw material that
you use
and what you guys can totally do
and you can definitely do with us you
can literally ask for the heavy metal
analysis if you guys want if you want to
see how clean our nutrients are go over
it you know send me a text
go to that's for you say instagram or us
you know go to our website contact us
um actually we also already have it out
on the website as well so you guys can
just look it up
you know i think we should as nutrients
manufacturers and brains we should be
open and transparent the words the
people about what's inside the products
you know what i mean absolutely i
completely agree with you on that one
for sure
let's move on to sulfur sulfur is one of
the ones where
i feel like not many people talk about
it but it's super important i mean it's
right up there with the importance of
npk a lot of people can
would uh would say so talk to us about
sulfur
how is it beneficial for the plant how
is it sourced what form does dutch pro
use so on and so forth
yeah exactly well sulfur is actually a
funny funny one in a variety of ways
well first of all it's an important
actually element because it's one of the
building blocks for two crucial amino
acids which is meteor 9 and sea stein
and they are both crucial actually for
the transportation
of electrons which are then actually
used to create the energy molecules
and basically without sulfur honestly
you would know that straight away with
deficiencies when your leaves turn
basically white yellow white but you
would definitely see that your growth is
stagnated in your overall
flower development as well
now funny enough
and i never realized it actually up
until i did like some deeper research
but do you remember like those videos
you basically saw them like back in the
days where you saw people like wearing
like
cotton cloths and you saw like these all
these gases around them
and it gets like yellow it's like
basically like a yellow mine there were
but there was on the outside these are
all gases
like the old silver sulfur mines
actually and it's super poisonous super
poisonous
and you still sometimes actually see it
you know in like very poor countries
because sulfur definitely brings in some
money but it's so poisonous so if you
look up like you know solver mines uh
poor countries or underdeveloped
countries you know give it a term you
would definitely find them and there was
also like
had back in the days would source it
but it was not a sustainable way it was
not actually a way that would work
long-term lives because of the health of
people
so basically how they then did it
was they used a different process it's
called the fresh
process actually
which is what they would do again they
would use the solvability of the
solubility of sulfur itself
so they would find solver mines they
would actually put hot water in there
hot enough so the sulfur would actually
melt and mix in the water
and then once brought to the surface
actually they would literally have like
a 99.5 percent efficiency ratio so 99.5
of the sulfur deep in the mines they
would get out
unfortunately this process was very
costly to do so so they turned away to a
different source and that source is
still used up till today
and honestly funny enough
sulfur right now
it is a
byproduct from the petroleum industry
yeah literally it's a by-product from
the uh petroleum industry and it had a
couple advantages
you know first of all less risk was
involved as far as like health concerns
but it was also cheaper
and basically what happens is
the byproduct it's called hydrogen
sulfide
and hydrogen sulfide actually goes
through a process called claus the
clause process
and this process actually is already
like pretty old we go back to like late
1800s
and basically what what happened and
it's just similar to the different
processes it would go through like
distillation
so we go through multiple distillation
processes where heat again was involved
temperatures of like said heat was
involved pressure was involved
catalyzation was involved
but when nitrogen needs like a
temperature like 800 fahrenheit we talk
about 1900 fahrenheit in this case wow
pretty pretty warm so uh
during wintertime guys whenever you're
cold just stay close to a
sulfur
[Laughter]
and and what i actually would get when
they were treated with this this heat is
they would get elemental sulfur
and again elemental sulfur is a pure
form that they could build on to
eventually create sulfuric acid because
that's by the way what we gonna end up
we're gonna end up with sulfuric acid
so with the elemental
sulfur
in this case
it would go through a different process
called the contact process
and basically whatever we do
is the sulfur is burned
to sulfur dioxide
and then sulfur dioxide
is again being turned into sulfur
trioxide
and again heat is involved pressure is
involved catalyzation is involved
and then the silver trioxide eventually
is being
mixed with water or added with water to
create sulphuric acid
and this sulfuric acid actually
is already a source of solver obviously
on its own but you often fight solver as
a combination of
so for example you have copper sulfates
you got
like a potassium sulfate you know epsom
salts is actually magnesium sulfate
you know so sulfates is often a
product that is
combined and mixed already with another
product
so the sulfuric acid is crucial
in
different processes to bind with for
example magnesium to bind with for
example potassium
yeah that is literally
in this case all there is to sacrifice
about sulfur
we use in this case not sulfuric acid on
its own on its own but we use
combination products like i said
potassium sulfate um
like i said like a copper sulfate for
example
anything
um
in a combination with
the epsom salts and everything as well
and it all comes down to how clean is
these nutrients and there's such a big
variety there are so many
if you think that the choice for picking
your nutrients in the store is already
big
just wait till you go to the back hand
of things
the amount of
you know raw materials that you can
choose from is crazy it's so diverse
and yeah it's difficult to to explain
and to show people because it's
obviously also you know like we don't
want to make our competition
smarter already than they are it's also
our secret recipe of course but uh
yeah you have to look at like how clean
is it how well is it filtered and also
like
what is important to us at least is like
the processes that were involved because
definitely what you see is um
a lot of like
sources actually you know are come from
low cost
places as well and that's something that
we don't deal with you know we don't
want to deal with low-cost countries
because they're often also like
safe on quality measures they also often
save on healthy measures you know or
even like kids involved or anything like
that and that's something that you we
don't want to be associated with so we
only actually do business with companies
um
that we actually align with as well if
that makes sense yeah that definitely
makes sense so we definitely covered not
really much when the grand scheme of
things we covered nitrogen phosphorus
potassium we did sulfur i wanted to get
more done but there's just there's so
much we're definitely gonna have to do a
part two that is for sure one thing i
did want to comment on is that i really
like and it's real
apparent that
you guys are focused on the science
behind things now i learned quite a bit
in this episode but there are some
things i'm currently attending utah
state university there's a horticultural
certification i'm going through right
now by dr bruce bugbee he's well known
in the the community here and one of the
things that you're saying in this
episode he's saying so i know that
you're going by the science when it
comes to these elements
you know sourcing avoiding some of the
things that you should avoid because
it's bad for the environment and so on
and so forth like i said we definitely
have to do a part two that is for sure
you know next episode i think silicon
calcium magnesium boron copper iron we
can go on and on and even chlorine is
something that's worth talking about but
let's do a part two here with the next
couple months i think this is one that
people are going to want to hear about
wrapping things up on this episode you
know how can the listeners find you and
what do you have upcoming in the future
yeah so there are a couple of ways
actually to find us i mean you can go to
our website that'sprousa.com
a lot of information videos out there
they can go to our instagram i'm
personally pretty active out there just
that's for usa
um unfortunately we go in and out of a
shadow band you know at the moment so we
probably have to put in desperate usa
completely in order to find us at the
moment uh we are starting our own
youtube channel pretty soon as well
actually uh we have a pretty cool idea
as far as podcast so hopefully we can
actually do it the other way around too
chris and have you in our show
um you know i think it could be pretty
cool yeah as far as like for the future
a lot of cool things we have some really
interesting uh things as far as product
development
we are gonna focus heavily on um
spreading and sharing knowledge you know
with you guys as much as we can because
we literally want to help out as many
growers as we can become better growers
and i learn every single day
from amazing people and i would love to
help other people as well and i know the
whole team is motivated to help other
people as well i'll definitely have your
channel and instagram and website all
linked down in the description section
below on youtube i know there's a lot
lot to discuss maybe for next time it's
going to be like a harry potter series
one two three four five
i'll definitely have your links down in
the description section below coupon
code as well if anyone's interested in
purchasing dutch pro products use the
coupon code mr growit 10dp
works on amazon also i believe it works
on your website correct me from wrong
there but it should work on your website
as well i use them in my garden plants
are looking great i love it so thank you
so much for coming on to this episode
hope you enjoy the rest of your day
same see you guys
foreign