coming up on garden talk it is
definitely not the optimal way to grow
it's just a way to grow that is
extremely simple so if you are in a
place where you have no energy access
where you can have a pump you can still
grow things hydroponically using the
kratky method it can be as complicated
or as simple as you want the simplest
versions of this are extremely simple i
can guarantee most people have the stuff
they need from a growing perspective in
their house if you use something like a
normal miracle grow that is a high urea
fertilizer in hydroponics the plants
will die when the plant gets the
solution it will uptake some things and
release some things and those things
that the plant uptakes and release
heavily affect the ph even though it
seems very intimidating it can't be
done and you will be saving yourself
like a lot of money
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the guard talk
podcast this episode number 79. in this
episode interview daniel fernandez he
has been gardening for 20 years and runs
the science and hydroponics youtube
channel in this episode he talks all
about hydroponics there's definitely
some good information for beginners such
as the basics but there's also a lot of
advanced information included in this
episode for those of you that already
have experience in hydroponics but want
to take your knowledge to the next level
thanks to all of you support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you can do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to vivosun for
sponsoring this episode vivosun recently
released the smart grow system this
marco system helps streamline the
growing process by automating stage of
growth requirements on and off schedules
spectral range airflow and circulation
and even records useful data about your
environment it is wi-fi capable and
connects to the vivosun app so you can
control your grow space from your
smartphone check out their website at
vivosun.com
i will provide a link in the youtube
description section below ac infiniti is
sponsoring this episode their clip-on
oscillating fan is now released i've
been using their six-inch version for
over six months now and i absolutely
love it it's easy to clip on the side of
my grow tent and it has 10 different
speeds which makes it easy to control
air circulation they do also have
non-oscillating versions of these
clip-on fans these fans are currently in
high demand when they sell out of the
fans which i expect them to often you
can pre-order them for the next release
you can also use discount code mr growit
if you're buying off their website
easyinfinity.com that discount code
works for all ac infinity items or
discount code mr growit15 if you're
buying off amazon
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
daniel fernandez from science on
hydroponics how you doing today i'm
doing great thanks for having me first
of all we enjoy your podcast so this is
a great opportunity for me to be able to
have this talk with you
yeah i appreciate you coming on when you
reached out to me through dms like i
mentioned before we hit the record
button here i noticed you from the
cultivation certificate program at utah
state university with dr bruce bugbee
and i actually attended that and i saw
you you have a couple videos through
that program and i recognize your name
right away through instagram and i was
like yes he wants to come on so i know
you have extensive knowledge when it
comes to hydroponics i mean you have a
whole youtube channel based around it
and that's what really what we're going
to get into today talk all about
hydroponics we're going to get into some
stuff for beginners but we're also
getting into some more advanced
knowledge stuff for those folks that
have the experience that want to get to
the next level so i think this is going
to appeal to a wide audience
but first what i like to do with all the
guests is an introduction can you tell
us a little bit about yourself and how
you got into gardening
uh yeah sure so as you mentioned my name
is daniel fernandez i
got into gardening around 20 years ago
when i was 15. you know i had a big
space that
i could grow things in and then a friend
told me that we should try hydroponics
so we actually started growing tomatoes
there and at the time
that was right before i started studying
chemistry so i did my undergrad in
chemistry while i learned hydroponics
and then i went and did a phd in spain
and
and i've been working in hydroponics
ever since so i've been working
in my own growth
20 years and then
i've been working with people as a
consultant for the past more or less 12
years awesome
so let's start with a basic question
super basic for the beginners
what is hydroponics and what are some of
the hydroponic systems out there so
that is an interesting question and it's
it's not as straightforward like there
are a lot of definitions out there i
like to think about hydroponics as any
crop where you have no soil in it
so for me anytime where you're growing
plants and there is no soil that
contains the nutrition that the plants
need then that to me is a hydroponic
crop in
the scientific community it will be more
formally defined as a crop where you
have only water so where you have no
media to support plants
while the growth where you have media
supporting the plants for example when
you grow in cocoa or in rock wool those
are more referred to as soilless culture
i like to think about all of those as
hydroponics
and i mean that's to me it's the science
of growing plants without soil like
hydroponic culture
regarding the types of systems that you
have
so
depending on the type of plant that you
have you have access to different
systems the most basic systems that we
have are basically a plant with its
roots sitting in water where you have
all
the things that we what we call deep
water culture
and what we call kratky systems and you
then have see this usually caters to
plants that are smaller
and normally
you have then systems for bigger plants
that you can have things like dutch
buckets where you have large amounts of
media there or you can even have bigger
plants in what we call like they there
are industrial systems to do this type
of thing
where we have channels you know if
somebody has ever seen
a hydroponic crop where you have these
huge gutters that are normally made of
plastic and then you have plants grown
on them and these plants these systems
are usually what we call nutrient flow
technique systems nft systems and we
also have dft systems and
which are deep
flow technique systems
so all of these systems can be used to
to grow plants
you mentioned the kratky method and
that's a method that has been around for
a very long time a lot of people use it
we haven't yet talked about it on this
podcast can you explain what is the
kratky method and how does that work
so the kratky method is
was created by dr kratkin hawaii
so
around the
20 years ago more or less are the first
papers about it and then you have papers
up until like
the mid-2010s
i believe and the idea here is basically
to grow a plant with no energy input
what happens is that when you have
something like a plant that is sitting
on water that the roots are in the water
the water needs to contain oxygen for
the roots to uptake nutrients if the
water runs out of oxygen then the roots
will die normally
so what happens in um kratky system
is that we want to be able to grow
without having to introduce that oxygen
because in a normal deep water culture
system you'll need to constantly pump
air to keep that oxygen high enough well
in the cracking method we say we don't
even need that what we're going to do is
that simply we're going to add all the
water that the plant needs for its
entire life
and then we're going to let the roots
drain that water so the plant will
transpire that water and by reducing the
level of the water the roots that get
exposed to the air will actually be able
to absorb oxygen and use that oxygen
transported to the roots that are
actually submerged in the water to get
nutrients so in this way you can grow
basically any plant
provided you can put all the water
that's ever gonna be needed
in the initial reservoir
so this sort of method is
sort of limited to plants that are small
because you can imagine that a tomato
plant might use
i don't know 100 gallons of water
through its lifetime so it might be
difficult for you to create a tall 100
gallon container and then have it empty
while a lettuce plant might use
a tenth of that or even less so it might
use very little water which allows you
to basically put the plant inside of a
the plant in a bucket
where the roots are growing into the
water and then they transpire the water
the water level is dropping it's
dropping is dropping it allows oxygen to
be transported and the plant does not
die
and it is a low yielding method yields
in kratky are obviously lower because
the plant is under like a optimal
condition the entire time trying to stay
alive but you can grow healthy plants
you can grow leafy greens you can't even
grow tomatoes if you like are willing to
replenish solution and introduce a
little bit of labor into it
but it is definitely not the optimal way
to grow it's just a way to grow that is
extremely simple so if you are in a
place where you have no energy access
where you can have a pump you can still
grow things hydroponically using the
kratky method that's interesting yeah
i've heard a lot of people having
success with that method and like they
said the same thing you did is it's a
simple method but i personally haven't
tried that method yet so yeah really
interesting to hear i know there's a lot
of people out there that you know they
hear about hydroponics talking about a
whole system that needs to be purchased
some people are spending hundreds of
dollars on systems
but really you don't have to spend that
much you can do a diy you can actually
build it yourself some people have the
materials just lying around their house
or in their garage for example
can you talk to us about how to create a
basic diy hydroponic system okay so it
depends fundamentally on the level of
complexity all you need in reality is a
container that you can put a plant in
with water in it
so think about akratki setup in a kratky
setup you can use a mason jar to build
that kratky setup or you can use any
sort of container where you can place
the plant and then have the water inside
the container there is no need for any
sort of a high tech stuff just a
container is enough for starting
of course
what do you want to achieve with your
growing system do you just want to grow
a plant and see it grow and you don't
care too much about learning about
what's going on and your priorities are
to have
less to to
spend less time growing the plan if
that's your priority then akratki system
is going to be a great introduction and
something that you can do basically set
and forget type of thing
however if you're interesting if you're
interested in growing
and
learning more about hydroponics then a
deep water culture system is
close to the exact same thing just with
an air pump in just with an air stone
and an air pump and the issue is that
because uh the water culture system is
way more efficient the plant will gather
way more nutrition from it and therefore
the chemistry will be affected
significantly more so you will need to
do things like ph monitoring ec
monitoring adjust the level of the
solution all these sorts of things that
a kratky setup doesn't have to deal with
because it's less efficient a less
efficient growing method anybody can do
a deep water culture system with like
minimal investment for like a couple of
plants or something like that
you can also go more into it and then
there are a bunch of alternatives that
are midway between buying something
fully made
and
building it yourself from like complete
scratch for example to build an nft
system maybe you
don't want to like cut the plastic
gutters yourself
you can just buy the the
gutters already pre-made and then do the
rest yourself it can be as complicated
or as simple as you want the simplest
versions of this are extremely simple i
can guarantee most people have the stuff
they need from a growing perspective in
their house not counting the fertilizer
but just the containers and stuff
and and then you can make it as
more advanced as as you want
and you know you could even go even some
diy people have gone into like fully
automated hydroponic systems where you
have peristaltic pumps doing all the
nutrient dosing and the ph adjusting and
you have environmental control and i
mean diy in hydroponics goes as simple
or as crazy as you want it to go
depending on your level of interest
the amount of time that you have and
well what your goals are
yeah everybody who actually he just
grows one plant and he took a five
gallon bucket with a lid
cut a hole in the top dropped a net pot
in there uh had his air stones fed into
there and that's pretty much it of
course you have the hydroton pellets in
the net pot and stuff like that but like
that's all he does you know he monitors
water level there's some maintenance but
very very basic something you can do on
your own with very minimal money so i
want to make that well known to the
folks that are beginners that maybe feel
overwhelmed listening to this
because it can be that simple
there are there are several videos on my
channel about a system that i built
using uh
what was it like a four gallon bucket a
five gallon bucket with a net pot and a
lid and it was a kratky system it didn't
have a pot it didn't have i i did
monitor the ph and the easy 24 7 because
part of the objective was to log it but
i could have not done that so
it is definitely can be extremely simple
absolutely
let's get into the fertilizer side of
things here so what fertilizers can be
used and then what fertilizers can't be
used in hydroponics so that's a very
interesting question and a question that
comes up very frequently they're the
fertilizers that most people are used to
are the fertilizers that are used for
soil
has a big advantage to it and it's that
it has a lot of microbes that can
process things into other things
and most importantly
you have urea
that is a very very common
commodity fertilizer because it's
practically the cheapest form of
nitrogen you can get of reduced nitrogen
and then
you can use that in soil because there
are bacteria there that can convert that
urea into nitrate which is a form of
nitrogen that plants do best with
now in hydroponics there are usually no
such bacterial bacterial populations so
if you use something like a normal
miracle grow that is a high urea
fertilizer in hydroponics the plants
will die because they will not get any
nitrate from it the ph will acidify
extremely fast whenever that urea is
decomposed to ammonium so
basically if you're thinking about soil
fertilizers especially the nitrogen
containing soil fertilizers all those
cannot be used in hydroponics
there are also a lot of things that are
insoluble that are used in soil we have
a lot of fertilizers like rock
phosphates like maybe
we have composts we have things that
are
good for soil because the microbes can
break it down but in a hydroponic setup
they would just sit there and there
would they wouldn't dissolve at all
so we definitely don't want to be using
anything that is insoluble or that is
the wrong chemical form
there are a bunch of things that are
shared between both worlds for example
calcium nitrate which is a super common
fertilizer used to green out
yards like front yards
uh green up incredibly easily when you
apply calcium nitrate to it so that's a
fertilizer that is sort of used in those
situations as well and then it is also
very commonly used in fertilizers
because in the end everything you use in
hydroponics you could use in soil but
not the other way around so anything
that is hydroponic that is a hydroponic
fertilizer is going to be
usable in a soil environment but the
other way around is not the case so if
you want to buy a fertilizer for
hydroponics then you need to ensure that
it is formulated for hydroponic growing
if you are not familiar with the
chemistry of how all this happens
got it and i know you're actually a
proponent of making your own nutrients
can you talk to us about how to make
your own nutrients for hydroponic
systems yeah so when i talk about making
your own nutrients i refer to using so
most of the fertilizers that you can buy
that are
for hydroponics are blends of
raw fertilizer inputs
so what i mean when i say make your own
fertilizer is instead of buying these
boutique blends for hydroponics you can
actually make your own from these raw
fertilizer inputs
so i created a program that's called
hydrobody that i created 13 years ago in
2009 that basically helps you formulate
your own fertilizers using these raw
inputs so chemistry can be extremely
um
extremely intimidating to a lot of
people
and so i understand that this is not
very easy to do
but there are like some baby steps that
can be involved here for example instead
of having to make a complete fertilizer
with all the elements that are required
for a plant to survive from scratch from
all the different raw fertilizer inputs
you can actually start by
going into for example a fertilizer like
uh
5 11 26
for example like a master blend or a
peters5 26 which has already most of the
things blended in ratios that are
adequate and then you just make
the calcium nitrate and the
let's say modern potassium phosphate or
some of these other fertilizers so sort
of a midpoint between these two things
and then from there
you know you can move into making your
own concentrated solutions so that you
can then
prepare your own fertilizers
and i at your
at your house or at your grow or
anything like this
um or you can also
move instead of making your nutrient
solution you can also move perhaps it's
less intimidating to then start making
your own amendments so there are things
for example like
calmax
that you can make yourself call max or
fertilizers that use calcium magnesium
salts that i have a videos i have a
video about making a calmac and you use
um calcium nitrate calcium acetate salts
of this sort you blend them and you
create you create a solution with them
and then that's your calmac and i know
i'm talking about all it's very hard to
talk about uh such a complicated topic
in such a short amount of time but if
you go to my website or if you look at
my youtube channel i have a lot of
videos about how to actually make your
own fertilizers where i talk about the
chemistry of how to do this properly
what inputs to use which sorts of
formulations to make
it's an entire world but what i want
people to take from this is that even
though it seems very intimidating
it can't be
done and you will be saving yourself
like a lot of money because the markup
in these hydroponic fertilizers the
markups are insane like the margins that
fertilizer manufacturers make are
very very large and especially the ones
that are selling you fertilizers that
are specialized for certain plants those
will be usually the most most expensive
because like definitely peters or master
blender aren't making like a lot of
margin on their
5 11 26 or these sorts of blends that
they make that are for like the large
scale horticultural industry i was gonna
say there must be a significant cost
savings and you answered that yeah there
is and if you spend the time to do the
research to learn how to do it you know
going to your website or youtube channel
or whatever and and learning how to
formulate your own nutrients in the long
run it'll definitely save you so yeah
thanks for sharing that with us today
the cost savings just to go a little bit
different though the cost savings are
normally for a single person making this
and
they can be it can be even 100 times
cheaper if you're willing to buy
a large enough quantity of things that's
incredible
so i have to ask about organic growing
in hydroponics some people say it's not
possible there's some people that say it
is possible
talk to us about organic growing and
hydroponics is it actually possible or
not it depends on how you define it
so if we define hydro if we define
organic growing as
the agricultural practice
that grows the soil then it is
impossible because by definition
hydroponics does not include any solid
so
if we start with that definition then
the answer is that it can't be done
however if we go for a more um holistic
definition where we do not say soil must
be involved but let's say no
um
processed fertilizers can be used no
like
synthetic fertilizers can be used so we
go into a world where can we grow in a
hydroponic setup using only the raw
inputs that would be allowed in a soil
hydroponic crop in a sorry in a soil
a organic crop
so could we do that uh the answer is
that we can we can do it like i've
worked i've been working with several
large-scale facilities growing leafy
greens organically
and we have achieved it and you can look
at that in my instagram and you can see
pictures where we we're growing
plants in fully organic solutions in
a hydroponic environment where we are
even beating the yields of the
conventional hydroponic setups that are
right next to them
so it can be done
and
it can be done very successfully now it
is tricky because a lot of the as i
mentioned there are things like the
nitrogen cycle that does not exist in a
hydroponic setup so we need to
separate things a little bit and what we
do need to do is a lot of pre-processing
of the solutions right so while you
would mix for example
i don't know your your
for example corn steeply core is a very
common
uh
source of phosphorus in organic growing
because it's very high phosphorus it
contains a lot of lactic acid for
example if you use stealing hydroponics
as is it wouldn't work well because that
amount of lactic acid would be toxic to
the plants so we need to
pre-ferment that in a tank with adequate
bacteria to get all those organic acids
to be used and turned into co2 and
we eliminate it and that way we can
create
a fertilizers that can be used in in a
hydroponic setup now at a large scale we
do this at the large-scale facilities
right but there are already companies
that are producing these like fertilizer
pre-fermented inputs that you can use
and
there is a company that is i'm not
affiliated with which is called
agriculture which has like potassium
nitrate equivalent solutions calcium
nitrate equivalent solutions that are
all omri registered and that are derived
fully from organic inputs and they are
just processed so that all these
available forms of nutrition are
already there so that they don't need to
be generated right there so
yeah if we define organics as growing
plants using only omri approved inputs
then we can we can do it and we can do
it with like we need actually active
bacterial populations to be able to
achieve these with without a problem now
what about microbial inoculants see i
mean touched upon microbes earlier in
this episode and uh you mentioned that
there's really no exchange happening as
far as the conversion of elements in
hydroponics
are microbial inoculants
useless when growing hydroponically or
are they useful in some ways
they are
so yeah this is super controversial
because the evidence is all over the
place if you look at the scientific
evidence of micro inoculation in
hydroponics you'll find anything
so
i think that the answer is
if you're perfect
the benefits from them are going to be
very limited
because if your growing conditions are
absolutely perfect the microbes are very
little to contribute because everything
is already perfect if you are not
perfect then they might give you some
breathing room if you screw up
so they can help you if your growing
conditions are not perfect if there's
stress going on there might be
mechanisms by which they can protect you
not all hydroponic systems are suitable
for microbes if you have a deep water
culture system and you add microbes to
it it will be
super
dirty and if the solution does not cater
to those microbes then those microbes
will likely become
or they will encourage pathogenic
microbes than getting in there so you
need to if you are going to have
microbes then the solution needs to
cater to them as well and the media also
needs to cater to them so it is a
decision that needs to be made like is
it going to have microbes or is it not
going to have microbes
if it is going to have microbes then
design everything around that if it's
not going to then
design it so that it's not going to it
is also easier to have microbes in
hydroponic systems where the solutions
are not recirculated for example if you
have a drain to waste setup where you
are just irrigating a plant in a
soilless medium then
inserting microbes there is far easier
than if you recirculated the solution
because the microbes are just going to
be there with the plan they're not going
to in your drip lines they're not going
to in your tanks they're not going to be
anywhere else so usually if you are
going to introduce micros in a system
like that
usually you're not going to have a
problem when you do that
i consider them useful like uh
another point is that microbes can also
help you with pathogens there are
microbes that are not for the plant but
for fighting pathogens so while they
might not help you with the optical
nutrients for the plant just the fact
that they're feeling an ecological niche
in the root zone will mean that
something else that's pathogenic will
not be able to fill it so
furthermore there are some microbes that
will actively fight
things that are there for example if you
have
um
let's say root aphids and you how you
inoculate your media
with um
poverty of asiana or with other microbes
that are pathogenic to root aphids then
they will fight their relations when
they get there so microbes are insurance
in my view they are something that we do
not need to grow perfect
if we can grow perfectly if you are not
perfect then i think that it's
not going to hurt you if you add them
and you have designed your system so
that adding them is beneficial i agree
when you said it was a controversial
topic because i get a lot of people that
are arguing both ways and so thanks for
bringing some clarity on that avenue
i want to switch it up i want to get
into silica next talk to us about
silicon and silicates in hydroponics
okay
so silicon is not an element that's
necessary for plant life
at least for
many uh plants like there are some
plants like grasses that require silicon
but for plants like tomatoes cucumbers
lettuce you don't really need silicone
for them to live
we have found through research that it
is beneficial uh there's a lot of
research in the scientific community
showing that if you can get silicon into
a plant then it will
at the very very least protected from a
fungal pathogens like that we have so
much evidence for that we already take
that as fact
um but how do you get it into the plants
the problem is that the chemistry of
silicon is tricky
most of the silicates that we have most
of the minerals that contain silicon
are not soluble they are just not going
to dissolve in water
so how do we get silicon in the water
so we have these products that are
called we have these types of minerals
called silicates and some of these
silicates like calcium silicate
potassium silicate and sodium silicate
are soluble in water at really high ph
so if you have a ph of above 11 then all
of these will be solvable
then
[Music]
as soon as you you can create a
concentrated solution of these silicates
they're dissolved in water then you can
add a little bit of that to a solution
to a hydroponic solution
and at the ph that you have in
hydroponics between five five and six
five let's say
all that silicate will be transformed
into silicic acid
which is a form that is available to
plants for their uptick
there is there are some hypotheses that
other slightly larger forms of silicon
are also available to plants very
difficult to test it
the issue is that these silicic acids
these monoxilicic acids are extremely
unstable under ph between in their phs
between four and eight they are
extremely unstable so they will quickly
polymerize and
be unavailable for the plant
so
that's the main issue with this
chemistry
now there are some products that will
give will not give you silicates the
basic solutions but they will give you
monoxilicic acids stabilized monoxylacic
acids which can exist in a stable form
at a ph below two so if you have these
silicic acid with molecules that can
stabilize its structure at a ph below
two then it will not polymerize because
this polymerization forms quartz like um
silicon dioxide which is insoluble or a
silica gel basically
so
you can have those these two extremes
now when those stabilized elastic acids
get put into a hydroponic solution at a
ph of five eight
or 55265 the question is
are they polymerizing as well or are
they not
so far
very few people have studied this
however we know that there are some
differences in availability of some of
these stabilized elastic acids there are
several i mean probably a handful of
studies right now that are showing that
it is different
and
then
monosyllabic acid derived just from
silicates that whose ph has been dropped
to the ph in hydroponics so which is
better
for root uptake we don't know there is
also the question of foliar feeding of
silicon if you feed silicon through
the leaves and not through the roots
then you need to consider that silicone
is completely immobile once it is
mobilized inside a plant and placed
somewhere it will not move so this means
you need to routinely apply it because
tissue that grows after you do the
foliar will never get the silicone that
you applied before
is it better to apply one form or the
other right now it is
unknown it is unknown evidence is
pointing to the fact that it is not
exactly the same but
acilisic assets ability like a
stabilized silicic acids properties will
depend heavily on what it was stabilized
for and how that was achieved
there are many there are maybe like 30
ways to achieve that so
it is a when things are marketed as
monocytelicic acids just bear in mind
that
what sort of stabilized monoxilicic acid
when mixing silica into a reservoir it's
generally recommended to mix that in
first and then mix in your other
nutrients can you talk to us about why
that is and then also what order
nutrient should be mixed into your
reservoir yeah so
normally you will mix the silicates
first because silicates are more stable
in
dilute solutions if they encounter a
solution that has more things in it more
cations and more anions it is bound to
be less stable and polymerize faster so
you add it first because the least
amount of things that your solution is
that we're going to have will be the
when it's like our water or tap water
when it's when it has when you have
added nothing else so you add the
silicon to that and when you add the
silicon the ph will be higher and it
will be a little bit more stable
normally you will inject silicone first
then you will inject whatever is more
acidic
which is normally a solution containing
acidic potassium phosphates of some sort
which is normally micros and potassium
so
more potassium phosphate or things like
this so silicate then this acidic
solution then the nitrates usually go or
the calcium containing solutions
and then finally you will set the ph
with an acid and to the final ph that
you want that is normally a way that
works well it is not the only way like
you could also for example do at the
silicon then
set the ph then add the other things
then set the ph again although that is
not very effective in terms of like the
amount of control that you require so
this is the standard what i've mentioned
is usually the standard it is also very
common to put a mixing chamber right
after the silicon especially if you're
using an injector system
because the silicates if they are not
fully mixed into the solution then they
can precipitate when the next injector
injects things into the line
if you are mixing into a large reservoir
by hand then you need to ensure that
that's properly mixed before adding the
the other
nutrients to your solution
gotcha okay
another controversial one i wanted to
touch base on is that gypsum so here
people adding in gypsum into their
hydroponic systems
and uh there's others that say you
shouldn't do that because it's not
soluble
give us a low down on gypsum with
calcium sulfate and hydroponics i have
an entire video on just this like
precise topic of gypsum in hydroponics
and gypsum is not as soluble as many
things it's not calcium nitrate but it
is very soluble like it is
i mean it is not as insoluble as many
other things it is not a rock phosphate
it is way more soluble than that so
it is definitely not soluble enough for
you to prepare
a concentrated solution of gibson to use
in your hydroponic setup that will not
work
but
you can get 400 ppms of calcium from
gibson
like from gypsum i mean it is soluble
enough that you could dissolve enough to
supply
more than double the nutrient
requirement of the highest calcium
requiring plant in a hydroponic solution
however you would need to add it
directly to the to the final nutrient
solution you cannot as i mentioned
prepare a concentrated solution and then
add it you will need to add it to the
final solution and then you have one
thing and it's that the kinetics of the
solution of the gypsum are slow so it
will take time for it to dissolve it
will take time in the order of maybe
hours for it to properly dissolve in a
solution
another thing that gypsum has that is
quite tricky is that its solubility goes
down as temperature increases so you
need to mix it at pretty low temperature
so if you have a solution that's above
70 fahrenheit then gypsum is going to be
less soluble than all the solubility
that could have so yeah it can be used
so under
precise conditions
okay
getting a little bit deeper into water
temperature
what is the optimal water temperature
when growing hydroponically
so in most cases i would say that around
70 fahrenheit is the optimal temperature
for roots in general
you can grow at a little bit higher
temperature and that can be optimal for
some plants under some conditions but
then we start getting into the point you
know oxygen solubility goes down as the
temperature goes up
so if it's a system that has
issues with its oxygenation then that's
not going to help it all for example if
you have a media that retains too much
water between irrigations
that's not going to help at all so
normally if you're at 70 that's perfect
if you are at 75 plants can most plants
can tolerate that if you are at 80 then
you're gonna have low oxygen and fungal
and bacterial issues because especially
anaerobic bacteria
will love
solutions that are low in oxygen and
high in temperature
to the low side then when you go 265 you
might still be able to do fine but the
problem is that the kinetics of nutrient
transport becomes slower as the
temperature drops so the uptake of
nutrients becomes more sluggish
so you start having issues with the
uptake of some things and then when you
drop below 65 phosphorus uptake drops to
basically zero because it does require
substantial
i mean it does require the temperature
for the uptake because of these kinetics
of uptake so if you drop the temperature
below 65 you'll start noticing that your
plants will basically turn purple
and
because of because of that
which some people use to their advantage
yeah the water temperature is one of my
biggest concerns uh yeah i live in a
desert region and i think right now it's
at uh okay in this room right here it's
at 81 degrees fahrenheit i turned off
the ac for recording blah blah blah
usually it's about 78 but water
temperature what i heard is over 75 is
really you're at risk of those pathogens
happening right and so uh i've just
avoided dwc you know hydroponics in
general because of that reason why but i
know there are hacks around it some
people add in like frozen water bottles
into the reservoir to lower the
temperature some people buy a chiller to
add to reduce the water temperature so
there are solutions for controlling it
but and if you're adding in a chiller
year you have to consume more energy
right and then do a cost analysis see if
it's worth it or not so that's just one
of my biggest things that i've avoided
hydroponic growing for is water
temperature alone so just just to tie to
the previous topic
one of the things that mainly limits
kratky usage is water temperature
because if the water gets hot then it's
not going to work at all so that's the
main limiting factor
as you say normally plants tolerate
warmer air way better than warmer water
because warm air still contains um
20 oxygen so plants will do much i mean
if you're growing in a hot region it is
much better to do something like
a dutch bucket or a system that is like
a drain to waste system with cocoa
because that way you can very easily
control the temperature even if your
plants get hot water for like water at
85 for
a few minutes or 30 minutes while you
irrigate them they will still get the
air soon after so it's way way less
troubling
okay that's good to know
ph
super important when it comes to
hydroponics what ph is optimal for
hydroponics and then stabilizing ph can
you get into that a little bit because
that's tricky for some people
so
the optimal ph in hydroponics for plants
for most higher plants is going to be
let's say between five eight and six two
like if you wanna be narrow but plants
can do well between five and six five
that's really the reason that they do
finding
um
it is
very important to keep them in that
region
because when you go to the lower end you
start getting
very high uptake of some nutrients
micronutrient uptake becomes way too
high below five five and also sulfur
uptake becomes way too low
and then to the upside then you get
issues with micro uptake becoming too
low so that's like the main thing that
happens is that your micro uptake just
plummets especially iron uptake at high
ph is super super low so
that's why you need to take care of your
of your ph
now
how do you make it stable there are two
things that change your ph one is
chemistry so
what the chemicals that are actually in
there when you prepare the solution
but the most important thing that
changes your ph is how the plant
modifies the solution when it gets it so
when the plant gets the solution it will
uptake some things and release some
things and those things that the plant
uptakes and release heavily affect the
ph
and the best way to stabilize the ph of
a solution and the media is to make sure
that the ratio of the things that the
plant uptakes causes as little of a
shift in the ph as possible this
normally means that you'll need to
play with your ammonium to nitrate ratio
so plants will generally uptake a lot of
nitrate and push the ph up under normal
circumstances most plants will do that
they when they're especially in vegging
phases they will push the ph up due to
nitrate uptake so if you add some
ammonium that ammonium is uptaken really
fast and it counter balances that so
that the plant does not modify the ph
much trying to stabilize the ph of the
solution itself
is very problematic if you are not also
catering to the
chemistry that the plant wants to uptake
because if you just try to add buffers
or stuff to like force the solution to a
ph the the and you feed things that the
plant will
uptake very drastically and dramatically
affect the ph then it's going to be a
losing game like the best solution that
you have to control the ph is to make
sure that the nutrients that you're
feeding
are actually
buffering the nutrient uptake of the
plant
now you can
buffer this nutrient uptake through this
but there are other plants for example
you have tomatoes that uptake massive
amounts of potassium and will heavily
acidify the solution at some points then
in those cases
you might want to use
uh add more nitrate for example to
counterbalance that
extreme
uptake of potassium
so
there are a bunch of
strategies you can use in terms of the
nutrient uptake but you need to consider
the plan like just chemically adjusting
the solution does not work that well
however when you adjust the solution you
can also consider the uptake when you
adjust it for example a very common
strategy is that when the ph increases
you add nitric acid with ammonium in it
so that you both replenish the nitrogen
but you are also increasing the ammonium
to nitrate ratio so that so that every
time you adjust
the probability of adjusting is lowered
because you are shifting things a little
bit every time you adjust
so that sort of like smart adjustment of
the ph
and works better
than
um
doing just adjustments with regular
acids or bases and you'll notice that
companies will often sell ph ups and ph
styles that consider that take these
into consideration like ph chaps are not
just potassium hydroxide and ph downs
are not just mono potassium phosphate
they often include
or phosphoric acid they include other
things to help you
buffer nutrient uptake
okay so basically you're saying most of
the causes are due to
the fertilizer not being balanced for
that plant so if somebody generally
speaking if somebody is growing
hydroponically and they continue to
struggle with that stable ph they may
want to consider going to a different
fertilizer yeah they might consider
changing their ratio of certain things
in your fertilizer
and so that they need to fight that less
however there's also the case that some
plants will be will grow way better in a
way that is very destabilizing to the ph
so
that is also a
counter to this like if you are going to
be growing a plant at its maximum
potential maybe your ph will never be
stable
man you you sometimes need to compromise
that you can also for example let's say
if you're using a drain to waste setup
and you're irrigating with um a ph of
six and then your runoff is always like
six five seven you can then water at
lower ph like at five five to like
compensate that change so that your
runoff does not shift that much and it's
in the zone that you want it to be so
you can also play with the in because
what what matters is the ph of the root
zone so in systems where you are
watering and then that solution is not
recirculated
you need to consider that you are blind
to the ph of the root zone and the ph of
the input is not as important as the ph
of the root zone that you're growing
got it i did actually watch your video
on runoff and ph really really good
video i totally recommend it for anybody
who hasn't seen it yet definitely check
it out a lot of good information you
clarify a lot of things in that video
next up i want to get into ec or ppm
what's the optimal range for hydroponics
so this is an interesting question
because different ions conduct
electricity differently and therefore
the ec of two solutions with different
composition and they won't be
they they're they won't be chemically
equivalent to the same ec so what i'm
saying is that while you might be at a
certain ec that works well for
a given nutrient composition then if you
have a nutrient composition that is
substantially different then that same
ec
will not be equivalent
so this is why talking terms of vc is a
little bit misleading because then
a person might say hey i grow out and
you see a 1-5 and it works great and
another person might say well i grow a
two and then the solutions are very
different
and then when you look at what the
actual osmotic pressure of the solutions
is they might be the same at one five
and a two so
it is it is not a good practice and i
know why it's so common but i think it
would be
um it is more
uh useful if
people only do easy comparisons when
they're talking about like the same
nutrients right
otherwise i prefer to think instead of
dc what are the optimal nutrient ratios
in hydroponics like what are the optimal
nutrients to grow in
and that we can have a deeper
conversation about and
like that goes into like the
formulations that are better for each
plant according to the tissue that each
plant is growing you know because like
it's not the same to grow ahead of
lettuce than it is to grow a tomato
because in one case we're growing fruits
and in the other kids we're growing
leaves so
what tissue are you growing and then
your nutrients need to cater to whatever
tissue you want to be grown yeah i was
going to say that the type of plant
would certainly have an impact on it as
well all right one more controversial
topic for you and i know people are
going to love this one
flushing
is there any science behind flushing
particularly medicinal plants prior to
harvest when growing in hydroponics or
actually growing in general
so
um
the question is do you
is there
a need to flush like is there
should we always flash it does flashing
accomplish anything so flushing really
does not take anything out of the plant
the conception that the like the concept
and this idea that the plant will lose
nutrients because your flush is
completely false like the plant will not
lose any nutrients it already has taken
up due to flushing so that won't happen
what you will do is that you will
completely
um you will reduce the concentration of
nutrients in the root zone
so do you need to do that because if
you're growing at very high easy values
in the root zone maybe lowering the ec
will give the plant some breathing room
and it will be able to grow better for
let's say that ending period
but are you growing at like the same
stable easy nutrient concentration the
entire time and then if you flush then
you're gonna deprive it of those
nutrients in the end
do you want to deprive it of those
nutrients and i don't see why you would
like you are going to be wasting some of
the most efficient like the ending part
of the growing cycle is the part where
you get the most yield because it's
where you have the most structure to
build into so
um
it depends can you benefit from it if
you can't benefit from it then you
should use it if you cannot benefit from
it because your conditions do not allow
you to benefit from it then you
shouldn't
because there is that's why there is a
big disconnect sometimes when
you talk about people who
like plant scientists who grow the
plants perfectly and then they say well
i flush and it's absolutely no benefit
to me i see a detriment and it's like
yeah well because you're growing this
way
and but if you grew this way where you
have all this much higher ec in the
media then you would see a benefit so
whether you see a benefit or not depends
on whether you need it or not so
it is definitely not something that
should be considered as a
should always be done
it should be done when it's necessary
that makes sense
so taking a step back and taking a look
at the folks that are new to hydroponics
what advice do you have for those that
are new
so for people who are new to hydroponics
i would say
you can
start very
a very simple level hydroponics is a
great way to grow plants
you have a lot of control that is both a
blessing and a curse because then you
need to realize that you are very likely
to fail
because you have all the power so in
soil there are a lot of mechanisms that
are working in your favor without you
doing anything in hydroponics you have
total control which means you have total
responsibility over the fate of the
plant and it's very likely that you will
kill several plants and that's not a bad
thing i think all of us who have ever
grown plants have probably a lot of
those plant carcasses in our closets
so
it is not anything to be afraid of and
you can try small systems i would say
start small and
depending on your region i would say you
can if you are in a cool cooler region
where your temperatures are fine you can
try kratky method or if it's a small
indoor thing if you want to grow at
outdoors then you might want to try a
soilless media type of thing like a
cocoa grow or something like that where
you have
um
a little bit less concern over the
temperature of the water and things like
this but don't be afraid of it i think
that's the main thing don't be afraid of
it it can be done simply and can be done
in a very complicated manner and there
are nutrients that are very low cost
that you can use
just go ahead and try i like asking that
question towards the end of the episode
because it gives the guest a chance to
speak on something they didn't speak on
the episode and also provides a ton of
tips like everybody who asks that
question to just provides so much good
information you know specifically for
beginners because a lot of the audience
a lot of them tuning in right now are
beginners they're just getting started
maybe they're in a state that just
legalized for example a certain plant
that they can grow and now they're
starting to grow so i'm having that
advice for beginners it's super valuable
to a lot of people so thanks for sharing
that another question i asked towards
the end is how can the listeners find
you and what do you have upcoming in the
future
also i have my website
sciencinghydroponics.com
where i talk about the science of
growing plants without soil and i try to
go into the scientific literature
and i try to address topics in a manner
that is more evidence based than other
sources i also
have my youtube channel
and science in hydroponics as well and i
also have my instagram with the same
name and you can find me in all of these
places
um
i do general i do consulting for
small to large hydroponic growers i am
one of the only consultants that you can
get on the hour
because most of the large-scale
hydroponic consultants would never
consult with you without like uh
like consulting contract
i've kept my hourly consulting basically
to allow people who have
um to allow the little guy a chance to
like uh benefit from my experience and
also the experience of other consultants
and growers i work with
so that um
the consulting is not monopolized by by
the big guys that's really cool that you
offer consulting like that not a lot of
people do and there are a lot of people
out there that need help
and so it's really really awesome that
you're there as a source i'll definitely
have a link to your youtube channel down
in the description section below if
you're tuning in on one of the podcast
platforms just search for them you'll
find them
if you enjoyed this episode click that
thumbs up button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend i'm releasing a new
garden talk podcast episode and i would
love for you to tune in to future
episodes daniel thanks so much for
coming on to this episode today this has
been awesome so much great information i
definitely learned a ton this is one of
the episodes where i'm going to watch
back several times probably to grasp all
the information
and uh and then yeah hope we keep in
touch and maybe you can come back for a
part two sometime in the future yeah
thanks thanks for having me this was
great as i mentioned i'm a big fan i
would definitely love doing uh part two
going deeper into some of the topics
that people find interesting awesome
alright well until next time peace out
everyone thanks for tuning in