welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr growt and you're tuned in to the
Gard Talk podcast this is episode number
161 in this episode I interview Matt
from strange show he has been gardening
for eight years and is a fellow content
creator his YouTube channel has over 305
th000 subscribers and covers a variety
of things such as the history of the
plant latest research gardening advice
and more in this podcast episode he
talks about how he grows his plants in
an EB and flow hydroponic system
everything from how the system works
nutrients pH PPM environment and more if
you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow both of those channels will be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their ion frame LED grow
lights which have the latest Samsung Evo
LEDs these girl lights include a
schedule controller that features 10
brightness levels dimming and a sunrise
sunset feature click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their ion frame LED
grow lights and the discount code Mr
Grow 15 works on both Amazon and their
website AC infinity.com stash blend
stash blend consists of several
ingredients in one so you no longer have
to buy individual bottles it includes
corn steep liquor seaweed extract humic
acid beneficial bacteria silica and
micro risal fungi it can be used in
addition to your synthetic Bas nutrients
or be used in living soil systems simply
mix it into water and water your plants
with it
you can get it at stash blend.com Link
in the description section below and use
to discount code the stash Mars Hydro
check out their new version of their
drip irrigation kit this system can
connect to a Mars Hydro Digital Timer
sold separately to enable fully
automated watering the reservoir was
constructed with a durable foldable
fabric a PVC coating and an odor nylon
layer making this system fully
waterproof and leak proof more
information is linked in the description
section below and right other winter
sales going on where you can get up to
25% off their products also try using
discount code Mr Grow you might be able
to save a little
more and we are back and I'm join with
Matt from strange show how you doing
today what's up buddy thanks for having
me on the show homie dude thanks for
coming on the show super excited to have
you on we actually met in MJ biscon you
are a cool dude that's all I can say
about that man The Vibes were right
there it's hard to really link up with
people and be on the same level as far
as things that you could talk about and
we have growing in common we have the
plant that we all know and love we have
that in common and it was just Good
Vibes all around for sure and have
someone that not only has those two
things in common but also making the
YouTube videos it's very rare that I
talk to someone who also makes YouTube
videos so that was very cool to link up
yeah content creation is its own thing
and yeah it's like you're talking a
different language and you're talking to
somebody who doesn't have experience
with it so awesome man well happy to
have you on the podcast today to talk
about gardening cuz you grow you're have
a very successful Channel I'm looking at
it right now it's over 300,000
subscribers congratulations on that by
the way that's not easy to do and uh I
know it takes a long long time uh it
took a little while but we got there you
make content not only on growing but on
the consumption side of things as well
very informative videos I really like
your history ones you had one on like
skunk number one and oh yeah a couple
other strains and really really good
information very entertaining so if
anybody hasn't checked out his channel
I'll definitely have it linked in the
description section below thank you
buddy so tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
oh man I've been into uh these plants
that we like so much for a long time
since I was young actually I used to
read about all kinds of cool growing
techniques and gardening
magazines but I never really got into
growing much back then just cuz the laws
weren't very favorable in my area
but in like 2017 is when I moved to
Colorado and not long after living in
Colorado I got a job in a big commercial
grow I did that for a few years working
in the Harvest side of things I did a
few big Harvest Crews we would go around
to a lot of different grow facilities so
that job was really cool cuz I got to
experience a lot of different growth
facilities just from one job and I
eventually moved to the cultivation side
of
the commercial grow space and eventually
when I moved out of my tiny apartment I
was like hey I'm living in Denver now
I'm going to start growing at home and
so that really all started in 2017
talking about your grow style are you
indoors Outdoors soil cocoa Hydro
organic synthetic what's your style uh
indoor I've only done indoor so
far and I've only really done synthetic
like salt-based nutrients so far most of
the grows I've done have been in cocoa
or like a cocoa mix but recently I moved
to like a flood and drain style growing
with uh hydren pellets the little
expanded clay pellets which is been
pretty fun I've been enjoying that how
much of the commercial side of things
like the processes that they do
commercially how much of that do you
take and Implement in your home grow
there's some of it that is
very you that was useful for me to see
just like um having a a sop and having a
way you do things and knowing like how
important it is maybe to only try to
implement one new change at a time
because if I'm implementing three new
changes at a time and one of them works
it's going to be really hard for me to
tell which one
worked um things like trellising
learning the importance of just learning
the importance of things that every grow
facility I've ever been in does across
the board and you're like there has to
be a reason why we're all doing this
like nice
defoliations trellising and supporting
your plants getting nice light
penetration and uh CO2 I don't know if I
would have been so determined that like
I have to run CO2 if I wouldn't have
seen like every single commercial
facility is all running CO2 and we're
going to get to CO2 here in a little bit
I know for homeg growing there's it's
kind of split between the people who do
supplement CO2 and people who don't
supplement CO2 so eager to hear your
thoughts on that here in a little bit so
in the commercial facilities that you
spoke about that you worked in did they
have an EB andf flow style like the
flood and drain style that you do now in
your home grow only at the very very
first grow facility I ever worked at
which I was on the cultivation side
there but it was such a large facility
and I was such a new employee there that
my main job was mostly just scrubbing
out reservoirs all day nothing uh really
glamorous and I didn't really get a
chance to learn a whole lot but they
were running basically the same exact
setup I'm running at home just on a much
larger scale but that's the only
commercial facility I've ever been in
that had that setup got it so you're
able to get a little bit of Knowledge
from there and bring it to your home
grow because of that at least it wasn't
like completely foreign I knew what the
base basic parts of the setup where I
knew how it functioned I knew how to
take one apart and put it back together
so that was a lot of weight off my
shoulders already cuz when you're
getting in like at least for me when I
was getting into this having all these
timers and water pumps and everything is
dependent on the
electricity it could all feel really
overwhelming really fast and so it was
nice to start with at least a system I
had had my hands on before yeah I can
imagine I know there's a lot of new
Growers out there that really get
intimidated by all the pieces of
equipment you know when it comes to the
hydroponic setup now we do have quite a
few beginners that tune into this
podcast we have beginners intermediate
and also Advanced folks looping in the
beginners there are some folks that
probably don't know what an ENT flow
system is could you explain what it is
and how it works yeah for sure um so
it's basically you have all of your
nutrients and your water in one main
reservoir you just have a couple of
pumps and timers and your timer is set
up to
where your water from your Reservoir
pumps to the buckets where your plants
are for a certain amount of time let's
them get some nutrient uptake and then
after whatever time you determine it
pumps the water out of the plant bucket
back into the main reservoir you can
just set that up to cycle throughout the
day so you can get different periods of
flooding and draining so you have
different periods where you have
nutrient uptake you have periods where
you also have a lot of availability for
the roots to get oxygen so you don't
have to worry about root rot and stuff
like that okay and then would that be on
a schedule can you talk about kind of
the watering flooding schedule for the
Ed and flow setup yeah the the system I
have right now is just some like the old
school analog timer where you push the
little pins out so every one of those
pins is 15 minutes and when I have a
Little Seedling that's just like in the
Little Pete Moss Cube I'll really only
try to
touch that Cube enough times throughout
the day so it doesn't dry out so maybe
one 15 minute flood every 2 or 3 hours
depending on how it seems to be reacting
and then as the plant is growing and
getting bigger then I'm bumping it up a
little maybe I'll go one 15 minute flood
every hour and then by the time I'm all
the way into flower and the plants are
bigger depending on how big the plants
are I might be flooding
multiple times per hour all the way
throughout the day 24 hours a day got it
and I assume that you've got nutrients
in there are you using some synthetic
line of nutrients and what's the EC or
PPM that you aim for for the different
stages of growth uh yeah I'm running uh
all salt-based nutrients right now
recently I've been running um Athena
I've been liking it a lot it's my first
run with Athena and I've also recently
been running autof flowers which I'm not
used to so usually I might be and a lot
of times I'm just testing this in like a
PPM reading so a lot of times in veg I
might be getting up to 700 or 800 ppms
in the peak of veg and then maybe even
over a th000 ppms in the peak of flow
but I found that these Auto flowers have
been running it's just a few but they
seem to like a lot or need a lot less
nutrients so I've been running about
half of that strength with the auto
flowers I've pretty much been taking the
feeding chart that Athena recommends and
just cutting it straight in half and
it's been working really well yeah
that's a common question that people ask
is about autof flowers and their feeding
it's often here that there it requires
less nutrition and there's some people
that say no it requires the same amount
so I think that's one of like the
debated topics amongst the community is
whether or not Autos should be treating
differently when it comes to feedings so
it's interesting to hear that your
experience that yeah you've had to cut
the dose in half there I heard the same
thing and so I tried I went with the
full
strength and I could just you could see
the normal signs it it just wasn't happy
you could see the leaf tip burn
starting and then I just backed off I
was like I let it go for maybe a whole
week before I was like I got to change
this Reservoir it's just too much
because it felt like too much because I
think what it was recommending even
early in veg was 1100 PPM and it said
that this
formulation is made to run at a higher
EC and I was like all right let's let's
try it never tried these nutrients
before I'll go with what they recommend
and I think it was just this particular
cultivar because the whole plant I mean
finished is only this big and so it
makes sense that it doesn't need that
much salt true yeah I know some aut
flowers can grow massive and then some
stay squat really comes down to genetics
obviously it comes down to other things
lighting environment nutrition all that
stuff but yeah some could be real small
so it makes sense for those smaller
plants to need lesser nutrition right
yeah it does to me now mixing up those
nutrients in water what is your water
source are you just using tap water or
are you filtering the water in some way
like reverse osmosis or what's your
water source I have a uh 75 gallon per
day AR filter in the house it's just
hooked up underneath my kitchen sink and
it's off 90% of the time but I know like
every time I'm about to have to say I
have to fill my reservoir tomorrow I'm
going to change it I'll go ahead and
turn on the filter tonight fill me up a
few five gallon buckets and get ready so
I always have uh the AR water at the
house I don't have to worry about going
and trying to get distilled water
worrying about what's in my water supply
because I know just a few years ago here
in Denver the city of Denver has sent
out brido water filters to everyone and
they're like hey we highly suggest that
before you drink the water from your
sink that you put it through this brida
filter so
since uh a lot of plants are so good at
holding on to things like heavy metals
and stuff that they have access through
through the roots I just figured that's
nothing I want to risk yeah better safe
than sorry man a similar boat to you I
live in Las Vegas and out the tap it's
485 PPM a lot of people who who tuned
into my content I've heard me say that a
ton of times but I fig I'd mention it
here and so yeah I also use reverse
osmosis and I like how the newer systems
are now kind of a one for one the past
system I had was a one for three for
every one gallon you get of reverse
osmosis water you're wasting three
gallons MH now the system that I bought
is a one for one which is so much better
and it's so much faster yes bigger
tubing you have the same one or uh no I
don't I'm still on the old one I don't
think it I don't know what the ratio is
but if you hold up the waist line and
the fill line you see the waistline
pouring and the fill line dripping and I
hate doing that I'm always trying to
figure out what what can we use this
water for what can we use this waste
water for and a lot of people what they
do is they put in their backyard they
water their plants out back with it
we've done that too for the house plants
some people use it and they they uh have
their drain line hooked up to a five
gallon bucket and they flush their
toilets with it oh that's smart that's
smart save you a couple of toilet
flushes there you go right so yeah you
can use that water and then a lot of
water sources they go right back into
the local water Min spell system and it
gets clean so is it really being fully
wasted
well it's going back into the system
yeah but there's energy that takes to
kind of recan and stuff like that so
yeah that's that's a bigger debate here
yeah okay and then after you mix in the
nutrients does it require a pH
adjustment at all uh yes well the way
Athena works is you put in the pH
adjustment first so it's sort of a
little it's actually the exact opposite
of what you would expect from a lot of
other lines where you would mix all of
your stuff and then adjust your pH at
the end you do it that way the first
time to judge how many milliliters per
gallon I needed then the next time you
can do that first but um with Hydro
especially I'm always super on top or I
try to be super on top of the pH because
not only have I experienced with Hydro
something I never dealt with before
which is a pH drift cuz I never really
had a reservoir of nutrients sitting
around for you know two weeks I would
mix up the nutrients and I would use
them that
day so you'll get a little drift your pH
will slightly rise over time and I think
that's because probably because I have a
AirStone in my reservoir but also with
Hydro there's
no uh buffer like if you had soil it
probably would be a much better buffer
cocoa would even be a good buffer if you
have some beneficial back IIA that's
going to help be a mediator between this
crazy pH water and your bare Roots but
in the hydro system it's just bare Roots
the nutrient mix goes right to them and
if you have a nutrient mix and the pH is
way way off that could really really
affect your plants with just like one or
two feedings so I try to go in every
single morning I check the pH every
morning adjust if needed and again in
the afternoon so I'm trying to check and
adjust my pH as needed twice a day got
it and what do you typically aim for for
a pH I'm going for uh 58 to
62 and when I first will reset the
reservoir like the first night I'm
always making sure that I'm shooting for
that low end so I'll shoot for the 5.8
cuz I know if in the 10 or 12 hours I'm
gone before I check it again if it does
rise a little bit hopefully I won't get
out of my sweet spot if that 58 to 62
okay that's typically what I'm aiming
for in deep water culture so similar
with Hydro setup right and I use blue
planet nutrients and the cool thing
about that set of nutrient lineup is
once I mix it in the nutrients it always
mixes up to 5.8 pH so it's like just
perfect exactly where I want it and so
when I change the reservoir I add that
in there and it's at the perfect set pH
now I do encounter a little bit of pH
Drift But I've noticed for the most part
it drift downwards I know some people
say the opposite they say it drifts
upwards for them but yeah I mean I go
5.8 pH the next St check it'll be at 5.5
I've even it's even gone down to like
5.1 and I have to pH Up it see I've
never heard of that either because even
before this I've only done Hydro a few
times and before this I was running um
the General Hydroponics uh Flora series
I think I was running like it was the
three-part Flora series plus a few
additives madebe a six part or something
like that and I was having the same
issue with the drift but it was still
going up and since I was really new to
this I just started asking around and
what I seem to hear from everyone is
that pH drift is common and it usually
always drifts up and I got a million
different reasons why that could happen
but I never really heard about it going
down yeah me neither until I actually
experienced it yeah but yeah I've been
able to adjust it and and get things
back on track there so but yeah five 8
6.2 same exact range I aim for nice I
want to take a step back and get more
into your gross space what size grow
space are you in and how many plants do
you typically run in that space what
I've been liking the most until I
recently had to downsize was a 5x5 tent
I was running two 5x5 tents I had like a
big basement that they could both go in
but I liked having the grow spaces
separated cuz I'd rather have two
harvests at two separate times rather
than harvesting a 10x10 plant and having
to deal with that whole drying and trim
gel of a
10x10 so I'll run the 5x5 and I like to
space out just four plants in there so
I'll be able to run those four plants a
little bit bigger but with uh some
trellising I'll still be able to fill
out the canopy all the way from corner
to corner really nice and I like that
mix cuz it's not too crowded and it's
not too many plants for me to work
on but with these new auto flowers I'm
running I'm looking at a 5x5 and
thinking that if I had these ones that
are staying this small and this wide you
know a foot tall and a foot wide that
there's no telling how many I could run
in a 5x5 especially if I'm doing like
three gallon pots maybe is that what
you're doing right now three gallon or I
have been doing five gallon pots but
that's because I'm usually running photo
period plants that let veg for a few
months and I usually run them pretty big
and so I want that big root mass for the
bigger plant but on this plant I'm
running now that's an
autoflow I don't think the plant is
barely is as wide as the pot is and the
rule of thumb I I've always heard as is
as above so below so roughly the size
and shape of your plant above the ground
will be roughly what your root mass size
will be so if I'm going off that I'm
looking at this pot and thinking it
might not even be needed to be that big
yeah I know a ton of people get away
with just one gallon containers in WoW
EB and flow system for example so they
can go a lot smaller and remind me I
know you said in the very beginning but
what's in the containers is it just
hydroton or did you say Coco I have a um
so inside of the buckets themselves
there're Square buckets and I have
square fabric pots the fabric pot is
filled with hydrogen clay play pets and
then right in the middle of that is like
a little net basket and that's what I'll
um have where I'm starting my seedling
and in the middle of the net basket will
be like a little Pete Moss based growing
Cube like a little rapid rotter Cube
okay got it and then since you're in a
flood drain system tray in that 5x5 are
you running a is it a 4ot by 4ot tray or
or what now the re the way this setup
works is it's all contained in buckets
so oh okay there's the reservoir and
then what you have called the brain
bucket and it has a few floats and
sensors in it and it just has lines at
the very bottom of the bucket so the
brain bucket which what it's called the
main bucket that feeds all your plant
buckets it will fill up to whatever
level you set it with the float and then
through the outlets in the very bottom
of that bucket it just leaks out through
the force of gravity and whatever level
this brain bucket is everything just
sort of settles out at that same level
and then when it's time to drain back to
the reservoir there's one pump in the
brain bucket that sort of sucks all the
water back from all of the plant buckets
and pumps it back to the reservoir got
it okay so it's a little bit different
than the traditional style ebb and flow
system where you have a a flood tray
yeah usually you might have like a table
like you're describing and you could
just flood the whole table let that sit
there for a while and then just let
gravity drain the whole table out
exactly but this way you have a little
more flexibility with your layout so I
could go maybe different different
shapes or wider than a tray might allow
me to go without having to buy a new
tray you know because with this I have a
30 gallon Reservoir that I only really
fill up to about 25 gallons full but
with this one brain bucket if I had like
a 60-gallon reservoir I could run you
know two dozen plant sites plant buckets
from that one brain bucket that's
awesome seems like you get some good
flexibility doing it that way yeah it
seems really cool I've never really
expanded it to more than four plants cuz
I've never really run this system in
anything bigger than a 5x5 but all if I
ever want to all I have to do is grab a
few more buckets and a few more beat of
rubber hose nice is this been on your
channel yet do you have videos of this
setup or maybe on your Instagram or no
no we've been running through it a
little bit on our live streams recently
but the
last grow series I did we were still in
Coco that was The Beginner's grow Guide
Series then I ran a 5x5 with the hydren
and the hydro setup like we've been
talking about in my kitchen and I did
end up filming the whole thing even
though it was sort of just to film it
cuz it was funny I'm growing a 5x5 tent
in my active kitchen that I also cook
dinner and eat in every day but I never
got around to uh eding it together I had
a bad habit of just filming the footage
and letting it sit in a folder thinking
you know I'll get to that one day and
now it's just gigabytes and gigabytes of
plant stuff and I need to find all these
notes and put it all together but I've
never put it out on the channel yet but
I'm gearing up right now setting up a
new grow space that I want to try a few
different kinds of I want to try like a
drip feed from the top too instead of a
flood and drain I want to try um I don't
know I want to try some new stuff so I'm
setting up some new growth spaces right
now so 2025 will hopefully have a lot of
hydroponics on the channel that's
awesome yeah I can totally relate when
you say that you you film all the
footage and then you never get around
editing it oh my gosh I have filmed
dozens of videos that never actually
made it to to YouTube Un unfortunately
because you know I don't think a lot of
viewers really understand how long it
takes to edit especially with a grow
video because
just the time involved you're looking at
at least four months of footage yep even
if you only go take a few Clips every
day that still so many shots yeah it's
it really is so getting into lighting
next what type of Lights do you use and
is there a certain amount of par that
you aim for freeer plants um I'm always
running uh LED lights it doesn't I
really don't have like a brand loyalty
to any specific LED
lights I know when I was first getting
into the legal industry I saw a lot of
places and I still do see a lot of
places running these big double-ended
12200 wat watt high pressure sodium
bulbs and they get so incredibly hot and
they use so much
energy it just doesn't make sense to me
why all of these facilities don't switch
over to LEDs especially with the LED
technology we have now like people are
growing amazing plants with LEDs so I
really like the LED I really like
any any light that I can take the
ballast off of the light and mount it
outside of the tent I really love those
cuz I like to uh shoot for lower Temps
at the end of flower especially if I
have something that has those really
pretty anthocyanins and I'm really
trying to bring that color change
out and uh as far as for like uh
par I really like anything I'm really
looking for that sweet spot of something
that can reach like a th micro moles per
meter squared per second I think is the
measurement yep ppfd
so I'm looking for that Center of that
heat map of the light and that's where
my eye always goes to First is it
hitting a TH or is it not because I know
especially like we were saying sometimes
if you're running
CO2 I feel like I can push the plant
harder with more lumens I can push it a
little harder with uh more heat I can
push it a little harder with nutrients
because it's just that CO2 is helping it
photosynthesize more efficiently
and uh I feel like if I want that really
bright light I would always rather have
more light than I need because you can
always turn it
down but if I get into the end of flower
and I feel like I don't have enough well
now I'm stuck with the light that I've
got yeah I completely agree being able
to dim it down it also increases the
lifespan of the fixture running it at a
lower percentage there yeah for sure
when you're not having to run it at a
100% all day every day yep so do you do
you know what brand and model like you
have in your 5x5 or the
5x5 was a spider farmer SE 7000 which is
a really nice light I really like it a
lot it's big and um it's bright but the
the ballast comes off so that was
helpful and it never gave me any
problems at all I actually just gifted
that light to a homie on the Discord so
I hope they're growing some good plants
with it now yeah that's nice of you yeah
spider farmer is a very popular brand
they've been around for so long now 10
plus years I know a lot of people run
their lights I had a handful of their
lights in the past and I used to do par
tests back in the day I think 2019 2020
and uh I had my hands on a bunch of
their fixtures and I used a couple of
their fixtures the
sp2000 I used SP 4000 see when they were
on the SP I don't even think I was
familiar with their products when they
were on the SP line I don't I don't even
know if I've heard of those
yeah I think I got it right but they
change up the line you know like the
acronyms for the line every few
years so I'm always getting confused but
I do see like even in the Discord
Community uh I see a lot of people in my
Discord running spider farmer lights and
all kinds of spider fer gear I'm sorry I
meant SF 2000 SF 4000 not SP yeah I
misspoke sorry it's been a long time
since I ran those
lights yeah but that's how they do they
will throw in a SP they'll throw in aill
SFS and they'll throw in SP and you'll
be like hold up what's the SP what is
sp yeah those are the board style that
they have I think they still sell it
today and then everybody's going after
the bar style which is the SE series
that that you had and I think that has a
lot better light spread provides that
light spread more even light spread
across across the coverage area having
that hot spot in the middle and then
having it drop off significantly towards
the outer edges that's kind of a thing
of the past now luckily uhhuh it's not
ideal at all and I also like the open
design of having these open bars rather
than a big hunk of like some kind of
plate because now all of that heat that
comes off your dodes it can just go
straight up between your bars instead of
having to make its way linger around
right at the top of your canopy until it
can eventually get blown by a fan and
make its way around that big board to
get up to your exhaust fan and make it
out true I know some of the heat does go
through the actual fixture it's kind of
like a heat sink so it does actually go
through it and and upwards and oh yeah
that's a good point too A lot of them
have like heat fins all over the top
yeah man there was some crazy designs
back in the day for for those things
yeah so heat is that an issue where you
are at um kind of let's get into
environment a little bit temperature
what do you typically aim for I'm
usually going for like a low around 75
maybe a high around like sometimes I'll
let I'll let some plants go like you
know high 80s uh like I'm not scared
when I have a a lot of CO2 in the tent
I'm not scared to see 90 89 90 if the
plant looks healthy I have my little um
infr
red thermometer so I can put the uh
laser on a leaf and see what my leaf
surface temp is and as long as the leaf
surface temp isn't crazy high I'm don't
really mind running hot and then I tried
to not well and that that's is with
supplemented
CO2 and then for my nighttime temps I
try not to
swing I really never want to swing more
than 15 from day to night and I really
like to keep it more to like
10 and if I want to go colder at night
I like to start dropping down in the
daytime too I'm really always thinking
about like what is the plant evolved to
like over Millennia of growing
outdoors and in the end of the season
you're going to get colder tempts in the
day and the night so a lot of times I'll
try to mimic that same thing indoors and
that can have so many benefits I know Dr
Bruce bugby had mentioned oh jeez it was
years ago now where he had he had
revealed that a lot of people are
dropping the temps late and flower in
order to conserve the tpin that are
there you as I actually recently watched
one of your videos you were talking
about how the tpin can volatize
evaporate you lose them in the air right
the higher the temp I think it was a
curing video that that you were talking
about that uh in particular but that's
true when you're growing the plant as
well now a lot of people will open up
their grow tent or or open up their room
and they're like ah it smells beautiful
in here but they're running too high of
attempt so they're losing all that those
Turpin off the plan it's going into the
air yeah that all would have been in
your curing jar if your temp would have
been lower and I think some of these can
start to volatize and evaporate at as
low as like 70 like just regular
standard what you would consider a cool
comfortable room so if you're thinking
about these things trying to survive
right under this light and they're 6 in
away and they're
96 with no air flow they don't have a
chance they're doing everything can just
to survive cooking off those dry combs
at those High temps yeah yeah so like Dr
bugby had mentioned is people drop it
down to about 75 fenhe 78 degrees Fen
some people go lower than that and just
to translate to the folks who Us in
Celsius 75 degrees fhe is 23 C and then
you had mentioned you go sometimes up to
85 which is 29 C so just wanted to
convert that over for the folks that are
working in celsius instead of f night
thanks for that I would had no idea what
the conversion is okay so that's daytime
and nighttime temps and you mentioned
your running CO2 how about relative
humidity what do you typically aim for
there in the beginning of um veg I'm
trying like when I have a really small
seedling I'm trying to do whatever I can
I might even put a little Dome over it
I'm trying to get maybe
65% or more and as I'm going through veg
that's going to eventually taper off and
level out to maybe around 55 60 uh%
relative humidity I have a big chart on
the wall that shows you where your ideal
VPD range is uh at whatever specific
temp you are for whatever desired kilop
Pascal range and I'm always trying to
reference that chart nowadays um and get
the VPD dialed in and uh it always seems
to
feel if I was going for off my gut I
think I would always run the ENT a
little drier than what this VPD chart
tells me but I've just been going with
it um and the plants like it they like
it a little hot and sticky yeah I
typically aim for that VPD range as well
and to my surprise it's usually when I'm
looking at the temperature I'm running
and the humidity I I naturally used to
run before I even knew about VPD it fell
within that VPD range the ideal range on
those char there's different colors
right the dark green is the optimal
range and then there's a light green
which are really the tolerance range or
acceptable range to be in so it's a
little bit wider and then you have the
yellow range or even red some of them
have red ranges and that's like gives it
I'm sorry to cut you off but that's that
relates directly to how efficient this
plant is going to be at using nutrients
because if it's not able to transpire
properly at the rate it needs to well
then it's not going to draw up
water in the rate it needs to or at the
rate that it could 100% now I've seen a
lot of new folks that are beginners and
they get caught up with it they uh
struggle with running those higher
humidities CU often time it runs a
little bit higher of a humidity it calls
on the VPD chart for a little bit higher
of humidity than what some people are
traditionally used to here a lot of
people that say oh I run around 40%
relative humidity in flowering or some
people run 50% in Edge well depending on
the temperature that could potentially
be a little bit outside of that optimal
range now it's still within the
tolerance range so the planet is still
going to grow but some people do aim to
be in that dark green range at all times
and know these plants a lot of these
medicinal plants they will they'll put
up with a lot and they'll still grow and
they'll take you all the way to harvest
and if you never knew to try something
else you might not even see a sign that
they could do much better until you
tried that I agree I grow in the desert
here and there's been times where I
really didn't monitor VPD or humidity at
all this was before YouTube back in 2011
2012 before I started watching YouTube I
should say I was running 30% humidity
35% humidity the whole grow and the
plants still grow and I still got to
harvest yeah and and you'll never know
that oh man maybe my plants would have
been a lot cooler if I would have uh
paid PA attention to that because you
got done and you're like wow these look
amazing yeah exactly and it could have
been so much better yeah uh humidity is
one thing that is a little tricky for me
here in Denver just like it is for you
in Vegas I assume because it's just dry
here it's just super dry here so to get
this high humidity I'm always running a
humidifier and the the Hydroponics does
help a lot because say I'm in the 5x5
I'm running a little high temp and I
have five five gallon buckets in the
tent that fill up you know a majority of
the way full of water or I mean four of
them so for a lot of the portion of the
day there's 20 gallons of water just
like open to the air in the tent so that
helps a lot which was great until this
last 5x5 run it came up like it was
going to be just so happens the last few
weeks of flower I was going to be out of
town and I didn't really have anyone who
knew what they were doing to watch the
plants that could really you know play
it by ear and make adjustments I just
had to say when the water gets low add
some more water please um make sure the
house doesn't catch on fire I'll be back
as soon as I can but that humidity from
those buckets just from that even with
my exhaust fan set on 10 they said this
exhaust fan didn't go off the whole time
you were out of town
but it just couldn't get it down enough
which really surprised me in Colorado
and I ended up getting Bud rot and like
the majority of my bigger chunkier uh
Bud sites I had Bud rot
and it was it was really surprising but
it was a big learning curve that I
didn't really think about I'm
introducing 20 gallons of water into
this grow tent right under a hot lamp
that's a lot of water that's a lot of
humidity that I'm going to have to deal
with and if I'm just exhausting it out
into my lung room and sucking it right
back up into the tent that humidity
never had a chance to go anywhere so I
end up having to use a uh I think I'm
going to use a twoin one
dehumidifier slac unit if I have to to
fight that on my next round it's really
shocking how much of an impact it has on
the humidity I had the same thing my dwc
system I don't even need to run a
humidifier in this grot because the
plant's just transpiring and it's
raising up that humidity so quickly and
then the exhaust kicks on a certain when
it reaches a certain point and it
exhausts the air out of there that that
humid air in there and it brings in that
dry air that I have naturally here in my
house yeah now also it's true for auto
watering systems so just going from
handw watering soil for example going to
an auto watering system whether it be a
auto poot system or I running blue mats
it's the same thing you you have that
constant moisture level in there the
plants able to take up water and
transpire and it raises the whole
humidity a lot of people run into the
problem where U lights off they realize
that lights off all of a sudden the
plant is transpiring like crazy the
humidity just spikes up and that's where
a lot of people they'll end their light
cycle and they open up their tent and
they'll they'll start to see powdery
mildew because of their unbeknownst to
this humidity Spike during lights off so
yeah it it's very surprising I was very
shocked when I first encountered that
it's helpful for me because I don't have
to fill my humidifier as
much yeah it's really nice it was a
shock though cuz I thought like you know
I thought this is going to be I thought
about the humidity but I didn't like I
really underestimated it I thought this
is going to be nice you know I'm filling
my humidifier less and my brother called
me I'm in Texas at the time and my
brother called me and he was like hey
man this humidity is like above what you
wrote down where it should be and the
fan just won't go off I was like well
you can open the door during lights on
but at night like I don't know what you
can do without me there like I would
have to Workshop this in front of the
tent and so I guess just to do what you
can and I'll be home soon man that's
rough yeah and that's one of the
importance and and Lessons Learned I
guess of if you can exhaust outside of
the room entirely don't just dump it
into your lung room now some people can
get away with it but uh traditionally a
lot of people have to resort to either
drilling a hole in their wall to get it
out to a whole different room or
exhausting it out a window for example
but yeah getting that air that's what
I'm trying to set up for the new room I
absolutely it's a must for me I'm going
to have to exhaust every tent out of the
house and I'm probably going to pull in
uh or at least have the option to
whenever I want flip on a and pull in
room I mean air from outside of the
house also so I can get the old air out
the new Air in but it's a little
different when you're running um CO2
because I also don't just if I want if I
can avoid it I don't want to just dump
all my CO2 straight out of the window
yes and that's I think where a lot of
people steer themselves the wrong way is
they'll supplement CO2 but then they'll
have their inline fan kick on and
exhaust it all out of the grow space
yeah so let's get into Co a little bit
deeper here how do you supplement CO2
using the tanks or you using one of the
other methods before um I've used I've
never tried the little cans but I have
tried the um uh what are they called I
can't remember the name but the little
uh mycelium
bags I've had those I've ran them more
than they recommend you to run them like
more in my space than they say you
need and it seemed like for me
personally in my limited experience I
could never really get the PPM of CO2 I
was looking for I think the highest I
ever got with three of those bags in a
5x5 tent was like 860
PPM so now I have got I just run a 20 lb
tank I have a 20 lb tank right outside
of my tent I have a automatic controller
that goes in the tent there's a little
fan in that controller that's always
pulling air through the box and getting
a CO2 rating on on it and I can set my
high and low and so then if I set my low
to say 800 and my high to
1,400 as soon as the CO2 dips below 800
the electronic valve will open and that
tank will start leaking out CO2 it's
just piped in through a little small air
hose this run right to the very top of
my tent because the CO2 is really heavy
so I run it up top the goal is to have
it fall down and as it's falling through
the canopy
all these fans towards the bottom of the
tan are just going to keep it moving all
around the leaf surfaces so they can
just use it all the time because your
Leaf can really only use the CO2 that is
like right there touching the leaf
surface on the top and the bottom so I
always want to be moving it around but
after you get it set up after I have
this set up it was a little expensive
the setup the controller is a little
expensive the valve isn't very expensive
but the electronic controller is and
that first CO2
tank I think was close to 200 bucks but
the way it works is it's just an
exchange program so now every time I
want to go get more CO2 I just take my
empty tank to the um grow shop drop it
off and pick up a new one like they
don't like refill it or anything they
have full ones there waiting on you and
that price to refill that is very very
small like um I'm paying like a under I
think it's like $15 I can't remember
exactly it's so small that I don't even
know the exact price because usually
when I add it to whatever else I'm
getting from the grow store like I can't
I'm not sure how much it costs you know
it under 20 bucks is all I
know but for the potential that you can
get in your growth um and not just your
growth because it's not always about
biomass it's not always always about
plant
size to me I like the CO2 really because
it makes my plant it just seems to make
the plant more hearty in every way I can
imagine it seems to make it more
resilient to Drought stress more
resilient to heat stress more resilient
to Pest and
pathogens and if I can get faster plant
growth that's always great even if I'm
not going for a bigger plant always like
to get to harvest vest you know quicker
if I can save a little time that's
always great it gives me time to start a
new round it's super beneficial I know
there's a study out of Utah State
University where they ran, 1400 PPM in
the flowering stage and they got a 30%
increase in yield I saw that I saw um
that I think it was debacco University
covered that on his YouTube channel and
when you see those
pictures of those plants you're like
well that's clear that's clear as day
that's the clearest thing I've ever seen
like there's no way I'm going to it's
when you realize it and for me it was
really like what really made me look
into it is when I realized how many of
these big commercial
facilities might cut Corners to save
money here and there and there and there
and they're cutting Corners to save
money wherever they can but never ever
ever on the CO2 the CO2 is running all
day every day really high 1,400 1500
ppms and it's because they've seen it
it's because they've had a room that had
a few hundred plants in it and then they
had a room right beside it with a few
hundred plants in it and they only had
enough CO2 one round to run it in one
room and they saw the difference in
these two rooms and they were like okay
that was huge that was a that was 30%
more money came out of the same size
room we can never make that mistake
again yeah so super beneficial a lot of
uh a lot of good can come out of it
although it is a uh upfront cost you
mentioned $200 for the tank to begin
plus hundreds of dollars for the
controller valve all that stuff but pays
for itself pretty quickly there yeah I
think so are you running it daytime only
a lot of people will we just do CO2 in
the daytime and they'll say ignore it
during night time yeah um the controller
I have is actually set up to run exactly
that way so it has it's monitoring two
things at the same time the first one is
the fan that pulls the air through and
reads the actual ppms of the CO2 the
second thing is just a little light
monitor right on the front of the
controller box so and you put that
inside of your tent and so anytime there
isn't a very bright light source like if
your grow light isn't turned on then
that thing just defaults to stay off all
night long so all during the night or
all during lights off it's not putting
out any CO2 at all and then as soon as
the lights come on in the morning it
just starts all over again pretty
straightforward there one thing to
mention about those tanks talking to uh
what I call a buddy of mine Chris from
Happy Hydro he was on the podcast
actually twice now and one of the things
he had mentioned is when he was running
CO2 actually I think he I think the
story had to do with this buddy running
a CO2 and getting a tank from the gross
store well he ended up getting a pest
infestation from that tank now I don't
know if this is just a a a one-off
instance but having I think he got
spider mites I don't know know how they
were attached to the tank but he brought
that in without cleaning the tank or
whatever and then U and then his garden
got infested so I don't know what the
odds are what the chances of that
happening but uh fig I'd mention that
here in case anybody else uh is getting
those tanks you might want to consider
cleaning it off to to prevent pest from
coming in and I've never um actually
done that but I have had the thought
before because I've been in the grow
store hearing someone talk about having
pest at home and I looked over at them
like oh man we're in the same building
right now the pest might have came from
your cuz like if you're in the garden
and they're on your clothes and then you
come to the grow store with all these
you know ornamental plants and all this
soil to live in it's like a pest dream
and they can just live in there and hit
Chik home on your on your sleeve or on
your CO2 tank that's scary happens more
than we know it I'm sure so getting into
pests a little bit more have you ever
come across any major pest infestations
luckily I've never come across any major
pest infestations at home in my personal
grow I've had pretty decent outbreaks of
fungus knats a couple of times but those
were pretty easily gotten under control
with just some yellow sticky traps and
some dious Earth on the top of my soil
but working in the legal like commercial
space
face I have seen I've seen things that
look like the movie Arachnophobia with
spiderm I've seen thrips so thick that
it makes you want to crawl out of your
skin I've seen so many worst case
scenarios I've seen rooms with you know
pm and stuff that make it look like it's
snowing when you shake the plants and so
I've always been since day one when I
started my first Garden at home I've
always been super duper scared of that
cross-contamination from the commercial
facility to my little home Garden cuz if
I bring I look at the bugs and the past
especially these
spiderm in the commercial space as like
super mites because you got to think
they come from a colony of like 40
million maybe 40 billion we have
multiple multiple rooms each room has
Maybe 100 a few hundred maybe a thousand
plants and it's all like a big budget
commercial grow they're running around
spraying their IPM and trying their best
to kill them so the ones that survived
all of that are the strongest of the
strong and they've lived in all these
environments they were born and bred
inside they they come from indoor
gardens so I feel like if I get these
little suckers in my
house that I'll never get rid of of them
cuz the infestations I see at work like
usually when I see these infestations
like the ones I'm talking about you just
open the door and you immediately see
webbing across a whole grow room there's
nothing you can do for that and I've
spent uh I've spent days pre Harvest is
trying to do physical removal it's far
too late into the grow cycle to use a
chemical but I'll be going through with
a wet paper towel or a rag or something
trying to wipe the the nugs off before
we go to harvest and it's just there's
nothing you can do when it gets that far
I think it's prevention is key so when I
come home I always quarantine my clothes
I will take my clothes off outside way
as far away from my grow space as I can
and I put those in a bag and I seal that
bag up and they stay in that bag until
they go to the laundry mat no chances
it's a smart way to go about it I'm glad
that you haven't had any major pest
festations that you brought from the uh
the commercial facility there that
you've only come across fungus Nets and
be able to get rid of them pretty easy
that that's good to hear pest can be a
challenge there are a lot of challenges
that can occur really not just with pest
but with different parts of growing EB
and flow system can you talk to us about
some of the common issues or challenges
that new Growers May face when using an
EB and flow system oh I think one of the
most common issues cuz I'm still new to
the EB and flow system so I think May
maybe some of these beginner problems I
haven't even faced yet so they're like
um right around the corner probably for
me find some new problems I haven't seen
one really common one is it's really
easy to forget that right behind you
this Reservoir has 30 gallons of water
in it and you forget how the properties
of siphoning and gravity work and if the
tip of this hose goes below the surface
level of that water and I turn my back
on it for two seconds I might have 20
gallons of water in the
floor then you have like things like pH
drift and I'm really not that's one
thing I'm looking forward to finding out
what are the common problems I know some
people run into issues with getting
their system clogged or dirty or maybe
running they're trying to run too many
organic nutrients or just stuff that
gets gunky in the lines but I really am
not sure what my problems are going to
be so far in my
experience I found that as long as I
keep my EC and my PPM dialed in in that
Reservoir that's the main thing that I'm
worrying about really this flood and
drain system has been a dream it's been
so easy for me and I don't want to curse
myself but it's been very very
hassle-free I haven't really had much of
any problems to speak of and the plants
just grow so fast and they grow so big
they have
like such constant almost constant
availability to nutrients I'm happy that
it's been so easy for you you know
you're saying those words and I feel the
same way about deep tic culture I grew
in soil for 14 years and I just did my
first run actually have it in flowering
here in a 2x4 and it's been so easy sure
there's a little stumbled at first
trying to figure things out getting the
pH kind of dialed in the EC water
temperature is another thing that that I
look at but once you figure those things
out it's been so easy for me for most of
the grow because of all that so yeah I
feel the same way about my hydroponic
system that you feel about yours are you
running any uh beneficial bacteria in
your uh flood and drain I mean in your I
mean in your deep water culture no just
the nutrients in there with an AirStone
that's it same here awesome so as we get
towards the end of the episode here one
of the questions I like to ask folks is
can you name off the top three strains
that you've grown and what you liked
about them let me see I haven't grown
too many at home but let me try to think
of something that we're at home one that
I really liked was uh Kush mins from
exotic genetics it was uh really dense
really pretty really nice crazy uh dark
purple Hues flavorful real nice it was
very
photogenic uh the Money Ball which is
the one I did in the flood and drain
down in the kitchen here
that was from uh oh the first one I said
Kush was from exotic that was actually
from
ethos the Money Ball was exotic genetics
that was a Gary Payton Gary Poppins
cross and that one was just super super
Frosty it had some really big nugs that
I lost to Bud rot but it was so Frosty
and then another one that was amazing
was one called orange herana that we
used to grow in this uh commercial
facility worked in probably one of the
has to be one of the top three craziest
smelling tarpine profiles I've ever
smelled before it smells like just pure
candy it does not smell like a plant at
all it smells like a sugar purple
candy very nice though and huge huge fat
nugs on it I'll have to check those out
I haven't grown any of those and yeah
this is a question that I've just
actually started asking about I don't
know half a dozen episodes or so and
seems like the audience really likes to
hear about what their favorite genetics
are and I've had some people in the
comments are like yeah I just picked
some up because I'm so stoked of what
I've heard you know about it blah blah
blah so thanks for sharing that oh of
course so wrapping things up here can
you tell the listeners how they can find
you and what you have upcoming in the
future I got a few different series
coming up about growing we're going to
do some more growing tips I'm going to
document some of uh my
hydro experiences coming up very soon
that's what we're starting off 2025 with
and that's all on my YouTube channel
just youtube.com/ Strow there we go
pretty straightforward I'll definitely
have a link to Matt's Channel down in
the YouTube description section below
and I also do a pinned comment as well
so you can easily get to his channel and
give him a subscription thank you buddy
want to give a big thanks to the folks
on patreon
patreon.com grow the folks that being
scrolled on the screen right now are in
the producer tier special thanks to you
you help keep this podcast going what
questions you have have on the EB and
flow system and what tips do you have
growing hydroponically let us know down
in the comments section below I love
reading through it because there are
really so many different ways to go
about it there's so many different Hydro
systems and people tend to do things
differently from system to system so
yeah drop down in the comments section
below let us know how you do things well
Matt thanks so much for coming on to the
podcast man really appreciate it good
talk thanks for having me on man it was
an honor to come on the show no problem
man hope to do it again sometime in the
future and hope to link up again in the
future dude MJ biscon was awesome it was
cool to chill and smoke and yeah Good
Vibes all around dude for sure we'll
have to link up next time I'm out in
Vegas sounds good man all right
everybody peace out catch you in the
next episode