what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr growit and i'm back with another
video got an announcement video for you
today
all good things come to an end and today
i want to announce the end of par tests
on this channel
it's definitely been a long journey but
i think it is for the best
in this video i'll explain why i got
into part test to begin with
why i'm stopping them and also i'm going
to refer you to some other channels that
do part tests
so first off why did i get into part
test to begin with well for me i know
when i'm looking for grow light
one of the things i like to look at is
par output so how much
par that grow light is emitting and you
can look on grow light listings a lot of
them do include a part
chart which it shows uh kind of the
footprint
overview and then it shows different
ppfd numbers across that footprint
some of the problems that i found with
that is that some companies only list
one light distance so when you move that
light to other light distances you're
kind of guessing to what the power
output is
also i found that some companies inflate
their numbers so
what they're actually showing on that
part chart is inflated it's higher
than what actually the par meter that
i'm using is showing
and i've also found that some grow light
companies only list the middle
dead center number so you don't really
know what that light spread is across
the footprint so
i decided to start doing par test videos
where i mean most of you have seen them
i basically take a par meter
and run it across the grow space and
show you what the different ppfd
measurements are
across that grow space and that provides
value because
those who have that grow light get a
better idea of what the grow
light distance should be at the
different stages of growth for example
so it's honestly been pretty fun doing
that you know i got to get my hands on a
bunch of different grow lights
got to talk with a bunch of different
companies and build relationships there
and over the past year i've done 41 par
tests on this channel alone
actually did one part test on my main
youtube channel so 42 total part tests
which is
kind of crazy looking back at it so
that's the reason why i got into them in
the first place
i know that there are people out there
that want to see this information and
this information wasn't out there
so why stop i decided to stop because
it really it's very time consuming to do
these part tests
you know from talking with the brands
having them send it over to me
unboxing it filming it editing
and most of the time i actually didn't
get paid anything for it they would
let me keep the grow light and i would
have to you know the only way really to
earn money was to resell the grow light
there was a few times where i did get a
small amount of money for doing the part
tests but
it was very very rare i think i maybe
got paid maybe two or three times out of
those 42 videos
anyways the money isn't something that i
really cared about
what i care about more is my time i
found that doing these part tests
really took up a lot of time and i
didn't put out nearly as many videos on
growing plants as i wanted to
i was prioritizing part tests filming
editing those
and then it would come time to film my
plants and edit videos for my main
channel
and i didn't have that time so now since
i'm not doing them anymore
i will be able to spend more time
filming and editing videos on plants
now there are several people who do part
tests on youtube so
since i don't do them anymore i'm going
to refer you to three people who do do
them
the second channel that i want to refer
you to is migrow
shane over at migrow he owns micro
lighting
and he does part tests on his channel
not just for his lights
but he does do them for uh several
lights his entire channel is grow light
information
so he's definitely very knowledgeable he
goes in depth about
the part tests and he gives you an
honest opinion on the part test so
some of you may say oh he's he owns a
lighting company
he's biased towards his own lights watch
his videos and you'll see that that's
really not the case last channel i want
to refer you to that does par test
is dr mj coco he just started doing part
test this year i think he probably has
like let's see two
four seven different part tests on his
channel
he talks about all the features in the
video shows you the part test results
and then he also has a grow like
calculator which he can calculate you
enter in the
power draw the cost of light the ppf of
the light
then it's going to output what the
photon efficiency is
what the cost efficiency is and then
what the harvest potential is
so lots of good information that he is
showing to his audience and really
this is going to give you more
information in order to make a smarter
buying decision
there are so many grow lights on the
market today it is so easy to get caught
up
and not know what's good versus bad
there are some companies out there that
are selling lights that are three
four five years old that are nowhere
near as efficient
as the grow lights that came out this
year and last year so if you want to
stay up to date on led grill lights
subscribe to these three guys i will
leave a link to their channels down in
the description section below
so what's going to be on this channel
then well i'm going to continue with the
topic videos
i'm going to do more one-on-one
discussion videos with other growers
and also anything else that might not
fit on my main youtube channel so yeah
that's pretty much all i wanted to cover
in this video
i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next
time peace
you