coming up on garden talk in the flower
tent i usually have some type of net
some type of netting in my flower tents
so if a plant gets into
that tent and it's like really starting
to get too big i'll kind of bend it over
using
that netting my pot sizes when i'm
flowering they
vary from like i guess the three gallon
to a five gallon just depending on
the strain that's in there i feel like
i'm that grower that's like
borderline i almost break every rule
possible or try to come as close to it
you know
if you get a strain it's great at
growing in the desert and you bring it
to
somewhere where it's damp and humid you
probably gonna mess that strain up
making everything as simple as possible
for you because let's face it at the end
of the day
gardening is not your life it's a part
of your life but you have other stuff to
do you know
you don't want to spend your whole time
sitting there babysitting literally
watching the grass grow
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 14.
in this episode i interview mr sparks a
lot he is a youtuber with over 3000
subscribers
and he's been gardening for five years
he grows citrus trees
leafy greens herbs and medicinal plants
in this episode we talk about
indoor gardening in small grow tents or
this is really for small spaces in
general don't forget to hit that thumbs
up button
and subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already if you're listening to
this podcast on one of the podcast
platforms such as apple podcasts
please leave a rating and review we're
actually up to about 35 ratings on apple
podcasts
so thank you so much to those 35 people
who have taken the time to
leave a review on there it really helps
out the podcast tremendously and if
you're liking these episodes and want to
support the podcast even more
you can do that through patreon the link
to that is patreon.com
mr growit and if you're watching this on
youtube i'll leave a link down in the
description section below
i hope you enjoyed this episode let's
get into it
all right mr sparks a lot welcome to
garden talk how you doing today
so far so good man hanging in there bro
i woke up this morning so i'm blessed
you know
like my hats say
[Laughter]
nice well i'm definitely glad that you
uh were able to tune in to the podcast
today
join us today we've actually been
talking for uh quite a while now i feel
like it's been several years
since we kind of first found out about
each other online
uh you know you have a youtube channel i
have a youtube channel and i know you
tuned into my live streams a couple
times
i tuned into your live streams a couple
times so here we are finally talking
face to face through video chat so
appreciate your time today yes the
the world has bumped us into each other
once again so
for those that don't know who you are
can you tell us a little bit about
yourself and
how you got into gardening i'm a small
pretty much home closet grower i guess
for the most part um
i pretty much started in nevada like
when
we went recreational out here and it was
kind of legal for me to grow
so to speak i mean when i first started
it was kind of still in the gray
area-ish
but um after it went wreck
or before i went wreck i got my medical
but once it went wreck out here stuff
kind of got a little bit more lenient so
i kind of started growing just to i
guess get my feet wet a little bit but
shortly after i started growing i
started reading a little bit more up on
different
strains medicinal strains and
um kind in hopes to find i guess
for my mother like she's got some health
issues and
at one point in time she was on around
seven or eight different medications
and i started making her
um like oil or i would make her edibles
and whatnot
and she would use that and pretty much
alleviate
her she got rid of the majority of the
prescriptions that she was taking so
it just kind of made me feel good to be
able to produce something
you know you could almost say in your
own backyard i don't have a backyard
in my closet in this instance but like
you know when you can grow something
kind of on-site or produce something on
site that's
not necessarily chemically altered and
you know i'm not in the science code
with the beakers and everything
sitting up messing with nature so to
speak you know
i don't know it just makes me feel good
so i've been pretty much
in love with it ever since and
here i am now i guess i i wish i had
more space you know one of these days
hopefully i'll get
be able to kind of i guess expand or
at least upgrade a little bit but
for my space in area i just kind of make
do with what i have you know
take it from there nice
nice and now you have a youtube channel
i know you've been doing it since 2016 i
believe
you have over 3 000 subscribers so uh
that's awesome congrats on that one
i know you do like live streams you do
chill smoke seshes
garden updates so you get a variety of
things on your channel
um and for those that are watching this
or tuned in to youtube in particular
i'll leave a link to his channel down in
the description section below
and if you're on one of the podcast
platforms such as apple podcast or
spotify
just go to youtube and type in mr sparks
a lot
it's spelled s-p-a-r-k-z-a-l-o-t
and then you'll be able to find his
channel and check out what he has there
so before we get into the nitty-gritty
on your grow 10 setup
and growing in small spaces
you know i really want to first address
what you have
as your primary goals right so everybody
has their goals before they grow
if you talk to me eight to 10 years ago
i would have told you my primary goal
was to
obtain as high of a yield as possible
that's not everybody's goal right i
think some people jump to the assumption
that everybody's goal is a high yield
that's not really
the case for everybody these days i'm
focused mostly on simplicity
how do i make things easier in the
garden and i've also been focusing on
efficiency so reducing that electrical
consumption
what would you say your goals are what
are your primary goals
for your garden when i first started off
i was kind of like you i think i wanted
that
i was just pushing for uh
two things i think i wanted to save
myself some money you know as far i
wouldn't have to go out and buy that bag
as much you know so to speak or
that my main goal is just i guess you
you know to try to get as much as i
could
and um over the years i've
kind of strayed away from that for the
most part especially
trying to work more with like medicinal
strains and trying to
kind of zone in on the strength of my
mother it's been more just like
quality for me for the most part um
viewed i mean yield is good but if you
have a pound of something it's like
compared to you know a half a pound or a
quarter pound
of something that's a1 or you know top
notch
and i guess it's all up to the person at
the end of the day you know but
overall now my my
my overall i guess expectation out of
the garden is just like my
quality for the most part and to make
sure everything you know kind of just
runs smoothly um
fortunately like i started growing
around the led era
so i i didn't have to go through the hps
and the
hid and all these extra other lights
that you know the old school growers
went through kind of
with them higher electricity bills and
honestly
i haven't like grown with leds for the
most part i really haven't seen like a
super
jump in my electricity bill in general
um but as i said
you know i don't run a huge goal either
so to speak
so you know if if
i guess it got to the point to where my
electricity was kind of getting out of
hand you know i would
kind of keep that in mind that hey i
need to kind of
make this as efficient as possible
because
ironically as the times are going on and
you know as more places legalized like
the cost of stuff is going down a lot
and you know in some instances it almost
might be easier for and i'm not trying
to discourage anybody from growing but
if you're paying more in electricity
and you know items for your grow and
more to keep up with it then it would
cost you to go
to your local produce market or
dispensary or whatever
you know it kind of defeats the purpose
unless you're doing it
with a specific purpose you know such as
breeding or
you just want variety of something that
you can't get you know where you're at
at the
moment in time but i i don't know i i
feel like for the most part
i i like to concentrate on the quality
of the product you know especially
working
with strange trying to help ease my
mom's
ailments and whatnot you know i just
want her to have the best
it's like i'm trying to get her the name
brand i don't want to get her to generic
that works i want to get her you know
make the best
brand possible for the most part so
gotcha and yeah just to piggyback off of
the whole efficiency thing i mean if you
have a small grow i mean that's you're
not going to really worry much about
it as long as you you're running the
appropriate
equipment within there so kind of to get
into your growth setup you know we'll
get into the topic today which is indoor
gardening and
a small grow tent or really any small
spaces i guess you could say this
can apply to so let's talk about your
current growth setup
i know you grow in a smaller tent can
you tell me a little bit about your
setup
like what size growth space lighting
equipment you have in there so on and so
forth
well currently i i have a
two by two by two just like a square
or a cube cube for the most part um
i use that for my germinating and maybe
keeping like
starting seeds or keeping cuts around
for the most part you know sometimes
i have the problem of overgrowing
because
of my space being so confined like a lot
of times
especially some of my keepers
my mom's training in particular likes to
grow and if i don't
keep that thing trimmed it's just like
you should try to grow out of the tent
you know and there's not a lot of space
in most two by twos to grow multiple
plants you know
i mean it's it's advised to grow like
one to two plants
two is kind of pushing it in a two by
two like one plant
will give you probably the best yield as
long as you
you know kind of scrog it out or make
your canopy
nice and even as even as possible you
know but
my two by two by two is a my germination
tent
and i'm running just regular
i think it's a four bay like it was a t5
setup or t3 something like that but
i found some led bulbs for it so
that's kind of reducing the electricity
usage of the light i really haven't
noticed any
i guess yield difference in that
specific tent but we are talking about a
small
like a small area and you know the
lights not the
i forget how many watts my my little
four bay uh
light thing is but i've had it for the
longest so um
you know if it's not broke don't fix it
but outside of that um in my closet i
have two
two by two by i think they're
they're not quite six feet because i'm
taller than the tents
so they might be like five and a half or
five nine something like that
and i use one for germinating
and one for i'm not germinating
one for veg the others for flower and i
just kind of rotate you know
i i attempt to keep a perpetual girl
going
as as much as i can every once in a
while something will happen and
you know i might have to restart or
whatever you know but for the most part
i try to keep that
there's always something in a
germination tent there's always
something in beds there's always
something in flower
you know but my my primary goal is to
get it to where like
i could harvest once every other month
but i just it's like i have the schedule
and i know what to do
it just never works out for me because
it's kind of dependent on the strangest
themselves and how far along the cuts
are and everything and it's it's
it's kind of weird but like i said i
keep something in each one of those and
as far as lighting goes
i've been approached by a few different
lighting companies to you know review
lights and this and that and
i think in the veg tent right now
i'm running to mars want to say ts 600
or something of that nature
and then in my flower tent and i got the
viper specter
so they're probably if they see that
they're probably mad he can't
tell the name of our like i'm sorry i
just
i don't have it written down right now
but i do have videos for them on my
channel so you know anytime i get a
new light or something i'll do a
unboxing or a review
and if i have a promo code or anything
like that you know i'll put it all in
the description of my video
so i think both of my flower lights are
considered 1000 watt leds or whatever
so they're not the highest end
you know but they're not like the lowest
and so my yields are
fairly decent but then again i'm not
i'm not really trying to push that pound
to plant envelope you know i'm more
like i said earlier i want that the
quality i just want to clarify that when
you say a thousand watts you're talking
about the equivalent
yeah of a thousand watt hps so really
it's around 100 watts is
true wattage for some of these lights
some of these chinese manufacturers
they'll say a thousand watt
uh in the title but it'd actually be a
thousand one equivalent
so there's a lot of controversy behind
all that so
yeah but as far as
you know in a two foot by two foot grow
tent when you're flowering in there you
mentioned that
one plant sometimes two plants you think
sometimes two plants
is pushing it now when you have two
plants in there what size grow
pot do you typically use and what type
do you use the plastic
fabric idealistically i would like to
keep one plant in my flower tent but i
can't
like just because of the fact that i
like varieties and
it's a must that i keep at least one of
my mom's
plants and flower pretty much at all
times so i can kind of keep up with her
you know that i don't want to call it
medicine but her
herbal supplement so to speak you know
and um then i push the envelope with my
two by twos like i
depending on pot size a lot of times
i put anywhere from one to
maybe four plants in my 2x2 and i can
fit
four or five gallon pots you know one in
each corner
if it's is it the best decision i'm not
gonna you know i'm not telling you to do
this at home kids
this is just something that works for me
you know
and i know that it could be better if i
put that one plan in there
you know my yield might be a little bit
better
but to me it's just like i said i'm a
stickler for variety i want to
have some flavors you know i kind of get
tired of
using the same thing over and over again
i don't know if they call it burnt out
or whatever i just
i don't know i like a little bit of
variety you know that's
one of the reasons you go to the beer
island that's a million beers right
there like if we all just wanted one
type of beer in the world then there
would just be one beer but there's not
there's a variety
and i like variety so i like to keep a
couple different plants in there but
my pot sizes when i'm flowering they
vary from like
i guess the three gallons to a five
gallon just depending on
the strain that's in there some of my
strengths my mom's constraints the
heavier feeders so i usually keep that
in a five gallon
and you know some of the other strains
that i know
aren't as heavy feeders i might get away
with putting a three gallon in there and
i've had at a time three five gallons
and then two
three gallons in in my plant in my tent
so
it's like i'm a bad landlord that just
likes to pack
i need as many tenants in my garden as i
can get you know
do you do uh plastic pots or
fabric pots air pots and then are you in
soil
or cocoa or what been in soil
pretty much since i started um i've
tried coco running coco straight i've
tried running
you know like different mixtures i ran
organic
like i made a super soil
about two years ago i um
i forget the name of the book but
i think his name is the rev or something
like that
um yeah true living organics by the rev
yeah i i picked that book up a while
back and made one of the
super soils or whatever you want to call
it from in there and
in all honesty i just watered that
specific
girl and that was probably some of the
best
quality that i've ever had and
the batch of soil that i made like it
kind of cost me a little pretty penny to
get that
batch together so at the time
you know i had a lot of synthetic
nutrients you know i've had a couple
people
every time i go to the the hydro store
out here you know they're always pawning
stuff off on you here try this or this
you know giving you samples and
i know i ran general hydro brands
sweet leafs products were like i think
those are supposed to be on the organic
they're not 100 organic but it's kind of
an
organic based synthetic nutrient mine if
there is such a thing i mean there are
people that kind of argue up and down
with that nature but i pretty much tried
it all
you know just to kind of get the
experience with different
nutrients and different mediums and in
general um i've always kind of tried to
want to go
uh do a hydro girl but unfortunately i'm
in an apartment on the second floor
and i'm super paranoid about leaks and
stuff going downstairs like if i was
downstairs it'd probably be different
but
i don't want to go through all that so
until i you know either move into a
single level area where i could kind of
try that out you know it's just been
pretty much cocoa
or some type of fox farm soil or
local soil from the home depot or
whatever whatever i can kind of get my
hands on and
after a while i tried to well not try to
i try to recycle as much as my soil
as i can as well like i try to clean out
you know any root
matter or whatever and um
when i first started doing it i wasn't
flushing it so to speak so there was a
lot of build up in my soil from like
you know past girls or whatever and
i learned the hard way you know i ate up
some plants just
burnt you know burnt them by over
feeding them because i was feeding them
on top of whatever was in the soil so
you know i learned a lot of diff just
different do's and don'ts
over the years because
it doesn't matter how many books you
read at the end of the day on the
subject matter until you get your hands
in that dirt
or that water or on the plants itself
like
there's nothing like the actual
experience itself so
um but you mentioned pots too like i've
had fabric pots i've ran
i guess like netted pots um plastic pots
air i think they're air pots it's pretty
much just been trial and error with me
i like i guess if i had my choice i love
fabric pots but cleaning those things
you know especially if you're not
if you don't catch those like right
before they start to kind of grow
they're not supposed to grow through the
pot so to speak you know they're
supposed to kind of air prune
roots wise but they don't always happen
sometimes
you know i've had those pots kind of
when i um feed from the bottom or just
water like
my catch tray and let the fabric pot
soak up the water
there's been instances where i've had a
little bit too much water in the trailer
that you know a little bit of water sit
in the bottom and like the roots will
start kind of growing through the pot
like throughout the tray into the water
or whatever
so it does help with air pruning a
little bit but it doesn't like alleviate
the problem
you know and getting that plant out of
there was like a pain in the butt
because i ended up
kind of pruning the roots myself pulling
it away from the pot or whatever you
know
but i've tried to use it all man
if it's out there i want to use it see
it you know try it whether i stick with
it or not that's a whole other thing but
you know
at least i can say yeah i've tried that
product or
i've tried that method i've attempted
that you know
i've tried the like the plastic bags
from
they're okay but i've always had to put
like more holes in them because
once you feel them and they sit right
it's like there's not the drainage isn't
proper so
i don't know if they thought about that
i mean i'm sure somebody has but i don't
know maybe i should come out with my own
grow bags with enough
hoes there you go to drain properly like
i don't know innovation for sure so
when you're growing in these small
spaces right they small or
grow tents are you mostly growing
autoflowers or photoperiod
i think i've grown one autoflower in the
six
or whatever five six years that i've
been growing um
i wasn't too pleased with the yield
in general and to me
i like the photo period there's
something about that hunt
like you know popping seeds
growing the plant for a little while
trying to figure out hey is this boy is
this a girl you know like playing the
guessing game it's kind of like being
pregnant
so to speak you know not knowing if it
is it a boy is it a girl like
you know and then that kind of moment of
truth
after you flower you know start to
flower the plant out to sea or or sex
the plant
so to speak you know and that moment of
truth when you actually see it's like
getting your ultrasound what's a boy or
it's a girl you know you
you see those those female hairs or the
the the male sacks coming off the plant
you know it's
i don't know there's just something
about that that has a little bit more
allure to me
than just yeah this is going to be a
female it's going to be this strain and
you know that's that but
that's not to say that i won't ever grow
them again i just i'm having too
much fun along my journey right now with
i guess photo period you know
plants to even get to that point and
on my journey i've made a couple i think
i've made like 10 crosses
i haven't stabilized anything you know
i'm not a
quote-unquote breeder as much as i
aspire to be one like it takes time to
kind of get there you know but i've had
people ask me about
some of the crosses that i made like you
ever think about feminizing those or
making autos and
i'm not at that point yeah i get what
you mean you know 10 15 years ago
these autoflowers the genetics they
stayed pretty small so some may
say hey that's good for small spaces
these days i mean i've had some autos
that blew up
like crazy like four feet five feet
easily so
um i hear a lot of people saying that
autoflowers
are good for small spaces i don't know
if i would necessarily agree with that
photo period you get that control to
where you can keep it small
via training which we'll talk about in a
little bit and then you're able to
change that light cycle and flip the
flower
to force flowering versus the autoflower
could blow up in the first 30 days all
of a sudden you've got height issues
and you've got another three weeks of
stretch on top of that so it could be
it could get out of hand pretty crazy
but um yeah
it comes down to a preference thing i
feel like but going into
transplanting i want to talk about that
you mentioned
you're in three to five gallon
containers typically right is your final
container
i've seen your videos you typically
start out correct me from wrong you
typically
will start out in a smaller like solo
cup for example
and then i believe you transplant up do
you go directly into that three
or five gallon container or are you
going to a one gallon container
and then your final container and then
when do you typically do that
transplanting
well for the most part if it's a season
i'm not going
to be sure of the six of the plant i
usually go to
like a one gallon or i've been known to
go to like a half gallon just depending
on what i started out at
i've started out seeds like in like a
clone
tray for the most part like i feel the
cone tray
or i guess they might be propagation
trays i don't know what they're called
i'd fill those up with you know soil or
some type of median and just put seeds
in there and then kind of
with that being so small i can go into a
solo cup after that and then maybe like
a half gallon
and then a one gallon or whatever if
it's a
a clone or something and i know it's a
female or whatever i
sometimes i'll go from once it gets
rooted into the biggest pot
you know or sometimes i'll go to that
one it really just depends on the space
in my garden like this space
and what's moving around where it really
depicts on
depicts what i kind of put stuff in you
know for the most part because
i used to keep like a five gallon pot in
my veg
tent as a mother plant for my mom strain
and i ended up
like cloning the mess out of that plant
because she was getting like way too big
for the tent
and i ended up dropping that down to two
and a half gallon but now it's like i
have to
almost clone her twice as often because
ironically enough it's like i almost
feel like
she's growing faster now in a smaller
area
and she's a lot more like susceptible
to stuff going wrong like her drying out
or being over under nutrient being over
under fed so that five gallon pot to me
is like the sweet spot but
it affects my space in there so it
really just depends on
the strains that i'm running and you
know the amount of space that i have in
there
kinda i told you i'm that mean landlord
i'm trying to stick everybody in there
like sardines and
i know it affects my growth especially
with some of the
i guess circulation you know sometimes
a lot sometimes i'll get that overlap
where your leaves are
you know this plant might be kind of
overlapping the plant next to it
and as much as i don't want it to affect
that grow like your plants need as much
energy as they can from that light
with me running leds you know it's
i'm just kind of pushing it i kind of
like to push the envelope a little bit
more but
i know that like i said if i put one
plant in there i can get a bigger yield
off of it but i just try to keep as much
in there as i can so i can get you know
just kind of keep all my bases covered
but i think i went
i ran a seven gallon fabric pot one time
i think in my tent or it wasn't
something here it was a
ten i was doing offsite for one of my
partners
and i really didn't see any difference
yield wise or like size wise from
running the same plant and a five gallon
but i really didn't do a scientific i
didn't measure
both fields and you know what was being
fed and the lighting there's two
different lights so
it's possible that the bigger median
area
gave off a bigger yield you know but i
don't know i really don't see a big
difference between
the yield and like i guess when i did
that five
down and the seven gallon but i noticed
when i do
when i flower out like either two and a
half or three gallon or five gallon like
there's a big
difference in the beer you know so
like i said i just i want to try it all
but i think that's my sweet spot for the
most part is like flour i like to keep
something you know i flower out in a
five gallon
um veg is anywhere from a half gallon to
maybe a two and a half gallon pot
and then in germination you know
i think i have like some little pint
sized
pots that like you get when you go home
depot and buy your little starter
seedlings or whatever i got a bunch of
those off the show that i did a long
time ago
that some folks were getting rid of so i
kind of left up on that but
i'm almost like you whatever's around
because i've had you know i've tried so
much to everything it's
sometimes i look in my tent there's a
fabric pot of five gallon home depots
you know paint bucket that i put holes
in and
a couple plastic bags and this and that
and it's like man you have the
just to throw two garden over here but
it works you know and at the end of the
day i think that's all you can do is do
what works best for you you know
so going back to plant training
you know when you're in small spaces you
have height restrictions
you have space restrictions just in
general what do you
typically do for plant training in order
to keep those plants
you know small within that growth space
usually in the germination stage i
really don't do too much to them i mean
as their
seedlings their small cuttings i i
really don't
do too much to them um sometimes if it's
if i do have a seedling and to me i feel
it's growing a little bit too
fast i might like crop it or super crop
it whatever
cut the top nodes off once it gets past
like its
fifth set of leaves or whatever and um
i'll let it sit maybe the germination
for probably about another week before i
put in
the veg tent and in the veg tent i mean
i've
used anything from um what they call it
garden tape
like the green garden tape and kind of
you know
loosely taped around limbs and kind of
bent them down and taped it to the pot
you know if i'm using a plastic pot in
that instance um
i've used string and in the past to kind
of tie
you know branches down to kind of slow
them from growth
growing as high as fast and promoting i
guess a bushier canopy as well
and the flower tent i usually have some
type of net
some type of netting in my flower tent
so if i need
if a plant gets into that tent and it's
like
really starting to get too big i'll kind
of bend it over using
that netting um
i also use the netting for kind of
spacing and trying to just get my
i guess get every
piece of the plant just kind of spread
out so it gets that
as even as amount of lighting as
possible a lot of times like when you
grow from seed
you have that uniform kind of christmas
tree structure with the plant
and that assuming you don't top it or
anything like that you know if you do
top it
and and kind of train it a little bit
more i guess you can spread that canopy
out but
sometimes from seed i like to just let
it grow like that first run
i just let it grow to see i guess some
of the plants
[Music]
you know the the node spacing and how i
guess fast it grows
and in that case the the net really
comes in handy because i can kind of
spread
i guess the the branches and the arms of
the
you're playing out but when you
you know do other training methods as
far as i guess super cropping and low
stress training and whatnot it just
the netting in there in my flower tent
it helps i guess keep everything at bay
as well as
keep your your canopy even you know
and with some of the strains i grew a
lemon tree strain out not too long ago
and it was like super spindly almost
it wasn't a very i guess bulky type of
strain it was kind of dainty on the
dainty side i don't know if it was just
that specific
um cut or whatever but
in that case it's almost like i needed
the the netting to kind of hold the
plant up once it got so big
because the branches were like smaller
than my pinky just
small branches super thin almost wispy
like
it was crazy the flower was decent but
it
the plant structure and everything to me
it just wasn't something that
i would keep you know in my garden for
the most part especially if
i was to try to take it outside i think
that thing would probably
fly away it looked like a tumbleweed you
know
crossing the road or something out here
i hear you and what you said about the
um
topping and then low stress training
from there that's what i typically do
now
especially when i'm trying to stay in a
smaller area
i've tried so many different training
methods over the years just about
everything you know topping filming
super cropping so on and so forth but
you know when i'm trying to keep it
small in small spaces i will do that
topping
typically i'll let it grow up to like
the fifth node the third node fourth
node fifth node
then i'll top the plant sometimes
depending on growth if it has real long
inner nodes
i'll take it from the fifth node top it
down to the third node
you know what it means i will remove
some of that growth then from there i'll
allow it to grow
and i'll bend down those branches
to make sure keep it small even canopy
like you mentioned
i like how you mentioned the netting in
there as well that definitely
would help in a small space you know
bending those branches down in the
netting
and then super cropping what i
personally like to do is even when using
the netting
sometimes some shoots will grow up
taller than others saw a super crop in
and that's usually when i'm
in that um that stretch period right so
i flipped a flower
now things are growing up in the netting
some growing more than the others so
within the first like two weeks or so
three weeks or so i'll do some super
cropping
that's typically what i'll do in smaller
spaces
in order to try to you know keep things
small all right let's get into
uh nutrients let's get into water what
do you typically use for base nutrients
and then what type of water do you use
do you use filtered water
tap water well water distilled water
that's another thing i
i could say i've almost tried it all
i started out with tap water from my
sink like
before i as a novice i mean a complete
novice from back in the day
um i was just running tap water you know
i was one of those guys oh you just need
to water it you know
and then i had to sit down and kind of
learn this trade
you know via youtube and books and other
social media platforms and a couple
friends or whatnot but
a lot of it was was trial and error just
getting
kind of doing it you know getting your
hands in that dirt so to speak
and um well from tap water
uh i bought a ph pen and a tds meter or
whatever
and i think the first time i took the
readings on
like my local tap water or whatever um
i want to say my tap water came out at
like 420
410 parts per million or something like
that i couldn't tell you what the ph was
on it
you know at the time or whatever but
once i figured that out
i went and i got the amazon i bought a
ro filter off amazon and i was running
that
for a while you know so i could get that
zero parts per million neutral water
in order to add my synthetic ingredients
because
when i first started off i was overfleet
i was over feeding my plants and i
didn't know it
like when i started i was using general
hydro
and they have like a feeding chart that
you can download offline
it might be on some of their products as
well but i i ended up downloading it
offline and
being new i kind of wanted to get the
best you know i wanted the best so to
speak and the guy
at the hydroponic store you know saw him
a young guppy fish and reeled me
in and i ended up buying like the
advanced
news chance products which is like
and it's our like in the top of each
week it gives you
like a ppm number of
once you mix the ingredient the
nutrients like your ppm should be around
whatever level like 800 or 400 or
whatever and when i was starting off
with 420
tap water and then adding however you
know many parts per million
depending on what week it was like i
would always be at least at 420
parts per million over so i was way over
feeding my plants in the beginning you
know
and then i got the ro filter but
after using that for probably i don't
know i want to say i use that about a
year
and then one of my buddies that pointed
out to me was like man you ever
you know notice how much water that
thing wastes
and i didn't and i was i ended up
hooking the runoff
you know of the ro filter
well i didn't hook it up into anything
there's a hose that comes off but i
ended up draining that into
like a a container and i kept like
measuring that out to every gallon of
water that i had
if i'm not mistaken my ro filter was
wasting
it was either three or four gallons of
water
in order for me to get one gallon of
you know zero water or neutral water for
the matter
and to me it's like
when you're paying for four gallons or
three gallons for that matter
to get one gallon of you know purified
water i just
i kind of stopped using that then i went
into
buying like purified water from
local places you know going to fill up a
five gallon
uh jug here and there or whatever i
needed water
and then after that i just kind of
i started using tap water again but
instead of doing a full feeding or
whatever
nutrients that i'm using i usually like
cut that in
either a half or like a quarter
and that kind of offsets that
whatever parts per million or what's in
my water the negative
about that though is at any given moment
you know in our
your city tap water there could be what
whatever nutrients you know
they try to keep it at a parts per
million at a very low
i guess rate but you never know what's
in your water is there iron from the
pipes in there is there
more copper or zinc or whatever's in the
water and
i always try to let it sit for a couple
days
so any chlorine and i guess chloramine
or whatever will kind of evaporate off
of there before i use it
and i've been having fairly decent luck
doing it that way
you know but i'd like to go back to
doing the ro water if i could find
a better ro filter but
even at the end of the day i mean i
think i've looked on amazon and they've
got up to like the one to one ratios
but there's something about wasting a
gallon of water to get a good gallon of
water to me at the end of the day it
just doesn't seem
right you know yeah three gallons to one
gallon uh one gallon of three gallons
is about right for the rl water now i'm
in the same boat as you as far as
the waste actually had a podcast with
somebody else dog of the hot not sure if
you know who he is but
he had mentioned that he takes his um
the drain line
and he'll actually use it on his outdoor
plants so he's not wasting
that uh additional water which i thought
was pretty cool
and that's something i'm transitioning
on to but uh yeah
as far as you don't know what's in your
water um the chloramine letting its
uh sorry chlorine letting it sit out for
24 hours so it dissipates
chlorine will chloramine won't now
luckily we live in las vegas we don't
you have chloramine
in our local water but there are some
places that do
so for anybody watching that you might
want to check your local water report
see if you have chlorine or chloramine
because you would take
different routes for that i believe you
can just filter out the chloramine if
you
had chloramine instead of chlorine yeah
all right let's move on to temperature
and humidity
what do you typically run for
temperature and humidity in your small
grow spaces
this is another one of those questions
that a lot of people are going to
probably
i feel like i'm that grower that's like
borderline i
almost break every rule possible or try
to come as close to it you know
i know the ideal humidity is
what is it are the ideal temperatures in
between 80
what 86 and something i'm in vegas it's
hot as hell
i like i said i have the two by two
tents i have two of those and i pretty
much
let my tent do what it does i i have my
air conditioning on my house it's 78 so
it kind of goes off the ambient
temperature of that
i also run my leds so it
usually doesn't get over
maybe 90 in my tent which is it's high
it's pushing it in the summer time
i've seen it go over that but i'll
usually just kick the air down a little
bit
more and it'll kind of keep those
temperatures down um
the leds work a lot it does not
alleviate
all your heat but it does work a lot you
know like i said i didn't really come up
in that
light bulb grow generation so to speak i
didn't have to do the hids or the
ballasts or all that extra stuff you
know that i guess or a little
a lot you know i know they've busted
gorilla groves for
readings because of the lights being so
hot back in the day not to say that they
couldn't do it maybe with these leds but
i think you'd have to have
a lot more or something like that you
know so
i just kind of let my tents just you
know
humidity wise whatever it is in there i
think it's
the watering and the feeding days are
i guess the days that it is it's as
humid as it's gonna get in my tents you
know for the most part
and my thermometer for the mo
it always reads like low humidity you
know and
i have a humidifier in the box sitting
in my closet i bought it
one day i'm like you know what i'm gonna
fix my
humidity issue then i got home and i'm
looking at both my tents and i'm like
one humidor humidifier
two tents like i was trying to think of
a way i could like
rig something up to it and poured it to
both
tents and then i'm like you know what no
maybe i'll go buy another one and put it
in there
but like i said in a 2x2 by the time you
put a humidifier in there
unless it's like mounted hanging up
something which i'm not even going to
try to do like
it's beneficial yes you know to keep
that humidity at the
the ideal temperature but or the ideal
rating but i just weighed it man
whatever
it is you know i keep my thermostat in
my house on 78 year round
you know summertime winter time whatever
it's always 78 in here so
i've been lucky enough that i guess my
ambient temperature kind of keeps
my temperatures at bay but i do
know that you know it could be a lot
better
if it was a little bit more controlled
but i just it's to me it's not that big
of an issue
you know i i could i would probably see
a better outcome at the end of the day
if my plants weren't idealistic
temperatures but
i mean let's face it this plant grows
from california to
kuz pakistan or whatever way on the
other side of the planet you know
so if you get the right strain in your
garden you don't have to worry about
temperatures
and all that other stuff you know if you
get a picky strain
or you know if if you get a strain it's
great at growing in the desert and you
bring it to
somewhere where it's damp and humid
you're probably gonna mess that strain
up but
you know due to the genetics so
that's something else that i kind of
incorporate into my crosses and
everything is our temperature out here
you know and in the past i've made
kind of testers and sent them out and
hey let me know how
they do in your neck of the woods so to
speak because
i want to know in different environments
you know how
something that i'm growing out here may
vary you know
so i just try to keep it as cool as i
can in there
you know i on each of my tents like the
flap down
part that covers i guess your zippers or
whatnot at the top
like i wrote the idealistic temperatures
what is it
it's 86 to from everything i've read
82 degrees leaf surface temperature
is said to be ideal now if your canopy
temperature is a little bit higher than
that your leaf surface temperature might
be a little bit lower than that so
some people will run up to 85. i've
heard people running up to 87. i've
tried
87 in the past but i've seen you know
heat
stress issues on my plants so i've
lowered it down but i usually aim for
about 80 to 82
leaf surface temperature now that like
you've said before the plant is going to
grow
outside of the ideal ranges for sure
absolutely
the plant is very resilient you can see
problems and you might not see optimal
growth but
the plant will still grow for sure same
thing with humidity right
we live in the same area we struggle
with i think at the natural humidity
level is about 20 percent
that's crazy crazy so having that
humidifier in there
i have three humidifiers i have uh
i have one in my lung room which i was
going to recommend to you is just having
like the room
that your grow tents are in maybe just
control that at the ideal humidity
so that way when you're exhausting out
you're bringing in that ideal
humidity level that might work because
you're stuck with space constraints not
being
able with that humidifier in those small
grow tents but
typically for humidity i'll have like a
higher humidity
when the plant is uh you know on the
seedling stage vegetation stage
65 to 85 maybe when it's super young
then i'll slowly reduce it and then
flowering you know
40 50 40 to 60 percent as a general
range now that kind of goes against vpd
that's optimal range is vpd um
but yeah again if the plan is going to
grow outside of those ideal ranges
for sure yeah it's it's
kind of funny i idealistically i would
like to have
all my tents in one room but just
i'm in a two-bedroom kind of like
roommate style apartment and
everything is cramped in my room and
it's
temperature wise you can tell like the
difference between a living room and my
room it's like
it's almost like walking out into the
sun from the shade but it's not
that drastic with you know of a change
it's like you know
if it's 90 degrees outside and
you're under some shade it doesn't feel
like 90 it might feel like that 85 or
you know lower 80 or whatever
but if you're in the sun yeah it's gonna
feel like that 90 you know and my room
is it's always
kind of pushing that temperature that
high temperature of the house because of
the fact
that the tents are in here the lights
are on
you know and i try to keep the majority
of this stuff
running at night just to kind of keep it
cooler in here and just
i guess uh kind of find a median zone
for my temperature in general because if
you know if i ran these lights in the
daytime oh my god i should probably be
ridiculously i my power bill would
probably jump up a lot more due
just to the my electricity as far as my
air conditioning
consuming a lot more to keep it cooler
in here but
anybody that's been in my room ever
they're always like why is it so hot in
here i'm like
you know in the first place we live in a
desert
so it's not hot in here you think it's
hot go outside
i aim to get into everything in the one
room sooner or later
if i if i can get a three bedroom but
yeah i like to get a house and then you
know
i got gross stuff all throughout my
apartment kind of scattered you know
there's old stuff
in a bin over here and you know
my master bathroom kind of has the
majority of my nutrients
and some spare pots and whatever and i
would love to get everything in one room
and just kind of concentrate on that one
specific area and
you should see me sometimes i'm
transplanting i gotta go in this room to
get a pot
and over here to get you know some great
white or some type of root
inoculant or something you know and it's
just like man if everything was in one
spot i wouldn't have to do all this but
that's my goal sooner or later is just
to get everything in
one spot either that or my child is
going to have to hurry up and turn 18 so
i can kick her out and take her
give me your room no i'm just playing
i'm not kicking her out she's probably
going to be the one to take care of my
old self when i turn
however old and we can't do it no more
i can see it now
yeah would definitely be easier to have
everything all in one area
so all right so that being said you know
we went over a decent amount of stuff
in this video everything you can think
about
in regards to growing in small spaces
what advice would you have for somebody
who's
new to growing in small spaces research
do your research do your research do
your research you know unless your daddy
wore bucks and you got money to blow
wasting on
trying to do everything you know like
gardening in general can be the most
simplistic
thing in the world or it can be the most
complicated it's just kind of what you
make out of it
um you know you got some guys out there
it's i know you mentioned you're trying
to get down to simplicity and efficiency
and you know making everything as simple
as possible for you
because let's face it at the end of the
day gardening
is not your life it's a part of your
life but you have other stuff to do you
know
you don't want to spend your whole time
sitting there babysitting literally
watching the grass grow
you know so just do as much research as
you can
um figure out what style
if any that you kind of want to hone in
on because there's a lot of girl styles
out there
you know and some style might be better
for you and your environment or your
atmosphere
so just do some research i mean
youtube is as long as you have internet
i mean that's youtube helped me out a
lot people like mr growit
and oh my gosh i'm having brain farts
right now everybody that i learned from
is probably like
this guy there's a large community on
youtube
i've kind of started seeking out a
little bit more knowledge as far as the
gardening community in general because
last year i bought it
two by four by like five and a half ten
and i started
indoor gardening so
i'm trying to alleviate like some of the
fruits and vegetables or at least the
vegetables that i buy the tomatoes and
lettuce and i'm always at the store
getting because
their shelf life isn't all that you know
long for the most part so if i can
take that eliminate that cost and grow
it myself here you know i could always
have stuff for salads and
herbs and spices and whatnot around and
that's kind of let me branch out my
gardening
if you can grow your own fruits and
vegetables or a little bit of
substance for yourself that's one less
thing you got to worry about you know if
the
if the s ever hits the fan at the end of
the day so
i think that's really good advice for
sure okay so
wrapping things up how can the listeners
find you and what do you have upcoming
in the future
i'm on just about every social platform
some more than others
um youtube probably has the biggest
collection of my work
i guess videos so to speak um instagram
you know i have i guess of course photos
on their short videos
um facebook i'm on just about anything
if you google my name
mr sparks a lot by lowercase um either
with the at sign or without it i'm
pretty sure it'll pull up just about
anything that
i'm on social media wise like i said i
have an account for just about
everything
twitter and snapchat and this and that
and i can't keep up with them i'm
getting over
you know but just at mr sparks a lot um
i also have a website i believe it's
www.irecreations
that's i r i e creations
c r e a t i o n z
instead of a s dot com um
that will pull up some of the things
that i kind of offer some of my
merchandise mr sparksville gear or
whatever
and um yeah just about just google me
well mr sparks a lot thank you so much
for coming on to the podcast today i
really
appreciate your time and yeah for those
watching
again i'll link his channel down in the
description section below for those of
you watching on youtube
i hope you enjoy the rest of your day
[Music]
bye