what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr growit and welcome back to my
talk channel a few months ago i released
a video with thc titan
it was actually a podcast episode from a
podcast that no longer exists
i mentioned in that video that had three
more episodes this is actually one of
them
in this video both myself and chris from
happy hydro
sit down with baby j from the grill 420
diaries for those of you who don't know
baby j
she has been uploading grow videos to
youtube for over five years now
and her channel has almost 7 000
subscribers we sit down we talked to her
we found out a little bit more about how
she got into growing and then we talk
into detail about her gross setup and
her gross style
since this was a podcast episode there's
actually no
video it is audio only so i apologize
for not having any visuals for you
but this podcast definitely has some
good information in it so i wanted to
repost
and i know for the last podcast episode
that also didn't have visuals
some had mentioned that it was good to
listen to in the garden anyways i will
stop rambling now
and uh let's just get into the episode
hey everybody this is a happy hour
podcast and we're here with baby j
baby j how you doing i'm doing good man
how are you guys doing today
i'm doing great how you doing mr growit
doing awesome doing really good
awesome we're excited to be here with
you guys today we're going to interview
baby j on her grow and her youtube
channel i'll kick off the questions
so baby j i've been watching channel for
quite some time i don't think since 2015
or something like that you got a ton of
videos it's clear that you're very very
passionate
tell us how did it all start how did you
get into grilling on my 21st birthday my
friend
he uh he decided to give me a plant as
before a present instead of you know
a normal present so um he was just
telling me he was like well
uh just go ahead go ahead and check out
youtube and it'll teach you everything
you need to know about growing this
plant
so i didn't know anything about the
youtube world i didn't even know anybody
was putting videos out about growing um
this was back in the back in the day
when mr tight and
angry closet first started his channel
and um
crazy it was crazy how much youtube has
progressed since then but um i got on
youtube
and i started watching all the videos
about people uh growing
there was so many different ways so many
different uh techniques
out there to uh to teach you how to grow
so
um i spent hours and hours and hours
every day watching youtube you guys like
literally
um i watched youtube more than i watched
my own television so
um literally watch it for about a few
months before i actually got comfortable
with actually posting videos because i
was watching it and i still had the plan
growing but i wasn't really too
comfortable posting because i really
didn't want people to
uh i don't know i didn't really want to
look like i didn't really know what i
was talking about
before i started making videos like you
know you know you have that fear of yeah
i don't i don't want to look stupid on
camera or whatever the case may be so
it took me a little while actually to
post content on my channel
but um i was actually growing you know a
few months prior to that
my first girl actually didn't really
turn out too well
as you may know yeah that's pretty much
how i got started literally
where'd you go for inspiration like who
who were you who were like a youtube
channel or like what's a
a youtube girl or something that you can
remember that like really
inspired you or helped you when you were
doing your first grow or when you got
started
grow for 20 guide you guys grow 420
guide was the guy
because he was pretty much doing the
same setup that i had like he was the
only grower that i seen
um because i started off with cfls so
um i was looking in the closet or
something yeah i was it was like
it was actually a little closet box
because um
you know the little plastic totes i
don't know if you guys watch love vibes
i don't know mr growth if you checked
out love life's channel
but um he in the beginning he started
off with these little
grow boxes you know you buy the little
plastic totes and you know you make a
little mini robots and
with cfls and i and like i said back in
the day i was started with cfl so i
watched a lot of videos that were
pertaining towards cfl
so go for 20 guy had an awesome cfo grow
um on his channel that i was watching
all the time and then uh
love vibes i got the little grow box
idea from love vibes and i had me i made
a few little grow boxes um you know to
start off with or whatever the case may
be but
um i would say early inspirations
grow 420 guide was really the main one
because he was actually growing in the
same type of setup that
i you know kind of sort of had is he
still active
um i haven't seen videos from him in in
quite a while
um but even even still now he has a
wealth of information on his channel
so you can go back you know videos and
videos back and you're still going to
find just a wealth of
you know content do you want to ask her
a couple more questions about her first
girl
yeah yeah let's get into the first goal
let's get into the the nitty-gritty of
the first girl you said it was bad i
want to hear about that
it was okay because okay you guys don't
laugh don't laugh this is me too
you you know newbie mistakes but i
okay when i first started growing like i
said i got the plant from my friend
and he told me to you know you look on
youtube and in blase blase blah now i
didn't know that
you know you would need nutrients for
the plants so you know i was under an
impression that you just get dirt you
know you feed the water and you know
like any noob would you know think
you know water dirt and it should grow
um
you know i got some miracle-gro soil and
everything was going good
you know the plant was go it was growing
you know miracle grow has you know a
little bit of substance in it now that i
you know i know really more about it so
it kept the plant going for a little bit
but when the plant actually needed
nutrients and started actually showing
deficiencies
you know i started to panic so of course
you know you know
second nature oh let me go on youtube
and figure out what what the problem is
or let me go check out let me go see
what the problem is
and you know i found out that i needed
to supplement with nutrients so i
ordered my first uh nutrient
supplement which was the general
hydroponics floor series you know on the
back of the the bottle it says
you know mix per gallon ratio now i'm so
impatient because
as a new grower if you're really into
the if you're really into growing
cannabis
you're literally and you're i'm in there
all the time looking at the plants i'm
you know they're not even doing anything
and i'm just staring at them hoping that
i can see a difference in them
so um you know i got my general
hydroponics and it said on the back of
the bottle mix per gallon
but i was so impatient thinking that if
i feed them
you know i had a little uh water bottle
just a little eight ounce water bottle
and i swear i mixed up a gallons worth
of nutrients in that little eight ounce
bottle
of nutrients and fed it to my plant and
must have fried the whole
crap out of my plants y'all like
yeah so that was it that was the end of
that story
i mean yeah because after that it really
i think i actually pushed it to go mail
honestly because it started
throwing ball sacks like crazy it could
have just been a male but
you know that you know i fried it
seriously bad and it turned out to be a
male so i had to get rid of him so i was
kind of down about that too so
well i'm sure uh i haven't seen your
youtube channel but i'm sure you've
figured it out since then if you have a
youtube channel
oh yeah of course of course of course
i'm telling you though
and those mistakes it's so funny because
a lot of new growers they make that
type of mistake all the time it's you
know
you you think that if you feed it more
you're going to get more results and
that's
never ever the case that's why
less is really more and a lot of growers
can tell you that themselves
let's get into the current grow so your
setup
is has expanded quite a bit i know you
have like a multiple tent set up now
stuff like that so let's talk about
tell us about your current growth setup
that you have go on all right so right
now
in the main fly room i have a spectrum
king
and two march hydro 600 watts
all led lights or yeah those are all led
right now currently i'm using majority
all led i haven't
experimented with any you know intent
you know hids or anything like that yet
honestly you know a lot of heating
issues i'm still trying to dial my
temperature and everything in
because even with the leds i'm still
experiencing you know
the spike in intent temperature um but
um
yeah i have all leds i have in the
bedroom i have my t5
it's a 240 watt t5 as well as i'm still
using some supplemental cfl
lighting as well for veg and then i have
uh
and that's all in the tent though i have
the cfl's in the tent and then
um my mars hydro 310 as well and then um
i have a breeding tent that's actually
using the my grow leds
i don't know if you guys heard about
micro led but a nice little 100 watt
unit
perfect for breeding perfect for you
know a small little two by four grow
especially because i have two of them
and you're making you're making your own
strains then
um yeah well i'm experimenting with a
little breeding uh nothing too serious
because you know i
uh i don't know i don't know how to say
because you know how like
people get so uptight about being you
know pollen chucking and whatever the
case may be
um a little bit what's pollen chuckin
apparently it's just when you just throw
whatever you can together
it's not really called you know true
breeding i guess gotcha
it's like a smorgasbord of pollen it's
not like a true just one-to-one
yeah you know and it's a lot of
controversy behind that you know like a
lot of breeders can tell you so
yeah gotcha and so like when you you
said you're having heat problems when
you like walk into your room do you have
all of these tents in one like bedroom
or
is it do you have an air conditioner in
there are they spread out
throughout or yeah so the way my room is
set up it's it's actually
pretty you you probably wouldn't even
think it would be like this but
i have where i have the main fly room
it's a huge
i'm talking about huge walk-in closet
like it's they're pretty much a whole
nother room in itself
then um that's the main flower room then
you come out so can you get
can you get air conditioning in there or
anything or like how do you i have a i
have air conditioning in my main
in my main room which is actually it's
like it's like in the dead center so
it's kind of like the epicenter
of my whole setup so i have an ac in the
main room
which actually you know supplies the
actual basement where the bedroom is as
well as the main fly room
but the only problem i'm having is
because i think i need to get a higher
btu
ac because it's not really i you know it
has that little it's like a 5000 btu but
it has to cover
you know the basement as well as the
flower room so it's kind of
it's not it's not enough yeah no five
thousand
i mean they get like a normal window
unit is usually like 10 000 b2 right
does anyone know yeah and i have a
smaller unit now and i've been meaning
to upgrade the uh the ac unit i was
actually thinking about going 10
10 000 btus using up because this one is
the window unit or
yeah it's a window unit got you because
i know some people use the standing air
conditioners and
i i don't know i've heard mixed reviews
about them like i know
there's two different versions one
version actually releases
smelly air through the exhaust
and then there's another version that
actually pulls air from the outside and
then
uses that and then sends that same air
out so it like doesn't
release uh smelly air of course of
course those ones
i would be able to get with some one of
those but you know
pocketed funds and everything like that
those are like super expensive yeah
those are more expensive
and i don't know if they're even better
i was just saying i've just heard of
them i don't know if they're better at
all i know window units are pretty
reliable and
yeah they're pretty reliable and the
thing about it is too because i have
central i have central
you know air conditioner in the house so
i have it's like i have that going as
well as the window unit just trying to
combat to kind of
even it out because right now since it's
so hot right now
and i'm in california you know my flower
room is getting with all the leds on and
everything
um 82 80 to 86 that's like the highest
that yeah it's kind of a little hot for
me you know
i'm used to floating in like the 79 inch
range you know and that's
and that's you know in winter you know
so it's it's kind of it's touching it
it's touching it for me
even though for leds though because uh i
mean most manufacturers recommend you
run
higher temperatures like spectrum kicks
yeah spectrum king
brandon over there he recommended me to
run up to 87 degrees which
i thought was kind of crazy but what's
the
point of that what he had mentioned that
um you know in some places
weed grows naturally at this temperature
and high humidity so it can survive and
it's actually more happier and
and vpt charges
i know the higher humidity kind of helps
it out like in the 60 percentile range
kind of helps out with the flowers i
don't know
i mean my thing is with the heat problem
i'm kind of paranoid about you know
uh pottery mill doing everything because
i've had a bad experience with powdery
mildew before
um and that's with me picking up clones
from the dispensary that's why man
you got to be safe with where you're
getting cloned you got to make sure you
and
on top of that quarantine it because um
i brought the clone home and
it just was you know i didn't know what
the festival powder mill do until it hit
flower that's what pissed me off so much
about it
tell me about the quarantine situation a
little bit more like brick get the
clones bring them in put them in a
little tent by themselves
yeah put them somewhere away from your
main your main
stuff you got going at least for a few
weeks because i mean whatever that
that clone brings in you're going to
infest your garden with you know you got
to kind of think about that so
i would say quarantine it away from your
other plants and just like make sure you
keep up on like
you know your ipms and making sure you
know the maintenance is on point
now what if it's in a cloned dome one of
those small clone domes in like the the
corner of your tent for example is that
segregated enough or would you recommend
more than that i mean
man me i like you know i'm i'm heir of
caution you know
as being a grower you know a lot yeah
you go through a lot of problems i just
wouldn't want
you know you get a clone in the next
thing you know it's infested with mites
or something and then you know your
whole freaking garden has mites now
because
yeah you know for sure it's like co2
tanks if you're
if you're using co2 tanks and you're
exchanging them at the grow store
i mean they are they're they're just
mites pottery mildew anything that was
in the garden that that co2 tank was in
before
is gonna be on that tank now grow stores
are infested with
bugs and mildew and stuff so i worked at
one for three years i'm well aware
i used to tell people before you put
that co2 tank in your grow room you
better
bleach it or you know it's ideally keep
it outside of the room do you use co2
uh no i do not use co2 right now um
because i'm you know
my whole theory is that you know the ac
is actually bringing in a lot of co2 and
since i'm actually in the room
i you know i'm breathing breathing yeah
and all that good stuff so i mean
it's probably not enough co2 but i you
know i'm pretty comfortable with you
know not actually having a supplement
with it maybe and you know maybe it
might help to grow if i do
you know you know you never know but um
right now i'm not really too
big on me getting co2 well i wasn't just
going to say basement growing like if
you're
um if you're growing in the basement i
mean co2 is heavier than air
naturally if there's a bunch of people
living in the house co2 is probably
levels are probably going to be
higher down there i would assume from
its sinking yeah well i have a gang of
people you know
that stay in the house i live in a
pretty big house so you know i
i'm very confident about the co2 i don't
feel like i have to get external co2
right now
um although i think it may benefit
benefit to grow a little bit because you
know
steel two is really beneficial but so
i'm gonna just go through what we have
here
flower room led lights veg tent
cfls t5s i wanna say you said there's
led in there too
yeah there is there's one mars hydro 300
watt unit that's still in the tent just
to give it that you know that mixed
spectrum kind of sort of but um
yeah yeah everything is right now still
in veg because i just harvested
i'm still getting you know flowers
trimmed up and everything like that but
right now i still
just have plants in the veg the flower
room is kind of out of commission for
right now you know
you go through your harvest period and
you got to reset you know this it's a
whole process clean the room
for sure so are you growing hydro
soil cocoa bring bring me into that
department tell me a little bit about
that
growing in pro mix hp so i guess it is a
soil
soil medium if you right it doesn't have
any food in it though so you have to
feed it all the nutrients i have to
supplement all the time yes and
that's one of the things i like about
the pro-mix brand is just
i like the the controllability you have
when you know
you get to control it yourself you don't
have to worry like i said miracle grow
has
[ __ ] in it so right really you know
let's say you
you got the miracle grow soil you can't
really just go and dump nutrients in it
right now because it already you're
going to burn your plants it already has
stuff in it for sure and i want to say
pro-mix has beneficial bacteria in it
mycorrhizae
do you know does it either i i'm using
the one with the mycorrhizae in it as
well it's really beneficial for roots
and so do you like uh are you using
plastic pots or fabric pots
i'm using plastic right now i have a i
have a couple fabric pots outside i have
a little outdoor project that i'm doing
that's
in fabric pots but indoors i use mostly
plastic
and so you're not mixing anything with
the pro-mix just using that do you put
like clay pebbles in the bottom of the
pot or anything
no i was actually thinking about that to
kind of help as far as like with uh
drainage and stuff yeah drainage and
everything like that because i was
thinking
more so i'm like you know
because i'm going to try to scrog this
next round and flushing is my main
that that's been my main thing about the
scrog but i killed it last like you know
last round with the scrog everything
went well
but i was thinking that if i was to
layer the bottoms of the pots
with you know at least some clay pebbles
or something it would kind of help get
all
you know the excess salts uh oh for sure
you get what i'm saying to kind of not
have the plant just sitting in it
because like i said with the scrog you
kind of can't move it around
you can't but you're still you just told
me you're still killing it without the
clay pebbles so
yeah but you know i'm really ain't know
about the flushing thing i
really want to make sure that for sure i
just wanted the listeners to
to know and hear that like even if you
forget to put your clay pebbles in as
long as you
are careful and do all your youtube
homework you can still come out with a
a good girl most definitely most
definitely a lot of people think that
you have to have a lot of expensive
equipment
literally i didn't start my channel off
with expensive equipment at all
i you know of course you know i got
youtube i got
i'm sorry i got leds you know later on
but i didn't just start you know i
didn't
start off with expensive equipment to
start my grow or my channel
you know you can grow without all of
that for sure and
so do you put your plants just like on
the ground in saucers or do you have
like a big tray or something
in saucers i've had them all in saucers
um i was thinking i wanted to actually
get an actual big tray for there so i
don't have to actually carry around all
the saucers and everything just kind of
coagulate in the same place and so can
you tell me like what size pots you use
how many plants and like what do your
roots look like when you pull them out
at the end
is it like filling up your whole pot
yeah and that's a problem that i've been
noticing as well um i'm using
five gallon tall pots for my main fire
room uh for veg everything is in a two
gallon right now except the the you know
the little babies
when do you transplant i like to see
i'm a little unorthodox with
transplanting i keep my plants in these
small containers for a little bit longer
than i should
i'm not even gonna lie to you guys um
you know when it's one person taking
care of like
20 plants or something yeah you know
and then you know i'm working on working
like that yeah it's a lot of work so i
kind of
you know drag on the transplant a little
bit man it's yeah are you
are you hand watering then or right yeah
right now i'm hand watering
i have a little watering wand that i you
know put into a little bucket and i'm
just you know
awesome and one more one more question
before i let mr grow it tick over again
what type of nutrients are you using now
um
i was last round using the rainbow i'm
i've been
every round i've been changed switching
nutrients and i know that's not really
not really a good idea for a lot of new
growers i don't want to tell anybody to
do that but i'm still trying to find
my niche i'm still trying to find what i
can dial in and what i can use
that's going to be you know convenient
more easier for me um as far as because
you know
i have a i have a i have people send me
nutrients all the time
but i really just want to find a simpler
way to supplement my plants
and not have to use so many bottles do
you pa well remo
before i ask this question how many
bottles does remo have i don't really
know much about them
i want to say seven i think it's about
seven bottles
[ __ ] but no it's like advanced but you
don't use all seven though you
use about foreign veg and then use about
five in flour
gotcha and do you have to adjust your ph
and you have a ppm meter
uh yes sir very very important things
that every grower should have
what kind of meters do you use i'm using
uh what is the name of my ph pen it was
it's uh
it's like an expensive one or is it just
like yeah it was about 80 bucks but the
thing about it is i had one of the cheap
i had the cheap chinese ones and they
worked good but
i don't know for some reason mine's died
out so i just
i was like i'm not gonna keep buying you
know spending forty dollars for a ph pen
i'll just go ahead and buy
the you know the eighty dollar digital
one it should be good
for sure yeah yeah the brand of uh ph
pen i have is is an eco tester
there we go eco yeah i'm familiar with
them we just used to sell a bunch of
them at the
grow shop yeah they're decent they're
waterproof right
yes sir and so when you're checking ph
and ppm you're doing
are you doing pre-feed are you doing
runoff or are you doing both
both both it's very important to do both
because i've had ph issues in the past
um you know i like to know what's going
on in my soil as well
um you know as well as when i'm
supplementing giving them the food
before
if that makes any sense yeah yeah and
what what
using pro-mix what ph range do you like
to stay in
and then throughout like um you know
growing what ppms do you try to keep
your plants in
ph wise i like to stay 6-2 in
in pro mix it's very comfortable the
plants do
really well um literally like i
if i keep it at 6-2 i don't have to
worry about lockout issues
now depending on the i remember i had a
really bad ph swing
the nutrients that you're using whatever
you supplement your plants you know like
flora nova i don't know if you guys are
familiar with that flora nova
scene it's like a thick organic
semi-organic whatever the hell you want
to call it
from gh uh-huh that thing
will cause some major like soil ph
wings for sure you have to make sure you
flush your your like if you're gonna use
that you gotta flush regularly like
literally because
you will get some major ph swings with
that for sure
sounds like you lived it oh yeah yeah
for sure
i'm really glad you're sharing that
information i was actually thinking
about trying out that line of nutrients
and it's good to hear that you know
tips like that i think is helpful for um
you know people
that currently use the nutrients or are
looking to use the nutrients so
yeah of course i know a lot of people
that have had very good success the
plants like when i immediately fed it
like especially the grow
it immediately gave like i love the fact
that it's just a one bottle
you know base no you know you don't have
to give it anything else literally you
could just feed it that and your plants
getting everything it needs
have you ever just grown fully
organically or like it
like the way that you're growing right
now has this kind of been the way that
you've always grown or have you ever
tried hydroponics or anything
i want to try hydro um and yeah the way
that i've been growing
right now i'm comfortable with you know
like like the medium like
i have cocoa i bought cocoa um a couple
weeks ago because i want to start
experimenting with cocoa because i think
that would be
the kind of it'll kind of be because you
know how it's a soilless medium you can
run it in hydro
and it can work very well with a hydro
system for sure
i'm since i'm so comfortable with soil i
think cocoa would be a really good
transition into hydro if you get what
i'm saying
um because i'm so familiar with the soil
base
it's kind of it's kind of similar just
definitely and uh the it's you can
over water in cocoa like if you
transplant a plant in the coca-cola and
then you don't let the roots
um establish themselves and then start
hammering it with water you definitely
can over water
but once those roots are established in
coco coir
you can hook up a drip system you can
water you can just really you can water
the [ __ ] out of them and
the plants love it as long as you have
good drainage most definitely good
drainage is always key
really key what about your ventilation
system do we talk about that yet like
what are you using for like an inline
fan
ducting out of the room i don't remember
if you said that and then do you have
like a lot of air circulation going on
with them oh yeah i have a [ __ ] kind of
air circulation as far as with inline
and out
i do not need as right now i don't need
it because the way
everything is like i said my room the
flowers is an open closet you know it's
it's a huge room and it i shaded off
with uh you know for the dark period i
shaded off with a plastic
sheeting over you know some panels over
the door out over the doorway so
um and at the top there is um there's a
little set
now i'm not gonna say a little section
it's a section where air
mo it it's it blows blows
i don't even need a ventilation system
it's pretty much what i'm getting at
do you have a lot of fans like us i have
a [ __ ] i have a whole ton of fans going
on through this room like
as i'm sitting here right now i can feel
the wind just nice that's awesome
so what what do you think your like
biggest catastrophe
was or your biggest failure growing i
would have to say my biggest
biggest fail with the grow would have
been that powdery mildew
incident but it didn't even collapse my
grow too much because
i mean i still ended up harvesting the
plant i just did it though jose
cervantes way you know how he you know
washes the buds after
harvest and everything with the peroxide
bath and everything i did it that way
and it kind of just washed the mildew
away but
what does he do can you explain that
because i have no idea what that
is he he watches um if he has a video on
it too
he for to get rid of powdery mildew on
your buds
um he takes the bud you know after
harvest he cuts it off
and he he has some water he has a bath
mixed up with some uh
hydrogen peroxide i think it's like uh
one teaspoon per like five gallons of
like hydrogen
you know hydrogen peroxide and then um
he just washes the buds and you can see
the powdery mildew float all over the
top of the water
have you seen this mr growit yeah i've
seen it you gotta watch it it's it's
definitely a controversial topic um some
people are
so against blood washing but i mean yeah
it's kind of scary seeing him
submerge an entire branch all the way
under water
um yeah it's pretty it's pretty gross
[ __ ] ton of powdery mildew yeah
hydrogen peroxide washed bugs i've never
heard of that that's
i'm not saying but if you really think
about it like super sanitizing your butt
but you just have to make sure you get
all that excess water out you don't want
to have rot or anything so
how he did it was he had a fan he had
him hanging up after he washed him and
bathed him and everything he rinsed them
down
and then he had him hanging on this
little rack and he just had the fan
blowing on him just to make sure you got
all that excess moisture out
because you know you don't want that in
your butt and everything you know pretty
cool i did that with mine and
it worked i ended up having a pretty
cool harvest but
i mean it you know is this something
that you know it's not nothing you want
to you know have in the back of your
mind that you have power removed on your
butt you know
yeah smoking mildew you know yeah it's
nasty
i'd rather wash that [ __ ] and some
hydrogen peroxide
i didn't know that's crazy man i gotta
watch that video dude i've watched
people cut down like
crops because they don't want to deal
with powdery mildew i've made it oh for
sure yeah
hurts like oh man you could have dunked
that [ __ ] in a bucket of water and kept
it no but you know you gotta think about
the labor for that too man you got about
100 plants from pm you know you gotta
dump all those it's kind of like
yeah i mean when that much shits on the
line you gotta get creative
you do you do and that's a very creative
way because you i mean you can literally
see the powdery mildew like
just off the bud floating on the water
baby joe
we want to ask you another question here
what's your biggest yield to date and
how much
how much wattage were you using oh man
oh
i'm so proud of this man you guys i have
to say this is really my proudest moment
because this is when you really found
your name awesome and growing you know
when you get that when you get that
satisfied feeling like yes i finally got
it
this is the one so um it's my season if
you guys go back for anybody watching
this podcast it's um
my spectrum king marsh hydro combo i
think that's the name of the actual
uh cycle that i named it oh my god
that's when i first got the setup when i
have
just got the spectrum king put in there
and i had my 600 watt both 600 watts
boom and i had like what 880 something
watts pumping in there
i had my gorilla smash from canon
genetics that's what you know
um it's gorilla it's gorilla glue
crossed with
is it lucky charms or i gotta get back
to y'all on that man
okay i mean i just i gotta get back to
you on that
but you have to name the strain but it's
from canada genetics that's what
genetics tests for
awesome strains but oh my god you guys i
yielded literally over a pound
four plants general general hydro floor
series
and yeah yeah in in my little people
i'm trying to tell you guys fair very
simple nutrient schedule
all i had was the led you know both leds
in there four straight
four plants of the gorilla smash over a
pound
in my little in my little grow area you
guys now if you have to check it out you
have to watch it for you to really see
that was perfect i didn't have any
problems on that grow
everything went as smooth as can be i
ran it nine weeks straight
harvested at nine weeks everything was
just perfect
perfect flush everything what you and um
you're like for drying your stuff do you
do you you like do you use dehumidifier
or anything like what's your what's your
drying
situation like so i dry in my actual
room and my
because i have the ac in here it kind of
keeps the room really cool so the
problem is actually cooler than the
actual fire room so if it's 82 in the
room in
the flower room it's about 72 it's like
10 degrees it's a diff it's a difference
for sure like
literally you can walk out the flower
room and feel the difference so
um with me having the lights off and
everything once i harvest i like to
give myself two weeks before i actually
reset the flower room so within that two
weeks i have everything drying and it's
like a 60
it's like a 69 ish 69 degrees
uh about 50 52 degrees humidity
i mean 50 humidity and i like to dry
around there and
i'd keep it about seven to ten days
depending
i'll keep it longer if it's a you know
if i got some girths
if you had to dip them in water or
anything oh no i haven't had you they've
been in water
i haven't had any p.m since that problem
yeah that's good i made sure of that i
made sure
that but yeah i like to dry 60 i drive
around 69
degrees 52 humidity uh 7 to 10 days
and depending on if i have some fat ass
but like some fat buds i'll keep it a
little longer just to make sure
but um yeah that's pretty much the baby
j
dry method that's awesome and you're
still you're are you still rolling the
same wattage in your flower room as you
were when you got this healed
and you just had a harvest so you'll be
able to maybe update us on
or you know on your yield from this
harvest you think it's gonna be bigger
or
good too if anything it's gonna be about
the same um
because i had two plants in there it's
actually the pheno2 of the same strain
that i got a pound off of
but um it's because of the phenol it's
not as
heavy yielding so i'm not going to get
you know as heavy yielding properties
that's why that's one of the reasons why
i didn't keep that pheno
but um i should pull pretty close too
because the mayhem bears which is
another string from canon genetics
is i mean the budge i mean mr grow it if
you
you you seen these buds are freaking
huge man
yeah i've seen some of your uh some of
your recent videos like i said and um
it's really impressive if you guys
haven't seen uh baby jay's garden you've
got to go over to her channel and check
it out because she's
really growing some really nice healthy
plants thank you so much man
i think we got one more question for you
mr growit uh
the loaded question yeah you usually ask
this one i like this one
i like this question all right so so
listen to this one
knowing what you know now if you can go
back in time
and talk to yourself right before you
started your first grow
what advice would you give yourself
simple do not mix a gallons worth of
nutrients in a little mini bottle
that is the worst mistake you could ever
make because it was like immediate
like it was immediate damage like
literally the plant started wilting
immediately when it got defeating
wow oh man i wish that would have been
on video
oh my god i met you guys i kind of wish
i didn't because
i'm one of those i like to show my
mistakes just so people know that i'm
not you know
i you know i have mistakes still too you
know with growing you're going to have
you're going to run into mistakes all
the time so
i like to document everything and i
really wish i was more comfortable back
then to be able to document that because
that was some it was funny it was really
funny every time i talk tell people
about that
they just crack up yeah it would be
sweet to watch like a time lapse video
and fast forward of like the plant
reacting to
being over fed or underwatered or like
stuff like that
but yeah i would i would say you know
makes my ratios
you know and i need to get better with
mixing my ratios for the nutrients
i would say get my i should have got my
ac unit sooner because
i was running into heat issues with my
cfls because like when once it gets hot
it gets hot
and the humidity was high and i started
getting fungus gnats i'm you know
i still get fungus in that till the day
but i got a really bad fungus in that
infestation
um on my season three so i would say get
my temperature and everything under
control
have better air circulation because if i
would have had better air circulation
in that flower room i would probably
wouldn't have had as bad of a fungus
that infestation
as i did so baby j what um do you have
anything like upcoming are you working
on like any projects or anything
what's what's the next reason of course
i want everybody to stay tuned for the
breeding project that i have going on
right now i mean i'm harvesting a [ __ ]
ton of pollen right now so i can get it
started
um i got my my sec my new round coming
on is about to be in the fire room
within the next week or so so
i want everybody to stay tuned for that
really got some great content coming
nice so how does everybody find you
through
youtube and social media and all that
stuff uh you can find me
on youtube at thegrow420 diaries um and
on instagram
grow 420 diaries as well very very
active on both
social media sites and um you can
contact them
contact me through email as well if you
you know you want to be more personal
all links to
her channel and social media will be in
the description section below
that's definitely man i really
appreciate you guys having me on the
show today i really really enjoyed it
really love talking about growing i'm
telling you it's really it's great to
talk about growing with people that
actually enjoy talking about growing
if you get what i'm saying yeah for sure
it's it's awesome we love doing this
podcast um we didn't we didn't know what
it was gonna be like going into it we've
got
we've recorded a few episodes so far but
we're still kind of figuring out
figuring it out and
we're still this episode was so full of
good information
and it was awesome having you on we
appreciate it
thank you so much hope to see hope to be
on another one thanks a lot baby jay
have a good one all right take care
[Music]
you