welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
155 in this episode I interview skit P
he has been guarding for 10 years and is
also a breeder he talks all about how he
does breeding in this episode everything
from the types of breeding he does what
he looks for in male and female plants
how he grows the plants when breeding
and more if you want to see short clips
of these podcast episodes search Garden
talk clips on YouTube I also have a
gardening Channel where I show the
plants that I grow both of those
channels will be linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who helped make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their controller
AI plus the first controller to use
artificial intelligence to run your grow
for you connect your grow devices to the
controller AI plus and pair it with the
AC Infinity app to gain access to the AI
tools that predict learn and adapt to
patterns and spikes for the most optimal
environment there's a lot more to it so
click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about the controller AI plus and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and and their website AC
infiniti.com stash blend stash blend
consists of several ingredients in one
so you no longer have to buy individual
bottles it includes corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and micro risal fungi it
can be used in addition to your
synthetic base nutrients or be used in
living soil systems simply mix it into
water and water your plants with it you
can get it at stash blend.com Link in
the description section below and used
to discount code the stash Mars Hydro
their Black Friday Sal is going on right
now you can get up to 25% off get 5x
points buy more get more and they also
are doing weekly flash sales everything
from grow lights grow tents grow tent
kits ventilation systems and more go to
the website at mars-hydro
docomo and you you can use discount code
Mr Grow it to save even more and we are
back and I'm joined with skit P how you
doing today oh all right all right how
about yourself doing pretty good man
thanks for coming on to the podcast
today today's going to be a fun talk
we're going to talk all about breeding
and there are so many different ways to
breed plants aim breeding reversing back
crossing the list goes on so I want to
dig in you know pick your brain a little
bit find out what you do your style of
breeding and things that kind of go
along with that you know how the plants
are grown throughout the grow cycle fale
hunting all that stuff but before we get
too deep into it can you give us a
little bit introduction tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening oh well hey skit PE uh man I
got in the gardening actually it started
way back as a shorty you know um really
just watching my grandfather work in the
garden and whatnot that he had in the
backyard and and just he grew these
crazy Tomatoes just all over the place
and you know that was kind of inspired
you know and um was always just uh just
driven to kind of really I guess just
produce my own and create my own you
know I mean as I am a Creator I'm kind
of all over the place from you know uh a
musician you know artist writer all that
stuff I just that's my thing nice and I
know you said before we hit the record
button you've been guarding for about 10
years now how did you get into breeding
talk to us about how that came about so
wow you know when it comes to breeding
you know that was that was really the
starting point for me you know um
when I first wanted to dive into you
know just uh the cultivation of the me
the medical plants um you know I wanted
to create my own you know I wanted the
like the master strand I was just like
well this is good but I know it could be
great if we take this and bring it with
that and bring it all together and it's
going to be amazing you know right um so
that was that was really the driving
force you know that got me going and um
and really just Hey where's the pollen
where's the feale emails say let's make
it happen and that uh that creativity
turned not just into gardening or
breeding but you're also a movie
producer and uh you put me in your film
so I'm officially a movie star I've got
Lion's gate hitting me up Disney hit me
up I'm just kidding I'm just kidding but
you do have a movie out can you talk
about your movie that you got real quick
yeah so uh the name of the film is
designer uh it's based a little bit you
know off my own experiences and whatnot
you know with a little bit of
embellishment you know for uh
entertainment purposes and whatnot um
it's uh really about a guy that's on a
journey you know to hey create the
master strain right and um along this
journey it's a it's a bit of a different
events you know and um yeah you know we
got you in it Mr Grow it which was
amazing you know we was able to make
that happen you know uh been a long time
view of your content and uh it's really
actually helped me in my own personal
journey of things you know uh just from
where we're at you know where I was and
where I'm at now you know so yeah that
was awesome man yeah I was so uh so
stoked when you hit me up and you're
like be in my movie I'm like movie whoa
that's so cool and then uh what you told
me about like the actual story of it and
now it's on tuby so people can watch it
for free on tub is that right it's
definitely available on tub um and
there's also a few other platforms
that'll be coming out in the near future
you know uh definitely looking to get it
on Prime but right now definitely check
it out to be hey it's live you know tap
in get the app right
now awesome congrats on all your success
there thank you thank you let's get into
breeding so like I mentioned there are
so many different types of breeding you
can do in breeding reversing back
Crossing what do you do for like what
what's your style of breeding what do
you do so forgive me for not having all
the uh formal terms and whatnot but it
really just uh my initial
uh I guess Beginnings with the breeding
you know it started really with uh the
first one was midnight cush and it was
that was the name of the strin and um
then it was just a a random uh seed that
I had lying around and luckily it was a
male and you know from there I was just
I kind of just was crossing it with
different ones I you know visiting
various seed banks and whatnot and um
and just you know I was just just
crossing them you know until I got a
little bit further on you know uh I
became priview you know to some of your
content and everything and then I know
uh the pheno hunting the back Crossing
and some of those topics and whatnot um
and it was uh that was when I the first
time I implemented the back Crossing you
know when I was just looking to try to
like just kind of he like hone in on
some of the uh characteristics of pretty
much one in particular you know um but
yeah okay so you're mostly doing kind of
the inbreeding side of things you're
taking one from one side mother father
Crossing that and then are you working
yourself down generation to generation
or you kind of just sticking with the
f1s I really just been sticking with the
f1s at this current time um up to the
point so yeah and I'm currently feno
hunting right now um in this particular
stage where I'm at I've been uh pretty
much just crossing down up to the point
and uh like I said once I kind of back
cross cuz I I was running into some
issues with uh it was actually I had
some Hermes in there where it was
expressing that so obviously that's
going to be a issue for you know
depending on how you look at
things so uh we definitely was looking
to to get that out of there and the back
Crossing um it definitely seemed to be
the way to get it out you know it just
with the really just like the one time
and it was for the most part okay so how
did you do that back cross so you did
that initial cross right and The
Offspring of that you planted you
finding Herms and then you uh would you
take one that wasn't a Herm and kind of
back crossed it to the father or how did
you do that so what ended up happening
was my particular cross that I've been
working with it had some hermy jeans in
um so what ended up happening was I kind
of got lucky I had a forbidden fruit uh
and I got a female and a male now when I
got the male I saved the pollen you know
I you know put it in the bag froze it so
I was able to preserve it and pretty
much over time what I ended up doing was
after the initial cross you know I ended
up with the forbidden fruit um pollen
that I had I ended up Crossing that back
into the mix and that next
Offspring it appeared that the hermy you
know Gene that it was expressing
previously was pretty much Clear okay
talk to us about your favorite cross
that you've ever created first of all
how many crosses have you done roughly
and what's your favorite one I'd have to
say up to this point um it was one of
the ones I referenced to as a night
cheddar cuz after the initial Cross of
the midnight cush with the uh the Rando
SE that I just had lying around um I
ended up Crossing it with a a blue
cheese and um I just remember the the
turpine profile of it was it it was just
something very unique I I'll say that
and I wish I actually uh due to the fact
that it was so early on and uh you know
I had the seeds for quite some time I
never
really you know I wish I was more into
feno hunting back in the day that's all
I could say because I I definitely
missed that one you know by the time I
actually thought about it it was sitting
around I kind of was already jumping
down the strain of I got to cross this
one with that one I still don't have it
yet
um you know it ended up uh yeah when I
tried coming back around like later in
the years and whatnot cuz I just been
holding on to them the seeds were pretty
much I couldn't get any of them
germinate so it was uh null and void you
know oh damn so on that cross what was
like the flavors and smells and effects
that you got out of it it just felt like
uh how can I it was just very like
floaty you know nothing too crazy where
it's going to be like the couch lock
effect but you know if you got things to
do you know it was still you know it
just was more so like a a even kill it
felt like a 5050 you know I've never
done any you know formal testing or
whatnot but just going off of like the
overall effects of it it was uh it was a
very like balanced kind of a effect that
you you know garnered from it um I felt
like it was like hints of the cheese you
know but there was also a remnants of
the midnight Kush which I was very fond
of it was um kind of gassy you know uh
it was elements of that it was just a
very nice blend from what I could
remember okay now are your genetics
available to the community or do you
just keep them internal no right now you
know it's all internal you know last
thing I want to do is put out some bad
uh you know genetics of any kind or
something that'll be uh cumbersome to
you know to work with you know I really
want to you know get it to a point where
it would be you know um it would be very
advantageous I would say for a new
beginner you know grower to come into it
and or or to a Conor sewer can also like
appreciate it you know
so it still has some work to be done for
sure for sure you know makes sense yeah
it can take so long to get through the
process I mean I started chill out OG
it's a the only cross I've actually ever
done in 2019 so started and I released
to the community in 2023 it took me kind
of several years in order to kind of
really confident that what I had was
going to be stable enough to we really
weren't going to find any Herms or say
many I would to say none because like
from my understanding it's still kind of
always within its genetics no matter
what I know some people will debate that
fact but for the most part what I was
Finding in the population I wasn't
really finding any hermaphrodite plants
so got to the point where I was
comfortable to actually do the release
but yeah it takes very very long time so
uh you you got to have patience for it
you know I know some people will just
pollen Chuck and then they'll create
seeds and then push it out to the
community without testing that's a
separate conversation but yeah it seems
like you're going about it the right
ethical way to where you haven't even
released anything yet you're just kind
of working things so it's good to hear
definitely definitely you know uh I
think also too after watching some of
the content and listening in on on some
of the discussions I was like I'm going
get ridiculed I I can't I can't have
myself out there like that you know so
there a lot of pressure you know what I
mean it's it's like if you if you
release something there's just a bunch
of Herms I mean look what happened to
Humbolt seed company they released the
donuts triploid and it's like a really
really high percentage of Herms and it
they got exposed and it was just not a
good thing for them and I don't I don't
think they're selling them anymore their
listing is still up but it was a
catastrophe and uh yeah that's
apparently there wasn't enough testing
done yes they we just doing it Outdoors
once they got to indoors that's like I
guess where a lot of those problems were
happening yeah which that's interesting
you know that environmental change you
know can definitely impact a lot of
things for sure oh for sure yeah
absolutely but yeah it's good that
you're patient with things it's good to
here now when you are doing pheno
hunting right when you're looking for
that male when you're looking for that
female there are different
characteristics that you can look for
talking about males in particular what
do you typically look for when searching
for males to breed with
so I mean the biggest thing is how fast
is it growing how well does it adapt to
my environment right you know um and
also too one thing I've implemented as
of late I feel that uh more so a more
mature male plant at least from my own
experience doing the stem rub you know
just to see the tarpine because I feel
like that adds to the experience and
that's one of the things I feel like
when feno hunting just in general you
know is just looking for that that tur
profile that you know that essence you
know I feel like that's why you know
people burn incense you know that that
experience is everything you know um
well at least a big part of it um
obviously the flavor but you can't tell
that right there from the mail you know
but as far as the mail goes yeah that's
the biggest things you know growth
factors how well it thrives in my
environment because that's where I'm
going be growing it predominantly and
yeah you know the smell that I'm getting
from it if any and then how about female
plants do you look for kind of the same
thing are there other characteristics
that you look for when searching for
female plants to breed with so with the
females is more so I'd say like Midway
through you know I'm kind of looking for
certain things once again the smell that
is putting out uh the flower development
you know the node separation all those
things um
also the fan Leaf production as of
recent you know it's been a big thing
that I've been experiencing you know
just with implementing certain strains
into the cross it kind of like I don't I
don't know if it would be a mutation or
it's just a overabundance of that Gene
or whatever you know I can't say you
know but uh I know that's huge because
if you don't want to defoliate you know
three four times throughout the process
maybe five six you know uh some of them
you're just crazy with family production
and that could be a hindrance for some
that's interesting yeah so the
morphology of the plant you're looking
real deep into that and kind of
selecting from there huh yeah you know
all those characteristics you know for
the most part and you know at that point
you know like Midway through at least it
would be you know if you're looking to
um breed and whatnot and have something
available clone it if it looks anywh you
know um of something you know uh desire
characteristics that I'm seing and then
from there uh you know obviously the
effect that you know I would get from it
you know um upon Harvest but which is
why it's definitely you know you want to
clone it you know Midway through if it's
even looking of such and obviously you
got the triom production and things of
that nature because if you're looking
for like extracts and whatnot um I've
come across you know some interesting
you know strains out there where I've
seen just looking under the jeweler's
Loop the Tricom production is very
interesting you know it's just uh some
are far more prevalent than others you
know like I've seen them where they're
looking like they're almost like stacked
on top of each other it's it's pretty
wild you mentioned Midway through you
take clones are you talking Midway
through veg period period or are you
going into flower and uh taking clones
dur the flower stage yeah meaning the
actual flower stage you know um in
regards to the female plant you know uh
cuz I know when we speak on seeking
characteristics for me you know uh as
far as a female is concerned you know
that's when we're going to see like what
we're really getting granted structure
and whatnot um but you know the plan
itself can always be manipulated you
know to the growth space you know using
various techniques and whatnot so you
know that's really not a big thing for
me I'm just I'm really seeking the
overall effect
um and you know really once again
adaptability to the environment you know
um some are far more heavier feeders
than others you know and whatnot and
then I sometimes I I do like to maybe
grow one or
two at least two you know different
strains throughout so that way when I
harvest you know I could have a
different selection and whatnot cuz you
know you could kind of get used to uh
one plant you know so it's nice for a
change up got it so you're doing what a
lot of people call monster cropping
where you're basically just taking a
clone and flower bringing it back
revegging it and then kind of working
with from there that makes sense i' I've
been doing that recently and I've had
pasts where I was taking clones within
the veg stage and yeah I mean you can
argue that it takes a little bit longer
to go through the Rev process but a
letot people have the time you know if
you're working the plants and finishing
off the flowering stage you can bring
that back and by the time you finish
that Harvest well it's already reving
and you're kind of working on it there
so timing I think is kind of important
when it comes to on that Avenue yeah for
sure you know I I think uh there's been
times where I've seen a plant and maybe
I I'll go ahead and you know
um kind of been let down and whatnot you
know hey it smells good and everything
like that and it's like oh we need this
this and then by the time we get to
actually experiencing the effects of it
it's very underwhelming and it was just
like ah you know
so it like you said very timec consuming
you know when going through the process
I think sometimes I could be overly
patient but hey you know yeah I guess
you can't rush perfection right all
right let's get deeper into the actual
growing process when you're breeding so
when you are breeding are you in soil
cocoa
Hydroponics well soil it's a bit of a
mixture I know I probably get ridiculed
for this cuz I've seen um different
sides of it but I'm kind of using I
guess it would be a bit of a three-part
you know it's already a premixed soil um
I just recently added like some cocoa in
it so I I kind of like broke it down and
then I have perlite
where I don't know if it would still be
defined as soil lless or whatever I know
some people have reference uh to it as
but um that's just my thing it's just
like the three-part you know it's very
light you know adding the extra cocoa in
as well with the perite
um so yeah but yeah soil nonetheless I
know I'm getting into specifics and
whatnot oh let's get into specifics so
what was it like a brand of bagged soil
that you mix with the cocoa and what's
the ratio between soil and cocoa and
prite so I would just say it's um just a
three-part you know so one part soil one
part cocoa and then one part
perlite um the what is it I want to say
it's uh Earth's forest or Earth's floor
something like that it's the green bag
that I think you could probably find in
every you know uh Garden store you know
that's uh in your local neighborhood so
yeah okay so one to one to one and then
what do you use for nutrients throughout
the growth cycle and how do you go about
those feedings throughout the growth
cycle do we have to name uh we talking
name brands or we just talking yeah you
talk Brands that' be helpful because the
the folks do like to have the details
now you don't want to reveal anything by
all means you don't have to buty it's
more so cuz I I feel like I'm going to
get lit up in the comments with it but I
use I use General Hydroponics honestly
because it's the most uh cost effective
but um I really just use their base veg
uh you know for veg I add the the silica
I also supplement the cow mag the micro
um and then I also uh throw some sugars
in there um I forget the name of it but
it's pretty much at the end of the day
it's like like a cane sugar base along
with some black strap molasses and you
know the basic stuff you know try to
keep it basic little bit of micro rising
in there throughout the process and just
to keep it going so I assume you're
following the General Hydroponics
feeding chart are you doing the full
dose according to what it says on the
chart are you doing half dose or or what
you know in all honesty I couldn't tell
you what it says I know I I just used
the five milliliters you know uh of
every single one that I use I throw it
together I do it all together you know
so I call it the uh I think we call it
the swamp juice if I'm not mistaken me
and my buddy but uh you know um yeah it
just mix it all together you know 5 MLS
each and then is every other you know uh
every other feeding so pretty much give
it the noes one water it with just some
sugar and then repeat are you doing the
same type of ratios for plants that
you're growing for flower production for
example versus a run where you're
creating seeds I know some people what
they do is they'll just stay on that V
ratio while they're creating seeds for
the entire run for the whole flowering
period and then they swear that that
helps with healthier seeds just
wondering if you did that technique or
did you just stick with what the feeding
chart says for most flowering uh Parts
where it basically knocks down the
nitrogen and increases the phosphorus of
potassium so yeah um when it when we
switch over to flour it's pretty much
obviously I'm not feeding it the the veg
NES at that point which is pretty much
you know high in nitrogen and everything
I switch to the flower base and that's
the the major thing that I I use um I
guess the major difference that's it
everything else is pretty much the same
um and you know there will be at some
point I'll say
roughly maybe six to 7even weeks I might
up the dosing of the phosphorus you know
which is pretty much the flower base you
know instead of from 5 MLS to 10 um and
then I'd say it's usually about you know
two weeks about a week and a half at
that point I I'll just switch to pretty
much you know the water and sugar you
know and um that's pretty much it I I've
never really done anything known have I
known for that to I guess uh help with
any healthier seeds or anything like
that I've always just tried to keep it
as basic as possible and uh and repeat
you know and if I do try something it's
always maybe a little bit here a little
bit there instead of just diving into it
need you know got it yeah I've mostly
just been doing when I have a seated run
a breeding run where have crossed a male
and a female or pollinated a female and
it's creating seeds I have mostly just
been falling the feeding show where it
does kind of you know when you get into
flowering it's reducing the nitrogen
increasing the phosphorus and potassium
but this run in particular actually
working on F4 generation of chill OG and
this run I am kind of sticking with the
what it says for week one flower where
it kind of knocks back the nitrogen but
not as much as it does later on in
flowering and I'm just sticking with
that for the entire power in stage and
so far so good I mean I've got a couple
weeks left here until I harvest and the
true telling will be once I dry and then
crumble up the flowers and see what does
the seeds look like are there any
underdeveloped seeds what's the
percentage of developed seeds versus
Under underdeveloped seeds so on and so
forth so yeah I'm personally doing a
little little experimenting there when
it comes to uh the nutrients and and how
I do my feedings so let me ask you
something had do you find when you have
a plant that has seeds in it it takes
longer to mature or does uh does that
affect anything for you as far as the
development time 100% yeah I push it
further in order to try to get more
seeds developed so like right now I
could if I was just growing the females
and just harvesting the buds I'd be
harvesting them right now but I'm going
to push it additional weeks in order to
try to get more seeds out of it so I am
starting to see the fade on the plant
like normal normal Essence that happens
towards the end of the grow cycle I'm
keeping a close aisle for nanners to
potentially pop out nothing so far but
uh yeah I push it a couple more weeks in
order to try to get more more yield of
seeds out of it I think a lot of folks
do that and I I think it's a smart way
to go about it just got to keep an eye
on making sure like the seeds will drop
off the plant right so like it continues
to grow and KX open up and then the
seeds drop so if you have a whole bunch
of plants in the same grow space all the
seeds are dropping you might get mixed
up on what's what so you don't want to
go too long because you're going to have
all these seeds all over the floor but
uh yeah I definitely push it a little
bit longer than uh than I normally would
with just a a female plant that hasn't
been pollinated okay yeah I'm just
curious let's get into Precision stress
techniques so a lot of people will do
things to stress the plant in order to
try to get a better result do you do any
Precision stress techniques specifically
when breeding or fenal hunting so I've
done a lot over uh the years you know
just trying different uh techniques I
guess you would say you know everything
from almost impaling a pencil you know
into the base of it you know where it
splits it out and um you know cuz it's
supposed to create more Tri cone
production and everything else um
amongst uh many of other just different
things you know that they put out there
I I feel like we've all gone through
that but um the one the base that I
stick to is topping and LST I keep it
basic I like the top relatively early
um to allow you know
those the uh stems that is Created from
the topping you know to really develop
you know and you know to have a a base
that can pretty much hold up some heavy
uh flowers you know um but yeah and then
I also like in regards to the LS which
is there's so many ways to go about it
and it really just depends on like the
growth space and whatnot you know in
particular I like to kind of create the
branched out of effect where uh you know
you and then it kind of grows up
um the more tops the more yield I'm
definitely a yield guy I like to uh get
the most out of the Harvest understood
and then within the gross space there
different environment conditions that
you can aim for temperature relative
humidity some people supplement CO2 can
you talk to us about what environment
conditions that you aim for when
breeding so I definitely so when
breeding um I would treat it just as any
other uh flowering portion of the uh of
the grow time um you know I like to keep
it you know in between in between the
spectrum of like 55 you know 60 right
there I feel like that's the sweet spot
for me at least um and then as far as
temperature you know I in between 60 and
70 is is kind of a peak you know um I'm
one that I'm a fan of the purple color
and you know so I I was just like to see
what the plant does in the cooler
temperatures you know it's always uh
pretty interesting got it so pretty
straightforward there now when breeding
there so many different Expressions that
you can see amongst the plants mutations
happen every now and then right have you
come across any mutations when breeding
what would you refer to as a a mutation
anything from like Duck's foot or uh to
long list of ones albino plants uh
anything like that any funky growth that
you seen could be Twisted leaves
anything like that at all or no uh you
know I can't say so much mutations like
that the the only thing I would
reference to I guess would be close to a
mutation is a plant that grows like it's
been topped just by itself it doesn't
stick to the um the normal I guess
Christmas tree you know type look it's
it it's very branchy almost like if you
were to flip a a grape you know like a a
The Grapes pretty much upside down and
how that would look you know it it does
something along those very very weird
you know but yeah I that would be the
the closest to a mutation I would I
would say I've seen yeah I I call that
self topping how it's like it just kind
of splits off into two different
directions without you even even doing
the topping right yeah and I I feel some
of that is induced with the LST method
when you kind of expose the lower
branches where they normally wouldn't
get I guess they wouldn't normally
develop as they would you know um if it
you just let it do what it would do by
itself so some of it may be you know uh
my own doing I guess to some extent but
like I said some of them that I have
seen some plants that just grow like
that um yeah one in particular I want to
say it is uh might be from Herby seeds
if I'm not mistaken it's the uh Apple
betties and the runs punch I want to say
I seen kind of that's at least what I
experienced from it it was it was
interesting cool I had to pull up the
list here of potential mutations we've
got poly Ploy stringy Australian bastard
or ABC uh there is vinik there's creeper
phenotype Ducks foot I already mentioned
Leaf buds we have buds actually that are
on the pedal between the pedial and the
actual Leaf albino which I talked about
Ford phot taxi that's the quick list of
mutations and there's also that double
seedling I don't know if you've ever
come across I've seen some people come
across it where they plant a seed and
then two Sprout out I thought that was
pretty cool I can't say that I've
experienced that but the uh the butt in
between the leaves you know that sounds
interesting like I think that would just
be cool to see I don't know yeah yeah I
actually haven't come across that yet
but I'm waiting I'm waiting I wonder
what the odds are to come across that
maybe I don't know one in 10,000 or
something I don't even know what those
that would be if anybody knows comment
below man please please let me know hey
and take a picture take a picture so
there are many challenges that you could
come across when breeding what are some
common challenges that you Face
Time um
knowledge uh you know when I started it
was a very uh I guess primitive concept
of uh just growing in general let alone
breeding you know given the information
that was available to me uh versus uh
you know where we're at now you know
it's so readily available I'm kind of
jealous of all the new Growers getting
into the game you know they just got all
this is just it's just there for him you
know um but yeah um but as far as uh
yeah so a lot of it is just you know
knowledge and everything so that those
are some of my own uh personal obstacles
um not making the most of each of each
grow you know and that just kind of
falls into the knowledge right not
knowing up until I'd say about uh 3 4
years ago just feno hunting right that's
when it finally dawned on me I was like
whoa so that
means what I found to be underwhelming
the one or two seeds that I grew out of
the batch and was like uh this is all
right you know I could have had
something amazing in that batch you know
cuz now knowing like okay a F1 versus a
F3 um man and also too when you're
implementing certain
genetics even with just the seed banks
I'm seeing some now put this in like the
listings but actually putting F1 F2
F3 um which I I really love you know
just the transparency because that could
help with making a decision you know
just with uh I guess uh limiting the
variables of of what you may get you
know um especially when you're seeking a
particular like trait from what they're
uh you know putting in the description
of that particular
so um man it's it's so many I could I
could ramble on all day for as far as
obstacles that you may come across as
breeding you know because this yeah it's
been a long
one yeah it's crazy how many different
phenotypes you can find within a batch
of seeds how many different Expressions
you can find and I think the fenal
hunting part is real fun and you
mentioned kind of knowledge is being a
uh challenge that you face I think with
breeding in particular there's so much
to know and sure there's some
information on the internet right you
can just do Google searches and and
learn how to do breeding there and learn
the different terms and different ways
to go about and stuff like that but it
might be valuable to purchase a book you
know there are many books out there I
just bought the one by James loud he has
one on breeding and uh that's been my
go-to as of right now anything that cuz
he just released it I think this year
maybe 2024 or maybe he released in 2023
but I just got my hands on it this year
very detailed book and you know you can
just easily get to it and I can just go
over my bookshelf there pick it out and
then go back to the index if I'm looking
for something in particular or look by
chapter and uh learn so much it's I
really recommend folks dig into some of
these books that are out there because
again sure you can go ahead and do
Google searches on the internet but
unfortunately there's a lot of mixed
information M
misinformation it can be tougher a
little bit tougher to navigate in my
opinion so yeah I can totally see how
the knowledge can be a barrier and I'm
glad you brought that one up oh yeah now
how about common
misconceptions about breeding what are
some things that you feel like people
say is one thing but it's actually a
misconception oh wow man that kind of
Falls uh into the knowledge portion of
it which I mean hey the Mis I one of the
things that it was a misconception for
me was hey you take this OG and mix it
with this sherb over here and uh the
first uh you know one you try is going
to be amazing cuz you had two amazing
plants and it's still a journey from
there you know um so that right there
I'd say one for sure um and wow you know
what may grow good in your environment
may not be suitable from you know for
someone else's you know
uh the region that you're in you may it
may be more humidity or lack thereof you
know so um while this plant May Thrive
the cooler temperatures at night you
know um and some plants is is not going
to uh happen I've had some while you
know just testing out genetics and
whatnot some thrived you know in the
cool like the colder temperatures and it
just did some cool things you know with
the colors and whatnot right but then
others the the harvest or or you know I
guess if I could even call the Harvest
you know it was underdeveloped flour and
everything else that you know you were
dealing with so um yeah those are some
good ones let's talk about the future of
breeding what trends do you see in the
future and how might advances in
genetics and Technology shape the next
generation of strains oh man um you know
I say first of all is uh definitely the
the transparency and the things that's
just out there right now um is going to
help with everything you know um people
that are aspiring you know that aspiring
breeders and and may have like a goal in
mind mind that they want to do I think
that that's huge um but as far as on the
technology
level I I which I'd have to imagine
they're already doing some of these
things I mean I I've never worn a lab
coat you know or whatnot but I know you
know just from seeing how they cross the
plants and just the vegetables that we
have every day you know um and really
being able to hone in and just
manipulate things like um I'd have to
say like maybe to the point with a
crisper if you're familiar with that
like some of that technology I mean if
they're you know able to hone in on
certain genes you know within us I mean
obviously they could do it with the
plants I know they can and if you have
Precision technology like that uh you
know you could do some amazing things I
mean I'd have to say the uh the future
is really is kind of endless you know um
yeah or the possibility yeah I think
there's going to be a lot of changes in
the future for breeding I mean tissue
culture that's becoming more and more
popular it's becoming more and more
accessible
to the hom Growers I know Athena put out
that tissue culture kit I haven't had a
chance to try it myself but seems like
it makes things a lot more easier for
small home Growers individuals to do
tissue culture and I foresee people
using that to kind of store genetics I
think also uh testing will kind of be
get a lot better in the future being
able to test for resistance pathogens
diseases so on and so forth I think
that's going to be big in the future but
yeah we'll see I mean it's it's kind of
hard to imagine the whole crisper thing
is nuts I've seen a few documentaries on
it and seeing what they're doing with
like humans you know and how there was
somebody in China who who did it for a
birth or something like that and I was
like what the heck yeah yeah it's wild
to see what the future is like for that
and how that translates over to the
plant side of things yeah I think they
reference to them as designer babies you
know so uh I'm sure they got designer
plants for sure you know it's going down
um I mean yeah it's just it's it's
really interesting I think some of the
things that you touched on I know uh
just the technology I I think being
readily available to the hom grower
right you know just to the average
consumer you know you would say um I
think that that's huge uh I know some of
the testing that they have like uh with
being able to determine whether it's
male or female I know uh some things
like that you know available um
personally I've never uh you know used
it but you know uh because at this point
I'm I'm kind of stuck in the Stone Age
with some of the things I'm like I'm
going just stick to what I know and and
whatnot you know um but yeah you know
that's uh that that that's huge I mean
accessibility is everything that DNA sex
testing is what you're talking about I
actually just sent out a bunch of
samples the other day and I'm waiting to
hear back that service is awesome little
bit off topic here but but that's really
helpful how long does that take once
they receive the samples you're able to
they flip it and within a day or so they
give you the result and then so like I
have seedlings that just popped mhm I
went ahead and snipped off the cot lead
leavea of each one sent those in and now
I should be able to identify what the MS
are and kill them off before I hit day
14 of
sprout and so like that helps out a ton
because I'm not wasting time
transplanting nutrients watering all
that space all that stuff is saved cuz
I'm able to kill off my males here and
in about a week actually in a couple
days wouldn't be surprised if I got it
back on uh a Friday we're on Wednesday
here and I shipped it out on Monday so
yeah I should hopefully get the result
back and then that that helps and
actually does relate to the whole
breeding side of things because that's a
tool that you can use in order to kind
of speed things up a little bit right so
you're not just if you're not if you're
not looking for males or if you just
want to segregate your males you want to
identify what your males and females are
and you can put them in different spaces
yeah I guess it actually does relate to
to what we're talking about here but
yeah really good service I do use it
often I'm going definitely that's
something I'm might have to tap into for
sure for sure um you know cuz while I
I've more so kind of transition into the
feno hunting and just locking in you
know on this latest Cross of mind um you
know that's definitely something in the
future that will definitely speed up the
process cuz like you say it's a lot of
resources lost you know with the energy
and everything else you know the all the
lights and even though they've uh I
think the energy build is you know
they've condensed on that you know and
helped out with the savings a little bit
with the LED and everything but uh cuz
man you know I started off with the
metal highight and the uh what is that
hpl uh the HPS yes yeah HPS thank you
thank you thank you it's been honestly
it's really just been collecting dust
you know uh at this point you know since
I transition to LED it's like I can't go
back while it it helped out a lot on the
heating aspect of things you know if you
didn't have a heater in the space and
you had some cooler temperatures um I I
just buy a mini heater at this point you
know I think it yeah it eats up more uh
energy than anything so we have a lot of
beginners that tune into this podcast
really this podcast is for all
experience levels beginner intermediate
Advanced and the guests are also on all
experience levels but we do have a lot
of folks that are tuning in right now
that are beginners and they're just
getting started breeding what advice do
you have for them watch Garden
talk just continue to tune into to this
podcast and uh you'll learn everything
just Kidd that's it that's it you know
hey hey grab a book obviously you know
do your research you know cross
reference um but really study study
before just diving into it you know um
you know uh save yourself you know a
couple of steps you know uh that I could
have saved I guess you know uh because I
remember I think I killed my first two
uh times around or I you know I don't
know if I could say that I we're talking
about plants but uh you know
but you know hey uh my first two
attempts did not last so you know um
really just study you know um understand
it what what it is that you're you know
you're doing with this and what it takes
and uh cuz everything is you know is
different you know uh they're not all
the same you know you got some
that yeah so study the strain you know
um because you it often times you can't
just take a one siiz fit all approach
you know definitely some good advice
there so let's uh let's wrap things up
here can you tell the listeners how they
can find you and what you have upcoming
in the future man what's upcoming in the
future you know uh everything and
everything um you know you can find me
at at Instagram Facebook YouTube uh or
just go directly to another Vision
productions.com you know you can find me
there and um you know hey definitely in
a lot of spaces but yeah you know just
search up skit P another Vision
production
and you'll find me in the rest of the
crew I'll definitely have a link to your
Instagram down in the YouTube
description section below so folks that
are tuning in on YouTube can click on
the description section and click your
link right away so go ahead and give him
a follow if you are looking to follow
his breeding journey and then also
follow up on his movies and Productions
that he's doing that movie I was in I
think a lot of people will like it it's
a you know Stoner comedy really and uh
that's the audience here so I did it for
the
people also big thanks to the folks that
are supporting on patreon 100% of the
money that supported through patreon
goes right back into the podcast
everything from paying for the editor
paying for the podcast platform all that
stuff is covered through your support on
patreon so thank you so much
patreon.com grow on the screen right now
big thanks to the folks in the producer
tier appreciate you well skip thanks so
much for coming on to the podcast today
I appreciate you chopping it up and kind
of breaking it down for us kind of how
you go about breeding and how you do the
grow and so on and so forth so thanks so
much and hope you enjoy the rest of your
day oh man right back at you I
appreciate you having me appreciate you
taking the time and uh man it's all love
man hey hopefully we could work in the
future peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode