what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr growit and i'm back with another
q a video
this time around i decided to do
intermediate questions
now some of you may see the questions
that are in this video and think to
yourself this is more of a beginner
question
trust me i do have beginner questions in
a separate category
these ones i felt like they're more
intermediate questions you might
disagree
that being said this will be the
intermediate questions q a
i'll have a beginner questions q a and
also an advanced
questions q a so if you have any
questions that you want me to
potentially answer in a future episode
please leave them down in the comment
section below i do get a ton of
questions in the comment section so
i certainly can't guarantee that i'm
gonna answer every question that's asked
before we get into the questions i just
want to give a quick shout out to our
sponsor for this episode
thanks to mars hydro for sponsoring this
episode they sent me over their
fc-4800 led grill light and this thing
looks pretty awesome
it has 2016 total diodes consisting of
samsung lm301b and osram 616 nanometer
diodes
and they're powered by an inventronix
driver it pulls
480 watts from the wall covers a 4 foot
by 4 foot grow space
and has an efficiency of 2.8 micromoles
per joule
it does have a dimmer on it so you can
adjust the power output
and it's daisy chainable up to 15 lights
i personally like the
bar style design which helps provide an
even light spread across the footprint
i will leave a link to mars hydro
website down in the description section
below
and you can also use coupon code mr
growit for a discount on any of their
products
all right let's get into the video
getting close to harvest
should i do a 48 hour blackout before i
harvest for better results
or is it just a myth so i don't think
there's actually any scientific studies
on
the 48 hours of darkness before harvest
if there actually is a study out there
and somebody knows of it please leave it
down in the comments section below so i
can read into it but things that we do
know about this is
you know number one is that we know
secondary metabolites are
produced during lights-off periods so
secondary metabolites
that includes resin the trichomes that's
produced during
lights-off periods so that's the whole
thought process behind it is
give your plants 48 hours some people do
72 hours
of complete darkness that way the plant
can't produce those secondary
metabolites the extra
resin or trichome production and then
from there you would harvest
so as of right now i guess we can chalk
it up as bro science until
actual science comes out behind it now i
know there are some
youtubers out there that have done their
own individual studies
lost leaf i believe is one of them you
can search for his name
on youtube and he did a 48-hour darkness
study i believe he we actually took
tests
he did thc test results for a plant that
was
48 hours of darkness and one that was
not done with 48 hours of darkness and
he did see a slight difference there so
you may want to check that out to learn
more i'm sure that there's other
youtubers out there
other people who have done their own
individual studies
and reported their findings on whether
or not
48 hours of darkness worked for them or
not
my question is about organic amendment
fertilizers
i understand their instructions however
after using them
and doing a lot of research i found that
although the fertilizers sound great
it's hard to determine when the
nutrients will be plant ready
mineralized do you think going to a
single amendments
bone meal fish meal etc is better for my
conditions
than the premix versions bio live bloom
boost
and if so where's a good place i can
find recommendations you can certainly
do individual amendments instead of
doing the blends
the blends are just one way to go about
it the individual amendments are a
different way to go about it now if
you're going to go the individual
amendment route i highly recommend you
go buy
a soil mix or method that has been tried
and
works a great place where you can find
recommendations is build the soil
so buildthesoil.com they have a
resources
section in there i think they have three
different soil recipes
i know a ton of people that use those
recipes with success
if you really want to go buy the
individual amendments
maybe check out build a sole see if they
have certain ratios
that you need to go by because if your
ratios get out of whack
you may see deficiencies in the plants
some nutrients can lock out other
nutrients
so on and so forth something i seem to
always struggle with those calcium
deficiencies
in transition and flower can't seem to
ever get it 100
would enjoy if you touched on that
specifically so calcium deficiency is
one of the most common deficiencies
out there if you're growing in soil a
lot of folks what they'll do is they'll
add in calmag
every time so they'll add it in along
with their base nutrients
when you're mixing with water calmed
first
then base nutrients and then on watering
days where you're supposed to feed water
only some people also do calmag on
those days as well so that might be what
you're missing is just not
feeding calmag in on watering days could
be causing a deficiency
if you're in coco coir most growers do
feed calmag
every single time as far as dosage 5
to 10 milliliters per gallon i believe
is what the back of most bottled say
you don't have to do a half dose at
least in my experience you don't really
have to do a half dose you can
do a full dose of calmag i know one of
the mistakes that a lot of beginners
make is they'll do
half the dose because they always hear
about half dose of nutrients
that's usually for base nutrients
additives such as calamag you can do a
full dose
one last thing if you're struggling with
calcium deficiency particularly also if
you're growing in soil
is staying above 6.2 ph
provides a little bit better of calcium
uptake can you reuse soil that has
bottled nutrients
if you really try to wash or flush it
out short answer is yes you can reuse
that soil
i've done it before where i've flushed
out the nutrients
in a previous soil that i had used
bottle nutrients on so i flushed it
reused that soil did come across some
deficiencies
i mean when you're doing that you're
risking your nutrient ratio kind of
being out of whack and some nutrients
getting locked out
because there's excess of other
nutrients now when i did actually reuse
soil that i had used bottled nutrients
in
on a previous grow i did actually take
that soil and send in a soil sample to
logan labs
and one thing i found on that soil
sample report was
it was high in sodium and i think that
was
probably one of the reasons why i was
seeing issues
so for me personally i really don't like
to reuse soil that i've used
synthetic nutrients in prior and i think
a lot of growers out there i feel like a
majority of the growers will actually
just
toss out that soil and start fresh just
because there is that risk
um you know it's definitely frustrating
when you're
trying to get through a grow and all of
a sudden you see deficiencies popped up
and all you have you're scrambling have
to flush the plant
and so on and so forth so it's just it
can be a little bit easier if you're
just using fresh soil each time
when using synthetic bottled nutrients
it's a waste but
it can be easier how can you tell if the
strain you're growing is legit strained
to be a mother plant
i think that really comes down to
personal preference you know if you're
growing out a plant and you get into the
flowering stage and you really like how
that plant
looks some of the characteristics that
you're looking for whether it be
you know frost production the colors
so on and so forth and you want to keep
that strain around you can actually
clone it in the flower stage
re-veg it that's called monster cropping
that can be done and that can be taken
and used as a mother plant a lot of
people instead of doing that they'll
actually cut clones while it's in the
vegetation stage still
and they'll keep those plants around
then when they get into flowering if
they like that plant they'll keep those
clones around
and continue to grow maybe they'll use
one of those as a mother plant or if
they don't like that plant that they're
flowering they'll just
dispose of those clones so some people
cut the clones
prior so they have them just in case
they want to keep them others will do
that monster cropping process
and bring it back but as far as how to
tell if your strain is
is good enough to be a mother plant any
photo period plant can be turned into a
mother plant
when you're talking about oil flower
plants those are on a limited life span
so
you definitely can't keep auto flower
plants as mother plants
how do you like earth dust products and
do you add anything else to it when
using it
so i actually struggled using earth dust
at first however over the years
i've gotten the hang of it so i actually
do like using earthdust now
a couple tips i would start in larger
containers i was starting in like three
gallon containers
five gallon containers and sometimes
it's a struggle compared to if you're
using a larger container which
i'm using now i'm using a 7 gallon
container some people use
15 gallon containers or even larger than
that when they're
growing with organic nutrients or living
soil things i add with it
recharge is great mammoth p any microbes
are going to be good data in it
root magic by blue plant nutrients i
like to add into it
i also do teas teas more so in the
flowering stages when i'll add teas in
they're either just a nutrient tea or
with earth dust products you can
actually do
two tablespoons per plant which i think
is what dan from the green sunshine
company recommends
a worm castings you know high quality
worm castings those can be added
just about any point throughout the
grill or can be put into teas
and then i also like to use molasses as
well both as a soil drench
sometimes mostly in flowering stage
and also as a food source in my teeth is
it okay to use flavored epsom salts
than just plain epsom salt if you can't
find it epsom salt is magnesium sulfate
i highly recommend getting a epsom salt
that doesn't have any additives in it so
just look in the back of the directions
look for 100 magnesium sulfate i'm not
sure what additional additives are in
the epsom salt that you're looking at
but
it's probably not good in your garden
what do you think about growing at a low
20 to 30 rh during the flowering stage
will it make my buds more dense
so that's a really low humidity rh
stands for relative humidity for for
those that don't know that low humidity
goes against
vpd vapor pressure deficit some of you
may have heard of that not really know
what it is
with a low humidity like that vpd
actually increases
what's going to happen there is the
stomata on your plants leaves are going
to be smaller
as it gets smaller co2 uptake reduces
also as the vpd increases
transpiration increases as well as
transpiration increases
roots pull in more nutrients which could
actually lead to a toxicity issue so
for example if you have a lot of plant
available nitrogen in the medium
and your transpiration increases the
plants intaking more of that nitrogen
it could lead to a nitrogen toxicity
that's happened with me before it's
happened to a lot of
people that have posted on my forum
before it's somewhat common
for those that are running low humidity
like that so
overall running a lower humidity like
that the plant will still grow
it's just not ideal and it does cause
more stress on the plant to answer your
question on whether or not it makes the
buds more dense
in my experience it actually makes the
buds more airy that's just my experience
it might have just been the cultivars i
was growing but
yeah i usually have a better result as
far as bud structure when i'm in the
proper humidity range
after re-amending your used soil how
long does it need to cook before it's
ready to reuse
rule of thumb is two weeks some people
say three weeks
if you have a larger pile i was actually
talking to an outdoor grower quite
recently he says that for large piles
that he's growing outdoors
he actually weighed 16 to 90 days i
believe he said which is
very long but if you're a small indoor
grower two or three weeks
is general how many books do you have so
i'm not really sure if you're talking
about how many books i've written
or if you're talking about how many grow
books that i have i'll quickly show you
what books i have
so a lot of you have seen me mention
this one before this is jorge cevante's
growers bible i mean this was 2006 i
think is this edition so there are some
outdated things in here however there's
a whole bunch of good information
here so i do really enjoy this one true
living organics by the rev
this is my go-to for organic material
haven't gotten through this one entirely
skipped around it
quite a bit definitely need to sit
through and read this thing from cover
to cover still but uh yeah really good
stuff if you're going organically
ed rosenthal's handbook this is actually
used at oakster dam university
another one i've just kind of browsed
through i mean this is like a textbook
here
a ton of good information in this one ed
rosenthal is a legend
uh love this one uh this one's really
heavy here cannabis grill bible
super thick i mean how many pages is
this 636 so six
almost 700 pages in this book this is by
greg green
and yes a whole wealth of information i
definitely haven't read this from cover
to cover yet but
uh maybe someday the emperor wears no
clothes by jack herrer
some people mispronounce his name jack
herrer it's
uh according to him it's jack hare
rhymes with terror this is the 14th
edition of this book i actually just got
this i haven't cracked into it yet
i've seen the previous edition and have
browsed through it a little bit
but yeah still need to read this one i
do have the beginner's guide
from danny danko this one is a pretty
good read a lot of general information
in here
i did read this from cover to cover
pretty enjoyable and then
my book right here a complete beginner's
guide for growing indoors
now just to talk a little bit more about
this this is really for the complete
beginners so i've had a couple people
buy this
and they have you know two three years
of experience and like oh i knew
almost all this stuff so it's really
more geared towards if you're just
starting out your first or second grow
and you need kind of a walk through it's
a lot of general information
in order just to get you through that
grow there's a lot
more that can be said about the growing
process beyond this
but yeah complete beginners this is
available on amazon only i'll link it
down
in the description section below covers
both soil
and coco coir and if you do end up
buying it on amazon please
leave a review i would greatly
appreciate it trying to get up to 500
reviews i think i'm at like 220 reviews
so far
so i've got quite a ways to go almost
halfway there but uh if everybody out
there that had purchased the book
if you're able to leave a review on
amazon or rating i think a star rating
i would greatly appreciate it and i am
working on another book which i hope to
have
released by either late this year the
end of this year
or early next year it's probably more
early next year
but i've definitely been making a little
bit of progress on it so far and
books take a while especially the
research side of things and
you know having more hands-on
experiences some things i want to get
some hands-on experience
on and then write about so it's a
process but i'm
super excited about this one i think
it's gonna bring a lot of value i'm not
gonna reveal what it's about just yet
as time gets closer i i will giveaway
time
got another giveaway for you all and
this is actually a few different things
first off we've got the set of rope
ratchet hangers this is by
vivo sun or vivosun you know i might
have been pronouncing it wrong this
entire time and they never corrected me
on it
so i guess i'll continue to say vivo sun
could be vivo somehow a pair of rope
ratchet hangers
we've got some protective glasses here
these are i believe they're
the the green lens specifically for the
blurple style lights
got it indoor outdoor digital hygrometer
and aluminum clamp lamp so these are
really good for seedlings
all you have to do is click the link
down in the description section below
it's going to take you over to
rafflecopter
and there's a few ways that you can
enter the giveaway that's pretty much it
for this video guys if you enjoyed it
please click that thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
[Music]
peace
you