thanks to mars hydro for sponsoring this
video mars hydro is running a big sale
for 420 where you can get up to 15 off
plus on top of that discount you can
stack my coupon code to save even more
they have deals on their fc series fce
series ts series sp series and more so
during checkout use coupon code mr
growit to save an additional amount off
of their listed sale prices
links are in the description section
below and the sale ends on april 24th
can you flush organic you could but why
flushing in organics is generally not
recommended because
you're flushing out nutrients now if you
are running into a problem you might
have to right so maybe your organic
inputs maybe you're trying to play soil
scientists and you're feeding in
individual amendments as you see fit and
then also there's an imbalance of
nutrients in the medium and you're
having problems that might warrant a
flush in my opinion but if you're
talking about flushing at the end of the
grow i wouldn't i don't see a need to
whatever happened to the ac infinity
clip-on fans still use them they're
working great i think they're due out
next month i believe i think i think
they change it to april slash may so
hopefully they release them soon because
that's a big it's a hot product right
now for sure tips for blue mats my
typically
the water medium really well and then
i'll wait a day until i install it once
i install the blue mats make sure you
you know you push them down as far as
they need to go that ceramic should be
completely
covered by soil make sure you fill up if
you have any like air bubbles
in it you can actually use a little
pipette and fill the rest of it with
water unscrew it real quick and fill the
rest with water because any air bubbles
in it could impact the way it drops
water down i use two and a seven gallon
pot one on kind of each side so
depending on what size grow pot you're
in you may want to consider running two
if you're in a larger grill pot instead
of just running one they work good with
synthetic nutrients the line you could
have some thicker
synthetic nutrient lineups that would
clog it so just be careful on that one
if you're top dressing with organic
inputs
i typically like to top dress the
nutrients where the spot is to where the
water is dripping down on so it helps
ensure that those amendments are getting
wet and staying moist in order for the
microbes to be active on there breaking
them down look into a nutrient well
that's another technique that you can
use if you're top dressing and using
blue mats and then check out the podcast
episode i did with michael box
just search mr growit michael box it
should come up
it's
how to
perfectly irrigate your plants or some
title like that check out that one
because he works for blue mats and he
gave a lot of good advice when it comes
to how to use blue mats do you add
oxygen to your water air stones i don't
no i use rl water put them into one
gallon jugs from my kitchen sink
then i'll bring it up into my grove
space and i'll have a five gallon bucket
and then depending on what i need to mix
in i'll just put the gallon of water two
gallons three gallons whatever amount of
water i'm using into that five gallon
bucket then i'll mix up my nutrients and
then give to the plant so i don't do any
sort of
adding oxygen to the water at all what's
some good advice for some dense nugs add
more blue light dense nugs i think
number one i'd say is genetics
you know you're going to get some
genetics that no matter what you do
in your environment in your grow
they're just going to be airy so
genetics is probably you know number one
i'd say uh number two i mean
just speaking off top of my mind i don't
want to put them in any particular order
but make sure the plan has proper
nutrition if it's lacking in some areas
particularly those elements that are
going to contribute to blood production
then you might see some airy buds
humidity temperature humidity your
environment kind of being dialed in i've
grown some plants in the past was a very
dry environment i'm talking like 20
percent 30 percent rh and it just it did
not dense up and it might have been
because my temperature was a little bit
too high as well so making sure the
temperature is in the proper range not
too high
because the higher the temperature you
know if you have your your nutrition and
environment dialed in
in increases photosynthesis you could
have
you see it a lot in folks that are in
flowering it's just their flowers are
bursting out in all directions towards
the end of flowering and then it's kind
of becoming more of an area structure
lowering the temps towards the end of
flowering is another way to kind of kind
of conserve those dense blood structures
as well as conservative terpenes
hopefully that answered your question
what else we got here what are your
thoughts on pre-made soils fox farm is
one that i've been using a lot of you
have tuned into my channels know this
fox farm ocean four so is primarily what
i use it's available in my local nursery
so i try to buy local i never really get
soils shipped
that's a great mix i know there's some
folks that say that it's too hot for
seedlings it's going to burn your
seedlings
i've only had like maybe one or two
plants that haven't had good results in
fox farm motion for soil
sure you might get a little bit of tip
burn uh while you're in the veg stage
that's not detrimental to your grill in
my opinion i mean that's something that
you can easily rebound from so i think a
lot of people shake off fox farm because
of that but i've always been using it
and it's been fine
primik soul is in general
it really depends on which one you're
talking about there are some good ones
out there the ratio is going to be a big
impact of it right the npk it says it
usually says it on the bag now some of
these pre-mixed bags they're gonna tell
you
what it's for right so talk about all
plants here you've got plants that are
like citrus trees like you might have
some
soil blends that are particular
particularly for that you might have
some soil blends particularly for flour
some particularly for vegetables i think
primarily that's what a lot of growers
were they'll go after that pre-mixed
soil that's for for vegetables so that
might be where you want to start i'm not
sure therapy grow if you have a
particular brand in mind that you wanted
me to to speak about that's kind of the
high level my high level thoughts on on
pre-made soils you can definitely use
them absolutely and it saves you a lot
of work compared to if you were trying
to create your own soil do you soak your
seeds in water or just go straight to
the paper towel method so i personally
will uh i mean i've done it all i've
done paper towel method right away i've
done the soak the seeds and then go to
paper towel i've planted directly into
the medium you could do it either way
one of my favorites you know i've been
skipping the paper towel often for the
past several years i've just been
letting it float in water you know small
shot glass of water filled with about
three fourths of the way full
putting the seeds in there and then just
let them float for a couple days you'll
see that the seeds should crack open and
the root will appear at that point you
know you can go directly in the medium
so
or you could go into the paper towel
from there so whatever you really want
to do
but i've done it both ways does soil
buffer ph to where you don't have to be
concerned too much provided the water is
in a decent range
exactly water is in a decent range
you don't have to generally speaking not
to worry about
ph nearly as much there are going to be
so many things in the actual medium
that's going to adjust the ph obviously
the solution you put in the ph of that
is going to have an impact on it the
microbes are going to have an impact on
the ph the plant is going to excrete
acids which is going to have an impact
on the ph there are various things that
happen in the medium that controls the
ph so as long as you're putting in
the proper ph nutrient solution or water
then you should be okay depending on
again the variables are the amendments
that you're putting in a lot of people
talking about dolomite lime as a
something to buffer ph some that's
commonly used so yeah i mean if you have
a low ph dolomite line that's something
that you can use in order to to raise it
what's the longest you've grown an
autoflower i still go on growing pop
december 4th so december
january february march so you've been 90
days you're at like 100 and something
115-ish days that's about the longest
i've done it's about 110 i think as long
as i had to go the trichomes just
weren't ready i think it said it was
like a 75 day
i was like what no way end up going 110.
some of the phenos went 75 80 five
but i caught other females i had to go
100 110. do you clown yes i do sometimes
not anymore really i mean i have so many
seeds
from so many different breeders that i
don't uh i haven't been cloning i
haven't cloned in years actually just
because i don't need to i can just plant
the seeds and i don't do perpetual
either i just grow from seed once it
grows over i'll restart what is the
craziest way you trained i can talk
about a terrible way i mean i took i
tried the old in my opinion
you know the plant grew like crazy and
then i basically just bent this one the
main stock down and kind of around i
started training too late and so
and it was so like lopsided so as it
came around like you know eventually the
branches grew up and the buds just
caused it to be such a shifty plant
and uh it was just not ideal in my
opinion that's going to be like the
craziest way i guess i've done main
lining before
if you consider that crazy or not i
personally like to
do a little bit of a variation to
mainlining which is i usually wait until
the plant grows to its fourth or fifth
note then i'll top down to the third
node i'll leave
the second node branches that come out
i'll remove the first node branches so
as the
node as the branches from the second
and third node grow up
top those and then you've got yourself
eight main tops right so instead of four
you would do a top on each one it would
go to eight then you can let it grow a
little bit more and do again and go 16
main tops i've gone as high as just 30
32 main tops i thought that was a little
bit too much i don't think i'd ever as
an indoor grower
i don't think i would ever go do that
again indoors
16 was a good amount in my opinion eight
was also a good amount as well do you
check moisture content in the medium
i actually don't i've been using blue
mats so
that kind of dials in the moisture level
on the medium without actually
needing to know what that moisture level
is i do want to get one of those
moisture meters though i need to get one
of those actually thanks for the
reminder i'll get one what's your
favorite line of dry amendments i like
to build a soil craft blend but that's
been my go-to recently for the past year
year and a half and it's so easy to use
just one cup per plant you know you have
that initial amending of the medium and
that's one cup per plant before flipping
the flour
30 days into flour
depending on if you're an 8 week
cultivar
nine ten week or beyond you might want
to do another top dressing on top of it
but i've had good results with build a
salt craft blend any tips for dry and
cure dry
60 60 60 humidity 60 degrees fahrenheit
if you can if your temperature goes up
70 75 the higher goes up the more
terpenes of volatizing so you're losing
those terpenes a little tip for flour is
drop your temperatures towards the end
of flour to kind of conserve terpenes
same thing with curing your storage
temperature a lot of people ignore that
i live in an area here where it's
probably well it's 75 degrees right now
just in this room temperature and if i
had a jar like a jar right here i'm
potentially losing some terpenes just
from this regular temperature i i now
have a wine fridge that have set i think
the upper part is set to 54 the lower
part is set to 60 degrees fahrenheit and
now i storm there in order to try to
conserve terpenes do you use silica
throughout the grill i do yeah it's safe
to use throughout the grow there's so
many benefits for celica
now short answer yeah i use silica
throughout the grow does freak show have
a traditional skunky smell or something
different uh you know it's more of like
a at least the cultivar i have is more
like a lemony type smell it's funny i
was uh
moving the
freak show for one tent to another and i
had it like all over my arms it was
flopping all over the place the buds are
just they're so heavy that they're
flopping all over the place
and uh i had it all over my arms and i'm
just like smelling myself and it's it's
definitely more of a lemony at least for
the finos that i have when will chillout
og be sent out for testing
wow that is a good question
lots of people been asking that question
it's going to be a while currently right
now i'm working i just planted some f2s
i'm going to go towards an f3
um see what i get there
then potentially go down to an f4 and f5
so i've got it's a ways to go until i
stabilize it
really when you go down generation to
generation it's just it becomes more and
more stable right now with f2s it opens
up the gene pool
i don't know how much knowledge you have
in regards to this but it's going to
open up the gene pool you can see a lot
of characteristics from both the male
and the female and so
if i were to send out f2s all the ones
you plant you could see a ton of
differences
i personally would want to be more
stable unfortunate's going to be a
little while here next year at the
earliest
you