coming up on garden talk you don't have
to go buy calcium at the store
you can make your own calcium with
eggshells and vinegar i love
vermicompost using worm compost is one
of the best
natural ways to feed your plants you
don't need guanos or cow manure or all
any of those other things so the first
thing you need to gauge is how much food
waste are you producing
and then how much do you need to augment
on top of that and in general the worms
aren't going to escape because they
don't like light to get the full
benefits out of cover crops
you need to chop and drop in general
right you should never have naked soil
after a while if you have a good amount
of soil and you have a good process
going you don't actually have to go buy
soil either
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 38. in
this episode i interview hota herb he
has been gardening for 35 years and he
has extensive knowledge when it comes to
regenerative farming or gardening and
that's what we're going to be talking
about today i'll talk about what
regenerative gardening is its benefits
and several different practices that you
can implement in your garden thanks to
all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr grow it before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast who helped make that goal
possible ac infiniti is a sponsor of the
podcast coupon code mr growit will get
you a discount on their products
i've been using their cloudline t6 and
t4 inline fans for several years now and
absolutely love the automation built
into them on the inline fans controller
you can have set points for high and low
temperature as well as high and low
humidity this greatly helps control my
indoor garden environment so the
temperature and humidity stays in the
ideal ranges i will leave a link to ac
infiniti down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit for discount on their
products thanks to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro
products are now available in several
countries across the world for those of
you that don't know dutch pro is a plant
fertilizer company that has base
nutrients additives and ph regulators
they have different formulas of base
nutrients for if you're in soil or if
you're in hydro or cocoa they also
formulate their base nutrients for if
you're using hard water or if using ro
or soft water i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow 10dp for a
discount on their products big shout out
to spider farmer for sponsoring this
podcast spider farmer is well known to
produce high quality led grow lights at
a price lower than nearly all other
companies they have board style led grow
lights as well as power style led grow
lights i've used their sf 1000 sf 2000
and sf 4000 led grow lights in the past
and i got some excellent results with
them they also have grow tents in-line
fans and carbon filters i will leave a
link to spider farmer down in the
description section below and you can
use discount code mr grow at 5 during
checkout for a discount on their
products
and we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast
today i am joined with hota herb how are
you today i'm doing fantastic thanks so
much for having me really really excited
to have this conversation with you today
i'm excited to have you on you have
extensive knowledge when it comes to
regenerative gardening or regenerative
farming whatever you want to call it k f
you do a lot of these practices within
your garden i know you through instagram
i also seen that you've been on other
podcasts and shows and just spilling a
bunch of good knowledge so super excited
to have you on today this is going to be
pretty much like an
i would say an introduction to
regenerative gardening a lot of my
audience i would say
is i would say a majority probably are
home growers and that they are probably
more on the bottled nutrient side of
things
there's quite a few organic gardeners as
well that are part of it but i know
there's a lot of people that are looking
to transition over to the organic side
looking to start regenerative gardening
so i thought this would be a good
episode to kind of be an introduction to
it and then hopefully viewers will be
able to get an understanding of it at
least a basic understanding of what it
is and hopefully learn some practices
that they can implement in their garden
you know yeah yep and i'm gonna
hopefully provide some fantastic uh
names as well for people to follow up on
because there's just so much great work
going on
uh all over the globe really uh in
regenerative farming practices so it's
it's fantastic um i personally got into
growing things
because i grew up in a food business
and so
i was always around
fresh foods uh fresh herbs and
ingredients that my
family used in the cooking
my grandfather was a butcher so he also
used to go get the full sides of beef
and my dad ran restaurants and used to
pick out all the vegetables and fruits
and things by hand and
we always had gardens going as well so
that we had fresh stuff to cook with
lots of rosemaries and
spices and garlic and onions and things
like that my parents were always growing
some type of an ingredient and as i got
older and was continuing to work in the
food business we always had
herbs available at the restaurants there
was usually something
growing out back that we would go and
pick at the beginning of the day or
excuse me we were getting
lots of fresh herbs in and i always
would
tend to gravitate towards helping care
for those plants and helping bring the
fresh stuff in and helping pick out the
right uh the right types of vegetables
and things to consume so so that was my
background and so i have a real
appreciation for high quality
food
and so that's really where i got started
and
i've always been really interested in
just gardening and having those
ingredients at hand year round i put you
know basil and parsley and
other things on my windowsill i keep
them under fluorescent lights
do different things to keep them going
year round
as i was talking with you earlier i've
started playing around with micro greens
too i love micro greens they're
fantastically
fantastic to taste and
tremendously beneficial uh health-wise
for you so that's uh that's kind of
where i got into it and
regenerative farming
is um
really really important
if you look at
how where our food comes from and
unfortunately we've gotten very
disconnected
as a society
on where our food comes from right most
people's interaction with food is at the
store the grocery store they have no
idea where it came from they don't know
what the plant looks like it was picked
off of they may not even know that much
about the animal that it came from
either
and
that disconnection
has allowed a lot of practices that have
been going on that have been harmful
to the environment and very impactful
to
all sorts of different things because
our environment is connected right you
can't
everything impacts everything else
the
um there the winds
that uh blow in the middle east pick up
nitrogen and sand
that blows across in the atmosphere and
lands in brazil
and is actually one of the is one of the
ways that that the rain forests are
nutrified
so we are in a big large global
connected system but when you look
closer to home
and you look at our
agricultural practices unfortunately
over the last 150 years
and and really the last 70 years
primarily
commercial agriculture has
followed practices that while they were
able to produce large amounts of food
that food did not have
a lot of
nutritive value to it
and all of those practices were
extremely detrimental
to the land
that those
foods and animals were being grown on
what you know the farmer will grow on a
bunch of land and use it until it's
basically just
dead
and then move on to another plot of land
and they keep going and going and going
and
the the
property becomes so depleted in
natural
biology
and natural protections that it's not
able to heal
and so regenerative farming
is a
a whole bunch of different practices
that revolve around trying to re
regenerate
the area but
in general what we're trying to do is
leave the land better
than when we got it
so as opposed to this almost strip
mining approach
that has caused us to lose
70 of the top soil in the middle of the
united states
that was responsible for the dust bowl
that's been responsible for that's
responsible for a lot of our flooding
and runoff problems and pollution within
our oceans and rivers today
is because of this
destruction of the natural
environment
you can
[Music]
farm
in
ways though that help actually
regenerate the soils and help give back
to the land and
capture carbon
and
stop
runoff so there's less flooding because
it'll the water can flow down
into these really really healthy soils
so regenerative farming is again looking
is
looking for ways to rebuild and make
things better than when we left them
organic
is not the same
as regenerative and that's an important
thing to remember
organic means that
all of the things that went into the
making of that plant or animal were also
certified organic the seeds
the nutrients
the soils the teas whatever was applied
to those plants had to be certified
organic for them to be able to claim
that this is a certified organic
product
however
it's still in many cases following bad
commercial practices which continue to
destroy the land like tilling
tilling is one of the largest
reasons why
we've we have so many problems with our
soil health today
and and you know tilling's been around
for a long long time
if you go back even in u.s history some
of our first presidents were promoters
of tilling as a way to break up the land
and make it a little bit easier for
planting and in many cases the way that
we used to till in those days with like
just a big wedge dragged behind a horse
was not as bad as what we do today where
we have these huge mechanized spinning
discs
that
cut through
the soil and destroy
all of the natural
fungal
and biology biological life that's in
that soil all the worms
all of the uh orthopods
all of the fungal bodies they get
destroyed by tilling so what are you
left with you're left with a bacterial a
highly bacterial soil
that isn't as
balanced for the
plant this causes
increase in weed pressure
and causes increases in pest pressures
it again
it causes the soil to lose its ability
to retain water so we have to use more
water to feed our plants
because of the loss of the fungal and
back biological life in the soil
the plants aren't able to get as much
access to the minerals and nutrients
that are in that soil
so you have to add more stuff on
right so even if you're using an organic
product but you till your soil
you're still not
following regenerative practices
regenerative practices are also great
for animals as well it's not just about
plants and in fact the two together
are a symbiotic combination that needs
to be followed one of the things that um
i think is is uh really interesting for
vegetarians to consider okay
is that we still need cows
okay
the reason is
that we don't have
the
herds
of animals that used to exist
in
nature
that would help with the basic
biological processes
that regenerated the soil
their urine and defecation their
churning up the land but primarily in
large herds that moved at very rapid
paces and didn't stay in one place for a
very long time because of predators
that type of movement that type of
activity is extremely beneficial for the
land and if you look at places in the
u.s where they've actually allowed the
wild buffalos to come back
those grasslands have come back from
what they once were to once they once
were that and they were
in some cases almost desertifica
desertified
because there were wasn't the proper
type of animals on that land
just holding cattle and pens outside
though is not enough you have to rotate
them much more often than our practices
are today and you also need to keep them
in smaller pens to keep them clumped a
little closer so that you get some of
the benefits
of them stomping the ground
and and kind of breaking down the cover
crop
and vegetation back into the soil
but also creating small pockets where
water and bacteria can build because
their hoof prints will actually create
these little puddles and micro
microbiomes
and again you're in the feces and all
those things and by keeping them
rotating
you don't allow those animals to eat all
the vegetation to the point where it's
detrimental to that land right
uh there's uh there's a couple of
brothers and i think it's last name is
silva but i can't remember the last name
but they're doing some stuff in in the
oaxaca desert which is in between texas
and mexico
and it's basically one of the largest
deserts in the world the oaxaca desert
and they
a large portion of their property is in
that desert and what they did was they
changed the way they
moved their cattle their cattle farmers
so they changed the way they moved their
cattle and were able to actually
rebuild the entire area of their land
through proper cattle rotation only by
using proper cattle rotation
the natural species came back in the
birds and the animals carried the seeds
the plants spread
the biology moved with the water and the
streams and things started to re
come back from being a desert actually
turned back into
a grassland
naturally just by changing the way
they moved their cattle but the use of
cattle was necessary and important so
bringing cattle across a field
before you do planting
is a great way to help reinvigorate your
field working with your neighbors
having your neighbors maybe feed on some
of your crops so that their
their cows are also getting some of the
benefits of your naturally grown
vegetable vegetation and they're also
helping
heal your land as well
so
lots of great things some people to look
at would be dr elaine ingham
who is the person who coined the soil
food web
and
really
learn about the soil food web because
it's a tremendous tremendous important
part of regenerative farming
ray archuleta
gabe brown are also some fantastic
people that you can go find out more
from
um and those are those are definitely
some some some names i would recommend
looking up and finding out more about if
you're interested in regenerative
practices i follow
primarily a family of farming called
korean natural farming
which is a family again it's a korean
based natural farming set of practices
that utilizes
natural inputs that you collect locally
in your environment
to feed your plants so you collect
plants to feed your plants you use
ferments fermentation
and
vinegars and sugars and other techniques
for
capturing
uh indigenous microorganisms
and building beneficial
inputs
for your own gardens i this is what i do
all the time
i make all my own inputs i don't buy
anything at the store at the groce store
if i go to a grow store it's because i
need a new fan
[Music]
or something along those lines i don't
go to the grow store for nutrients i
actually make all of my own nutrients i
make fpjs which are fermented plant
juice ffjs fermented fruit juices
you can make your own calcium your own
calcium you don't have to go buy calcium
at the store
you can make your own calcium with
eggshells and vinegar
or oyster shells in vinegar
seven days with a breathable cap and you
have your own calcium for pennies
and it's really really really
interesting
way of creating
nutrients and inputs for your plants
it's a wonderful way of farming and all
of the inputs are in many cases good for
us as humans as well they're good for
animals so there's approaches for
chicken coops for for no smell chicken
coops and no smell pig styes with korean
natural farming which are amazing using
lactic acid bacteria
um or lactobacillus
and some other techniques uh just really
really cool stuff
so i hope that uh helped kind of give a
little bit of a background and a primer
on regenerative farming
absolutely it has a lot very interesting
stuff there a lot to unpack so just a
quick recap i got a short list here so
regenerative gardening some of these
things you said some of them you didn't
say you know sun grown you know rely on
the sun to grow instead of kind of doing
it indoors crop rotation closed loop
on-site plant nutrition composting
systems
so for watering doing strategies through
soil management irrigation methods
using rainwater right right yep talk
about how it's beneficial to animals you
know healthy plants with companion
planting cover cropping on-site food
systems pest management not relying on
chemical pesticides and herbicides so a
whole bunch of different things can be
enacted here now narrowing it down to
kind of the home grower you know the
person indoors that's doing their own
gardening you know maybe they have a 6
or 12 plant set up or house plants or
whatever talk to us about closed loop
operations i know a lot of people that
is something that you can enact within
the home gardening so can you first tell
us like what is closed loop operations
and what are some things that people
could do at home in order to implement
that yep
so i've actually mentioned a few of them
already but closed loop has to do with
basically
getting everything you need from within
the confines of your own property right
so if you're running a farm
nothing comes in from the outside
you're building and utilizing all of the
things within your property to feed and
support and nurture and sustain your
farm
it's the same thing for us as home
cultivators whether you're growing
edible or medicinal plants it really
doesn't matter
even your regular house plants as well
in many cases can benefit from these
systems and um
as a
as as just a home owner in general
right composting is a tremendous
uh is a tremendous benefit
so if you're going to if you have some a
little bit of land
building an outdoor compost or getting a
compost box or something along those
lines is a fantastic way to start
and it's a great way to reduce your
food waste
and your overall trash that you're
sending to landfills and you're having
picked up and all those things you can
take your coffee grounds your used tea
your eggshells
the old vegetables
the ends the green ends on the carrots
that you don't want to eat all the
different pieces all the things that you
strip off of the vegetables when you
peel your carrots or you know the banana
that just was over ripe and you didn't
want to eat it all these things can go
in your compost pile and can be
recovered
and re-nutrify your own
for the benefit of your own garden
so composting is outdoors is one way to
do it another thing you can do is as i
mentioned vermicompost or or worm
farming and that's great for indoors
because you can have
worms in a five gallon bucket you can
keep worms in a little box
if you really want to obviously they're
only going to produce so much worm cast
things and they're only going to take up
so much waste if you have only a small
amount
but having a worm bin
is a tremendous benefit and actually one
of my favorite things i love
vermicompost using worm compost is one
of the best
natural ways to feed your plants you
don't need
guanos or cow manure or all any of those
other things
really vermicompost is mostly all you
need
and it has the benefit of providing a
lot of natural organisms and fungi along
with it
that help benefit the soil and build
soil structure and all those things
i do
put some worms in my pots
occasionally but i tend to keep them in
my worm bin actually and i use red
wrigglers
is the type of worm i use
i get my worms from uncle jim's worm
farm
i order them online every time i need if
i need some new worms but for the most
part once you get worms if you take care
of them you don't need more they will
double
every three months so if you have 250
worms you'll have 500 worms in three
months and you'll have almost a thousand
worms in six months so they
they will
grow to the size of your space and and
you can do them and you know get a bunch
of 35 gallon totes from target and make
your own worm bins and keep these things
in your basement
you can go year round
if you live in a cold environment like i
do i live in massachusetts it freezes in
the winter i can't stir a compost pile
the wood chips that i would normally add
for my browns are also frozen the leaves
are frozen they're buried in snow or ice
and so for me the alternative in the
winter is a worm bin uh or uh doing some
bokashi fermentation so another great
thing that you can do if you're in if
you have an apartment or a small space
you can actually do composting with
akashi
it's a it's a japanese technique that
uses fermentation
to convert your food wastes
over to a product that breaks down very
quickly in soil so you could do
a 30 day ferment
on your food waste in a four or five
gallon bucket with a lid
and then take that and mix it with soil
in a big tote
let that cook again for another 30 days
and you will have an incredibly rich
soil that you can use on your plants so
there's lots of great techniques that we
can use even if you have a very small
space you don't have to have a big
compost pile outside and turning it and
worrying about temperatures and all
those things worms are the best
but there's also great approaches with
bokashi
i know people who also if you have
chickens
soldier flies is also a fantastic way to
do composting
if you can deal with
with all the soldier fly larva and all
that which the chickens love
so that's um so that's um
a bit about composting i like to use
compost teas and
that's one of the primary ways that i
feed my plants is i like to brew up a
weekly
compost tea
uh with an airlift brewer so before we
get into that sorry to cut you off sure
i would like to dig a little bit deeper
into actually a worm bin
because i'm actually starting it for the
first time i actually had a podcast
episode with queen of the sun grown not
sure if you know who she is and she
actually found out i was not doing
composting and just her
you could sense like a little bit of
like frustration in her like her just
passion came out of her like once you
said that like you aren't doing it why
aren't you doing it so like it really
like it's kind of like a whip me into
shape type thing right so i went out i
started doing research i'm about to go
buy i have a plan in place about to go
buy the bins right now i'm going to buy
the i think they're 18 gallon bins okay
i think i'm going to buy two of them i'm
going to double stack it i'll have worms
in there but just talking about the
inputs i think a lot of people probably
in myself included i'm kind of getting
caught up on what to input in there to
begin so my plan is just things i have
around the house right so junk mail i
get a lot of junk mail that i come in so
putting it through the shredder
adding that in there coffee grounds i
was going to put in there i have i have
basil plant and i have some house plants
that are kind of you know some leaves
like die off and stuff put that in there
you know lettuce any salads that i don't
eat banana peels
hair i guess you can put your own hair
in there as well sure you could so you
can even go that far i'm trying to think
of what other things i plan to add in
there that's kind of the main things
that i'm going to be starting with oh
grass clippings clippings from plants
outside as well if i'm like trimming
bushes or whatever i was going to throw
that in there those tend to be a little
bit more for traditional compost piles
especially
clippings um so you wouldn't recommend
them bringing them inside to your worm i
don't know if i would do that um you i
mean you could bring in some of those uh
items from the outside but you also got
to remember your pl your worms are only
going to eat so much
so the first thing you need to gauge is
how much food waste are you producing
and then how much do you need to augment
on top of that okay
uh
in general you want to start with
shredded paper and some fresh cocoa
as the very beginning the base and you
wet it you know you want to squeeze it
so that you know it pretty much is dry
it's not like squeezing out water but
maybe a little bit of a drip
um you don't want it to be too dry but
you kind of mix that all together that
paper and that cocoa and then you put
your worms down in that and then give
them a day or so to settle in
and then what you want to start using
all the most of those things that you
said are great
with banana peels apple corers things
like that you want to try to chop them
up because the smaller they are the
faster they're going to break down
berries are awesome they love berries
some
you'll have to kind of gauge sometimes
some plants
they don't like
especially the fresh leaves
they may not like them they might be a
little bit too bitter or a little bit
too
odorous
they don't some things they will
actually move away from until they break
down or dry out so you might need to you
might want to let the plant material dry
another thing you need to to keep an eye
on is your moisture levels so
if you're putting in a lot of coffee
grounds and
fruit and things like that you may want
to add some extra paper or cardboard or
things like that that will help balance
off some of that you don't want it to
get too moist in there right and you
want to make sure that there's some good
drainage at the bottom of the of
whatever the bin is that you put them in
gotcha yeah that's all good information
that i'm i'm definitely gonna be able to
use and like i mentioned i was gonna do
the kind of like the double stack bin so
the the the bin that's stacked inside
the other one is gonna have the holes
drilled through just like you can look
up any youtube video and see how they're
drilling holes all around the bottom and
then upon the top as well like not the
top lid i guess a lot of people don't do
the lid but they'll do like a round
they'll put a couple air holes at the
top just because you don't want it to be
a closed
uh environment you want some airflow to
be able to get in there so that's why
they put a couple of those holes at the
top yep and in general the worms aren't
going to escape because they don't like
light
so they're going to stay away from the
as soon as you open up the bin the lid
on the bin they're going to dig down in
because they don't they don't want to be
near the light and so even if you have
some holes on the side they're not going
to crawl out
because they're going to try to avoid
the light and then from my understanding
it should be you know once once they're
stacked in there
you do it kind of like on a weekly basis
to where on one week you're kind of
putting things on one side of the bin
you know lightly covering it and then
the next week you're putting something
on the other part of the bin and kind of
moving things over so that way there's
some kind of rotation going on yeah and
then i
i do quarters quarters okay kind of
quadrants
um and move them around and and again
you need to gauge
how fast the worms are consuming what
you're putting in if there's a lot of
food left from the previous one
you just let them go don't feed them
again
because you want to give them time you
don't want a large buildup of composters
and other types of
smaller
organisms and insects that you'll see
you will see some other small bugs
crawling around in there
but those are composters they're
breaking those foods down worms don't
actually eat the food in most cases
they're eating the molds and bacterias
and things that grow on the foods as
they break down and their movements and
shooting through things is what helps
break down some of those materials they
also love avocado that's a great thing
to use melons
things like that
you want to stay away from meats and
dairy
if you're going to be doing mail be
careful to get rid of those little
plastic view windows you don't want
those in there don't be shredding your
credit cards because then you're putting
really sharp plastic
into your worm bin and the worms aren't
going to like that very much and you
really don't want plastics in there
anyway
and
you know i i always feel a little uh
have mixed feelings about using mail in
general just because you don't know what
they're printing it with
um and everything that goes into
your worm bin is going to go into the
worms themselves and into the castings
and then those casts whatever goes into
those castings is going to go into your
plants and then into you
so um i try to uh i try to you know
a lot of inks are actually soap based
and they don't tend to be chemicals
most printers and things like that they
actually print with it's kind of a kind
of a soap
but you know i mean things that are
really really
lots of colors i try to stay away from
things that are very glossy
i'll stay away from and just try to use
things that are really just paper you
know
things that are you know bill electrical
bills and things like that those are
fine
but i would shy away from some of the
really you know glossy printed stuff
that comes in the mail and some of those
flyers and things like that
cardboard also cardboard is good
especially if you see recycling
symbols on it or made from recycled
cardboard things like that um so those
are those are all good inputs okay and
then from my understanding you know
roughly 30 days could be longer you know
there's a lot of variables with the
temperature and so on and so forth but
roughly 30 days then you kind of have
verma compost which you can use you can
take that and and top dress your plants
with it for example and then my question
is underneath so that second barrel is
going to be collecting the the waste
right the the verma vermi tea right
vermicompost tea type thing right it's a
leachate
yeah okay how long does it take for that
to develop and then
will it ever go like anaerobic like is
there a chance that like do you need to
be moving it around so it doesn't go
anaerobic and bad pathogens yeah i would
use it right away it's not something you
want to store it's not something you
want to keep it's uh you know you
i would check your bins once a week
at least and and then make sure that
there isn't a lot of you know that
moisture that water and i would use it
right away that leachate if you're gonna
use it i would not store it or keep it
around
you may not get any i don't get any in
my bin it just depends on your uh
moisture levels of your inputs okay and
then that should be diluted is that
correct yeah i i i mean if you're going
to topdress with it you are kind of
diluting it right you're not
in most cases when you put if you pour
something on the soil it's kind of going
to dilute naturally but yeah you could
mix it in with some water or something
as part of your feeding
um
absolutely cool
nice well i appreciate you taking some
time to answer my questions there
because i am about to start which is
exciting for me something new you know
yeah like i said i like to use the the
verma compost in a compost tea
so what i like to do is i use a paint
sprayer bag that's actually paint
strainer bags so when you can get them
at home depot they're super cheap
um and they're they're great they make
these like five gallon strainer bags and
you can put all of you you can put
vermicompost and leaf mold and all sorts
of things for whatever you're using for
your compost tea mixture
and they're great and they're easy to
clean so you can wash them and use them
over and over again but that's how i
like to use my vermicompost instead of
top dressing with it
because
i don't have enough if i had a lot of
vermicompost then maybe i would probably
top-dress with it more but to stretch it
out i think a great way to do that is to
use you know a cup or so in a compost
hebrew and feed all of the plants off of
that tea brew
as opposed to just you know putting like
a tablespoon or two on every one of the
plants
but that's a great that's also an easy
way to do it is to just walk around put
a tablespoon or two right on top of the
soil and the water will naturally wash
that stuff in and and
provide the benefit gotcha i'm talking
about compost teas a little bit more is
there anything beyond the traditional
things that we hear i mean just
traditional you know people use five
gallon buckets they fill about four
gallons of water they put about a cup of
compost in there then you know they add
a sugar source
brew for around 24 hours some people up
to 48 hours however i've heard that
there's issues going that long anything
to kind of add to that process
sure sure um there's a there's a couple
of things actually that i can add to
that number one if you're going to use
molasses
as your sugar component
make sure to work that molasses into
some warm water
before you pour it into your compost tea
mixture okay and the reason for that is
that molasses are highly viscous
and
they may
in some cases end up coding some of the
bubbles
that are being that are you know showing
up as you're brewing and that coating
causes that actually creates a small
little anaerobic pocket
and so you end up brewing some anaerobic
bacteria as well as your aerobic
bacteria and so you're not fully getting
the benefits so if you take that
molasses and mix it with some water
first some warm water first to thin it
down and kind of break up some of that
viscosity and then pour it into your
compost tea
good to go uh so that's the first thing
the second thing is
you should be aerating the inside of
your compost tea bag
as well as the outside process that's
brewing right so i run an airline into
the bag itself
so there's air bubbling inside the bag
so again i'm not getting an anaerobic
pocket if all that material kind of you
know meshes together
and some ways blocks out some of the
access to the oxygen and the water
that's floating around it
it's going to create an anaerobic pocket
as well so you want to keep air
inside those bags as well as the air
that's happening from the rotation of
the tbr process
third thing i'll mention is air stones
can be problematic
because they build up bacteria
and not good bacteria over time so if
you clean them and and or replace them
you probably aren't going to run into
any issues but i would highly recommend
just going without the
air stone on there just running the tube
of air directly onto the inside of the
bag or into the bottoms of your of your
thing or use an air lift brewer like i
use as a better approach as from as
opposed to air stones and you'll avoid
any possible issues from those so that's
my recommendations
from korean natural farming
compost tea or liquid imo is usually
brewed for 24 to 36 hours and we tend to
watch it by smell
so uh when thing you'll the smell will
change over time of your brew you'll
start out with a sweet and earthy smell
of course because you have the molasses
and some of those other sweeteners in
there so you'll get this like earthy
natural
sweet smell to them and and over time
though
if you go too far
you'll actually start to get some moldy
or rotting smells and that means that
you went too far so that's kind of one
of the things that we watch for a lot in
korean natural farming are smells and
tastes uh when we're creating our
preparations so yeah
usually we don't go beyond 36 hours
because you do start to run into some of
those conditions where you've started to
burn out the good bacteria and you're
left with nothing but the bacteria who
actually are the cleaners the p the
bacteria that eat the other dead
bacteria
that's good information i use air stones
right now and i might switch over but
one tip that i you i've heard and what
i've been doing is in between
brews right so if i'm done brewing i'll
take the air stones and i'll boil them
right boil them in water so that'll kill
off you know the temperature gets so
high it'll kill off any bacteria on
there at all so that's what i personally
do in order to prevent some hydrogen
peroxide could also be useful
um
but yeah i you know as long as you're
cleaning them and maintaining them if
you use them again and again every day
and they're just sitting there bubbling
away day after day
you're going to start to attract molds
and bacterias inside that stone that
will do bad things
makes sense so i know we're kind of
going off course here from the the list
of questions i gave you but i think it's
really good that we're going because
there's a lot of good information here
is there anything else can you talk to
us about some other things that you
think that
home gardeners can do as far as
implementation practices for generative
gardening yeah yeah so um again i think
using composting is an important
practice
that you should consider
one of the one of the great resources
that most home gardeners have access to
actually is leaf mold
leaf mold is an incredible input and
basically leaf mold is the stuff you
find underneath your pile of leaves
that's not quite soil but almost soil
well that's pure humic
humus
and it's a beautiful beautiful organic
material and you can actually take that
and put that in
with mix that in with your soils to kind
of give them a inoculation
actually
of natural organisms and life that will
help those plants get started if you're
trying to follow into a living and
organic
type of an approach and and you know i
think one of the things that i we should
probably cover is is just real briefly
soils because there's a lot of different
terms for soils right you have
soilless mediums
you have soil soil itself is sand silt
and clay
humic material and
right
so you can't have uh
actual soil if you don't have the
biological compound the biology in there
too that's what turns dirt into soil is
the life
the humic uh the humic materials and the
life the biology
you also hear a lot of these terms
living soil and super soil right that's
common uh
terms of phrase that are used out there
uh often
super soil is really a enriched soil
okay
super soil is actually a specific recipe
created by a
soup by a specific person
that had a specific set of materials and
inputs in it
that's right
and then we coined uh super soil but the
reality is it's an enhanced medium it's
not a true soil some people will refer
to it as a soilless medium because
you're taking soil and then you're
mixing in a lot of other compounds and
substrates peats
perlites
crab meal lobster compost different
types of things and when you do that
you're kind of getting away from real
true soil and you're you're creating
what i like to refer to as enhanced or
enriched soil and that tends to actually
be my base so i actually use coasta
maine stonington blend is my primary
base
has a tremendous amount of really good
organic compounds it's made here in new
england where i live coastal maine i'm
in massachusetts so it's it's um it's a
product that's produced here it has a
lot of peat
in it it has lobster compost
it has some kelp some kelp meal and some
other great things so it's an enriched
medium
living soil on the other hand is
actually
true
natural soil
that is alive and you're relying on the
biology worms arthropods ciliates all
the bacterial and fungal life that
you're promoting
to
create the nutrients that the plant
needs to survive
right
and
to do true living soil as a home
gardener as a home grower you need at
least a 35 gallon pot
which can be difficult for people
indoors especially you need you need
something on wheels
a lot of people have been moving into uh
no-till beds
living soil beds and i mentioned
no-tilling
earlier on in the podcast right and so
this is a fantastic approach for anybody
who's looking to go
completely regenerative completely
closed loop
is using living soil beds
as opposed to pots
having a two by two
soil bed is actually is is a two by two
pot is about 35 40 gallons of soil
a three by three is about
75 gallons of soil
a four foot by four foot bed is actually
about a hundred gallons of soil so
imagine trying to lift 100 gallons of
soil
you can't do it you actually have to
shovel
the soil out of those beds if you don't
have them on wheels
i've seen people fill their tent with
one big 4x4
living soil bed it's a beautiful
approach
you're allowing
you're using cover crops
you're utilizing worms
you're using utilizing um natural
type you're using companion plants
uh which is also great
and you're allowing the
you're building basically a natural
environment
that's alive and as close to
a biodynamic approach as possible as
close to a natural approach as possible
you're trying to create the outdoors
inside you're allowing the plant to
naturally
manage
the biology and the soil to get what it
needs and it's a fantastic approach i
have a friend
blue
who uses avocado tech to help keep his
living soil beds going and he
he's gone 16 17 cycles
in the same beds
all he does is chop the plant he leaves
all the roots and everything in
he lets leaves and things fall to the
ground he's got cover crops in there
that he chops and drops and smashes down
but he also uses this great thing called
avocado tech yeah i'm actually uh having
him on the podcast soon to talk all
about avocado awesome yeah he's he's a
fantastic guy and a great friend of mine
uh we actually went to a regenerative
conference together which is where i met
him
and his avocado tech is fantastic and so
he makes kind of a guacamole
with some
crab meal and some other inputs azomite
and some good natural inputs makes this
guacamole and stuffs it back in the in
the avocado skin and puts it face down
on the soil and what happens is the
worms actually come up out of the soil
bed and run through the avocado
and move and actually bring all that
nutrient goodness back down into the
soil naturally for him
he put uses three avocados
an entire cycle that's his whole deal
that's incorrect and other than that he
just puts he just has water dripping
with the blue mat system
um which is an incredible water saving
system i love blue mat
i
don't i myself
don't run i try to use as little water
as possible so i don't
i keep my plants wet
but i don't water to run off which a lot
of people do
i'm just trying to use just as much
water as i need to keep the plants wet
i'm not trying to soak them down
but i'm and i'm trying to make sure that
obviously they don't develop dry spots
but i'm just trying to keep them wet
blue mats are a great system that is a
passive system even you don't really
even need any power for them you can use
gravity
and basically fill you fill a bucket of
water
and um you use these uh they have these
carrots these electrostatic carrots that
basically sit in the soil and detect
soil moisture and based on the level of
moisture they let water drip
and so you get these little drips of
water all day long and that's actually
one of the most efficient watering
systems around because you're allowing
the plants actually to dictate the
moisture level in the soil and they just
get as much as they need they're really
thirsty you're going to use up some more
water but you're only using what the
plant needs you're not pouring a ton on
and having runoff and then throwing that
out
you're not you know trying to recycle
you don't need to it's all
keeping maintained and the only thing
that you know it only drips as needed
they're really really great systems i
really enjoy using the bluemount i'm not
using them i don't have them plugged in
right now but i'm probably going to be
going back to them too and they tend to
develop some amazing root balls as well
really really impressive root structures
when you use the when you use that type
of an approach i've been using bluemax
and you see pictures online you can see
like the roots coming up going towards
the dripper you know where it's actually
dripping and i believe it can kind of
clog your lines too right if you're not
if you're not keeping an eye on it the
root will go all the way up into the
there and clog it so you got to be
careful there but yeah once you get that
saturation rate down as far as what you
want yeah in that container stick the
carrot in there you got it hooked up to
your res just all gravity fed you know
if you're using organics you're just top
dressing the medium staying that
moisture level that it needs to be for
that those microbes to break down those
amendments and it's it's so much
hands-off compared to a synthetic
bottled nutrient line where you're
mixing nutrients every week sometimes
twice a week in order to you know hand
water your plant or i mean you can
always put you can always do that
synthetic nutrients in the blue mat as
well but just in general like you have
to be careful yeah yeah because you'll
clog though you can clog those lines if
you're careful you'd have to flush them
often
um so you definitely have to be careful
especially with some of the organic
nutrients
some of those tend to be uh thick like i
used to use uh medi1 from green planet
and that stuff is like just sludge
the main base uh but it's an organic
medical base it's a great product really
beautiful but i definitely wouldn't have
fed that through the blue mats
so one more thing let's talk about
before we wrap things up i kind of want
to get into cover crops a little bit so
i've been using cover crops i just use
the white dutch clover right now i know
it's well known for nitrogen fixation
right it's going to take nitrogen in the
air convert it to a form that's usable
by the plant the plant will be able to
uptake it now can you talk to us just
about your knowledge about cover crops
and what other cover crops can we be
using in an indoor environment home
growers you know the benefits of of
cover crops yeah i um i i there's a lot
of mixes out there already on the market
and and most of them have a combination
of different types of clovers
white clovers red clovers
which actually have different benefits
both the red and the white clovers
vetch
sweet peas
different types of grasses
and
having a mix of different types of cover
crops is actually a benefit
i think ray archuleta is up to like 16
or 17 different crops uh in his mix that
he's been testing and that he's using
out in his fields for cattle and things
like that
it depends on
you know what you're
what you're trying to accomplish i know
there's also been some information out
recently about clover
and i start avoiding clover in some
cases because mites love clover oh
interesting
so um although you might you know you
might not necessarily have mites on your
plants they might be in your clover so
it could be a trap plant might be good
for a trap plant to keep the mites off
of your plant
uh it might encourage them to go after
the clover because they love clover
and i know there's a few folks out there
i think tad hussey possibly kiss
organics or one of the other gentlemen
he actually stopped using clovers in his
mixes because of the mite problems that
can develop especially with your
outdoors
using clover in your mixes
so
i love vetch
i love sweet peas beans are also great
if you plant beans
rosemary
thyme
um even throat you know you can throw
some of your companion plants in there
as well calendula
is a great plant to put in there
marigolds
you can put those in there as well they
have good ipm benefits they help keep
pests away
lavender thyme
rosemary
things like that and if you're doing a
living soil bed
you may want to consider some of the
perennial forms of that because there's
like climbing forms of rosemary and
thyme that you could grow for years and
years and kind of you know grow it uh
throughout your bed or in your
environment and
maybe bonsai it even if you want but
having a good variety of plants in your
mix is really important
blue even i think he even has squash
growing
and some other vegetables and things in
his living soil beds as well but yeah no
i i like the veggies and grasses and i
still use some clover in my mix as well
because of that nitrogen fixation i
think some of the thing that people
should also remember though is that to
get the full benefits out of club cover
crops
you need to chop and drop
explain that because i don't think
people know what it exactly it is right
so um in general right
you should never have naked soil
keep your soil covered
i like to use rice holes
and a mix of
i do a mix with some wood shavings some
bokashi
and then a bunch of rice holes and i put
about an inch
inch and a half deep on the top of my
soil
keep your soil covered at all times
indoors or outdoors
exposed soil outdoor is actually one of
the problem one of the
things that is causing climate change
and co2
release
again as they till the fields
they turn the soil over and expose the
carbon in the soil to the oxygen which
creates co2
carbon oxygen co2
and it
rises and they've actually photographed
nasa has uh maps
that show the growth the the increases
in co2 release from space the increases
in co2 release at the times when they're
tilling all the fields
you can actually see this from space
um so it's it's it's definitely
something that that
you want to try to uh to avoid but um so
you wanna you wanna use those mulches uh
those green mulches or cover crops are
also beneficial the cover crops
themselves will in some cases release
beneficial things into the soil
uh nitrogen fixing like you were saying
clover releases nitrogen actually that's
a great thing for your lawn don't get
rid of the clover in your lawn add the
clover back in because if you add the
clover back in you don't need scots
fertilizer on your lawn because the
clover will help your grass you don't
need it
get all the nitrogen you need from the
worms and the clover
but
so you want to then um what's called
chop and drop so
you chop those cover crops you chop them
down you cut them snip snip snip snip
like mowing
you don't cut them all the way to the
ground or kill them the idea is you want
to cut them so that you're leaving some
of the plant to grow back like you're
mowing the lawn almost
and then you leave that material in the
pot in the soil to become a natural
mulch
when plants grow
they are carbon capture machines
everything that a plant produces
is car comes with a carbon exchange okay
everything whether it's their smell
their body their leaves their stems
their fruits all of it
has to do with a carbon exchange and the
and are created
they have carbon they're part of carbon
they have carbon everything has carbon
in it and so plants are
as they grow they are capturing carbon
and other minerals and nutrients
and
if you
drop them directly into the soil and
allow them to go back into the ground
you're re-nutrifying you're putting
those minerals that carbon
and those vitamins and nutrients back
into the soil where they can be
recaptured by the biology and the plants
okay so cover crops
themselves are beneficial because they
help retain moisture in the soil they
help keep your soil
covered
and in many in some cases as we were
saying they'll help add
nutrients back into the soil
cutting them down and dropping them in
also helps add re-mineralize the soil if
you take that stuff out what's happening
is those plants are leaching minerals
and nutrients out of the soil
and then if you chop them and take them
away
you basically lost all those minerals
and nutrients from your soil if you drop
them back in
you're putting them back in the ground
where they came from
so that's kind of the idea and then
ideally to really take advantage of chop
and drop you need worms
you need
biology in the soil that's going to
break down
those
compounds
back into
minerals and nutrients that the plant
can absorb gotcha that makes sense yeah
i've been practicing chop and drop for a
couple grows now
and yeah it's something i'm definitely
going to continue to do because it makes
sense you know it makes sense and
you're saving on nutrients in a sense
right i mean if you're putting it back
into the system that it was in it's just
breaking down and then the plant is
uptaking it eventually and i think a
perfect example of chop and drop which a
lot of people don't really think of is
when you're mowing your lawn right you
should keep those lawn clippings there
as ugly as they may be sometimes right
keep them there because those are going
to break down and that'll rejuvenate
your lawn like you mentioned you get to
spend less money on scots fertilizer if
you do it that way so don't rake your
leaves mulch them in mulch them in yeah
good point absolutely because that's all
fantastic beneficial nutrients back into
the soil
when you haul those things away you're
robbing your environment of those those
great great natural materials i mean you
look at the rain forest
right the rainforest nobody cleans and
picks those leaves up
right nobody the plants drop they fall
they die animals swing through break
stuff eat stuff
and they're these extremely healthy
environments why because everything's
is retained within that environment
nothing gets taken out of that
environment and taken away
well said
well we covered quite a bit in this
podcast i mean this hour flew by
definitely a lot of great information
here i definitely think there's some
information here that home gardeners
will be able to grasp onto let me
explain it in a very beginner friendly
manner hopefully some of you guys will
be able to implement this into your
gardens you know i'm doing composting
now i'm doing chop and drop we covered a
whole bunch of other things but really
in the grand scheme of things we didn't
cover a lot at all when it comes to
regenerative gardening there's so much
more to it and maybe in the future yeah
yeah we just scratched the surface so
maybe sometime in the future we can have
you on for a part two and kind of get
deeper into things because i definitely
think there's a lot of other things that
we could have covered
so yeah i appreciate your time here i
encourage people to
look for opportunities
to
use
the things they have around them in some
way shape or form whether it's your food
waste
whether it's your
leaves
grass clippings
plants all of the stuff around you are
natural beneficial items that can be
incorporated into your garden in some
way shape or form
keep your
soils covered
don't have naked soil
and look for opportunities to
keep the plants
in the ground keep the ground intact
when you harvest as well right so chop
the plant at the stock leave the roots
in there let that biology
let that net all those natural wonderful
things that are going on in that soil
continue
don't rip out that
don't rip it out plant right next to it
keep moving around
if you're in small pots obviously you're
gonna be
having to redo those pots you can't
really do uh living soil in a five
gallon pot
as i was saying earlier so if you're in
pots
you can actually recycle your soil even
so when you're done with your cycle
of that plant
take the roots take the roots and rinse
the soil off of it you can soak those
roots in water
and pull that will pull sugars and
exodites out of them and you can use
them also to feed your plants and water
your plants with
you can
save that soil and actually add compost
and natural things back into it and let
it cook
over the winter
and in the spring you can utilize it you
can do it in bins in your basement as
well
you could take a mix in worm castings so
take your worm castings mix it in with
some of that used soil
and maybe do a little avocado tech on
top
and you won't after a while if you have
a good amount of soil and you have a
good process going you don't actually
have to go buy soil either
you can build up to the point where you
have a good pile of soil that you
recycle
and you can re
you can re-mineralize so that you can
use it over and over again that's
another place where you can look to
preserve and save some money and
try to do some more regenerative
practices and really looking to
again reduce waste i think that's the
best thing to do look look for
opportunities to use the things around
you
don't
if you're in the middle of kansas you
don't need oyster shells
well said well wrapping things up how
can the listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future uh so i
can be found
every day on instagram where i post
pictures of my garden every morning uh
at hoterbj
on instagram i can also be found
extremely frequently on clubhouse so for
those that are uh unaware clubhouse is
an app that's available on both ios and
android it's free to join you don't need
to be invited anymore and it's a
fantastic
audio only
conversation app and so i'm on there
having conversations with people about
growing and agriculture
but also i do a i host a show every
thursday night at 9 00 pm eastern 6 p.m
pacific which is also simulcast on
youtube awesome well i will provide a
link to his instagram down in the
description section below if you like
this video click that thumbs up button
comment drop a comment below let us know
what you think of this video let us know
what regenerative practices you do in
your garden we'd love to hear like you
said we just scratched the surface on
this one there's a lot more to talk
about so let us know what you do and
what you recommend down in the comments
section below if you haven't already
subscribe to the channel i release these
podcast episodes every single weekend
either saturdays or sometimes sundays
depending on how the weekend goes
depending on if susan from youtube
approves the video and allows me to post
it on time or not
also if you are on apple podcast please
leave a rating in review
coming up to 200 ratings and reviews
that's what we're trying to get to next
there has actually been a lot of people
leaving radiant reviews lately so if
you're on apple podcast please please
leave that rating in review and yeah
thank you so much one more time for
coming on to this podcast and i hope you
enjoy the rest of your day
yeah no i appreciate you having me on
thank you so much it's been a great
great conversation and absolutely happy
to have another one again so thanks
everybody and happy growing
take care peace
[Music]
you