hey what's up everybody welcome back to
my channel for those of you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and today I've got a q a video for you
just want to clarify one thing real
quick and the last video I released on
this channel I imagine I'm taking a
break that's for the garden Talk podcast
only I will still upload videos to this
channel such as these q a videos if you
want to ask me questions and potentially
get featured in one of these q a videos
follow me on Twitch twitch.tv Mr Grow it
make sure notifications are on that way
you'll be notified when I go live next
and then you can come hang out and ask
some questions that is all I have for
now let's get into today's questions
when reamending your soil could use the
water from your dehumidifier to moist on
the soil I say thumbs up to that and I'm
kind of going off of a study and this
one is by question let me pull it up
right here Quest dehumidifiers what this
is is they got a lot of feedback of
people saying that you shouldn't use
water from your dehumidifier because it
contains heavy metals so what they did
was they went and tested that and they
found uh right here you can see my mouse
pointer aluminum copper zinc so it did
show some copper but remember copper is
an element that the plant can uptake
they did all different tests I'll
actually put this in the twitch chair
right now we've seen some aluminum and
there's some copper but there's such
small amounts very little impact parts
per billion I think is what they were
saying I'm not going to read through the
whole study here but check it out in the
description section below if you want to
reference that study and learn more
about it got a question from Mr growett
where should I buy the auto parts so I
recommend happy Hydro to go there and
buy them they're actually a sponsor of
this video so big shout out to them auto
parts are an awesome Auto watering
system there's no timers or electricity
and they have systems for all size
operations I use the autopod XL in the
past really got some great results using
it they have systems look at this 100
pot system they have 16 pot systems nine
pot systems 60 pot systems so they have
really for any applications you're
looking for and it also comes with a
reservoir on a lot of these kits so
definitely check them out I have a link
to the auto parts on the happy hydro
website down in the YouTube description
section below if you had one trellis net
when is the best time to put it in
during veg or right before flower I
think it you're going to get mixed
answers depending on who you ask I would
add it in veg before flipping the flour
but there have been times where I added
in the trellis net after flipping a
flower because I realized I was going to
need some support you know the branches
kind of starting to flop over and just
like the structure kind of looking at it
looked like it it was going to be one of
those plants where once it gets deep
into the flowering stage the branches
are just going to be too weak to kind of
kind of hold its buds so I personally
will add in the trellis nut during
vegetation stage at most times and then
I'll work that plant into the trellis as
it's continuing to grow on the veg stage
and then once it's just about filled up
or I don't really fill up my tense wall
to wall you know whenever the structures
where I kind of want to be it is what I
should say that's when I'll go ahead and
I'll flip it now I've made the mistake
of continuing to bend down those
branches for several weeks into
flowering and then of course the
branches were kind of stuck under and
stop stretching and then the buds were
kind of within the knit so I don't
recommend doing that I think you know
moving forward I'm only really doing
seven days the first seven days of the
stretch phase after switching life cycle
tucking down branches and then after
that kind of letting it go from there
what week of flour do you pollinate your
plants when making seeds how long do you
let them mature before Harvest I forget
who said this but pollinate the plants
when they look horny as funny as that
may seem you can kinda think about it
there is that point where the flowers
have grown to the point where there's
pistols just bursting out everywhere
typically it's around day 28 in the
flowering stage now of course it's going
to depend on if you're talking about
when flipping the light cycle when the
plant starts to show flowering so it's
really hard to give you an exact answer
but look around 28 days or so that's
typically when I pollinate when the
plant looks horny enough to uh want to
be pollinated who do you recommend for
water testing very hard water 800 PPM
from the tap a lot of people go through
Logan Labs check out them I'm not the
best person to talk to when it comes
about different testing facilities Logan
Labs is just one of those common ones
they do both soil testing as well as
water testing but I definitely want to
refer you over to the soil doctor Bryant
Mason he was actually my podcast years
ago now really good episode talking
about soil testing he would be the one
to kind of give you insight about water
testing and he can actually review your
results and kind of give you feedback on
what nutrition you know what your
nutrition regimen should be what
amendments you can add in how long do
you just want to sit before reusing
after amending it man I have planted in
it right away I've waited a week I've
waited two weeks I've waited a month
I've waited 60 days it's hard to give
you the answer on what the best time is
right every single time no matter what
even when I planted in the same day I
mended it it turned out to be fine so
some people that is it for seven days 14
days 30 days you can hear different
recommendations from different people my
personal opinion 7 to 14 days and it
should be fun I guess it's also going to
depend on how much you're actually
amending in if you're loading it with
nutrition it could become hot really
quick risky in a way but yeah you're
just gonna have to just try it have you
tried singing it grow or have you done
just fully organic or fully bottled
nutrients absolutely definitely done
sanganic got some really good results
doing sanganic and there's so many
different ways you can kind of go about
it right I think a lot of people will
traditionally go sanganic where they
start off with a potting mix that
includes organic nutrients in it so for
example Fox foam ocean for soil and I
know they're not um recertified or
anything like that there's some specular
relation whether or not that mix is
organic or not but assuming it is
organic that's an example where you
start off with a fox emotion Force mix
and then you're adding in synthetic
nutrients throughout the grill that's
one way of doing synchronic I've done
that I've also done started off and just
in a nursing or soil with not much
nutrition in it add in organic blend of
amendments and also fed in synthetics
throughout the grill it's a way to grow
where if you need that fast acting
response like say the plant is starting
to show like a sign of deficiency or
whatever that's what I really like to
just say okay let me give it a real
light dose of synthetic nutrients
something that's in a plant available
form and so I can see the fast recovery
so I don't have anything against
synganic I think it's a great way to go
about it you can get some really good
results with it so I don't discriminate
organic versus synthetic I'm not
somebody who's going to be they refer to
them as organic snobs to where it's all
organic and that's the only thing
everybody who grows up bottles are
terrible people bottles of her babies
you know
that's not me although I really haven't
been using a lot of synthetic nutrients
in the past two years now it's really
just been organic organic inputs whether
that be compost or dry amendments you
know whether it be a bland or individual
amendments it's just been a little bit
easier for me my style of growing to use
Organics but yes organic is is awesome
when you add your power Bloom dry
amendments when flipping the flower
before changing lights I go after is
power bloom a brand because if it is
then I don't use that but any blend that
I use organic blend I'm adding in a top
dressing prior to flipping flour so
usually it'll be upwards of seven days
before flipping flour sometimes it's on
the day of Flipping The Flower I'll top
dress but yeah it's either on or before
flipping the flowers when I'll add in
that top dressing of organic inputs and
then after that once I change the light
cycle it's usually about 30 days 20 to
30 days is when I'm doing that next top
dressing get the book Chris may even
autograph it for you I would yeah I mean
if you get it from my website mrgrow.com
buy through there leave a comment on
during checkout a note or a comment or
whatever and just say you want it signed
and then I'll go ahead and sign it and
ship it to you right now I'm only
shipping to the us though through my
book just because it's so much money to
ship to a different country although if
you're in a different country other than
the US Canada Europe anywhere check your
local Amazon it should be available on
your local Amazon so you can actually go
to Amazon.com or dot EU or dot UK or
Amazon dot what else CA amazon.de all
those should be available there just
search just for my book and thanks to
everyone who has left a review on that
book on Amazon that has helped out
tremendously it's over I think it's 1
200 reviews on that listing blows my
mind I'm so thankful that you guys take
the time to actually go there leave a
review some people have uploaded
pictures of it some people have uploaded
videos onto Amazon and showed during
their review that helps me out
tremendously so thank you so much this
it's really gone beyond my expectations
as far as getting reviews on Amazon so
once again thank you Enviro cleanse
works really well can't even tell I have
54. I have the Enviro cleanse do you
work with them grow 10 I'm kind of
curious because uh van they suck with
communication I can't even support them
anymore because their communication is
just so bad I'd be interested know if
you're able to get a hold of somebody
because I need to get a hold of somebody
is it beneficial to top dress with
Organics and then introduce microbes
yeah absolutely you can totally top
dress with Organics then include
microbes now it depends on what you're
talking about here give me a second one
cat here wants to jump up on my lap so
let me go organic so you're talking
about like an organic input like compost
includes a lot of those beneficials
already so adding in a micro product
people can will still do it but you
might not really need to some people say
you don't need to but yeah if your top
dressing with just like an organic Blend
or whatever you can totally inoculate
with microbes after before during after
yeah absolutely now a lot of people that
say you should avoid buying micro pucks
altogether because you can get them from
your backyard with the IMO process
that's one stance on it but a lot of
people will for convenience purposes buy
microbes and inoculate their medium can
you overuse molasses in a grow I use a
small amount to adjust my ph's watering
along with nutrients so I actually
created a whole video on molasses and I
think that's one thing I said in the
video is oh you really can't overuse
this I got roast in the comments a
little bit it was kind of funny yeah of
course if you like if you're pouring a
bottle onto your medium that's overdoing
it right what I kind of meant by that
was like if you're using a teaspoon per
gallon or tablespoon per gallon of water
and some people are doing it throughout
the entire Grill successfully so that's
kind of what I meant that video by over
not being able to overdo it you can
certainly do small amounts throughout
the grow and be fine I personally found
most value in it in the flowering stage
mid to late flowering is usually when I
like to do it done it throughout the
grill before no problem every single
watering or every other watering I've
done that as well and it's been fine
have you tried or considered doing
Hydroponics yeah this is kind of a hot
Topic in my world I I get asked this a
lot and I have not done a true
hydroponic growth such as dwc Coco is
considered Hydroponics I've done that
but dwc system for example that's one
very common system that people use when
growing in Hydroponics I have not used
yet my only concern is that the water
temperature of the reservoir
unfortunately where I live I feel like
it would be difficult to control and for
me being a small home grower I feel like
got me investing for all the equipment
and then monitoring it I think it's a
little bit more to monitor it say
something like oh Hydroponics is easy
it's easier than growing in soil it's
better than growing in soil you higher
yield you get better Terps you know you
hear everything from so many different
people but the reason why I speaking for
myself haven't yet grown Hydroponics
here is just because the temperature
gets so high here that I think it's
going to be hard to control the water
temperature it needs to be between I
believe it's 68 and 74 degrees
Fahrenheit is the optimal temperature I
could be slightly off on that don't
quote me on it but if it goes 75 degrees
Fahrenheit or higher you're at risk for
bad pathogens I could potentially do a
dwc run in the winter time which is
something I really I should do I want to
do because temperatures are cold and I I
don't think I'm gonna have to worry
about the water temperature as much as I
will in spring summer and fall so yeah I
haven't really tried doing a dvwc System
hydroponic system like that yep but I'd
love to try one in the future when I
feel like it's going to be a little bit
easier have you done an episode on K and
F do you have one planned yes I've done
a couple I think this episode right here
with Green Goblin episode number 47 is
another one that he does talk about knf
a little bit in there greens goddess
episode 57 this is a good one on knf
she's freaking awesome this one right
here has a lot of stuff about knf
episode 59 and then the last one I'll
recommend Chris Trump well known for knf
a lot people say this is a must watch
episode number 67 so check those ones
out
thank you