welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr growt and you're tuned into to the
guard do podcast this is episode number
128 in this episode I interview Matthew
Gates he is an IPM specialist and has
been on the podcast once before episode
48 where he talked about the top 10
Garden pests in and how to combat them
I'm happy to have him back on the
podcast so we can get deeper into Pest
Management in this episode he reveals
some of the best ways to prevent and
eliminate pests if you want to see short
clips of these podcast episodes search
Garden talk clips on YouTube I also have
a gardening Channel where I show off the
plants set I've grown I'll have both of
those channels linked down in the
YouTube description section below one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening to the
general public that being said I'd like
to thank the sponsors of today's episode
who help make that possible thanks to a
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their instant potty mix a
soiless grow medium made from 100%
organic cocao fiber it's buffered and
triple washed to maintain pH stability
and reduce salinity it comes in a 2B
brick which expands to fill up to a 3
gallon growt click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their instant potting
mix and the discount code Mr Grow 15
works on both Amazon and their website
ACM infinity.com stash blend stash blend
is a 215 plant additive that can be used
with synthetic bottle nutrients or in
living soil systems simply mix half
teaspoon of stash blend into a gallon of
water then water your plants with it
ingredients include corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and micro risal fungi
check it out at stash blend.com Link in
the description section below and use
the discount code the stash
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I'm joined with
Matthew Gates how you doing I'm doing
very well welcome back to the podcast
Second Time Around first time we talked
about pests some of the common pests
what they are and how to combat them
great great conversation just loaded
with information I mean you have so much
knowledge when it comes to pests in
particular and you've got other areas
knowledge as well which I'm hoping we're
going to get into today's episode but
yeah welcome back to the podcast I'm
glad to have you back on once again can
you introduce yourself for those that
didn't catch the first episode we did
together yeah absolutely so my name is
Matthew Gates I'm an integrated Pest
Management specialist I take a holistic
approach to Pest Management I like to
consider many different kinds of factors
and I'm the founder of zenthanol
Consulting so I'm a professional uh
consultant with regards to IPM and um
Pest Management advisory and um I work
with all kinds of people um a commercial
levels and also for private as well and
I'm excited to talk about all echelons
of Pest Management from the Strategic to
the the lower level awesome and we
actually had the chance to meet in
person pretty recently over at the soil
life Summit in parump Nevada awesome
awesome event and you had a talk there
actually had a a great talk which I
watched the replay on it on the
Grassroots website but great great job
there and uh yeah I'm excited to uh to
get into this one thanks I really
appreciate it worked hard on that
let's start with IPM I have to warn you
some of the folks that I have listening
this podcast are beginners although we
do have some intermediate and Advance as
well so starting with IPM what is IPM
and then also get into the everwarm
concept which is something that I
actually learned from you yeah so this
everstorm concept is an idea that um
I've kind of come up with although to be
honest it's not like super unique it's
just a way of rethinking certain aspects
of like ecology and biology and and in
particular through the funnel of how can
we as
cultivators most sustainably or most um
efficiently tackle the issue of pests
especially as they move between
continents and are always constantly
evolving adapting so it's about being
able to disrupt the sort of system and
and preferably ideally using um many
different kinds
of Pathways to that objective
um ways that will like so you don't have
chemical resistance for example which
we've seen agriculture that's the common
example but pests can get resistant to
things like biocontrols too microbial
biocontrols uh bacteria and fungi and
that kind of thing or even viruses that
are used so if we if you understand like
a a greater sort of um ecological Theory
then you can understand why certain
techniques do or don't work um and which
ones are most relevant and what's the
most practical thing a lot of this is
really sort of high high level stuff but
it can be broken down into the
mechanisms of interactions between
plants and pests and IPM essentially is
all about doing that kind of thing and
uh as a concept obviously a lot of these
concepts are sometimes even ancient but
uh generally speaking IPM has been
around since like the 1950s or so and
it's this idea of integrating different
management practices for Pest and it's
evolved over time too has a lot to do
with like preventing pest right so a lot
of these things you're actually doing
before pests are visible right before
pests are even there and I have a IPM
routine that I do um you know I can't
say that I'm super strict on it but uh
there are some things that I do in my
garden indoor garden in particular I
mostly grow indoors although I do have a
vegetable garden Outdoors but there are
some things that I do in order to try to
prevent pests from invading my grow
space and I'd like to kind of go over
some of my IPM methods my my routine
really and some of these things that
we're about to go through I don't do on
every grow some I do do on every grow
I'd like to kind of get your feedback on
some of these things and kind of get
some more details on things so first off
I think pretty straightforward is
scouting plants lot of people say oh
yeah Scout plants look at your plants
some people do it every single day some
people like ah you don't need to do that
often every week or so you want to look
at plants some people say hey that's not
frequently enough you can certainly get
an infestation and have pests take over
your grow space in a faster period of
time so you want to have them frequently
now as far as scouting P what's your
opinion on how often to Scout and also
where this go right are we looking at
the soil are we looking at the bottom
part of the plant we looking at the top
part of the plant so on and so forth
Yeah so basically I think IPM and and
crop scouting in general whether you're
doing it in like one single tent or a
large field or however your context is
it's always going to be context
dependent where you're at also matters a
lot like you kind of say here like
sometimes you can get away with not
doing it every day some people it's a
little bit different everyone's context
is a little bit different so you have to
find the right uh plan for your
particular scenario but yes generally
speaking crop scouting is very important
it's I think the foundation because if
you don't know what's going on in
various ways you won't be able to make
an informed decision and a lot of these
pests can be uh pretty difficult to see
or are invisible to see when they start
like the germination of powdery mil on
leaves for example it's like you know
100 plus hours before you're going to
even possibly see like the mildew grow
or something like this and when you're
looking you want to look at various
parts of the plant not just the foliage
you know if it's a flower look at the
flower look at the leaves look at the
stems as well look Underside leaves a
lot of times insects and mites will like
be on underside leaves um you know look
also at the roots if you can sometimes
you can sometimes it's harder to do that
depending on your context but look at
every aspect of the plant and also um
you know if you can incorporate other
kinds of sensors besides the Mark 1
eyeball you know there's other things
out there that people use to um give
them a better idea about what's going on
in their local environment I think one
of the most common things is using one
of those handheld microscopes I think
they're like a 10x or 30X microscope in
order to kind of see things that's what
I use I know that yeah you mentioned
can't really see everything with the
naked eye right so it's like having a
hand scope in there can be beneficial to
see some of those microscopic pests yeah
definitely now yellow stickies that's
another thing I want to talk about
that's something I use really not as
something to eliminate pests but to
identify that the pests are there so I
personally have yellow sticky traps kind
just stuck into the soil you usually
have one in each pot some people may say
that's an Overkill others say no that's
perfectly fine I know some people use
the yellow stickies and they put them by
the soil some have one hanging up in the
air what's your take on yellow stickies
and how to use them proper L well I like
what you said at the beginning that a
lot of people do there are there are
like glue traps so to speak that you can
use that might be more about like
killing a large amount if you get like a
bunch of flies or other kinds of flying
bugs around like thrips but generally
speaking Yeah yellow yellow glue traps
are not for uh disposing of the pest
really is about sampling them and I
would say that if you're in a small tent
a lot of times in commercial settings
like a standard sized card uh might be
used like per Greenhouse or or for like
a larger section than you might normally
typically see in a smaller tent so maybe
one is good enough um putting one in
every single one though like I think
that's just a matter of like how many
are you getting in a pack and and how
much how long how often are you um
replacing them uh typically I advise
people to replace like in a commercial
setting every week if you have the the
labor and the capabilities to do that um
I think from a homeg grow perspective
that's also true as well no matter what
plant you're growing um because if you
have if you take it off every week you
put a new one in and then you look at
what was in the old one and you take
note you might see things like
parasitoid wasps you might think see
things like uh flies or even like a
house fly or something that you know is
not a pest but it was around in your
house or something and being able to
discern the difference between different
things is very crucial for making it uh
you know most maximal in the way that
you deploy it really good points there
now another thing that I like to do is
avoid going directly from my outdoor
Garden immediately to my indoor garden
and I know some people say that's an
Overkill but others swear that you can
certainly bring in pests from the
outside and your indoor garden so I'm
often taking off my clothes changing my
clothes between my outdoor and indoor
garden would you say that's a good
practice to do or is that kind of an
Overkill can't say it's a bad practice
um I think that's totally valid
especially because like in different
seasons you know like in winter time
maybe you might feel a little bit safer
you know because there might be less
things out and about whereas like during
spring and summertime you know I I will
be walking in I'll be like hiking and
I'll see like an apit or something you
know blow onto like my shirt or a jacket
or somebody else's shirt or their hair
or something like it does happen uh you
might not realize it but it does and um
I would also say that like in a similar
vein if you get like fresh produce you
should check that too I live in
California so I know that there are
different pests that can get into
produce like thrips in berries like
raspberries and blackberries I
definitely see that all the time and so
people are wondering they might even
treat a thrips problem everything's fine
then they come back again like how did
this happen that's by um that's your
biocurity procedure uh taking effect and
so I think that changing your clothing
before entering your grow space is
certainly valid I didn't even think of
bringing it in on your produce that's
yeah that's interesting next up on the
list I have dious Earth so this is
something that's commonly used I know we
kind of talked about this a little bit
we touched upon in our last episode but
I want to bring it back up because
something I've done in the past I don't
do it every grow but I've done in the
past where I sprinkle some Diet tomati
Earth on the top of the medium and from
what you hear through the gra Vine is
that it really helps prevent things like
fungus Nets helps uh they apparently
it's like glass shards to them and it's
really hard for them to kind of be on
top of the medium I'm not sure if it
destroys their exoskeleton or what but I
know in our past episode you had
mentioned that you had some concerns
about the effectiveness of dious Earth
using it what are your thoughts on dious
Earth is it still kind of something
where the effectiveness is questionable
or uh is this something that's kind of
proven to be helpful in preventing pests
yeah I mean di Earth has its place for
sure um but I feel like when you apply
it on soil when it gets moist it's not
effective anymore so since substrates
are usually getting irrigated um that
kind of hampers its Effectiveness in
that way uh but but you know despite
saying that and despite also mentioning
that I've um read a bunch of research
about using them especially for fungus
STS in particular apparently it was not
found to be very
efficacious but people report it being
uh effective for them so I wonder if
there's something going on with certain
pests I mean when people say pests
that's kind of broad uh but you know
specific kinds of pest might be totally
unaffected whereas others might be also
how are you evaluating that I think is
very important if people just apply it
and they just don't get any pests
because they just weren't there you
can't really attribute that to having
like a resistance effect if that makes
sense so I think also people should pay
attention to how they're evaluating
different products um in the first place
where I would use it um would be like a
on a hard surface that's not typically
getting moist or hydrated and then using
that as like a physical barrier cuz
you're right what happens is that the
the datom that are harvested in the
ocean they have these silicate bodies
and they crush them up into like
basically glass and then the insect
cuticle which is like a armored you know
body there's little joints and those
shards can get into them and they can
cause a problem and so it's like getting
all cut up by glass shards while you're
in a suit of armor it's not a pleasant
situation to be in super interesting
it's so you said hard surface can you
give kind of examples on what you mean
yeah like a floor perhaps like maybe
like outside the yeah like at the
threshold between like a door of like
two rooms or something if um if it's
typically not getting like really maybe
on the outside potentially like that's
how people use for like home pests like
ants and and that kind of thing okay got
it let's talk about sprays next a lot of
people will use sprays as a preventative
uh I used to rotate my sprays I used to
do like neoil one week and then next
week do peppermint spray the next week
do a rosemary spray I've used products
like Mammoth can control which is uh for
my understanding I think it's thyme oil
and a corn oil if I remember correctly
and then there's also the amazing Dr zes
which is a product I've used been very
very helpful for not just pest
prevention but also like eliminating
pest as well can you give us your
overall thoughts on those type of
products I mentioned and kind of the
rotating maybe some best practices on
rotating them yeah well I would say that
like um I think that your context really
dictates whether I would personally use
it or not for example if you have um a
situation where you typically get a lot
of pests like kind of constantly like a
low pressure but still present like
thrips are really famous for this kind
of thing they'll get in they won't maybe
you can keep the population from getting
high but you're constantly having them
and if you know that they're coming
around like late spring and summer then
maybe you start applying this um
previous L before you have a problem and
then you don't have like this population
increase um so you could go at like a
weekly rate or a bi-weekly rate of some
sort of like a like a pyin product for
example or maybe asid duratin or
something like in veg but you have to be
careful and I'm very hesitant about
using things in flour not necessarily
because because a product might be
non-toxic or might volatize quickly or
something like this where you don't have
residual however you might still like
disrupt the tricomes or other sorts of
things that might be a quality control
issue so in some cases it might matter
in some cases I would not necessarily um
go that route okay and rotating the the
sprays on like a weekly basis for
example is that effective would you say
because uh I think you touched upon this
in the beginning of the episode where
it's like pest can kind of get used to
it right so if you're spraying neem
every single week they can get used to
it and then it's not really doing
anything to them so rotating around
peppermint is a common one that you hear
about using Rosemary those three in
particular I used to rotate around every
week would you say that could be
effective for the average homeg grower
is there a different spray that you
would add in or or replace yeah well I
think that so like the products that
you're talking about they they work kind
of broadly against a lot of different
like insect and my pest so if those are
the things you're concerned with then
yeah that could be helpful although I
would say that typically I think from
that ever sworm concept we talked about
if you want to disrupt a system you want
to have redundancy that can mean greater
cost sometimes because you have
different products being applied that
kind of do similar things or do them in
a different way and that might seem too
redundant but actually it's helpful for
resistance management um also when
you're applying these products like you
don't know what pest you're going to
encounter so an insecticidal agent is
not going to affect like a fungus for
example so again when you're rotating a
lot of that's I think going to be based
on what when you normally encounter
these pests so like maybe in Autumn and
and winter perhaps you get more fungal
uh problems maybe it rains a lot more
where you're at and so you might start
applying like a potassium bicarbonate
product which is going to have like a pH
effect on the
foliage it has negative effects against
like pwy mill do but you might follow
that up with like an oil product or
something that also harms the spores and
also kills the fungi in a different way
just as an example
understood the last one I want to talk
about here on my IPM routine things that
I've used in the past for IPM maybe not
every grow and actually I've used this
particular product as well in order to
battle fungus knats which is mosquito
bits now I know it's there mosquito bits
is mosquito dunks is a couple different
products but it's all essentially the
same thing which is a type of bacteria
right
BT can you talk to us about BT you know
what is it what it actually does in
regards to pest elimination and or pest
prevention yes so BT stands for basilis
th ganis and it is a species of bacteria
with various strains now you have
different ones out there that are
available so some like israelensis are
used against flies and fly larv
especially um kraki and isawi for
example are used against caterpillars
typically and if you use the wrong
strain it will usually not have very
much much an effect at all against the
the misapplied Target and how these work
is essentially that these different
strains they produce various proteins
like cry proteins for example for
caterpillars and those they all are
toxic for the caterpillar or the fly
larvae it gets into their gut it um
gives them sepsis and they die very
quickly so it's not a great way to go
out um people are sometimes concerned
because they think that maybe the BT
would be uh harmful for themselves uh
but it's actually very very narrow um in
what they affect it can't affect us and
also they require a alkaline gut which
caterpillars for example have um to
damage them so we don't have that kind
of gut anyways so that's how it works
and it was pretty effective in my
opinion it's one of the better things to
use against things like Bud worm Mo for
example the only thing is that the
organism has to come into contact with
enough of the of the propag goals that
you're applying and usually that does
require them to be feeding at that time
so you're in this situation where you
have to apply it and you have to apply
it early and you have to apply it before
the first sign of like budw worms for
example or fungus at larby or something
like that to have the the best effect
now can you overdo it with BT right so
like adding it to the soil we hear about
having a balanced soil food web right
and if you're continuing to add this in
over and over and over again this
particular species well can this
Dominate and kind of throw things off in
regards to the balance of the soil food
web that's a good question and although
other microbes maybe this would be more
true for um BT I don't think so much
because it's kind of an obligate or
maybe a facultative uh or faculative uh
uh parasite so other bacteria and fungi
in the in the uh phylane and the ropl
the foliage surface and the root surface
um I think probably want maybe a a
different kind of bacteria or fungus um
or youd consider something different uh
that would have that kind of disruptive
effect potentially okay next up I have a
viewer question so this is actually a
viewer from our last episode he
commented and he wanted to get your
thoughts on a few things so the question
is how do you feel about pyin and
spinosad or IPM both are entirely
organic and are approved for use on
medicinal plants and they both some of
the well tested products for IPM also
what are your thoughts on bener I'm
going to butcher this one benia basana a
fungus attack pests so I think Pine and
and spinosin which make up spinosad
those are pretty effective they are also
I would I would cause I would call Pre
pretty safe I feel like um compared to
other products like people learn about
like systemic compounds and things you
shouldn't be using in medicinal plants
and potentially other plants too because
they get into like the
nectaries um like NE nanoids do this
sometimes or a lot of the time and then
insects like honeybees come in or or
native pollinators they come in they
feed on it and they die and that's not
great so you know really consider those
sorts of products when you're applying
them uh but I do like to use pyrine
because pyin um they volatize really
quickly and they decay in the presence
of water and sunlight which you get a
lot in various kinds of situations right
so pyin doesn't stay as a res residual
which is nice and as far as um sort of
other products I do like buia bastiana I
like to use it quite a bit you can not
really overdo it for the most part it's
typically kind of expensive though so
you're probably not going to be doing
that um but it's a broadspectrum
entomopathogenic fungus which basically
means that it's a fungus that can feed
on various kinds of mainly insects like
thrips even aphids I like to use a lot
against rude aphids for example so yeah
I have a lot of applications for boaria
and there's different strains of boaria
too and also aera fumosa Oria is another
fungus that you can maybe use in Li of
bouvia if you can't get boaria awesome
now are there any sprays whether it be
those or any other sprays out there that
are safe to use in the flowering stage
you know I'm not somebody who can uh say
that like some of these products have
been tested because unfortunately
there's not a lot of the research that I
would normally rely on uh if I want to
be into ually honest but I think that
for example like the BT I mentioned
earlier I feel pretty comfortable with
that um in some cases the pyin feels
pretty comfortable although I'm very
hesitant to use it past like the very
beginning of flower um just primarily
because I don't like how um for one
thing when you get these products the
pyrine product itself might be fine and
it might volatize very quickly but you
don't know what other products are being
used like inertly in uh products that
you buy right so like if you could just
snap your fingers and just apply pyrin
that's one thing when you buy a
commercial product like one time I had
an example where I was working with a
client they had been buying a pyin
product it was fine no problem then one
day they get um one that has an enhancer
called pipol butoxide which are not
supposed to use or you weren't supposed
to use at the time and they had no they
didn't know how this happened
uh they tested it they we talked to the
the supplier they don't know how it
happened so it just has given me pause
ever since experiences like this you
know so like don't just think that uh
just because the label says one thing
you know sometimes there's weird batches
and things like that to consider that
makes sense what about jadam wedding
agent I've heard a lot of people using
that as like a preventative and somebody
actually mentioned that was safe to
spray and flour would you agree with
that disagree with that or what do your
overall thoughts yeah I don't have a lot
of experience with jadam but um I do uh
talk to a lot of people who do use it a
lot so uh personally I don't have a very
informed opinion on it to be honest um
as far as using it like in veg and
something like that I'm not really
against it necessarily but in flower I'm
not sure as well okay so that's pretty
much all that I've done in the past is
regard as preventative for IPM now are
there any other IPM methods that I
should consider adding to my rtin
well you you've got good crop scouting
so you might for example entertain the
use of how big is your area uh I'm
working in a 13x13 realm okay so um I
would say that you could consider maybe
if you want to splurge like there's
different echelons to this if you want
to splurge you might be able to get some
of these uh High flutin cameras that
they got out there that are like AI I
see people using those um uh there's a
product I saw recently where um it it
flies around on like a um cables uh like
like a thre like really thin cables and
it takes pictures of your of your
canopy and it uses AI to kind of look at
uh the different Spectra of the foliage
and check for different changes and
growth and that kind of a thing but uh
that's really mostly speculative that's
one thing you could do on one extreme
angle uh maybe if you have more plants
the other thing that you could do though
is you could consider adding um a plan
of various pests that you normally
encounter and even just tracking when uh
you encounter them during the year and
once you've got sort of a
regularity you then might look and see
if you have products that you could add
like an additional Mo of action to or
maybe attack a certain life stage so for
example ideally if you've got like a
fungus net there's an egg a larvae and
adult stage and in a pupil stage too if
you can attack every single life stage
and ideally with multiple modes of
action that's like the ideal and so if
you almost always get only fungus Nets
maybe you would spend a little bit of
extra um resources to uh increase that
robustness potentially or you might
realize that that's very expensive and
what you're doing now works fine and
it's very efficient and economical so
it's all context dependent I appreciate
the advice one other thing that comes to
mind that people are starting to use
these days and I want to get your input
on is UV light I think it's UVC light in
particular is what they're using to
shine onto both the soil as well as the
undersides of the leaves what's your
take on that is that an effective
solution for pest prevention or
elimination absolutely it's been used
for a long time um so UV light being
used as like a pesticidal also like for
insects for mites for fungi um it's been
around for a long time uh I used to know
some Dutch Growers use it in glass
houses on like a boom like you would use
like a boom sprayer in a large
greenhouse and they would just attach
lights to it um dosage is very important
because and also being very safe with
its uh use because you don't want those
lights to so UVB and UVC are detrimental
to your skin detrimental to your eyes
you don't want to hurt yourself uh there
was a famous um uh party that happened
recently for some like nft like monkey
coins or whatever those things are and
they put UV lights that were harmful to
your eyes people went to the club and
they reported having like partial
blindness and things like this so you
got to be careful you know if you go to
a party you see UV lights there you
don't know what they used anyways my
point is that you should be concerned
about um the safety but if you use it
responsibly it's highly effective and
you don't even have to dose for very
long so it basically works because the
UV light gets through the cuticle of the
insects or the fungi and it basically
disrupts their DNA
and they die pretty quickly so that's
why it's really highly effective and I
think if uh more people were to
implement them it's important to know
your setup and also to know um the best
way of applying it because in my opinion
the best way to do that is at a level a
stable range where you know how far the
light is from the canopy and you also
know uh and you can be consistent in
your dosage of how long the lights are
on for which shouldn't be too long
typically yeah I've heard of as low as 5
minutes a day some people say 10 minutes
a day is that reasonable I think that's
even sort of um sort of long in some
cases it depends on the frequency though
um of the of the ultraviolet radiation I
think it also depends maybe even like if
you're doing it if you're just having
them on or if you're like moving them
around um to get like an even spread or
something like that but uh for example I
know ex I know situations where people
in research have used against pmu
petritis and they only need to apply for
a few minutes I know UVC light I believe
also comes in some air purification
systems so I have one of the systems
where it uses UV light as well to help
destroy I don't know if it's the viruses
get caught in the air filter or what but
I thought that was pretty interesting
yeah it's a great way to use UV too uh
for air filtration that's part of that
biocurity
where um having like filters and just
understanding like where these organisms
are coming from because people will ask
me they're like my plan works really
well usually but I keep getting these
problems that keep coming in and for
people who are experienced and kind of
know what they're doing already usually
it's some sort of breakdown in your
information pipeline um you know
something that you thought was a true is
a false basically like maybe you thought
that you were secure but oh there's a
hole in your Greenhouse or maybe you
thought everything was fine but your
vents you know your filter isn't working
or you don't have a filter you forgot to
replace it like something is there's a
breakdown in the reality that you
thought you were existing in basically
so you have to go put on your Sherlock
Holmes cap and check around moving on
from IPM let's get into some other
things uh I know you wanted to talk
about mites insects maybe we can get
into fungi bacteria viruses let's start
with mites talk to us about mites and
solutions to eliminate them really just
kind of giving you the microphone here
and drop some knowledge bombs on us for
sure so I think the big one that most
people are dealing with like with the
not just medicinal plants but in general
are like two spot spidermite um I talked
about it extensively they feed on like
4,000 plus plants spidermites are really
good at adapting to different plants and
they can even have populations become
very specific on different species in as
much as a few Generations where they've
uh where they adapt their genes very
very quickly to the hostplant um so
spider mites are very common but there's
also a lot of solutions for them I like
to use things like wettable sulfur for
example that can be very helpful unless
it's harsh for a particular plant that
you're applying to so always be careful
always apply a little bit to see uh if
the plant has a a phytotoxic response or
something like this that's always
helpful for other products that are new
that you haven't applied before you can
also use bio controls I'm a huge fan of
using things like pimus MIT or
californicus mites or things like that I
also like to use them preventatively I
think that's their most efficient use
case although it does require the um you
know the uh best practices and uh the
use cases knowing your quality control
knowing you're sourcing are you getting
them from a tertiary distributor or a
primary producer um how many are you
applying are you applying too many for
your location and maybe you're in a a
smaller area and maybe even the smallest
increment of the bio control you can get
is kind of Overkill already so you'll
have to make those choices yourself this
will be true for most bio controls um
rites are also a big deal uh obviously
in medicinal plants but um also in a lot
of other plants too I dealt with rose
Rite in uh like eight years ago with
Gerber daisies and roses and things and
that cost a lot of uh money and it also
costs a supplier like a million dollars
to like retrofit everything because it
it transfers a virus so the rites that
other people are dealing with in other
plants this is not necessarily the case
but in the Rose Rite that was the case
and anyways the way that you deal with
them is um you got to be very preventive
usually they're very small their damage
is very overt though so if you see
gnarling and curling then you know
you're looking at something that might
be a Rite other damage can look like
rites but um if you see this like sort
of crinkling damage that's typically a
Telltale sign broad mites are like that
too uh but if you are dealing with rites
one thing to note that I think a lot of
people don't realize is that rites are
very specialized so most of the time
you're only dealing with a specific
species so for example if you're if
you're growing coconuts so you're
growing a medicinal plant and you've got
tomatoes and you know there's a tomato
reite uh the Tomato reite probably won't
be able to feed on uh your other plants
if that makes sense so that's something
that I see people getting um confused
about online a lot and I have a video on
my YouTube channel that basically talks
about all kinds of rites where they come
from evolutionarily how did they adapt
the way they did and what you can do to
defeat defeat them same with spider
mites and a lot of these other pests as
well I have been fortunate enough not to
come across spidermites or russed mites
so fingers crossed that that never
happens I'm going to knock on wood right
here and hope that it it never happens
there because I heard that both of those
are very tough to combat particularly
the russed MIT are said to be more tough
to combat than the spiderm but spiderm
can be very difficult to combat that uh
from what I hear particularly when
you're in flowering cuz it's harder to
kind of you know you don't have the
sprays to really fall back on and uh
once they get out of control and start
webbing it's just game over from there
yeah they're really difficult I feel
like uh they represent two ends of a
spectrum of what kind of pests you can
deal with on the one hand you've got
spider mites super common in my opinion
less difficult to deal with although if
you let them get out of control they all
become very hard to diff uh to deal with
on the other hand you've got rites which
I feel like are a little bit less common
for people maybe it depends on where
you're at and but they're much more
extreme in their damage when you get
them and the Damage they cause is
typically like permanent afterwards you
get stunting you get the other problems
so uh you have different maybe threat
levels for different pests I want to get
into insects next but first I'd like if
you could explain the difference between
mites and insects yeah sure so
they last they last share a common
ancestor like over 500 million years ago
even though they look kind of similar
they're actually very different so mites
are like uh arachnids you see so like
spiders and their relatives in that
group they've got eight legs they
typically have eight legs but like rest
of mites only have four because they're
well they've lost a lot of genes over
time let's put it that way you can watch
the video if you'd like to learn more
but um mites
have they have an extensive
um you know various uh various
ecological regions they've gone into
they basically are in all kinds of
niches and the ones we're dealing with
are mostly
herbivorous most mice like spider mice
broad mice and romice are what you're
going to be dealing with with medicinal
plants generally and um the damage that
they cause is usually through feeding on
plant cells uh and usually they can be
kind of innocuous some mites are even
beneficial like in the soil whereas
insects for example they are kind of
they're a smaller group for one a
taxonomic range
smaller uh but there's actually maybe
even more parasitic wasps and beetles
than there are like basically any other
organism on Earth so insects are
incredibly adaptive um highly adaptable
they basically are shrimp that learned
how to live in not the ocean but the air
uh by by evolving Wings they're the
first animals on Earth to have wing
flight so powered flight by the by their
own wings and not by gliding and things
like that and there's all kinds of
insects the ones that you have to deal
with typically are things like thrips
and the hemeras or like aphids and other
insects with like a piercing mouth part
um you've got uh you've got insects that
have chewing mouth Parts too like for
example caterpillars which eventually
become moths and butterflies which all
butterflies are moths uh I could go on
and on but um the the four biggest
groups of insects that people deal with
are or that there are actually on Earth
are flies moths beetles and the hota
which are wasp bees and and ants so
they're all related and I bring these up
because they're the the four biggest
groups they're called the big four um
and so you'll also notice that all of
these are insects that have the larva
Pupa adult life stage development now
might don't have that they have a
different sort of Life stage but it's
basically like the earliest insects had
where they just start off as a little
nymph that looks like the adult and they
get bigger and bigger and bigger and
they they become the adult anyways
that's your uh that's your evolutionary
nutshell now that's great explanation I
think that's helpful for not only me but
many of my audience as well knowing the
difference between those two so talk to
us a little bit more about the big four
that you mentioned as far as insects and
like Solutions some Solutions in order
to eliminate them yeah so the big four
again flies beetles wasp bees and ants
and uh
moths and I think caterpillars the saral
MS are like the biggest issue that most
people are dealing with I think are the
strongest one that people uh encounter
because there's so many different ones
out there uh across the Earth you're
probably going to deal with some kind of
caterpillar that can feed on the plant
that you're dealing with and I think
that the best way to deal with
caterpillars is to First understand that
generally they're going to become
they're going to become active in the
spring and um maybe late spring time and
you're going to have populations usually
that were pupating either in debris or
they were in soil or something like that
and then they they overwinter and they
come out as adults at least if you're in
a place where it Winters if you're in a
tropical area they're probably just
constantly around and that's important
because this first population they're
going to be moving across your region so
if you're in the USA uh maybe they start
off in like Southwest USA and then they
move South uh Northeast essentially a
northeasterly movement as the uh
temperature increases you get more of
them like with the budworm moth um helik
veraza the corn earworm that people deal
with with uh medicinal plants and really
like 200 plus crops across earth um they
start off in the spring and summer they
they ramp up into late summer they
become super active and they move across
earth or ac across the us from the Corn
Belt especially so there's a place in
the USA where most of the Corn is
produced various States um like in kind
of in the Midwest and North Midwest area
mostly so that place is like a powder
keg and then the MS will uh disperse
from that location to other parts of the
USA so if you kind of know that there's
this Rhythm that you can pay attention
to you can avert it by for example
germinating later in the year or getting
plants that germinate later in the year
uh or earlier in the year some way that
allows you to harvest before or after
the peak where the bud worms are going
to go after the flower that's one
example there are many ones out there
got it some really good info there and I
know there's a lot more that can be said
about mites and insects uh we could have
a whole whole episode on each one of
those topics really but let's let's keep
it brief let's move on to the next thing
we have here on the list which is fungi
talk to us about fungi they're all kinds
of fungi right but I think that my
favorite ones to talk about are the uh
powy milw and the necrot Tres the like
Bettis and things like that I like to
bring these up because they represent
two different Pathways to colonizing
plants P milw are what we call
biotopes so they require a living host
to feed on one interest interesting
thing about powdery mildew which you uh
heard me talk about the soil Summit was
that powdery mildew if you go back far
enough they're related to fungi that
broke down plant tissues um so they have
the same genes that they use to break
down the cellulose in plant cells so
perhaps they evolved from these fungi
that used to break down decaying plant
matter and they became really good at
breaking down living plant matter
instead so they became parasites I think
that's really interesting when it comes
the soil food web and that kind of thing
where what could be a beneficial can
eventually become a parasite given
enough time and uh you know uh
familiarity with the host so to speak
and powdery mildew they um they are not
systemic some people think they're
systemic pathogen but things like
petritis are or fusarium are whereas
powder milw only exists on the epidermis
of the plant so only kind of like skin
deep but they um
they uh they're really good at
colonizing the plant once they've
established so when you see different
spots colonize um it's not because
they're moving through the tissue is
because they're recolonizing the host
and powdery milw are not super
detrimental to their plant host
typically whereas things like petritis
they get onto the plant they trick the
plant to kill itself it tricks the cells
to uh destroy themselves and they sop up
the nutrients afterwards so they're a
real threat
and uh they can attack different parts
of the plant petritis for example is
commonly associated with the flower
right uh with the rotting of floral
tissue in particular you also get things
like fusarium that will attack things
like the roots or the stem and sometimes
you have plants where everything looked
fine but then like a few days later it
suddenly starts to wilt um you don't
know what's going on you check the roots
and you see that there's um all kinds of
like oozing you know tissue and
dilapidated structures and it's because
this fungus attacks the tissue and like
immediately destroys the roots and once
the roots are gone there's really not
very much for the plant or if the stem
is really damaged then there's not a lot
of nutrient transfer it dies very
quickly so you got to you got to know
these two different kinds of fungies
some of them are not a huge deal some of
them are a huge deal and they can be a
quick problem so having a plan knowing
that those things are even possible and
then having something that you can apply
beforehand like a microbe or um or a
compound or something like that and also
just keeping your plants hygienic is
also really helpful maybe chopping and
dropping is not always the greatest when
it comes to these uh pathogens that can
be uh on or in the tissues or if you are
going to do something like that like
compost it process it and then reapply
it I had Bud rot before you know when
you mentioned that it just brought up
memories bad memories of course but
Trisa had that I actually had indoors
the oscillating fan died overnight and
so uh there was just that stagnant air
humidity rose right it ended up
attacking four of my plants if I
remember correctly four of the plants
had buritis in it Bud rot and uh it was
just really in the main Cola so uh these
are plants where I had really huge Buds
and it was really just this main Cola
that kind of stuck up more there was Bud
Rod right in the middle because of it
and a lot of people was kind of
surprised because you know obviously I
corrected the problem right so this was
late and flowering when the fan died I
corrected the problem within I think 24
to 48 hours right but correct me up
wrong that is enough time in order for
it to kind of establish from there and
then I spent two more weeks growing the
plants well that doesn't mean that since
I have air circulation now that it's
just going to stop growing right so
it'll continue to spread right so I get
to harvest and then realized oh my gosh
I had Bud Rod it must have been from
when my fan died two weeks ago so um
that wasn't fun now I was able to still
utilize the bottom buds that didn't have
Bud rot and I know some people are
against that they say hey you got bud
Rod one part of the plant throw away the
entire plant other people are going to
say hey just cut off that bud that's
impacted the rest of the plant is fine
what's your take on that yeah that's a
good question because it is systemic
like I said I think that if you're
seeing like if you don't see the
colonization of the the tissues itself
so now you can't necessarily see some of
these things cuz they're microsc opic
right so I think that having a a
cautious approach is definitely valid uh
certainly you could do something like
that generally though I think um at the
very least like not at a homeg grow
perspective when you're growing plants
by yourselves like even if you have like
produce like petritis will colonize the
fruit tissue or the floral tissue um you
know like you know maybe maybe discard
the orange that has the fungus but maybe
don't necessarily discard the orange or
the or the fruit that has no signs of a
of mosis essentially but if You' got
like that moldy uh uh uh development
that ferous oder maybe maybe cut that
part out don't don't try your luck with
that one I think that's totally valid um
but from a commercial level you know you
might be looking at different things uh
you might be able to perceive through
testing and other things if there is
other stuff that you don't want people
to be exposed to as well so it
definitely makes sense to to be cautious
um and I think that also one other thing
I like to say is that bud rot doesn't
necessarily only colonize the floral
tissue and in some cases in some plants
uh it can be a folar pathogen or even a
stem or root pathogen I don't wish Bud R
upon anyone it is not fun at all it's
it's the feeling of going all the way to
the point where you're ready to harvest
and realizing that you've got bud rot
it's just a feeling that I don't want
anybody to have such a waste
it just feels so bad I totally agree
with that let's get into bacteria next
so yeah just open-ended question there
talk to us what you know about bacteria
and what we need to know basically with
regards to IPM and also with regards to
plant Health the most interesting thing
for me is that the there's this like
idea that there's like a fungal or
bacterial dominance that you might be
looking to accentuate and I think that
that's not necessarily the a correct
dichotomy um there's bacteria that are
beneficial those that are detrimental
and then those that even work with each
other as well um it's hard to get a good
snapshot of the microbes going going on
in the uh soil microbiome but also even
on the um phytol plane of the foliage um
I think that it helps to Envision the
plant's surface as like a hostile
environment for the most part you got
these Jagged tricomes and um sto and wax
and secretions and things and I think
that without getting into too much
detail one of the best things people can
do from an IPM perspective is try to
apply some of these bacteria that have a
pathogenic effect against parasites uh
but not just insect semites but also
like fungi there's bacteria that you can
apply and even fungi as well that you
can apply to the foliage and to um other
tissues like the roots that will uh
either colonize the those tissues uh
internally or just on the surface and
they will create a disruptive
environment where other microbes that
you don't want are not able to uh
colonize very well you can also combine
this with so not just microbes or
bacteria that
parasitize like fungi and other bacteria
but also those that produce
antimicrobial compounds and that kind of
a thing but the most important thing is
to find things that will play nicely
with each other and there's a lot more
research to cover but um if we take a
look at the Ecology of microbes and
bacteria on different kinds of plants we
can find what works maybe more generally
and then apply those to other plants
that kind of research is ongoing
bacteria is super fascinating I mean
once I learned that
99.9% of the bacteria we haven't even
discovered yet or researched yet it just
blew my mind that there's so much that
we don't know and so much more to
uncover and we won't uncover It In Our
Lifetime that's for sure and the next
thing to talk about is is pretty
interesting to me as well which is
viruses so uh again want to hand the
microphone over to you and just drop
some knowledge bombs on us in regards to
viruses what do we need to know here's
the biggest knowledge bomb um I was
reading a report recently that talked
about the uh sort of evolution of
viruses and basically they talked about
how it's it's it's possible that when
cellular Life as We Know It And even
pre-cellular Life as we know it sort of
developed things like viroids for
example are not quite viruses right
they're like strands of RNA and thought
that there was a pre-dna world an RNA
world and that vroid are basically like
a reli of that era of life history and
viruses though perhaps especially RNA
viruses they may have been like the
first things that
became uh like
what we now think of as the nucleus of
cells it's possible that as like a
genetic component viruses are basically
you know part of us and have been for
the entirety of cellular life on
Earth knowledge bomb but um so what I'm
trying to say here is that we shouldn't
be surprised that um there are various
kinds of viruses out there some of them
are detrimental obviously but actually a
lot of them are either neutral or even
beneficial for their hosts some of them
them exists inside our genome uh as
retroviruses some of them um can escape
uh or genetic codes that escape from
other cells and things like that um so
that's a little bit high-minded but uh I
think it shows uh contextually exactly
what we're dealing with here these
organisms or not organisms that are like
quasi life and um they're around and
they basically work like
molecular um
uh additions basically um and so
bringing it down to IPM though we have
things like viroids that are huge pain
for exactly that reason it's because
things like hot PL and vroid you know
they they're basically strog gentic code
that our cells or in this case the plant
cells they take and they go oh this is
plant RNA let me replicate you and by
replicating the RNA of the viroid and
not everything else is supposed to do
for the cell you get these weird things
like stunting closis other kinds of
weird damage because you have these
Oddball genes that are just not being uh
expressed in the plant which are very
important and so viruses also um they
can do things weird like you've got
these recombination viruses where their
genome is split up into different chunks
and they move between different plants
and then recombine with each other um
it's very fascinating um and
unfortunately there's not a whole a lot
of conventional solutions for viruses
because they're basically genetic code
and it's very hard to Target genetic
code without targeting the plants code
too it's pretty scary you know once I
heard particularly about hot plade vroid
being identified at 73% of commercial
facilities in the US it just kind of
blew my mind and the fact that in
California alone 90% of facilities uh
medicinal plants tested positive for hot
PL and viroids so I can only imagine the
amount of people that are that have hot
plade and vroid in their garden and
don't know it and they are seeing
deficiency seeing plant problems and
trying to figure it out but it's really
a vroid which they really can't do
anything about so it's really scary I
know it comes into it can be within the
seed it can be transferred in water as
well next week the guest that's coming
on this podcast is going to talk all
about hot plade and viroids so you guys
stay tuned for that one that's going to
be real in depth all about hot PL and
vroid and I'm looking forward to that
conversation now is there any other
viruses or viroids besides hot PL and
vroid that's kind of worthy of of
mentioning and keeping an eye out for
yeah so I want to say one thing about
hot plon vroid uh in particular is that
it was recently found that other plants
like we call the we give viruses these
names typically the first host we find
them in and a symptom that they have
about them like tobacco mosaic virus
right for example example um so hop
latent vroid right and what what's
interesting though is that hopl virid
has been found in things like tomato
sunflower cucumber and um its ability to
transfer from parent Offspring through
seed uh and other older research was
kind of low in newer research it's
showing really high transmission rates
vertically from parent to offspring um
so it can be not just in hop it could be
in other plants too that you might be
growing in your garden it could in other
commercial plants that are being sold
right now they're not being tested um so
that's just a thing to consider so I
would definitely check out that vroid
video upcoming um there's a lot of
information that we should be kept up on
other viroids though there's um um there
are stunt viroids in other kinds of
plants uh Citrus um gets a vroid for
example um that's pretty common peanut
for example um but there's also viroids
that have been found in the human oral
microbiome uh or Le virid like things
recently it came out these so-called
Obelisk like um uh viroids that were
found in the bacteria in our own mouths
and in all the continents on earth they
uh they went through and they
categorized the genetic structure of
these obelisks and they found them in
human samples so we even have viroids in
it around ourselves too it seems like
and as our ability to sequence and look
in finer and finer detail increases
we'll probably be able to find more and
more things like that um generally
though I mean like uh there's a there's
some viruses that are going around right
now in tomato they are a huge deal a
ringspot virus for example um there are
um I guess the another big one that
people are dealing with a lot is be krop
virus very common a lot of people know
about it um it's spreading all
throughout uh various medicinal plants
in the USA and abroad um it's vectored
by the Beet Leaf Hopper pretty much
solely and we have found that uh viruses
that are like 95 to 98% the same as like
vir bctv we find in tomatoes and peppers
in the area they're coming back very
similar so it means that these beat Leaf
Hoppers are going into crops and they're
taking up the virus and then they're
moving into medicinal crops and other
plants and also plants that are just
living around around in the environment
and they act as reservoirs and so if you
live in these areas like Nevada and
Arizona and other places where bctv is
very common um or Colorado then uh you
should be aware of that and have some
plans for finding the symptoms which is
usually like a stunting in the leaves
and a curling of the leaves and
chlorosis as well but if you're suspect
you should definitely get it tested uh
to find out if you can cuz then you know
that probably you won't be able to find
a solution unfortunately and then you
should use your resources for something
else super interesting stuff yeah it's
good that there is some testing out
there now that you can get if you feel
like you might have virus go out and get
it tested there's some affordable
options out there so that's good stuff
so one of the questions I like to ask uh
almost on every episode towards the end
is really looking for advice like I
mentioned we have a lot of beginners
that tune into this podcast what advice
do you have for beginners who are
battling pests for the first time I
think the number one advice for
especially for beginners is to learn
what pests you might be able to deal
with so not just for your particular
region although that's very crucial and
you can find information out from
various kinds of research reports you
can look up there are extension agents
for various places in the world that you
can go to to find out what is a problem
in your region for the plants that
you're trying to grow and then also
having a plan so if you already know
some of those pests or you've
encountered them already then learning
about not only those but the ones that
you might not have encountered yet is so
important it's so useful it's like gold
because you aren't going to be running
around um panicking because you've never
dealt with this problem before and you
don't know what to do and you've never
even looked into it so just having that
it's just such a um just such a valuable
thing in adversity to have that
knowledge set in the beginning before
you deal with a problem that's probably
the number one advice I completely agree
with that okay so let's wrap things up
tell us how can the listeners find you
and what do you have upcoming in the
future you can find me for professional
inquiries at zenthanol decom you can
also check out my informational videos
about plant Health pests and other
interesting facts at uh youtube.com/
senel and you can also find my musings
on my personal account at syn angel on
Instagram and on X and you can also
uh go join my patreon for as little as
$1 a month you can check me out you can
ask me questions and also ask a
community of about maybe 140 people now
um for advice regarding IPM and that
sort of a thing so that's also an an
option as well if you're interested
patreon.com/lenguin
ever swarm concept it's basically um all
you need to know about IPM some
highlevel Theory out there and also some
practical applications of a system of
systems approach and a multi-domain uh
holistic approach to Pest Management not
just products on a list but how can you
look at the ecosystem pests plants and
all the various organisms therein and
I'm very excited to work on it hopefully
I'll be done sometime at the end of this
year or beginning of next year awesome
well Matthew once again this was loaded
with information I appreciate you
dropping those knowledge bombs on us I
learned so much and I have a feeling a
lot of my audience has learned so much
as well so thank you so much for your
time today and hope you enjoy the rest
of your day thanks you too have a blast
peace out everyone catch you in the next
episode