what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you'll watch um extra channel here I
have the plant max jungle g2 LED grow
light they sent me over this girl light
specifically to do this unboxing in part
test video if this is your first time
watching one of my part test videos I do
these just to give you a general idea of
what the power output is it's not gonna
be exact I take measurements in grow
tents whichever reflective walls this
could increase the numbers that you see
on the par meter but knowing these
numbers should help determine what the
light distance should be from the grow
light to the top of a plants I use apple
gmq 500 par meter this meaning measures
from 389 nanometers to 692 nanometers
plus or minus 5 nanometers and the
measurements are in ppfd
okay after I unbox the unit there is
this ziplock bag that includes a power
cord these brackets to hang the light
this cord here is for daisy chaining a
24 volt adapter and the user manual okay
so I've been told that the coverage area
for this girl light is at least two foot
by four foot
however this girl light does not
physically fit in a 2 foot by 4 foot
grow tent so I placed this girl light in
a full foot by 4 foot row 10 which is
actually a pretty snug fit and when I
take the measurements I'll try to keep
my apart meter on one side of the tent
I'll be taking measurements at 3
different distances 12 inches away 18
inches away and 24 inches away before
taking measurements I plugged the scroll
light into my kilowatt meter and it
shows 245 watts being pulled from the
wall and it shows two amps alright let's
get into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comment section below
that's pretty much it for this video
guys if you enjoyed it please click that
thumbs up and I will leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time peace
[Music]