coming up on garden talk when you have
the light really close to your canopy
and you don't have this massive amount
of infrared spectrum that like an hbs
say would have
you're not radiating those plant leaves
and just burning them like a crisp
and you're also not losing the the light
spread i think there's a lot of
misconception where people think adding
uv or infrared makes a
massive difference even in small
quantities it really it really doesn't
make a big difference when you only have
a tiny little bit of it
light spread is critical if you can't
find a par chart for a light
kind of a red flag to me your plant's
not going to be able to accept
you know a high amount of ppfd if your
environment is not dialed in
your nutrients aren't good to go it's
important to make sure that the company
you're buying from
has lab tests done on their fixtures so
that you know that they're not just
making these numbers up there's a lot of
misinformation in the industry and a lot
of manufacturers who aren't afraid to
lie
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 18.
in this episode i interview austin from
chill tech austin has been working for
chill tech for a year and a half
and he has some excellent knowledge when
it comes to led grow lights so i figured
he'd be a great person to sit down with
and talk about
things to look for when buying an led
grill light a buyer's guide as some may
call it
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already and click the bell to be
notified when i release a new video
if you're listening to this podcast on
apple podcasts please leave a rating or
review
those things help the podcast with
ranking and also helps reach more
listeners
if you want to support the podcast even
more i do have a patreon
you can go to patreon.com mr growit and
there are various tiers that you can
choose from on there
i'll also link it down in the
description section below if you're
watching on youtube
before we get to the episode i'd like to
give a shout out to our sponsor
dutch pro nutrients dutch pro sent me
over their entire lineup of nutrients
and i'll be using them in an upcoming
grow they are a plant fertilizer company
that was established in amsterdam 30
years ago
so they've been around for quite some
time their nutrients are available in
several countries across the world and
they have everything needed for proper
plant nutrition
they have different base nutrients
depending on if you're in soil
or cocoa hydro and they also have
different base nutrients if you're using
hard water or ro water to really dial
things in
they also have ph regulators and
additives such as calmag
silica a pk booster and more i'll leave
a link to their amazon store down in the
description section below for those of
you on youtube
and you can use discount code mr growit
10dp
for a discount on their products all
right now let's get into the episode
all right we are back here with austin
from chiltech
how you doing today i'm doing great how
are you i'm doing good
good thanks for joining me today yeah
absolutely so we're gonna be talking all
about grow lights today
and uh really i wanted this video to be
more about
what the consumers should look for when
buying a grow light right there are so
many different things that people can
look for
for somebody who's new to gardening just
starting to grow indoors making their
first girl life purchase or whatever
there's just so many different things it
can be frankly overwhelming so
i thought you would be a perfect fit you
work for chill tech a lighting company
yeah and uh you talk with customers all
the time about this so i thought you
would be the perfect person
on this talk so yeah well thank you yeah
my name's austin i work for chill tech
i've been working for chill tech
since january of last year and really
before chill tech i never really had
much growing experience at all i mean
my mother she was someone who always
kind of had a green thumb and
i always found it interesting but
truthfully i was a gear head
and i like building computers i didn't
really spend much time in the garden but
you know starting at chill tech has
really it's really opened up my world
it's truthfully i've learned so much in
this just
you know it's been about a year and a
half and i've kind of developed a
passion for plants you know truthfully
all of them i mean for me i really like
pepper plants i think they're really
really fun and exciting and there's
so many different species and you know i
love spicy food so it's kind of fun but
i've really just i've discovered the
value of growing so
just been learning more and more every
day but yeah like you said i talk with
people
all the time you know who are looking
for their new grow light and it's
it's it's a tough industry there's a lot
of misinformation
and marketing that is misleading
and you know all these companies they
they really sometimes i feel like focus
on the wrong things
but hopefully i can help do my best to
explain you know because like you said i
talked to a lot of people about these
things so
that's a little bit about me and so uh
we can go ahead and jump right into it
nice yeah and before we actually get
into the nitty-gritty of things austin's
not paying me anything chill tech isn't
paying me anything
i just want to make that clear however i
am affiliated
with chill tech that's a company that i
stand by i have an affiliate
coupon code to where i get referral fees
you can use code mr
grow it to get a percentage off and i
think this month
june we've got something special going
on right so right now all affiliate
codes including yours
are worth ten percent up from the five
percent
all affiliates only get five percent but
right now you're bumped up to 10 percent
um which if you know anything about
chilled we don't often offer
that big of a discount for you know for
coupon codes it's not stackable but
right now yeah you can get that 10
percent
uh which will take you down from the
already sale price so
it's it's really a great time to buy
awesome cool
i also leave a link to chill tech down
in the description section below along
with the coupon codes so
you can easily navigate to that so
awesome
all right let's get into it so uh
talking about grow lights and what
consumers can kind of look for like
ultimate buyer's guide what people
should be looking for when
buying a grow light oftentimes i get the
question from people
you know as i think i believe you know i
tested grow lights for
a year year and a half i got my hands on
about 50 different grow lights and
i grew with a handful of them and did
par tests and all that stuff so i've
seen
a lot of different grow lights and so
people often come to me and ask me the
question
what is the best growth light that
question is kind of difficult to
answer it's kind of like asking what's
the best tv well first you want to know
what size tv are you looking for right
you're looking for a 32 inch you're
looking for a 50 inch a 60 inch
uh and then once you find the size you
can kind of really narrow
down uh what you're looking at
so for example if you're looking for a
three foot by three foot grow space if
that's what you have and you want to
cover that area
you can narrow it down right also when
we talk about
coverage area light distance as well
kind of factoring that in
because some of these grow lights you
have to have them
24 inches 30 inches away so if you're
limited on height if you have a height
constraint
right if you're in a grow tent for
example and you got that light all the
way up well what is 24 inches away
and how much space you have for your
plant underneath that
so i feel like coverage area is kind of
like the number one thing that people
should kind of
understand first know first what area
you're looking to cover
and then kind of factoring that light
distance
what are your thoughts on that one yeah
it's really like you said
it's it's important to know the desired
coverage area first that's one of your
the biggest things you need to pay
attention to oftentimes people reach out
and go
what's your best grow light well that
depends you know
they're not all able to fit in the same
grow spaces and
and so for example we could say a two by
four our best two by four light
is the x3 330 and the hanging height for
that we suggest between 12 and 24
but that goes there's a step further on
that you know your best
hanging height it depends on the stage
of plant growth you're at
but one of the advantages of grow craft
is how close you can get to the canopy
without worrying about you know losing
that light spread like you mentioned
some
some lights have to be at least 24
inches just so that that light can
distribute right
uh whereas growcraft you know it's it
fits right into that two 2x4 that x3 is
just it's like a glove
you know just enough room where it's not
touching the walls or anything but
you really have a smooth canopy light
distribution
and you don't have to hang the light
really high which in turn
gives you a lot better penetration right
you know
when you have the light really close to
your canopy and you don't have this
uh infrared the massive amount of
infrared spectrum that like an hp say
would have
you're not radiating those plant leaves
and just burning them like a crisp
and you're also not losing the the light
spread so
i guess my suggestion for people would
be is to you know figure out
the the space that you want to have it
in the dimensions
and then basically from there you can
start to determine well you know
which size fixture do i need but then
there's another factor to look at and
that's how many watts per square foot
typically i suggest getting around 35 to
40 watts per square foot
and we hold the standard pretty high at
chill tech
a lot of people might compare it to
other lights and see well i can spend
you know just
this this little amount and get this you
know just have just this amount of
wattage
but in reality these companies they've
kind of a lot of them stretch
how far you can really go with a given
amount of wattage at the efficacy that
they have
and so you know we hold the standard
very high and like i said
uh like the x3 330 for example in a 2x4
you have about 41 watts per square foot
which is great that's excellent good for
all plants even those really really
light hungry ones
tomatoes and you know really anything
and you you know since it's a dimmable
fixture you know you can always dim it
down but to get back to hanging heights
it really depends on what you're growing
what stage of plant growth you're at and
the fixture that you have
and then kind of getting into other
things that that people look at
par efficacy spectrum those are some
other things that that people look at
and there's certainly an argument some
people prefer
to look at some over the other as far as
importance right some people think par
is more important than efficacy for
example some people say no efficacy
efficacy then look at par or some people
might say hey spectrum spectrum's
more than that we'll start looking at
spectrum first then look at power then
look at fskc so
it really comes down to personal
preference let's start with par
par stands for photosynthetically active
radiation
it's the energy that the plants use in
order to grow right so these little
little balls of energy called photons
right that are coming down picture them
as as like rain
coming down right and then the the
density of photons or how fast it's
raining for example
can be measured in like a few different
ways right so there's ppf
and there's ppfd do you want to explain
what those
what those two measurements are for par
yeah so
ppf is photosynthetic photon flux
and that's basically the total amount of
light i could say or i guess you could
say total number of photons
that a light fixture outputs and
that's basically how you can use that
number to determine
how much total light a given fixture is
giving out but then you can look at ppfd
which is
uh basically the metric you would see
like a par map shown in for example or
you could see sometimes you'll see like
average
ppfd in a given space
and so that's uh photosynthetic photon
flux density
and so that's the amount of photons in a
given area
i guess you could say one square foot
you know has x amount of
uh you know ppfd and so that's kind of
the difference between those two um and
like you said they're both in par
and that gets into a whole different
world where a lot of people
aren't familiar with par you know if
you're not you know super familiar with
growing or you're just getting into
growing or
you just really don't know a whole lot
about grow lights in general uh par
is it's basically yeah it's like the you
could view it as like the energy raining
down onto the plants
but it's it's also i like to explain as
the way that
plants see light right or they it's the
energy they can use from that light
as opposed to lumens a lot of people
will reach out and say hey you know i
have a lumen meter how many lumens
should i be at and it's well
you know you can kind of use that a
little bit but that's really that's just
how
the human eye sees light and so your
plant isn't necessarily interested in
that so yeah i'm glad you brought up par
and kind of explained par
because that's that's half the battle
right there yeah
and there are some general guidelines
for measurements that that you should
look for
as a consumer so for ppf some numbers
that i have here
if you're in a two foot by two foot area
275 to 375
ends up being in micro moles per second
is the ppf measurement
three foot by three foot area 600 to 850
micromoles per second
four foot by four foot area 1100 to 1500
micromoles per second five foot by five
foot area
1500 or greater micro moles per second
and those are just general guidance
there's just general guidance some may
watch this and
argue that you know it's going to be
dependent on plants
what plant you're growing like austin
had mentioned but that was a kind of
general guide for what you can look at
for ppf and then when talking about ppfd
kind of narrowing it down typically 200
to 400 ppfd for seedlings clones and
mother plants
400 to 600 ppfd for plants in the
vegetation stage
600 to 900 ppfd for plants in the
flowering stage
and arguably can do more than that you
can go higher than that
if you're supplementing co2 and again
those are just kind of general ranges
that you can go by
and looking at the par map there will be
a lot of companies that have a par
map on their grow light listings it'll
tell you at the different distances
whether it be 12 inches away
the grill is 12 inches away from the
plants 24 inches away
30 inches away whatever what those ppfd
numbers are
so growers often will look at those
power maps kind of get an understanding
of the light distance
seeing if it will fit within their grow
tent knowing that they have to have
their light this far away and it's going
to give them the adequate amount of par
through the different stages of growth
that's kind of the way i kind of look at
it
and go about it yeah yeah i like that
you mentioned the
the jet that's a general guideline
because it it varies so much
uh plant genetics like you mentioned
plant genetics play a huge role
in how much you know total intensity
that it can take
at each you know stage of growth uh you
know
and the co2 is another role but also you
know your plants not going to be able to
accept
you know a high amount of ppfd if your
environment is not dialed in
your nutrients aren't good to go so
that's another thing that i
you know i mentioned to people when
they're trying to pick a grow light for
us
uh you know a lot of people will say oh
i have a 2x4 for example
and they'll go i should just go for the
x3
500 watt right which is kind of our 3x5
light
which you know has a lot more power than
even just the 330
and i kind of say to people you know
unless you are supplementing co2
you have everything dialed in you're
really not going to be able to take
advantage of
the jump from the x3 330 to the x3500
in a two-by-four space um you've really
got to have things dialed in so i you
know i
say hold on you know slow down a minute
and you don't need to have
way too much light but you know the one
thing to consider
is that all of our fixtures are dimmable
so you can you know from
from five five percent to 100 so you can
always you know adjust that
um but yeah like i said it's good that
you say that's kind of a general
guideline because it does vary
for sure and then kind of looking at
that that light
output right like ppf is a total light
output right but
how much is that is actually hitting the
footprint right your coverage
area and so some people look at the
light
spread across the coverage area that's
something that they consider they take
into consideration when purchasing a
grow light so
the bar style lights that chill has for
example has excellent light spread
across the entire canopy but you get
some other grow lights where it's very
focused in the dead center of the
footprint and that's it so you might
have
900 ppfd in the dead center but as you
see on that part chart or
some companies actually hide their part
chart they just show that dead center
number
so they look good but as you kind of go
away from the dead center of the
footprint
the light drops off considerably right
you're looking at 900 dead center
but it might be like 200 in the corner
having a light
spread evenly across the footprint
is another thing to consider when
looking at lights right yeah yeah
absolutely light spread
is very important and like i mentioned
before you know one of the advantages
of growcraft and having the bar design
is yeah that's spread
but yeah and the ability to hang it
lower without losing that spread
because yeah if you if you have one you
know a thousand ppfd
in the center but 200 on the edges
you're you're going to get
not a very great yield on those edges
you can have a lot of you know uh
i guess you'd call it larf or really
just like underground stuff because it's
just it's not getting the intensity that
it needs
and you're gonna have a really uneven
canopy another thing you'll you'll
notice with some
other style lights the more spotlight if
you would
lights or or quantum boards and stuff is
when you have to
you have this centralized area in the
center that's way more powerful your
canopy becomes
very uneven and then you know you have
your center your canopy is getting all
tall and then your edges are short
and it just it makes that even worse you
know right where the center is just
getting more and more light and the
outsides are not so yeah again light
spread very important
uh like you said some companies will
actually kind of hide
their power charts which to me deal
breaker for me because you
you've got to have not only tests done
by the company but also third-party
tests you know
we try to send our fixtures to as many
people as we can
and we don't you know we we don't really
sponsor we just we give them light and
say you know hey
check this out you know what do you
think test it out because we want to get
people's genuine
test results because you know we're
confident that you know we've really
narrowed it down and gotten that light
spread
to be optimal so i agree with you yeah
light spread is critical
if you can't find a par chart for a
light kind of a red flag to me
and we obviously offer par charts for
all of our fixtures but also there's
plenty of third-party
testing that's been done i had a company
hit me up last week
and they sent me there a picture of
their grow lighting like oh we're
looking for somebody to test it or
promote the grow light
and so i started asking about the
questions like so what's the par at the
different levels there's no part chart
and they said
what's par oh
the conversation ended pretty quickly
there but yeah get out of there
that's funny i've never heard that yeah
yeah what's part wow
there's so many different companies on
the market today that you just
dig into it do your due diligence make
sure they know what they're talking
about because there's people at these
companies
and lights that are out there that are
just hot garbage and
uh the people working for those
companies don't know what they're doing
so
yeah it's good to to go with a company
that um actually knows what they're
talking about for sure
right yeah that's that's pretty scary
not knowing what the car is
yeah but uh moving on to uh efficacy
talk to us about efficacy yeah so
efficacy is essentially and layman's
terms how efficiently a grow light can
take input wattage and turn it into
usable par which is what you want this
is like one of the most
important uh you know specifications or
metrics that you can look at for a grow
light
because you could have a thousand watts
but if you have an efficacy
you know below you know let's say you
know one micro per joule
you're not really getting a whole lot of
uh output you know in terms of what your
plants can use
and so when you have a low efficacy and
a high input wattage you're losing
a lot to heat you're losing a lot of
energy to heat which
heat is basically almost every grower's
worst enemy
unless you're somewhere that's extremely
you know cold but generally you never
really want to have
uh your thousand watts being turned into
a lot of heat so efficacy is one thing
that we
put a lot of focus on we strive to have
the most efficacious light
you know is in basically every regard
you know in every
single grow craft fixture that we have
and recently
we actually launched the pre-orders for
grow craft ultra which
chris i know you've checked it out so we
have the the grow craft ultra
which is our ultra efficient fixture you
know it's it basically takes
the grow craft fixture which is already
great and takes things up a notch and
that's done
through uh you know how making sure we
have the highest quality components
possible
and having more diodes so we basically
you know
an x3 330 on the ultra has 4104 diodes
uh which is you know quite a few you
know if you you guys who have you know
kind of paid attention to great
technology that's kind of unheard of you
know to have a three bar light fixture
with only 330 watts
and so what that does is it basically
drives down the wattage per diode
and when you do that it actually
increases the efficacy of the diodes and
they run cooler and since we have these
over built heat sinks
you know they run even cooler and so
they they're they run very efficiently
and and uh you know what that leads to
is basically
minimizing the amount of input wattage
you need which
is great you know everyone wants to
reduce uh electric electrical use and so
basically we could compare it to is is
we have our
x3 500 watt standard grow craft and
we have an x3 330 ultra and that ultra
is producing similar total ppf
to the x3500 watt but obviously uses
less wattage
now the cost is higher because the cost
for us is a lot higher we are using the
absolute
highest possible bin and best diodes on
the market
and they're hard to get they're very
hard to get especially right now with
all the shortages
and so that caught that cost is the cost
that we have to have but
it's something that i think is worth it
because we're pushing
the industry forward and really showing
what is possible
right so the x3 330 ultra you know with
a
3.19 micro mo per joule efficacy is the
highest lab tested ever to date so far
and the standard you know grow craft
lights they're not far away from that
but this jump you know it takes a lot to
get to but really just shows what's
possible
and so having a high efficacy is very
important
and like i said we strive to have that
in all fixtures
and we even hit that record you know
with with the ultra but that doesn't
mean the standard grow craft has a low
efficacy it's still you know class
leading uh the x6
600 watt standard growth craft for
example at full power has a 2.81
micro mole per joule efficacy which
you know you can kind of look around at
other girl lights it's pretty high and
that's it's backed by lab test
which is another thing that's really
really big it's important to make sure
that the company you're buying from
has lab tests done on their fixtures so
that you know
that they're not just making these
numbers up you know like i said there's
a lot of misinformation in the industry
and a lot of manufacturers who aren't
afraid to lie and that's not something
that chill does
it's not something i would ever support
so
just make sure you pay attention to to
the efficacy and you make sure that your
fixture has a high efficacy that way
you're making the most of that wattage
so fxc measurement like you mentioned
micro moles per joule so when you're
looking at the grow light listing you'll
see
uml slash j for joule
um sometimes the the u is actually a
symbol it looks like a u but it's
actually a stands for micro it's a
symbol that stands for micro so micro
mole
per joule um here in 2021 i think
many can agree that anything under 2.0
micro moles
per joule is not efficient
we're way beyond that i think average
what i usually see 2.7
2.8 or even beyond that micro mold per
joule and some people consider efficacy
like the number one thing they look at
they look at that before they even look
at the par
numbers or again like i mentioned some
people look at par they prioritize par
over efficacy but there's neck and neck
there
as far as what to look for good
spectrum spectrum is another big thing
that people look at
you know you've got the spectrum chart
with all the colors going on there
talk to us about spectrum yeah spectrum
is very important
obviously you know right now we offer
under standard
craft two spectrums we have the flower
slash
full cycle spectrum or the veg spectrum
and now i have a lot of people that will
ask you know which one should i get
which one's for me i want to
you know i want to be able to go from
seed to harvest and that's
that would be the flower full cycle
spectrum and the reason for that is that
spectrum
from the white diodes alone there's
almost 20 percent blue spectrum already
and so it veggies really quite well and
but you also have that advantage of when
you hit flower you know you've got
plenty of red
you know basically it's it's a really
well balanced spectrum that's just
geared towards flower
and so uh it's been fine-tuned over many
years
chilled was started in 2016 and vitali
has been messing with leds our founder
for a long time and has basically found
out the best recipe for a single channel
light
that really does everything great and
you know performs very well in flower
so if you want to get the veg spectrum
that that spectrum has
more blue or uh i guess it focuses on
450 nanometer blue
and so you lose a little bit of you know
far red with the 660 nanometer
and it you know in exchange for more
blue which in vegetative growth
or if you have leafy greens like lettuce
and stuff like that um they prefer
more of a blue spectrum um to help you
know
overall lateral lateral growth uh you
know keep that inner nodal spacing very
tight
and basically you know just overall some
slight improvements when you go for a
veg spectrum for vegetative growth
but it's not required with those two
spectrums
we also are going to be releasing our
guardian system
which allows people to add spectrum bars
and those spectrum bars they add uv
infrared a little bit more deep red and
far red and more 415 or
450 nanometer blue and what that allows
you to do is to manipulate the spectrum
because first of all not all plant
genetics like
the exact same spectrum some of them
prefer
more blue spectrum or more red spectrum
for example if you have a very
tall plant that's just growing very
stretchy
what you can do is use more blue
spectrum to help kind of tighten it down
get those nodes
to grow a little tighter and not have
such a tall lanky plant
so that's not required but it's some
something that i think a lot of people
enjoy to play with
and really get to mess with the
morphology of a plant which
i think is fascinating i love that um
but again
not required the standard full cycle
flower spectrum has been fine-tuned for
seed to harvest growth
and most of our commercial growers
currently use that and
um you know as you've probably seen with
a lot of the pictures on our instagram
and stuff it's
got great results it's really really
kicking it out there
and i think a lot of people will be very
satisfied with that spectrum
man i don't have too much to add to that
you covered cover just about everything
here
but i do want to highlight the blue
spectrum for the vegetative stage
so blue light inhibits cell division
that's what caused the tighter node
spacing on the plants
a lot of people prefer that for
medicinal varieties for example
so they don't have these long stretchy
lengthy plants
so they'll have a higher blue spectrum
now typically
what i've been told is between 15 to 20
blue now unfortunately you're not going
to be able to look at
companies don't really advertise what
percentage uh
the different colors are unfortunately
right so and you can't just look at the
par
map i'm sorry the spectrum chart see
that there's a blue spike and you can't
tell what percent blue is no matter how
big the spike is
no matter how it looks you can probably
reach out to manufacturer
and maybe ask them what percentage of
blue is but i consider that definitely
one of the
more important things when talking about
spectrum for sure
yeah one other thing i want to add about
spectrum is
you will see a lot of companies without
naming names that will
add uv like a diode or two or add
infrared in a diode or two
and it's such a you know small amount
just so that they can say that their
spectrum includes it and i think there's
a lot of
a misconception where people think
adding uv or infrared makes a
massive difference even in small
quantities it really it really doesn't
make a big difference when you only have
a tiny little bit of it
and so when you see companies that add
just like one diode of uv
don't be fooled you know it's such a
small amount that's kind of even hard
to see on a spectrograph you know if
you're using a reader to test it
so make sure if you have uv included
that you look at the spectrograph you
know
and make sure that it's that you know
you can actually see it especially
especially if it's backed by
you know lab data um so don't be you
know don't worry too much about
you know having it just a diode or two
of uv that's you know doesn't make
as big of a difference as having the
proper spectrum overall
and there are going to be some people
out there like some lighting scientists
actually say that photons are photons
you know the spectrum is very little
importance of it so
you're going to hear a lot of different
things depending on who you talk about
there's
you know we could get in deeper on uv we
can get into green light we could get
into ir but
um that's really probably best suited
for a different video
right because we started talking about
plant growth and stuff like that this is
more of like a buyer's guide
on what you should look for on that
avenue but um
but yeah that spectrum is another thing
to look at another thing that i don't
see on many grow light listings anymore
i feel like i used to like four or five
years ago
is cri can you talk to us a little bit
about cri
yeah so cri is is the color
rendering index and that's basically how
accurately
a light source can represent natural
color um
now with that there's also uh you know
color temperature
so it can get a little confusing and
there's even been some
considerations of using a different
metric for leds because leds have
have gotten so you know so accurate with
color and stuff like that and there's
such a wide range but one of the funny
things is that
growcraft actually has approximately a
93 cri
which 100 being uh you know it's
perfectly represents what
color or or something would look like
under natural lighting
and so uh with that you know as opposed
to something like a blurple or some of
the other lights uh
your your plant is gonna look you're
gonna be able to see things on it right
it looks like it's just under the
sunlight
uh so you can really see you know what's
going on on the leaves or you know if
you have any weird growth maybe some
some powdery mildew
or anything like that that you know you
want to be aware of right away
so having a high cri kind of a side
benefit
that growcraft does have um as opposed
to you know like a
you could have compared to a bad example
is or i guess a good example is a is a
blurble light which
uh if you've ever worked under a blurple
light is not
great it's not fun because it's first of
all it's not very good for your eyes but
you also
you can't really see it and it has a low
cri because
we don't see the world in blur pole
thankfully honestly cri isn't something
i really even look at
but uh but that's interesting that you
say that yeah i didn't know that
i think probably we don't see it as in
many listings is because a lot of these
lights are white light leds
would you think that that would probably
be the case why people don't
mention cri as much anymore i think cri
is just something that's more focused on
for the photography
industry right because you're it's more
of a selling point for something like
that where
if you're working with you know any sort
of color correction or
you know making sure that things are
represented appropriately
you know it's that's something that's
more for for like making a movie or
taking pictures and stuff like that
but it's it's a side benefit of a grow
light right it's not something that's
critical but you could also assume that
if something has a high cri
it probably is pretty accurate to what
sunlight is
you know what sunlight actually looks
like and that's where plants
grow right uh originally plants you know
started growing
outside and so having a high cri kind of
indicates yeah you have
a more white spectrum or uh accurate to
this what sunlight is
gotcha gotcha energy consumption let's
talk about watts
so 10 years ago it was all about watts
right
600 watts for a 4x4 thousand watts for a
5x5
and that was what people shopped by they
shopped by watts that's not really the
case anymore when we
moved over to leds right so watts is a
measurement of energy consumption you
can take that number
and you can actually use that and as
long as you have
a kilowatt per hour from your
electricity company you can actually
figure out what your electricity bill
would be by doing a calculation there so
that's mostly what people use
watts for they don't really use it these
days as an intensity
factor i mean you mentioned the watts
per square foot
earlier but you know really watts is
still being misused
a lot these days um there's no longer
you don't really need
600 watts in a 4x4 anymore you can get
away with 400 450 watts some of these
grill lights
and it depends on efficiency and it kind
of goes back to the
efficacy we talked about right how
efficient is the grow light
talk to us about watts what else do
people need to know yeah absolutely like
you said there's a lot of misconceptions
on
wattage and um you know how much wattage
you really need just depends on that
efficacy
uh you know we still use or like our x6
for example which is our best 4x4 light
we offer it in a 600 watt four that we
suggest for
for flowering a 4x4 and
i think that it's not required to have
600 watts even with a high efficacy but
it certainly helps
you know having a high wattage with a
high efficacy means you're really able
to push the plants hard
and back to kind of like supplementing
co2 with our x6 600 watt in a 4x4
you're you're probably going to want to
have co2 to really get the most out of
it or else you're going to end up
probably having to dim your light
without it but yeah you can stretch an
x6 600 watt to a 5x5 with no problem
that 600 watts these days it will cover
it you know having a 2.81
micro mole per joule efficacy really
makes the most of each watt
and back to the ultra it pushes that
even further you could use our x3 330
watt
ultra which you know does come at a
higher cost you could use that in a 4x4
though and get great results
and still have a good you know average
ppfd across the canopy
so yeah wattage has really changed but
one thing to also consider is that all
grow lights and their efficacy is not
the same so you cannot compare
the wattage you might find on this model
to the wattage on this model you've got
to pay attention to
back to you know making sure you look at
the wattage the efficacy
the total ppf uh the total p the average
ppfd across the grow space that you want
to use it in
basically you have to use all those
factors to figure out which light will
be best for you and the plants you're
growing
in this desired stage that you're
growing at but yeah wattage is
it's we're definitely seeing a decline
in the need for a high input wattage
but also at the same time increasing um
total output you know as opposed to like
a thousand watt hps
which yeah you needed a thousand watts
to cover a five by five
um you know effectively but you know not
anymore we're definitely bringing down
that wattage so
it's nice to see yeah and then like you
had mentioned even if you're putting a
600 watt one of the
chilled 600 watts in a 4x4 you can
always dim it down if you don't have
that
co2 supplementation that's features is
another thing to look at right
i highly recommend you get a dimmer on
your grow light these days just because
you have that flexibility
to reduce the amount of energy you're
consuming
therefore reducing your electricity bill
right you'll even be able to get the
light closer to your plants if you're
dimming it down
so it helps when you talk about light
distance so it just adds flexibility
having a dimmer in there you know that's
a feature to potentially look at
detached driver is another thing right
so some of these grow lights
chilled grow lights you can actually put
the driver which produces
heat outside of your grow tent for
example if you're hiding
if you're having in the grow tent so
that heat that's generated from the
driver it's not going into your
environment
so you have that or you have fixtures so
you know some companies will have the
driver mounted to the actual fixture and
again that produces heat increases heat
so that's a potential feature to look at
if a heat is a concern for you
120 volt 240 volt like you know that's
something else you got to look at
what features do you think that
consumers should be looking at these
days
definitely the dimmer like you said i i
don't think i i would really
even want to grow light without a dimmer
just because uh maybe it's just because
i'm so used to
how nice it is having the the chilled
grow craft lights with a dimmer because
you never know what you're going to be
growing you know truthfully you could be
growing this one time and then
next time you want to do this or you
know your plants might need different
intensities based on their genetics or
uh you know you change your light your
distance or you know your grow
environment
it's so nice to be able to uh you know
change the dim your grow light i think
that's extremely important and this
isn't
you know the meanwhile drivers that we
use we use the 48b
is the last you know serial numbers of
the the meanwhile drivers we use and
these have an external dimmer
and we have a dimmer pot or
potentiometer that has a very smooth
5 to 100 percent intensity range and
that way you can really you can use the
light for really anything at any stage
of growth
or if you know if you need to for
whatever reason you know kind of reduce
your your heat temporarily
you can kind of reduce reduce the the
intensity while you you know let's say
your ac
broke or something like that you want to
keep the light on its light schedule
you can do that and reduce the dim get
the heat down
but yeah that kind of goes into another
thing too uh
is is basically having that that driver
you can put the driver in the tent
if you need let's say it's winter time
and where you live it gets very very
cold
and you know with the reduced heat
output of led
versus hps that you could potentially be
used to
uh you know you may need that heat and
so you can put the driver in the tent
but yeah like you said you can remove it
out we include with all of our grow
craft fixtures
both diy kit and the pre-built
commercial
a seven foot extension that goes from
the driver
to the fixture and then we also have six
and a half feet from
the wall plug to the fixture but you can
also always come back to our site
and get uh more of that extension cable
now i don't typically suggest
going over 21 feet from the driver to
the fixture because then you
have to start worrying about you know
losing wattage
and things like that so typically we
suggest 21 feet which gives you plenty
of room to
you know mount around the wall outside
of your room or put you know a lot of
people just put it on top of the grow
tent or just on the floor
not really anywhere and you can remove
that heat which is to me is an awesome
feature that
a lot of grow lights miss out on you
know you'll see especially quantum
boards
you'll see they have the driver mounted
to the fixture
and so there's not really the ability to
remove that heat but also
not having the driver on top of the
fixture reduces the heat
of the grow light and like i mentioned
before you know essentially a cool diode
or
chill diode is a happy diode and one
that lasts longer but also can be more
efficacious
so yeah having that external removable
driver
it's excellent feature that i think a
lot of other companies should have
getting into drivers diodes the
components
of the fixture right that's a lot of
people put a lot of emphasis
on that you know diodes samsung we've
got ozram cree
bridge lux epistar there's just so many
different dial brands out there
drivers you got meanwhile eventronics
sosan there's
on and on and on give us some advice
about what
people should look for when it comes to
looking at the diodes
looking at the drivers the components of
the fixture yeah
so the diodes is obviously one that a
lot of people pay attention to
um but you know with chilled we don't
publicly disclose the exact model number
but i can tell you
you know for the for the white chips we
use top bin samsung's
um basically the highest you can get and
we don't disclose the reds but
if you look at the numbers and the lab
results it's very becomes very clear
especially to someone who's experienced
with grow lights that we must be using
the best of the best and to achieve
those numbers we have to be using the
best
but with you know with the diodes
there's also the drivers so there's kind
of two main manufacturers
that you should look for there's
meanwell which
you know typically is the most efficient
and then there's animatronics which is
also
a pretty efficient and good brand and
then there's
there's many other side brands with kind
of no names
which i can't speak on directly but
don't always have the best reliability
so i typically
would suggest looking for a meanwhile or
animatronics driver
like i said we use meanwell we use one
of their most efficient drivers
and has that ex you know it's a little
bit more expensive it has that external
dimmer that we connect the dimmer pot to
um for that really smooth uh dimming
zero zero two
or five to a hundred percent um also
another thing that i wanna hit on
is basically the overall build quality
of the fixture
this is something that surprises a lot
of people when they first get their grow
craft light
they're absolutely blown away by the
build quality and
i think that it's something that we have
an offer that a lot of companies don't
is really having a really robust strong
sturdy
american-made good-looking structure
and our u-frames are actually made
locally
in arlington just down the road from us
and they're powder coated the other way
down the road
in arlington washington and they're such
a high quality piece it's
it's hard to see over pictures and
videos just
how sturdy and solid these things are
and we have those really really nice
over built
aluminum heat sinks and yeah they just
the build quality is often referred to
as like an aerospace grade
which i totally agree with you know
actually i heard that from a from a
customer one time and i'm like yeah
that's that is true it does look like
it's aircraft grade you know it's built
really strong so
you never have to worry about dropping
this thing no i don't suggest dropping
it but
a while back uh you know later last year
we released a video
just kind of a funny spoof video where
we dropped uh you know dropped a
grovecraft light off of a ladder and
truth be told that did happen we did it
many times because there was multiple
cuts
and this thing was still fine no
problems at all i don't suggest it
again but it was totally fine and it's
because of that really really strong
structure
that i think a lot of other companies
miss out on you know they these are kind
of some of the spots they'll cheap out
on it
is is uh just the build quality and so
you don't you don't want to flimsy grow
light
you don't want that but also we we spent
a little more time in research and
development
and it costs a little more but we've
created a fixture that
um has replaceable parts as well so
basically
you if let's say you had a pcb go bad or
for whatever reason
you actually hit it with something and
you know broke broke a diode or whatever
you can always pop in a new pcb we sell
these on our site
uh you know for very reasonable costs we
even offer b grade which is just they're
just slightly scratched no
no physical damage or anything like that
uh so
that's another part of build quality i
think that's very important is just
having a very very sturdy light
that's going to last you a long time
uses you know like i said
top bin samsungs and really just the
best dials in the market having that
good driver
having the external dimmer all those
kind of things i think are very
important to look at yeah and and paying
a little extra for that stuff i think is
is worth it as well
and kind of getting into the price
prices can vary so much
i mean we're looking at for a four foot
by four foot coverage area
lights ranging from seven hundred
dollars all the way up to like
fourteen hundred dollars for something
like something even more than that
for that particular coverage area so
prices can range like crazy and that's
gonna be one of the things that
folks look at right is the price now one
of the things that
chilled does which i thought was pretty
interesting on your website you list a
couple measurements for price
things that consumers can look at which
is price per watt and price per micro
mall
can you talk to us a little bit about
those two yeah yeah absolutely so
the price per watt is one that i
typically steer away from i know
a lot of people especially some of the
more old school people
they really focus on that price per watt
back to wattage being more important
previously than it is now right and to
me
wattage is not what you should be
focusing on because truthfully a
high-end
high efficient grow light doesn't need
as much input
wattage as a cheaper one and so you
start looking at the dollar per watt
and things can get a little weird
because you're like well this this light
shows that it outputs this much ppf
but it has much lower wattage and so the
dollar per watt you know is
can be messed up so i prefer to look at
uh
you know dollar per per micromole which
is something that
that i think that we we do very well in
and that's because
having an eye high efficacy and you know
uh
having that respectable wattage number
basically
your your main focus is micro moles
because that's what your plant is using
it's using those photons right um
to see you know what what the the total
um
you know light output is you basically
that's what you're focused on is making
sure your plant gets the light it needs
at as cheap of a cost as possible that
makes sense
for sure now all that being said you
know you've
we've been through everything there
right you've you look to buy coverage
area
for the light you make sure that the
light distance is going to fix
fit within your grow space par efficacy
spectrum
you're looking at all those things watts
features
you've narrowed down the price you found
your fixture you buy the fixture and it
jumps out within six months and you
realize that the warranty
only lasts five months so warranty is
definitely something what i'm getting at
is warranty yeah is another thing you
should be looking at right so
we'll wrap it up there as far as
warranty some companies are
just going to give you one year you've
got one year if the fixture
burns out on you after that it's on you
some companies that do a three year
but if some of the components burn out
after a year
you get to pay for the components you
got to pay for shipping or something
along those lines
then you have some that have a full
warranty so three years full warranty
they'll do the fixture back and forth as
far as shipping costs they'll pay for
the components so some people have the
five year warranty
so there are many different warranties
and it varies by
led grille like company do you want to
talk to us a little bit about
warranty yeah warranty is a big one so
on our diy kits our our cheaper fixtures
you gotta assemble yourself
they have a one year parts warranty
which is kind of unheard of for a diy
product to offer that because the
assembly is in your hands we essentially
give you parts
kind of like legos and then are saying
if you have any problem with parts
within a year
we will cover you know if you're in the
states we'll cover shipping both ways
and you know we'll pay for the return
part and you'll be
basically up and running typically with
you know around a week
we basically from the time you email in
saying hey i had a bad pcb or or one of
my diodes is out or anything like that
or if you have a faulty meanwhile driver
we basically will send you a new one
within a day you know we're very very
big on that
because you know us all being growers
ourselves we understand that
the more time that your grow light is
down um the worse it can be
especially you know if you're any you
know you're you're growing really any
plan i guess but especially
like a medicinal plant uh you know
having that grow light go down
could could cost you your your harvest
which is not something you want to have
you don't want to have a girl like go
down
you got to wait you know a long time for
a warranty or you got to send the whole
thing out
and basically have it repaired you know
we'll send you parts out right away
so the commercial grow craft fixtures
have a three-year warranty
which allows you the ability if you have
any problems with the light
at all you can send the grow light back
to us
and we will fix it usually the
turnaround is pretty quick you know
under a month for sure you can basically
have a problem
reach out to us send us the picture we
fix it send it back
but also we do again back to
understanding that
you know the longer your grill light is
down the worse uh
we allow you the ability to just have
parts sent to you we are willing to send
parts cover shipping again with your
if you're within the states and you can
basically just swap out the part and
you're good to go
the grow craft fixtures they're very
easy to work on that's one thing that we
really focused on was the modularity and
the ability to
just basically swap parts out quickly
because again you just can't have your
grill light go down that's not something
anyone wants
you can lose a whole harvest because of
it so again
three year warranty on the commercial
fixtures one your parts warranty on the
diy
and again we don't there's no sort of
fine print in that warranty
where a lot of companies they'll offer a
three year warranty but after the first
year you have to cover
shipping most of the time both ways or
you have to start covering
the labor cost to fix it after two years
we don't do any of that
if you have a problem and it's you know
it's been two years
we treat you as if you just got the
fixture you know we don't we don't play
any games with you on the warranty
and again we're very quick about it we
are we have
one main location and it's in arlington
washington
in the states so you're you don't have
to wait for this to go overseas or
anything like that
and you can always you can almost always
call us even if we don't answer you can
shoot us an email and we typically
respond within 24 hours even on the
weekends when we're not in the office
i'm always checking and making sure
everyone's taken care of
shoot us a dm2 if you want on any of our
social media you know chill grow lights
and we'll take care of it you know we're
here to help people when we're growers
and we basically just try to provide the
best experience we can possibly when it
comes to warranty because
no one likes warranty claims no matter
what the product is it's not fun
to have a problem and we make sure we
make that as easy
and as quick as possible yeah warranty i
mean definitely
definitely look at that so you don't get
screwed that's for sure but yeah we
covered a lot so you know
i uh before we when i got this idea for
the video
and when i contact you i'm like man this
is gonna be a good video where things
are gonna be explained so
easily and people are going to get it
it's going to be all smooth
looking back what we just recorded
there's a lot of things to consider
when purchasing a grow light and there
are people that are going to leave this
conversation still confused and still
not know which way to go
definitely it's hard it's hard and
sometimes i feel like i'm bad at
explaining but
um i always just try to suggest people
to just reach out to me you know i love
talking about it and i'll
as you can see i'll just keep talking
and talking and talking
but it's because i just genuinely enjoy
it and i think there's so much
misinformation
and people are misled so often and i
really just want to help even if you
at the end of our conversation you don't
end up buying our light that's fine with
me i feel like i've helped you know i've
done my part
and that's kind of our whole mission
with chilled is to not
just just sell lights and turn a profit
it's you know
from the beginning vitali's mission has
always been to educate people
help drive a bet a more sustainable
efficient future
and really just get people into growing
you know i don't want anyone to feel
intimidated with growing because there's
too much information
um so please you know always just reach
out to us
like i said even if you're not buying
something let's talk let's let's figure
it out let's
figure out what's best for you and we'll
make it as easy as possible
cool so how can the listeners find you
and what does chill tech have upcoming
in the future
yeah so listeners could find you know me
and chilled really all over the place
you know we try to be
on all sorts of social media so twitter
you know uh
facebook instagram you know chilled grow
lights
you can find us on youtube chilled grow
lights um
email service at chill growlites.com you
can find
me all over the place there you know
we're even in the
ocean grown discord and uh we hope to
expand even further
as time goes on and uh you know i don't
have to wear so many hats you know
because right now
my focus is kind of all over the place
and uh i try to be as many places as
possible but hopefully
that'll expand even further some of the
things that we have coming up
if you guys haven't seen already we have
our guardian system coming out
and that system includes you know a
touchscreen
controller spectrum bars which add you
know uv infrared
deep red far red more blue and then
all these sensors that we're going to be
having we're you know we're going to
have co2 sensors
power sensors all sorts of sensors to
basically automate as much as you can
with your grow
and monitor things and and be able to
data log
um and then with that we also have our
ultra our chil
grow craft ultra fixtures that are
coming out and those again those are
kind of a
more of a limited run there you could
view them as kind of our
super car if you would um so if you want
one of those definitely hop in and
pre-order one
um but those will be coming in the
future but we
we plan to stick with the current grow
craft design for a while we
you know may expand here and there but
mostly our focus is to keep building
upon what is already great and already
there
as opposed to replacing it because you
know what's there is truly great
and this guardian system and stuff like
that will really just help
elevate it so if you want spectrum
control or you're interested in any of
that
definitely head to our youtube channel
and you know check out some of our
explanation videos
but also we're gonna have a lot more
content on that soon and hopefully you
know
i could potentially come back on the
show when it's all done
and fully released and not just
pre-order and kind of maybe show you
or talk to you about it and maybe
someday you know we could potentially
hook you up with a system
yeah absolutely that'd be cool so lots
of good stuff there
yeah i will leave a link to the chill
tech youtube channel
down in the description section below
and also link the chiltech
website down in the description section
below along with the coupon code so mr
grow it's going to give you
10 off this month and then every other
month it's just 5
so if you're watching this in june 2021
head on over there for that 10 for sure
and i'd love to know in the comments
section
of you guys watching what do you look
for when it comes to buying a grow light
like we went over a whole bunch of
things here did we miss anything
is there anything that you consider a
higher priority
so on and so forth so let us know down
in the comment section below
austin thank you so much for coming on
to the show today i truly
appreciate it and i hope you enjoy the
rest of your day yeah absolutely
thank you chris
[Music]
you