coming up on garden talk if you had 100
uva photons for example and 100 blue
photons the uva photons would only view
then 20 as effective as the blue photon
i've tested maybe 100 grow lights in the
last two or three years i haven't seen
one whose spectrum wasn't suitable for
growing you can hack to
getting at the equivalent of a three
hundred dollar quantum sensor parameter
for in about twenty dollars twenty five
dollars compared to blue and green red
photons are more photosynthetically
efficient by about 10 or 15
people see the blues and the uvs and the
far reds and these extra diodes and
think they add something all i see is
waste i see
money being put into stuff which is just
marketing trinkets and if you want more
growth get more power
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this is episode number 33. in
this episode i interview shane from
micro led he is a lighting expert and he
owns micro led grow light company many
of you know him from his youtube channel
where he does grow light testing and
reviews he'll talk a little bit about
the grow light testing that he does and
we'll also get into other lighting
topics such as measuring par
light spectrum in significant detail and
the future of grow lights thanks to all
of you who support this podcast or
patreon if you'd like to support you
could do so by going to patreon.com mr
growit before we get into it i want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of this
podcast to help make that goal possible
a big supporter of this podcast is
spider farmer they sponsor this podcast
and i use their led grow lights spider
farmer now has a bar style series of led
grow lights they have the se 3000 a four
bar fixture for a three foot by three
foot grow space the se 5000 a six
for a four foot by four foot grow space
and the sc7000 a six bar fixture for a
five foot by five foot grow space i will
leave a link to spider farmer down in
the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow at 5
during checkout for discount on their
products ac infiniti they sponsor this
podcast and i use their products ac
infinity now has gardening tools and
accessories such as heavy duty fabric
grill pots
trimmers grow room glasses drying racks
plant ties and trellis nuts
they also have all of the equipment
needed for a ventilation system
i will leave a link to ac infiniti down
in the description section below and you
can use discount code mr growit during
checkout for a discount on their
products big shout out to dutch pro for
sponsoring this podcast dutch pro is a
plant fertilizer company that has been
around for over 30 years they have base
nutrients and they also have additives
such as pk boosters root stimulators
calmag silica a nutrient optimizer and a
foiler feed they also have ph regulators
to help ensure that the nutrients can be
uptaken properly i will leave a link to
dutch pros amazon store down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mrgrow10dp
for a discount on their products
okay we are back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
shane from my grill how you doing today
chris i'm doing very well thank you and
i'm really delighted to be on your show
thanks for joining me we're going to
dive deep into lighting today
particularly lighting for plants so i
actually already did a lighting in a
past podcast episode it was called
things to look for when buying an led
grow light it was really an led grow
light buyer's guide it was more of a
beginner friendly conversation that was
episode 18 with austin from chill tech
if any of you want to check it out i'll
actually have that in the outro card of
this video if you're watching on youtube
but this conversation's gonna be more
intermediate knowledge i'd say we're
gonna get into grow like testing we'll
talk about measuring par
we'll talk about light spectrum so we'll
go over the different colors on the
spectrum and how they impact plant
growth and then lastly the future of led
growth lights so before we get into the
nitty gritty of things can you tell us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into lighting
yeah i've been have been
into growing for a long time so
horticultural background horticultural
parents
wife is into horticulture
and i'm an engineer manufacturing
engineer
so i was um i finished up with my
previous job i was working corporate
finished up and
wanted to look into doing something
myself and i sort of put two and two
together and came up with micro
so micro
we manufacture um
and sell our own range of grow lights
but we
as well of course we have the micro
youtube channel and instagram page
and uh yeah i've been running that for
about the last five years and you
currently have you're coming up on 70
000 subscribers on your youtube channel
so congrats to all your success there
that's not easy to do and on your
youtube channel you do a lot of grow
like testing can you talk to us about
the grow like testing you do and how you
measure grow light performance
yeah absolutely yes i originally started
doing grow light testing basically to
sell my own lights and it was to to
demonstrate the value of buying high
efficiency lights over
what a lot of the sort of
cheaper um
models were around at the time
particularly blurple lights this is
about four or five years ago
and kind of came up with a when i came
up with sort of refined i suppose
a method of testing which was um
getting the grow light in question
optimizing it for in terms of the area
that it's suited for optimizing in terms
of hanging height
simulating a grow tent environment so
silver molar walls
and then using what's called a quantum
sensor or a power sensor
to measure
that across a grid hopefully you guys
will be now aware of power maps
basically a chart showing the
power intensity or the light intensity
all across the um the
sort of test area which represents the
plant canopy the leaf canopy
and yeah it became very popular
people really got um
got into
seeing um you know how their life
performed how some lights perform
against other lights
and i guess sort of demystifying as well
some of the
confusion and the misconceptions around
grow lighting so a couple of
measurements that you highlighted seems
are micro moles per watt and then also
the average par over the footprint so
why are those measurements kind of the
most important in your opinion
so
a grow light um
so if you take for example a hid bulb as
a starting point so hps bulb
hps bulbs fire out
light or photons in all directions
and you have to then use reflectors and
reflective walls in order to direct that
all that light back down onto the plant
canopy and often there are
um losses involved in that so if the
reflector isn't good quality reflector
and if the the
hanging height isn't optimized
all these sort of things feed into how
many la how much loss you have typically
with a hid reflector you've had anywhere
between about 15 and 25 losses
and so
it's not just about the amount of light
that's coming out of the fixture itself
this just pertains to led as well but
really it's about the system efficiency
so as i said when you have it in the
correct grow light environment so the
right size uh grow grow area with
reflective walls at the optimized height
what's the best system efficiency so
getting that how much power you're
getting down onto the plant canopy
and so that's what i measure
and then simply that's the so that's the
power output
kind of called it i've become to call it
usable ppf
or usable power um in the last couple
years
and so it's how much usable power or
power is reaching your plant canopy and
then you if you divide that by the power
consumed you get the efficiency of the
system
so it's the amount of output delivered
to your plants
divided by the cost input in terms of
energy
and that gives you um it's not
exactly the correct term to say micro
moles per watt it should really be micro
moles per joule joule of energy but it's
a bit simpler
and easier to understand to say micro
moles per
per um per watt
and again it's it's uh i found that
people really like having that simple
reference point in the same way that if
you're going to buy a car
you'd want to get information on
what the fuel economy is so how many
miles per gallon
and even performance wise you know uh
not to 60s and that sort of thing so
it's just a simple reference point where
you can compare
different technologies different types
of grow lights
and have a benchmark and to compare them
to
okay that makes sense
this next question is very subjective so
i'll say in your opinion
what are some things that people should
look for when buying an led grill light
so
the simplest thing is the size of your
grow area
so
um you need to provide sufficient
quantity of light to get um good growth
and
that's a function of obviously the
length
by the width so the the surface area
that you're trying to light
but also as i said as a function of the
system so the
using reflective walls and having the
right reflectors are the right hanging
height so generally i recommend starting
off at 500 micro moles per meter square
per second
that's just a power intensity which will
deliver
good level of performance in terms of
the grow area
but that can rise all the way up to sort
of eight nine hundred micro moles
average power
and you will literally get uh you know
if you go from 500 up to 900 you will
get sort of 40 45 more growth it's
linear so the the return on um your
light intensity is linear up to about a
thousand micromoles
beyond then we recommend you can use
those higher intensities
but you'll generally get plant stress
unless you're supplementing the
environment with elevated co2 or are
supplementing with co2 and elevating the
co2 levels in the grow area
there are lower levels i would recommend
for seedlings so around 200 to 250.
so once you've established
um you know are do you want to really
uh do you want to just have sort of a
reasonable level of performance out of
the grow area which would be 500
micromoles or a high performance level
which would be 800 or 900 micromoles
make that decision again usually i would
recommend
learners or beginners would start at 500
because you've got to really have your
um all your other aspects of your grow
your environment the nutrients the
medium
everything else um on point to really
take advantage of those higher um light
levels
so you've established that and then
you're trying to find a fixture which
will deliver at that level in the grow
area size that you have
most manufacturers now these days um
publish power maps so they'll show the
power intensity over the designed and
grow area and they should give you the
average micro moles over the grow area
too
next step really is about
efficiency and cost
and
like most things in life you know you
can get what you pay for you can pay for
an entry light these days
so
and and by the way the entry lights
generally these days are very good um
and they will be about
in in efficiency terms about two
micromoles per watt in terms of
efficiency
and you would pay
somewhere in the region of maybe
a dollar 20 per watt so you want to get
100 watt light for 2x2 it'll cost you
about 120 130
and then you can go higher performance
than that
with than you know maybe 2.4 micromoles
per watt some 20 more efficiency 2.5
even but you will pay
you could pay 50 more per watt so maybe
up to 1.82 dollars a watt for that you
do get a return over time
and you get other benefits like lower
heat and put into your tent
but you know that's the sort of range
that you'd be operating in
and the last one is spectrum
and i know we're going to talk a lot
about spectrum later but
in general terms most grow lights that
i've seen
and tested and around the market these
days have a spectrum which is totally
suitable for growing um all the way from
seed to harvest you don't need to be
changing grow lights you don't need to
be tweaking or anything like that the um
the spectrums are particularly concerned
about it generally white led lights will
grow um
all plant types
perfectly well all with good development
good shape good structure all the way
through
um so yeah your your
size
work out your area
know your area then find lights that are
designed and suited for that area
then look at the power intensity that
they're designed for
and decide where you want to be on that
range and then really it's you'll find a
range of lights
and usually
there'll be a price range in in in line
with performance for those lights
so one of the things you actually didn't
mention which it could be a little bit
surprising for so many people watching
this is you didn't talk about diodes or
drivers right i think that's one thing
that people look at the first thing oh
does it have samsung diodes does it have
an email driver right but you're saying
you know efficiency is kind of more
important in your opinion well
efficiency and
is related to quality
so
the drivers
higher efficiency driver so most
electronics burn out because of heat
and
um if you're running leds very hard so
running them at a very high wattage per
led so driving them hard using a low
amount of leds to get a high quantity of
light
and they will run hot but they will also
run less efficiently
and similarly with the transformers or
the led drivers if they're of low
quality they'll be also generally at low
efficiency
and higher quality is is achieved with
um better quality components internally
that are more accurate and and they
often have additional sort of circuitry
in the drivers to to
elevate
the performance of the drivers so the
driver and the leds combined
will deliver
a high quality driving leds combined
will deliver a high efficiency
and vice versa
and in terms of the leds themselves
there is an obsession with samsung and
they do tend to
be at the forefront in terms of
efficiency
but the difference between
samsung the most expensive and by the
way you'll pay for that
as i'm saying earlier you'll pay for it
significantly
um and um
your your you know your your samsungs
your soul uh semiconductors which i use
uh your asrams um
philips bridge looks all of these
manufacturers make great ships
um they're high volume high quality long
established manufacturers
and the quality of their components and
the longevity of their components will
be
in line with samsung's just as good
so there is an obsession and i think
it's it's borne out of people getting
burnt
excused upon by by by poor
specifications and poor technology in
the past
um but um
like those days are largely gone
and i still hear reports from people on
some of the lights they've tested that
you know they had some issues with for
example driver burnout and that kind of
thing
and but i have to say those the number
of complaints or the the amount of
feedback i've got on and that in the
last couple of years has reduced
significantly that makes sense yeah i've
seen less reports as well as far as burn
out of leds those are somewhat over i
guess you can see right
yeah
let's flip it up and let's talk about
measuring par i have the apogee mq 500
par meter that measures from 400 to 700
nanometers i also have the mq620 which
is the extended range one it measures
from 340 nanometers to 1040 nanometers
now you've recently found a par meter
that's a bit cheaper than the let's call
it industry standard apogee meters right
and they're just as accurate can you
talk to us about that
yeah so i was quite surprised myself
because i had looked in the past at
getting an affordable uh quantum sensors
and and getting um alternative ones to
the ones i've been using so i've been
using the apogee myself for about five
years and i would think it's the it's
pretty much the benchmark of people
using it in the industry
and this measures power itself it
doesn't actually read spectrum it
doesn't tell you what the spectrum looks
like that's slightly different to
spectroradiometer
but the the quantum sensor power sensors
are designed
to capture and count
um photons between 400 nanometers and
700 nanometers
which is basically from a deep blue up
to the far red
just to that point
and that's the power measurement
and good ones will measure
the the all the photons and all the
wavelengths in that power range
accurately so it'll count um blue
photons as accurately and red photons
accurately there are other sensors
around there which are sort of
anything you see that's going to be sub
say
hundred dollars and is likely to be a
modified look sensor light meter
uh which is
they're designed more for the visible
um
readings or readings of looks and lumens
and not totally suitable for power so
they'll give you slight errors
particularly in the the
deep blue and the far red areas
and i did find um
so i got a recommendation actually from
a viewer on one of my videos how i
checked out this other sensor
um i had a look at it it was
significantly cheaper so the apogee sq
520 um the power sensor i think with the
con the um display and the reading
meter is about
530 dollars in thereabouts
and this spot on um
power sensor was is 300
so i was a little bit skeptical i
thought it might be sort of a jumped up
looks meter
but i got a whole got in contact with
them
got a hold of when they sent me one over
for test and i started testing
in parallel with the two sensors so
doing my normal tests with the apogee
and this um spot-on sensor beside each
other and i found it to be
you know to a level of
similarity where you know i'm not sure
which one is more accurate by the way um
but they're both within
in any of the readings or series of
readings i took within a couple of
percent of each other
so i was really impressed with it i
thought just from a
you know a community and an industry
point of view
um it's a bit of a breakthrough for me
really because a lot of people
basically you know watch my channel
really because they can't afford a
quantum sensor to uh
to to find out the information that i'm
going to tell them so it's ring i think
it's great that the cost of these things
are coming down and it's becoming more
accessible for the average grower to um
to do the things that i would do so to
assess
and optimize their grow lighting setup
yeah i was just about to say that same
thing it's gla it's about time that
these prices have come down on par
meters because it is out of so many
people's reach you know 500 that's not a
lot of money for a lot of people you
know yeah it's expensive so it's good
that they're now at least one cheaper
option that's just as accurate as the
apogee meters
yeah there is another one chris which i
know we're going on to anyway but i did
publish um
some so i did some testing of lux meter
accuracy with different um
a different spectrum
and you can get pretty close accuracy or
at least consistency in the measurements
using a lux meter and then basically
apply and these lux meters you can get
anywhere from
get from anywhere from fifteen dollars
maybe up to about thirty forty dollars
so much much cheaper
and what i found was that i i did
readings under different spectrum from
about 150 micromoles up to about 1100
micromoles which is is about the full
range that you need to be able to read
at
and i found them to be linear so
using them under for say for example i
don't know you could have a mars hydro
sf 2000 or you could have a
viper spectra or you could have a
chilled or whatever light you have
generally these things will read
consistently
now you're reading you're still reading
a looks measurement so it's not power
that would we would want to have
but on on my channel um i've done a few
videos where given conversion
measurements for typical grow light
spectrum
but the most important thing is that
it's linear and this means that you can
map out your grow area you can find out
the relative intensity so are there hot
spots
are there cool spots
and you can also
do your own power maps
and then optimize your own setup so
repeat the testing of your power map in
your own area with your own light setup
at different hanging heights for example
and find out which one gives you the
best
balance between getting the most light
down onto your grow area and the most
even spread across your grow area at the
same time and you can do that for
twenty dollars
okay yeah that's great information
another cheap alternative is you can
actually there are now phone apps you
can download a phone app and measure par
just using your phone
but some of these are some of these apps
are more accurate than others and you
did a whole video on that as well can
you talk to us about your findings there
yeah so
there's a bit of tech behind it in that
i use the photon app
it's not the new name i think it is
anyway they change name i think it's the
photon but um
they had um
they have they they're that's
exclusively available on apple store
for using with apple phones and the
front-facing camera
on apple
they all have the same sensor and the
same processing
uh
software for that sensor hardware and
software for that sensor
so you can get consistent readings on
any iphone with that app
whereas
with um
android you know
whether you have a samsung or some other
version phone
and even within samsung the um the light
sensors are different so it's i didn't
test for every different version of
android phone obviously
so i couldn't um
i couldn't guarantee or say that they
would be accurate for anybody's use
but certainly the photon one i found to
be consistent and useful
and so if you have an iphone definitely
download that and have a go
and then i
um the ppfd app
i'm in contact with the guys that
developed the ppfd app and they actually
have a bluetooth connection
to the to what's called the unity looks
meter
so you're basically using an external
device with your
smartphone and that has some calibration
for different grow light spectrum
so you can you can hack
to
getting at the equivalent of a 300
um
quantum sensor parameter
for i think it's i think the unity
bluetooth version is about again about
twenty dollars twenty-five dollars so
it's it's perfectly possible
and really any information in this
regard is better than none
so mapping out your area having a look
to see
where what the light intensity is at
different points
and then adjusting your hanging height
to optimize that will work with really
any of these devices or these systems
that's awesome so now there's just so
many different ways to kind of go about
measuring par that there wasn't five
years ago you know what i mean
so that's awesome that we're actually at
that point yeah absolutely okay so
people have power measurements another
thing i want to get into is dli now i
don't think i covered this on the
beginner video i did with austin from
chill tech dli daily lighting integral
can you talk to us about that
yeah so um
there's the
intensity at a moment in time which is
your power intensity and that's measured
in micro moles per meter squared per
second
that's the quantity of photons
impacting on a meter
every second
and obviously you've got different
lengths of day then
so what
biologists and horticulturalists are
interested in is
how much
will the plant uptake not just
instantaneously at that moment in time
but over the total day
and so it does vary by species
and so you know if it's a shade loving
plant for example
it's going to have a much lower
requirement um
for light intensity and it's not going
to want to be exposed to high light
intensity for a long period of time but
then you get um plants which are
will take up a lot of um light intensity
so you know anything from fruiting
plants
chilies peppers
tomatoes
corn
and
all the way to medicinal herbs and all
of those will
will utilize high levels of light and
just for reference by the way we were
talking earlier on um about high light
intensity being a thousand micro moles
the sun would be about 2 000 micro moles
midday
so what we're replicating indoors
is is a lower
uh maximum intensity than sunlight at
midday but of course you know the sun
varies throughout the day
and
dli is a measurement of capturing that
light intensity over a whole day and
which you know outside in the sun it
would start off at maybe about four or
five hundred micromoles in the morning
rise up and peak at about 2000 and drop
down to about 500 in the evening before
sunset
that's if it's a cloudless sky if it's a
clear sky
and um if you sum total that up over 12
hour day that equates roughly to about
40 dli
and dli daily light integral integral
means just
adding all of the results together just
combining everything under that graph
and some accumulating it together
and so the recommended maximum dli for
tomatoes for example is 40 40 40 miles
um and
that's just a general guide
you'll have a sort of
semi-shade plants or not as as hungry or
plants that would would be quite happy
with 20 moles per day
and as i said you'd have shade ones that
might only want five
but we look at it because you're trying
to understand as i said for the
um not just the light intensity but but
also looking at the aspect of over the
the light on time that you have how much
lights are the light as the plan are the
plants receiving
gotcha so actually i do have a cheat
sheet here furrows surfer dli low light
plants five to 10 medium light plants 10
to 15 and then highlight plants 15 plus
and there are various sources online
that kind of measure this you can
actually search dli calculator and
there's a number of different sources
that you can go in there you basically
just enter in the ppfd canopy and then
the number of hours that the light is on
then you press the calculate button and
then it'll calculate the dli and some
medicinal varieties i've heard of going
upwards of 65 dli so i thought that was
super interesting it is interesting and
the
interesting development led so it used
to be restricted in terms of indoor
lighting because hid base you would only
get so much light into it into an indoor
area
and before heat would overrun you and
you'd be battling against heat it was
the restrictive uh
measure really to to maximizing the
potential from the space
now that leds are involved in the much
more efficient people are starting to
use much higher light levels so 500
micromoles was high performance five six
years ago with hid as i said it's now
risen up to a thousand which means you
can
basically double the yield from the same
space and all of the things um you know
being in line so yeah it's it's
impressive that uh improvement is
technology has had a real benefit that's
one of the reasons why you can jump you
know when you're in the vegetation stage
for example i know i think you mentioned
like 500 ppfd and then you switch that
light cycle
instead of doing 18 hours a day now
you're down to 12 hours a day so you're
increasing the par number up to you know
900 is a rough number up to a thousand
as some people say but you do the dli
and it actually makes sense you use that
dll calculator it makes sense because
you're dropping the number of light
hours per day but you're increasing the
par so
exactly
let's get into light spectrum next i
wanted to start with green light because
a lot of misinformation when it comes to
green light but
i do want to kind of start from the
beginning of the electromagnetic
spectrum let's start with uv so there's
uva uvb and uvc can you talk to us about
uv light yeah so uv and the lower down
the spectrum we go the higher energy the
light photons are
and so
uv uvc would be the lowest um wavelength
of ultraviolet but it's got high energy
photons that's why they're damaging and
can cause cancer
fortunately you don't get uvc through
from the sun because it's it's filtered
out by the atmosphere
and similarly
with hid and leds you don't get um
you don't get uvc so we don't have to be
concerned about it and that's good
because it would damage us and damage
the plants
and uvb
is similar in that it's still high
energy photons but
not as damaging they're not
as cancer-causing um and
basically damaging cells as ubc would be
however they do some damage as we know
because we get sunburned
um it is it does there is a response you
can get from plants by using uvb in a
measured way
so you can stimulate
increases in oil production
and by using uvb
um
gardeners will know this if you've ever
grown rosemary outdoors and grown it
indoors under glass
outdoors you'll get a nice sticky resin
on the leaves
and you can feel it you can smell it
it's much richer in terms of its perfume
and its flavor where it's grown under
glass it'll be
it'll still be green you'll get as much
growth physical growth but it won't have
that stickiness and that resinous and
it's just the same with medicinal herbs
and lots of other plants where you're
looking for um oil production um for
higher quality
there's a few studies out there
and it's again it's it's one of those um
sort of frontier uh parts of of indoor
growing where people are learning and
developing and understanding
but in essence you can increase oil
production which is the terpenes and the
flavonoids so you can get better smell
you can't get higher potency with
additional herbs
and but you get a better quality in
terms of um
flavor and smell
um so that's used in short bursts
uh you don't want to use it all the way
through the grow because
basically it's it's um
it's
signaling the plant to divert its energy
from
growing in terms of of putting on mass
to
generating oils
and for that reason we only recommend
using it in the last two or three weeks
of flour um so once the plant has put on
most of its weight and its bulk
and we're trying then we're only using
it a couple of hours a day
uh in the middle of the light cycle
to again to trigger this response in the
plant to generate oil
and that oil is basically too it has
more uses than just you know to smell
the smell and
to taste better those oils also protect
the plant so it's like a natural
response to the plant to protect itself
against these uvb photons which could
potentially damage it
so that's uvb
we don't have uva which
um from a
photosynthetic point of view it's uh
and
from a development point of view it's
very like blue in that it has a an
effect on growth
and however it's not as
photosynthetically efficient so uva
photons
if you had 100 uva photons for example
and 100 blue
photons
the uva photons would only view then 20
percent as effective as the blue photons
so
they're not particularly useful
and they are
included in grow light spectrum
um
but they're costly to produce they don't
last very long and as i said they're no
different from a
plant development or growth point of
view than adding blue photons the the
plant responds to saying whether they're
blue or or uva
and that response is to shorten the um
basically smaller cell expansion which
means smaller cells which means shorter
denser plants and shorter denser leaves
but generally i wouldn't
recommend
to spend money or resources on uva in a
grow light system
okay that's really good information and
uvc goes from 100 to 280 nanometers uvb
280 to 315 nanometers and then uva 315
to 400 nanometers so lots of good
information about uv there next up is a
400 to 500 nanometers which blue light
falls into there and you kind of touched
on one of the effects of blue light
which is the shorter internodal spacing
and inhibits cell division do you talk
to us about blue light
yeah so blue light is photosynthetically
efficient
so it um it does it grows the plants
effectively it's about eighty percent
efficient
um it uh it has it it stimulates again a
response in the plant so
if you have less for example less than
about three or four percent blue you
will get very stretched out plants and
this is what growers used to experience
with high pressure sodium which is
certainly less usually about three
percent but certainly less than four
percent blue
and so the plant again it um responds
to the proportion of brule blue light
and it
will grow shorter as you said
international distances so the distance
between the branches
but all aspects of the plant will be
shorter and more compact and dense so
all of the stalks all of the leaves
will be slightly shorter and more dense
the more blue light you have in the
spectrum up to about 25 percent after
which
um you um
there's no difference
but
uh in in terms of the balance if you
look at again most white light so even a
color temperature so very warm
um
white light will have the minimum of
about five six percent blue
3000k up to about 5000k the percentage
blue will range from about 12 up to
about 23
so any of the
white lights that you get quite led
lights that manufacturers are producing
most of them will have sufficient blue
in the spectrum
to deliver short dense growth which is
what we want indoors we want the plants
to be short and compact
and because we're height limited and we
want the plants to
put on as much bulk as possible without
wasting energy basically growing at all
and unfortunately
most grow light listings they're not
going to tell you what the percent blue
is unfortunately you only see that from
an integrated sphere report now if your
manufacturer is cool and they are
transparent they will provide you that
information so you can certainly reach
out to your manufacturer ask them for
that report and then it will list the
different percentages of colors that
that grow light emits so
next up is a 500 to 600 nanometers green
light falls into that and i don't think
a lot of people know that green light is
actually used by the plant or absorbed
by the plant there's been a lot of
misinformation that says that green
light isn't used at all by the plant and
you've got those headlamps with the
green light that's emitted because it's
not supposed to impact the planet at all
but that's not actually the case can you
talk to us about green light
yeah so i'll debunk first of all
and so
in the early days of leds grow lights
people didn't have efficient white leds
they only had relatively efficient blue
and red leds so that's all they used in
grow lights and in order to sell them
they
took
data some sort of
scientific reports and studies and took
them out of context and used them as a
marketing tool to say
that we we are using blue and red in our
leds and they're more efficient than in
other lights for example like hps
because plants only absorb blue and red
light and they don't absorb green so all
the green light out of the hps is wasted
and because of that
basically you can you can use a much
smaller wattage led light than hid
which was total bs
and it was based on as i said
taking
scientific studies and reports and
criteria and using them totally out of
context
next piece that sort of confuses people
is that plants are generally green
and it stands you know it's common sense
that something that's green is
reflecting green light
and that is true it does reflect some of
the green light
um but it also uh green light tends to
penetrate deeper into the leaf
and also will bounce around within the
um within the canopy so
it um
it is is very useful as part of the
overall grow light recipe to have in
there because it'll get down into the
leaf and photosynthesize parts of the
leaf that other the blue and red for
example won't um photosynthesize
and also down into lower parts of the
plant which won't vince photosynthesize
i wouldn't photosynthesize otherwise
next part to it is um the green lamp
that people use for inspecting their
plants
green light tends to be the per
for the amount of photons output is the
highest response visually so we
if you took again 100 photons of blue
100 photons of green 100 photons of red
we would see much better under those
hundred photons of green light it gives
us our eyes are much more responsive to
uh to green light than other spectrum so
if you are going to use a light
in an environment it is better to use a
green light because you can use less of
it than a white light or a red light or
a blue light just to see
so again it's sort of
uh putting two and two together and
getting four to say that using a green
green light doesn't affect the plants it
will if you use enough of it but you're
able to use a very small amount of it to
see and therefore it's the best one to
use if you have to do it
and lastly
the experiments that were done in um so
mccree mccree curve maybe people have
seen
it's experiments that were done in the
70s which looked at the plant growth
rate
under
discrete
wavelengths of light so they took maybe
a five nanometer
um bandwidth of blue light they shot it
at a plant
it's actually algae in the solution and
they looked at the amount of oxygen it
produced so how much uh photosynthesis
was occurring and they looked at that
discretely
all the way up through the spectrum
to
see how responsive plants were to
different
discrete
wavelengths of light
that's not what happens in reality in
reality we don't mush a plan to put it
into a dish and shine beams of of of
narrow wavelength beams of light
the plant is in an environment where
there's all different wavelengths of
light all interacting with the plant in
a different way
and in in those studies it's shown that
green light
is just as effective as blue light
and but there still is a higher level of
photosynthetic efficiency with red
photons
and so green green is
the last thing about grain is that if
you have only blue and red you get a
purple light and purple light doesn't
reflect any light off the leaves and the
leaves look black and you can't see your
plants properly so having green light in
with blue and red means you get white
and white light means you can see your
plants more clearly
and
there's a proverb which is escaping me
now but
about gardening and it basically says
you know if you can't see what you're
doing you're not going to make mistakes
and so having a clear white light
and
where you can see um
you know where there might be nutrient
deficiencies you can see where there
might be some
burning okay occurring
um
you know disease any of those things
kind of things you can see much more
clearly under white light so for all
those reasons
green light is a very useful
part of the grow lighting recipe
that's super interesting yeah a lot of
misinformation about green light i'm
glad that more and more information more
and more people are talking about how
green light is useful to the plant so
let's talk about red light that's next
600 to 700 nanometers i think 660
nanometers kind of a highlight here a
lot of people talk about 616 nanometers
and then we get into far red as well 700
to 750 nanometers 730 nanometers is
talked about pretty often you talk to us
about red light and far red
yeah so red light is
useful in two ways
the
in the
is it's at the opposite end of the
spectrum of uv
and therefore
it's higher wavelength
and lower energy photons
so electrically they're cheaper to
produce because they're individually
they're lower energy
so you could per per watt you can
produce more
red photons than you can blue or uv
photons for example so they're
electrically efficient to produce
but also the plant is most responsive to
red photons so
compared to to blue and green
um red photons will are more
photosynthetically efficient by about 10
or 15
so having as much red as possible in
that mix
will deliver the highest electrical
and
and also photosynthetic efficiency
they don't have
a
an effect on the plant development so
it's like a thinner color it's like a
you know
your carbs in your dinner or whatever
you know it's it's not adding flavor
anything but it's adding bulk and it's
adding energy
it's not going to affect the way the
plant grows
and so the common misconception again
that
if a light doesn't have you know the
little red diodes in it that it's not
suitable for flowering that's not true
and they don't it doesn't make the plant
flower or enhance the flowering or
anything like that and what it does is
basically it boosts the electrical and
the photosynthetic efficiency of the
spectrum overall
so those little red diodes are generally
much more expensive than white diodes
but they're higher
micro mole per watt efficiency in terms
of output so we put them in there so
often described like a turbo booster so
you got your your main engine which is
the blue and the green and the bulk of
the red coming from the the white leds
and that's providing most of the light
and the spread and then you have these
red diodes which can boost
the electrical and photosynthetic
efficiency of the system overall that's
really good information for sure last
but not least
ir infrared light what do we need to
know about that
yeah we're going to start with fire red
actually so infrared is effectively heat
and it's not photosynthetic so it
doesn't cause plant growth
and infrared is what we'd look at with
that you know an infrared camera where
we'd see basically radiation coming off
the surface
so you can you know get night vision and
all that sort of stuff you can see in
the dark
infrared
is uh is is beyond 750 nanometers
far red is just beyond red it's actually
a very deep red
far red leds at 7 30 nanometers you can
see them
glowing is sort of a very deep red they
don't look bright but you can see you
can definitely see that there's light
coming from them so they're still in the
visible spectrum as well
and they're not as photosynthetically
efficient as red so
again adding far red diodes
if you wanted to get more growth you
would just simply add more white or red
diodes
however there is a belief that um adding
far red will somehow
boost
the other um
spectrum that you have in in the the the
power spectrum and again there's a bit
of a misuse around the the emerson
effect
um and the emerald and in effect the
emerson effect is really
um
a
complementary
uh effect that using different grow
light spectrum will have on the
um the overall rate of photosynthesis
the amount of growth that you'll get
from that lighting system it doesn't
um there is a very small
benefit to adding a small bit of far red
in with red
it'll complement the red and free up a
little bit more of the red photons to be
active so it'll boost the efficiency of
the red but it's literally it's it's i
can't remember the exact figure but
somewhere around
five percent or something and it's only
if you use a small amount of fire red
um
far red is
not like red or green it's it's like
blue in that it has this effect on plant
development as well as growth
and it has the opposite effect of blue
so far red
too much of it will cause plant
stretching it'll cause cell expansion
and plants to stretch
and that's a bit like blue where you
want a minimum of five percent to keep
plants dense
at far red you don't really want more
than five percent or you'll start to see
stretching now you can't balance it off
with blue but then you're into sort of a
war with the blue and the far red
and most leds if you look at their grow
light spectrum charts there'll be a
little tail or little at the end of the
curve will go beyond the 700 nanometers
beyond the red into far red
most led
white leds will
emit about two or three percent far red
anyway
so you don't again in my view um
there's a misconception that adding far
red leds is gonna
give this extraordinary boost to the to
the
uh effectiveness of the rest of the
photons of the other
the red the green and the blue photons
but it's only a very marginal effect and
one that you would get
from
almost every grow light anyway and
adding additional far red
um leds um
is
uh in my view counterproductive in that
you're now in having to add more blue in
order to balance that off so your plants
don't stretch
so if you want more growth more power
just more power keep it in the narrow
straight narrow between the 400 and the
and
in particular
in the red area because as i said that's
that's more electrically in
photosynthetically efficient
yeah i heard i also heard no more than
five percent for the far red and
one other effect particularly on
medicinal varieties is foxtailing so
i've had grow lights before that had
more than that five percent and towards
the end of flowering it's just there's
just fox town everywhere so it impacts
bud development in that avenue as well
so yeah yeah so it's it's again there's
a lot of marketing around grow light
spectrum and
the way i often describe it is you know
when you buy a stereo
for us for us of a certain vintage we'll
remember in the 90s there was this craze
with you know all these graphic
equalizers and lights
and buttons and sliders and all this
sort of thing none of which made the
sound any better
and in fact if anything they were taking
money away from putting in good quality
components into having flashing lights
and dials and indicators that didn't add
to the sound
and it's a bit like that with grow
lights as far as i'm concerned people
see the blues and you sorry the uvs and
the far reds and these extra diodes and
think they add something all i see is
waste i see
money being put into stuff which is just
marketing trinkets
and if you want more growth get more
power which is just
you know per watt getting higher
efficiency grow lights or having more
wattage simple as that
um most modern
there i haven't seen the ground light i
haven't tested the grow light
and i've tested maybe 100 grow lights in
the last
two years two or three years i haven't
seen one
whose uh
spectrum wasn't suitable for growing
so
there's a lot of search for sort of
little gains here and there with that
with spectrum or sort of magic secret
sauce and generally there isn't any and
as i said use a white light and use
enough of it distribute the light evenly
and
you'll get you'll you'll optimize your
your potential yield i remember going to
mj biz con a couple years ago for those
that don't know it's an expo and every
company is there basically every
company's there they show off their
newest products and this lighting
company stopped by their booth and i
forget the name of the grow light but
they had it so you could adjust the
spectrum and it was like super
customizable and i think it was like a
four thousand dollar grow light i walked
by there and just raised my eyebrow i'm
like really like four thousand dollars
to it just it made no sense and like you
said it's marketing is involved in that
as well
what i would say is if you're
if you're growing a very specific um
it could be a bedding plant
or it could be a herb
and you're a mass producer and you're
you know you're generating thousands you
know you've acres of of space
what you might do
is you might refine a spectrum
to for example
so tweaks in the red and tweaks in the
far red can affect for example the time
that
you know your petunias flower at
and you can trigger particular responses
in plants
and in order to make them flower in
order to make them more leafy so what i
said about far red
but again there's a misconception out
there because there's some videos out
there people showing that far red can
produce a higher yield but it's of
lettuce
and lettuce you're looking just to get
leaf you just want lots and lots of leaf
and you wanted to produce as much leaf
as possible so far red in that instance
is basically making them stretch a
little bit
and generating more leaf which is what
you want
also you could be using
a little bit higher blue will bring out
oh i gotta pronounce it properly
anthrocynons anyway did the sort of
purple
pigments in plants
so if you're producing a red lettuce for
example or a purple lettuce indoors
under green under um artificial lighting
you might want to
tweak
the light spectrum to bring out certain
characteristics of that plant
and but in general if you're a home
grower
in particular
it's a bit like um
you know
your setting will never be perfect for
the different stages of growth what you
want is something that hits the middle
for the whole
uh grow
um and in that sense
having
as i said anywhere between five and
fifteen percent blue
about thirty percent grain about forty
percent red is your optimum spectrum
and
the benefits of moving away from that so
putting money into having dials to
adjust spectrum and different drivers
and different channels and all that sort
of stuff
in my view you'd be far more better off
just having more light and a more
efficient light
and you're going to get more you're
certain to get more yield that way
rather than being uncertainly twiddling
around with things
trying to get an effect which will be
different based on different strains and
varieties of plants
so you know whether it's indica dominant
or sativa dominant for example with
medicinal herbs you could have
a different response from different
plants under the under different
lighting conditions so just stay in the
middle
don't make something more complicated
than it should be
just get as much light down there as
your plants can
can
absorb get it down evenly
and you know if you want to tweak and
twiddle start looking at medium or
you know nutrients or something else
because
if you've optimized your lighting
spectrum with with a modern grow light
which is white there really is is is not
much other places to go
well said so like you mentioned just a
few minutes ago you've tested over 100
grow lights
we got to know what are some of the best
grow lights on the market today that
you've tested well i put it into
different categories really because
there are some lights which are just
really really good value and
extraordinary quality for how cheap they
are
and there are others which are
multiple of times as expensive per what
to buy
but are extraordinary because they have
really good efficiency and really high
quality in terms of their build
i would say in the budget category
i reviewed some that have been
exceptionally good from a build quantity
a quilt build
quality point of view
so your your ton of amazony type lights
around a dollar a what
generally they tend to be a little bit
tinny and flimsy in at parts but uh one
that stood out for me was maxi sun
really high quality build
it's that sort of build quality where
you just when you have it in your hand
it's nothing in particular it's all the
little details it's everything is
finished off really well so they have
that sort of um baking tin type
reflector that mars hydro used and a few
other manufacturers use but it's a
little bit more solid and it's a little
bit more robust
than maybe the mars hydro one
and speaking of mars hydro there
what's the name of it again the
long-form one
sp 3000
sp
the sp series it's been added by two
years they've revised that this year
it's really good quality
and so again in the lower price category
that's that's a good one
in the medium price range
i'm going to plug my own so microarray
and i try to strike that balance between
being
good quality as well as good performance
and decent price so it's you know that
that
a a good balance of all those
um you get up into the higher
performance range a higher price range
more commercial type fixtures
um
in terms of the um
you know the uh the cost in particular
and i would say lumatec
uh also known as photon tech in the us
are an excellent brand i've i've i used
to use them
i've been using them for 15 years you
know my first digital ballast i bought
was lumatec
and i've never heard anything other than
good things about them their build
quality is excellent the performance is
excellent bit of a premium for it but
it's worthwhile
uh
gavita
love their led light but again it's you
know
you probably would be in the commercial
space if you're going to be paying that
much for them because they're quite
expensive in terms of cost per dollar
um
but yeah i've reviewed
hundreds of them
uh i don't review all the grow lights i
get offered or asked to review
so
anyone that i do has sort of passed the
basic test but i've taken it out of the
box it hasn't fallen apart in my hands
the build quality is good the
performance is decent
the
in particular kind of particular about
the information they provide as well so
check to see are they making reasonable
are their specifications reasonable
um and like i would reject
i'd probably reject like two to one so
i'd probably reject two grow lights for
every one i test
and on the basis that there's an awful
lot of
um spurious sort of
you know uh
yeah just missing on a few of the main
points in terms of build quality and in
particular the marketing information or
the specifications
um
you know i had one the other day and i
looked okay on the website i got it
delivered it was a chinese manufacturer
which by the way is not a
derogatory term i use i use it sometimes
and people think that i'm using that as
a derogatory term it's not
um
you know
my drivers are made in hong kong my my
led boards are assembled in china and
shipped here you know pretty much every
grow light is made in china these days
so it's not a i'm not separating out
chinese as a drugs return but anyway
they were marketed and sold directly by
themselves they sent me the light i took
it out of the box and immediately
um the central beam which had the
drivers in it was just rattling around
and
so i opened up the cover and
it was you could just the build quality
that the
extrusions were really thin and really
tinny
and um
the drivers weren't fixed down properly
and when i opened it up it was just like
a rat's nest of wiring and
you know
anyway i i called them up luigi and just
said look i'm going to throw it on the
bin or you can collect this i'm not
testing this so
um there is still
quite a lot of junk out there so i would
recommend if you're going to buy a grow
light do have a look at the channel
because it's a it's at least a minimum
level
of guarantee that the build quality is
up to a comparable standard or a good
standard for the industry
and then as i said
you'll see from the performance
whether the components are of a good
quality or not high performance means
they've had to use
good quality
components
medium you know it's probably price
related they're probably um trading off
with with cost and price
and uh low efficiency
you know i may not be you know i'm not
saying it directly to camera but you can
usually tell if you watch me closely
that i'm sort of
yeah this could be better you know
i'll be subtly hinting that there's
better things on the market than this
one even though it might be adequate in
other ways you know yeah you're very
transparent when it comes and very
honest when it comes to your girl light
reviews and you don't review any bad
grow lights but just for clarification
you used to years ago and used to be
very brutally honest and it was actually
kind of funny i'm looking at one of your
titles right now totally pointless grow
light i love it
but there were some sort of novelty uh
grow lights that um because people would
would send me emails saying you know
so for example i bought some of these i
know if you've seen them when i was
under the the home garden lights and
they have a they have a stand and they
have these flexible arms with these
little led bars on the top yeah they're
still purple and you're supposed to
position them over your house plants so
you know people have offered me them and
i've actually gathered together about
five or six of them
to do like you know when i have a couple
of days where i just want to have a bit
of fun to reduce i'm going to test those
and see what they do because i'm pretty
sure they're going to be atrocious but
um
yeah i i
i don't want i i like to keep things
not non-contentious but
i basically don't want to be rubbishing
anybody else's products i don't want to
be having a negative effect on another
company unnecessarily
um so um i just don't like that five i
don't like you know the sort of
comments that come with it and all that
stuff so i'll be gracious i hope um when
a really good light that's much better
than mine is there
um and uh you know i'll just be quiet
and hold my peace when um when there's
some junk or you know i'll give a subtle
indication that i'm you know not very
impressed with the particular fixture
lady technology has come so far in such
a short period of time i mean you
mentioned mars hydro having a good light
you say that you know back in 2015 2016
people will laugh at you they had hot
garbage lights back then but they've
really turned their things around and
their lights have gotten a lot better
and they're up there with the best
nowadays
now my question is with lighting
technology moving so rapidly
what do you see what innovations do you
see happening with lighting technology
in the upcoming five years
getting cheaper
is the big thing so
and it's the same with the you know
domestic lighting
all forms of lighting
the um
so
in terms of failure and problems with
led lights
um biggest issue up to the last few
years was actually the power supplies
for the led drivers they were the thing
most likely to fail out of a lighting
system and most of that was just cheap
cheaply made
low efficiency
drivers
and they would generate a lot of heat
and
there's uh components called capacitors
in them and they're a little bit like a
battery but they've got a gel in them
and they literally dry out and pop when
uh when heating too much and that's you
know you get the flickering of an led
light like a home light or whatever
starts to flicker that's or you see it
in in vehicle lights as well that's
often because the driver has blown um
not necessarily the leds or starting to
go
and
with the leds themselves the technology
so
if you look beneath that
phosphorus the yellow coating on top of
the leds down into what's underneath
and the basic technology has not changed
in the last 10 years
in terms of white leds so they're
basically a blue led underneath that
white phosphorous coating and that white
phosphorus diffracts or breaks up that
blue light into other colors so into
green or red and the more phosphorus we
use the more
um
warm the color will go so the more red
it'll produce and vice versa
and but that technology hasn't changed
very much what has happened is is we've
got it's got cheaper so people are using
more leds compared to before
and because they're using more of them
they're per watt because they're using
more of them they're running them at
lower currents lower wattage
and because of that
at lower wattage they run more
efficiently but they also run cooler and
they're less likely to
to to burn out
and within the leds there's tiny little
gold wires attached onto the wafers
and if they overheat those gold wires
melt or detach from the wafers and
that's when leds blow basically
or burn out um
so
it's between the driver technology
getting better up to about 95 is pretty
standard now they're not that's not
going to improve very much the basic led
technology has there isn't a new
technology out
in the last 10 years so they're all just
refining and tweaking and twiddling and
improving the overall system efficiency
by using more leds with better tolerance
or more accuracy in terms of the
circuitry
and that's delivering slightly higher
efficiencies
and but what is being obtained today
could have been obtained seven or eight
years ago with a very high amount of
cost
or at least close to
and the biggest difference now is cost
so um where
uh you know it wouldn't have been
uncommon for a 100 watt so say a little
light for two by two would have been
three hundred dollars for a high
efficiency one
uh and i'm saying high efficiency sort
of two to two point two micromoles per
watt these uh
four or five years ago
you could now get for a hundred dollars
so it was dropped by a third
and i've seen a big reduction just in
the last 12 months
and it's typical of a maturing industry
really
that when people stop you know sort of
innovating and getting new developments
in technology they then all fight each
other for with the same technology for
the same market share and that goes all
the way up and down the supply chain and
everybody tightens their belts and
usually you'll end up with
a smaller number of large manufacturers
who are very efficient
um very
cut their cost
controlled very well
and delivering high volumes and
therefore
able to deliver low prices
we've seen a lot of new entry big
entrance into the market in the last
year or so coming in very aggressively
with low pricing so
i think that's what's going to change i
think the next thing is
as i was saying before about pushing
the limit of where of light levels and
light intensity and yields per square
meter per square foot
and i think um
one of the developments which might
assist that is cheaper and more
accessible
um environment control in terms of co2
supplementation and that type of thing
so
you've already got these sensors you get
a co2 sensor now for 40 or 50 dollars
where
you know i bought one
four years ago and i
bought the cheapest one i could find and
it's 350. you know so
um
sensing technology getting better
like we were talking about earlier
having better control over your lighting
system so getting
getting equipment and technology that
will help you set up better and optimize
your setup better
um
yeah that's where i think things are
going over the next certainly the next
two or three years
awesome well definitely that's exciting
for consumers to have cheaper prices you
know
more more and more affordable for people
definitely yeah so wrapping things up
how can listeners find you and what do
you have upcoming in the future
yeah so uh the youtube channel is micro
migro um
the instagram it's a
microlight so instagram forward slash
microlight
website is www.microlight.com
and
yeah we do
you know interviews with
industry professionals and experts do
the reviews to tips and tricks and how
to's and hacks and
all that sort of stuff so anything grow
lighting really
related so any of the topics we
discussed this evening for example i'll
have either a video or a couple of posts
on it on instagram or a blog on the
website related
and really just refining that and
improving that over time
and so lots more grow light reviews
um just finishing um filming a series on
to grow like sort of up-to-date um
videos on grow light spectrum how to
size your grow light how high to hang
your grow light all those basic things
that people want to know
um i'm just about to release a whole
sort of new version of those
the um as you know yourself from
sort of being a
producer uh that i look back on the ones
that i did three years ago and i cringe
now and i think god
i really got
to get them up up to at least my my
current standard because uh yeah they
were um
they're hard even for me to get through
because i was uh
you know i wasn't as as capable as i am
so
yeah
all right well i will link shane's
youtube channel down in the description
section below on youtube i also link the
website micro led i will link that
website down in the description section
below if you enjoyed this video click
that thumbs up button also drop a
comment down below let me know what you
thought of this talk subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already if you're
listening in on apple podcasts please
leave a rating and review
shane thank you so much for joining us
today and just dropping a ton of
knowledge bombs about lighting i think
you've definitely expanded my knowledge
quite a bit as well as the audience
knowledge so thank you for your time and
i hope you enjoy the rest of your day
it's been a real honor and a pleasure to
be on chris your your um
your channels are a reference point for
me too i've watched a lot of your stuff
learned a lot and so it's a real honor
to be on here
that's really cool to hear
all right take care
thanks
[Music]
you