welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr grew it
and you're too dig to the Garden Talk
podcast this episode number 106. in this
episode I interview Dr MJ Coco many of
you caught the episode I did with him
last week where he talked about growing
in Coco coir while he's back again for
this back-to-back episode Special and
this week he's going to talk all about
LED grow lights another area where his
knowledge goes deep not only does he
talk about LED grow lights versus other
types of lighting but he also gets into
things to look for in an LED grow light
he talks about the girl like calculator
he created talks about some of the best
LED grow lights on the market today here
in 2023 and so much more I do have a
quick announcement that I wanted to
mention before we get into the episode I
have launched a Clips Channel on YouTube
so basically these Garden Talk podcast
episodes will be cut down into smaller
Clips bite-sized chunks and they'll be
on that Clips Channel new clip every
single day so check out that channel
simply search Garden talk Clips I also
have a link in the YouTube description
section below I want to ignore I was one
of my goals for this podcast is to bring
free information about gardening all
plants to the general public that being
said I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to aec Infinity for
sponsoring this episode they have two
different series LED grow lights the ion
board and the ion grid the ion board
fixtures are board style and use Samsung
LM 301b diodes while the ion grid series
has an open Center design and uses
Samsung lm301h diodes I'll have a link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about these grow lights
and the discount code Mr grod15 works on
both Amazon and their website
acinfinity.com
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with Dr
MJ Coco how you doing today I'm doing
great thanks for having me back on the
show yeah back to back episodes first
time we've ever done that on the garden
Talk podcast uh if you guys missed last
week's episode I sat down with Dr MJ
Coco and we talked about growing in
Cocoa a lot of good information and then
you also have a lot of knowledge when it
comes to LEDs that's what I want to get
into in this episode because really
Lighting in general I know we can narrow
down the focus lighting is such a broad
topic right so if we can narrow it down
to LEDs but I'm sure there's going to be
some overlapping with other lighting as
well but uh yeah looking forward to
picking your brain on this one
yeah it's you know understanding light
is something that a lot of farmers take
for granted because you're going
Outdoors Under the Sun
um it's something that I didn't think
about a whole lot until I became
um you know an indoor grower an indoor
growing you know understanding how to
deal with Horticultural lighting and
what we need to understand about it and
um you know how to effectively deploy it
as we were talking in the first episode
we did you know the the cost of running
those lights is just such a huge part of
sort of what we're doing as Growers that
really understanding what light is how
light works what we need how to get it
um can really improve the efficiency in
your grow definitely a key component of
the grow that is for sure so I'm excited
for this one but first can you introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together sure yeah
I'm Dr MJ Coco trying to just you know
share scientifically sound knowledge
about how to grow soilless and Beyond
just getting into growing in Cocoa like
we talked about last time
um you know how to grow effectively how
to understand the various aspects of
that are really sort of scientific
around being an effective indoor you
know doing effective indoor Horticulture
so not just sort of understanding
fertilization
root health you know irrigation those
kinds of issues different grow media
um but like we're talking about now
lighting is such a huge aspect of of
indoor Horticulture so and it's not you
know whether you're growing in in you
know living soil or rock wool or cocoa
or whatever other media
um you know it's applicable to All
Growers to to understand how to
effectively use light so
um
yeah that's my background I have a PhD
in
um Agricultural and economic
anthropology I worked with Farmers from
Central America and southern Mexico
um and really got into studying the the
science of indoor Horticulture
um right after I got back from doing my
dissertation field work and like I told
you last time you know kind of took that
same approach so
um training as a graduate student as a
professor and you know access to to
those materials and sort of that
background in terms of how to approach
this you know one of the things when I
really started getting into the online
growing Community
um was the amount of like bro science uh
the amount of sort of
things that weren't valid that a lot of
Growers believed in and still practice
um you know
more so in in certain online growing
communities than in others but I I
definitely saw the need to just sort of
provide accessible knowledge to Growers
that was scientifically valid
um so that's what I've tried to do and
you know getting into lighting was we're
going to get into today this has been my
my big project for the last several
years and it's something that gets me
excited I'm in the middle of testing
light right now actually so
um and doing that kind of primary
research basically doing my own tests
and understanding how lights work
because I get my hands on a lot of them
has been a really exciting part of of
learning about how lights work it's
exciting to me as well I know it's not
exciting for everybody but it's
certainly exciting for me let's start
off with the basics here I started
growing about 13 years ago and there was
no LEDs there was HPS MH and HBS
and flowering under HPS yes right yeah
exactly and then you know I got my first
led in 2015. and now it seems like
everybody's buying LEDs what was your
first led back in 2015. it was P9 xml2
by Platinum LED old school they're
actually a funny thing is they're still
selling that light today
it's like it was released in 2015 it's
like uh okay outdated but um okay
that whole Horticultural the revolution
that we've seen in the last 10 years in
Horticultural lighting but basically
from you know 2012 to 2022 or so was
just such an exciting and dynamic time
where
the whole industry just kind of flipped
on itself
um
LEDs not only sort of came to the
mainstream but became more efficient
um that was sort of the the first wave
was LEDs became more efficient than the
gas discharge lighting and then the
costs of the LEDs came down right and
that happened in sort of two distinct
movements
um like from 2012 to 2016 the capacity
for LEDs to really perform better than
the gas discharge lights like hit I mean
and it became obvious by the end of that
period that you know LEDs were were
better than than guest discharge lights
um but they were super expensive at that
point to get good ones there was a lot
of crappy ones that started entering the
market but to get good ones they were
really expensive and you know since like
2016 to 2022 that the prices have just
come down as as more and more
manufacturing has come online
um you know as the full spectrum dial in
particular have have found more
mainstream applications and been
manufactured in larger and larger
quantities that the unit prices dropped
significantly and that's allowed you
know all manufacturers to produce lights
that are like
you know even cheap lights these days
that now not all lights but you can
still get you can certainly get some
cheap lights on like Amazon that are
better than anything that was available
in 2016.
um better than you know your first cob
and they are still selling some of those
but it's just it's tremendous how we've
seen that sort of the the technology
progress and then the prices collapse
yeah I lived through that time as well
and it's it's crazy to see the way it
went let's uh let's start from the the
beginning here just Basics LEDs what are
they actually
ladies are are you just make the use of
semiconductors so semiconductor is just
material that doesn't conduct
electricity well it conducts electricity
sort of somewhat it's semi-conductive
and that's why it's called a
semiconductor
um
LEDs in particular use a PN type
semiconductor where
um you know electrons are basically
pushed from p-type material to n-type
material and as they cross that juncture
um the electrons are forced to to
descend in orbit
um as they descend in orbit they lose
energy and we can
we can by selecting the right
semiconductor materials sort of make the
electron lose the right amount of energy
and it will produce a photon of a
specific amount of energy so you know a
semiconductor basically we just push
electricity through this material and as
the electrons and I'm sorry they move
from the n-type to the p-type material
as they move across there they release
this energy that is in the form of an
electron
um each semiconductor will
lead to a specific drop in energy so as
it moves from the n-type to the p-type
it's got to you know drop so many band
levels basically and that determines how
much energy it has to release and that
determines the wavelength of the photon
that's created different wavelengths
photons have different sort of amounts
of energy in them so if there's a lot of
energy in the photon then it's going to
be blue or ultraviolet if there's less
be red or infrared
um and every single Photon that comes
out of a semiconductor is going to have
basically the same amount of energy and
B basically the same wavelength because
that's determined by the specific
materials that are used in the pnn type
material sort of how far that electron
has to drop as it crosses the junction
um
if you get deeper and deeper into that
but it gets sort of deeper and deeper
into
quite literally theoretical physics well
we will get too deep into it I want to
go over some of these beginners heads
here but uh appreciate the explanation
that's it so electricity sort of gets
pushed through a semiconductor and
energy is released by by controlling the
materials in the semiconductor we can
tune it up so that almost all of the
energy that's released comes off as
light because it could also come off as
heat so that's one area where different
kinds of semiconductors
um are more or less efficient and in you
know that first part of the sort of
historical Trend right when we're going
from like 2012 to 2016.
um we saw tremendous gains in the
semiconductor materials that were used
to really make it so more and more of
the energy was being released as light
and less and less of the energy was
being released as heat
um and that's really how semiconductors
became so much more sort of efficient at
this point the 450 nanometer
semiconductors are 90 efficient so 90 of
the power that we drive to them and this
is blue 450 nanometers
90 percent of the energy that sort of is
consumed is blue light becomes Blue
Light Energy
um and laws of physics suggest that you
know we can't we can't get more than a
hundred percent of the energy consumed
to be blue light energy right so we're
already at 90 percent so LEDs those
semiconductors especially the blue
semiconductors are becoming are sort of
reaching the maximum of efficiency what
we could ever expect out of any lighting
technology so a lot of Growers outside
what's next and you know isn't there
going to be some new Revolution that
like replaces LEDs and gets us you know
LEDs are twice as good as HPS is
something else going to come along
that's going to be twice as good as LEDs
no it can't happen it's violational laws
of physics LEDs like HPS was 40
efficient and LEDs and like you know 80
percent efficient some of the blue chips
like I just said are up to 90 efficient
we're running out of room to to continue
to sort of grow that that's interesting
now what about the Spectrum I know the
Spectrum you can get with LEDs it can be
different than a lot the traditional HPS
for example a lot of people claim that
the HPS is a close closer Spectrum to
the Sun than any LED is talk to us about
like the Spectrum differences between
LEDs what you can get out of LEDs versus
what you can get out of some of the
other traditional lighting so each each
semiconductor creates one wavelength of
light that's it so 660 nanometer you
know semiconductor it creates
photons from like 655 to 665 nanometers
but they're all right in this really
narrow little range of spectrum right
um the 450 nanometer semiconductors are
almost exactly at 450 so like every
Photon coming out of that they're
monochromatic they create one color of
light
um and and you know the earlier
generations of LEDs used blue diodes and
they used red diodes and in sorry
conjunction
um and that's why because you have
semiconductors that create blue light
and you have semiconductors they create
red light there are no semiconductors
that create quote-unquote white light
white light is the combination of
several different Spectra so you have
photons at different wavelengths all can
coming together that create white light
and interestingly you don't need a lot
of all of the different lights you can
have a lot of red and a lot of blue as
long as you have some greens and yellows
the light looks pretty why if you only
have red and blue the light looks
blurple and you know Growers that have
been around the block for a few years
and then what purple light looks like
it's it's not sort of a
it's certainly not white and it's not
pleasant you can't really see your
plants under it very well and that was
one of the big problems with with purple
light so what they do to create white
light or white diodes is they start with
the 450 nanometer blue semiconductor and
then they use phosphor in the glue that
sort of holds that semiconductor and
that phosphor distributes the the energy
to the other spectral Brands so they're
able to sort of
what you're basically doing there blue
photons at 450 nanometers have a lot of
energy red photons sit like 650 to 700
nanometers have less energy so when you
push those blue photons through a media
like phosphor that strips them of some
of their energy some of those photons
become redder and it sort of diffuses
the light through the Spectrum to create
that white tint now all
full spectrum diodes are heavy on blue
because they are blue semiconductors so
if you look at the spectral output sort
of diagram of what the diodes produce
they all have a strong Peak at 450
nanometers because they're using 450
nanometer semiconductors to create the
light sort of in the first place right
um and then they'll have a secondary
Peak out usually at 650 660 in the high
600s there which is where most of the
photons got sort of filtered to as they
pass through the the phosphor
um but some photons will land in the
middle and these are green and yellow
Spectrum so you know as you're throwing
a bunch of photons out towards the high
600s you end up with some in the 400 or
the high 400s 500s lows 600s even out to
the 700s and and sort of Beyond some
photons get sort of slowed down more
they're not not slowed down stripped of
more energy
um
because all photons travel at the speed
of light right some like longer
wavelength photons travel at the speedo
so they get from like this side of the
screen to this side of the screen like
that right just like maybe one wave
um like 800 nanometer or you know 650
nanometer but then you get like 450
nanometer right
um 300 nanometer you have to like start
vibrating more in the same space now
every single Photon gets from here to
here in the same amount of time so if
you have to do 20 vibrations that's more
energy than if you only have to do one
vibration in that time right so blue
photons vibrate faster than red photons
in that case but they all travel at the
speed of light
um so
that's one side they now light like
um HPS
um or the the other you know gas
discharge lights
they create light in a different way and
they basically heat up elements
um that they create different gases and
then they bombard those gases with
electrons
as the electrons hit different gases
they gain energy and then as they fall
back down to their original energy level
they release photons and since those
collisions happen somewhat chaotically
that you know they go to different
heights and they fall down at different
heights so they create a blend of
photons across different Spectra and to
change the Spectrum in gas discharge
lighting you change the the gaseous
elements that are going to be vaporized
so
um you know
sodium and different
um Mercury and different things can be
vaporized and bombarded that's the way
fluorescent lights work too fluorescent
lights vaporize Mercury and then bombard
it with photons and it's the photons
sort of hit it they gain energy and when
a photon or when an electron sorry with
an electron loses energy it will release
a photon that energy becomes a photon
so that's one side of it very different
the other thing we can do with LEDs is
we can Target Spectra so we can create a
diode at 660 nanometers and grow lights
all use not all but almost all of them
use 660 nanometer diodes because you
know the full spectrum are really 450
nanometer diodes that are throwing some
portion of their energy out to the red
but not enough they're strong in blue
and sort of weaker and red so grow light
manufacturers add red to their you know
ad specific red diodes which are Super
efficient the the red diodes are only
like 70 percent energy efficient
but since red photons have less energy
you actually get more photons per watt
with a red diode than you do with the
blue diode so like the best blue diodes
are like 3.2 3.3 like the best blue
diodes 3.2 3.3 micro moles of photons
per walk of energy
the best red 660 nanometer photons are
over four micro moles of photons per
watt of energy
even though they're less energy
efficient so basically four micro moles
worth of red photons have less energy
than three micro moles of blue photons
but plants don't really care about that
the plants care about how many photons
are hitting them plants care less about
sort of how much energy is in each
individual Photon plants respond just as
well to a red Photon as they do to a
blue Photon so one thing we're able to
do with LEDs is give them more red
photons which we're able to make to
create really efficiently
um and you know sort of Spike our
efficiency numbers by by targeting the
red photons with you know a specific
semiconductor that very efficiently
creates those photons and they're not
filtered through anything
um that gas discharge if you want to
change the the Spectrum you either
change the the elements that are getting
heated in that the the electrons are are
colliding with where you filter the
light with various things and anytime
you filter the light you lose efficiency
so the ability of LEDs to create any
specific spectrum of light is one of
LEDs significant advantages really
because we can Target things
I think
we need to at least mention the other
side of this which is sort of like what
spectrum do we want for different plants
um what what spectrum are we trying to
create and
you know that there's still some really
exciting research on that really
exciting Research into how much far red
light might be beneficial for plants for
example
um but the best research suggests that
plants want at least a distribution of
light energy sources such that you know
the purples weren't terrible in that
they did Target sort of the 450 and the
um ranges so they weren't sort of just
Drilling in on one photo system
um they're activating both and you know
plants do better really with a full
spectrum light but they're most
photosynthetically responsive to the
blue light into the red light adding
green and yellow light the primary
importance of that is for us as Growers
to be able to see our plants better if
we grow just under blurple blue and and
red light it's really hard to identify
like plant nutrient deficiencies pest
issues overall plant health issues
because you just don't get to see your
plant very well but in terms of
photosynthetic response plants grown
under blurple lights do pretty well
um vis-a-vis plants grown Under full
spectrum lights during the vegetative
growth
um
plants growing under monochromatic light
so only blue or only red light don't do
very well during vegetative growth
and during flowering or reproductive
growth for most plants there's less
significance on Spectrum
more significance on flocks so how much
light the plant is harvesting as opposed
to what specific sorry qualities the
lights are I know a lot of Growers think
that the specific spectrum that you give
especially during the flowering phase is
going to be sort of the key to harvest
quality or to getting the best out of
your plants we don't have really any
scientific research to to support those
beliefs all the research that's been
done on flowering plants and altering
the Spectrum really suggests that
altering the Spectrum has almost no
impact on on harvest yield or harvest
quality we do know that during
vegetative growth plants will respond
differently to to Red heavy Spectra
versus blue heavy Spectra so if we
redshift our vegetating light then the
plants will grow lankier
evolutionarily red light is usually
filtered through something so it sends
the signal to the plants that you're
growing under somebody else you better
kind of get taller and get up above them
um so they they try to stretch more
often in a way that we as Growers don't
want they become too sort of stretched
out and lanky so so we don't want to put
them under too much red light that's why
back in the days that we did HPS and
metal halide we'd veg under metal halide
it's not because metal halide were
better it's because metal halide have
less red in them and the plants wouldn't
sort of grow too much a lot of Growers
got the idea that we switched to HPS
because like HPS was better Spectrum for
flowering
that's really not true HPS are more
efficient than metal halide
um and plants don't really care what
spectrum they're flowered under so if we
veg plants under HPS they grow too lanky
so that was the problem so we'd veg
plants under metal halide and then we'd
switch them to HPS because HPS is more
efficient not necessarily because it's
going to produce sort of better Harvest
quality it would produce higher yields
but the higher yield was because of the
increase in efficiency
for the same sort of wattage output
um so I I just want to say that we want
to distribute the light
understanding something about Spectrum
especially during vegetative plants
vegetating growth is important but I
think a lot of Growers sort of think
that there's some magic in Spectrum
during flowering
we don't have anything in sort of the
scientific data that suggests that
that's really the case I appreciate you
getting into so much detail in regards
to Spectrum and uh clarifying some
things that were incorrect over the
years now let's get into kind of what to
look for in an LED grow light there are
so many different things that you can
look for I know you created a grow light
calculator which is awesome hoping you
can talk about that here but um you know
what should folks be looking for since
you mentioned Spectrum we already
already talked about that as something
to look at and what to look at within
the Spectrum but par efficiency of the
fixture I'm even going and on what are
the kind of like the top things people
should look for because there are so
many different things people get
confused used pretty easily when it
comes to shopping for an LED grow light
so so break it down for us
so first we just got to break light into
two parts light is a particle a light is
a wave so far we've been talking about
light as a wave we've been talking about
Spectrum we're talking about different
nanometers of wavelength red light
versus blue light how all that that's
all light as a wave light is also a
particle
photons and what really matters that
side flux what we call flux the the
amount of photons basically that are
hitting the plant the amount of radiated
energy that's going to be hitting the
plant
um it that's more important for almost
all reasons than Spectrum I think a lot
of girls get caught up thinking about
spectrum and they think about different
colors of light and all of this but the
overall amount of light is what
ultimately really matters almost every
grow light has a decent enough Spectrum
I don't I don't sort of knock a lot of
grow lights because they have a terrible
Spectrum but I'll certainly knock them
because they don't produce enough
photons so they don't have enough
efficiency in in producing their photons
so we want to talk about counting
photons and understanding how many
photons your grow light will sort of
produce because there's a number when
we're talking about micro moles we're
talking about a number of photons so
think of it as a quantity of light so
every every grow light can produce a
certain quantity of light per second
okay and that's what we call the ppf the
photosynthetic Photon flux
um that total amount of light that's
created per second there's different
ways to measure it you can just say hey
I'm using these diodes that get you know
3.2 micromoles per watt and I got a
hundred Watts so I got 320 microballs
you could just do a calculation like
that right a lot of grow light companies
do exactly that and when you see a
number often advertised for their ppf
that's just a a calculation of what the
diode could theoretically do times the
number of Watts that are being driven
through this fixture and it's kind of BS
because it's not reality
so we call that the calculated ppf right
because it's not measured it's just what
they do based on the published numbers
or the components that they're using
um the other thing we could do to
measure the amount of light that a grow
light fixture creates is we could stick
it in a device called an integrating
sphere in an integrating sphere measures
what we call the total ppf it actually
counts each Photon that comes out of
that fixture each and every Photon no
matter where it goes basically unless it
hits the grow light fixture itself
because it's in the integrating sphere
and gets like a converted to heat by
hitting the gray light fixture itself
it's going to be counted by the
integrating sphere so we call that the
total ppf and a lot of better grow light
manufacturers will sort of have their
lights sphere tested and then they'll
report a sphere test number usually out
to two or three decimal places so if you
see a sphere test number they're going
to advertise something like our fixture
gets
2.379 micromoles per per Joule they're
not just going to say like 3.4 or
whatever they're getting they're going
to sort of have that
sort of finer granularity because they
actually ran a test and they actually
have something that they're reporting
there
but we don't grow our plants in a sphere
um you know we don't grow our plants on
the inside of an integrating sphere we
grow our plants usually in a grow tent
so a sphere is an over count of how many
photons will actually hit your plants in
a grow tent so if you want a better
understanding of sort of what a grow
light is going to be able to deliver to
the canopy of your garden then you want
to look at a par test result
um a well set up par test can measure
what we call the usable ppf and the
usable ppf is the number of photons that
actually are going to hit the plants in
your grow
um that's what I try to measure in my
par tests so you set up a fixture and
the way it could be used and then you
measure how many photons actually arrive
to the the canopy of that space so what
we're doing there is we're using a
Quantum sentence you're a par sensor
which is actually measuring ppf D the d
stands for density so we're not the
sensor doesn't count the total number of
them it doesn't know the total number of
them it just knows the number that are
hitting the sensor and it says well this
is how dense the photons are they're
basically hitting this sensor if we take
a good sample across a par test like
that then we can extrapolate from that
density across the area the size of the
area that we know and that gets us to
the quantity the overall quantity of
light
um
there's a lot into ppf but ppf whether
it's calculated ppf whether it's total
ppf or whether it's usable ppf are
metrics to describe the total amount of
light that a fixture will produce and
and that's what our calculator sort of
fundamentally works with because the the
amount of light that a grow light
fixture creates determines how much area
that grow light can cover at a given
density you know a density of light so
if you have a thousand micro moles
of light and you want 500 micromoles per
square meter of density
and you had perfect distribution which
isn't realistic but just to say you had
perfect distribution then you could grow
with two square meters right because you
have a thousand micro moles divided by
two square meters would be 500
micromoles per square meter that micro
moles per square meter is the ppfd
measurement
um and that's basically how we go from
an amount
of light we have an idea of how much
density we want to grow with what the
plants can tolerate and so how much
space a different grow light will be
able to cover
um the grow light calculator sort of
works with those numbers so if a grow
light will tell you something like
this girl that gets 2.8 micromoles per
Joule and that might be all you know
about the gorilla you should assume that
that number is a calculated PP PPE
that's photosynthetic Photon efficacy
but it relates to
um ppf which is the total amount of
photons so you can take that 2.8 over to
our grow light calculator take that 2.8
and plug that into the the micro moles
per Joule tag and then how many watts
does it grow light say it has it's a you
know 100 watt light
um just for simplistic reasons so you'd
put that in the in the watt field and
then you put the the cost which it just
needs to do the cost efficiency and then
you'd be able to select is this total
ppf do I think that they actually did a
sphere test I'll call it total PP after
I think that this is just a number that
they calculated you know I'll call it
calculated ppf
um and the calculator will make its own
conversions based on all right if that's
calculated ppf this is what we would
expect it to be able to do in terms of
usable ppf that's one of the big things
that the calculator does is convert
between those different types of ppf and
then some actually more simple
calculations about how much area could
this grow light cover how much could you
reasonably expect to harvest from such a
grow light because all of that really is
a function of the amount of light that
you're you're providing to your plan so
we can have a fairly good estimate of
your Harvest potential not your sort of
guarantee that you'll actually hit that
but what your Harvest potential is how
much coverage you could get
um and break down you know how efficient
the the light is and whether or not it's
a good deal so that's what the the
calculator is designed to do and and
that's it the number one thing if you're
out there shopping for a grow light that
I think you should pay attention to is
the parmap
um you see because the department talks
about the actual light that's hitting
the canopy those those numbers that you
see in a par map are the ppfd numbers so
the density of photons at each position
across that map
um good distribution you don't want to
grow most Growers don't want to put
unless you're supplementing carbon
dioxide you're not going to want to put
your plants under more than a thousand
micro malls of ppfd
um light basically and even though you
can go outside in the Noonday sun and
measure the Sun at about 2 000 ppfd you
don't want to grow plants indoors under
a steady light source from higher than a
thousand ppfd because they will have
light toxicity issues if you do
supplementing CO2 can get a little bit
higher than that so if you're evaluating
a par map make sure that the numbers in
the middle of the power map aren't above
a thousand it if they are that's not a
realistic map it's also not a realistic
map if they're like 500 you'd probably
want more light than that so try to find
a power map with the center value is
close to a thousand and when the center
value is close to a thousand you want
the corners to be at least 500.
um that's a good distribution of light
no no hot spot higher than a thousand
and the lowest areas are at least 500.
um and that's sort of what I try to
evaluate in my par test now make sure
that it's a Well set up par test there's
any number of ways that manufacturers
can sort of goose the numbers on their
own tests so where possible use the
third party test or at least be
confident in how how they set it up that
makes sense yeah I'm looking at your
grow light calculator on your website
right now and I remember when you first
came out with us this was awesome one
thing I really like about it is if you
put the cost in there you can see what
the cost efficiency is like how much
you're paying per micromole that's cool
because you know if you're paying
outrageous price for it then the
fixtures is just not worth it
relationship there right in in these
days that's the best way to evaluate the
cost of a grow light too is the cost per
microball because what you're buying is
a light creating machine so how much
light can it create and then you know
divide that by the purchase cost is what
we do for cost efficiency so say a light
that can create 600 micro malls that
costs you know two hundred dollars that
would be a tremendous deal that would be
like you know 33 cents per micro Mall
um which there are some lights that that
are getting towards that range down into
the the 30 cents per micro Mall you know
when we started when I did the grow
light calculator and we considered
anything under a dollar to be a good
deal right and this is the the sort of
price drop that we were talking about
and the efficiency gain had already
happened but you go back to like 2016
2017 2018
if you could find grow light that got
better than two micromoles per watt and
you could find them but not that was
less than two micromorphs per dollar or
two dollars per micro Mall basically
um and now you can get them for like 40
or 50 cents
per micro Mall
um some of the the best deals out there
like on sales and stuff are down in the
30 cents per micro mole so the prices
have been basically cut in the third
over the last four or five years
um really sort of tremendous yeah it's
really incredible to see that huge price
drop and it's a lot better for consumers
of course because they're spending less
money on these grow lights it's pretty
new problems four or five years ago I
could basically assume when I'd start
talking to a grower that they were under
lit every grower was under lit didn't
have really enough light it's really
actually hard to be fully lit with HPS
lighting because it the you know it's
just one bulb in the center and that the
reflectors aren't that great and it
creates that Central Hot Spot and it's
just hard to get sort of a good
distribution of light so you'd always
sort of end up with you know good light
in the middle and crappy light towards
the corners if you were in a single
fixture space
um and and Growers under LEDs four or
five years ago man they were they were
all buying the the lies that this 100
watt light was a thousand watt HPS
replacement or whatever and everybody
was under lit but since the efficiency's
gone up and the prices come down more
and more Growers are not only full lit
but they have the capacity we want to be
a grower that's fully lit but you have
the the capacity to be over lit and to
be actually I mean I I'm running into
more and more Growers now that are are
creating light talks situations
um for their plants so that that used to
not be a thing really I mean especially
amongst home Growers it it wasn't a
thing to be sort of bleaching your buds
because you actually unless you wear HPS
and you knew you were too close to the
mhps but not just because like you had
too much LED light in your tent so it's
it's crazy how that's happened but
Growers can definitely be fully lit and
we're seeing home Growers pull down
tremendous numbers because you know
they're great distribution of light
across their their tents and really you
know good numbers not too much heat
either just sort of the other side of
that so you talk to us about things you
can look for in an LED grow light let's
talk Brands so you either of us are have
any exclusive relationships with LED
grow light company so we're free to talk
about whatever Brands we want however we
want to talk about them which is uh
fantastic here so let's talk Brands what
is someone like the top brands or model
lights here in 2023 that you recommend
people to check out
it kind of depends on your price point
to be perfectly honest with you
um I definitely think there's ways to to
waste a lot of money on lights
um I think there's a lot of expensive
lights on the market that
for me don't justify the return on
investment I mean there is no return on
investment I so to be aware of sort of
that side
um
due to the changes in the market over
the last you know like we've been
talking about decade
you can get really decent quality lights
for not a lot of money
um and there's no reason to pay sort of
a tremendous premium five years ago
there was a reason to pay a tremendous
premium for LED lights because the
difference between the top of the market
and the bottom of the market was really
significant and the only way you could
get the high efficiency fixtures was to
to show out sort of the the premium
prices for those products a lot of those
companies are continuing to try to
demand a premium price but they're no
longer offering sort of a compelling
advantage over lower cost competitors so
you know just to be aware of that I I I
see a lot of Growers I'm thinking man
you didn't have to spend that much I
mean this is really even more true in
the commercial side of of growing now
um than in the the home growth side
although I think it's it's sort of true
on both sides that
there's a certain sense of luxury
pricing where people think that if I'm
spending more for something I'm getting
a better quality product
in the end I think uh
you know you want to pay attention to
these and sort of Statistics that we've
been talking about making sure you're
getting a quality fixture
um
with whatever fixture you're getting
making sure like things you know they're
not overpowering the diodes they're not
sort of goosing the numbers in that way
look at diode count I think is really
something that I'd encourage you to look
at even over a brand of fixture brand of
light
um at the at the lower end because you
did ask about Brands
um you know I've reviewed several of the
the medicro fixtures that are down in
the the 30 cents per micro Mall
territory
um and I'm working with a a couple
different commercial Growers now that
I've used those have
um set up the Medicare lights in their
facilities and have been happy with them
so I'm continuing to sort of keep my eye
on that that's one I've been I first
reviewed I think about three years ago
now and at that time I was like this
price is too good to be true like what
what's the cash on this
um you know the more mainstream discount
Brands
um Mars hydros your spider farmers of
the world
um those sort of they do a lot of direct
marketing they do a lot of marketing
through Amazon
um they have a pretty big chunk of the
home grow market in terms of market and
cop
um a lot of their fixtures are pretty
decent they're a little bit more
expensive a little bit more expensive
than the medicro fixtures but you know
the pretty decent fixtures I I from both
of those companies spider farmer and
Marsh Hydro I prefer their sort of more
discounted line over there more premium
line
um in both cases they have a premium
line that uses the Samsung LM 301b
diodes which have gotten and we should
probably talk a little bit about that
because it's like the one brand name of
diode that Growers really now them in
the austram 660 animators
um that Growers often look for
specifically but I think that sometimes
gets you into trouble and this is a good
sort of case point of it spider farmer
and Mars Hydro both have their top end
product lines that use the the Samsung
LN 301h and austram 660 nanometer years
they have reasonable diode quantities
and sort of a higher price tag both
those companies also have sort of a more
discounted line that uses Bridge locks
diodes
um and they use like three times as many
Bridge Lux diodes as they use of the
ostram diodes
um granted the bridge looks diodes are
not as high or rated for as high of
wattage but they're still powering them
at a lower percentage of the rated
capacity than they are of the Samsungs
and that makes the bridge lugs diodes
ever so slightly more efficient than the
Samsung diodes in their top and sort of
model lines so even though the diodes
themselves aren't quite as good they're
using so many more of them that that
ends up being more efficient because
you're powering them less and when you
when you power a diode at a lower
current it's more efficient when you try
to like step on the gas you just get you
can get more light but that lower and
lower efficiency so you step on the gas
harder
um
so those are interesting sort of things
to think about even amongst different
brands moving up a sort of a little bit
from there and I can justify some of
these fixtures in terms of different
features and and different sort of
options and things that they have
um worked with Photon Tech
um the photon Tech is Luma Tech in the
rest of the world they have they have
nice fixtures they're
I think 50 percent more than the the
Mars Hydro spider farmer fixtures of the
world and they're like 60 70 percent
more than the the medicro fixtures
um sometimes even more than that so you
know at a certain point it becomes hard
to to justify anything kind of above
there there's certainly companies that
are trying to Market higher quality
lights or
other gimmicks and lights but you know
the real differentiation is what we
talked about how many photons can you
create and how well do you do at
Distributing them across the the grow
space
um
every other thing that grow like
manufacturers are trying to do you know
we were at MJ bizcon and you'd see all
these grow light manufacturers that have
like
um angle they can adjust the angle on
the LED bar so you can like tilt them
back and forth like that
um the supplemental UV and and
supplemental IR bars or including UV and
IR diodes and it's just gimmicks it's
it's literally just gimmicks to try to
differentiate from other people in the
market and and or some more likes or
charge more money
um a lot of talk about tunable spectrums
and you know or proprietary spectrums or
it's it's just mumbo jumbo it's not
related to anything it's a marketing
battle pay attention to how many photons
are created how efficient it is how much
it costs
um
you know how how hard the diodes are
driven is probably the next most
important factor to consider so how many
diodes there are in total and how much
power is there you want to have you know
three to four diodes per watt is is a
good sort of rule to just take to
evaluating
um like any standard grow light there
may be reasons that I would agree that
you you'd accept lower than that
depending on what the diodes were but in
general you want three to four diodes
per watt if you have less than that
you're going to burn out your diodes
faster regardless of what brand the
diodes are and you're not going to run
as efficiently
um sort of more diodes than that you may
increase the longevity of your light
um but all LEDs are going to sort of
lose efficiency through time so if you
buy an LED and you're running it at a
hundred percent out of the box
you may need to supplement light after
five years or replace it after five
years a lot of the commercial Growers I
work with we plan so that they're only
running it at like 85 percent out of the
box and can ramp up power over the next
few years to extend the life of their
fixtures I know obviously I said enough
about brands in there do you want to add
anything any specific brands that you'd
like feedback on well yeah I was going
to ask you about like the what I kind of
call The Big Three coming out of China
you know you already kind of touched on
Mars Hydro spider farmer and and Viper
Specter is the other one I kind of want
to name that that you know they're
coming out with really other so it's
really
yeah there's a real relationship between
Mars hydro and spider farmer Viper
Spectra is a completely different
um entity I think of them slightly
different although I like the new Viper
Specter bar lights
um for homegirls in particular I think
that they are actually better than than
the
um better at distribution because
they're a little bit bigger than the
Mars and the spider farmer fixtures
um I agree I should have brought them up
I also think they they're a good source
of even smaller lights you know which is
another interesting point two by two
grows earned down in that area I would
use a little Quantum board
um if you're in a three by three or four
by four or a larger space I would go
with an LED bar fixture
um not a Quantum board style light or a
cob or whatever the LED bars are are
sort of considerably more efficient and
better at Distributing the light well
what I was going to ask you about what
those three brands in particular is some
of them are coming in I mean you can buy
like the ks 5000 for example from my
perspective which I've ran for several
grows and I love it as well it's like
500 bucks you know to cover a 4x4 or 5x5
grow space now there are some American
brands out there such as like chill Tech
and hlg for example who so for that same
growth space they have prices that are a
lot higher upwards of a thousand dollars
to cover that size growth space is it
worth it to be spending hundreds of
dollars more for these American brands
I mean I I suppose to a certain extent
that might depend on on what you're
spending the money for
um it's important to to sort of
recognize the components in a lot of the
manufacturing are still being done
overseas even for a lot of the American
brands
um they're distributed in the United
States but often manufactured overseas
anyways
um it's hard for me to justify spending
twice as much it's hard for me to ever
adjust if I spent even more than twice
as much which some of those sites cost
um
and you know chilled in particular is
creating some of the most efficient
fixtures on the market
um they're Ultra Series I believe is the
most efficient series on the market
right now but
like
you know it would be
Decades of running at that efficiency
before you'd recover the initial
investment in terms of how much more
expensive those fixtures are
so you know fluence is is another one
that's in that
um
um oh who's the the big one that gets on
my nerves all the time with their their
marketing foes
um f-o-h-s-e is is another one that they
sell these really high cost lights
um they target it foes in particularly
targeted sort of the commercial market
and their marketing is basically like
we know something about like that nobody
else knows and like only our light does
it so if you want this super special
magic exhaust then you need to get our
specific light there's a lot of lighting
companies that have basically taken that
marketing approach to try to convince
Growers that there's some special
quality to their light and that they're
the only light that offers it and so if
you want to have the best results get
this and then they Goose numbers on sort
of their grams per square foot or their
returns or whatever it is that they're
trying to sort of prove that point over
um
I I I I I don't see how you justify
spending the the costs for for the that
technology some of the fixtures are very
nice but in the end these grow lights
get mounted onto the ceiling of your
grow space and like you want them to
come on when you want them to come on
and you want them to go off when you
want them to go off you don't need them
to cook you breakfast and make your bed
and you know do anything else they're
just lights so that's kind of my my take
on on the really expensive models and
that's my pitch to the commercial scale
like I said I'm working with a couple of
big commercial Farms that just went in
all in on medicro because what we're
buying are micro moles of light and
that's the cheapest micro malls per
light basically that are out there
um and now there are legitimate other
reasons I think for for choosing
different brands but
um you want to be able to have a good
customer service experience
uh and that can be a challenge depending
on on who you're working with and if
you're working with a dealer that they
can actually get responses from these
organizations uh from these different
companies and I think some of the
American companies may offer you know
somewhat better
um points of contact yeah but you're
you're being asked to pay twice and you
know I I was looking at actual quotes
for one of these grows that I was
working with
um of a hundred and sixty thousand
dollars for the the medicro lights or
six hundred and forty thousand dollars
okay it wasn't it's like okay you can
pay an extra half million dollars I mean
what what do we get for our extra half
million dollars it better be like damn
good customer service that's crazy yeah
think about it but micromole per watt or
a cost per micro Mall
um you know some of those fixtures and
some of those companies that are
targeting the commercial space in
particular
um are still charging a dollar or more
per micro mall where you know
companies that you're in more com more
competitive markets it's interesting
um and I do Consulting in the commercial
space and I work with the Growers I like
this on these lights a lot of the the
commercial scale Growers are spending
other people's money and if they have a
good sales pitch to go back to their
investors or their their you know money
man with about well this says the latest
science lights whatever then they'll
they'll get that I mean people don't
know enough now home Growers don't know
enough either and that's sort of
hopefully what you and I are on this
mission to improve the the knowledge
base so that Growers can't be taken
advantage of
um by companies they're just put on a
selling Mobility Goods well I appreciate
you shedding some light on lighting and
talking about some of the things that
people can look for within lighting so
they aren't getting ripped off you know
we could go deeper and deeper into
Brands and there's so many other things
that we could talk to about lighting we
can't fit into this episode episode but
maybe come back in the future for
another LED lighting episode talk to us
how can the listeners find you and what
do you have upcoming in the future yes
yeah so listeners can find me on my
YouTube channel Dr MJ Coco YouTube
channel I am on Instagram at Dr MJ Coco
and run the website cokeovercanabis.com
which is probably the best place to to
sort of get in touch with me at this
point
um I'm setting up a a new sort of
landing page but that's not not quite
ready for myself yet
um so yeah I love working with home
Growers I've got a bunch of resources
and articles available for all sorts of
Growers
um do Consulting work with a lot of of
commercial Farms either on sort of
getting them set up in the first place
or solving problems or increasing
efficiency and sort of achieving their
goals
um you know if you're interested to to
talk about lights or if you're sort of
planning to to purchase lights as well
check out our grow light guide
um on the recommended grow lights page
you know there's a forum for people to
to schedule appointments with me if they
want to talk about larger purchases or
if they've got a bigger room that they
want to set up and think about how to to
do a light layout or sort of how to
effectively approach that so love
working with with Growers I love sort of
straightening out grows and helping
um sort of bring people to that that
next level
um really enjoyed talking about lighting
I hope none of the brands feel
particularly called out
um you know I think that there's there's
a whole sort of set of brands that that
they need to to figure out what
justifies the costs that that they're
asking and if they're saying things that
I think aren't valid that's my job is to
say I'm not sure that that sort of valid
out there so I I'm not trying to make
any enemies we with that but I I do
think you need to ask yourself as a as a
grower
you know what are you paying for in this
and you know whether or not it makes
sense to to opt in at these different
price points
um so hopefully this has been fun and
enlightening I've really enjoyed doing
both of these shows with you so thanks
for having me on and and you know it'd
be a real pleasure to come back yeah
thanks for coming on appreciate you
spitting your knowledge to us uh if
you're tuning in on YouTube I'll
definitely have a link to his YouTube
channel down in the description section
below he's got a ton of Park test videos
on there and also information about
growing in Cocoa which we talked about
in the previous episode I'll definitely
link that in the description section as
well if you're interested in more of
that uh science of LED stuff that we got
into a little bit my recent video on the
the science of Horticultural LEDs
um dive is pretty deep into like how
LEDs work and the efficiencies the
different spectrum and you know all
kinds of questions like that so
um if that part of this conversation was
interesting I recommend following up
with that video absolutely if you
enjoyed this episode click that Thumbs
Up Button also subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already every single
weekend I'm releasing a new Garden Talk
podcast episode and I'd love you to tune
in to future episodes Dr MJ Coco thank
you so much once again I appreciate you
and hope you enjoy the rest of your day
absolutely it's a pleasure and grow our
love to everyone out there peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode