welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden hey everybody for those of you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr growt and you're tuned into the
garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 144 in this episode I interview
Joshua steensland he's been gardening
for 27 years and is regarded as an
expert when it comes to growing and
living soil he gets into several key
aspects for this grow method such as
building a soil from scratch soil
microbiology compost and so much more if
you want to see short clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I show the plants that I
grow both of those channels will be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said I'd like to thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible
thanks to AC Infinity for sponsoring
this episode check out their instant
potting mix a soilless grow medium made
from 100% organic coca COA fiber it's
buffered and triple washed to maintain
pH stability and reduce salinity it
comes in a 2 pound brick which expands
to fill up to a 3 gallon grow pot click
the link in the description section
below so you can learn more about their
instant potting mix and the discount
code Mr grow5 works on both Amazon and
their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend is a 215 plant
additive that can be used with synthetic
bottle nutrients or in living soil
systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash and we are back
and I'm joined with Joshua steensland
how you doing today I'm doing well how
are you doing pretty good thanks for
coming on to the podcast today we're
going to talk all about living soil now
this is an area that you have many many
years experience so really excited to
have you on the podcast today to get
deep into it but first can you give us
an introduction tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening sure sure uh my name is Joshua
steensland and um I've been cultivating
plants and and tending Gardens um since
about 1997 when I got out of the Marines
um I really uh had an itch to to to get
involved um
horticulturally um with all kinds of
plants medicinal plants veggie gardens
the works and um really just kind of hit
the ground running and I've been
cultivating pretty much continuously
since 97 awesome yeah I think I first
came across you in 2016 if I remember
correctly came across your content I was
like man this guy he's really good at
dialed in and you were doing Organics
and living soil back then so you've been
had so many years experience here doing
it how many years have you kind of had
your feet wet with living soil in
particular yeah well I ironically I
think you probably uh came across me
right around the time I was um first
discovering and sharing my process so
before about 2016 I I would cultivate in
many different I used to own a couple
brick and mortar hydroponic shops or
garden centers in southern Oregon and um
that afforded me the opportunity to try
lots of different cultivation Styles
aeroponic deep water culture
recirculating deep water culture Coco
you the works so I had been in um the
middle of lots of different transitions
I had a really bad run with h a popular
nutrient brand that I won't name um and
I was just kind of fed up and so I hit
the IC M forums and I saw a picture in a
post of probably the most beautiful
plant I had ever seen and the caption
underneath the picture
was this plant was grown with nothing
but water and its own shade leaves and I
was just Gob smacked completely blown
away how that was even possible so I
went in I just Dove deep into the rabbit
hole I started with the subcool super
soil type um blend and then um really
Dove uh head first into and a huge shout
out to Jeremy at Builder soil uh he his
website was uh really and still is a a
vast um resource for knowledge and
especially in those early days there was
not a lot of people talking living soil
and um it really gave me the confidence
to kind of jump in with both feet and I
decided at that time to just document my
journey so I started a YouTube
channel and you can watch like my first
12 Cycles or something might might only
be 10 um on YouTube they're all on there
and I just kind of documenting my
journey and uh uh really got to watch
the the living soil methodology take off
over the years it was uh really great I
feel fortunate to have been in a unique
position to kind of watch this Rebirth
of these old School cultivation
techniques that are are being embraced
um in all different sectors of of
horiculture and agriculture that's
awesome so lots of history there yeah I
remember when I first started I started
with the synthetic bottle nutrients and
I'm slowly transitioned over to the
organic side of things and it seems like
the past 10 years in particular there's
been a large transition from using
bottle nutrients to Organics living soil
no to living soil regenerative Garden
right what is meant by living soil so
say all your organic gardening or you're
living soil and what's the difference
break it down for us sure so living soil
you know there's life everywhere even in
the worst like Dusty dirt that has no
organic matter there's still bacteria
there present so everything is really
alive so some people get confused with
like what is this living soil mean and
really uh uh horticulturally speaking
it's
having not just bacteria but fungi
protozoa M micro arthopods worms you're
having a whole Consortium of of biology
Dr Lane in refers to it as the soil food
web I highly recommend folks going down
that rabbit
hole um but in a living soil system
we're paying as much or more frankly
attention to the soil than we are are
actual the crop that we're trying to
grow or trying to cultivate and um
there's there's practices that can that
that you can do to help increase the
biological diversity and the quantity of
biology in your soils to uh really help
facilitate that nutrient cycling process
so um it's really all about biology in
in diversity and in the correct
quantities in order for it to kind of be
a a quote unquote living soil um system
okay so if someone were to use organic
inputs for example they add an organic
inputs throughout the growth cycle they
do that initial mending to begin of
course and then they add in uh microbial
inoculant for example would that be
considered a living soil system or do
they also need worms and they need to
use compost and where's like the line I
guess when it comes to True living soil
versus just growing organically with
Organic and you know what I mean
absolutely I think that's a really good
question and that's a that's a kind of a
hard distinction to make because there's
a lot of gray area on the lines outside
of these definitions so I think for me
personally and I've really struggled
hard with trying to not be an absolutist
in this in this game um because first
off that that can come across as um
holier than now or can come across as
like oh we know everything when really
we we just know what we've been doing
and we share my experience and I can't
say that my definition is the absolutes
definition but I think the most most
people in the living soil Community
would agree that um there's so many
different ways to to tackle fertility
and I don't poo poo on people who use um
organic amendments or even even organic
kind of soluble nutrients um as long as
you're still paying attention ption to
the soil biology and you're not doing
anything that's a detriment to the soil
biology you can still amend you can
still fol your feed with your plants you
can do all kinds of different things um
outside of just tending to soil putting
worms and using water only which happens
to be kind of my minimalist approach I
don't I don't use a lot of top dresses I
don't use anything like that um but when
other people do I don't say oh you're
not living soil you know uh as long as
they're as long as you if if worms can
live in your system and you're not
killing your worms then you've got a
living soil system to be frank they are
the they're like the canary and the coal
mine they will scram if anything's weird
they will scram they will not survive
and if you're if if what you're doing if
the variable that you're adding to your
system it it makes it to where you can't
have those that kind of life in your
system I would start to question whether
you have a living soil system thanks for
breaking that down for us I feel like
that's an area where just there's so
much confusion I agree though I think
that I think that that distinction needs
to be made because a lot of folks have
this really absolutist approach and um
this kind of All or Nothing approach
when it comes to regenerative
agriculture in general and it can be
off-putting to people who are trying to
get in who are trying to just trying to
understand the system and trying to
convert maybe ass salt system into a
living soil system it's nice to know
that you've got flexibility in leeway
with how to how to apply the these
techniques and still and still qualify
as a living soil system got it so how
does the overall health and productivity
of plants grown in living soil differ
from plants grown in other systems such
as synthetic nutrients in soil or
Hydroponics yeah that's another great
question I think you know with
Hydroponics and salt based systems you
get very rapid growth especially in the
vegetative stage of of certain plants so
that you'll get um very fast very fast
growth
and um if that's your only metric for
success or for plant Health then that
then that really kind of keeps people in
that you know in that system because
there's like oh my plants grow very fast
and they look very green and they're
beautiful and that's your only metric
then that tends to work but um in an
organic system you might get a little
your veg time might be a little lower
the but the overall health of your plant
is going to be the same or better uh
than a salt-based system and that's just
based on my experience I know plenty of
my friends and plenty of my very good uh
colleagues uh they grow using salt-based
nutrients they've just done it forever
and that's what they do and they got
their systems dialed and you know I'll
still smoke their material I've got many
friends that grow in with Sal based
nutrients and um I have no problem going
over to their house eating their fruits
and veggies
cuz I know that they're doing things
properly they're flushing things
properly and they're not
um they care about what they're putting
out they care about what their end
product is so once again I'm not an
absolutist in that sense where I just um
if people aren't growing in living soil
then I'm shaming them or or anything
like that because I think I think
there's plenty of room for everybody to
cultivate cultivate the way they're
comfortable I in my experience happened
to have experienced uh a greater degree
of success and a higher level of quality
um when going the organic route
understood yeah I think the debate is
going to be going on for many years from
now what's better living soil or growing
with synthetic inputs and uh you know
it's not something we're really going to
get deeper into in this episode I have
other episodes where we kind of get
deeper into the differences there but
yeah it was interesting to get your
thoughts on on the differences there
let's get into soil microbiology next I
want get deeper into that and how it
works in living soil are you able to
kind of break it down for us how
different microorganisms benefit plant
growth yeah absolutely I I'm I'm no Dr
elain um but I think I've got a pretty
good grasp I actually did her foundation
course and um I found it really really
beneficial for me to to connect some of
the dots uh as far as what I was
experience experiencing with plant
health and plant fertility and and so
the takeaway with the biology is once
again as I referenced the soil food web
earlier um if you just have bacteria in
your system which is everywhere I mean
bacteria is literally everywhere it's
out on if I remember right it's they're
they're finding bacteria that survive on
the outside of the Space Shuttle when it
goes into the vacuum of space and the
mariia trench at the really hot vents
there's just bacteria everywhere so
we're not really concerned about our
bacteria levels as long as there's not
bad bacteria but what we really want to
see and especially in row crops
vegetables medicinal plants those type
of things we really want a One toone
bacterial to fungal ratio so the hard
part for a lot of um soils and
agricultural soils is getting the
organic matter up to the level where you
can start to increase fungal diversity
and aerobic fungal diversity uh
specifically
and so you know if you have a system
where you have plenty of bacteria and
fungi you might be think that you've
you've made it but to be honest that
you're all of your nutrient that the
bacteria and fungi are mining from your
organic matter and hopefully you have
beautiful agricultural soils with lots
of organic matter um that's where the
bacteria and fungi mine the minerals and
nutrients that they in turn
exchange with the plants and a lot of
that nutrient and mineral can get locked
up in the living bodies of the bacteria
and fungi and so there needs to be a
predator a higher order predator in that
system that kind of facilitates their
demise so you really want the protozoa
in there
to get at the bacteria and fungi and
will now in turn release some of that
soluble nutrient um that's going to be
right kind of around the risos spere of
the plant so the plant Works in
conjunction with the biology to get what
it needs uh without getting too specific
and drilling down into some of the
specifics a byproduct of photosynthesis
in the plant creates carbohydrates the
plant is so intelligent it has the
ability to formulate that carbohydrate
from moment to moment and then at night
it sends it back down into the root Zone
and that those
exudates cover the root Zone and
depending on the formulation of the
exudate it attracts whatever biology
has the plant needs so the plant needs a
very specific micronutrient it will and
it it already knows that the the biology
that likes that micronutrient and has it
stored in its bodies likes this specific
configuration of carbohydrate it
attracts it to the root Zone and then
the soil food web does its thing and
everything is kind released in a soluble
plant ready form there at the rizosphere
so it's really important not just to
have bacteria and fungi but it's
important to have those uh the protozoa
as well to help release uh to help
release that uh that trapped nutrient
and mineral and then on the way up the
microarthropod and all those other
things those just work on your organic
matter and um they have waste products
that are beneficial to the system so you
know really just like you want to see in
nature you want to see a a a diverse
population of Life uh flourishing in
your system when you have that um then
you know uh you're kind of working in
accordance with nature and the way
plants work with soil is so supremely
designed it's it's
unbelievable how
amazingly uh Adept and and the plants
are at feeding themselves they do not
need our help they do not need us in
there um fidgeting around with things
for them as long as you have biology
organic matter moisture sun and a plant
it's going to do its thing you just have
to you just have to know and trust that
process um and that comes with
experience and just really just doing it
you mentioned protozoa and I feel like a
lot of folks will rely on micr products
in order to kind of enhance the
microbiology in their soil right and I
feel like a lot of these microducts
don't have protozoa in it would you Happ
to know why no I think though I think
because they're a larger uh a little bit
larger life form and a little more
fragile than the so say like a a
bacteria have a really good um ability
to to kind of preserve themselves if
they get into a dry or a hot or
undesirable condition a lot of them have
a ways just kind of like go into like a
suspended animation and then they'll
when the moisture content is correct
again they'll come back protozoa don't
really have that ability they're a
little more fragile I mean I think
amoeba will go into like a testate form
when they get shaken up um but I don't
think that they're very tolerant of
drought or anything like that so
um they kind of fragility uh lends to
them being um the kind of the first ones
to go when you have a systemic issue or
a crash or you've uh let your system dry
out um but the wonderful thing about
that is is that if you all you have to
do is get your system back in to balance
and get your organic matter right get
your moisture right protozoa will
arrive they'll just arrive and if you
have any kind of uh compost or Verma
compost there's tons of protozoa in in
fresh worm castings um if you do a
thermophilic compost there's going to be
tons of protozoa I've never seen the
Johnson Sue kind of bioreactor material
under a microscope but I've heard lots
of really good things about that
composting process so um there's ways to
just kind of reintroduce them into your
system um at at random intervals or at
set intervals to ensure that you're
you're kind of keeping your protozoa uh
and your bacterial to fungal po
populations correct that's interesting I
don't know if a lot of people know about
that so yeah if you're adding in worm
castings you're adding in protozoa as
well so that's really good to know now
how about micr products you know we kind
of talked about that a bit a lot of
people do rely on micro products to
inoculate the medium with microbes
however the diversity there is pretty
limited right now you could go out and
do the IMO process and get more
diversity can you kind of talk to us
about the difference between inoculating
with a micr product versus the IMO
process maybe some of the pros and cons
to both of them yeah sure so look I
think there's a lot there's a lot of
kind of what what are lovingly referred
to as bugs in a jug products out there
and
um my very basic kind of rudimentary
understanding of this I'm not going to
pretend to be um the the expert in this
but but my basic General understanding
is is that you do better in your
cultivation system if you can gather um
those microbes kind of regionally uh
otherwise you're you're very limited
like you said to a very specific um type
of biology and sometimes they might not
be suited for your region and so what
you end up doing is you just end up
applying a bunch of biology to your
system that just ends up being food for
your native biology um which causes a
which causes a bloom in biology and
you're like oh wow the product worked
great and you know maybe it did May
maybe if that's one of the functions of
those products then that that still
technically Works maybe just not in the
same modality that people are thinking
when they're applying it um and there
also you know based off of this the the
schooling that the stuff that I learned
at the soil food web school was a lot of
those bugs and The Jug recipes have um
like some kind of acid in there to to
stabilize it to make it shelf stable and
that can have a negative impact on your
native biology as well so I've always
just tried to avoid um those products in
and work to cultivate
that biology on my own property or in my
own region once again via Thermo Thermo
composting I've never done IMO
collection I I know lots of people who
do lots of people who are really have
found great success you taking bits and
pieces of the k&amp;f practices and applying
them to their system and I think
obviously one of the most successful
things that you can do outside of like
fpj's and stuff is that that IMO
collection technique is really stellar
and I really I'm really intrigued by
that process and I really like to see
people follow through with it I've just
I've never done it I've focused more on
the vermac composting side and the ther
thermophilic composting side to make the
the biocomplete compost and I've just
had great success with that and just
felt like um if I'm getting the biology
into my system this way I just really
didn't need to to to venture into that
other uh technique that being said I
encourage people to try as many of these
techniques and find out which one
scratches your itches you know which one
feels good you know lots of people are a
type and they like to be busy and they
like to do things and feel like they're
participating I'm more of a hands off I
like to just kind of set it and forget
it I don't like to spend hours in my
grow I like to just go in and look at it
like things are great see you later I'm
going to apply compost to my to my beds
twice a year or maybe even just once a
year and just kind of leave it at that
and don't fuss over things but if
there's people who are like super a type
I encourage them to check those things
out try the things you know build the
cedar box take it out to the woods do do
all those things and uh and I'm sure
it'll feel great and you'll get great
results I'm just like you I haven't had
the chance to do the IMO process I've
just like you been focusing on vermac
composting and cool I I think a lot of
people are under the you know have the
misconception that if you're not doing
the IMO process then you're not doing it
right and I think that's just the wrong
way to think about things I think there
are other ways to get to the Finish Line
like you mentioned the verac composting
that's another way where you can create
biology get biology maintain it take it
from your vermac compost system and then
put it into your garden whether it be an
outdoor Garden or indoor garden with
grow pots or containers there are
multiple ways to get to that goal of
increasing the microbial population in
the medium so yeah that's uh some really
good info that you shared with us right
there and I'm glad you expanded on it
and and mentioned it in that way let's
get into building soil from scratch you
know a lot of folks that are just
getting started and they want to start
off with a living soil what's your
recommendations what should people use
for materials in order to start to build
their own living soil you know I think
there's there's a couple ways that you
can tackle this you could build your own
um and and that's I highly recommend
people Venture into doing that it really
gets you more connected to your system
and and get you more uh um familiar with
sourcing the ingredients and
understanding how difficult that could
be sometimes or you can go through a
company like um keep it simple or any of
these other uh build a soil that have
these really great kind of Custom Blends
and most of those are based off of the
Coots recipe I don't know if many of
your Growers would be familiar with
Clackamus cot or many of your viewers be
familiar with Clackamus cot he's been a
little uh a little less vocal on social
media over the past five years or so but
early on around the time I first started
come on his soil Blend or soil recipe um
had become very very popularized and
most um living soil Blends you're going
to find here in the states are are going
to be basically A variation of of the
Coots recipe um and that's it's changed
it's changed a little bit over the years
and some people like Mountain Organics
have have really kind of tweaked it and
um you know it's a one3 compost uh one3
like p uh uh Iration and oneir Pete or
cocoa I think a lot of people are still
using Pete I've never done cocoa in a
living soil blend I think I think
there's some unique differences there um
and then that being your base you add
your nutrients and minerals and that's
where things get um interesting because
people people take that recipe and do
all kinds of things with it some people
just use like Mountain Organics for a
while was just using glacial Rock Dust
at like four cups per cubic foot of uh
base and was doing great with that like
was just doing amazing so I think you
know you could use that you can look at
that cot's base and then just add kind
of mess with it and add things if you
got a crustation mix you can add you've
got you know kelp all these different
all these different things that you can
add to it and you're going to have some
fun and get get acquainted with um
putting those systems together is really
good and beneficial for your cultivation
Journey um if you don't have time or
patience for those things like I said
just getting into a reputable company
that's been producing um soil for living
soil cultivators for years um uh
literally a decade or more some of these
companies and and you can't go wrong
it's it's it's hard to go wrong so with
any living soil recipe
most of the time nutrients are going to
deplete right so unless it's quote a
super soil to where it's a water only
recipe for example of course it's going
to depend on how long you veg the plants
for but some of them you can just do an
initial mending and then you just water
only for the rest of the cycle other
recipes which are a majority of the
recipes the nutrients are going to
deplete at some point for those recipes
What organic inputs do you typically add
in throughout the growth cycle and when
do you add them in yeah this is this
tends to be a very uh hotly debated
topic amongst um agronomists and um and
especially large scale agriculturists
and hor culturists um I have a differing
opinion so there's two uh trains of
thought when it comes to fertility and
available nutrients and just to kind of
briefly describe the two different camps
well I me there of three but there's one
that's in the middle
so the the far far off to one side I
don't want to say right or left but far
off to one side is the uh Dr Elaine Camp
which I tend to be in and that camp is
you know and that's based off of what
I've learned in um going through her
foundation course material and then also
how that
information uh laid over my experience
and really helped connect a lot of dots
and so according to Dr
Elaine as long as you have adequate
biology once again diversity and
quantities um and aerobic and you have
adequate organic matter that biology
will be able to mine whatever nutrient
whatever mineral that that crop needs
whether it's corn potatoes medicinal
plants Tomatoes herbs any of that her
body of work has led her to the
conclusion
that all nutrient needs for all plants
can be met entirely and
completely with Biology and organic
matter and so if you go by that then
really all you need to do is keep track
of your biology make sure that your
biology is flourishing and make sure
you've got plenty of organic matter and
if you follow those two rules you'll be
able to continuously crop without ever
really to
amend she goes as far to say you don't
even need to get a chemistry analysis
now when I when I say these words I can
see the Peds exploding in your
viewership right now because there's
lots of people who are going to say
hogwash and they're going to fish at
that and I get it I totally understand
for me personally
I started not understanding the soil
food web web but just kind of trusting
the process and really wanting to see
how little I could do how minimum how
many variables can I exclude from my
system and still pull off a viable crop
not just a viable
but better than average right and I was
experiencing that for years once again
you can go back back into my YouTube and
look at my first six
cycles first eight cycles and I I talk
about these very things I have not in
the over 10 years I've had my beds and
the soil that I've had now I've never
done one chemistry analysis on my soil
and my yield numbers are the same from
day one from 10 years ago they're the
same and so and all I've been doing for
the past about 5 years is just adding
compost or Verma compost or some kind of
compost
extract to my system to maintain biology
because I know myem has plenty of
organic matter so you can you can take
that kind of ultra extremist biological
approach to cultivation and you'll be
just fine I'm a testament to that um I
we've set up uh uh commercial
cultivation facilities with the same
ideology and they do great they do
amazing we've done large scale outdoor
um
fiber and hemp crops that we've put
nutrient Blends in half of the acreage
and then left the other half of the
acreage with without any whatsoever just
water and native soil which was woefully
inadequate organic matter and they
produced the same the yields were the
same in one half of the field to the
other and we were adding it was costing
$550 an acre to add that nutrient so
over 100 acres you know
$55,000 that was not needed at all we
could have used that $55,000 anywhere
else the other half of the acreage that
we didn't put the nutrient mix on did
exactly the same that you could not tell
the difference one one field to the next
one row to the next so that to me was
spoke volumes about the power of biology
and the power of this soil food web now
that being
said that doesn't that doesn't do it
some folks there's a lot of folks that
are so tied into the the chemistry part
of it that they have to know the
chemistry and so that's the other side
is the people that completely ignore
biology and only focus on chemistry and
you find that those are the people that
are using the salt-based chemical
fertilizers and pesticides and all those
other things they live in that camp and
somewhere in the middle is a guy named
John Kemp and and he's his company is
advancing ecological agriculture they're
huge they're gigantic he firmly believes
in the biological portion he's actually
been on podcast with Dr Lane they've had
some really interesting conversations
about about about the way there two
different takes on this
he is not ready to just drink the
Kool-Aid and go 100% biology even though
he knows that the biology supersedes
the chemistry in any kind of cultivation
system biology will always supersede
chemistry and so what he's done with a
lot of conventional a big conventional
AG guys is that he's come to the table
and said hey look let's focus on biology
and then let's watch what happens to our
chemistry and so he's
utilizing the data that conventional
Farmers have relied on for generations
and for decades right this this this
this chemistry data
and exposing them to the biological data
and saying hey look what happens when we
marry these two look at the changes that
take place and he's done a really good
job at convincing
Farmers that one they can remove certain
things from their system because it's
the the it it's not beneficial you know
the the the the biology is not present
to process the the raw amendments that
you're putting down you're just leaving
money on the table or you're L literally
letting it Blow Away In The Wind and so
he's combining these two uh
methodologies to really bring
conventional a into the fold and then
where he differs from Dr Lane is that he
says hey look yeah you can the natural
Order Drive cultivation and drive
fertility but if you're producing a cash
crop and you were trying to maximize you
can drive that in an organic way
while still keeping in mind what's
happening with your biology and not
doing
anything that's going to have negative
impact on that so over the years where
I've went from this very hardcore doct
Elaine curist you know wouldn't even
tell a client to get a soil test or
anything now I kind of understand the
John km ideology where it's really you
know like like let's let's leverage the
data that that most people are relying
on they really want to see that
chemistry data and let's just kind of
use that to kind of prove the concept of
what's happening and then you can drive
your crop you can drive your crop I know
Steve kwell good live productions they
they do uhry analysis but they're still
very heavily biologically focused and um
one of my colleagues M Davenport with
the ma designs he's uh very much the
same way I think he had his hand he had
a hand in in designing um
GOP and um and so I've really kind of
eased off of that that hardcore purist
not when it comes to my personal grow my
personal grow I'm still very hardcore I
I still don't do chemistry analysis I
still don't top feed or top dress
anything that I think I might be missing
I just focus on my biology my crops are
great my yields are great I'm happy
camper um that just doesn't cut it for
other folks so if I work with somebody
on a personal basis or so I'm working
with a client that has a commercial
growth I'll introduce this kind of John
km or or kind of a Matt Davenport or
Steve kwells kind of a ideology where
hey look let's take a peek at the
chemistry let's see where we're at and
let's just make sure that we're at those
numbers because that makes everybody
feel happy and so I'm not opposed to
that so I don't have a lot of experience
kind of a long way around to answering
your question I don't have a lot of
experience with adding amendments to
systems because I've just been mainly
focused on biological driven fertility
systems and I have no interest in you
know pushing my crop to yield 15% more
um by tweaking certain numbers um not
that it can't be done just have no
interest in it and and and I've had
really a great level of success just
kind of being on that other e uh extreme
end um but that being said there's lots
of data and information and and podcasts
that people can Digest like I highly
recommend John km anything that he's got
is just really I've learned so much um
from his material uh that um it can
scratch that itch once again if you're
the a type that really likes to be in
charge and really likes to know
everything that's going on um there's a
methodology and a template for you to
achieve that I think it might be a bit
eye openening for some of the viewers
here some of the listeners here when we
talk about some of these prominent
figures such as Dr laningham versus
versus John Kemp who they've got
different insight and different data and
different ways to go about it a lot of
people reference Dr Bruce bugby and they
say he's the end all be all what he says
goes and and everybody else is wrong you
know but there are a lot of scientists
out there that disagree with his ways to
go about it right next topic we're going
to get into here but I I just have a
followup question for you but the next
topic when we get into teas there's
actually some pretty big disagreement in
regards to some high level scientists
who disagree whether or not you should
do teas sure but before we get into te's
you mentioned you do compost only right
can you give us some insight in just
like how much compost and how often you
apply it yeah so with my uh with my
methodology it it tends to be once again
frustrating to the a types because I'm
just really run uh very
intuitively um I'm fortunate enough to
have a very wellestablished
beds um before I moved to my new
location my current location about a
year year and a half ago the beds that I
had were in 3 4X 8 by 1s and they were
like 8 years old so very established
beds just I could put anything in them
and it would just flourish it wouldn't
have to really do anything as long as
the moisture levels are on point
everything was great I moved into my new
uh place and I had to add about two and
a half yards of new soil to the new beds
that I built so I've kind of got like a
layered system where my upper part of my
bed is the newer soil and the lower
lower part is that older aged soil so I
really have this benefit of having a
large Storehouse of organic matter and
biological activity deep in my beds so I
could I really feel like I could go
quite a while without ever having to
amend um because look if if if you're
cultivating in your system and it's not
just sitting there um uh uh not doing
anything uh
then that cultiv
process with mulching and living if you
got if you got companion plants or or or
cover crops going all of that is
contributing to New Life in your system
and sustaining the life that's there so
you could theoretically build a living
soil system and never really add compost
ever as long as you're cultivating the
system I mean out in nature in the
forest there's nobody out there
spreading compost around it just is kind
of cre that that natural hum natural
humic
is just there it's developed over time
and you can build that same type of
system um with your system and just kind
of allowing the natural process to build
over time you don't have major dry out
events or major flooding events or any
of those things those will be setbacks
but eventually your system would build
back up so what I do is I just kind of
once or twice a year add compost to my
soil um I do have a microscope scope I
do take periodic um microscopy readings
just to kind of analyze make sure
everything's good but you know after
doing so many slides you really just
kind of know when your soil's on point
if I ended up getting having an
overwatering event and I felt like I had
an anerobic pocket I would I would try
to analyze and make sure I didn't have
any pathogenic fungi or any of the bad
um bad biology present in the system
that could have a leous effect um but
really that's just that's frankly that's
never happened so I've I've stopped
using the microscope almost entirely I I
still think it's a valuable tool um but
I've built compost so much and I've and
I've my system is so stable that I just
I know when I have good compost and I
know when my system is good and I just
kind of
intuitively uh amend a lot of people
aren't going to like
that yeah I think a lot of people
process is that you're growing a plant
and then you're removing that biomass
and all the you know as the plant's
growing obviously the nutrients being
uptaken by the plant so when you remove
that biomass you're removing the
nutrients from the system so that's when
adding in more inputs is you know
requirement really for for the most part
it's not like the the out in the forest
where nobody touches and stuff well the
leaves are falling down right and then
they break it down but everything's kind
of being recycled within the same area
but when you're removing that biomass I
think that that's a concern for a lot of
people yeah it really is and I think
that's where um trying to wrap your head
around and having a deeper understanding
of kind of the Dr Elaine ideology where
look you don't need to worry about what
the plant is taking out of the system
because it'll be just be replenished
like she had lots of in that course I
took there was lots of graphs and
information and data where they took
organic matter and extracted it and and
calculated how much nitrogen was
available and just kind of basic organic
matter that you would find in soils and
it far
exceeded the AAL of nitrogen that was
available in to be mined not plant ready
or available but available to be mined
by biology was like four times the needs
of some of your most nitrogen hungry
crops like corn that like like quite
literally there is so much nutrient in
Mineral now of course if you're in a
sandy desert you know that that and
you're dealing with a very heavy sand
soil that's going to have a that's going
to play a factor and I think that's
where John km comes in and is like hey
look not every agricultural soil this is
going to work with but you know given
enough time and enough organic matter
you could convert that sandy soil into
really good tith and find yourself in a
situation where you have actually superb
uh uh superb organic matter content and
and thusly nutrient cycling capability
so that's a tough pill for a lot of
folks to swallow when you tell somebody
that they could get all the nutrients
they need out of the organic matter in
your dirt and biology they just don't
they don't buy it I challenge folks to
kind of step out of this absolutist
approach and just look into it maybe try
it maybe try growing without amending
your soil uh every six months or just
see what happens if you think that
you've gotten to the point where you're
low run a cycle run a cycle see where
your yields and where your numbers are
at um and and
my guess is that you're going to find
that there's going to be a negligible
difference between the two so negligible
that any number of variable could have
contributed to whatever difference
you're seeing so um yeah I I hold hard
and stand hard and fast uh to that to
that fact that you can literally get
whatever you need in
perpetuity as long as you're cultivating
in that system as long as you've got
adequate organic matter and biology
uh your plants will be able to mine
exactly what they need precisely what
they need awesome yeah you mentioned Dr
lingham's course and I've been wanting
to take that for several years now it's
just so hard to find the time you know
I've got a daughter now and so all my
time is occupied by her and uh but
eventually it's on my list of of uh
courses to tackle there's so many good
courses out there and so many great
teachers out there but she's definitely
that course in particular I think she
has a couple different courses I
definitely want to go through at least
one of them here in the upcoming years
yeah highly recommended Foundation
course material was a real eye opener
for me let's get into Brewing teas now
this is an area like I mentioned people
are split upon right so you've got
different te's first off you know you've
got everything from nutrient te's manure
te's you've got te's that focus on
increasing the microbiology but you have
folks that Brew the te's and say it's
great successful it's very beneficial
but you've got other there's one
scientist particular I can't remember
her name but she had mentioned they're
completely pointless nobody should be
Brewing teas adding compost and then
watering in that compost is just as
beneficial what's your take on Brewing
teas yeah no is definitely a Hot Topic I
think um folks are not going to be
surprised that my my concept of of tea
application I think I think first off I
think there there needs to be a an
important distinction that needs to be
made uh between um what's commonly
referred to as a tea
and what should be uh uh classified as
an
extract and so Al what an extract is
just basically simply what the name
states it is you're basically just
extracting biology from a medium whether
it's vermac compost or or thermophilic
compost you you're you're putting um
some of your highquality biocomplete
compost that has all the protozoa and
protozoa and necessary fungi and
bacteria in there and it's all attached
basically glued and stuck to the organic
matter in your
compost you put that into like a 220 bag
or paint bag or whatever your uh your um
your bubble bag reused old Bubble Bag
220 thing and we would use that to
dunk the just dunk gently dunk the uh
compost in and out of kind of room
temperature water and slowly agitating
and knocking off the the biology from
the organic matter and then suspending
it into the liquid Matrix right so now
you've got you've got this liquid that's
just full of floating biology and um
that's a really great way to introduce
concentrated biology because you could
use three or four cups dunk it into a 5
gallon bucket for a minute or 90 seconds
two minutes and then get another one a
fresh load it's like putting two tea
bags of Earl gry in your morning tea
you're going to get a St a stiff cup of
tea um you or stiff extract we should
say so you know by doing that you could
really kind of control the the the
concentration of biology in whatever
your whatever you're suspending and the
water you're suspending it in and so
what the benefit of that is is that when
you water that in it it really travels
with the water penetrates deep into the
root Zone where you really want that
biology to reside um very few variables
considering your compost was properly
made you've properly analyzed it you
know you don't have bad guys in there
it's not Anor robic or any of those
other things and you're not basically
just adding concentrated Anor robes to
your system assuming that all of those
factors have been met and you've got a
really great Stellar product you're just
going to be adding those concentrated
microbes directly to the root Zone where
they belong and that's the safest way
with the fewest variables to introduce
biology into your
system now a t what people call te some
people would call the extract a tea I
think we should get away from that I
think we should we should call an
extract an extract and we should call
anything that we actively Brew anything
that we're brewing for 4 hours 12 hours
36 hours 72 hours there's all kinds of
recipes and this is I think where some
people have
issue and and and I'll say that there is
a time in place for a brooded compost
tea and I think that and this is what I
learned taking Dr Elaine's course I
don't want to sound like a one trick
pony or just tooting one horn the whole
time but it she really like lays things
out in in a in a great way when you
brew a tea usually you're adding a food
source it's highly oxygenated and so
what's happening is when you add a food
source and lots of oxygen that biology
is going to multiply and it's going to
breed I think biology uh bacterial
colonies they double every 20 minutes so
there's an exponential growth rate that
takes place when you're when you're
brewing a te
and and it's this process that if you do
it right you can leverage it in your
favor if you don't do it right you can
be doing nothing at all or you could
actually be causing harm to your system
compounding harm to your system over
time and I'll and I'll I'll uh I'll
explain I'll um a little better so an
extract great for the root Zone the the
the the biology is just suspended in the
water flows out the water colonizes the
root Zone gets back onto organic matter
in the soil starts doing its business
let's say you brew a tea that doubling
that multiplication process the biology
just getting busy in there doing their
thing creates a very sticky glomulin
kind of gluey type substance and you can
use that to your benefit by only
applying that as a foler cuz now what
happens is you've got all of that
biology encased in a slimy sticky glue
and when you spray it onto the surface
of a plant or onto the onto the the
trunk of a plant that water is carrying
that sticky substance boom it slaps onto
the leaf and then the water falls off
and leaves the biology behind on the
surface of the leaf and so now you've
got active biology ready to populate the
entire surface of your plant and
literally create a castle wall a
microscopic wall of biology that covers
all of your plant so when outside spores
land on the plant and try to hook in and
do its thing there's there's nowhere for
it to go it's literally landing on
something else right that's landing on
that biological film that's taking place
if you inversely if you take that sticky
glue e substance and you try to water it
into the soil it's all going to get
stuck at the top layer of your soil and
it's not going to penetrate down deep so
taking an actively brewed tea and
applying it to your root
Zone I don't know if it's been
Quantified you know like how much is not
making it down to the bottom but the
vast majority of it going to get trapped
at that upper layer and that upper layer
is the most volatile that upper layer is
the layer that dries out first and when
it dries out the biology dies the amoeba
go into testate form and then eventually
they die if the moisture doesn't get
back up back up so you're really you've
taken all this time to create a te and
what you're trying to accomplish is
being reduced by 80% or even if it's 30%
reduction in what's being delivered to
the system you kind of have to like
weigh things out like is this even worth
it so if you can think of T's as a folio
application and extracts as a root Zone
application you're going to eliminate a
lot of variables that could lend itself
to undesirable results or just kind of
results that are me you know so I think
if you follow those two rules you'll be
really you'll be fine now with the
Brewing aspect of it if you're brewing a
tea without the aid of of microscopy
you're really just rolling the dice um
what happens is when you've got biology
in there and they're reproducing at this
exponential rate they will eventually
and in very short order use up all of
the available oxygen it doesn't matter
how big of an air pump you've got
pumping into your 200 gallons of water
or whatever you'll eventually reach a
Tipping Point of bi of of biological
population that they simply have used
all the oxygen available you you can't
add enough oxygen when it reaches a
certain point now at that point you have
an anerobic brew and all of that good
biology that you had bloomed or grew
over 12 hours or 24 hours is now
starting to die because there's not
enough oxygen and they're being replaced
by Anor
robes there's this window when this is
happening that you're not going to be
able to tell with your old factory
senses that you've gone anerobic now
obviously you let it go long enough it's
going to smell like sewage you're be
like I'm anerobic
but there's going to be a period where
it's going to smell earthy it's going to
smell okay you're be like oh man I can
drink this you know like this is great
but it's not great because now you've
started you because oxygen has been
depleted now you've got now you've
created an environment where Anor robes
Thrive and that's where all your harble
pathogenic things uh reside so I
understand where people are like uh
don't don't Brew you know don't Brew
teas because you you know once again if
you're not visually seeing what's
happening in there you are literally
rolling the dice if your Source material
was full of anoes and you're and that's
what you're using you're just breeding
more Anor robes like you really could be
causing yourself more problems in your
system or just not doing anything at all
and just wasting time and money which
time is the most precious thing that I
have and I hate wasting it and so um I
basically stick to straight extracts I
don't even really do tease for folar
applications I've just really never felt
that necessary now if I had an orchard
and um there was all kinds of uh fungal
threats to my Orchard and uh and regular
folar applications made more sense then
I'd be doing that but the kind of crops
that I that I'm involved with just just
don't have that kind of pressure so I'm
more uh concerned with making sure that
my soil soil is healthy and the soil
biology is active and then whatever
foliar I do are strictly for a nutrient
or exudate
enrichment uh tactics or strategies so
would you say that it's impossible to
answer the question when somebody says
how long brewing tea is too
long yeah because I mean there's so many
different variables as to like what what
what your starting material was like
what's the temperature where you're
Brewing it are you temp Brewing it in a
uh pole barn you know in in February in
the northeast or you know are you doing
it in 110 degree weather you know out
the sun beating down on it there so
there's going to be so many different
variables it's really hard to say and
and the best most responsible answer is
when you can just have it analyzed
there's plenty of soil food web Labs
that will analyze your material um
they'll analyze what you've got and let
you know whether you've got good guys or
bad guys or at safe to use look if
you've got a a a cash crop um even if
it's just your hobby hobby situation you
know 80 bucks for a test is not the end
of the world as far as I'm concerned to
to get that peace of mind and and know
where you reside and on the flip side of
that too like you know learning how to
use the microscope and identify the
constituents of of what you want to find
in there would be well worth it as well
it's not hard I'm not a brilliant person
I was able to learn the things and able
to apply them in in a way that was
effective and and created um a a nice uh
level of understanding that provided
comfort in what I was doing and not just
kind of doing things willy-nilly which
is fine proofs in the pudding but at at
some level I wanted to know why it was
working and how it was working and the
microscope really just aided in seeing
uh what was happening uh at this level
that we can't see I had a feeling you
were going to say that there was too
many variables in order to answer the
question on the time length there less
is more just do four hours four 6 hours
you're going to get plenty of
reproduction in that amount of time
obviously the longer you go the longer
chance you have of depleting your oxygen
and obviously the smaller vessel you're
brewing in if you're brewing in a five
gallon uh bucket for 72 hours you do not
have an aerobic mix at the end of that I
I I I I'm pretty confident in saying
that that you know you're you're
definitely going to be tipping the
scales into the Anor robic you know and
so less is more if you could do a 4our
brew and that makes you feel better and
you're good do it because there's every
20 minutes the microbial population the
bacterial population doubles every 20
minutes so 12 hours is a long time when
you've got this exponential growth and
certainly 72 good to know man what a
conversation we have reached the hour
mark here and uh man there's a lot more
we could have got into and this episode
but I think we might have to get you
back on another episode if you're
willing to come back on in the future
here at some point I'd be thrilled that
would be awesome yeah we can get in
things such as like cover crops
companion planting mulch layers there's
managing Pest and diseases in an
allnatural way there's so many different
things that we can get into that relate
to living soil so I'd love to have you
on for a part two but let's wrap things
up here can you tell listeners how they
can find you and what you have upcoming
in the future Yeah so basically you can
really just find me on Instagram um just
use my name I don't use a handle so it's
just Joshua C steensland on Instagram I
do have a YouTube channel with a lot of
like that older material it's still
valuable a lot of that there's a few
things that have changed in the living
soil Community since then but nothing
that was that's major enough to to
invalidate the system so by all means go
back watch some of those earlier some no
till live stream talks they're about 8
years old now so there's there's some
good information there and um like I
said you can reach me on Instagram I'm
pretty much not doing much these days
corporate wise I've really just kind of
taken a taken the chance to relax and
kind of work on this property that we
just acquired a year and a half ago um
so but I'm always open to answer
questions anybody has any questions just
DM me it might take me a day or two but
I typically get back to everybody sweet
well I'll definitely have a link to
Joshua's Instagram and maybe YouTube
channel down in the YouTube description
section below so you can easily get to
him and give him a follow or a
subscription big shout out to all the
patreon folks
patreon.com grow 100% of what is donated
there goes right back into the podcast
everything from the editor fee to the
fee for the editing software to the fee
to the virtual Studio that we use to
record these podcasts thank you for your
contributions you are really what keep
this podcast going and I'm going to
scroll on the screen right now the
contributors that are in the producer
tier so different tiers that you can
join with get early access to these
episodes before they're posted or you
get producer credits or even merch or my
book so they're different tiers check
that out if you get a chance and yeah
just want to say thank you so much
Joshua once again for coming on to the
podcast great great episode looking
forward to a part two some point in the
future and hope you enjoy the rest of
your day thank you you as well it was my
pleasure peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode