coming up on Garden talk it's just
basically touching the top of the soil
and what that will do is that will
incorporate all those amendments it'll
get rid of all those weed seeds that
have germinated and it also will allow
us to have soil contact with our Korean
natural farming input the soil Health
that we have on the farm indigenous
microorganisms or IMO is our very best
friend people are buying all these
bottles of microbes we call them bugs in
a jug and that's great but it's very
limited diversity out in nature you can
pick up a teaspoon of soil and within
that teaspoon of soil there are
literally thousands of different species
of microbiology Korean natural farming
has that microbiology diversity that
diversity of soil biology allows those
plants to uptake nutrients that are
harder to get normally that allows it
for it to be a stronger healthier plant
foreign
Talk podcast this episode number 90. in
this episode I interview Wendy kornberg
of sun Abyss she has been gardening all
her life and is a licensed cultivator in
Humboldt County she does low-till
farming and also a lot of natural
farming techniques she talks about
low-till farming and how it differs from
no-till farming as well as other
techniques that she does on her Farm if
you gain value from these podcast
episodes please click the Thumbs Up And
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already that way you can be notified
when new episodes are released if you'd
like to support even more visit
patreon.com Mr Grow it there are various
rewards set up for those of you who
support and you could pledge any amount
that you'd like 100 of the money that
gets pledged through patreon goes right
back into the podcast it really helps
the podcast keep going so thank you so
much to those of you who support before
we get into it I want to acknowledge
that one of my goals for this podcast is
to provide free information about
gardening all plants to the general
public that being said I like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
grow strong Industries for sponsoring
this episode they have Gorilla grow
tents which I've used for many years
they are well known for their thickness
durability and height adjusting roof
they also sell super closet products
which consist of grow boxes grow
cabinets grow tank kits and hydroponic
systems to see their products in action
check out their first ever grow strong
grow off go to their website grow
strongindustries.com linked below and
use the discount code Mr Grow it for 15
off AC Infinity is sponsoring this
episode my entire ventilation system is
AC Infinity I have their inline fan
ducting and carbon filter I love the
controller with the temperature and
humidity programming and having control
of different fan speeds this makes it so
much easier to control my grow
environment and I can't wait for the
controller 69 Wi-Fi version which also
controls their oscillating fans and grow
lights you can use discount code Mr Grow
it for any of their products on their
website AC infinity.com or use discount
code Mr Grow at 15. if you're buying off
Amazon
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Wendy kornberg of sun Abyss how you
doing today doing good how are you doing
I'm doing good thanks for asking today
we're going to get into low till farming
a lot of people have heard of no-till
farming low till something kind of new
here right seems like more and more
Growers are going towards no-till but
low till something you're going to give
us the rundown on because you have
experience on it and so in this episode
I like to get into kind of what you do
in your garden on your farm but first
what I want to do which I do with all
guests is an introduction so can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening yeah my name
is Wendy kornberg and I run sunnibus
Humboldt's full sun Farms we are a small
family farm that grows mostly medicinal
plants on the banks of the Eel River in
southern Humboldt County in California
and I basically grew up gardening I I
don't really remember a time in my life
that I haven't had something growing I
did find when I went to college and
lived in an apartment for a while that
I'm not the best at growing uh plants
like house plants I managed to kill a
fern I managed to kill a ficus it's like
the plants that you're you know
supposedly not able to kill and then I
got orchids and found out that those
work very well for me because I think I
was killing them literally with kindness
I was paying too much attention to the
plants and orchids are supposed to die
after they bloom or so I was told so I
had bought some and just like they
bloomed they're beautiful and then I
ignored them and they didn't die and I
went oh maybe this is my key but yeah
other than that basically my family
growing up my mother had about a one
acre Garden including Orchard trees and
some grapevines and things like that so
that was always what I considered you
know a garden is a decent amount of
square footage and that was all
substance food for our family for the
winter so my mom would grow a lot of
tomatoes and you know do a bunch of
canning of spaghetti sauce and tomato
sauces and things like that we often
dried fruit so we would have like dried
apples and things for through the winter
potatoes you know we had a root cellar
so potatoes onions like all that stuff
canned peaches basically you name it we
we would try and grow it and figure out
how to save it over the winter awesome
so gardening all your life lots and lots
of experience so 18 years of gardening
right that's that's all your life yeah
yeah eight it's 20 now you know I didn't
Garden when I was two but yeah yeah
so no-till gardening a lot of people
know what that is but I have a lot of
beginners on that listen to this podcast
all the beginners and intermediate so
some people that might not know what
no-till is can you talk to us about what
no-till is and also what low till is and
kind of the differences between the two
yeah
yeah to preface
would wait for my dad to get the huge
BCS rototiller that was always kind of
on its last legs and oh I just I
remember as a kid it was so loud so she
would spread a lot of chicken manure and
some other soil amendments
um I think we usually use oyster shell a
little bit of green sand maybe some
calfas or sauce or something along those
lines and then my dad would come through
with the BCS and just you know till
through all the beds multiple passes and
my mom would plant and that was the the
kind of the way that I learned how to
garden
um but as I started gardening and
farming on my own I quickly realized
that like tillage is actually
a I didn't have a rototiller so I had to
rent one they're expensive where I live
um they're loud they're obnoxious I'm
five foot two and weighed at the time
when I started about a you know 120
pounds so trying to mangle one of those
beasts into doing what I wanted it to do
was always a challenge
um so we started looking into no-till
which means you literally do not till
the soil and in a lot of ways it's
really really great we also utilize
Korean natural farming which benefits
from no-till the problem we came into
over and over again is that
um number one if you let your soil lay
fallow or get bare at any point in time
where you're not cultivating crops on it
our soil gets very hard and compact very
quickly the rain will literally pound
the soil into like a cement brick and at
that point in order to break that up
again you can do things like broad
forking which is basically a big huge
like imagine a giant 4 work that you
pound into the ground and then you lean
back until your soil cracks open and
it's a way to protect the microbiology
and protect your soil but unfortunately
I again this soil would be so hard I
literally couldn't even get a broad Fork
into it I'd be jumping up and down on it
and falling over and it just wasn't
wasn't working for us
um so that is an option that is a
no-till situation you can do no-till
lasagna bed methods which is really cool
as well if you've got a small square
footage so you can utilize cardboard
which Smothers the weeds it suppresses
any weed germination okay and then you
can put compost and soil and things on
top of that and then Mulch on top of
that and you can plant in that and it's
a great way to Garden I've done that in
small scale so you know utilizing maybe
a
what I guess those beds are three feet
by 20 feet I could do that easily on my
own but it does take a lot of cardboard
it does take some time and energy and
inevitably because I live out in the
country we have weed seeds that are
constantly blowing back in so I'd have
to redo it basically every year to
smother those weeds out so that wasn't
working very well for us cover crop is
great to try and suppress the weeds but
inevitably you know our our farm is
um eighteen thousand square feet of
medicinal plants as well as another 2
000 currently for vegetable crops just
on the farm itself we'll be expanding
that out we were trying to expand it
this year but we just didn't have the
time and Manpower
um so you know looking at basically a
half an acre to three quarters of an
acre hopefully up to an acre by next
year of total cultivated square footage
but that's run by myself my fiance James
and my mom who is 73 years old and we
have 5 kids
so it's a lot to work with just a very
very small amount of people we've
definitely been trying to get people on
board we have a lot of people that come
and volunteer for a few days here and
there but when you hit those crunch
times of it's time to get the soil
prepped and it's time to get planted we
quickly find that we usually run out of
time so what we've turned to that works
for us is a low till situation so
generally when you're using a tiller
what you're doing is you're actually
cultivating the soil you're turning it
and you're grinding it up and you're
doing that at some pretty deep levels
most tillage recommends like 12 to 18
inches if not deeper that way you get a
really good bed of really soft soil that
your plants don't have to work to get
their Roots through
the problem with this is all the
microbiology that exists in that soil
and hopefully you're working with soil
and not dead dirt so hopefully you have
a lot of biology in there it gets turned
up to the surface and it gets mangled
and pulverized and what ends up
happening is it dies and as that
microbiology dies number one you're
losing diversity of microbiology in your
soil which means that you're losing
plant Health inevitably or you're having
to replace it
um a lot of times people are buying all
these bottles of microbes we call them
bugs in a jug
um and that's great but it's very
limited diversity out in nature you can
pick up a teaspoon of soil and within
that teaspoon of soil there are
literally thousands of different species
of microbiology the best jugs I've come
across have between 20 and 40 species
it's just it's not the same thing at all
so if you've tilled appropriately you've
turned all your microbiology up to the
surface they've died back and the real
detriment to this is they have now
actually created carbon dioxide so a lot
of the carbon dioxide that we deal with
nowadays is not coming from driving or
flying or producing tires or things like
that a lot of it is actually industrial
tillage of commercial cultivation of
food
so it's not a great practice on a lot of
levels but what do you do when you have
something that's like okay I have an
acre that I'm running I I don't have an
acre worth of cardboard
um I don't like silage tarps and it's
not working for me because weed seeds
are blowing in every single time of the
year and if it's not dandelions in the
spring then it's foxtails in the summer
and then it's um lamb's quarter in the
fall and ah what do I do
what we've turned to is what we call low
till so that means that we're not
tilling deep we're not going 12 inches
we're not going 18 inches we're
literally just tilting the top inch or
two of the soil this allows us to get
our nutrients in easier so if we're
using something like compost or chicken
manure or if we want to put out some
rock dust we can actually incorporate
that into the top layer of the soil
gently it loosens that soil bed so that
our seed bed is nice and soft so that
our plants are easy to transplant if
we're transplanting our seeds are able
to germinate and take root easily if
we're germinating seeds and it also
allows us to cultivate the weed seeds
that have germinated and get them to
basically be tilled back under but
without actually tilling and really
disturbing the soil
that was a rather long explanation of
the differences but you know they're
they're varied and uh vast and that
actually was a short version
no it's really really good to have that
amount of detail I appreciate that so is
it the same piece of equipment you're
using for low till we actually purchased
a Kubota tractor last
skin reason I
will scale indigenous microorganism
piles which is a Korean natural farming
methodology but as we went through it
turned out they were like oh wow like
go figure Farmers really need tractors
they're very very useful for a lot of
things uh we used it for putting rock
out on the road and uh through that
system I was like you know yes I can
rent that BCS rototiller from my local
shop that rents out equipment but that
thing costs I think like 60 bucks a day
we usually need it for at least a week
we're gonna need it a couple times a
year and we can't do things like move
rock around with it so
um so with the Kubota tractor what we
can do is we now we don't actually have
it yet but we're working on getting a
um a couple of attachments on the back
one of them will be a rototiller
attachment
um and they also make
um they make they make a lot of
different equipment for tractors
actually it's kind of amazing if I had
my choice I would probably get something
that is and I can't remember the name of
it right now but there are ones that
actually will fold the soil over rather
than tilling and so it's like a I know
there are different companies not Kubota
specifically
um that make they're called bio
some things my friend Sunshine knows
um and those the reason why we would
like that equipment at some point is
because we're planning on doing a dry
farm so dry Farms are farms that have no
irrigation and people are like how okay
wait how do you grow things without
water and it's actually just a
completely different methodology what
you're doing is your
keeping there's no cover crop there's no
companion plants well you cover crop in
the winter but there's no companion
plants there's nothing growing except
for your cash crops in your soil and
what happens is you end up with like a
dust mulch layer so there's a layer on
the top that's hot and dry and as that
gets hot the just the Tran the way water
Wicks the way it transpires the way it
moves in soil if you have the right soil
texture that's key which we happen to
have so that top layer will dry it will
get hot the cool water from below will
be Wicked upwards towards the plants and
what you end up with is a little layer
of hot dry soil and then a layer a
really moist beautiful rich soil
underneath so this tuner tiller it's
Tata it starts with the T I can't
remember uh whatever this thing is
called
um bio Turner maybe something like that
what it does is it protects your biology
and it just literally flips your soil
around so it loosens it it aerates it a
little bit but it doesn't actually till
it up so we do want one of those and
then for the Farmland that is irrigated
that thing doesn't work as well to my
understanding and so what we'll do is
have the rototiller attachment on the
back of the tractor that we're just
going to set your depth so instead of
setting it all the way down where it's
tilling 18 inches or so you just set it
so it's just basically just touching the
top of the soil and what that will do is
that will incorporate all those
amendments it'll get rid of all those
weed seeds that have germinated
and it also will allow us to have soil
contact with our Korean natural farming
inputs so indigenous microorganisms need
to actually contact the soil so if
you're just spraying it on top of
grasses and things you have it still
works it's just a more limited efficacy
than if you can actually have contact
with the soil itself then of course we
will be
um well I guess you're gonna say of
course because a lot of people don't do
this but then we'll be mulching on top
of that and then the plants go into the
soil through the mulch got it I imagine
for the folks that are tuning in that
are more of a small scale like I have a
lot of Home Growers that grow indoors or
they have small outdoor Gardens if they
were to implement low till they could
probably just use a small hand rake for
example and dig down an inch or two and
I think I imagine a lot of people doing
that when they're top dressing in
organic amendments is their top dressing
but using a small little rake or
something or using their hands to mix
things up on the top so it's kind of
similar to doing that huh yeah it's
basically like scratching it into the
top of the soil there it works it works
out really well a lot of times with home
Growers and with people that are you
know have indoor gardens
um you it's a little different because
you're not working with
living soil so much there's so many
people that are like but I do I have
worms and I'm like and worms are amazing
and they're awesome it's not necessarily
an indicator that you have a functional
soil food web true living soil is a
system that is self-sustaining that
means that you're not adding microbial
activity microbiology every single week
anytime I see a bottle of microbes that
says you need to add this with every
watering my brain goes okay but why
because biology works in the same way
that all life works right is that it
replicates be it through asexual or
sexual
um
uh replication it doesn't matter it
should be doing that so if it's not
doing that there's something wrong with
this environment and if there's
something wrong with this environment
you're having to keep adding new
populations all the time and this to me
just doesn't make sense like out there
in nature nobody's going out there and
adding bacillus species to the forest
every single week right so if you're if
you're trying to get a biologically
active soil your big takeaway here is
you're not going to do it with potting
soil you're not going to do it with a
soilless medium and most potting soil is
pretty junky most compost that you buy
commercially is pretty junky like
Municipal compost is full of pesticides
and herbicides because there's no check
and balance anybody who wants to put
green waste into a municipal composting
facility they just send their green
waste off and you have no recourse on or
no knowledge even of what was put on
those plants before they went into that
facility most composting facilities
don't use biology they just use heat and
pressure and turning and oxygenation
which is great for breaking down
material but truthfully it doesn't
mitigate anything that's in there so if
there's poisons or herbicides or even
excess fertilizer it's not really
getting broken down and that composting
process now when you start adding
biology it's a whole different world
there are amazing studies that I read
all the time about how different fungal
species and different bacterial species
have the ability to actually mitigate
things like you know oil spills we've
heard about that for years right there's
ones now that are showing that they're
mitigating heavy metals so toxic heavy
metals like cadmium and arsenic are a
lot of problem in a lot of native soils
what do you do about it well if you have
an extremely diverse microbiological
population that has lots of fungi lots
of bacteria lots of you know amoeba and
nematodes and everything you need to
show that you have a functional soil
food web you're gonna probably or
possibly I don't know you know there's
the jury is still out on that one what
the probability is
um but there's a good likelihood that
you have something that can actually
start mitigating those heavy metals and
they'll tie it up in their body or
they'll chelate it and actually make it
into a compound that's not a
bioavailable to the plants it's just
cool cool cool amazing stuff
um and again that has more to do with
people that are growing outside in
native soil than people that are inside
um but even for people that are inside
they're like well I mean I don't want to
bring the outside inside like I have
this nice sterile environment that I
think I'm you know able to to kind of
keep in its little bubble and again it's
not it's not really the way plants grow
you know you have a limited cycle with
your potting soil inside
um you know I we used to grow inside
back in the day in Humboldt County a lot
and we basically at some point the norm
became to take out your dirt every time
you planted a new plant so you'd remove
all your soil and you bring in all new
bags of soil and at some point I was
just like okay this is this is silly
this feels really silly to me like my
garden loved it because it got fresh
topsoil or fresh potting soil all the
time made my heavy clay much more
aerated and light uh but I was like you
know I'm tired of doing all this work
we're gonna do something different we're
just gonna reuse our soil so we'll just
add compost and some amendments like we
would outside and we'll just see how
that goes and it worked really well for
a while and then what I found was that
and we still we actually moved into beds
and we did bring in a little tiny
rototiller like a little mantis thing so
you would like ring and turn everything
around and you'd till it up and um what
we found is that pretty soon your soil
texture turns into dust it turns into
garbage you lose all the good texture
that's in that soil it gets really
compacted plants start getting really
unhappy and I was like huh
okay so potting soil is not like regular
outside soil this is when you look at it
it's pretty obvious but you know
experientially especially as a young
person that was growing up doing a lot
of gardening and a lot of farming of
medicinal plants that aren't you know
widely talked about
um or that weren't widely talked about
at the time it was like you didn't you
didn't really know what you were doing
wrong you were just experiencing things
and realizing that like oh after you
know doing this four or five times it's
not working anymore so why would that be
what's different from outside and you
know kind of looking back and forth and
being like ah you know different organic
matter different starting material and
so then we started incorporating native
soil back in so we'd actually go and dig
buckets up out of the garden and bring
those inside and realized very quickly
that you could actually kind of
rehabilitate that potting soil if you
are if you will like we'd bring in wood
chips and Duff from the forest and you
know different we we started mulching we
weren't mulching at the time we didn't
mulch inside because I don't know why
would you I didn't really know what I
was you know soil science wasn't such a
thing when I was in my like you know
early 20s
um or maybe it wasn't I just didn't know
about it maybe I wasn't such a soil nerd
that's very possible
but we started mulching so we were
protecting that layer of our soil and
then as we would you know gently turn it
in on the next round it added organic
material to the soil itself which added
to the soil structure you know looking
back on it now I'm like man I wish I had
somebody like me to tell me how to do it
you know back then rather than doing all
of this trial and error over years and
years of being like why is this so
different I don't understand and why are
we having to like why are we having so
many pest issues like I don't have
problems like this outside why do I have
this inside I know it's more protected
but still there's got to be more to it
than this we have certainly come a long
way and things are a lot easier now with
the knowledge we have today versus five
years ago 10 years ago and so on and so
forth it's just it's incredible the
amount of knowledge that uh is circling
around there in the community and people
are implementing in their Gardens today
it's wild so going back to low till so
you you've low tilled your soil
are you doing anything else to prepare
for planting like some people add in
amendments or compost some people will
plant a cover crop and then grow their
plants with it are you doing anything
else preparing the soil for planting
um yes so we basically want to have
something growing in our soil at all
times ideally it's not our native
grasses because they seed readily and
frequently and they have deep roots and
they're just really difficult they
outgrow everything they're they're
difficult to deal with so
um in the winter time we have it I we we
missed our little window we just had
some rain up here so I was trying to get
out to actually do our cover crop in the
areas that we have already
harvested but we didn't quite get to
that we did we've done living mulch at
different times this year we really like
to have Mulch on our soil so it's the
easiest way for people to kind of keep
soil covered and not have to worry about
um cultivating or taking care of
something or you know weeding all the
time if you just do a super heavy thick
layer of mulch Alfalfa organic Alfalfa
is really the jam it is amazing you'll
actually see the residual benefits the
next year of that organic Alfalfa
unfortunately organic Alfalfa is
apparently next to impossible to find so
if you are trying to mulch 18 000 square
feet with Organic Alfalfa you need these
very very large Bales they weigh about
500 pounds and we usually use about six
we usually use um about 10 to 12 of them
per year
and we couldn't get any this year there
was none to be had I mean I was calling
from California I was calling Arizona I
was calling Nevada I was calling Oregon
Washington up into Idaho and I couldn't
find anybody that didn't that had
organic Alfalfa available for purchase
they were all have been contracted out
so something's going on with like the
dairy industry I guess or animal
husbandry that people are really moving
towards needing that organic Alfalfa for
animal feed so it's not available for
Farmers like me to use for mulch so this
year we tried
um living mulch which is basically a
short growing plant that grows
underneath your your cash crop and it
keeps your soil from being bare so we
had limited success with that
um part of the problem was by the time I
gave up on finding Alfalfa uh we were
well into summertime so all the seed
that we put out didn't germinate very
well because it was too hot and dry
already
so you know we and we've had years where
it's very successful and we've had years
like this where it wasn't
um so luckily in a way we don't have to
worry about a living mulch that we have
to contend with trying to save I've had
years where I literally would dig it up
and move it out of the way because once
you add cover crop that generally grows
tall and High and
um you have to cut it down so if you're
growing cover crop and you're chopping
it down you're living mulch is now being
smothered out so if you're gonna have
living Mulch and cover crop you're gonna
have to remove your living mulch uh and
my living mulches generally don't
overwinter they die back I'm back at
that problem of having bare soil again
so we will as soon as we can plant a um
a cover crop my preferred cover crop is
a mixture of legumes so different peas
and like fava beans and things like that
um and some veg there's a lot of like
winter Rye that people add and grasses
um for us I'm not a huge fan of the
grasses as much we don't need to break
up any compaction layers so some of
those grasses have really really deep
roots they're really good for heavy
thick soil but our soil has been
cultivated now for
um I think the the most recent Garden is
a running on eight years now oh gosh
maybe more than that
somewhere around in that range and then
the oldest Garden is about 15 years of
that same soil being taken care of and
being built every year so it's it's got
beautiful texture it's nice and loose we
do amend every year we did not send out
for soil test this year but I do
recommend you do test your soil just so
you kind of have an idea of Baseline of
what's there what kind of macronutrients
are available or present what kind of
micronutrients are present and that can
help you just kind of decide what you
want to amend with if you want to amend
I am a I'm gonna go against the grain of
um what people are frequently told
um if you pay any attention to people
like Dr Elaine Ingham
um and a lot of the wonderful
regenerative scientists and
um people that that advocate for
regenerative agriculture they're all
phenomenal and I love them to death I
think they're amazing and super smart
but experientially I have not had the
experience that they say which is that
everything that you need in the soil is
present in the soil that has not been
what I've noticed at all we are
generally very nitrogen deficient if we
don't add nitrogen to our soil or else
I'm having to constantly feed my plants
all the time and I'd rather put it in at
the beginning and have it be there in
the soil so that the plants have access
to it when they need it rather than me
dictating when I think the plant needs
it usually by the time I notice a
deficiency even if it's super early on
the plant is like yeah I've been
starving for like two weeks thanks for
finally feeding me so if I make sure
they're in the soil then I don't have to
worry about that I can take that kind of
off my plate and and not have it be a
concern I think one of the main things
that gets kind of missed is certain
crops especially our medicinal herbs
we're removing the entire plant we're
not just removing the fruit so if you
have a tomato and you're just taking the
tomato fruit off you're removing that
nutrient all the nutrients and minerals
that it took to make that fruit have
disappeared but if you leave the plant
itself all of the leaves will Decay your
Vines will Decay they'll add they'll add
to your soil and anything that that
plant utilized from the soil will be
returned to the soil but if you have a
medicinal plant and you're taking the
whole thing out you're removing all the
nutrients that that plant accumulated
over the course of its life from the
soil that means you're going to have to
replace it
so for us again nitrogen's the big one
we prefer organic manures we prefer
organic alfalfa meal when I can find it
um some crustacean meals and things are
really really great and then we usually
do rock dust every year ideally I'd like
to get enough Rock Dust to do it once
every 20 years but that would be like a
lot of rock dust Rock Dust has all of
your trace minerals and micro Newton not
all of but most of your trace minerals
and micronutrients that your plants need
we usually do some oyster shell that
adds to our calcium which tends to get
depleted rather rapidly with the crops
that we farm
and earthworm castings
um if you're working with fallow soil or
native soil that hasn't ever been
utilized before all as many earthworms
castings as you can afford is great it
adds biology instantly it's
once you're getting rolling you don't
need to add as much or you don't need to
add as much every year you can kind of
go you know when you're on when you're
off type of thing
um what else do we put in there I think
that's kind of the majority of it and
then we do Korean natural farming so
that's really our big ticket item so our
you know do this one thing to get the
most out of it is going to be indigenous
microorganisms so I've mentioned that a
few times we shorten it I I laugh a lot
because in k f it's like oh we have more
acronyms than the Navy Seals Everything
is acronym acronymized I don't know if
that's where it is now uh
so IMO indigenous microorganism and what
that is is you're going out into nature
you're finding areas that are
undisturbed so we're talking you know
it's not
um it's not your backyard okay it's not
your garden that you've already been
cultivating it's definitely not your
compost pile people really like look at
my IMO from my compost pile I'm like
that's compost microorganism it's not
indigenous microorganism it's a whole
different thing
and the reason why we want to go out
into undisturbed areas is because it has
the most biodiversity so what we're
trying to do is capture as much
diversity as we can in these collections
we're trying to do it as often as we can
from as many different subtle locations
so our farm I have an oak tree that I
love it's right on the edge of a field I
get great collections from that but I
also want to have a collection
underneath the Bay Tree which has a
different
microbiological community living under
it I also want to do under a tan Oak
which is again another one and then we
have fur trees we have maple trees where
I live we have Live Oak we have we have
a lot of trees in California so that
means that that diversity under the soil
mimics the diversity above the soil so I
have a lot of diversity in my indigenous
microorganism collections then what I'm
doing
is I'm taking all of those I'm
inoculating out and culturing a
large-scale pile that is comprised of
carbon and carbohydrates and what we're
doing is we're really trying to Peg food
for fungi so we want all of the
mushroomy type things all the mycelium
that's running through the forest I want
to say you should come to my garden you
should come live with my plants my
plants and you guys would get along
really well I think and and it's not
there in native soil quite often it's in
our deciduous trees and it's in our old
growth forests
um obviously I'm not going to dig up all
the dirt in the old growth forest to
move to my farm because then I would be
killing my old growth forest and I don't
want to do that so we culture it on a
bed of rice we take that Rice we then
have like 10 to 12 of those culture rice
cultures that all have different biology
in them we inoculated out into this
carbon and carbohydrate substrate and
what that does is that's the perfect
food for fungi specifically you also
have bacteria terrestrial yeast so all
that being said
um obviously you know to increase the
um the soil Health that we have on the
farm indigenous microorganisms or IMO is
our very best friend so every year well
or every other year give or take what we
try to do is make sure that we are
adding more of those indigenous
microorganisms this is an ongoing
process like it doesn't ever stop so I'm
always doing IMO one which is that
initial collection from the forest and
every year I'm trying to make that into
im03 which is many many IMO 2
collections which is the stabilized form
of im01 and then I'm taking that imo3
marrying it with my garden soil and then
broadcasting that out I usually don't go
all the way to im05 just because I don't
generally have a lot of time so the
compost or the manure that we use will
just go kind of on top or again be low
tilled in now the one thing that k f
really works well with no-till
situations is because you're not
tearing apart those fungal hyphae you're
not exposing that microbiology and
therefore you're not having to add it as
often with what we're doing with the low
till situation we know that that first
few inches of soil is going to end up
being you know not so happy it's going
to have biology that's dying back and
that's why we want to add it back with
the IMO so you know the great thing
about IMO is that you really don't need
a lot you do need a decent amount but
it's not like you know hundreds of
thousands of pounds or anything
I believe that the standard application
rate is three
thousand pounds per acre if I recall
correctly I always have to go to my
notes but in general where I'm at now is
that we just want to every year try and
make a two thousand to five thousand
pound pile and then just broadcast that
out over whatever square footage we're
using you really can't overdo it either
which is a nice thing about im03 and
im04 is that um
it's not like chicken manure where it's
hot so if you put it in there you might
overdo it and kill all your plants you
could literally grow in just im04 if you
wanted to it would be a lot of work and
I don't know that I would necessarily
recommend it because you don't have to
do that and again a part of a part of
Korean natural farming is utilizing as
little as you can for the most efficacy
so the biggest bang for your buck for
the least amount of work because as a
gardener or a farmer you have a ton of
other things that you have to do in any
given hour so if I can do something that
has you know a percent success rate of
you know 80 percent I want to focus on
that one thing and that for us is
indigenous microorganisms
um the benefit another benefit that we
haven't even touched on yet is pest
resistance so we have plants that will
come into us from nurseries and things
and from other other sources that will
have like aphids or mites of some kind
and for the most part or thrips is
another great one that plants love to
they love to hitchhike in on you and
everything that comes to you and uh what
we found is once we plant them in the
garden like they'll they'll the
population will Boom for a minute and
then it just dies back naturally we also
have access to open air like again we're
outside not inside so if you're inside I
don't know that this works quite as well
there's a lot of people that are
espousing that if you have a healthy
enough plant it is pest resistant
naturally and while I agree with that to
a certain extent it's kind of impossible
to know how healthy your Healthy plant
has to be what looks healthy to us might
not be truly 100 Optimal Health I also
know that like with human beings
um the only people that are at Optimal
Health are people that are you know
a have the amazing genetics that they
have and B are extremely high level
athletes that are watching their diet
and they're exercising and they're being
very careful most of us are not at that
level I don't think most plants are at
that level either I I think that it
doesn't really matter how
healthy your plant looks to you there is
probably some amount of weakness in it
and so therefore once pests take hold
especially if you're inside it's near
impossible to get rid of them if you're
outside
um again it's a little different we
don't have this beautiful environment
that's all protected and there's no
natural predators that can come in and
you know the pests just love that you
put thrips in an inside garden and they
just you know go Richter you put spider
mites in an inside Garden or aphids and
if there's no predators in there and
there's no wind to knock them down and
there's no rain to wash them off there
they get to be pretty difficult even in
a really really healthy soil system so
that's why we have IPM integrated Pest
Management it's integrated Pest
Management not integrated pest
eradication so if you're inside even if
you're practicing living soil technique
and Korean natural farming you know
you're gonna find less bugs probably but
it's not necessarily going to eradicate
them 100 percent and you may need to
stay on top of some type of preventative
maintenance even if it's just bio
control so if you have Healthy Living
soil it's well mulched and covered
you've got microbiology that's extremely
diverse you've got a really really
healthy plant you're probably okay with
just monthly releases of Bio control
agents so those would be Predators for
your pests so if you notice you have a
couple spider mites you're going to get
a predatory Mite if you notice you have
a couple aphids you're going to get some
green lace Wing larvae so these are
things that you can use inside that can
mitigate problems before they become
super problematic
outside again I don't really do any of
that we just plant them in the dirt and
we allow them to grow for you know
usually it's somewhere in the two to
three weeks and we'll watch the
population just get decimated and part
of that I think is that the plants
become stronger and healthier they have
access to more nutrients their cellular
walls get thicker which makes it harder
for sap sucking insects to pierce them
and get into that sap
um and then we also have access to the
wind and the rain and the natural
predators that are there but again
Korean natural farming has that
microbiology diversity that diversity of
soil biology allows those plants to
uptake nutrients that are harder to get
normally that allows it for it to be a
stronger healthier plant a lot of people
what they'll do is they'll resort to
sprays as a preventative are you doing
any type of sprays in order to prevent
pests are you like avoiding spraying
your plants
um we avoid spraying unless we're fully
you're feeding we want to foliar feed
our plants that's something that we do
when they are not producing fruits or
flowers yet once they start producing
fruits and flowers we tend to avoid away
from that especially our medicinal herb
plants those ones we really don't want
once they're once they're in their
production stage we don't want to be
spraying anything on them at all
um
that being said you know there is
something called jwa or chadam wedding
agent which is a homemade soap basically
and we found that it mitigates just
about everything so there's a Mite HRM
mites that are out there those who know
and if you know you know it's really
really difficult to combat we found
wonderful success with just jwh and I'm
wetting agent
um it's just it you have to be on top of
it you've got to do it every third day
for three weeks is my protocol for that
one and it does have pretty much almost
full eradication and then you have
Predator insects that you bring in to
kind of do the mop up of anybody that
you might have missed but as far as you
know IPM sprays it's
um if you can avoid it and if you can
get plants that are super healthy and
happy and not have to do that and just
use bio control it is a much better
process to go down but if you are not
paying attention and you have of a
population explosion of pests you're
gonna have to use knockback spray once
they get past the point where you're
like oh shoot I have bugs it's too late
Predator insects are not going to do the
job for you it doesn't matter I mean I
know people that say that they have done
like massive releases of like um
californicus or Swarovski which are
different mites predatory mites and been
able to mitigate pest problems I myself
have tried that and not had that success
I know a lot of other Growers that have
not had that success and they're
expensive so you've also got a problem
if you did not identify your pest
correctly and you did not release the
right predator for it you've now wasted
a lot of money on predators that are not
specific to that pest so knockback spray
of a simple soap is a really really good
way to go if you have to but again
ideally your you know your your your IPM
your integrated Pest Management is that
you're managing your pests before they
even get there so you have predators
prevalent and ready to fight if they
show up
um and you have a healthy enough plant
that if they show up they're like this
is maybe too hard I might hitchhike back
out to something that's you know easier
easier victims out there in the
neighborhood got it yeah if you can
avoid those sprays it can certainly save
a ton of time I mean I know people who
are spraying their plants every single
week religiously just to prevent you
know they aren't even battling
infestation but uh yeah if you can get
to a point where you don't have to spray
on a weekly basis you can save a ton of
time doing that now one thing that we
didn't get into really that kind of
relates to all this is companion
planting I love my companion plants so
companion planting so there's there's
two terminologies and they're kind of
used Loosely and interchangeably but in
my mind they shouldn't be so you have a
cover crop which is really meant to
cover your soil when you don't have a
crop in so that's that was the the first
definition of these was cover crops were
put in in the fall and it covered the
soil so that in and a lot of it were
winter die backs so if you live in a
place where it's really cold you can put
a winter Rye in and it will grow it will
nice and big and then as the freeze
comes it will die back but it'll turn
into its own layer of mulch it's a
really easy way to just you know have
both mulching and covering at the same
time so
um for People Like Us in California that
doesn't work so well because we don't
have killing Frost so things don't die
back very well
um so that's your cover crop and then
your companion plant is just what it
sounds like it's a plant that is company
for your cash crops so companion plants
are amazing there is a big bean here
hello buddy
um companion plants are amazing for a
lot of reasons one of the things I
really love about companion plants is
that different plants have different
microbial interactions in the soil so if
you have a more increased plant
diversity above the soil you have a more
increased microbiological diversity
under the soil that means that if your
plant has different communities it likes
to hang out with there's a greater
chance of those communities being there
and staying alive with other plants
being there and Alive as well so um
companion plants we've used in the past
we've used food crops I've used
watermelon and cucumber I do not
recommend you use a Vine as a companion
plant because it can strangle your cash
crops
um that being said I tend to break all
the rules on my own because I can I
guess or because I want to see
um some of those have been very very bad
choices like letting my kids plant bird
seed wild bird seed turned into Millet
which has turned into a five-year issue
I can't get rid of it I always miss some
it set seeds really easily also led to
me discovering though that it makes a
really great mulch so if you can get
your Millet out there you can buy bird
seed literally for bird seed it's very
cheap right and you can spread it and
you'll generally have Millet
um possibly some amaranth and some
sunflowers and all of those are
wonderful plants to have in your garden
if you can make sure that you your
Millet doesn't take takeover Millet has
really really deep roots so it's really
hard to get it out of the ground it
comes back from the crown really easily
it moves through the rhizosphere very
easily so it'll actually send out like
roots that will pop up new Millet plants
um so if you've got a small gardening
space I don't recommend it but if you
have a large gardening space you might
dedicate part of it to just be Millet
you can go and cut it down and have your
own mulch really easily that way but
again not not your best companion plant
either
um which was what I originally let my
kids do I was like yeah this is your
area do whatever you want well it's kind
of started taking over other areas
um so Millet not your best choice for a
companion plant may be a good choice for
a cover crop dependent
um but what is good then so something
that grows low purslane fabulous
fabulous cover crop companion plant it
will cover your soil it will last
through the winter it will reseed it
will come back and it grows for the most
part fairly low to the soil up to about
six to eight inches so if you have a
cash crop or a herbal medicinal plant
that grows very tall you can easily
utilize that and it's a it's a really
easy one it doesn't take any management
whatsoever it generally likes
um you know it can handle drought
tolerant not super drought tolerant but
it does okay in low water situations if
you do a low-till situation you can
literally till it under and it'll come
back from its seeds the next year so
it's it's a fun one
um what else have we done I've tried
beets which didn't turn out very well
there wasn't enough sunlight underneath
so that didn't companion plant well
marigolds people talk about a lot
because they think that it has a natural
pyrethrin in it which is a pest
deterrent but most of the marigolds that
people plant are not the ones that
actually contain that and it might not
be the pyrethrin actually now that I
think about it might be something else I
don't I don't quite recall but it's only
french marigolds it's a very specific
strain or cultivar of Marigold that has
that and I haven't noticed it to
necessarily work that well that being
said I do love marigolds they're
absolutely gorgeous and I use them as a
companion plant every year I love
petunias what do they do for me well you
know they maybe increase the diversity
in the soil because it's a petunia but
nothing really grows
petunias will take over their area
they're they're literally so
um prolific with their foliage and their
flowers that they'll they'll take
everything that they can and nothing
else can grow underneath them but
they're easy to care for they're super
pretty I don't know how good of a
pollinator they are I don't usually see
my pollinators on my petunias I usually
see them on the dandelions that are
right next to the petunias so um as far
as a pollinator companion goes not sure
that one's your best bet
um we've used lamb's quarter with
varying success lamb's quarter is a
great bio accumulator so what it will do
is it'll actually take nutrients out of
the deep soil and put them up into its
leaves and store it and then you can cut
it down and compost it or chop and drop
it and those nutrients will return to
the soil and be more available to your
cash crops however they also are really
tall and they're kind of a pain in the
butt so I don't know that I I have mixed
feelings about lamb's quarter I
generally forget how much of a pain in
the butt it is and then will allow it to
come back one year and then the next few
years be like oh yeah that was kind of
difficult to deal with so
um yeah I think personally it's kind of
our big one right now if you're in a
cold area dichondra ripens is a
wonderful cover crop or companion plant
I mean that doesn't die back in the
winter so it's another one that kind of
bridges that that gap of companion plant
cover crop
s yeah there's tons I mean you can use
times as companions if you're growing in
herbal medicinal plant that you want to
be more prolific in the way that it
smells you can do things like basil
thyme oregano Rosemary and these things
all have the potential to make your
herbal plants more herbaceous and higher
have higher smelling points on higher
aromatics I don't know that there's been
a lot of firm research that shows that
definitively but anecdotally people
definitely say that that is something
that happens
so yeah personally like food crops or
crops that have a secondary use are my
favorite companion plants so our
purslane we utilize to make fermented
plant juice which is one of our Korean
natural farming fertilizer inputs
um so for us it's easy it takes care of
itself it doesn't require anything it
comes back every year and I can use it
for fertilizer as well as it protecting
the soil and adding to that diversity
that we talked about so if you can find
things that are like triple threats like
that right singing dancing and acting
you've got fertilizer microbiological
diversity and keeping your soil covered
and safe like that's a great companion
plant definitely a lot of good
information there I myself have been
grown indoors for 12 years and I've only
grown Outdoors since 2018 so it's what
four or four or five years and I haven't
yet used companion plants so um
definitely some of the information is
takeaways for me on that one one note be
careful of what you do use as a
companion plant and pay attention to
what kind of pests are prevalent on that
companion plant I made the mistake of
utilizing white Dutch Clover you hear
all when you start going down this like
companion plant cover crop type of
rabbit hole one of the first things you
hear about is white Dutch Clover that's
what I use right now
so my white Dutch Clover became a
phenomenal Banker for thrips
I had thrips that went up and down
between my white Dutch Clover and my
plants that were there my cash crop
plants up and down and up and down and I
I could not get rid of them at all it
was impossible and because there was
that white Dutch Clover that was such a
um preferred food source and then they
would go up and nibble on my cash crop
and then they'd go back down and hide in
the cover or in the companion plant
um I couldn't I couldn't mitigate them
at all I couldn't even manage them
because I couldn't spray my cover crop
or my companion plant my Clover that was
down below so I ended up having to
continually chop that Clover down Clover
is great for a lot of things it is it
makes wonderful biomass but if it
becomes a banker for something like
thrips it becomes an extreme problem
because you can't get rid of it like it
also will send out Runners that become
new plants it's self-seed so it comes
back every year I've now got it to where
it stays in my walkways and gets
trampled on and then if there's a pest
problem it's not spreading to my other
plants nearly as much it is the
preferred food source so they tend to
stay in it so they don't go to my other
plants but especially if you're in an
indoor situation your your Clover can
become a problem with thrips
specifically
um there's nasturtiums and violas or
violets or pansies that all become
problems for spider mites so your spider
mites will go in and out of those
companion plants and in and out of your
foliage back and forth and they're just
having a sweet old time and you know it
wouldn't it's not as much of a problem
if you have those other plants there
because they'll be the primary food
source but you will have some plant
resist or plant weakening in your cash
crops because they're constantly being
kind of nibbled on russet mites
specifically are very very host specific
so there are tomato russet mites they
eat tomatoes there is
um you know hempress it might it eats
hemp there is
um a uh well that's a galmite I guess um
but but most mites most of most russet
mites are plant specific they don't tend
to go back and forth and in fact as far
as I know and I could be wrong there
because I know they have been studying a
lot these recipe in um institutions and
things now
um but as far as I last knew they were
trying to get russet mites to move
between hemp and
um and uh hops and they were not having
good success with that so they couldn't
they couldn't get them to go back and
forth the way that they wanted to Hops
being one of the closest
um plants to have so that they were you
know unable to do that in a educational
setting so out in nature might be a
little bit different but as far as it
goes with the studies that are being
done they've not had good success so um
just kind of have a mindset of like okay
if I wanted to use Columbine what likes
to eat Columbine Leaf Miners and thrips
so maybe Columbine is not going to be
even though it's a beautiful flower and
I love it I might not want to put that
in as a companion with my cash crops I
might want to look at things that are
um less that have less pests in similar
in in similarity in similarities that a
word yeah sure
less pests similar
definitely some good tips there I am
probably going to stop using white touch
Clover now that you mentioned that I
have a little bit of a bag left so I
won't waste it I'll still use it but uh
but yeah that's that's crazy that drips
feed off it alright so we are getting up
towards the end of the episode here uh
you hear a wealth of information this
has been fantastic we covered so much so
much everything from how you do low till
low till versus no-till cover crops
companion plants mulch layers some of
the knf inputs that you do pest
prevention a long list of things we
covered in this episode and I definitely
appreciate your time tell us how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future so you can find
us online at
www.sunabus.com that's
s-u-n-n-a-b-i-s.com uh we're also very
active on Instagram son of us is our
Instagram handle as well
um I do a repost thing that posts to I
think Twitter and
um on my Facebook page which I think is
now sunabis but it might be Humboldt's
full sun Farms I'm not as active with
engagement on those platforms though
um and I feel like I am missing
something uh you can email me at Wendy
cinebist.com if you have a burning
question but again a direct message
through Instagram might be a little bit
of a better and quicker bet on that you
can also find us on organic
cultivators.net there's a list of
resources there that kind of goes a
little bit deeper into some of this
stuff we're working on getting some
blogs up on that and if you want to come
and hang out in person you can find me
at the Cowboy Cup in December on
Oklahoma and if you want to hang out for
three days and get a ton of Education
you can come to the organic cultivators
Supernatural conference which will be in
Sturbridge Massachusetts in February
fantastic so lots of good stuff there if
you enjoyed this episode click that
Thumbs Up Button also subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single weekend I'm releasing a new
Garden Talk podcast episode and I'd love
for you to tune into future episodes
Wendy once again thanks so much for
coming on this has been awesome I
definitely appreciate your time and hope
you enjoy the rest of your day yeah it's
been great thank you so much for having
me I I love spreading this message I
love sharing the information and kind of
all the trials and tribulations we've
gone through
um like I said I hope this helps people
kind of you know get through that
learning curve a little bit quicker than
than I may have and I really encourage
people to go out there and plant
something grow something if you've got a
windowsill you can get a small pot of
dirt and you can grow something and um
it's really going to be something that
changes your life it's super fun
absolutely all right peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode