what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. Grouch and
today I get a part test video for you
this is the Mars hi Joe SP 250 LED real
light it has a flower and coverage area
of 2 foot by 4 foot and actually have
placed here in a 2 foot by 4 foot grow
tab I'm gonna be doing par measurements
in this video I'll be using the apogee
MQ 500 par meter measurements are taken
in a ppfd I'm just gonna do the
measurements in this video I'm not going
to be talking about the features or
anything like that if you want to learn
more about this light I will link it in
the description section below ok let's
get right into it just like the other
videos I won't talk I'll let the
measurements do the talking
[Music]
well there you have it
power measurements for the Mars hi Joe
SP 250 LED grow light from three
different distances 12 inches 18 inches
in 24 inches what do you think of these
measurements let me know in the comment
section below I have about let's see one
two three four five more of these part
test videos coming at you those will be
out in the coming weeks and I have a
whole list of other types of videos that
I'm going to be putting out on this
channel so if you haven't already please
hit that subscribe button and I will
leave it at that
thank you so much for watching and until
next time face
[Music]