what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching my extras channel
mars hydro sent me over there fc
3000 led grill light and in this video i
am going to unbox the unit
i'm going to test the power output and
i'm going to do a heat test on it i'm
not gonna go over all the specs that
this urlite has
but i will leave a link down in the
description section below so you can
click on that if you want to learn more
about this light
okay first thing out the box is the
fixture
after that you can see they have
included a sheet of stickers
here is the meanwhile driver as you can
see they already have pieces attached to
it
so all you have to do is place onto the
fixture and then tighten the screws
to secure they've included a set of rope
ratchet hangers
here's the power cord a cable
and the user manual for the part test
i'm going to use the apogee mq620
extended range par meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers
and the measurements are in ppfd this
light does have a dimmer on it
for the part test i'm going to set it to
100 so it's operating at full power
i do these part tests just to give you a
general idea of what the power output is
they're not meant to be 100 accurate i
take measurements and grow tents which
have reflective walls
that will increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the coverage area for
this grow light is
four feet by four feet for veg and three
feet by three feet for flower i'm going
to take measurements in a four foot by
four foot grow tent
and i'll take measurements at three
different distances 12 inches
18 inches and 24 inches since 18 inches
and 24 inches are
veg recommended height distances i'll
move my par meter around
the entire footprint and then for the 12
inch measurements which are recommended
for the flowering stage
i'll keep my par meter in a three foot
by three foot area i plug the led grill
light into my kilowatt meter and it
shows
2.48 amps pulling 295 watts from the
wall
all right let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
so
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
this grow light down in the description
section below
and i've also included a coupon code
down there that's pretty much it for
this video guys if you enjoyed it please
click that thumbs up
and i will leave it at that thank you so
much for watching
and until next time peace