what's up everybody feel that don't know
me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it and
you're watching Max's channel Mars hydro
sent me over there new girl light the SP
3000 LED grow light in this video I'm
going to unboxing it I am going to test
the power output and I'll do a heat test
on it I'm not gonna go over all of the
girl lights features in this video but I
will leave a link down in the
description section below if you want to
learn more about it such as what diodes
are used to drive our spectrum so on and
so forth alright first thing out the box
is a user manual this includes
information such as assembly
instructions dimming operation some grow
tips some safety information and
information on their warranty next out
the box is to rope ratchet hangers and
in this bag there's also two metal
brackets for hanging they've included a
sheet of stickers and here's the fixture
oh and they've also included an Ethernet
cable for the part test I'm gonna use
the apogee mq6 20 extended part meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers and the measurements
are in ppfd I do these videos just to
give you a general idea of what the part
output is it's not gonna be hundred
percent accurate I take measurements in
grow tents which have reflective walls
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the flower and
coverage area for this girl light is 2
feet by 5 feet but Mars hydro mentioned
that this would do great and they 2 foot
by 4 foot grow 10 they actually sent me
over two of these grill lights and
they've requested that I take
measurements in a 4 foot by 4 foot grow
10 so you can see what the power
measurements are in that size grow 10 if
you want me to do another video where I
take measurements in a 2 foot by 4 foot
grow 10 let me know down in the comment
section below this LED grow light does
have a dimmer on it for the measurements
i'll set the different to 100% i've
plugged the LED grow light into my
kilowatt meter and it shows two point
four five amps pulling 290 watts from
the wall alright let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below just a reminder that there is a
link to this girl right down in the
description section below so you can
learn more about it that's pretty much
it for this video guys if you enjoyed
you please click that thumbs up and I
will leave that that thank you so much
for watching and until next time peace
you
[Music]