what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're watching max's channel
chilled led sent me over their brand new
led grow light
this is the growcraft x1 mini this led
grill light is used for side lighting
and in this video i am going to unbox
the unit i will test the power output
and i'll do a heat test on it i'm not
going to go over all of the features
that this grow light has
but i will leave a link down in the
description section below so you can
click on that to learn more about the
light
okay first thing out the box are these
cables one of the cables is an
extension cable that goes from the led
grow light to the driver
and then there's a cable that goes from
the driver to the wall outlet
in this bag there is a dimmer and
there's also two rope ratchet hangers
in this box is the meanwhile driver
and lastly is the fixture
chilled led is actually giving one of
these away and they're also giving away
an
x1 i'll leave a link to the giveaway
down in the description section below
you can click on that to learn more
about the giveaway and to join it
for the part test i'm going to use the
apogee mq620 extended rage par meter
this meter measures from 340 nanometers
to 1040 nanometers
and the measurements are in ppfd this
part test isn't meant to be exact
it's meant to give you a general idea
for what the power output is
especially since this is for side
lighting like i mentioned earlier
i take measurements and grow tents that
have reflective walls that will increase
the numbers
so just keep that in mind as you saw
when i unbox the light
this light does come with a dimmer i
didn't plug the dimmer in
so the grow light is operating at 100
for this part test
i'll take measurements at three
different distances 12 inches
18 inches and 24 inches i plugged the
led grill light into my kilowatt meter
and it shows
0.56 amps pulling 67.5 watts from the
wall
all right let's get into the
measurements
[Music]
hey
so
[Music]
hey
my
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know down in the comment section
below
just a reminder that there is a link to
this grow light down in the description
section below
there's also a link to the giveaway
chilled led is giving away one of these
x1 minis
as well as one of the regular x1 grill
craft lights that's pretty much it for
this video guys if you enjoyed it please
click that thumbs up
and i will leave it that thank you so
much for watching and until next time
[Music]
peace
you