a new study done on the drying process
reveals that the 6060 method actually
results in less Tarpin compared to a
different drying method the 6060 method
for those of you that don't know is
simply drying in a space that is 60° F
in a relative humidity of 60% drying in
these conditions result in the plants
not drying too fast and also not drying
too slow the final product has enough
moisture in it so it's not too dry and
harsh when consumed the 6060 method is
widely spoken about across the community
it's deemed as the best conditions to
dry in and these conditions are also
used in many commercial facilities as
well but what is the science behind the
660 method if any and what does this new
study reveal hey everybody welcome back
to my channel for those of you that
don't know me my name is Chris aka Mr
Grow and you're tuned in to my garden
talk Channel got a juicy one for you
today this one is going to raise some
eyebrows this one is going to cause some
people to feel anger this one is also
going to cause people actually change
the way they go about the drying process
process let's start with the science of
the 6060 method back when I first heard
about drying in those specific
conditions I did a deep dive to try to
find studies to back its legitimacy and
there wasn't any studies available at
all in fact still L this day I don't
think there are any studies on the 6060
dry method if I'm mistaken please post a
link down in the comment section below
I'd love to read it but as of this
recording in late 2023 there are no
studies on the 6060 method although
there isn't any science behind the 6060
method that doesn't mean that it doesn't
work well I personally used the 6060 dry
method for several harvests for the past
5 plus years and the final product was
great so I'm certainly not saying that
it is a bad way to go about it by any
means but finding out that a study has
been done on the 6060 method comparing
it to a different drying method and that
different drying method showed better
results had to share it the title says
Vapor troll technology is proven to
retain higher turpine levels the VAP
Patrol technology is in the canol cool
cure some of you have seen the videos
that I've made made on that system in
the past it goes on to say independent
research conducted by the CRC in
cooperation with the hemp mine canol
samples were held at 60° F dry bulb and
a 54° f dupoint Legacy samples were held
at 60° F dry bulb and 60% RH using
traditional HVAC equipment with
dehumidifiers in order to combat
negative side effects from mishandling
at a testic facility samples were
extracted immediately after post Harvest
treatment additionally water content was
measured to correct for water dilution
by the way I'll have a link to the study
down in the YouTube description section
below it also shows this chart that
breaks it down by different tpin and
shows the total Tarpin the samples held
in the krol at 68° F 54 dupoint had 16%
higher tpin than the samples strive with
the 6060 method that's actually all that
they show on this page right now I'd
like to see more information on this
study such as how long were the samples
dried for I have to assume that more
details will come out on this eventually
and that this is just the initial
announcement taking a deeper look into
the CRC who conducted the research I see
some credible people here Dr James F Dr
Alison Justice Ashley Manning who's the
COO Dr mayab Shields Dr Marcus rogin
Selena LeBlanc and Michael alen are
listed as the leaders and I'm very sorry
if I pronounced any of those names wrong
I do a fantastic job at butchering names
bake yes sir my name is
Blake so does this new information now
deem the 6060 method Pro science Pro
science after learning about this
information will you be changing your
drying conditions let me know down in
the comment section below before we end
here got to give thanks to AC Infinity
for sponsoring this channel you can use
the discount code Mr Grow 15 to get a
discount on the gardening equipment on
the website or on Amazon and also thanks
to stash blend premium plant additive
several inputs in one blend you can get
it at stash blend.com thanks for tuning
into this video everyone and I'll catch
you in the next one