take an avocado superfood super nutrient
rich to begin with
and you mix in some stuff like say
malted barley flour because the worms
they really like the malted barley flour
and then put it
top down onto the soil and what's going
to happen is the worms in your soil are
going to come up and they're going to
just start
feeding on this stuff you want to think
about it like a fish tank where
if you have a very small fish tank any
changes in that system are going to
greatly affect
how things work so the bigger the system
that you have
the easier it is to sustain it and
maintain it and big changes
may have less of an effect overall
blends tend to use a lot of things like
bone meal blood meal
and you have to think about where did
those come from
organically
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and welcome to my talk channel in this
video i interview another youtuber
he goes by photosyntec he is an organic
gardener
he goes indoors i think he has plants
outdoors as well and i pick his brain
pretty good in this video we talk about
a ton of different things
we talk about pot size we talk about
what's in his mix we talk about cover
crops mulch layer avocado tech
a whole bunch of different things in
this video and i think we'll get a lot
of value out of it if you like these
types of videos be sure to click that
thumbs up button
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
done so already and if you want to
directly support this channel
i will link my patreon down in the
description section below
all right let's get into the video
all right we are here welcome matt
photosynthetic how you doing not too bad
chris said yourself
good good thanks for coming on to my
channel and talking today
appreciate it appreciate you having me
on here uh
definitely uh like the opportunity to to
stop by and visit
for sure all right let's just get right
into it um so why don't you tell me a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into growing
yeah for sure so i'm up in canada uh
canadian ac mpr grower is what i'm
called up here
licensed legal grower for medical
cannabis
i've been gardening for easily a dozen
years but i've only been growing
cannabis now
since well legalization came back in
october of 2018.
otherwise started outgrowing synthetics
as i think most growers do
and evolved into organics says i see a
lot of growers are starting to do now
uh definitely becoming a more popular
way to grow other than that i
run a youtube channel called photosyntec
talk about organics a lot gardening and
you know just generally there to help
people
you know learn how to grow and you know
do the best cannabis they can
nice so i'm going to pick your brain
specifically about the organic side of
things
i know you got some good knowledge in
that let's start with
pot size so what size grill pots do you
use when growing organically
well ideally the biggest that you
possibly can
especially if you're going to introduce
worms into the system
right now in my space i'm using some 15
gallon pots and that's about the
smallest that you'd want to go
realistically 30 would be better but i
will be moving into some 80 gallon grass
root fabric pots here
over the next couple weeks and that's
really going to allow me to have a a
much
better system i mean you want to think
about it like a fish tank where
if you have a very small fish tank any
changes in that system are going to
greatly affect
how things work so the bigger the system
that you have
the easier it is to sustain it and
maintain it and big changes
may have less of an effect overall
that's a really good point i've
um i started out with bottle nutrients
as well and then kind of switched to
organics i've been mostly doing the
blends but i did try them out in three
gallon containers
five gallon containers and you know
oftentimes it's kind of a struggle
and i like the way you put that with the
with the fish tank so
what type of grill pot do you use use
plastic do you use plastic at all or
just the the fabric pots that you
mentioned
been playing around with a couple
different things trying to find stuff
that works the best
uh right now and again going back on the
grass root stuff uh
something that i've recently tried is
the transplantators
i don't know if you're aware it's a
fabric pot but it actually has velcro on
the sides so you can split the thing
open to take your plants out
but you know it depends i i'll take
clones i'll put them in just little tiny
plastic jars because i'm not or i should
say plastic containers
because i'm not planning on keeping them
in there for a long time if i know what
i'm going to transplant
out i do prefer plastic because
well any fabric pot as i'm sure you've
found they are a pain
to pull the the plant out of and again
why i like these transplantators
because they've got the velcro side so
excited to use those
that makes sense i was actually at mj
bizcon um
last year they didn't have it but the
year before 2019 i did talk to the guys
at grassroots
and one of the things that they had
pointed out that was pretty interesting
is now
instead of just doing straight up fabric
they're adding in that liner
yeah on the inside uh because one thing
they had mentioned is that
you know when you're running living soil
with
the regular fabric pots it's drying out
from all the sides
and he says that's really not natural so
um
there is still aeration down below it's
still just fabric down below
and i think on the very top there's also
some air in there i got a visitor
but i thought that was pretty
interesting um so i'm actually using
the plastic pots now but i wouldn't um
i do actually have a two foot by ten
foot bed for outdoors
okay and it does have the liner it's for
my vegetables right right um which works
pretty good but yeah i thought that was
that was pretty interesting when he had
mentioned that
yeah so just to touch back on that i've
even seen and talked to some of my
viewers who will take and
wrap plastic wrap around a fabric pot to
act just like that liner and tell me
that they get great success with it
oh that's a good hack that's a really
good yeah i haven't tried it myself but
as soon as i get the opportunity if i
need to but because i'm moving all over
the fabric
beds anyway we'll see hmm makes sense
so what do you use for uh medium i've
been playing around
um mostly living soil here for at least
over the last six months
uh a mix that i've originally sort of
tried to make myself and
i recently did a video on that calling
that sort of my biggest failing
as an organic grower was thinking that i
was a soil scientist and knew how to go
about making this stuff myself
and for the most part it's not too
difficult to mix up with soil there's
lots of recipes out there
and you know as an organic grower and
most organic cannabis growers i think
what turned me on was mr canucks grow
his coco coir his dry amendments
making it look easy boy is that a rabbit
hole you can go down
but to that point um i i do mainly a
cocoa base now
and it's based heavily off of the build
a soil mix and when i say heavily about
the only thing that i'm doing different
than their recipe is i'm adding in some
biochar
uh for many many beneficial qualities
got it okay and correct me farm on they
have three different mixes on their
website
yours is the thirty thirty three thirty
three thirty three right so one point
one part
and it's um coco co so thirty three
percent coco coir
thirty three percent aeration and then
thirty 33
compost is that right yeah you bet now
just to point on that um they've got
another mix on there it's uh i believe
it's uh what is it
five parts compost two parts aeration
one part
uh no sorry five parts cocoa two parts
anyway you'd have to go on it's recipe
number two i can't remember
but the the takeaway there is i'm using
the one that's heavy compost the 33 33
because i have excellent quality compost
sea soil stuff i
i get it up here i don't know if you
guys can get it down there but it's
excellent excellent quality so that's
the takeaway there is if you can get the
really
good good high quality uh i think booze
blend is what i've heard recommended
down there
um then maybe look at that 33 33 33 mix
i've had wicked results with it super
super pleased and that's what i'm going
to be filling my uh
my beds with when i when i get those
kicked off here in the next couple weeks
got it and then so the the last 33 is
going to be aeration
you can use a bunch of different things
variation what do you use for aeration
i've been playing around um i've landed
on a mix of
hydroton clay pebbles and rice hulls
uh the nice thing about the rice hulls
is they break down over time
and help give you a little extra silicon
to your medium and silica as i'm sure
you know
uh will help your plants grow bigger
stronger cellular walls protect against
pests
it's just a very beneficial
micronutrient to have into the
the mix nice yeah
so what else do you amend into the
medium to begin with on top of that
33 33 33 well following of course that
build a soil mix
that's the thing i like about it is
their their recipe number one it's a
really
simple simple mix you've got your npk
uh parts it's uh neem or karanja
now just to get into that for a minute
neem is uh something that's broken down
from the neem tree
and karanja very similar and if you
can't
get karanjan you can only get neem or
vice versa they can be used pretty much
interchangeably
they look very similar and they have
very similar properties and also very
very good at protecting against pests
the other npk ingredients that go in
there is kelp meal
high in potassium tons of micronutrients
as well and you know just
well kelp of course fastest growing
plant on the planet so why not use
kelp and then the other one that goes in
there is going to be some crab meal
you've got your chitin
you've got um other beneficial parts to
it as well
and then there's going to be the mineral
side of things uh
basil rock dust which i'm actually
playing with a little bit um up here
gaia green has a rock
dust blend that i'm looking at trying to
change in because it's got some glacial
rock dust
some basalt rock dust as well as a few
other sources and i think
one of the things i really try to focus
on doing organic growing
is as many diverse sources as possible
just to
get that mix as as well again diverse
because
having a large variety of inputs
really make sure that the plants gonna
get what it needs and then the last
thing of course that i put in there is
oyster shell
flour which helps with your calcium
and i believe the osf also does a little
bit of buffering of ph
as well as the microbes in the soil so i
don't have to worry about doing things
like ph
my water okay i know you also
add worms to your medium which type do
you use
right now i've just got the the red
wigglers i would like to get the night
crawlers
and the difference there is the red
wigglers they sit up top they're a
compost worm so they're doing all that
work up in the
the rhizosphere up in the top part of
the soil but the night crawlers they're
going to go down deeper and until that
lower part of the soil so
having a good mixture again of both that
diversity is going to give you the best
results
so in a previous convo you actually
introduced me to avocado tech
can you explain to the listeners what
that is and how you incorporate that
into your garden
so definitely have to give a shout out
to uh
to blue at blue of green tank on
instagram
at blue underscore of underscore green
tank there
uh he came up with this it's based off
the idea of fruit drop theory
uh as a fruit tree grows up or a berry
bush
it's going to grow some fruit and
eventually drop it with the idea or the
hope that
and an animal is going to pick it up or
perhaps it's just going to decompose
there in the ground
so you've got this wonderful piece of
fruit that's full of all these nutrients
and it's decomposing going back in
and feeding that soil and of course
there's an organic or that's what we do
we feed the soil to feed the plant
so the idea with avocado tech is to do
just that
take an avocado superfood super nutrient
rich to begin with
and you mix in some stuff like say
malted barley flour because the worms
they really like the malted barley flour
or some oyster shellflower uh worms need
a little bit of grit
so some sand if you don't have it in
your mix uh some osf is nice in there
give them that little bit of grit to
help digest things
but basically you just take this mix it
all up like you would
you know a deviled egg put it back into
that avocado shell and then put it
top down onto the soil and what's going
to happen is the worms in your soil are
going to come up and they're going to
just start
feeding on this stuff and returning
those nutrients into a bioavailable form
so your plant can uptake it and then the
best thing about this
the best thing about this is it's it's
so low maintenance because you only have
to do it
three times a grow and this is how blue
sells it is it's just you've got a half
an avocado for veg
a half an avocado at the beginning of
flower or a week or two before flour
starts
and then another half an avocado about
halfway through
and the only thing that you're really
changing there is once you get into
flour you're going to add in a little
extra
phosphorus i like to use mineralized
phosphate bat guano if you're unfamiliar
but i'm looking around seeing what other
more sustainable sources i can find out
there
and that's sort of the challenge too is
always to see what
better practices i as an organic grower
can
take from industry and you know bring
into my grow room in a more sustainable
fashion
got it yeah i saw a video on it actually
after you mentioned it
and that was blue talking about it and
it showed him flipping over that
uh avocado shell and it was just loaded
with worms
yeah loaded it was it was pretty cool to
see yeah i know i had a buddy stop by
the grower room today to just uh pick up
a clone
and he'd never seen it myself or himself
and
same thing you pull up the avocado and
there's just swarming worms
it's just it's a testament to how well
it works and the takeaway there too is
it doesn't have to necessarily be
avocado uh
i know that blues tries uh cantaloupes
and some other you know smaller
dome fruit so the idea is it's a
humidity dome it's completely dark
perfect environment for worms the only
takeaway is if you are going to try
avocado tech and i strongly recommend
this
uh is get some bokashi grades and put a
little bokashi mix
in there because i've seen some avocados
start to go anaerobic
so if you've got some bokashi grains in
there bokashi being an anaerobic
compost microorganism it's going to help
break down that that nutrient internal
and
you know provide just a safer way to get
things done
that makes sense yeah okay so i want to
flip back to water you briefly talked
about water
um what type of water do you use do you
use reverse osmosis
distilled well tap water
i've used a variety actually uh so
up until recently my main source of
water in the grow room has been
just half water good old dechlorinated
tap water except in the summer
uh where i've got rain barrels sitting
on the side of my house because
why pay for water when you can get it
for free but recently i did install an
arrow watering system
um or i should say ro filter for
watering i use roof water all the time
for my humidifiers because where i live
i have very heavy water
and if you if you see all of a sudden
say you're
you know starting off growing and pretty
humidifier in your space and you're
seeing like a white foamy powder
everywhere it's not powdery mildew per
se
it's likely uh minerals that have come
out of humidifier deposited onto the
surfaces
so that's why i use ro water it's
demineralized water
in my humidifiers but since getting an
ro water filter installed in my house
i've actually changed
over to that to start watering all my
plants because the big thing for me is
my groom's actually outside in my garage
which is
you know good 15 feet from the house and
i don't have water out there so i
normally fill up five
five gallon buckets bring them out there
let the water dechlorinate
and then i'll use that to water my
plants over the course of a couple weeks
so having the ability to
just fill up a five gallon container
with our water works really really well
it makes sense yeah it's funny you
mentioned the um the white powdery
substance coming from the
humidifier and you know the root cause
of that is tap water with the minerals
and so on and so forth
um two other things that that impacts is
the carbon filter it actually clogs
those carbon filtered socks
good point you know i've had so many
people say uh reach out to me like i'm
getting no suction coming out what's
going on and then
you know the root cause was because they
were using tap water
in their humidifier it was just clogging
that up like pretty quickly
and then i had another person reach out
to me and mention that he saw
a build up on his fan so it was like it
went internal components
actually got into his fan it's all white
substance within his fan it did damage
on that one so
yeah yeah definitely whenever you're
using a humidifier definitely want to
have
filtered water or ideally reverse
osmosis water or distilled water
for sure and you know one other thing to
think about and this is just me
thinking out loud is i'm wondering if
you get build up
on the leaves of the plants and it
affects the stomata and the ability to
intake actual moisture and whatnot so
curious
so yeah if you're using humidifier
definitely horror water
and you said you don't ph adjust your
water i
don't know what the ph is in my water
when i grow
i haven't measured it in a long long
time i i shouldn't say that i
i do occasionally measure my top water
if i'm where when i was doing top water
just to make sure that things were
staying on point but because i
you know sit around 7.4 to 7.8
i don't worry about ph i let the
the gardening i let the medium do that
for me
because the microbiology will take and
along with the nutrients that i put in
there help
buffer that ph to the range that it
needs to be and you know i've even
recently learned
that the plant within an area close to
the roots has the ability to affect the
ph around it
to also help make that a more hospitable
zone for the microbiology
but the key takeaway there is know what
it is like don't just think you can't
not ph you have to know what it is um
i've got a whole video that i talk about
this on my channel too
i've i agree i've had at one point my
the
water coming out of my tap was over
eight 8.0 ph
uh dechlorinated it and gave my plants
and didn't get a good result
you know measuring that runoff uh ph it
was
high and i was seeing deficiencies in my
plants so
i personally do ph my ph adjusts my
water to make sure it's
within you know if i'm growing in soil
between six and seven ph
um that's just what's worked best for me
and that's the thing
like it's it works well for me i don't
have to but
i mean let me put it through this way if
i start to see deficiency or some sort
of toxicity the first thing i'm gonna do
is check runoff and see if that i've got
something odd going on
and that should be the takeaway i don't
ph because i don't have to
but i know that it's an absolute top
tool in the arsenal if i need to use it
makes sense cool okay
so we know what your pot size is uh we
know what your mix is you've amended
that mix up
um you know you've got your plants going
when do you give your first
feeding how do you and how do you
feed well it depends like right now i've
been
working on trying to do a perpetual so
get to the point where
i would just ideally be
pulling veg plants out of my tent that i
have here behind me and putting those
into the flower room
um so i'd be more reamending the medium
ideally at the point of planting or very
close to it
but because i've been changing beds out
and and working through this whole new
system
um i i don't have a very consistent
approach
to it at this time however that being
said
the idea is if you're doing something
like avocado attack you're doing one of
the avocados throughout veg in a couple
weeks
before you're getting into golden flower
you want to go again
so you've got a cat running around there
or something
but you know to that point the the thing
that you need to remember is if you're
doing organic growing your your
nutrients aren't immediately available
so you have to plan it out
and i think that's that's the main thing
is if you know you're going into flour
or you're planning on flour in two weeks
time
get your your extra phosphorus your
extra potassium boost
in now because that's when it's going to
need it get it ready to be bioavailable
for when the plant starts to take it up
so so that's the thing is organics
really involve
a whole lot of planning uh it sounds
like it's not a lot of work because well
i don't ph and i only have to add water
and that's all i do it's but
it isn't there's there's so much
planning involved to
to be successful in that grow to be able
to sit back and just
water yep i agree let's talk a little
bit about cover crops
um so which cover crops do you use and
when do you plant them
uh so the best time to do cover crops is
when you're first starting off your
living soil
mix a week or two before your plants
going in to give them some time to
get built up and start getting some of
that nitrogen into the soil
um the way that i've been doing things
it's just lately i
because i if if uh well let me let me
back this up a bit if people haven't
seen my channel i recently ran into an
issue where my growth seeded
so i've been trying to recover by
bringing in and doing a whole bunch of
uh well fast methods to get things
turned around
so right now i'm just doing cover crop
and then i get the plant in there
kind of at the same time but the idea is
yeah cover crop a couple weeks ahead
now cover crop that i use you can go as
simple as say
red clove or white clove or something
along those lines but
going back to the diversity thing i use
a five seed mix i get from black swallow
living soils up here in canada
uh it's got fenugreek uh clover
uh a couple of i can't remember off the
top of my head but it's again it's it's
got
multiple things in it to provide a
higher level of diversity
nice yeah i'm just using the white dutch
clover right now but
um yeah i've seen the uh the blends that
they have with
a couple different ones think about
trying those out in the future yeah
i'm actually thinking of maybe throwing
some peas in the grove once i get these
uh grassroots fabric pots going just
because they got the trellis going up
the side
and yeah these are extra excellent
nitrogen fixers
and delicious and mulch layer i know you
add one of those to the top
of the soil what do you use for a mulch
layer and when do you apply that
generally just straw and right away as
soon as you get that that plant
transplanted
you want to get the mulch layer down and
if you're doing cover crop don't worry
about
putting the mulch over top to cover crop
the cover crop will grow up and through
uh i've been working on as well a
a mix of different uh mulches where i've
got some cedar wood chips and people are
gonna go you can't do cedar yeah you can
hit me up on my my channel we'll talk to
you about it uh
as well as some was it uh pine and uh
again just straw the idea there is
getting some
wood in there because what is going to
bring in that fungal component and
again with diversity not only do you
want good bacterial components in your
soil you want lots of fungal components
because funguses
will help break down and and move things
around a lot better
and then of course when we talk about
things like mycorrhizae the
most beneficial fungus you can have in
the garden well
it's good to have a lot of different
sources yeah that makes sense
so you told us when that first feeding
happens all those you know it's kind of
a gray area it depends a lot of things
you know what about the second feeding
like something within
flowering uh typically people will do
they'll mend the medium to begin with
then before flipping a flower they'll do
some sort of top dressing
um you know with some flour type
nutrients and then like 30 days into
flowering
along those lines week three four or
five of flowering something like that
they will do a another type of top
feeding
do you do anything like that absolutely
yeah week
week three is when i prefer to hit them
um because
i'll go and do my my initial flower feed
a couple weeks ahead
and then once i get into week three i
like to do that feed because again i
gotta give that a couple weeks for it to
become bioavailable and ready for the
plants and
you know that that was a bit of a
learning thing too because
going from synthetics to organics it was
just okay well i'm gonna change up my
feed week five i'm gonna use this set of
bottles and
you know you have to be prepared for
that but then
also bringing in things like sugars to
help increase microbes and
well boost the ripeness i mean there's
lots of different organic
brightness boosters out there too that
you can use so
so what exactly like for that second
feeding is there anything in particular
that you um give to the plant at that
time
yeah we touched on that before it's uh
like i'll do the pk boost the same stuff
phosphorus and stuff
and then like kelp for getting your
potassium and whatnot so
okay and then um so you do incorporate
sugars into your garden
absolutely so i i actually sugars once a
week
um and i'll mix it up too i like to use
molasses blackstrap molasses and then
i've got some
coconut nectar sugar which i picked up
by accident from the costco
thinking it was a different type of
coconut product but
actually i find that i really like this
stuff it's a light sugar that dissolves
really well in water and i'll alternate
each week i'll do
one tablespoon of sugar or molasses into
the water
uh per gallon mix that up and feed that
and that helps boost up that
microbiology because
one of the things that i don't do is
compost teas
now the reason for that um if you're
familiar with the future cannabis
project earlier this summer they had a
really great episode on talking about
bro
science and uh linda chalker scott i
hope i got her name right
uh fantastic scientist she doesn't work
with cannabis she just
works with gardening but she came on she
talked a great deal about
compost tea and why it's not really
necessary to use compost tea because you
can get the same level of
benefit from it by just top dressing
with compost and that's something that
i've been doing a lot of lately is i'll
just
top dress with the compost some
earthworm casting some bokashi in the
mix
and then just water in with my molasses
water which is
effectively the same thing as doing a
compost tea
with the exception of i'm not letting it
brew overnight and letting that
that microbiology bloom in a big pot of
water
but i'm letting it bloom in a big pot of
soil so
the idea is all of that compost tea
action is happening but it's already in
the pot
in a more concentrated form and i'll say
that i've been getting amazing results
with this method
got it so you don't really do compost
teas do you need like nutrient teas
plant teas manure teas anything like
that absolutely you know i've never
heard of manure tea
yeah that's i could see how that might
be beneficial um
no i do seed sprouties uh once a week uh
depending on where i'm in the cycle
vegetative i'll do
pardon me corn barley and alfalfa
and then in flour i'll do corn barley
and mung beans
each one has its own benefits i've got a
whole video up on my channel that talks
in depth about it but the short of it is
it's part of the routine corn takes
several days to sprout
barley doesn't take quite as long and
alfalfa and mung beans take even less
so on friday night for example i'll take
some corn seeds
i'll put them in some water and let
those soak for a day the next day
dump those out add some barley into
another jar let those soak and over the
next you know four or five days
i'm getting these seeds to the point
where they've sprouted and then
i take and cannibalize them by hitting
them with the blender
add those into some water to dilute it
and then water from there
and um biggest takeaway there is you
want to talk about
overnight growth uh especially with
alfalfa
alfalfa has a chemical in it called
tricontinol which is a growth booster
so if if you want to see immediate
growth
um you know like steroid like growth
with your plants just try an alfalfa
sprouted tea just once
the way to mix them is quite simple
you're generally going a half a cup of
seeds
per five gallons
and then if you're using alfalfa do a
quarter cup because it's it's it'll come
in really hot
and then yeah just just blend that up
and then mix the juice in there i'll
strain it through like a nylon bag too
just so i'm not putting all the seed
stuff into the water itself
but then those seeds that i've ground up
and put into the nylon bag i'll take an
old top dress into my
pots as well as a little extra treat for
the worms yeah so you talked a little
bit about uh gaia green i use those
organic blends so um i'm sure there's
people that are watching here that are
brand new to my channel maybe this is
the first video
you've ever seen of me so a little bit
background on me is i've been growing
for almost 11 years now
and most of the time i've been using
those bottled nutrients right synthetics
but i've slowly worked my way it's only
weaned my way off the bottles
and i started with uh organic blends
so i started with earth dust by the
green sunshine company
and uh instructions are pretty pretty
straightforward
they have a formula for base and they
have a formula for boost
the base is what you use when you first
amend into and during veg
and then use boost for flowering um so
that's what i would typically do i
forget what it was i think it's like two
to four tablespoons per gallon
or something like that for the base and
then the boost
had some pretty good results doing that
there's so many different organic blends
out there
we've got dr earth down to earth mr bees
trees
um there is a new one that i try to with
slow dirt
build the soil has their own craft blend
um that they call it uh you've used guya
green have you used any others
besides gaia green guy green and then
just the stuff from black swallow
we're i don't know if it's limited up
here but
i've got two good sources and and that's
who i rely on and whatnot
um i've heard down to earth stuff down
in the states is also really good to
work with
uh so it's it's really just looking at
where the amendment's coming from how
are they sourcing it like
one other thing about blends and this is
why i've decided to mix it myself is
pardon me blends tend to use a lot of
things like bone meal blood meal and
you have to think about where did those
come from
organically you know it's it's waste by
product
from the the food industry and
now it's good that there's a use for
that but does that necessarily mean you
want to be using that to grow
your your plants with and if it works
for you it works for you um you know
like
just side note to talk about blood meal
for a minute
um if you've got a nitrogen deficiency
in your plants
make up a quick tea using just a little
bit of blood meal and water that into
your plants
it's just like a synthetic nutrient at
that point because you're making it
bioavailable
because it is a dried blood that's
basically turned into a ground nutrient
so those those nutrients may have their
place but uh yeah no um
it's just it's about finding stuff and
local too like
the local stuff that you can get is way
better um
you know don't buy and ship nutrients
across the country if you don't have to
rice hulls for example i need to go and
get more rice holes for my growth so i'm
going to go to the local brewery
and get them there i can get 50 pounds
for 50 bucks you know
that's the thing about organic nutrients
they should be relatively inexpensive
uh a 50-pound bag of oyster shell flour
flowers gonna cost me i think seventy
five dollars
and that's going to feed my two 80
gallon beds
for the foreseeable future
so organics you know should be fairly
inexpensive to do in that regard so what
other advice do you have for growers who
are maybe switching from you know
synthetics over to the organic side of
things
learn about inoculation that's that's a
really important thing
because i've said this a couple times
throughout our chat here is those
nutrients take some time to become
available
and that process is made
faster is increased by inoculating your
medium
you can inoculate your medium through a
bacteria that comes in a powder form uh
or by doing a compost again i just
talked about compost teas
and it can be just that simple and the
way that i kick start my medium i just
did transplanting last night
was just to again compost on top a
little bokashi in the mix little earth
worm castings and just water in you know
and and that's
that's going to be the best way to do it
but
if you understand how inoculation works
in that you need to get
something living in that medium to start
eating these nutrients and providing
them in a
a more ionic form to your plants then
you're going to be sort of off to the
races
and then it's just planning planning
planning planning
thinking about what you want to do but
don't try and be a soil scientist find a
recipe
stick to that recipe and and then start
experimenting because then i think
you're going to find a much
better level of success that's really
good advice that's one thing we didn't
talk about is microbial inoculants do
you use any products
microbial inoculants or recharge mammoth
p anything like that
not so much um i've been thinking about
getting into the recharge just because i
hear
so many good things about it and i'm a
huge fan of the dude girls
podcast i like watching these guys but
uh no i
i rely mostly on just the compost and
this compost that i get the sea soil
seems to really do the trick but then to
that point if i could get another source
of compost it wouldn't be a bad idea
either
and using some vermicompost i've started
up a warm bin a couple months ago so
i've got fresh worm castings
and just adding in as many different
sources as
you can well matt thank you so much for
coming on to my channel tonight
and uh you know letting people know how
you do your grow i think there's a lot
of good information
for my audience most my audience is
beginners
kind of shifting over from the bottled
side of things to the organic side of
things and you provide a lot of really
good
useful information for them so thank you
for coming on here
oh chris absolutely happy to come and
chat and you know stop by my channel if
you want to come and see a conversation
that chris and i had about a week ago we
got to learn about chris and his grow
style
otherwise yeah you know stop on by and
say hi i'd love to have you over there
and again chris
thank you so much for giving the
opportunity to come and speak with your
viewers like this
no problem i will link matt's channel
down in the description section below
along with a couple videos that we kind
of talked about already talked about the
avocado attack
and uh there might be something else
that i'll link down in there that goes
to your channel for the viewers to watch
cool all right thanks again matt have a
good one you too sir
[Music]
you