coming up on Garden talk same way that
you would see a tropical forest Run
itself or a woodland run itself that's
how I tend to think of no-till is not
disturbing the soil and just let it do
it it was naturally designed to do so
I'll take 30 percent of good native soil
from my food forest and I'll use that to
create my beds because what better way
to introduce fungal and bacterial life
than to take it from somewhere that's
shown and proved that it can sustain
something way bigger than what you're
attempting to do I see no point in being
organic and going no-till and still have
to feed the same way that the synthetic
guys have to feed and still stay on the
same cycle that they have to feed
because somehow in nature this process
happens by itself I don't have to worry
about mixing bottles of nutrients and
having this and running out of this I
don't have to deal with any of that no
more now I can actually just enjoy
growing
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr grew it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 87. in this
episode I interview Beast Coast grower
he was on the podcast in the past
episode number 34 and a countless number
of you have requested for me to bring
him back for another episode in this
episode he talks about no-till farming
how he goes about doing it thanks to all
of you who support this podcast through
patreon if you'd like to support you can
do so by going to patreon.com Mr Grow it
before we get into it I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to vivosun for
sponsoring this episode vivosun recently
released the smart grow system this
Marco system helps streamline the
growing process by automating a stage of
growth requirements on and off schedules
spectral range airflow and circulation
and even records useful data about your
environment it is Wi-Fi capable and
connects to the vivosun app so you can
control your grow space from your
smartphone check out their website at
vivosun.com I will provide a link in the
YouTube description section below AC
Infinity is sponsoring this episode they
have two different series LED grow
lights the ion board and the ion grid
the ion board fixtures are board style
and use Samsung LM 301b diodes while the
ion grid series has an open Center
design and uses Samsung
lm301h diodes I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow lights and
you can use discount code Mr Grow it if
you're buying off their website AC
infinity.com that discount code works
for all AC Infinity items or discount
code Mr Grow at 15 if you're buying off
Amazon
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Beast Coast grower how you doing today
I'm great enjoying the day
same here so you're back for a second
time around first time you talked about
how you do plant training and the scrog
technique in particular which people
loved I mean that episode passed 67 000
views on YouTube and what pretty
mind-blowing uh there really have been a
countless number of people requesting
you to come back for a part two so here
we are thank you everybody yeah this
time around we're going to talk no-till
farming this is the way that you
currently grow and I'm excited to hear
all about it but first can you introduce
yourself for those that didn't catch the
first episode we did together yes so for
everybody tuning in I'm Beast Coast
grower420
um kind of in a permaculture that's what
I'm mainly known for doing a whole bunch
of fruits and vegetables and everything
also co-host to the green table podcast
um it's just good to be back glad you
guys like the first one
um that I'm really simple like everybody
else I'm just somebody who fell in love
with plants not pretty straightforward
there and so you've done a whole bunch
of different styles of growing in the
past but right now you're into no-till
farming so I have a lot of beginners and
intermediate folks that tune into my
podcast I do have some Advanced folks as
well but I feel like a majority is
beginner and intermediate some people
might not know what no-till farming is
so can you break it down for us what is
no-till farming well in my opinion
no-till farming is not disturbing the
soil not disturbing the mycelium layer
that's getting built not disturbing that
connection of roots that's happening
inside of the soil like some people will
go through break the soil up after each
round reamend it put it back uh no-till
is more of a sustainable way of growing
where you don't actually deserve disturb
the soil other than you transplanting
back into it so to me no-till is just
letting the Earth be the Earth that's
the best way I can describe it the same
way that you would see uh a tropical
forest Run itself or a woodland run
itself uh that that's how I tend to
think of no-till is not disturb Urban
soil and just let it do it it was
naturally designed to do what's the
downside of disturbing the soil uh break
mainly to mycelium that fungal Colony
that builds in the soil you you don't
really want to disturb that connection
because once the roots connected at it
starts pulling nutrients from distances
that it normally wouldn't have been able
to and the more you disturb that the
less microbes you have the less fungal
life that you have the more you're going
to have to amend like now you're going
to have to actually put food back into
it because you're not able to you don't
have that same access you normally would
yeah those mycelium networks can extend
for miles and miles and miles I watched
it's one of the biggest organisms on the
planet yeah yeah it's it's amazing how
big those networks are I mean you talked
about the old growth growth forests out
there and I watched the documentary
fantastic fungi not sure if you've seen
that one it talks all about it yeah and
uh it's crazy how how long the network
actually extends to and the fact that
nutrients can be can't be transported
from so far away into the plant you know
so and it's always weird how like they
discuss like microbes they discuss mpk
they discuss a whole bunch of other
stuff and for some reason fungal is
really kind of left out it's like that
that thing you don't really want to talk
about and I get it when it comes to like
a lot of mushrooms you don't exactly
know which you can eat that'll harm you
and what you can eat that'll help you so
I get it it's kind of a gray area but
when it comes to the plants this should
be one of the first topics that's spoken
about yeah good point I felt kind of I
felt kind of cheated after I seen
fantastic fungi like wait a minute have
we been focusing on a lot of the wrong
things today
yeah a lot of people are using you know
chemicals and salts that's one way of
growing or there's the organic side of
things and and nove-till goes right with
that right so let's start with the media
or medium uh what do you use for that
when no-till farming it's a bunch of
different ways you can start and I know
the way that I'm gonna say a lot of
people don't agree with you're going to
hear a bunch of people tell you that
that's crazy don't do that but what I
choose to do is I like the Pro mix BX uh
is people don't know there's a different
type of Pro mix there's the HP that's
the high porosity one that's the one you
would mainly use if you were going to do
more synthetic feeding the BX is a
heavier Pro mix that you can use that's
mainly used for like no-till if you're
going to build a system where that soil
is going to stay put you would rather go
with the pro-mix BX now another thing I
did in the beds that I know people won't
agree with is my beds are 30 native soil
so I'll take 30 of good native soil from
my food forest and I'll use that to
create my beds because what better way
to introduce fungal and bacterial life
than to take it from somewhere that's
shown and prove that it can sustain
something way bigger than what you're
attempting to do so I like to take 30
native soil and also add it but I also
use uh Happy Frog and
some I don't have a problem with ocean
Forest but it can run a bit hot so it's
something that I tread lightly on and if
I was to use it it would be in the very
bottoms of the beds but that that's the
medium that I like to go with is 30
native soil 70 Pro mix or maybe added at
70 maybe take 20 percent of that and use
maybe uh Fox Farm Happy Frog or ocean
force or maybe another one uh I know
they have the Malibu compost and they
have a other ones on build the soil you
can use as well yeah I hear about more
and more people using the native soil in
their backyard and just grabbing that
and rehabbing it I guess you can call it
and that's where the Pro mix comes in
here right right so that way it's not
too compact because a lot of these
plants of course we know that oxygen is
needed down in the root Zone some of
these native soils are going to be too
Compact and you're just not going to get
optimal growth out of it so adding in
pro-mix adding in some of the the bag
soil that you use could certainly be
beneficial on that Avenue
yeah it's going to come with your
perlite or your vermiculite uh some wood
chips are going to be inside of there
there's going to be things in there that
help to aerate and and let the water get
through that's another thing if you have
heavy clay soils you you stand that
chance of a lot of your water not being
able to even penetrate through if you
don't mix it right so that's the reason
I only go 30 instead of 50 50 because
you can still risk compaction if you go
50 50. depending on if you don't mix it
right so I'd rather stay on the safe
side with the 30 70. is this for your
indoor garden or outdoor Garden indoor
okay both actually I'll if I had to
build beds outdoor I would build them
the exact same way okay got it and then
what else do you abandon to the medium
begin like some folks will do some sort
of amendments that have you know
nutrients in that obviously break down
are you adding anything else into the
medium to begin yes uh when I first make
the beds um there's 444
um what is that down to earth yeah down
to earth 444 uh Lang benite kelp
and maybe some Epsom salt Epsom salt is
super important it is something they
always leave out when it's time to amend
is Epsom salt but that calcium uptake is
important and you can't do it without
magnesium so I make sure that I always
add some Epsom salt to them too and
besides that that's it the beds run
themselves after that I know oh and also
human do you know offhand the ratios
that you use like the amount you
actually put in to the soil at all or no
I know they're supposed to be uh you use
a cup of this or half a cup of this I
eyeball it I'm not gonna lie like a chef
or just a little bit of this something a
little sprinkle of this yes
making sure that 444 be the uh bulk of
it of whatever I'm going to be using
because that's the main source of mpk
that they're going to be getting the
langva Knight is really it's slow
release so the langba Knight will get
released later but that's a potassium
Source
um so so I make sure that I add that and
that and again it depends on the layer
because I layer my beds like lasagna so
at the bottom there will be a stronger
layer of amendments than it will be at
the top because you don't want to put
Plants right into hot soil like if
peppers are burned up tomatoes are burnt
you don't want to deal with that so you
you want to go as light as possible on
the top because plants don't need as
much nutrients as they say they do so
really light on the top and it can get
heavier as it gets to the bottom okay
and then you mentioned you're in beds or
do you also or you also grow pots I use
I have I have some smart pots too what
size do you use and well what size do
you recommend at least seven you're
gonna need at least seven gallons I know
most people say five uh five is a pretty
safe Zone but when you're gonna have to
keep bad in layers of hay and and other
things eventually you're just you're
going to need a little bit more so I
like to go with seven fill it to five
and and leave that last two because
eventually it'll get filled up over time
and I don't I don't want to deal with
that and wind up having to switch these
pots out so at bare minimum of seven but
I use 20s yeah I use threes five sevens
and the sevens are our easiest you know
see easier it is sevens are the best and
I'm gonna be trying tens and trying for
for larger ones as well so you know a
lot of people say that the larger the
grow pot or bed the easier it is it is
it is and you know what I have 20s but I
have them folded down to tens and after
each round you'll notice you'll have to
fold the bag up a little bit more fold
the bag up a little bit more so that's
what happens over time
oh that's interesting so you actually
folding down the sides of it and then
kind of unraveling It Grow off to grow
and yes because you're gonna have to add
another layer of mulch is going to
heighten it and you don't want to have
to water and then your water is running
off after a while
everything on the bottom will eventually
turn into a compost or worm castings and
that's what you'll be able to that
that's what's going to keep on raising
the height of it that's a good technique
so the hail disappear but it'll leave a
whole bunch of uh insect Frost or worm
castings whatever got it that makes
sense so when does your first feeding
happen and what does it consist of
but it so I'm going into the beds I'm in
veg I'm just getting the plants in there
for the first time yeah they're not
going to get a first feeding for a month
and then what do you typically do for
the that feeding
uh uh ferments so fpjs will be one of
the first things that I'm going to be
feeding because after they veg for that
month they'll be transitioning into the
flower stages and at that point that's
when I wanna I wanna boost the potassium
the phosphorus everything else so I'll
go with fpj feeding fpj fermented plant
juice okay so you're doing a natural
farming technique there for your first
feeding can you talk about fpj and like
how you go about doing that it just
makes sense for me to do ferments
because I'm vegan so most of the stuff
that I'm throwing away is reusable
anyway so I mainly just ferment the
fruits and the vegetables separately the
vegetables that I firm it that's for veg
the fruits that I ferment those are for
Bloom so you wind up with two almost
separate nutrients and you can use them
at whatever stage that you want to do
that works best I just normally never
need them in veg because they don't take
a lot of nutrients in veg especially in
big beds so my ferment process is
actually to take the fruit
um some people use brown sugar some
people use white sugar I like Agave I
don't know why I like Agave but it's
just something I always have on hand so
I'll take the Agave let it sit for a
week and a half after a week and a half
strain it take the juices from it dilute
that probably like three milliliters to
a gallon and and that's what I'll use to
feed what's the shelf life on fpj
truthfully I don't know they said the
longer you sit sometimes the better it
gets if you can store it properly but I
try to make mine small batches at a time
so I don't have them sitting around too
long to wind up just having to throw
them away so I'll do them as needed and
in the meantime any of that extra stuff
will just go into the worm bin but when
I know I want to do a feeding coming up
within the next week or so that's when
I'll go ahead and make the fpj that
makes sense and then are you just
following like the recipe that say Chris
Trump for example is a well-known
natural Farmer on YouTube and he has
step-by-step instructions on how to do
the technique or you just phone his
technique or is there some other thing
that you're doing besides what he does
I'll do mixture of what I can from some
of these people and what I can't because
they're in different areas they have
access to different live plants they
have like some people use banana flour
like there's no way for me to get that
where I'm at Banana bananas just don't
grow where I'm at so I just try to fuse
the two so I'll take some of the stuff
that I have access to from some of these
people and the rest of it is literally
just kitchen scraps and that that makes
life the easiest for me because I know
that uh if you're thinking like
cantaloupe you're talking about
something heavy in phosphorus and
potassium it's a big bulky fruit you
know phosphorus and potassium you
everyone knows bananas are full of
potassium so I I try to think of it by
nutrient value like what's inside of
these fruits that I'm going to be using
and what part of growing would I like to
add these in so I may be a little
different than some of the other ones
got it so you're first feeding is fpj
fermented plant juice and then after
that I assume that you're kind of
already flipped a flower at that point
so you're doing fermented fruit juice is
that right sure as your second feeding
yes yes I forgot there's a difference
there's the fermented fruit juice and
the fermented plant juice I say that the
plant juice is for veg and the fruit
juice is for flour okay yeah I've heard
a lot of people that do the natural
farming techniques that's what they've
been doing or you could just make a full
spectrum blend and you basically have a
one-part nutrient that you can use all
the way through huh okay that's awesome
that's pretty cool and then you're doing
a third feeding after that I try my best
not to have to feed
um so it's rare that I feed I'm straight
water from beginning to end like if they
go check the rounds that I have recently
those are ran off water for the most
part I'll feed if I decide to but if not
they still they still hold steady that's
mainly just the microbial feeding or if
I want to boost the bacterial fungi or
something but they don't exactly need
the feedings after you build the beds
right if you if you've got the worms in
there and if you're doing the method
that I use then you're constantly making
worm castings and Foods you don't have
to worry about it so how do you know
when how do you know when to feed feed
it's really up to you so if you're in
weak if you're in week two or a flower
and you're trying to get uh more flower
sites and more flowers to develop and
you want to boost that you see you see
it and you think you just want to boost
that go ahead and add a feeding if you
get into week five and you want to do a
little bit more bulking feel free to go
ahead and use the same way that you
would use any other PK booster is the
same way that you would use this the
only difference is you're not feeding in
between time you're only targeting those
specific points where you just want to
boost something because I I see no point
in being organic and going no-till and
still have to feed the same way that the
synthetic guys have to feed and still
stay on the same cycle that they have to
feed because somehow in nature this
process happens by itself no no one's
there feeding anything and yet these
trees grow to hundreds of feet and they
do just fine I try to replicate that
same method understood yeah I know a lot
of people doing the natural farming
technique and no-till but they're also
doing like some people use the organic
Blends and they'll top dress at certain
times typically some people do got 30
days into it to do a top dress then
every 30 days after that they'll do a
top dress and they'll just really just
top dress in the water after that so it
seems to be like the similar frequency
to what you're doing with the ferments
so would you say that's just kind of an
alternate way to go about the no-till
yes and the ferments are readily
available immediately like the reason
that they have to feed 30 days in or are
the time after that is because that has
to take time to break down so if I'm
gonna want a feeding week two I have to
go two weeks back and already amend it
so two weeks later they're finally
starting to uptake it it's finally
broken down is finally available when it
comes to ferments if I feed today they
took that today
so I don't have to worry about it again
afterwards every time I'm watering
afterwards I'm pretty much just diluting
what's already in there God it's a big
difference there and that's definitely a
pro having that readily available you
know especially if you've got a problem
and you need to fix it because in soil
the hardest thing is running into a
problem because sometimes it can take
days before you can fix it and it might
take weeks before it shows that fix
shows up like you're running low on on
nitrogen you you add some nitrogen two
weeks later they'll finally start
Greening up but for the two weeks in
between that your plans ain't gonna be
looking good
I think a lot of people start off
organic and they run into the point
where they're seeing deficiencies in
their plants and they'll top dress but
like you said it's gonna you're gonna
wait those two weeks in order for it to
break down I don't think a lot of people
know about the alternative of fpj and
ffj the ferments uh and then being
readily available so instead of
resorting back to synthetic nutrients
the fact that fast acting stuff which I
think a lot of people doing might want
to consider going after a ferment since
that is fast reacting than just top
dressing and waiting until the Organics
break down exactly it's just a cheat
sheet like if I if I need something
right now and I know that I created this
ferment out of a whole lot of greens I
know it's loaded with nitrogen and if I
feed this right now they can uptake this
nitrogen right now uh but if I decide to
give them some 444 it's going to be a
week or two before they get ready to
uptake that and something else is most
people aren't dealing with deficiencies
when it comes to Soy they're dealing
with toxicities so like you'll go get
your happy frog or you whatever you're
gonna the gate you pop your plan in but
you're also going to run the fox farm
nutrient line right along with it what
they don't tell you is to add water
until that runs its course because
there's there's tons of food in the
Happy Frog and the ocean Forest already
so imagine imagine you're trying to feed
on top of everything that's already
available there you wind up burning your
plant but it shows up like a deficiency
because you can't tell the difference so
I think most people are not dealing with
deficiencies depending on what they're
using they're dealing with toxicities
and over watering yep I ran into it 10
years ago and 12 years ago when I first
started you know not not realizing that
the dark dark green leaves are actually
toxic toxicity right yeah now are you
running into any toxicity issues using
fpj or ffj nope because I don't use it
often okay so you're controlling it now
if I used it if I used it more maybe
because all the nutrients also available
in the soil but I haven't ran into that
problem
I go I'm I'm really easy I try to go as
light as possible on the plants because
there's so much available there and when
you're adding things like ferments that
is feeding the microbes and bacteria
they start releasing more nutrients
available for the plants you you don't
have to really worry about that I think
the synthetic way of us learning just
has us thinking we constantly have to
keep feeding our eventually they're
going to run out but there's so much
food available in that soil that you you
wouldn't believe it especially in a bed
and a pot maybe not as much but it you
you in a four by eight bed that holds
hundreds of gallons of soil like yeah
yeah you're good and that's where having
a bigger container can make things
easier because there's more availability
right yes so you mentioned worms in your
garden I want to get a little bit deeper
into that because a lot of people are
utilizing worms and either containers or
beds when they're growing organically
now there are several different types of
worms that you can use right red
wigglers European night crawlers African
nightcrawlers what do you use for worms
in your bed I choose the red red
wigglers but I also do add earthworms as
well but they serve two different
purposes
um red regulars are mainly going to be
at the top they're going to deal with
the composting the things that land on
that top layer they're going to break
all of that downturn that into castings
for you the earthworms on the other hand
they're gonna stay a bit lower and
they're they're going to eat the peat
they're going to eat they eat other
things they handle other processes but
for that top layer to get broken down as
fast as possible you're going to want
the red wigglers or the African
nightcrawl you're going to want the
smaller worms
the thinner worms are mainly used for
composting the bigger thicker worms are
mainly used to create tunnels and do
other things inside of the soil so I do
a mixture of both but I mainly focus on
the red wigglers now are you just
getting the worms from your native soil
that 30 percent does that include worms
are you Outsourcing it are you buying it
somewhere whether it be from a local
Walmart in the bait section or whatever
or ordering it online like Uncle Jim's
worm farm is a common source a lot of
people go to where do you get your worms
Uncle Jim yep so I I'll get my worms
from there but I I am still adding worms
all the time like if it's a rainy day
and I know it's done raining I'll go out
lift some bricks up take some of those
worms and bring them right back in as
well just to just to keep them
reproducing instead of having to keep on
adding them why why when they're free
I'll pay for them the first time when I
add them but after that I'm never paying
to add worms again they're gonna I'm
gonna give them every reason to stay
that's another thing people add worms
and give them nothing to do afterwards
like you're going to add composting
worms to it but you're not giving them
anything to compost what are they going
to do eventually they're going to leave
you're going to start digging through
your soil and you won't find worms
anymore and you're going to wonder
what's going on well you sent a bunch of
workers to a job site and there was no
work to do so they went home
that's funny I I started vermicomposting
last year so I got about a year under my
belt and uh yeah I'm at the point where
I can actually just take some worms from
my vermicompost bin which is it now a
year-round thing and then put it into my
containers as needed so it's a good way
to have them on hand at all times just
have a firmer compost bin exactly and
then every time that you have to clean
it out to harvest the the castings and
everything when you add those castings
they're going to have a bunch of little
worms and eggs and stuff inside of them
and they're going to re-inoculate the
Bed full of worms as long as you got a
layer for them to live in as long as you
got some bedding for them to live in
they'll handle the rest like I added a
thousand worms per four by eight I know
a lot of people would have said use a
whole bunch more but no I added a
thousand her 4x8 gave them a proper
environment to live in and now there's
there's more than I could ever count
like you'll lift you'll lift a layer
ahead in this thousands of worms yeah
because they'll reproduce right what do
they make they have to make contact with
each other and then they uh they
reproduce that way or something like
that I think so yeah but they they all
they lay eggs too you'll see them all
through the uh through the hay when you
lift it they lay a bunch of eggs inside
of there and that's why you need that
and a lot of people use an avocado Tech
I'm not sure if you've heard about
avocado yeah that's uh I have it's a way
to attract the worms into one area right
so they'll go after the avocado and then
uh and then once they're making that
contact and they're reproducing so you
can get faster reproduction just by
putting avocado face down on the top of
the medium yeah that that works too
cover crops let's get into that next
what do you use for cover crops and when
do you plant them uh there's this a a
medium the as soon as I make the beds I
make a layer of cover crop that's the
very first thing I do before any other
plants are gone in before anything I'm
going to grow a really thick layer of
cover crop really thick like purposely
I'm gonna let it overgrow itself because
that's going to be the first layer of
food and mulch for those beds because
once I hate that over that becomes the
first layer of food going in is that
layer of cover crop that happens right
there but uh Harry vetch um the daikon
radishes the Red Clovers the the snow
peas the the regular I think it's like a
20c variety that use and that's what I
go along with where did you get the 20c
variety was it locally or probably
Amazon it was like a non it was a
non-GMO uh pack from Amazon a cover crop
and it was like a 20 seed blend I think
I showed it on my Instagram or something
the the actual pack of it nice nice yeah
a lot of people buying the 12 seed blend
from Builders soil that seems to be very
popular I've used that before too that
works well too I was just in a rush and
I needed it faster so I chose to go with
Amazon to get them because I needed it
faster but the build the soil one works
perfect as well
you said you're planting the cover crops
right away so as the cover crops growing
up you have to eventually cut it back
right
when do you make that call to cut back
your cover crop uh when they pass the
Ring of the bed so there's a distance
between where my soil starts and where
the actual bed is once they pass that
that uh that arm rest basically on the
beds that's when it's time to hang them
over some people just cut them back I
hit them over completely that's going to
be the first layer of food the worms and
bugs are gonna love me after I smother
that underneath there they're gonna go
crazy and all of that turns into just a
massive layer of worm castings later on
like you'll go back at the end of that
round and then to just be black
underneath there that's another source
of nutrition right once you put that
mulch layer over it and it dies off and
the worms are going after it and the
microbes and all that stuff that's
turning into usable nutrients that's the
plant can uptick yes and on top of it
the plants themselves that that want
ended up getting hated over their Roots
start to release nutrients once the once
they notice that the plant's dead so
they'll start to let go of some of the
nutrients that they've been holding on
to and you're watering in a worm casting
tea every time you get fresh water so I
can say that I'm not feeding I'm just
giving them fresh water all the time but
I'm not just giving them fresh water
there's such a big layer of thick layer
of worm castings underneath that hay
that I'm watering in a worm casting tea
every single time that I water are you
just using the hay as a mulch layer
there are several different things that
you can use I'm not sure if you're
you're just using that is it barley
straw or what exactly is it yeah
or Alfalfa some people use Alfalfa
there's there's a couple different ones
that you can use but yeah but on top of
that I still do chop and drop too so
when I go to Leaf strip or I lollipop
and clean the bottoms all of that goes
to the soil goes right to the soil does
it go on top of the mulch layer are you
lifting up that mulch layer and then
sliding it underneath if it's a new
layer of of straw Then I then I'll
purposely go underneath and put it
because it takes a little while for that
uh straw to flatten uh but but if it's
already been in and it's kind of flat
and compacted already then I'll just
throw it right on top it'll still serve
its purpose eventually it'll just
disappear or it'll turn into a black
spot on top of the straw and then
that'll let you know that it's now a
bunch of insect Frost and worm castings
okay have you used any some people use
wood chips as a mulch layer have you
done that at all or no I don't like wood
chips because since I have to transplant
back into these beds I never want to
risk this these wood chips getting mixed
back into the soil because uh they'll
start to Leach nitrogen they'll cause a
whole bunch of issues being inside of
your soil only good for the very top
layer of your soil if I was outdoor then
maybe I would go with wood chips I
wouldn't have as much of a problem with
it but indoor I'm not even messing
around with it I'm just gonna go with
straw
if I use wood chips it's literally
because I put them outside to inoculate
them with some microbes and brought them
back afterwards that's the only time
I'll be using them understood and what
type of water do you use when doing
no-till are using oral water distilled
tap water well water what are you using
for a water source they gonna chew me up
in the comments over this one tap
I I don't get what everyone's big issue
with the tap water is go look at your
lawn go look at your garden in the
backyard go look at anywhere else and
it's It's tap water that's doing that
like tap water is not the worst thing in
the world I think mine comes out at
around like 225 or something I think
it's all calcium and whatever it's not I
have mycelium to be able to disinfect it
that's anti-bacterial properties inside
of it I'm not exactly too worried about
that like the once you learn what
mycelium actually does with one layer of
skin compared to ours with like seven
you start thinking about things
completely different like am I am I
willing to waste a five to one ratio on
our RO water I'm not I'm not willing to
waste five gallons of tap water to make
me one gallon of usable RO water that's
that no I'm cool on that so I'll just
tap water right out the right out the
hose I think mine comes out at three to
one
but still that's that's crazy as far as
the uh yeah I'm wasting three gallons
just to get one of of possibly some
better water but possibly tip for
anybody doing that you can always take
your drain line of the RO put into a
bucket and use it elsewhere right your
outdoor plants for example some people
like oh you're wasting it with RO water
but uh you know most people's drains are
going right back into local water
Municipal system so it's not really
being wasted yep and now now if I had
bad water like I hear some people's PPM
at the top and I'm like I wouldn't use
that either mine is 485. I I would
filter that in some way shape or form
like I don't care if I created my own
charcoals filters or or no matter in
some way I would filter that water yeah
mine comes out at 485 PPM so I'm just
like I've got the RO system I have to do
something it's just yeah in your case it
makes sense it's just a little bit safer
because if I get through if I start
watering my plants I've done this before
I water it with tap water trying to get
through it plants are struggling and I
need the yield right I need the end
result off of it and I'm messing up my
plants all of a sudden quality goes down
the drain well that now my stash is
going down the drain too somewhat so
exactly so I I safe side it although I
am revisiting the whole tap water and
trying to use it straight from the top
and I'm trying to get some sort of
result in there and I'm hoping that
organic no-till that I'll be able to get
away with it you know it just depends on
what's coming out of it like if you're
getting a bunch of like iron in your
water you're gonna come out with a
problem that that that you won't even
recognize like you'll look at it and be
like am I over watering am I
underwatering like what's going on I've
seen another grower deal with it where
they were trying to keep the water from
the dehumidifier so they would use the
water from the dehumidifier and they
were wondering why the room kept on
having problems and it was because the
extra iron that was coming through the
coils of the dehumidifier that iron was
in the water and just the smallest
percentage of it was burned in the
plants because they don't need the
amount of iron that's coming out of that
it's a small percentage to us it's a
large percentage to a plant that doesn't
exactly need it so if I had worse water
then yeah I'd have to have some kind of
system to stop it
that's interesting that that grower came
across an issue where iron was leaking
in through their dehumidifier I've
actually come across studies where I
think it was by like Quest dehumidifier
humidification systems that company they
have a study on theirs they did testing
and everything seemed to be clear on
multiple dehumidifiers but uh but it's
kind of like a as a biased Source I
guess you can say because they're
selling that equipment right Quest also
has a completely different system than
the person who was using this
dehumidifier was using that wasn't a
quest well well they tested other brands
as well I forget exactly what the oh and
then they found out that it was they
found out it was cool yeah I think
copper was like there was like Trace
Amounts of copper but that was it like
parts per billion or something like that
so like very small amounts but I have to
revisit that study it's interesting that
that grower came across that and the
moment that they stopped using the water
that they were reclaiming from the
dehumidifier the problem went away in
the garden like this so I could have
just been there dehuman humidifier but
there's there's just instances where
you're gonna need a filter like I'm not
just one of those people that's just all
or nothing we got to be for the
environment we I get that and I love
that but uh if my tap order is coming
out at 480 I'm doing something about
that like I I can't just feed that to my
plants like you you mix three bottles of
nutrients and it comes out to 480 like I
can't have that coming fresh out to tap
into my plants right yeah I mean the
elements some cations you know if
there's excess of some elements they
could lock out other elements inhibit
the uptake of other elements so if you
have a whole bunch of cations of calcium
for example it could be inhibiting the
uptake of magnesium or some of the other
cations so that balance is certainly
important now are you phing your water
no
I think I think my pH of the water is
like 6.3 or something so it comes out in
the range that is acceptable for for the
plants that you're growing and then the
language and stuff like that buffer it
once it gets inside of the soil so it's
fine by the time it touches if the water
out of your TAP came in at like 8.0 pH
would you pH adjustment I'm lowering it
yeah
100 yeah again I just lucked up and
winded up with a situation where
everything just kind of worked the way
it was but I know everybody's situation
isn't going to be like that so if your
tap water is coming out way too acidic
or way too alkaline do something about
that I get it you want to be as natural
as possible find a natural way to lower
it like there's natural ways to lower
your pH as well but it does pH Up and
Down ain't the worst thing in the world
uh get your pH in range to make sure
that your plants are happy that's the
that's the end goal is to have happy
plants so don't be so encased in I don't
want to use anything that you you're
willing to sacrifice the round don't do
that some people worried about using
those few drops of phosphoric acid lower
their pH and they think it's just wiping
out their micro population which isn't
true you know it's just some
misinformation that's been passed along
generation to generation and it's been
debunked over and over and over again so
yeah if those folks that are in living
soils you know growing organically you
can use a little bit of pH Up and PH
down and um it's not going to
drastically harm your population to
where your plants are going to be all
screwed up and you're not going to get a
harvest no it's not going to destroy all
of your microbes it's not going to
destroy your fungal colonies and all
other funny stuff that they decided to
tell you guys none of that is going to
happen over a few drops of some ph up or
down it is not the end of the world and
you guys being like 30 gallons like and
you're worried about a few drops like no
this is going to make a difference now
do you incorporate any sugars into your
garden at all when I feed the ferments
okay so just that you're not doing any
like some people do molasses no it's in
the ferment so there there's no point of
adding it separately if I if I want to
do a sugar feed and I'll just add some
of that makes sense so it's kind of one
last step yep and the only time I'm
feeding that anyway is latent flour like
there's no other time where the plant is
going to really need some sugars are you
adding in any microbial inoculants at
all imos okay yeah so I'll go and get
the microbes and stuff myself but do I
use any specific product no okay so no
specific product of microbial napkins
but you're doing IMO the Imo's process
can you actually break that down for
those that don't know what IMO is uh
indigenous microorganisms so outside in
nature there's plenty of fungal and
bacterial life if you know how to go and
find it some people uh they'll sit like
rice out or something and they'll
collect it that way some people will
take the leaf mulch lift it up find the
fungal colonies take that I cheat and
either use a paper bag or cardboard on a
rainy day I'll let it sit out there and
then I'll go back later on lift the
cardboard and it'll just be covered in
fungi and I'll shred that into pieces
bring it back up Let the worms go
through it and everything and it'll
inoculate the beds themselves
that's pretty cool I never heard about
that cardboard technique yeah cheat
sheet so if you got some dirt just go
out there Lay It Lay It Down Let It Rain
on top of it or water it yourself when
you come back in a few days later as
that box is kind of sort of starting to
break down you'll lift it up and it'll
just be covered with fungi on one side
of it enough to try that out I live in
the desert so I'm like oh yeah dirt out
here you'll be you'll be surprised which
you can find yeah I mean it doesn't work
maybe that'll that'll bring up some of
those microbes uh and then I'll maybe
I'll be able to use them in my garden in
the future because now they're protected
from the Sun now they have uh something
they can latch onto and you'll be
surprised how much of it it is I was
shocked like when I first seen the
method done I went and tried it myself
and then afterwards I looked and I'm
like yo I think everyone should know
about this I even took the dirt layer
that was underneath it because that was
fully covered in mycelium afterwards so
I even took that with me as well that's
awesome that's really cool that that
works how about aerated compost teas or
nutrient teas plant teas manure teas
anything like that do you do uh I'll do
a tea
probably once every couple of rounds
so I uh main it's mainly just for root
health is what I'm doing it for it's not
for readily available nutrients or
anything it's mainly just for like root
health so I'll do like stinging nettle
uh maybe a little bit of neem
um I like and maybe just some worm
castings or some IMO or something that's
the that's the most I'm gonna do I try
to keep it as simple as possible like I
didn't want to take no-till and turn it
into synthetic growing all over again
by having to do five six different
things throughout the stage of flower
like my entire last two rounds was just
water I didn't even feed them so for the
teas that you do just to dig a little
bit deeper into that how do you brew the
tea uh I I have like uh you get the mesh
um put everything inside of there and
Brew it just like everybody else hang it
off the side of your res and and let it
Brew for 24 hours sorry what what I
missed what it actually consists of is
it consists of worm castings and then
you said neem in there as well neem yup
I'll use neem for a root health and it's
also a good nitrogen Source
um and stinging nettle because one thing
you're going to worry about and no-till
is going to be fungus gnats and a nice
easy way to get rid of fungus gnats is
to brew sting and nettle teas because
they don't like it they can't stand it
so when you water in stinging nettle
teas into your soil you're kind of
decreasing your chance of having that
fungus night outbreak because it it'll
it'll destroy them for you so that's the
most I'll do if if I do it now I'm not
telling no one to not do it uh please
use all the aerated teas that you want
to the more the better like I'm not
going to tell you guys not to do that
but I just don't do it often yeah this
is just your style of growing right
there are so many different ways to do
it and that's a good question for the
audience actually tuning in right now if
you're doing no-till or if you're going
organically in general what way do you
do it let us know down in the comment
section below some of your techniques do
you do the same techniques as Beast
cross grower here or are you doing your
own thing a different way to go about it
let us know I love going through the
comment section and reading and just
seeing the different methods that are
out there because it's so many and they
poke holes in a lot of your theory
sometimes like sometimes times you'll
have a way of doing something and
somebody will be like hey instead of
that why don't you just try this and
you're like
genius yeah genius how did I not how did
I not think of that like how did I not
see myself running into this problem or
that problem like you know what you're
absolutely right thank you so I still
watch a whole bunch of no-till Growers I
don't think I know it all I love all of
the no-till Growers out there Queen of
the sun grown full of knowledge people
like that I nerd out on all day IPM I
want to get into that before we wrap
things up here I know this wasn't on our
original list of questions but uh if
you're comfortable talking about it you
know one of the common concerns of
people going to organic so going to
no-till is that they think they're gonna
have bugs more prone to pests do you do
anything in particular in order to
prevent pests the native soil
so you'll you'll find the area that is
loaded with plants and you will see Mite
damage on some of those plants you'll
see mildew on some of those plants
you'll see bugs eating on some of those
plants and then you'll see a section
that's just pristine
that lets you know that there are
predators there and large numbers
keeping the pests down I want the soil
from that section that's going to bring
in all of the predator mites and
everything else that I need but if need
be I would also release predator mites
and that's the the most I would do I try
to stay away from spraying anything in
no-till situations and I just haven't
had no bug problems mainly because I
brought the good bugs to fight the bad
bugs some people want to fight it with a
spray bottle I don't have time to be
doing that but that's a lot of spraying
especially when you got dense canopies
and you tight spaces you don't want to
be going in there spraying all the time
so I just make sure that I find areas
when I bring the native soil that like I
specifically look for areas heavy in bug
damage and then I look for an area
that's not heavy and Bug damage that's
nearby and I'll know that this area has
more Predators than that area apparently
because you can see the Damage Done to
one and not done to the other so I want
the area that has nothing done to it
that's right next to it
that's the that's the best way I can
think of it yeah so I know I'm bringing
a whole bunch of predators and I've seen
them I've looked at them under
microscopes yeah so there's Predators
all over the place in my garden and I'm
perfectly okay with that and I would
release some too if I didn't have that
that would be my IPM right there is to
release Predators or use like a jidon
spray uh maybe use a genome wedding
agent with maybe like a compost tea or
something uh they're safer soaps that
you can use and spend aside and the rest
of that
I don't like doing all of that
so so far so good if I run into that
problem I may wind up using a different
product but so far so good that makes
sense so we're getting up towards the
end of the episode here a couple more
things I want to ask you actually one of
them do you have any advice on no-till
farming that we didn't talk about here
in this episode or just general advice
for beginners
do your best
to maybe use beds if you can
um like like the pots do work don't get
me wrong the pots work amazing but if
you're going to be doing no-tilling this
soil is not going to be going anywhere
anyway then just go ahead and use the
beds there's no point in still cleaning
up your floors in between all of these
pots and everything when you could just
have if you got a 4x4 tent they have
four by four beds you got a five by five
tent they got five by five beds
um there's really no point in in doing
Pots if you don't have to now if you may
have to move these plants at some point
in time you got inspectors coming
through or people coming by you might
have to move these one day go ahead and
use your pots but if not use beds um you
kind of save yourself from over watering
it's a little harder to over water at
that because you're just kind of going
by Judgment of how much water these beds
need and they hold a lot too so it's
kind of hard to over water
um and
these plants don't need as much
nutrients as you're thinking
that's another word of advice that I'll
give you guys like if you're if you're
going to do anything close to the method
that I said where you're amending when
you make the soil or you're starting
with a super soil use fresh water and
maybe have some salt for as long as
possible
let let the nutrients run its course
because you're going to start feeding in
there you're going to get dark green
leaves you're going to deal with
nitrogen burn you're going to deal with
all sorts of problems uh if you you go
ahead and start feeding like you're in a
synthetic system that nutrient needs to
run its course
less is more a hundred percent less is
more like you guys heard I dilute the
ferments three milliliters per gallon
that's not a lot at all that's not a lot
at all and it but yet it's more than
enough because we're talking about a
pure concentrate so at three milliliters
a gallon it's still plenty I have yet to
venture down the fpgas and ffjs but it's
on my list of things to do I think
probably next grow is when I'm going to
try it out for the first time and I'm
excited because it's something I haven't
done before you know I've been gardening
for 12 years now and I haven't done that
and there's actually still other ways of
growing that I haven't done and just
doing these different ways it's just
been so fun and that's why I encourage
folks listening in just have fun with it
you know don't try not to get
overwhelmed with all the different ways
to go about it just
just try one way and then see what
happens and make adjustments from there
because check back last episode I was in
one gallon pots of cocoa on tables with
watering systems and said soil grows too
slow and everything but outdoor I'm a
100 no-till grower so I'm like let I
have an extra room let me just try
no-till indoor and just see how it is
and I and I'm gonna I'm gonna go with
the stun method sheer total utter
neglect I'm gonna build these beds the
way that I'm thinking I'm gonna build
them and I'm gonna give the plants
straight water the entire round just to
see how much nutrients is actually here
with the entire round and it was
beautiful converted all the other rooms
in no-till after and that's just how
because it was more fun it freed me up
on more time I don't have to worry about
no watering systems getting clogged I
don't have to worry about mixing bottles
of nutrients and having this and running
out of this I don't have to deal with
any of that no more now I can actually
just enjoy growing so do you have
definitely a big change from last year
we actually recorded that first episode
October of last year so one year ago
well is when we actually filmed that
episode so I'll definitely have that
episode linked down in the YouTube
description section below if you're on
one of the podcast platforms just search
for it you'll find it let's uh let's
wrap things up here how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
upcoming in the future uh you can find
me Beast coastgrower420 on everything uh
and you can also find me Sundays at the
green table podcast
um coming up in the future
um a lot of organic talk a lot of
regenerative agriculture talk uh a lot
of ways to show you guys how to be more
sustainable and a game where it's
forcing you to have to be more
sustainable like eventually there's
going to be no way around it that's how
I got here because it's almost it's
almost no way around it but to become as
efficient as possible and I think this
method is the most efficient method that
there is no-till in some way shape or
form or organic gardening in some way
shape or form to me is going to be more
viable than any other system that you're
going to be using so a lot of that
coming up and more episodes with the
green table sweet well that's I have a
link to your channel down in the YouTube
description section below if you enjoyed
this episode click that Thumbs Up Button
also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already every single weekend I'm
releasing one of these new Garden Talk
podcast episodes and I would love for
you to tune in to future episodes Beast
coast once again man thanks so much for
coming on and spilling your knowledge
about no-till you know last episode we
had was the scrog technique and you
killed it man so many people love that a
lot of great information I think this
episode there's a lot of great
information as well something completely
different and thanks once again one more
thing yeah go ahead I'm still using that
exact same scrog method so the same
scrog technique that I was talking about
using with the one gallon pots of cocoa
in the water I still use the exact same
scrog method now I transferred that
right over the only thing that changed
was the medium that's awesome all right
well thanks again and I hope you enjoy
the rest of your day yes same to you
peace out everyone catch you in the next
episode Peace