welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody if you
that don't know me my name is Chris aka
Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
Garden Talk podcast this episode number
111 in this episode I interview Luna
witcom she has been gardening for 15
years and has experience with indoor
outdoor greenhouse and field cultivation
she is a writer for conk magazine and
her methodologies revolve around organic
gardening she has knowledge on
microscopy biology entomology Agronomy
botney and enzymology in this episode
she talks about organic gardening
methods that she does in order to help
improve the taste and smell of the final
product if you want to see highlights of
these podcast episodes search Garden
talk clips on YouTube that is a channel
dedicated to short clips of these
podcast episodes one of my goals of this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that that being said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
my entire ventilation system is AC
Infinity I have their inline fan ducting
carbon filter and their controller I
love the controller 69 Pro with
temperature humidity and VPD programming
and having control of different fan
speeds this makes it so much easier to
control my grow environment their
controller 69 pro version also controls
their oscill fans grow lights and
humidifier the discount code Mr Grow 15
works on both Amazon and their website
AC infinity.com stash blend I've been
using stash blend for over a year now
and it's awesome one of the things that
I really like is that it saves me money
it's a whole bunch of different inputs
in one so I no longer have to go out
there and buy a silica bottle then a
separate seaweed bottle beneficial
bacteria then a separate one for microle
fungi all of that plus more is in this
one blend go go to stash blend.com to
learn more about it and I also have a
link down in the YouTube description
section below and we are back welcome to
the Garden Talk podcast today I am
joined with Luna whip how you doing
today pretty good thanks for having me
on and thanks for coming on so I
initially came across you through the
FCP Channel and I I think you've been on
there multiple times and I mean if you
just search your name into YouTube
there's several different talks and you
have a lot of knowledge when it comes to
gardening more on the advanced side of
things which really piqu my interest
because we do have uh quite a bit of
advanced folks here that tune in to this
podcast and I know you're all into the
organic side of things that's really
what I want to get into today is kind of
organic gardening and I know a lot of
folks their goal is really to bring out
a good taste and smell in the final
product so kind of utilizing these
methods and kind of how we go here if
you have any tips along those lines
please feel free to mention them because
that is certainly an end goal for a lot
of folks but before we get into the
questions can you just give us a little
bit of background about yourself kind of
tell us how you got into gardening and
stuff like that yeah sure uh so my name
is Luna Wickham I specialize in Agronomy
soil biology microscopy enology um I do
a lot of work on building soil and
making nutrients available in soil
through balancing nutrients through the
soil mineral balancing Theory as well as
making them available with mimicking
root exit dates adding amino acids
enzymes
carbohydrates uh and processes that
promote biology consume nutrients cycle
them through their different processes
and make them available to plants to
promote Health Vigor flavor and Aroma I
originally got into gardening um through
growing medicinal plants I started
cultivating in 2009 I've been
cultivating for 15 years um doing
outdoor living soil outdoor organic
cultivation um growing in ground using a
lot of teas a lot of different
inoculants a lot of compost um and
really forming an alliance with nature
to promote you know healthy vigorous
medicine like to to grow real medicine
that's therapeutic flavorful enjoyable
for people um did this in Northern
California I've also done it in southern
Oregon I have experience doing
consulting on hemp farms and growing in
green houses indoor outdoor um using
synthetic nutrients also using organic
nutrients I kind of just touched on all
of that good stuff there so I'm GNA ask
you a controversial question right off
the bat and uh do it I
like many Growers claim that growing
with Organic inputs and utilizing
microbiology results in the plants
producing a better taste and smell they
swear by it they say hey organic way
better than anything bottle grown what's
your take on that I subscribe to that
ideology also I've done hydroponic
cultivation for many years um I've also
done living soil and organic cultivation
from my understanding of how it kind of
results in better flavor and Aroma is
that each of these compounds that
produce flavonoids they produce Aroma
they produce you know the different
diversities of smell they all require a
complex chain of compounds prior to
their formation to be able to be
expressed genetically expressed in a
plant so if you're lacking any piece in
the chain that's required to
biosynthesize these compounds they
simply just won't synthesize so in a
hydroponic growing environment we have a
very we have a much more narrow profile
of nutrients and compounds we have our
major ones you know that you hear of the
NPK the calcium the Magnesium um but
when it comes down to different forms of
nitrogen different forms of phosphorus
different forms of calcium living soil
has a much broader diversity of these
compounds while also including a
diversity of amino acids A diversity of
enzymes A diversity of organic acids and
these compounds all have uh they create
unique physiological responses in plants
and they produce different genetic
Expressions so when you have a larger
diversity of these compounds it allows
the plant to biosynthesize different
flavonoids and and you know volatile
organic compounds the things that
produce Aroma like Esters phenols thols
which produce a different profile a more
depth profile of Aroma and I believe
that that's more achievable and more
likely to be achievable in a living soil
setting in an organic setting than in a
hydroponic setting however that's going
to be based on user un like the user
success so just because you're growing
an organic doesn't necessarily mean
you're going to end up with a better
product um and a lot of the times it's
more difficult for people to grow in
organic settings because it can be a
little bit more complicated um and you
may not result uh have an end result
that is you know more flavorful has more
Aroma more aromatic so I think that it's
potentially possible that you can have
more flavor more smell um but it doesn't
necessarily mean that you well
understood that's a really good way to
break it down and I think you've
revealed some information here that
hasn't been revealed on any of the past
episodes now one of the things a
follow-up question to this is uh and I
know we're going to get into microbes
here in a little bit but uh this relates
to microbes is what is their impact to
the taste and smell that the plants
Express so microbes during their
processes of decomposing organic matter
they secrete enzymes that are key
components and building blocks um or key
components to processes that provide the
diversity of organic compounds needed by
plants to produce different flavonoids
and Aromas they also they secrete um
they secrete enzymes they secrete
carbohydrates they break down organic
matter but they also convert particular
organic acids into other organic acids
they can also break certain organic
acids down um so they're no longer
viable are no longer useful by the plant
but they can also stabilize organic
acids and like I mentioned earlier they
organic acids have specific plant
physiologic stimulating effects so
microbes with their interaction with the
soil and the diversity of compounds in
the soil the nutrients the um organic
acids like I had said and the different
the broad profile of these different
things that exist inside of the soil
their their role changes the composition
of these things and allows for a wider
diversity
so on top of that also microbes can be
what's called endic and what that means
is they can exist inside the cell of the
plant and inside the cell of the plant
they also do these processes but an
important part of this P like an
important piece of this puzzle is that
they also can create phyto hormones so
phyto hormones they trigger specific
actions in the plant they can trigger um
like P pest defense stress responses
they can promote different flowering
stages they can Pro promote you know
node elongation you know bud swelling
and stuff like that they're made by the
plant but they you like the plant and
the microb work together to create these
compounds they can be created in the
soil they can also be created in the
cell of the plant so we have our our
decomposing microbes that do what I had
mentioned but we also have our endic
microbes which can exist inside the cell
of the plant and produce these phyto
hormones directly at the cell to
stimulate the plant to do these
different processes and produce more
Aroma more
flavor resulting in a better product
incredible yeah Endo fights is something
that uh I picked up learned from Jeff
lenells so shout out to him I had him on
the podcast in the past he did a really
good breakdown of endo fights and their
role and he was so excited about it it
was incredible I I say a newer thing
that's kind of been learned over the
past you know 5 10 years or so it seems
like there's more Focus talking about
end fights versus just the soil microb
and really uncovering more things that
we're learning about Endo fights and how
it impacts the plant so really cool that
you had mentioned that here they're
extremely fascinating yeah and talking
about the other microbes particularly
the ones in the soil you did a really
good breakdown on another top I had
tuned in of yours talking about you know
bacteria and fungi and ARA can you give
us kind of like layman's terms or just
kind of the basics of those microbes
kind of information Growers should know
to help improve plant health and growth
sure so um what it sounds like you
referring to is like the soil food web
and we have like our lower bacteria
right which is you know kind of just
what you think of when you think of
bacteria we also have like our protozoa
which are which are kind of just like
the the Predators within the the soil
World um protozoa actually means early
animal or first animal they're
supposedly the first step in evolution
between bacteria and animal and what
they do is they run around they swim
around they little wiggle around and
stuff um and they consume the lower
bacteria so the lower bacteria consumes
organic matter um that possesses forms
of nutrients and then the protozoa will
come around and consume that bacteria
and unlock those nutrient nutrients they
change it from one form to another like
I had mentioned earlier just kind of
touched on it there are different forms
of these nutrients with different forms
of nitrogen there's different forms of
phosphorus and what this biology is
doing when it's consuming lower bacteria
is it's changing it from one cycle to
another and you hear this as the
nitrogen cycle or the phosphorus
cycle um there's also nematodes
nematodes are like tiny little little
worms they serve a whole bunch of
different functions there's predatory
nematodes um there's a lot of different
species of nematodes but a lot of the
time they consume bacteria they can also
consume fungus and in this process
they're breaking down and releasing
nutrients from bacteria but also
converting things like polysaccharides
into um simple sugars so they're taking
complex sugars they're turning them into
simple sugars um and they're allowing
for other biology to consume it and feed
on it's all just like this big cycle
right right and then we also have you
know
um amibas and ARA and stuff like that
and they all kind of serve similar
functions as protozoa there's felet
they're within the protozoa
family um but further on like in the
soil food web we have like
microarthropods right which are tiny
tiny insects like mites and mites can
actually consume forms of protozoa they
also break down in Trad organic matter
and their excrement um is full of
nutrients for the plant as well so all
of these components are required to
really have like a healthy living
organic soil that's full of cycling
nutrients and a diversity of compounds
that promote that flavor and that give
give people the the outcome that they're
looking for with living soil and organic
cultivation we can tailor different
fermentations whether they're aerobic
with oxygen um multiplied with oxygen or
anerobic multiplied without oxygen we
can tailor different mentations to
introduce specific forms of these
biology we can also tailor them by
adding different food sources to our
fermentations different different
species of bacteria they they prefer
different food sources which is why
there's different types of like agar
plates and stuff like that right um so
we can actually tailor our fermentations
through different food sources through
different polysaccharides as well as
different enzymes and amino acids to
promote diversity Within in like our
fermentations and introduce them to the
soil that's kind of more complicated and
requires a little bit of understanding
but it's a really really fascinating
aspect of living soil that I think
people shouldn't
ignore and it's also really a lot of fun
so you hear about people talking about
um lactic acid bacteria serum or
fermenting you know making activated um
effective microorganisms or um ired
compost tees and things like that that's
that's kind of the the the foundation of
it but you can take it a little bit
further when you understand how biology
works and what it requires to multiply
then you can you can promote the
multiplication of very specific species
of biology especially if you're using
inoculants like a source inoculant for
example there's um you know phosphorus
solubilizing microbes right you can
introduce phosphorous solubilizing
microbes the food source they prefer as
well as the enzymes that they secrete to
kind of give them the home and the
stimulation they require
um to thrive and multiply
them and I think that that's like that's
kind of like the next level like
advanced stuff that people can get into
um that really takes someone from
struggling with living soil and organic
cultivation to like really taking full
advantage of it and seeing like it's
real potential which can be intimidating
but in the end the juice is definitely
worth a squeeze and I highly encourage
people to dive down those rabbit holes
and learn about microbes and biology to
you know level up their game that's
interesting yeah I think a lot of people
use microbial inoculant um you know
they're buying it off the shelf whether
it be like a mammoth P or tribus or
there's a ton of different microbi
inoculant products on the market today
and uh you know they're using those
they're adding them in and then of
course it's they're doing their jobs in
the soil there do you use any microbial
inoculant or you kind of doing like the
Imo natural farming process IMO for
those that don't know it's indigenous
microorganisms there's basically a
process that's done where you can get
microbes naturally from your native soil
for example can you talk to us about
kind of microbial inoculant like ones
that you use or maybe the IMO process if
you do that sure um so I actually don't
use the IML process I have um particular
opinions about it um and we can get into
that too but to first answer your
original question I will use some microb
ulence specifically if I'm after a
particular end of Fight right so a lot
of these bottle inoculants they have you
know basilla species that are pretty
common um and exist kind of ubiquitously
in nature um and you can really harness
them just with high quality earthworm
castings and insect frass so I like to
just source that my inoculant source is
earthworm castings and insect Fass which
is my preferred method of
inoculant because insects they do what's
called mesophilic composting where they
take organic matter and they break it
down mesophilic which is like uh medium
temperature which so they have we have
mesophilic we have thermophilic
thermophilic would be like traditional
composting where you're turning and it's
getting really hot um that heat can
limit diversity of microbes it also
produces CO2 not in any excessive amount
that it's you know really damaging to
the environment but potentially it can
be and and I prefer to not put the labor
in to turn compost piles but to use
insects kind of as my allies to break
down organic matter faster in my opinion
with less labor and produce a wider
diversity of biology that I can
introduce as my microbial inoculate so
if I am after very specific species of
of biology of microbes like um you know
the phosphorous solubilizing bacteria
that I had mentioned earlier I'll pick
up a product like Mammoth P I'll also
you know find all Source enzymes that
are secret secreted by those specific
bacteria you can buy them online with
different websites um introduce them to
like a fermentation find the specific
food source that they prefer introduce
that as as well and let them multiply so
that I'm not limited to the very small
amount that I've purchased and I like to
do that with a bunch of different
biology um it sounds kind of
intimidating it's really not but um when
I do use bottled inoculants I'll find
specific bottled inoculants that have
specific endites so another one is uh
rotos sudon rotos sudam monus palestras
which is a photosynthetic Endy that you
can find in a product like uh
photosynthetic Plus or I'm sorry
photosynthesis plus which is a microbl
product so those are the two that I
really use um I'll use micro um
photosynthesis plus and I'll also use
Mammoth P cuzz those have very
particular bacteria that I want um
another one would be like nitrogen um
solubilizing and fixing bacteria so
those are like the big ones that I'll
use those are the big inoculant that
I'll go after but other than that I use
earthworm castings and insect frass as
my go-to for my inoculant for my soil
earthworm castings in Tech fast I love
those two inputs really really good I
use them in just about every grow as
well well let's get into inputs actually
let's first get into initial soil mix
right so what is your kind of
recommended soil mix to begin a lot of
people are going after the the one to
one: one clamus cot is kind of made that
famous although he got that from
University I forget which university you
got it from but one part where it's
either Pete or cocoa one part Iration
and then uh one part of compost to worm
casting and then some people add
fertilizer on it as well but what's your
recommended soil mix so I love coup um
I've actually done podcasts with him
before um I don't follow that heavy of
an organic matter mix I'll max out my
organic matter at about 20% but I've
seen great results with organic matter
as low as 5% um 20% from a study that
I've seen recently released by uh
Cornell University is kind of the
maximum that that Cornell has
recommended in recent years and I know
that that c is you know a very
knowledgeable person um
but I think that that study was from a
while ago he released that CP mix um
quite some time ago now and it's a very
it's like probably the most well-known
living soil organic mix out there is the
the cot mix cuz he was one of the first
people to just release it I've used it
before it's not my favorite in terms of
like what's my favorite mix if I told
you you wouldn't know the name of it so
like no one would know what it is but um
what I do is I follow a system called
the alre soil mineral balancing Theory
and I encourage everyone to look this up
and it has different ratios of nutrients
um that are applicable to different soil
compositions and one of them being um
like Rich potting soil that's mixed you
know with Pete or cocoa um and it has
different different ratios for NPK so on
through your your trace minerals your
micros um and that's what I like to
follow um is the soil mineral balancing
Theory there are some bagged soils that
I will use there's sensy side that I
like to use in southern Oregon um I had
U I grew the these monster plants um in
southern Oregan a few years ago and I
used that soil it was great it was a
cocoa core based mix that was also
balanced with Al soil mineral balancing
Theory um you know he was an agronomist
that came up with this this approach to
generating and remediating soil after
the dust bow um he saw that there was a
problem that needed to be fixed and he
came up with these
techniques and released it to the world
but it was all kind of ignored um
because there was a whole bunch of
ammonium nitrate that had just hit the
uh the industry um after the world war
and people you know are there was a
gentleman I forgot his name but he
realized that you can use ammonium
nitrate to grow crops with and it
totally changed the world and it
produced tons of food for people um so
his theory um Dr Al his theories kind of
got brushed to the side because you know
we can use this byproduct from the
military industrial complex to grow all
this food but now it's kind of becoming
more applicable with medicinal plant
cultivation where people are really
trying to level up the the nutrient
cycling the nutrient availability um in
custom soil
mixes and so now it's becoming more
applicable um but you look at all of his
work and it's back you know in the 20s
and the 30s um but it's really
interesting and I definitely recommend
people look into it um any living soil
mix is going to be pretty good they
typically tend to be pretty expensive
and I recommend people learn how to mix
it and do it themselves cuz not only are
you going to have a soil composition and
a soil blend that's unique to you it'll
produce a unique expression within a
plant um resulting in an end product
that cannot be mimicked without your
very specific soil mix so you can dive
down this Rabbit Hole kind of learn a
little bit about Agronomy and create
your own soil mix that'll result in your
own unique product but what it also does
when when you learn this is you now have
the skill to take any soil outside and
turn it into a lush fertile Garden you
can take native soil from anywhere with
these practices and principles that you
can Implement and turn dead dirt into
living soil and have a farm anywhere
which I think is one of the most
invaluable skills that anyone can have
so I try to encourage people to to learn
how to use these techniques so that you
can then it's you can then just possess
what I think is one of the most valuable
skills and powers out there like there's
no bigger power than being able to feed
yourself off of the land because of
knowledge that you've Poss possessed and
learned you know absolutely yeah I mean
having the end goal of being able to use
the native soil out of your backyard and
use that then you wouldn't have to go to
the store to buy begged soil you know
spending money at the the hydroponic
store or your local Nursery um you
wouldn't have to do that if you're able
to take the the soil from your backyard
repurpose it you know maybe a lot of
these are soils are too compact
depending on where you live right but I
know a lot of people uh run into the
issue where there it's just too compact
not enough ariation so they have to add
ariation I know some people well first
of all generally advised to grab a so
test right you want to get a so test
find out what's in your soil to begin
and then kind of make adjustments from
there I know Tad hussy kiss organic
shout out to him he had found uh
considerable a heavy metals in in some
of his native soil I forget where
exactly it was on if it was his current
land or or past land but he had
mentioned that he's not really able to
use it so like for those folks that are
interested in using their native soil
you probably get a soil test to find out
what's in there to begin uh and then
kind of make adjustments from there 100%
so so that's kind of one of the
principles that are that are recommended
in this this soil balancing theory is
like you know step one you get a soil
test you see what's in it you see what
is lacking you see what it's abundant in
and then you make calculations and
alterations from there and if you do
have an abundance of heavy metals over
time you can remediate it with like
cover crops and biology but you may not
be able to immediately use um that soil
right away um if you're worried about
heavy metals or testing requirements um
there are also options of introducing
certain inputs that will kind of suck in
those those heavy metals things like
biochar there's also an amendment um
called zolly um which has a very unique
structure uh like molecular structure
that holds on to heavy metals also so
there are ways to like remediate heavy
metals but you're 100% right you a lot
of times cannot just take a native soil
um and start using it to to grow in um
you 100% have to get testing done and
then make calculations and alterations
from there good to know I'm going to
have to look into that uh so balancing
theory in more detail and kind of get
familiar with it uh because yeah that's
right now I am using just bag soil
started off with Fox pH otion forest
soil and I turn that in and I've been
using that soil for six seven Groves now
so you know adding organic inputs and
being able to reuse that so over and
over and over again so I don't have to
go to the store to buy begged soil
anymore I live in Las Vegas and uh it's
desert out here so like I'm really
nervous to try to use the the native
soil in my backyard it's mostly just
sand and rock and but hey I I've heard
it's possible so maybe I you need to
roll up my sleeves and figure it out
yeah there's people who even dry Farm in
sand and have success with it there's
there's all these different regenerative
and cultivation techniques um that are
really unique that have come up with
solutions to a lot of different problems
you just kind of got to look around for
them or ask someone who who might know
the answers yeah absolutely now for a
lot of folks uh that are tuning in
they're probably not going to use their
native soil they probably are going to
go out and buy a bag soil and then
they're going to attempt to use that as
a good starting point and then continue
to put in organic inputs and then of
course reuse that soil over and over
again if somebody's going that route or
even doing like a Coots mix where
they're creating their own soil mix
organic fertilizers or organic inputs
what do you recommend and how often to
apply them I know it's a very broad
question but throwing that at you see if
you can answer that it is a broad
question so I use amendments right I use
soil amendments to balance my soil and
then I focus on making those amendments
available to the plant and usable by the
plant through adding amino acids enzymes
carbohydrates poly saccharides um
biology and filling in the gaps of the
soil food web so fertilizers fertilizer
is kind of a funny word um so in terms
of fertilizers I guess the the
fertilizers that I use would be um
sources of soy amino acids as my um
cation form of nitrogen the nh4 positive
right um amino acids the building blocks
of proteins they're also needed to for
the formation of enzymes um I focus a
lot on amino acids in my grow um also
the cation form of of nitrogen found in
amino acids doesn't leech right you hear
about like nitrate runoff and stuff and
how it affects the environment um this
doesn't it it holds on to the negative
charge um cation exchange sites in the
soil better so that doesn't rinse out
opposed to um
uh the NO3 negative annion that a lot of
nitrogen sources are so in terms of
fertilizer I use a lot of soy based
amino acids I also use a lot of
micronized inputs so I'll use things
like micronized lonite which is um
sulfur potassium magnesium right it's a
mineral that is rich in Sulfur potassium
and magnesium um and if I need those
nutrient sources those elements in my my
soil um or my plants require them I'll
add them in micronized form into a
solution um with like some fulvic acid
or some humic acid to kind of create my
own carbon based fertilizers I'll also
use things like micronized rock
phosphate um which is calcium phosphate
so it has a lot of calcium it has a lot
of phosphate in it um and phosphate is a
key part of energy production inside of
a plant um same thing with nitrogen so
there's um I think it's ATP adamine
triphosphate I think is how you
pronounce it right and it's um formed
with nitrogen and phosphorus right and
when you introduce both of them you're
you're kind of creating an energy source
for the plant so I do things I focus a
lot on amino acids micronized inputs
calcium phosphate potassium um in
micronized forms after I've custom built
my soil
to have a balance of these different
nutrients with things like
gypsum um fishbone
meal uh greens sand crab meal shrimp
meal kelp meal um Lang bite like I
mentioned what else is in my soil mix
earthworm castings um earthworm castings
are also a source of nutrients um
however I don't know I don't I don't
know if I would consider them
fertilizer um yeah and then there's also
other inputs that I'll add that aren't
technically fertilizers things that just
kind of like promote cation exchange
capacity like uh Clays like bentonite
clay zeolite that's a lot of it for in
terms of like fertilizer is just I use
organic dry amendments that I mix into
soil with um a biology Source like Earth
room castings insect frass and then my
inert you know um organic matter things
like Pete M cocoa cor whatever so that's
mostly what I do I don't actually buy
much of anything that is like a nutrient
Source except for those micronized
inputs but I like to use a lot of fulvic
acids and enzymes and amino acids also
to kind of like promote the availability
and mimic root exid
dates which is like the function of how
plants make plants I mean make nutrients
readily available got it yeah I use uh a
handful of those inputs that you
mentioned as well so you mentioned amino
acids and one thing uh I'm look at
online right now actually I pulled it up
is raw amino acids and uh these things
are quite expensive I mean uh you get 2
ounces for
$16.20 that's $8 an ounce or you get
like 2 pound for
$135 you talked about amino acids and
how you focus on that is a product like
this raw amino acids is this something
that you would potentially incorporate
in your garden is it useful so I think
that's a dietary
supplement um so no I wouldn't use that
I like to use bioag so they have a few
different products that have amino acids
they have calino they have Mulino um
they have nitroamino nitroamino is the
most potent one I think it's 14 or 15%
nitrogen um and that is not that
expensive I think it's a pound for like
$18 or something like that $15 um and it
goes a long way and no so I think what
you found was like a dietary supplement
for people because all all cells require
amino acids and they helpful for humans
to consume and for the soil to utilize
and biology to utilize biology plant
cells human you know animal cells you
know we all use amino acids so no I
don't I wouldn't use that one okay no
this one actually is from NPK Industries
uh and it does talk about oh really yeah
yeah it does talk about like keates ion
nutrients and facilitating plane uptake
movement into cells yeah this particular
one does seem to be that sounds very
expensive yeah it does that's what I say
what I was asking is it even worth it to
buy it that way or can we get amino
acids from somewhere else you know we
can get amino acids from from other
places um you know since cells are all
made of proteins you can break proteins
back down into amino acids using enzymes
that break proteins down into amino
acids these are called proteolytic
enzymes or protees and it's a form of
enzyme that will take a protein and
break it back down into its original
amino acid form you can find this inside
of um U things like lactic acid bacteria
serum which I'm not sure if everyone's
familiar with but it's a fermentation of
milk with lactic acid bacteria
lactobacillus species um that then
contains protolytic enzymes that you can
add to plant matter that will break it
down and turn it into amino acids
there's also specific plant inputs that
are rich in amino acids things like aloe
vera which I'm a big fan of using in in
my soil and I'll just take aloe vera
whether cultivated by myself or from
like a grocery store clean it nice and
good so you don't have kind of like
funky weird stuff on it chop it up into
little pieces throw it in a blender
strain it and water it into your plants
and there's a lot of really simple
techniques like that that you can do to
introduce you know um amino acids as
well as different compounds and phyto
hormones to your garden um another one
that I really like is um red beet um it
is rich in a polysaccharide called inin
which is great at multiplying um
bacteria it also has nitric oxide in it
which promotes um you know metabolic
processes inside of the plant the list
goes on and on and if you have something
growing in your native environment you
can actually look up the phytochemical
composition of that plant on websites
like Dr Duke's phytochemical database um
and it'll tell you the full
phytochemical composition and you can
take that information and look it up and
see what each organic acid's
physiological effect are on a plant and
integrate it into your garden and you
can identify what the parts per million
of phosphorus that contains potassium
nitrogen and so on so that you can take
your local native plants and through
fermentation or through just blending
and straining or composting or feeding
two insects you can integrate it into
your garden organically sustainably
regeneratively um there's just so many
cool things like that that would be
really difficult to cover all of them in
this in this talk but you can absolutely
go out and find stuff and integrate it
into your garden from your local
environment and I think that's where
like the creativity and the the art
really comes into living soil
cultivation I think one thing that
people worry about going that route is
bringing in pathogens right kind of
going back to the IMO process that we
talked about and bringing in good
microbes but they also could be bringing
in some bad microbes and I know with
fermentation if it's not done right
there could be bad microbes in there as
well
so I think that's one thing that kind of
that's true cautions people away from it
so but yeah you can definitely do it
safely from what I've learned and kind
of what you're mentioning here so I
guess it's just a matter of uh following
it step by step and doing your due
diligence and uh looking under a
microscope and seeing if those bad
microbes exist in there or not or if
there are just good microbes in there
and then utilizing that that's really
difficult to do um you know you can make
a slide and look at it under a
microscope but being able to identify
which
species um in which fungi based on their
like morphological properties is
extremely difficult um and you could be
sitting there looking at stock images
all day long trying to find the one
thing and then think that you found it
and you haven't um it's it's difficult
it's difficult to do um and often times
you see people posting microscopy images
making claims that they've found this
particular thing and they're completely
base um it's it's definitely there's a
reason why you know people are you go to
college and study for for years and
years and years behind this particular
uh this study you know it's it's
definitely really difficult um but
you're 100% right like you can bring in
pathogens from the outside um which is
one of the reasons why I'm really big
into um insect um breakdown of things
because their gut microbiome is really
effective at breaking down pathogens
um and then it's a much safer way to
introduce it which is why I really like
earthworm castings and insect f um and
things like you know doing turning of
compost piles and stuff I have seen so
many people incorrectly compost and
incorrectly make IMO and introduce
pathogens to their Garden um it is it's
hard it's hard to do it um and it takes
finesse it takes a lot of attention to
detail and thoroughness to really
accomplish
fully and like effectively um I just
Outsource that labor to the bugs you
know that's that's my Approach um but
yeah you're 100% right you can
absolutely go out and take something
from somewhere and bring it in um
especially if your native environment
isn't entirely healthy and your native
you know ecosystem isn't fully intact
that makes total sense now we took a
short break and you mentioned uh
something that you wanted to talk about
root exit dates root exites yeah let's
get into that have you yeah are you
familiar with root exit dates at all
yeah a little bit okay um so root exites
are compounds that are secreted by roots
to facilitate several functions um one
that I've touched on before um is that
they they feed specific profiles of
biology to accomplish specific goals for
example there will secrete profiles of
amino acids enzymes carbohydrates that
promote the um multiplication of
phosphorus cycling um bacteria this is
called the rise of fagy
cycle and during particular stages in
the plant's development it has different
profiles of root exites and of these
compounds I just mentioned to feed
specific species of bacteria to make
certain nutrients available during
certain stages in the correct
proportions that the plant wants them
right this is like the the the
overwhelming majority of how nutrients
are cycled um and delivered to a plant
in a living soil system is through root
egg States and each plant is each
species of plant is more or less
effective at certain at feeding certain
profiles or um yeah profiles of these
compounds to feed specific species of
bacteria so you'll see people introduce
cover crops and companion plants living
mulches
that have a diversity of different plant
species that are more or less effective
at secreting root exid dates tailor to
specific nutrients to make them
available so you'll see people use
Clover um for nitrogen um it fixes
nitrogen from the
atmosphere but it also solubilizes
nitrogen in the rizosphere and then you
have things like buckwheat which is
really effective at um phosphorus
solubilization um it secretes phosphates
or it could be phosphotase
anyway and um it's an enzyme that helps
with nutrient cycling of phosphorus this
is crucial this is like super key in BIO
remediation of soil as well as making
nutrients available to your plants and
keep in mind that these profiles of
biology you know while they are also I'm
sorry these profiles of compounds while
they're feeding biology they're also
catalyzing chemical reactions and calent
bonds in the soil to make nutrients you
know transform from one form to another
right so while living soil is like an
ecosystem of bacteria and biology um
it's also a Perpetual chemical reaction
and so not only are we kind of working
with nature um well chemistry is still
nature but we are working with chemistry
we're working with bacteria biology kind
of forming an alliance with these these
living organisms but we're also needing
to understand how those aspects
influence chemical reactions in the soil
and this is done a lot of the time
through root exit dates um and we can
introduce and kind of mimic root exit
dates with the different compounds that
we play with and that's like the the key
the like the secret key behind
effectively growing living soil is is
mimicking root exit dates cuz this is
how most nutrients change forms and
become readily available um there's also
the the soil food web and how I
mentioned earlier bacteria being
consumed by protozoa but the vast
majority of how nutrients are uptaken is
through the rise of fagy cycle and how
root exites interact with chemicals and
with Biology and those biology in that
biology breaking down specific nutrients
it's crazy the amount of reactions that
are happening down in that area right I
mean what blew my mind is back when I
learned that uh you know acids were
released by the plant in order to and
you touched on this is kind of adjust
the pH uh to make nutrients more
available right iron is is a good
example of that where the pH is too high
it's going to iron's going to be in a
form that the plant can't uptake so the
release acids gets in the correct PH
range then the iron is able to be
converted into that form and uptaken by
the plant so it's so fascinating and I
feel like there's still so much that we
don't know that we still learning about
it and um man it goes above a lot of
people's heads it goes above my head to
be honest with you because there's
there's just so much to it it goes over
everyone's head there's a tremendous
amount about soil that we don't know um
that nobody knows that we're just still
figuring out and Yeah like he had said
there's such a complex network of
reactions happening that how they all
function and how they all interconnect
with each other is would be would be so
difficult to study because it's all in
this microcosm world that is really
difficult to observe um and it's all
mixed together and this like Melting Pot
of of things that's separating them and
and studying them is really really
difficult for humans to do um and often
times we just kind of have to like let
nature do it you know let nature take
care of it let the biology take care of
it yep and you know that's one thing
that makes it so fun is like we're still
identifying things and we're always
going to be learning I think all of us
that are living here on Earth right now
uh we're going to be learning till the
day we die right and still not
everything's going to be uncovered in
regards to Growing these plants and and
uh soil biology and so on and so forth I
think I read a stat somewhere where it's
um
99.9% of microbes haven't even been
studied yet so it's like we've got way
like yeah it's it's insane also is that
they're constantly quote unquote
evolving right they're they're not
necessarily evolving as as much as like
their genetic composition is constantly
changing are you familiar with um
horizontal Gene transfer no okay so this
is cool um horizontal Gene transfer is
when there is a microbial density of
bacteria to where they're so tight
together inside of like a biofilm or
just like a you know sludge whatever
inside a solution inside of water where
there's so much compaction there's so
much microbial density that they start
tossing genes back and forth they start
tossing DNA back and forth and those
random combinations of DNA being passed
back and forth can actually create new
species of bacteria like
spontaneously and this is how like the
first evolutions and combinations of
bacteria formed um were through this
horizontal Gene transfer back in like
the primordial soup of like early amino
acids and humates and enzymes um you
know it it's perpetually happening so
you can
experience biology
changing potentially rapidly but it
pretty much means that we will never
ever ever document all the different
species of bacteria um in the world cuz
it's it's constantly changing so we
could we could find new bacteria that do
new things every day for the rest of our
life you know and never and never find
them all it's like this it's like trying
to find the edge of the universe you
know you just can't you just can't do it
you're not going to be able to do it
right yeah it actually reminds me of
viruses viroid those can change up too
right I mean we won't get too deep into
to that when we get off the subject here
but like it reminds me exactly of that
how they're always changing evolving um
yeah let's bring it back into kind of
more of I guess uh let's Loop in the
beginners and Inter media folks a little
bit more and give them some actions okay
what advice or tips do you have for
folks that are maybe just getting
started growing organically and they're
really focusing on they want a better
taste to come out of there they want a
better smell to be produced from these
plants what's some uh advice you have
for them I'd say like the the first kind
of easy step is make sure you have
enough Iration in your soil make sure
that you maintain
it wet you need to keep living soil
moist there are some habits that people
learn from growing um hydroponically
that don't translate to living soil
cultivation one of them is letting your
soil dry out too much um and there
probably will be people that disagree
with me and want to talk about root
respiration um dry backs and stuff like
that and I'd be happy to get into that
conversation with people but you need to
keep living soil wet one is because
bacteria needs to be moist it needs to
have um a a solution a space to exist a
media which is water to exist in and to
multiply in all of living soil processes
are so much dependent on bacteria and
biology that when they start getting dry
they stop functioning properly the rise
of fagy cycle is very dependent on
moisture keep your soil wet keep your
soil irated that is the the I see it so
much I see it so much so I have a
patreon where I help people um and they
post images and stuff like that um I see
people just drying out their soil too
much all the time just make sure you
have enough biology um make sure you
keep it wet and make sure that you have
good drainage if you can do that you
could just water only if you had enough
soil you could water only um and grow a
plant completely to finish in living
soil um if you're having a small soil
Mass it's going to be very difficult and
you will have to have to add nutrients
um and it's going to be very difficult
to keep nutrients balanced in a small
pot living soil really wants large soil
masses moisture and drainage and biology
that's like the stepping stone for
growing living soil and some people
really struggle with that um but but
that's that's it that's like the
beginner step that I recommend to people
and then you can get into like
fermenting and you know adding different
profiles and stuff like that after you
learn about it you know um people it's a
lot of fun to do these things people
like to get ahead of themselves but you
can make mistakes you can introduce
pathogens you can add too much of an
enzyme and cook your roots or kill your
worms um kill your microarthropods it's
it can be complicated um so just start
with a lot of soil keep it moist keep it
draining add simple inoculant like
earthworm castings and insect fress if
you want to use Bashi that's great use
cover crops companion plants to provide
like that diversity of rot ex States
like we had discussed earlier and you
can just water it you just you can just
water it um I did a full run in a tent
with a in like a 4x4 bed in a in a tent
and it was just water companion plants
soil with you know nine plants in it and
it just that was it and it was great it
worked out great I didn't have to do
anything to it super simple don't over
complicate it yeah it definitely can be
super simple now that's one thing that
uh you know you talk about keeping
things moist that's one thing I wasn't
told when I first started growing
organic so I was taking my practice grow
using synthetics to where I was letting
the medium dry out between waterings and
then the plan was showing deficiencies
and I'm like hm is organic really the
easier way to about I was just doing it
wrong I didn't have the medium moist
enough I didn't keep a consistent
moisture level and then of course I
learned about that had much better
success having a a moist medium the
whole time introduced blue mats Auto
watering system so really dial in that
moisture level in the medium and it's
just been a GameChanger for me I love
blue mats um I've used them for years um
they're probably my favorite way to just
keep soil wet um BL mats are great but
yeah and and like you mentioned and I
think it's important to note is that
when you're growing in living soil and
you let things dry out you start seeing
symptoms um plant symptoms that mimic
deficiencies when your soil actually has
the nutrients in it that the plant needs
but you let it dry out too much um and
you know the the plant was not able to
cycle nutrients effectively and then it
started showing these signs of
deficiencies and what people often do is
they let their plants Dr out too much
they see these deficiencies and then
they have their but or themselves or a
book help them identify the deficiency
and then they start pumping it with that
deficiency I mean with that nutrient you
know and um and then they create an
imbalance in the soil um that
antagonizes another element you know
creating an improper you know form
improper Bond right an improper chemical
reaction and now you're perpetuating
this teen reaction of aors in your soil
and you start seeing all these different
Burns you start seeing overdoses of
nutrients you start seeing deficiencies
of nutrients and you're chasing your
tail around trying to pump your soil
with all these different nutrients
spending all this money um when you just
need to keep your soil wet and that's
that's tough that's hard for people and
then they want to be like no I know that
it needs more more calcium I know it
needs more magnesium I know it needs
more nitrogen and they just start
hitting it and hitting it and hitting it
and then things get out of whack things
get out of balance you know bacteria
colonies break down they don't function
properly it's
just keep keep it wet keep it wet keep
it full of biology that's got to be one
of the biggest frustrations for new
organic Growers is keeping that Medium
moist and then yeah going through the
the Motions that you mentioned is like
you know things dry out and you see
deficiencies and do adding inputs and so
on and so forth you can just sounds like
a headache sounds like a big headache
there it is it's a huge headache now you
mentioned you caution people on using
small container sizes what's your
recommended minimum container size to
use for Organics you can pull off 20
I like to use 45 G for for a single
plant um if I'm using a
container um I grow in beds though I
grow in big
4x8 you know in like an indoor setting
of 4x8 bed um you know that's at least
12 in deep I like to have them 18 in
deep if you don't have enough drainage
18 in can provide problems so 12 is good
for most people but my bad at my
Greenhouse is 5 ft wide and 60 ft long
you know and 18 in deep uh and that's
that's how I prefer to grow is I like to
have a solid soil mask cuz now it turns
into like an entire ecosystem um and
roots go really far and micro risal
networks go really far and things get
transported from really long distances
nutrients can be transported long
distances through micro isal networks
But to answer your question 20 gallons I
think is minimum 45 is what I recommend
um but growing in beds is what I think
is ideal in living soil cultivation that
makes sense yeah I mean I've tried
growing in you know organic in puts in
one gallon containers three gallons five
gallons I had pretty good results with
seven gallons okay then I worked my way
up to 10 gallons which I'm actually in
right now and I'm having some pretty
good success but I know that as a track
record the bigger container I go the
easier it's getting you know so uh it's
only a matter of time before I'm in a
bed I actually have a twoot by 10 foot
bed outside for my vegetable garden and
I love it as far as my indoors only
amount of time before I'm in beds as
well so good advice there fantastic
episode we had today great great talk I
definitely learned quite a bit here I
appreciate you coming on can you uh can
you tell the listeners how they can find
you and what do you have upcoming in the
future yeah for sure so um I host
podcasts on the future cannabis project
every Sunday at 4:20 um I I rotate
co-hosts and we we go over research
papers it's kind of like highle stuff
really nerdy stuff um each co-host has
like a specific specialty that that we
go over uh you can find me on my
Instagram it's @ Luna all day um I have
a patreon um if you go to my Instagram
you can look at my bio there's a link
tree to all my different articles and
stuff I write for skunk magazine um I've
written for Greenpoint seeds and for SD
microbes so I do a lot of writing I do
Consulting um I do
podcasts um and my my Instagram is
probably where I'm the most active and
share my different concoctions my
recipes and my approaches you know as
well as how I like to shape plants and
um just My overall General approach to
living soil cultivation so it's all
mostly on Instagram @ Luna all day the a
in Luna and all is shared so um l u n a
l l d a y that's that's that's pretty
much it awesome I'll definitely have a
link to where people can find you down
in the YouTube description section below
and then if you're on one of the podcast
platforms just just search for her
you'll find her I have a gut feeling
here that there's going to be quite a
few people in the comment section asking
for a part two so uh if we get enough
people demanding to for a part two would
you be willing to come on for a part two
where we talk about something else kind
of maybe dive deeper into one of the
areas or talking about a different area
that you have knowledge on I'd love to
there's there is so much to talk about
there's an endless amount of topics to
talk about in living soil so I would be
happy to thank you awesome well if you
want to see part two definitely comment
down below and we will get her back on
Luna thanks so much for coming on I
really appreciate it this has been this
has been awesome and I hope you enjoy
the rest of your day thank you so much
have a great day