coming up on garden talk it can
strengthen anything from trichomes to
stems to your leafs it strengthens
everything on your plant i'm not gonna
lie i always follow the directions on
the packaging it's a good baseline when
it's an already mixed inert soil i mean
it's really rare for something to be too
hot to handle a seedling or a clone or
really anything i just open up the lid
there'll be condensation there'll be
moisture and you put your hand in the
soil it's actually gonna be warm that's
still cooking you gotta wait another
week it's worth every dollar i highly
suggest if you guys are into organic
growing in any capacity indoor outdoor
grab one of those i would rather that it
got disturbed and replenished then
nothing happening at all it's always a
better option doing nothing is never the
right idea
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 47. in this
episode i interview green lantern he has
been gardening for 13 years and grows
plants such as bamboo house plants
medicinal plants bonsai trees and more
in this episode he talks about a variety
of organic gardening methods in
particular he talks about building soil
feeding organic amendments k f ipm and
more thanks to all of you support this
podcast through patreon if you'd like to
support you could do so by going to
patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to aec infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast they sent me
over their grow tent which has a canvas
density of 2000 d making them the
thickest grow tent on the market today
it has an aluminum plate that mounts
your controller to the grow tent with
the light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has fifty percent
thicker steel pulls and carries two
times more weight than the standard grow
tents
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their website down in
the description section below dutch pro
is a sponsor of the podcast coupon code
mrgrow10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mr growit10dp for a discount on
their products
alright we're back welcome to the garden
talk podcast today i am joined with
green lantern how you doing today i'm
doing great how you doing man doing good
good thanks for asking we're gonna get
right into things today we've got so
much to talk about so much good stuff to
talk about we're gonna get into mixing
soils we're going to get into feeding
we're going to get into a little bit
into k f so
action-packed episode that we have today
really excited for this one first what i
usually do with all the guests is
introduction so can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and kind of how you
got into gardening
yeah my name's uh green lantern or jacob
uh is my real name
and i got into gardening a long while
back just as uh something fun to do
really i really enjoyed the medicinal
properties of the medical plants and uh
at first it was just because it was fun
and then you know years later i had a
lot of back issues uh happen i had a car
accidents and i was overweight
back got all messed up and
formed an s in my spine and they call
that sublaxation scoliosis
and then i started using it medicinally
and then i got way more interested in it
started doing crazy amounts of research
with uh green goblin and you know
now we're here
that's awesome yeah green goblin is you
know he's been on the channel before and
people loved that episode we had had
with him because he was just spitting
off a ton of knowledge when it comes to
organics and you're right there by a
side you know growing in the same garden
so we're gonna hear a lot of good
techniques today and yeah let's start
with mixing soil because i know you have
a lot of good information about
mixing soil in particular so talk to us
what's in your mix
and how do you mix it
so uh our mix has kind of been building
over almost a decade now so it
originally it started off with maybe a
few pro mix bales from back in the day
uh and then we started adding you know
everything that one would need to add to
build a soil uh we got sphagnum peat
moss we started doing large pieces of
perlite and then we switched to uh
high porosity clay
pellets in
uh
rice holes and uh
you know just we just started messing
around with different blends and i mean
at at this point right now i'd say
everything in there is
sphagnum
the clay pellets
and
uh compost that's pretty that's pretty
much it
what's the ratios of each and you talk
about clay pellets it's something that
we don't really hear people using much
can you talk to us about why the clay
pellets and then also the kind of the
ratios of each of the things that you
have in there yeah we're doing like a 30
20 uh
30 20 20 mix i would say uh you know 30
sphagnum meat peat moss 20
uh manure uh compost manures
uh and 20
others which might be you know your rice
halls and your uh clay pellets things
like that we we started doing rice holes
a while back because they add a lot of
benefit to the soil uh in
the only problem we had with that is it
doesn't affect drainage as much as we
wanted
uh and they break down pretty quickly so
if you're looking for something to stay
in your mix a little bit longer the clay
pellets will give you that advantage as
well as add a little bit of silica to
your mix which
helps with so many things uh j just like
uh
dr bruce was talking about on the uh
last podcast
it can strengthen anything from
trichomes to
stems to
your leafs i mean pretty much it
strengthens everything on your plant
and then for the compost you mentioned
you said 20 compost is there any you
have any tips in regards to that because
that could be
different types of compost right yeah
and honestly i suggest using whatever is
the
most readily available in your area i
prefer mushroom compost but if you can't
find mushroom compost uh i'm seeing
booze blend compost and a lot of plate
and a lot of uh
hydro shops and and grow shops in
general i've even seen it in home depot
before
and booze blend is just this is a solid
compost that
you don't have to worry about
too many things with it uh sourcing of
where the materials came from or
uh
maybe possibly having too much
background all that was sourced
incorrectly uh
issues
there's no issues with it that i've i've
i've personally come across with it so
if i see booze blend i'll probably grab
that if i see mushroom compost somewhere
i would i would 100 much much rather get
the mushroom compost
okay so you have your 30 20 20
and then are you adding any additional
amendments in there like some people
will do blends right so build a soil is
infamous for their craft blend we've got
green sunshine company they have earth
dust nutrients and they have a mixture
that you initially blend in
with your initial mix do you do any
additional amendments on top of what you
had just mentioned
yes um what uh me and gr what me and
green goblin usually do there is
build a soil craft blend like you're
saying
if that's not around we'll use a dr
earth blend
pretty much same same idea same stuffs
in it different name brand
you can find it at home depot and some
hydro shops around uh i prefer the craft
blend
it has a couple different ingredients in
it
and in different ratios
uh that are more preferable for
organic growing in my opinion
but if you're in a pinch and that's the
stuff that's around it's going to do
great
uh but i i prefer to use the craft blend
and we use uh
i gotta change the measurements in my
head now because we switched the way we
mix our soil it's like seven gallons
that fits in the
mixer rather
so it's like two and a half cups of that
mix and then we'll add some frass
sometimes or uh silica uh if we if we
notice that the last round had issues
with
uh
nitrogen we'll add more compost we'll
add
it depends on what's going on with the
last cycle
okay so as far as like ratios specific
ratios i know we have a lot of uh folks
that are tuning in that you know more on
the beginner side they will kind of want
to know the nitty gritty details about
the exact ratios i personally use about
one cup per plant for the build a soil
craft blend that's pretty accurate
i think that's what it says on their
instructions on their website i think
it's a third cup to one cup per plant
are you also like the doctor earth and
stuff like that are you following the
direct the directions that they say on
the packaging or are you doing something
completely different
i'm not gonna lie i always follow
directions on the packaging it's a good
baseline either it's gonna be maybe a
little bit too much or maybe a little
bit too less but if you start with that
baseline in the instructions that
they've given you it's going to be
generally right around where you want it
and then you can adjust from there based
off from your needs
uh maybe
maybe your particular cultivars of said
strain
really just need way more nitrogen than
other other strains that you've had or
they need way more potassium or or
whatever's going on then you can start
minutely changing a few different things
uh in amounts of ingredients that you
use
to mitigate those things for maybe the
next round or even top dressing on your
current point current round of medicinal
plants or any plants
to
get the desired result out of it got it
that makes sense yeah i've been using
you mentioned insect fast i've used that
in the past also alfalfa meal is another
thing i've used so often times i start
off with the bag soil you know fox from
ocean forest oil is is local to me as
far as i'm able to pick it up locally so
i go with that but i'll start with the
foxpro motion for soil and there's
actually been times where i mixed in
insect frass and alfalfa meal into the
ocean forest and i got a lot of people
raising their eyebrows there like ocean
forest it's already too hot you should
never be adding anything more than that
you're burning your seedlings you're
ruining your plants blah blah blah blah
blah but i actually got a really good
result you know i started in one gallon
containers fox from ocean forest oil
we'll put some insect frost in there an
alfalfa meal i got some really really
good results off of that first
vegetation stage in the beginning there
obviously the nutrients deplete over
time and had to top dress in add more
nutrients in which actually we're going
to get into that next here yeah and i
think people get a little confused with
this terminology of a of a soil blend
maybe possibly being too hot
uh in reality if the blend has already
been mixed and it's in a bag like fox
farm that's an inert mix it's it's been
mixed already um
the hotness that we're referring to
in a hot mix is is literally a
temperature it's
you can feel it you'll reach your hand
into the uh uh your soil mix and it's
20 30 40 degrees warmer
uh and if you do this in a tent out in
the backyard or a tarp rather out in the
backyard in the winter you'll see actual
steam coming off from this it's it's
that's what we're talking about when we
say uh we gotta cook this soil mix
it's literally cooking and if you were
to use that soil during that process
that mix is literally too hot it's
physically too hot and nutriently too
hot
and everything is just bioactively
readily available so as soon as you
plant a
seed into something like that or a clone
into something like that you're
definitely gonna have problems
but when you when it's an already mixed
inert soil
that i mean it's really rare for
something to be too hot
to handle a seedling or a
clone or really anything got it so when
you when you do that initial mixing that
you mentioned you're letting it cook for
a little while right so what time period
are you letting how long are you letting
this cook for so if you're doing it in
batches of about 30 gallons which i
would recommend if you're going to mix a
soil do at least 30 gallons because
you're gonna use it you're gonna love it
and you're gonna have to make more for
about 30 gallons a cook time with a good
cook time would be about two weeks uh
and a good way to check this is you know
a week in
open up uh if it's in a i use trash cans
i use 35 gallon trash cans uh
heavy duty
if i just open up the lid there will be
condensation there'll be moisture and
you put your hand in the soil it's
actually going to be warm that's still
cooking you got to wait another week
typically two weeks is perfect
if it is going past two weeks you
probably did mix it a little too hot in
which case i would take that one and mix
it with another one
another trash can that i'd already
pre-mixed that's a little less hot
and then you got like a diluted version
of that original mix
that's still going to be plenty potent
enough to do whatever you want in
vegetative or
flowering stage
so you're holding off until the
temperature kind of goes down do you
know what temperature would be too hot
by chance like are people taking like a
temperature gun and like putting it on
their pile and then saying oh okay this
is low enough i would recommend that
actually because during the exothermic
reaction you could get anywhere up to
like 130 degrees fahrenheit which is
very warm like
that's why i like to use heavy duty
trash cans because
it can get a little out of control
sometimes with the amount of heat that
these things can produce
and also if you have the if you're doing
this in your area where you have your
grow
keep that in mind as well because it may
actually increase the temperature of
that room
which you may may or may not want at
that time
uh but i would i would definitely do a
temperature or i i don't i don't use
temperature guns because
it's so much faster for me to reach my
hand in uh if it's fiz if the dirt is
our soil is physically warmer than the
air
that's kind of that's kind of a good
sign that it's still working on some
stuff and you should wait a little bit
longer
also if you start if you start to see
like white mycelium forming on the top
of your soil
things are finishing out it's it's fully
cooked you
feel very safe and using that and uh you
can feel like you did a really well
really really good job because when
that's showing up you know you've got
the microbes and the mycorrhizal life
that you wanted to create in the in your
mix in the first place
sounds like some good general guidelines
there now for the
two week period that you're letting the
soil cook
are you going in there i know you said
you had a top on the container are you
going in there and doing like any type
of aeration like taking the top off once
a day like fanning it are you turning
the pile at all are you doing any of
that or just letting it sit uh i just
let it sit i do have a couple holes
poked in the lids of the trash cans
so that it can have air gas exchange
uh
which is it is kind of they're not super
air tight so you don't need to poke the
hole but it does help
okay and then before we actually started
recording you brought up a interesting
thing is a lot of people what they'll do
is they'll lay a tarp out and they'll
put their mixture in together right and
then they'll physically use their hands
to mix in things yeah you had mentioned
some downsides to that and then you had
mentioned something that you do instead
which is use a mixer can you talk to us
about that
yeah most certainly like you were saying
the i was doing the tarp method for
years and i would uh i would get a whole
bunch of uh expended
pots onto the tarp and i'd break them
all up and i'd put all the amendments on
there and i'd put more
compost on there and i just start
folding this tarp
and it's hundreds of pounds at that
point you got to add water and then it's
getting heavier
eventually it was just too back-breaking
uh
we started looking into like
alternatives and we found uh cement
mixers were amazing at mixing
soil
because they can handle
super heavy loads they can handle
wet temp wet high temperature low
temperature
uh everything we're like shoot we're
gonna give that a try we grabbed one
that's not very big i would maybe
recommend getting one just a little bit
bigger than i have it fits about seven
gallons but
all the work is taken out of
out of my hands and i'm getting a way
more thorough mix
because there's just no no possible way
that
you're going to have enough energy and
strength to
mix that much
as much as a concrete mixer can in that
amount of time so i i get to save a
whole bunch of time and a whole bunch of
labor
which is
a big reason why i got into organic
growing i'm a little lazy
and i like to
[Music]
take long periods where i don't have to
do a whole bunch of physical labor and
to take one more thing out of the line
of things especially
moving and mixing soil
shoot it's worth every dollar i highly
suggest if you guys are into organic
growing in any capacity indoor outdoor
you just want to make your own mix for
anything
grab one of those it'll say it'll save
your back i'm telling you how much do
they cost
ours i believe was like 300 uh it wasn't
super outrageous and i think that's what
also turned us on to it was you know
300 can be a lot at one point in time
but it's gonna save me
countless hours of work and maybe even a
few chiropractor visits
and then one of the dimensions on it i
don't know if you mentioned the actual
dimensions just so people at home if
they're wondering you know is this
something you can keep in your grow room
or you know is it more garage your
backyard type size
it's like a two point you can keep it in
your garage or in a basement very easily
uh the drum fits about seven gallons i
want to say they called it like a 3.7
liter because they're talking about
cement terms here
uh
and it's it's super easy to use it's got
elsa has is an on and off button one
plug
uh
the handle
is retracting so you just retract the
handle out and you dump it
with it on and it pushes all the dirt
into your container
and you're done and that's it it's super
duper simple
anybody could run one
and it just saves so much work
it's been a godsend yeah i'll definitely
have to check that out maybe i'll buy
one for the future yeah they're super
portable they come on on two wheels you
can you can roll them around put them in
the corner take it out only when you
need to get your job done
it's it's it's become a must-have in the
grow room for me
for sure all right so moving along so
they have their soil mixed up they ready
to plant they plant what size containers
do you generally recommend like i think
you mentioned seven gallon containers
are you in larger containers and then
when does that first feeding actually
happen
so i would recommend
maybe starting in a seven and moving to
a 15 if you're gonna want to do like a
midway transfer a mid mid transplant or
just going straight to the 15 if you
don't want to deal with that and add the
extra stressor
uh
it's
kind of crucial to have that surface
area in an organic
setting
so that you
so i i call them batteries they're soil
batteries if you got a 15 gallon soil
battery it's gonna have enough juice to
supply that plant for
all the way through the vegetative state
and maybe a few weeks into flower at
that point you're gonna want a top dress
uh
you're gonna want to start using some
compost teas
i like to use them
once a week
during like the first three to four
weeks of flower
because there's a huge
a huge uptake in nutrients and they're
shooting up sometimes
double their size to three times their
size in the flower room after the flip
and that takes a lot of energy it takes
a lot of nutrients and it's safe to say
that a good 60 to 70 percent of the
stuff that you thought was there
is been eaten has been eaten up by that
point in time
um
if you are doing seven gallon pots
uh and you just don't have the room to
do 15 or 10 gallon pots
it just means you got to do a couple
more top dressings i would top dress
halfway through vegetative stage
uh if your veg if your veg period is
usually
six weeks let's say or four weeks and
i'll do do a top dress at two weeks in
and then top dress right before it goes
in the flower
um and you should be pretty solid
okay so if you're trying to make it very
as easy as possible 15 gallon containers
literally plant in there
you don't have to do your first feeding
or top dressing until the flowering
stage is what you mentioned several
weeks into the flowering stage which is
awesome i've just been using these seven
gallon containers right now and i've
been doing exactly kind of what you just
mentioned is there are feedings within
the vegetation stage i'm doing a top
dressing within the vegetation stage
it's usually what i'll do is i'll do
about 30 days
then 20 to 30 days then i'll do a top
dressing and then shortly after that i'm
usually flipping the flower and then
from there i will do another top
dressing roughly 20 30 days into flower
and that usually gets me through the
grow and that's in seven gallon
containers but
you know you make me want to actually
switch to a larger container because
then i have to do less feedings right
it's worth it's worth it in the long run
uh and
it usually ends up equaling out i'm
always worried you know maybe if i do
that i i'm not going to be able to run
as many uh plants and and my harvest
isn't gonna be what it needs to be uh
but typically when you're running bigger
pots you're gonna get a bigger plant and
you'll get that heart that same harvest
that you were thinking of just with less
plants
and
it's gotten me so convinced that i'm
starting to think maybe i should move up
to 30 gallons and and do half the amount
of plants but i gotta really convince
goblin about that that would be a hard
one
so when you're doing the let's say let's
say you need to feed in veg right what
are you feeding in veg
um in in veg i really would just do a
light top dressing of the craft blend or
the dr earth blend that we were talking
about earlier
uh and just kind of let it do its work
uh water it in a little bit
let it let it take off if if i'm
noticing that that's not enough
for a certain plant then i'll probably
add some worm castings and a little bit
of compost if i've got some extra from
mixing soil
and that just kind of re it's like
recharge it reactivates the microbial
life and kind of gives it a kick in the
butt and say hey wake up and start
delivering nutrients to this plant and
then when you get into flowering are you
doing any different type of feeding or
is it the same exact thing that you just
mentioned that you do for veg
yeah same exact thing we might add a
little bit of what if we're doing a
compost tea you might add a little bit
of sugar i don't like to go too hard on
the sugar because most everything
uh
about the mix in in what you're doing
in organic growing is to get that
microbial life to
to be alive and to multiply and
it it can get a little too hardcore if
you start going crazy with molasses or
sugar so use i use that sparingly and
that's probably that's pretty much the
only other thing i add i'll you know
when i'm doing compost teas we'll do
the same stuff that's in the in the soil
mix the
booze compost the
little bit of little handful of craft
blend uh when i say handful i literally
mean i'll grab a handful and
that's it and i use a 30 gallon uh 35
gallon trash cans for everything i do it
keeps all the metrics the same so
my
water reservoirs 35 gallons the
soil batteries that i just made 35
gallons everything
adds up and i don't have to do a whole
bunch of math i'm thinking
maybe i didn't make this here t strong
enough there's no i don't have it i've
i've been doing it for so long that i've
taken a lot of the measurements out
and just started using
what what works for the containers that
i have because nothing
if the container doesn't change you know
exactly what you're dealing with they
mentioned worm castings and compost i
know microbes are going to come along
with that there's so many microbial
inoculants on the market today you also
mentioned recharge do you use any of the
micro products to inoculate the medium
at any point in the grow whether it be
you know recharge or mammoth p or any of
the micro products out there
not always uh if i have some around i
will i'll do it because it's a big
benefit it it is going to help i mean
there's no there's no reason not to use
it if you have it around if you don't
have it around i also wouldn't feel too
bad about it you can mitigate that
process like we were saying with
with your compost and your uh with your
manures and with your worm castings and
pretty much any other type of castings
uh
so i don't worry about it too much but
if i do have it around it's a blessing
i'll use it and
it speeds things up
uh you'll notice i've at least i've
noticed an increase in growth uh
in the increase in in the speed of
growth
when i use products like that
i wouldn't rely on them solely
because
i'm trying to get away from relying on
products
but also
it's great to have something to run to
like that it's the convenience of it is
amazing you also briefly talked about
compost teas so you do aerated compost
teas throughout the grow can we get
deeper into that a little bit i'm
wondering when you apply the compost
teas i know it's going to add in a lot
of beneficial bacteria microbes that are
needed to help break down those
amendments you know help with nutrient
uptake speed up growth so on and so
forth how often are you doing these
compost teas and what's your process for
brewing
so i like to do compost teas when i'm
noticing that the uh plant battery is
running out of juice and you'll you'll
you'll notice this with the way your
plants behaving it might be uh praying
one day then the next day you got a
couple yellow leaves and everything's
hanging down and it just the plant looks
sad doesn't look happening happy anymore
that's a good sign that it's time to
recharge up some of those microbes and
to do that the easiest way for a lot of
people including myself is a compost tea
i like to take a five gallon bucket with
two very large air stones
uh and i have a micron filter bag meant
for compost teas
i'll throw my ingredients in there
typically like a cup of booze blend a
handful craft mix uh
maybe a little bit of sugar
and we'll throw that we'll throw one air
stone in the bag and one air stone in
the bucket with the
mostly full of water you know it's 90
full of water and we'll leave that there
for 16
to 20 hours
i find if i go past 24 or into the 48
it's starting to get a little
too anaerobic in a sense uh for lack of
a better word
and i'd rather use it when it when it
has all that fresh new life that
just came out and it's ready to work
gotcha now i was going to ask you about
nutrient teas as well but it looks like
that's your you know that compost tea
that you mentioned you're adding in
nutrients right you said you're adding
in some craft blends and stuff like that
yeah so some of those i assume are going
to be water-soluble others aren't going
to be water soluble so do you take that
bag and then put it you know top dress
your soil with it or what do you do um i
use yeah honestly i'll take what's left
of that bag and i'll put it back into my
soil mix
and just kind of mix it back in and
whatever whatever's left is
only going to benefit that soil mix now
all right how about seed sprouted teas
do you use utilize those at all or no
me and goblin have not really used them
that much uh we have
tried it out you know just as a just as
a kind of science experiment but
i'm i'm pretty interested in it
it's kind of it's kind of more new to me
so
i'd like to try it out in a more
controlled setting maybe pick a tent and
those ones are going to get that and
everything else won't kind of thing and
just just see what happens
but no it was a it's a it's a
fascinating idea and i started looking
more into it once uh once you've brought
it up and
it's kind of it's kind of fascinating to
germinate a bunch of these seeds and
juice them up and then feed them back to
your
plants it's
it's a crazy idea that just might work
absolutely let's move on to mulch layers
so definitely key to use you know
especially when you're growing
organically you need to make sure that
the
that top layer is moist right the soil
needs to be moist in order to have those
micro ups active and a mulch layer is
one of those things that helps retain
the moisture in the medium right what do
you use for mulch layers typically right
now i use straw uh
it's pretty easy to deal with you know
and it does an excellent job of trapping
moisture on that top layer so that
things don't dry out
but
it's kind of a pain in the butt in a way
as well
and i'm i'm
exploring different ideas maybe uh
maybe even like a
non-organic idea maybe something like uh
that those sheets that they put on
gardens outdoors something that's just a
little less messy because when you go
back to
[Music]
i need to take the
this soil and mix it again you've got a
whole bunch of straw that you've got to
deal with and some of it is in big
pieces which is awesome you can grab
that pretty easy and some of it is kind
of shredded or or not decaying and
it it becomes a problem for me because
i'm super ocd when it comes to mixing
the soil and i only want the things that
i put in the soil in the soil
but
it works it works excellent and besides
you know getting a little
ocd about cleanliness
it's it's probably one of the best uh
options for a mulch layer
in my opinion
i've been using barley straw as a mulch
layer as well and yeah it's pretty easy
to use for sure you know when i am doing
that top dressing i am lifting it up and
putting those amendments underneath the
layer and kind of mixing in the soil
underneath that layer sometimes i'm
actually removing them entirely and then
putting the amendments up top and mixing
them in and then reapplying now some
people would probably probably say i'm
disturbing the microbe life a little bit
by removing that layer then re-adding it
but they might they might i mean it
might be but i'm not gonna lie
we do the same thing
i like you gotta lift that up and you
gotta sometimes you gotta move some soil
around and really mix it in there uh i
would rather that it got disturbed
and replenished
then
nothing happening at all
ah that's always a better option
doing nothing is never the right idea
let's move on to cover crops can you
talk to us about cover crops a little
bit what you do for them
yeah right now we're not using any cover
crops uh
but they can be very beneficial
especially in determining signs of
deficiencies uh before the plant is
actually
being harmed uh because those cover
crops are going to be the first ones to
see see the signs of a of any type of
deficiency
uh i think it's very smart to use a wide
variety of cover crops i see a lot of
people picking one and sticking with it
uh and that'll just be the cover crop on
every plant in in every pot
which is convenient it's easier i'll
give you that much but i think if you
had a mixture then you could see
different traits of different
deficiencies in different ways
on different cover crops giving you a
little wider spectrum of information
uh
and more benefits because once a lot of
these different cover crops degrade
differently when they die off which
giving you different types of nutrients
and maybe
you thought that this cover crop was
going to give you
more potassium but it actually gave you
way too much phosphorus and now you've
got a really really hot phosphorus in
your in your mix and
you're not really sure what to do at
that point that that's the only worry i
have with cover crops
is just if you are going to use them
keep them diverse
that way
your soil is eating a whole diverse
palette like a buffet of different
things and that's that's all everybody
wants really
gotcha definitely some good advice there
for sure
okay so
they've mixed their soil they've grown
their plant or they're using mulch
layers and cover crops or they're not
they're using compost teas
top dressing when needed they've gone
through their growth successfully
what do you do with that 15 gallon
container are you
removing it from that container and then
re-amending and then putting it back in
your concrete mixer or are you
keeping that container and just doing
kind of like a no-till style to where
you're just replanting directly into
that container re-amending and so on and
so forth
um a good 99 of the time i'm pulling
them and i'm gonna mix them with the
concrete mixer
if i had a rare case where i noticed
that the mix was hot all the way through
i didn't have to top dress in the flower
stage
and i wasn't doing very many compost
teas
and everything still went fine then i'm
gonna take those specific uh pots and
i'll replant directly in them i'll pull
the stock right out and i'll replant in
them for the veg and then that round uh
you'll have to keep an eye on a little
bit
a little bit more and
you might have to do more top dressings
and more feedings
on on that specific ground but it'll
save you a bunch of work if you're
dealing with with large numbers
uh
sometimes it's nice to be able to take
10 or 12
that are already
hot enough to handle a veg period and
just replanting them
gotcha i was just curious on that one
what you did because i know there's a
couple different ways to go about it for
sure let's go into k f so i think
there's probably quite a few people here
that are interested in knowing about knf
that's not something that we've talked
about yet on the podcast i haven't
really had any guests that really talked
about k f so let's just get a little bit
into it today maybe in the future i can
have somebody on here to talk a full
blown episode with k f i know you just
do a little bit of k f can you talk to
us about you know what is k f and then
what are some of the k f methods that
you practice
so k f just stands for korean natural
farming uh it's a it's a way of
organically growing uh in making your
own amendments
uh a lot of people are dependent
most of us are dependent on going to a
store and buying our own amendments
whether that's
uh a nutrient line or or even organic
amendments that are dried out and
to to get away from that you can
start
exploring the land of knf and
uh master chao is the guy that
kind of invented it or coined it or or
whatever you wanna whatever you wanna
say
and
he
shows you a plethora of different ways
to make things like fermented plant
juice and uh
labs and
you can
essentially replace everything you're
doing with
natural products that you can make at
home okay and then what do you typically
do for k f
i can't the only k f that i've
personally messed with
is like fermented plant juice uh i have
tried to make a few imo boxes
i'm still looking for the right area for
it uh
an imo is where you take
a sticky form of
rice uh you you cook up some rice you
get a sticky rice and you put it in a
box literally and you cover it up with a
paper towel
put it out in the forest where you where
you see there's a high microbial life
and you hope that
that rice gets inoculated by the
naturally occurring
funguses that are in that forest and
then you do some more there's like eight
18 more processes and i'm just a
beginner in k f
so i don't know exactly what happens
after that but you know that's the stuff
that i've been practicing so far
and it's it's a really fascinating world
to dive into because it starts getting
into the specifics of
exactly what's scientifically happening
when you feed your soil and when the
plant is
uptaking nutrients from the things that
you've given it with organics you kind
of take a step back and you're you're
just kind of
mixing things together and letting
nature take its course and then with knf
in my opinion it starts diving back into
the territory where you're in full
control
and you know exactly what each products
for and
what's happening when you give that
product and
and why that's so cool yeah a whole
different rabbit hole to go down you
know i mentioned this in far too many of
my videos but there are so many
different ways to grow this plant you
know and knf is another method to grow
it yeah
i was just watching some of chris
trump's videos uh if you guys are
interested in learning more k f i i
highly suggest checking out some of
those videos they're very informative
and they'll kind of go step by step in
explaining
what's going on with k f and why it's
really important
i've heard his name quite a few times i
heard he's an excellent resource for k f
super smart super smart individual
let's uh let's talk about one more thing
ipm you know i sometimes i feel like we
should talk about this first you know
pest prevention right what do we do to
what do we do to prevent pests i know
you grow organically you know all
natural what is your ipm routine so
first things first uh the best ipm
routine that you can keep in an organic
garden is make sure your your soil
batteries are moist always
that's going to be your first step
the second step is i love to use jadam
it's a wedding agent
uh
and it kind of follows along the same
lines as knf just a different category
of learning in
in
practice
and
it works so well as a disrefacton it has
a super widespread covering of the
leaves uh
it's super easy to coat both sides of
the leaves and
it doesn't have any downsides that i've
seen
it's a
it's a natural disrefacton it degrades
off the plant naturally uh within a few
days so
i've i've used it all the way through
flour even
and not notice the difference in
my product the way it tastes the way it
smells
and it's just gener generally a great
idea to have around if that if that's
not enough then i'll start adding
neem seed oil and lavender
to the to the judom
so that not only is it getting that
awesome widespread coverage
but it has
more
insect uh repellent and management
ingredients in it that are going to be
more effective because of that spray how
often do you spray and at what point in
the day do you spray
so if i'm having pest issues i'll spray
every day
if i'm not having pest issues i'll spray
twice to three times a week
uh
and and more often in the veg if i'm not
spraying with your dom i'll just spray
with just plain water uh in the veg and
just the act of of getting the leaves
moist and then them drying out is enough
to kill certain insects in and their
eggs
so that practice alone can
just save you a whole bunch of time and
i usually use it like before lights on
or uh yeah throughout the day okay yeah
especially in flower i spray i spray
before the lights are on probably 20
minutes before i'll go in there in the
dark
and just kind of feel the plant while
i'm spraying it which is another good
way to ensure
you're spraying the bottoms of the
leaves so if you grab a stock and you
just kind of spray in your hand while
you're moving up the stock
you know you're getting every leaf all
the way up that stock even in the dark
uh that's just kind of a trick i picked
up after years of spraying plants
but it it's very effective and it's
gonna just physically disturb if there
are eggs or actual pests on the bottoms
of those leaves it will physically
disturb them and
remove them essentially i think a lot of
people will spray during veg you know
sometimes it's once a week i know you
said every day you're spraying and then
you mentioned flowering as well and a
lot of people will stop spraying and
flowering because they don't want any of
this on their buds or flowers at all are
you do you spray and flower as well uh i
will only the jedom only the jadom
uh that's the only thing i'll spray in
flower and that's only because it
naturally degrades within two to three
days
uh
at first i was highly skeptical of doing
that in flower
and i was just like everybody else you
know i was super worried that it was
gonna affect the product in in any way
and that's not cool not cool with me
uh we gave it a shot
on the last couple
and
nothing nothing bad happened i i mean we
even if you have a pest issued during
flower and that's why we really wanted
to try it
if you have a pest issue during flower
you don't have a lot of options you know
you can you can get some green lace wigs
you can get some predatory mites you can
there's like only a few things you can
do without
severely degrading your product
and i was hoping that that could be one
more thing we could add to our list uh
to maybe save some plants in the future
that we're not as lucky so you only
spraying in flour if you see an issue or
are you okay only if you okay i wasn't
sure if you were still doing it as a
preventative everyday spraying through a
flower or not no no that'd be just
that'd be so much work in and it's not
if you're having that much of a problem
it's not a practical solution
uh
and then i just i would have i would
ought to drop the jadom thing a while
ago
but it but it is a good solution and
it's
super duper cheap it's super effective
uh we actually have a video on green
goblin 510 showing you how to make it
yourself
uh and it is available on the green
goblin 510 website as well if you just
want to give it a shot to see if it'd be
worth it uh in your garden uh or worth
it for you to make it and that's gonna
help repel or battle off tons of pests
right i mean we talking spider mites
aphids things like that or oh yeah we're
talking spider mites aphids thrips uh
you name it it's it's it's a powerful
disrefacton and it dry it's a it's a
soap in reality so it dries out the
exoskeletons
of
said bugs
uh if the bug doesn't have an outer
exoskeleton
it's even it's gonna work even better
so it really doesn't have a downside and
if you use it as intended and you and
you mix it as intended you'll dilute it
in a in your in your ipm regimen you
know there's no reason not to use it man
it's saved me so many headaches in in
pest management that i can't speak
highly of it enough
that's awesome
now we have a lot of good information
this video you know we talked about
mixing soil we talked about feeding
we touched on compost teas mulch layers
cover crops k f ipm a whole bunch of
things were packed into this episode
really appreciate your time today tell
us how can the listeners find you and
then we have upcoming in the future
uh so if you're trying to find me you
can find me on greengoblin510 uh the
youtube channel as well as twitch
greengoblin510
me and goblin are always streaming over
there as much as we can getting some
games in answering some girl questions
uh as well as if you're looking to
listen to some music in the garden i got
a bunch of that on soundcloud under
lantern beats
and uh
the only thing i got coming up is more
grow videos and more music
awesome i'll definitely link your
channel down in the youtube description
section below if you enjoyed this video
click that thumbs up button if you
haven't subscribed to the channel please
do i release these episodes every single
weekend and then if you're tuned in on
one of the podcast platforms uh
particularly apple podcast please leave
a rating and review green lantern thank
you so much for coming on to the podcast
today this has been awesome i totally
appreciate your time not a problem
hope you enjoy the rest of your day you
too thank you so much
[Music]
you