coming up on Garden talk I'm a big
believer in making sure your minerals
are up where they need to be you know we
focus a lot on NPK but really it's it's
all the kind of micronutrients and
minerals that really make the difference
you're better off just going out and
getting some Leaf litter the diversity
that's in some Leaf litter from the
forest floor is gonna far out compete
anything that you're buying from the
store the reason why a lot of people are
having to reinoculate or even say in the
package you know you have to do this
every month or every 90 days is because
most people are growing in volumes of
soil that are too small to sustain a
proper soil food web it's nice to do it
in a way that's not only responsible
because it's a regenerative practice but
in a lot of ways it's been proven that
it is the best way to produce that type
of medicine
foreign
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 88 in this
episode I interview James of organic
cultivators he runs a large-scale farm
and that's what we're going to get into
in today's episode he talks about how he
does things on his farm and some best
practices for farming on a large scale
if you gain value from these podcast
episodes please click the like button
and also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already so you can be notified
when I release new episodes if you'd
like to support even more visit
patreon.com Mr Grow it there are various
rewards set up for those of you who
support and you could pledge any amount
that you'd like 100 of the money pledged
through patreon goes right back into the
podcast it helps keep this podcast going
so thank you so much for those of you
who support before we get into it I want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring free gardening
information of all plants to the general
public switched it up a little bit there
eh that being said I like that thank the
sponsors of today's episode who helped
make that goal possible AC Infinity is
sponsoring this episode The Grow tank
hits are incredible you get there ion
board LED grow light their grow tent
which is currently the thickest on the
market the ventilation system clip-on
fan and the controller 69 to control it
all you also get their fabric pots a
trellis nut plant ties and trimmers
definitely a good price for all that you
get in the kit I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about these grow tent kits
and you can use discount code Mr Grow it
if you're buying off their website AC
infinity.com that discount code actually
works for all AC Infinity items or
discount code Mr Grow at 15 if you're
buying off Amazon and we are back
welcome to the Garden Talk podcast today
I am joined with James from organic
cultivators how you doing today I'm
doing good how are you good thanks for
asking today we're going to get into
large-scale farming so this topic has
actually been requested by quite a few
people because we haven't really covered
it on this podcast yet most episodes
really revolve around small operations
such as home grows so in this episode
let's focus on your experience in large
scale operations but first what I like
to do with all the guests is an
introduction can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening yeah I've been gardening
vegetables for probably 25 years or so I
was like a science experiment in
elementary school I don't remember what
it was but I had tomato seeds in a bag
and they germinated and sprouted and my
teacher was like you should go home and
plant those and it just like sparked a
thing where it was like this amazing
cool thing I could put a plant in the
ground and grow it and I put my first
Garden in the worst place possible uh up
against a building that was not facing
the South so
um it was mostly in the shadow the
entire time but over the years I kind of
just gradually uh grew things bigger and
started out as a lot of people do
especially you know back when I was a
kid you know you bought Miracle Grow and
you use that to fertilize your garden
and thought you were doing amazing
wonderful things because that's what
everybody did
and then I was 18 and I grew some
medicinal plants and a closet I built a
homemade nft system and grew plants with
a good old Dyna grow and eventually use
like the leftovers in my outdoor Garden
because you know it said I could and say
it's nutrients so why not over time uh
just kind of paying attention to what
was going on around me made these
logical leaps to moving away from that
stuff and building composts
um
really doing like polycropping I never
really just separated plants so I just
kind of started mimicking nature and
throwing like 20 of my Harvest just
right back onto the ground like
literally go out there and pick stuff
off the plants and drop it on the ground
and uh I just kind of felt like hey this
is what's happening naturally so this is
what should happen and my garden just
got better and better every year and uh
yeah and then eventually uh in Michigan
uh things ended up in a place to where
we could grow medicinal plants without
the fear of anyone coming in and getting
in trouble and uh kind of started
looking into my intention was to do an
nft system again but I figured I wanted
something a little faster and I grow my
garden outside every year so why not
grow and some soil indoors and I started
Googling like what's the best soil to
grow this plant and stumbled onto the
concept of the soil food web and Jeff
lowenfels and Lane Ingham and all these
people and
I stumbled into a couple other people
that kind of sparked the whole no-till
thing and really kind of being more
hands-off and so all these practices I
had been doing for like the last 20
years I had no idea any of the science
behind it the nomenclature nothing at
all so kind of stumbling into this uh
just kind of broadened this whole huge
picture for me and then I ended up in
some Facebook groups
and kind of there's a lot of drama in
them so I started my own group which has
kind of grown it's it's like 13 000
people in the group and we focus on
regenerative agriculture we put our
first conference on uh this year in
February in Sturbridge Massachusetts we
put our second one on this next February
and uh it's been kind of a crazy Journey
finding natural farming and it led me to
my fiance and moving to California and
stumbling into large scale uh medicinal
plant farming so uh yeah it's it's been
quite a change from growing in a few
tents in a basement to Growing 18 000
square feet outside
pretty wild wow 18 000 square feet that
that is huge roughly how many plants are
you growing in that space uh there are
nine light depth Hoops uh that take up
roughly uh 9 000 square feet each one of
those Hoops gets around 300 plants uh
per run uh so you know what's the 2700
plants I guess in the light depths and
then the full term Garden uh that kind
of varies depending on how early the
plants go in uh this year we got a a
much later start because of weird
weather out here so we have many more
plants in the space kind of like
hedgerows and much smaller so you see
you know people walking around with
plants that are at least as tall as them
which is nice any taller than that it's
unmanageable I would not want to be
getting on a ladder and dealing with
some of the monsters that people grow
which is a nice photo op and Wendy and I
are next year we're going to grow a
couple of them just so we can be like
you know check these monsters out but
for management of the canopy it's you
know it's definitely not economical uh
for time at all so uh yeah I think a lot
more smaller plants is probably the way
to go when you're growing at scale for
sure I can imagine the difficulty the
more difficult it gets with the bigger
plants me I'm just a small home grower
so I'm growing uh you know mostly
indoors I do have some outdoor plants
but mostly indoors grow tents you know
and I do keep my plants pretty small and
you know when I grow those bigger plants
what I call Big you know five six feet
it's uh certainly more work involved
than it is smaller plants you know two
three feet I gotta imagine the tools and
equipment are a lot different right so
when you're outdoors in a large scale
operation what tools and equipment you
typically use uh well I mean honestly
for us it's not that much different uh
certainly not that much different from
having
um well I mean I guess it depends if
you're talking about moving from tents
to a big uh large-scale operation that's
probably a lot of it is going to be a
bit different but if you've been doing
any type of home vegetable gardening or
anything like that what we do on our
farm is very similar
we do very minimal tillage basically if
we have to till we will there are
certain situations where that's
necessity certainly if you're opening up
a new field or something like that
tilling makes sense get some amendments
in there break up the the the grass and
so you can actually plant into it
but you know this last year when we had
to rip some ground like you know rented
a tiller we have a tractor that we
bought last year but we don't have the
funds to buy uh attachments for it right
now so it was me walking behind a tiller
tilling up some ground
you know again we try to do that as
minimally as possible
and really try to focus on things like
cover crops and doing some silage
tarping after knocking down cover crop
to kind of break things down but this
year the way things worked out we just
were not able to do that so you know we
made a decision and it it really it kind
of worked out it benefited us because we
do do a cover crop so heavily and that
ground was cover crop through the winter
um it seated so when we tilled
everything in there's a lot of biomass
and it all just grew back
um so we basically didn't have to to
reseed because we tilled all that in and
we were able to get some amendments in
there too so
um that that full term Garden right now
you walk out there there's personally
and that's like a foot and a half high
and that's you know we literally Chopped
all that stuff down and tilled it in so
it comes back pretty well okay so let me
ask you this we'll get into cover crops
first and then we'll kind of get back
into kind of how you prepare the soil
for planting because I assume that
you're doing cover crops between grows
is that right and what do you typically
do for cover crops
so out here
um we buy like a
fodder scene basically
um it's uh it's what's available locally
um so there's like some fava beans and
some veg and stuff like that in there
um
you know the cover cropping we do is
really like at the end of cycle and then
there's companion plants that are out
there along with the plants if you want
to get technical about what you're
calling you know each thing and at the
end of the year we will plant different
things and what we're companion planting
with everything I just described like
the purslane those are companion plants
that were put out there
and then our covers depending on the
situation we'll use different things
this is my this will be my second winter
in California
so my goal is to really try to put out
some different cover crops than where
last year which was kind of like
a variety depending on what the soil
tests reads so we may change up what
we're doing I know we're talking about
planting
um
for making our own mulch next year
because we weren't able to get any mulch
this year everybody was contracted out
so there are some considerations that
we're trying to make outside of just
nutritional but how much biomass is
created by whatever we're planting out
there because we got a fair amount of
ground we need to cover and we don't
necessarily want to do it with Native
grasses that seed really fast and we
don't want to deal with that but in
between grows we basically just follow
everything we let it go let the plants
ride out the winter come back knock
everything down try to get some tarps on
it let the sun bake everything and come
back and you can literally just stick
your hand in the ground
unfortunately we weren't able to do that
this year with the amount of rain that
we had how long does it take after you
you knock down the cover crop and you're
saying you're putting like a tarp over
it how long until you actually we take
that off and then start planting in a
few weeks depending on the weather
and how much sun there is it can be a
few weeks
we got out to our planting started so
late in the season that we had plants
the weather was there so you know we
just honestly got out there a little
late this year and weren't able to to
make it happen but ideally given the
amount of
old light depth tarps that we have on
hand you know it just makes sense to use
that certainly over you know using you
know tilling every year or something
like that it really does destroy your uh
the micro life in your soil so
so we try to avoid that got it and then
after you remove those tarps are you
doing anything to prepare the soil for
planting like some people add in
amendments for example some people will
inoculate with microbes for example are
you doing any sort of preparation prior
to planting so
um this year what we did ideally you'd
want to get a soil test to kind of gauge
where you're at
um we weren't we did not do that this
year so basically what we did is we
um each bed got some rock dust it got
some organic chicken manure uh it got
some some lime
and some alfalfa meal so we do do
amendments between Cycles I'm a big
believer in making sure your minerals
are up where they need to be you know we
focus a lot on NPK but really it's it's
all the kind of micronutrients and
minerals that really make the difference
uh so I'm a big believer and get some
rock dust out there every time
um you you can do uh you know a larger
application of rock dust
um less times depending on how much
you're doing it you could do an
application of rockness like once every
20 years
as far as inoculations
in my home grows I was doing all kinds
of stuff I was doing compost teas and
playing with IMO and in the beginning
was really heavy-handed I think a lot of
us when we get into growing it's like we
want to play with everything and it's
such a responsive plant that you know it
it's satisfying you really can see
changes when you're when you're playing
with things the danger with that is even
if you have a fair understanding of what
you're trying to do is being
heavy-handed and you can throw things
out of bounds so for for me I was doing
teas like every week and I know people
do do tease every week for me I was
adding too much to my teas and then
throwing things out of balance so
you got to kind of be careful what
you're when you're going and getting
information online who you're getting it
from and kind of parse that with some
common sense and understand that the
system itself works pretty well on its
own
out on the farm the inoculations that
get done are imos
and Imo hasn't been done for the last
few years so our plan is to do one for
this next season but essentially we're
going out and collecting indigenous
microorganisms from different biomes
essentially and then propagating them
out on piles of of carbohydrates and
carbon and it is a you know it's a
selection for bacterial or excuse me for
terrestrial yeast and fungi and there
will be some different bacterias in
there but essentially the way it's done
um is you know it's just a great
collection of uh microbes that you can
bring to your farm for very little money
as opposed to buying an inoculum from
the store which you know
they're usually you know it's four or
five species it's very limited so you
don't have diversity there not saying it
can't help you certainly in an indoor
growth and if you're in a sterile soil
or dirt essentially you know those
inoculums can help you uh definitely but
you're better off many times just going
out and getting some Leaf litter the
diversity that's in some Leaf litter
from the forest floor is gonna far out
compete anything that you're buying from
the store keeping in mind and having an
understanding that you're also bringing
in other things into an indoor
environment that's not a complete soil
food web so you can have things run out
of control a lot of people like seeing
roly-polies and they're they're grow
because they bind up heavy metals and
you know they eat detritus the problem
is they they explode out of control so a
lot of
um living soil Growers are now having
problems with roly-polies and bringing
uh Leaf litter into your grow while it's
can be a great idea can also cause you
some problems so some of these things
you kind of need to understand that
there's a balance here and
indoor and outdoor like in my indoor
I've always had a low level thrips issue
about six months in I had thrips under
my grow
they're not that bad apply some
beneficials I did some sprays here and
there but I had a clover cover they love
that stuff and they live everywhere they
live in the plant tissue they're very
hard to get rid of
so I just kind of dealt with them and
and survived with them
um Outdoors you know on the farm and
even in my vegetable grow I just let
pests go generally if I saw a pest enter
the garden they weren't there very long
had aphids come and attack my milkweed
every year in Michigan and within a week
or two they were gone
they never became a problem because I
had a diverse population of plants on my
property and kept everything pretty
healthy because I wasn't spraying a
bunch of stuff on it all the time you
mentioned balance a few different times
and I want to kind of focus in on this
for a little bit specifically the
balance of nutrition in the soil so you
mentioned that you're typically doing a
soil test and then you're finding the
balances off so you're amending in there
I think there's a lot of folks that grow
organic or no-till regenerative and they
hear that the plant uptakes nutrients as
needed and it's a common misconception
that things can't get out of balance
because of that can you talk to us about
like how important it is to stay in
balance and what damage can actually be
done if you're out of balance yeah and I
I will say all of this with the caveat
that I'm not a soil scientist
I've caught myself as someone who's very
good at collect acting people who are
wildly more intelligent than I am and
know a lot more about this stuff than I
do they help me run my group so I defer
to them on a lot of this stuff I will
say that in my experience
depending on the size of your
vesicle that you're growing in
much like a fish tank it has more
buffering capacity so there's more room
for error you can throw a lot of things
at it for much longer without throwing
it out of balance
um
I think again for me I think if you
start off with a base if you have a an
understanding of
um how the different nutrients work
together and I don't have a great
understanding of that
um soil science is extremely complicated
I'm reading books all the time when I
have the time but
um there's a lot of nuance in this and
the science is just barely being
scratched at
I will say that you know there are some
important things we understand about
mineral balance and how cations work and
if you have certain things super out of
balance then nutrients won't uptake and
there's part of the problem is we look
at this as a chemistry thing so it's
like you know nutrients in a certain pH
are available and that is very true
um
but you know the biology is so important
in all of this so I think really if you
create a environment that's hospitable
to a a diverse biology and you don't
mess with them too much they can balance
a lot of things
but again you know if you're I think of
a lot of problems come with people think
they're or growing organically and
they're using bottled nutrients there's
a lot of soluble
nutrients in those bottles and that can
throw things off of balance a lot faster
than if you're overdoing it on some dry
amendments it's it's a little bit harder
to overdo it that way
but people do it all the time so you
know for me I started out with like a
clats Coots mix with basically with
negating the neem meal because I could
it and get it locally and people are
kind of weird about it so I just didn't
use it and I've just kind of
grew the soil from there
I think if you really want to look into
like soil science and the numbers and
balancing things behind soil testing you
should look into Dan kitchen just talks
on YouTube he's actually one of the
speakers at the conference he's able to
break things down in a way that kids
understand it so you know explaining how
what PH actually is and how it functions
and and what it means looking at it as a
fuel tank as opposed to just a number
that makes a nutrient available
so yeah I think looking
the ideas that he presents are largely
from
um on the soil science aspect the
testing uh John or not John Kemp
Albrecht and so there are some specific
numbers
on the mineral side of things that have
kind of been
collectively decided upon by albrecht's
students they've kind of all come
together and decided what these optimal
numbers are
and there there are some slides on his
Talks on YouTube that he kind of like
lays it all out so if you're someone who
has a hard time deep diving into the
books that can be kind of long-winded
and complicated there are some some
cheats out there that you can go and
find these people and and get into that
aspect of it outside of that I think
keep it simple is probably the best
advice and the best path forward if
you're doing a worm casting tee once a
month you're probably killing it you
know like that is a really easy
maintenance thing to do uh for your
indoor as a maintenance tee for biology
I'm not really familiar with those
sources I'll have to check them out
there's so much good information out
there you mentioned that the when it
comes to soil science it's so complex it
really is and we're just scratching the
surface like you said like there's a lot
of things we do not know about this and
uh it's exciting to be the things that
we're unraveling as we continue to go on
so so yeah I'll definitely check out
those sources Let's uh let's flip it up
let's talk about mulch layers so uh from
my understanding you do use multiple
layers large scale it can certainly be
different than smaller scales so talk to
us about mulch layers yeah I mean in my
indoor I grew all kinds of stuff in my
bed and would just smash it down and use
it as mulch you know Swiss chard like
just stuff for biomass essentially
um in the on the farm we try to use uh
alfalfa
straw as much as we can but like I said
this year we weren't able to get any of
it it's all been contracted
you know anything that you can get on
your soil to cover it up so it's not
bare is probably a good thing outside of
a bunch of you know grass seeds that you
don't want to deal with later on down
the line
um
yeah you know nature really you know
doesn't like bare soil the microbes have
a real hard time existing in an
environment that's just being baked by
UV rays and dried out and generally if
soil is not covered up it dries out
really fast
we try to add a mulch that has some
nutritional aspect to it as hence the
Alfalfa but if you don't have that even
like a third or fourth cutting hay you
know get it on there and cover it up
you're going to be doing much better
certainly you know if you can't
you know use cover crops in the winter
or you know for whatever reason a layer
of you know eight to ten inches of mulch
you'd be surprised at how much that does
to improve soil aeration and soil health
over a winter like you come back and
there's a good amount of topsoil there
that's nice and loose and arable so
definitely beneficial eight to ten
inches huh it seems kind of thick is
that typical for outdoors oh that's what
we put on that's what we put on our beds
uh for our plants on the farm a nice
thick layer of mulch and you know before
Harvest it's gone it's it's generally
mostly gone interesting yeah I usually
just do it indoors I mean completely
different right but uh you know two
inches roughly is what I do but maybe I
need to thicken it up a little bit it'd
probably be beneficial especially if I'm
using something that's going to break
down and be nutrients for the plant so
well that's what I was going to ask you
how how long before you have to
replenish your mulch uh you know
typically lasts most of the grow you
know I'm in a very dry climate I live in
the desert and so the water retention in
the soil keeping that top layer moist is
difficult for me so adding in that mulch
layer is is very beneficial but it can
last but pretty much the entire grow how
big is your are you growing in a pot hot
or a bed I've been doing seven gallon
pots okay so
um do you have a microscope I do not
okay so I will tell you that the single
best investment in a tool that I ever
made
um for growing was a microscope
um
we like to think that we're growing in
living soil uh in small pots because
we're doing all of these practices that
really are beneficial to building and
maintaining a living soil unfortunately
when you're in that small of a volume
it's it doesn't have that buffering
capacity that we're talking about it
doesn't have the ability to sustain
moisture
the way that you would like to it's not
enough volume for life to sustain itself
in a cycle Without You consistent
continually having to add more life to
it so when you see that when you buy
something from the store
um like an inoculum
there's two facets to this one is that
it's a lab-grown microbe so
they're kind of weaker but they should
propagate and live in an environment
um and and keep breeding and living and
reproducing as long as they have food
and the conditions are right so the
reason why a lot of people are having to
reinoculate or even stay in the package
you know you have to do this every month
or every 90 days is because most people
are growing in volumes of soil that are
too small to sustain a proper soil food
web there has I don't I'll have to ask
uh Wendy what the guy's name was but
there has been
um some limited research done that shows
at about 60 to 65 gallons of soil is the
minimum you want to have a self-cycling
self-sustaining living soil that you're
not constantly having to add things to
my suspicion is that your mulch is
lasting so long because you don't have
the amount of microbiology that would be
efficient to actually break it down
and that in turn you probably you would
see an increase in your cannabinoid and
terpene levels if you got into a larger
volume of soil because you would have
that diversity and microbiology and that
would create a more complex cannabinoid
and terpene profile
the reason why our mulch doesn't last
very long out on the farm is because the
microbiology out there kills it you can
literally lift up clumps of dirt that
have fungi running through them and we
have like I said we haven't inoculated I
don't think Wendy's put I am author this
will be the fourth season so it's been
four years since she's made an IMO
application it's a testament to you know
the microbes being Hardy and the
environment being such that
you know once there's water out there
they just go off you know so and that's
the other thing too is
you know people have this and again not
a soil scientist but people have this
misnomer about
um microbiology like dying off when
things get dry
yeah I mean sure but they you know
mostly they go dormant and it can take a
long time for them to come back so you
know Outdoors where they the biology
goes deep the soil can get pretty dry in
areas out there and then once we have
water out there the plants just they
kill it and you can see the activity you
can see the fungi coming back Plumping
up it never disappeared it was always
there just kind of dried out and went
dormant
indoors when your pot dries out and
everything goes dormant it takes a long
time for it to wake up because it's all
gone dormant and then again you're
having to reinoculate so there are all
these things that when you're in a small
pot fighting all these forces they stack
up and it makes it harder for you to
maintain so I like I said I I think if
you get into a bigger volume you and
focus on getting more diversity in there
you'll probably notice your going away
faster and if you get a microscope and
you Scope your seven gallon pot compared
to like a good living soil I think
you're going to be surprised at how
little is actually happening in there
because I thought I was killing it
in my bed and then I got a microscope
and I was like wow there's almost
nothing happening here and I could see
the effects of it starting to happen in
the plant but I still thought I was
doing such a great job
so once and the other aspect of that is
I don't know if you do teas at all
compost teas but I was doing compost
teas a lot and just going off of recipes
and times you know you put this in the
tea and your boy you know you run it for
36 hours
um
until you have a microscope and you're
actually looking at the T itself you
have no idea what you've grown in there
and you're not going to know all the
names of everything because that's
impossible no one does but you can
definitely look in there and see you
know do I have bacteria in there is it
full of just a bunch of E coli uh you
know do I have some higher order
organisms have I brewed it to a point
where it's nothing but those higher
order protozoa and they've consumed all
the bacteria and all the oxygen
depending on the type of tea that you're
going for that might be a great thing if
your soil is completely dead you know
some produce oil Not a Bad Thing an
anaerobic tea
it's not the worst thing it's not the
greatest thing there are anaerobes that
live in your soil so like there are all
these taboo things you don't want to put
a super anaerobic stinky tea on your
soil don't get me wrong but there are
some some words like anaerobes or people
like yeah it can't be anaerobic it can't
whatever
you know there are facultative anaerobes
there are things like
lactobacilli which you know are
definitely facultative anaerobes and
they're good they're in your gut they're
they're all over the place we use them
to to clean with so gotta yeah time and
time again organic farmers have
mentioned that uh should be using a
larger container and uh yeah some people
are trying to you know they're they're
they're trying to run Organics in three
gallons five gallons because it's easier
to move that around but I mean you bring
up some fantastic points and I've heard
it before I'm slowly working towards
larger containers it's only a matter of
time before I'm in a bed running
Organics and uh potentially you know
getting to the point where I don't have
to till at all but I'm a little bit of
ways there I would say I'll tell you
when you make the switch to your bed the
biggest learning curve I would tell
everyone this when they're switching to
beds is watering that'll be your biggest
learning curve is how to water that bed
properly without over watering it or
underdoing it and so my
my biggest piece of advice to you is
when you build your bed and you're
putting soil in it water your soil in
layers as you're building it so you make
sure your bed is watered sufficiently
from top to bottom the first time you
put your soil in there because if you
fill that with dry soil and then you
start to water that you will have
hydrophobic pockets in that that you are
battling forever so I I can't stress
enough uh you know water that as you're
putting it in
that's a really good tip for sure so
tucking on a large scale fertilizer you
know you have the plants growing you
already mentioned what you do for cover
crops mulch layer how you prepare the
soil to begin you've planted those
plants in there and they start to grow
at what point do you fertilize and what
do you use for a fertilizer so it really
depends on you know and and the outdoor
really kind of keeping an eye on the
plants
when we're able to be out there on a
regular basis and for this next year
we're trying to set it up so we have
somebody out there on a more regular
basis we have five kids we don't live on
our farm our farm is about 45 minutes
away from the homestead so just to get
out there it's a trip but
in an Ideal World we would be doing a
weekly maintenance spray which is a
Korean natural farming
concoction of some k f inputs uh it's a
fermented plant juice an oriental
Oriental herbal nutrient which is a
tincture with vodka and a brown rice
vinegar or a live vinegar and and that's
sprayed as like a weekly maintenance
which is basically a super minor plant
food which has all different types of
micro and macronutrients in it some of
the fpjs that we've seen the
uh nutrient test results on have been
really interesting there's there's a
wide variation of nutrients in there but
they're all at very you know it's all
one to one thousand one to five hundred
so it's not very much uh the nice thing
about all of the k f inputs is they're
they're edible you can take them a lot
of people take them for human health but
you certainly don't have to worry about
them hurting you uh because you can eat
them uh so it'd be like a weekly spray
of that and then there are some other
inputs if you needed some calcium and
some phosphorus you could add some
calfas which is essentially some some
charred bones that are then soaked in
vinegar
um really you know ideally you have all
of the nutrients and everything you need
in the ground
uh at the beginning of the year you've
kind of you've set your you know you've
filled your fuel tank up essentially
um and then we have all of these tools
that we can use to kind of top it off
when we need to
um but you know last year we weren't
able to do anything uh as far as k f
maintenance sprays really um at the end
of the year we didn't do anything to our
full term it was you know water only and
again that is a testament to the
microbiology that that is out there a
lot of people would say the terroir and
I I think there probably is something to
that as well as far as the end product
goes
um
but yeah so we'd be doing like
maintenance sprays and then you know
topping it off with the occasional
addition to those sprays sometimes we
will fertigate with those same uh
concoctions
those same inputs all at the same rate
you're just using more of it because
you're soaking it into the ground as
opposed to foliar feeding once we get
towards the end of the cycle we don't
really like spraying stuff on the plants
so we move away from that and then
certainly if you're doing something like
a liquid IMO which is the IMO in kind of
a compost tea form you definitely don't
want to be spraying that on flowers
because you can fail microbial testing
and stuff like that
but yeah essentially we're pretty hands
off and and mostly you know setting
ourselves up at the beginning of the
year really taking care of the
microbiology
making sure we have you know a diverse
set of plants out there we always have
flowers and different kind of wild
plants and
you know given that it's it's me and my
fiance and her you know 70 year old mom
uh you know we we're pretty limited on
how much we can be out there but the
fact that uh you know the end products
consistently won awards and uh you know
people definitely really enjoy it I uh
you know it works out pretty well so I'm
I'm a firm believer of the you know
keeping it simple kind of trying to stay
hands off and a lot of that comes down
to you know working in concert with
nature understanding that not everything
is going to go your way you're not going
to be able to control everything and
that's probably a good thing
I think the best thing about
uh the plant that we're talking about is
that
um it's a Gateway plant it everybody
wants to grow everything after they
start growing it I hardly know anyone
that started growing it that hasn't
moved to other things it was the reverse
for me I I liked growing plants period
so it's just a really fun plant to grow
and it brings a lot of joy to people and
and healing so it's nice to do it in a
way that's not only responsible because
it's it's a regenerative practice
but you know I think it
in a lot of ways it's been proven that
it is the best way to produce that type
of medicine
so you're almost entirely doing natural
farming techniques besides that rock
phosphate for example that you mentioned
for the initial amending or the initial
amendments that you put in prior to
planting you're doing natural farming
techniques now let me ask you prior to
implementing these natural farming
techniques was your farm using chemicals
at all or did you always just start with
the natural farming Yeah Wendy on their
Farm
uh I'm trying to think I think you know
back in the day like a long time ago
when her parents were growing and she
was growing up and that kind of stuff
they were definitely
um
using some chemical nutrients here and
there but I think everybody was back in
the day I will say that when everything
went legal here and everyone was
freaking out Wendy was confused why and
then everyone started feeling testing
and she was like oh because everyone
uses like crazy chemicals and they don't
um
I think at you know early on they made
the switch from anything that was a
synthetic nutrient to organic because
that's how they were growing their food
so it didn't make sense to keep doing it
like that
I know you know as far as K F that farm
has been running you know knf inputs for
six years now
uh where it's you know they're it's just
you know us making inputs and then
applying them
um you know as I said before when I
started out growing I was definitely
using Miracle Grow and
um hydroponic whatever uh that was out
there and it you know it was a few shops
in Michigan that had that stuff because
it wasn't like every corner store like
it is now there was like one spot you
had to drive an hour and a half to and
get your nutrients for your tomatoes
that you're growing and uh you know do
it like that
um you know I don't
fault anyone who's using that stuff I
mean the thing is
a lot of people just don't have a deeper
understanding of soil science because a
lot of it's so new and it is just
permeating the culture and
um you know there are all these new hot
button things that you know regenerative
and organic and
um you know unfortunately all these
labels kind of get co-opted and people
you know twist things around and then
there ends up hat being negative
connotations to them that's part of the
reason why I'm trying to talk to so many
people in different camps you know the
permaculture people don't necessarily
hang out with the biodynamic people they
don't necessarily hang out with just the
organic dudes who are buying bottles of
whatever
um you know there's a lot of people that
really believe in in that you know
bottle of magic or whatever that they're
buying from the store like it's the best
stuff unfortunately at Large Scale you
it's you know it's far too expensive you
can't grow at Large Scale by buying
bottles of nutrients and I'll tell you
right now that you know some of the
farmers that are
um you know hyping these expensive
nutrient lines out there uh you know
they're they're not hyping them because
they're buying them and they work so
great they're hyping them because
they're paid money and they were given
to them they would never buy those
because they can't afford them at large
scale it's the same reason why nutrient
companies go all around the world and
get Farmers hooked on fertilizer and
teach them how to grow with their
fertilizer and then basically make them
indentured slaves for the rest of their
life because it's the only way they know
how to grow and they have to buy these
nutrients from the companies that have
come in that's part of the reason why
we're trying to set up our non-profit is
to show people that they can make
nutrients from the things around them in
nature and and you know kind of get off
that teep and I'll tell you that people
who are fighting really hard in the
regenerative space and natural farming
you know those are people that
um you know their their Rebels out you
know they're they're the people on the
front line who when this really starts
to threaten uh fertilizer companies
um know they're the ones who are going
to take the brunt of the hit
so it's really important that we all
connect and not in fight and come
together because you know we have much
more power uh coming together as one big
loud voice as we do a bunch of small
camps that are in fighting with each
other and we're all banging the same
drum but we're banging it at a different
beat and we all got to get on the same
beat
um so that's kind of what my goal has
been is to get everybody talking about
the same thing and you know right now is
a great time because
with everything going on fertilizer
costs are super high or you can't even
get it so a lot of farmers are making
the switch to organic practices but
they're gonna fail they're going to fail
a lot because their land is screwed up
and it takes time to repair that it
doesn't take a lot of time it can
actually take a very short amount of
time if you do it properly but there are
there are a lot of people that are going
to make mistakes and they need help and
they shouldn't be ostracized because
they've been growing with chemical
nutrients this whole time that's what
they were taught
you know you can't fault them for that I
think it's foolish to try to fight with
the big AG companies because you're
never going to win and they're not going
anywhere I think our main goal needs to
be to show them how this is the best way
for one thing farmers can save a lot of
money by switching the natural farming
you're certainly going to save money on
inputs your labor is going to go up a
bit but in the end once the consumer is
fully educated on what nutrient density
is and why it is important how you grow
your crops in medicine is going to
become instrumental and it will drive
the price of Commodities as opposed to
there just being a flat price right now
basically unless you're in a farmer's
market a tomato is the cost of a tomato
you know but they're
there can be
um incentive there for Farmers to grow
the best produce possible as opposed to
the most produce and it is a shift
that's happening
um and it's interesting to see got it
yeah I was just curious about that one
going from chemical nutrients to Natural
farming with the time savings would be
versus the the cost savings the
difference in product and all that stuff
I'll tell you that you know if you're
you know buying anything in a bottle you
are mostly paying for water
um and you're paying for it to be
shipped to you uh so you know the cost
for sunabis to switch from its regular
you know buying
um fertilizer uh and amending and all of
its other practices she was spending two
dollars an acre going from two dollars
an acre to 20 cents an acre so you're
talking about ten percent of the input
cost
um than than what it was so again like
your input cost will go down but you are
going to go up in labor a little bit
because it takes time to make this stuff
but you know if you get a group of
people together at the beginning of the
year you can smash out your inputs for
the whole year in a couple of days
so you're making all your inputs in a
couple of days and then there's the
added labor of applying like maintenance
brace to your plants or whatever but
depending on your setup if you're a
large-scale farm and you have a tractor
certainly you have a sprayer for the
back of that tractor so you hook your
sprayer up and you put your maintenance
spray in there and you drive up and down
the rows and it sprays the spray on your
plants and you're done
so I I know that you know there are
people who you know do a whole Orchard
in an hour or less
uh they just drive up and down the rows
and they spray and their Orchards do
that all the time anyway they're
spraying all kinds of chemicals on those
trees so you just switch over to the k f
input or whatever other thing you're
using that's a natural farming input and
you're not really increasing your labor
costs there because you're already
spraying other chemicals so really in
those situations it's a huge cost
savings because you have dropped your
inputs down so much I will say that you
know there are
there's lots of different natural
farming stuff out there and you know
there's knf and there's jadam and
there's other practices not all of them
are interchangeable and they have
different applications there's not a
whole lot in the way of pest control in
Korean natural farming but there is in
jadam so yeah significant cost savings
which is what I assumed and what I've
heard so that's really good to know okay
few more questions for you one of them I
like to ask towards the end of every
episode which is really advice for
beginners you know there are people
listening in here that are transitioning
to a large scale operational maybe they
just started working in a large scale
operation what tips do you have for
those that are making that transition oh
a laundry list
um I I would say that if you're moving
into the industry as a whole not even
just as a grower
um
it's probably going to dishearten you a
little bit there aren't much ethics
involved yet because there isn't a whole
lot of in the way of legal recourse
um so uh just a word of caution there as
far as people uh moving into growing or
learning about how to grow
um
I I would say be very careful where
you're getting information from there
are a lot of people out there who
pretend to be experts in everything
uh and I will tell you that the Kruger
dining syndrome is a real thing
um you know people often before they
people think they know more than they
know
um anyone who's claiming to be a master
grower
you should probably be wary of them
um
you use common sense
uh whenever someone is trying to tell
you something try to think about does
this apply in the natural world
um they're like there's a lot of
tinkering that goes on and that's fine
but really keep it simple
um
there are some great learning resources
out there
uh
some of them even though they're great
learning resources have the tendency to
push some what we would consider bro
science uh and it's it may only be Bro
Science because it hasn't been uh proven
out in a way that can be peer-reviewed
so you need to be careful when you're
listening to people who do have
authority and a lot of followers and
understand that unless you can find this
information in white papers online
scholarly articles that have been
published then this is just conjecture
on someone's part I'm a big fan of
people saying I don't know
uh so anyone who can be upfront and
honest about their limitations and their
knowledge that's huge uh you want to
listen to those people
um
that's probably the best advice I can
give is and be careful of who you are
getting advice from reach out to people
who are trusted and have been around for
a long time and ask their advice uh you
know feel it out a bit before you just
go down a rabbit hole of adding a bunch
of stuff to your grow and then you've
killed all of your plants
that would be my second piece of advice
is trial everything out do side by sides
don't assume that because you applied
something to your grow and you killed it
that that thing was the determining
Factor did you apply five other things
that you hadn't done before did you do a
side by side with a control group if you
did not do that you have no idea that
what you have done has been beneficial
or negative to you in any way
so if you're moving into this space and
you want to learn the best way possible
and you are going to Tinker make sure
you're doing side by sides make sure
you're keeping a track of what you're
doing because in our group if you say
something you need to be able to back it
up and it doesn't have to be something
that is out there for the whole world
the published study but have some data
we like to debate things we like to talk
about what people have done but if you
don't do that work and you just have a
claim
you don't really know you have no idea
what you did
did anything for you at all
solid advice obviously do your due
diligence try to find those research
papers if they're out there and um yeah
sharing sharing is caring James how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future uh well you
can always find us on Facebook in the
organic cultivators Facebook group uh it
is you know you got to work to get in
there there's some questions to answer
we don't we don't want to do the work
for you you know you got to do some work
for yourself so if you can't at least
Google to answer some questions you know
you're probably going to be somebody
that takes too much time
um there's a lot of people in the group
uh the people that you know
uh some bigger names in the industry so
to speak and they all help out in the
group which is kind of cool you can find
me on Instagram at organic cultivators
and we're gonna have our next conference
in Sturbridge Massachusetts February
17th 18th and 19th and the 20th will be
a special Workshop day with Suzanne
Wainwright uh so yeah come check it out
it's going to be a lot of fun we'll have
Dan kittridge there and Dr James White
from Rutgers if you guys know who he is
he's done some amazing work on the
rhizophagy cycle so we're gonna have him
come out and talk and Suzanne Wainwright
will be there and uh yeah it's gonna be
a lot of fun organic cultivators.net
awesome I'll definitely have a link to
to list your Instagram down in the
YouTube description section below and
then of course if you're listening I
know one of the podcast platforms just
search from he'll show up James thanks
again for coming on this is a great talk
I definitely learned a few things and I
think it's going to bring a lot of value
to my audience so thank you for your
time today and I hope you enjoy the rest
of your day yeah thanks it was a lot of
fun it was it was good to meet you and I
hope to see you at the conference
absolutely peace out everyone catch you
in the next episode