welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 142 in this episode I
interview Mr ganx he is an organic
Gardener and he grows his plants in
small containers it's often said that
you can't be successful growing
organically in smaller containers but he
proves otherwise and he talks all about
it in this episode unfortunately we had
a technical issue with this episode the
recording platform didn't capture his
video properly so I just have a
screenshot for him the audio is
perfectly fine though so for all of you
listening in on podcast platforms
there's no impact to you if you want to
see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said I
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make that goal
possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
Advanced grow kits which include nearly
everything you need to start growing
indoors they have several different size
kits and they all come with a grow tent
grow light ventilation system
oscillating clip fan a controller 69 Pro
and so much more click the the link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about their grow kits and the
discount code Mr Grow 15 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infiniti.com
stash blend stash blend is a
215 plant additive that can be used with
synthetic bottled nutrients or in living
soil systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risle fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the
stash and we are back and I'm joined
with Mr ganx how you doing today I'm
doing good how are youing good man
thanks for asking a little bit congested
I'm getting over a sickness here so you
can hear my voice a little bit I
apologize in advance to those folks that
are listening in but we're going to
power through it we got a great
conversation today going to be talking
all about growing organically so this is
the way that you uh grow uh you have a
couple different grow Styles which we'll
get into here but yeah why don't we
start off with an introduction can you
tell us a little bit about yourself and
how you got into gardening absolutely so
I'm Mr ganx um from hom grow the
community and I got into growing right
around the 2018 Mark I think it was the
this may of
2018 um I got going for my first round
was outdoors and
um yeah I just got the bug right away
and once I got through my very first
season um I couldn't wait for the next
season to come along so I did all the
research I could possibly do and that's
when I started doing my whole indoor
thing awesome so you grow both indoor as
well as outdoor you got experience in
both areas which are two different
battlefields really particularly when it
comes to things like pests which we're
going to get into here in a little bit
I'm sure there's a a lot of people out
there that are in a situation that
they're battling pests and they want to
take an organic approach to elimination
so we'll definitely get into that here
but I'd like to start off with soil mix
so can you talk to us in detail what is
your soil mix sure um so I start with
promix as my base promix HP and I like
to use promix because it's bare there
isn't anything in it um you don't have
to worry about anything being too hot or
not enough of something or whatever you
can kind of pick and choose what you
want to put in there so I use Gaia green
as my the majority of what I put in
there um I'll start off with like the
allpurpose
444 for for veg and I'll mix everything
into the soil before I fill up the pots
and I I like to use like a 3 to 5 gallon
because my my setup isn't overly big so
I like to keep
it be able to put as many plants in
there as I can
um so I'll start off with promix HP I'll
add allpurpose
444 I like to use alphalpha meal um kelp
meal um I use dious Earth um oyster
shell flour I like to use that for like
my my calcium I add a little bit of
Epsom salt for magnesium and that's
basically it that I would add in at the
beginning and then as time goes on I'll
I'll do a top dress every couple weeks
two to three weeks depending on what the
plants are looking like I listen to the
plants I let them kind of tell me what
to do next if if I don't see anything
going on you know I'll just kind of
stick to a schedule but if there's
something that I notice you know a
yellowing or deficiencies of any kind I
I'll kind of Judge my next round of
nutrients based off of that got it and
then what are you using for container
size are you starting off in small
containers and then kind of working your
way up transplanting into larger
containers or are you just in one
container for the entire grow cycle um
most of the time I I like to go straight
from germinated seed straight into the
forever home then I don't have to worry
about disturbing any of the roots or
anything like that I've done the Solo
cup thing and and like I have the bud
cups as well I haven't used them yet but
Solo cups I've done that but I I really
like to just go straight into the
forever home so I'll go into like a like
either a three or a 5 gallon pot okay
all right so you're actually uh growing
entirely organic in three and five
gallon pots yes so it is possible ladies
and gentlemen there are so many people
out there who are like a it's going to
be big containers bigger container the
better and uh it's often said that you
can't be successful in 3 to 5 gallons
growing organically but you're doing it
and I know there are some other people
doing it a while Mr conu he is one of
the ones that do it and I believe three
gallon containers he's doing it and so
it is possible whether or not it's more
challenging I think that's a debatable
thing but you could certainly get to
harvest in smaller type containers when
you're growing organically cool so
that's what you start off for a soil mix
you've got de Pro mix Gia green 444
alala kelp oyster shell epom salt you
got some de in there eventually the
nutrients are going to deplete from The
Medium right so at what point are you
adding in more of those amendments it's
usually right in the 2 to 3 week Mark
when I first started doing it I kind of
followed the directions and I went every
four weeks but that that was a little
bit too late not knowing at the time
that things take a little bit of time to
break down it's not readily available as
soon as you put it in the soil so I you
know you have to kind of give it that
buffer time to break down a little bit
so if you can just stay a little bit
ahead of the game then really I mean you
don't run into a whole lot of problems
for deficiency wise so every couple
weeks two to 3 weeks is it the same
amendments that you mentioned before
that you're adding in more
444 alala meal Kel meal oyer shell up
some same exact thing yeah for the most
part I do I do add a little bit in
between sometimes like I I use hyra as
well so I'll um I use their whole lineup
so I'll add in their enzyme formula
um I add in their uh hyren which is a
microbial
blend um also the the high Shield which
is more of a defense kind
of um it gives the plants it gets their
defense mechanism going and makes them
think that they're being attacked which
kind of makes them A Little Bit Stronger
more resilient I guess so there there is
a few things and and I do I do add teas
as time goes on as well in between and
kind of buys me a little bit of time in
between top dressings and stuff so are
you switching from the 444 to the 484
for Bloom at all or you just sticking
with the 444 guag green throughout the
entire grow cycle when I go into so when
I get to flip when I'm about to flip I
try to kind of schedule everything so
that I can do a top dress about a week
before I flip and I like to do like a
50/50 blend of the 444 and the 284
and then once my next top dress comes
around once I'm in full flow then it'll
all eliminate the 444 alog together and
it's the the power bloom after that but
basically again almost the same
nutrients all the way through switching
out the 444 and the 284 and so you're
doing a top dressing before flipping and
then about 3 weeks into flow and then at
what the six week Mark in flour and then
after that you're harvesting depending
on how long that genetics are due to
flower for exactly y as simple as I
possibly can
really it's funny that we talked about
Mr kanuck cuz I really honestly when I
first started I I based almost every
move I made in the garden off of what he
was doing because it was so simple
because it worked and he proved it time
and time again so yeah he's been growing
that way for so many years and uh very
successful you know he look plants has
some beautiful plants being healthy
throughout the whole grow cycle so yeah
that method uh has been very very
popular and I feel like he kind of put
Gia green on the map a little bit you
know what I mean I would have to agree I
would agree not many people knew about
guia green until he came around at least
the the YouTube Community became very
familiar with with guy green after he
came around so yeah so how about any
like sugars or microbial inoculant you
kind of talked about how you inoculate
with microbes but what about like sugars
any molasses or anything like that that
you use or no yeah I do I use molasses
in um when I make my my teas I'll add
masses I don't I don't normally add
molasses just in between like I always
do it when I make my tea walk us through
your tea brewing process cuz that can
vary a little bit as well some people
just use compost some people use worm
casting some people do nutrient tea Tu
us what's in your te Brew how long you
brewing and so on and so forth so in veg
I will I do do a couple different teas
actually I do uh a veg tea and I do a
flour tea so for veg I'll add my worm
casting I put it in like a little bag
like a tea bag I guess and I put I just
put it in like a 5 gallon bucket so I'll
put my my worm castings in there I add
Alaska fish fertilizer which is I think
it's a 511 mix so it's it's readily
available
nitrogen um I'll add that in there I add
a little bit of hydrozyme the enzyme
formula and I also add in Hydro Ben and
I sprinkle in a little bit of like
dinico type of stuff or great white
depending on what I have at the time and
I I let it Brew for 24 to 48
hours depends on how long it takes to
kind of hit that froth when it just
starts to kind of go off you kind of
know when it's ready it'll just start to
it's like when you shake a can of pop it
just comes right over the top of the
bucket so 2448 hour brew and then are
you taking that solution and diluting it
down in water before giving your plants
or you just taking that full
concentration and Watering your plants
with it I just do the full concentration
I've never had a problem yet I've heard
of people that do that dilute it they
cut it in half or you know they'll
they'll add 25% more water whatever it
is that they do but personally I've
always just given it the concentrated
mix and I missed it are you Brewing it
in like a a small five gallon bucket or
you in like a larger bucket or what it's
actually like an eight I think it's an 8
gallon bucket it's like a like a wine
making bucket and uh I put about 5
gallons in there just to kind of give it
that room so I don't boil over it's a
little bit cleaner for me and are you
doing that like on a weekly basis or
bi-weekly basis or how often usually
about every 2 weeks but for sure when I
do my top dressing I like to I like to
work it out so that I can do my tea at
the same time as I do my top dress so
I'll top dress first and then I'll I'll
water in my tea and in in my head maybe
it's right maybe it's wrong but in in my
head it helps break everything down
maybe a little bit faster I'm you know
rejuvenating the the microbes that are
already in the soil plus adding more
microbes adding a little bit of sugar
and I to me it just it helps break
everything down just a little bit
quicker plus it's it's readily available
nutrients for your plants right now so
awesome now how about earthworms are you
using those in your garden at all or or
no I was I was I had a little worm a
worm bin going and I was doing it
indoors and it just got to be too much
for the space that I have and and I
ended up letting them letting them all
go out in the garden but uh so long
story short I guess I don't I don't use
Earth worms now but I do use worm
casting so I'm still getting the benefit
from them but I'm not using the actual
worms thes nice nice yeah worms can be
so beneficial in the garden I've been
using them red wigglers European
nightcrawlers African nightcrawlers or
there several different types that you
can use and I'm actually wearing the
shirt Uncle Jim Uncle Jim's worm farm so
that's where I end up uh additionally
buying the worms and once you buy them
once the population will multiply really
in the containers as well as I have a
worm bin I'm doing vermac composting and
taking what I get from there and put
into the containers and it's uh it's a
fun cycle you know to to see all that
happening and definitely worms is one of
those things where it's not a
requirement when you're growing
organically but it can certainly help
it's very beneficial for sure absolutely
well I mean it does so much like the the
worm castings do so much plus with the
worms being in there I think it kind of
like helps air raid the soil oil and it
just helps keep everything nice and
loose and Airy I guess so yeah they do
they do a lot and plus having a worm bin
like having having a a home for your
worms is it's pretty cool to watch the
process happen free worms for life as
long as you keep that bin going right
for real like it happens so fast so fast
I remember when I first got into it I um
they so being in Canada I went with a
Canadian company and it was winter so he
said I can't ship the worms to you right
now but I can do the cocoons and I said
oh yeah sure so we got some cocoons and
and it was um once I did the re I got
the cocoons first and I asked I can't it
was a ridiculous number way more than I
probably ever needed but uh I asked for
it and he sent them and once I did the
research I think it was like 3 to six
worms or something per per cocoon and
and I think I had like 3 or 400 cocoons
and I I'm looking at this going oh my
God what did I just do but um it wasn't
happening fast enough for me like I
didn't must my temperatures must have
been off or something like that like
there's a specifics that you got to kind
of follow and so I ordered a pound of
worms so then the worms came and then
next thing you know I had like a million
worms in this bin and I didn't know what
to do and so yeah it it happens really
quickly when it does that's funny yeah
you mentioned uh it's slowing down if
you don't have the the right temperature
it it will slow down like wintertime for
example my worm bin is the breakdown
happens a lot slower than in the
summertime when it's warm right so I
actually had some pests as well in my
worm bin and sometimes we get pests
within the grow space as well and that's
kind of what I want to get into next is
talking about pests what do you do to
prevent pests in your garden well the
number one pest I think
that any organic grower will have is
100%
gats um so right off the bat I tell
everybody be preventative right from day
one even if you've never seen one just
be preventative yellow sticky traps um
you can make your own traps out of um
apple cider vinegar with a piece of
plastic over top a couple holes poked in
it um I'll do that every now and then I
like to hang sticky traps at different
levels I like to put them right on the
soil and I like to hang them so that
they're different heights in the tent um
D Tous Earth sprinkle that onto the soil
um I use I've gone through a whole
different array of um sprays like I've
done the the crop Defender from Petra
tools um Lost
Coast um I'm trying one right now from
hyra they're new their new um Hydro
punch so I'm going to be trying that one
now and that's that's an all natural
different essential oils cinnamon is one
of the things that's in there which is
another thing you can you can use for
Pest and stuff like that um yeah so I
mean like I I I just kind of try to stay
on top of it right from basically the
day that pot goes into that tent I like
to just be ready for anything that can
come my way and if I do run into knats
or something like that I mean you i'
I've removed the top layer of soil
before put new soil in there um there's
a few other things that I've heard you
can do that I've never actually had to
get to like putting sand on the top
layer of your pots so that then they
can't get in and out of the
soil um yeah all kinds of fun stuff and
I'm sure I'm I'm missing some I'm sure
some of the ones that I do practice now
I'm sure I'm missing some of them but
well there are so many different
solutions to gats one of the ones that I
use that have has been successful is
Mammoth can control so it's an all
natural product that has worked really
really well for me also the amazing Dr
zes another product that I used I've
heard I haven't used that one that one I
don't think has been available in Canada
for too too long I know I know it is now
so I think it's been here maybe for
about a year but I mean I I've kind of
already been fully stocked up on
everything else in the meantime so I
never really got a chance to try it but
mosquito dunks was another one that I
like I use mosquito dunks also mosquito
bits two different products there but
they're both BT type of bacteria that
helps within the medium there yeah
there's so many different ways to go
about it I have battled with fungus gats
for many many years I mean jez seems
like whenever I get like a new bag of
soil is kind of when they come back in
there so they'll come in with a lot of
bagged soils unfortunately soils worm
casting stuff like that anything yeah
anything organic I I feel
I feel like fungus Dan is one of the
easier pests to battle has there been
any other pest infestations that you
needed to battle besides fungus knats
unfortunately yes um my first my first
go at battling something other than Nats
was spidermites
and I'm no longer in that house that
that happened at a previous place that I
lived but um somebody had given
me a drawing rack with a bunch of stuff
in there and it was from outside and I
never I never even thought about it it
came in it was in a garbage bag I put it
down in my grow room kind of forgot
about it and then one day I just started
seeing webs looking around like what is
happening but everything was in flour at
this time so there wasn't a lot I could
do with spraying so I mean I would go in
there I would clean off everything that
I possibly could at the
time and I just tried to finish I just
tried to get to the end of then when I
got to the end I did a wash chopped
everything down and washed everything so
that was sad to see but I was so against
washing at the time too and then I felt
like I had no other option it was that
or throw it in the garbage so I figured
I'm going to try it and see what happens
and and that's what I did but I was able
to get everything cut down after that
and then I was able to do a full
reset disinfect everything go through
that whole room top to bottom with a
fine tooth comb and just sterilize
everything I
could so and thrips battle thrips as
well and that's since I've been in this
address I work
outside and uh coming home sometimes you
know you're excited to get in the grow
room and and when people say change your
clothes have a shower do all this stuff
like it it's true you really you really
got to watch what you're doing
especially when you're outside digging
and you're in gardens and you're in you
know grass and stuff like that you bring
this stuff in with you and you don't
even know it's on your clothes and
whatever so thrips is one that I battled
last year and uh Unfortunately they beat
me I went through I think every possible
measure that I could find and and it
just it didn't work for me I ended up
cutting everything down and shutting
down for about a month and then I went
through with bleach and a steamer and Li
all and everything that you can think of
and just cleaned and scrubbed and
steamed and scrubbed and steamed and
more steaming
and till I was comfortable and and I
haven't had an issue since so yeah
that's a tough battle and I'm I'm glad
you were able to salvage at least the
spiderm one that you had I'll never
forget I had somebody post on my Forum
years ago now and they posted a think it
was a short video and they asking the
question is my plan ready for Harvest
and this beautiful plant amazing looking
nug well top Cola really is what I'm
referring to and like puring and it was
ready for Harvest but there was this
massive web on it and then spiderm it's
all around it and I'm just like uh so
sad to see you know you have a Spiderman
infestation I felt sad because you go
all the way up until Harvest and then
like all of a sudden you're just loaded
with spider mites I've always felt
that's when the problem happens though
it's it's never when you can get in
there and spray at least for me anyways
it was never when I could get in there
and spray things on the plants it was
always like the last few weeks and it
was like that's that's when you don't
want to be spraying anything on there
you know it's so painful yeah I've been
fortunate enough not to battle
spidermites at all so hopefully I mean
yeah just got to keep it clean you know
I hope you never have to yeah that and
THS is another thing as you mentioned
it's as far far as which one's harder to
battle I mean I'll leave it up to the
folks that have the experience battl on
them I've heard that they're pretty much
equally difficult to battle I had russed
mites is like one of the hardest things
to battle uh you luck that's another
thing I haven't come across but like I
haven't had that one yet yeah there are
so many different pasts that you got to
worry about and indoors is one thing
Outdoors is another thing Outdoors is a
totally that's a whole another battle
right there just Outdoors alone past are
no pass it's that's yeah it's something
else for sure but focusing on indoors
let's switch it up a little bit I want
to talk about lighting what are you
using for lighting indoors so I have a
couple different lights actually they're
both basically the same light um so
right now the setup that I have I have
two two 3x3
T um and in one tent I have the mar
Hydro fce 3000 I think and then in the
other 10 is it's the SF SF no
se3000 it's the equivalent it's the the
bar style lights On's Mars Hydro One
spider farmer so pretty well the same
light but yeah it's the the 3000s which
I think is like a 300 wat light okay
yeah I'm familiar with both of those
models now are you aiming for a certain
par during the different stages of
growth or are you just kind of going by
what the manufacturer suggests in their
listing description mainly just going by
what the manufacturer suggests like I I
haven't really got into the whole par
and VPD and all that yet that's I think
that's probably in one of my next
Ventures I'll start kind of testing that
and looking more into into the lighting
and stuff like that and I'll probably
find out that you know my lighting isn't
quite adequate but I mean I I've never
actually had those lights turned up 100%
in those tents so light CJs are so
powerful a lot of people aren't running
them at 100% you know what I mean I'm
I'm getting away with 50 60% in early
flower you know so it's like I don't
think I'm going to be dialing mine up to
100% usually I'm running at 70 or 80% so
heat is an issue with with some of those
lights too I I feel like the the higher
you go the hotter I mean of course it
does the the hotter everything gets
right so I feel like that that can be an
issue too unless you kind of have
everything 100% dialed in which I mine's
up and down a little bit um yeah I I
just I'm usually like I'm no more than
80% but usually between like 60
70% at the end of flower so you know the
higher those lights go the the more heat
that it's emitting and it can certainly
be a challenge for your environment you
know for your plants if the temperature
gets too high I want to ask you next
what environment conditions do you aim
for with temperature humidity CO2 talk
to us about that um so I don't I don't
use CO2 I haven't I haven't gone down
that road yet
um but so being in canidate again I'm
going to use uh I'm going to use Celsius
here um I keep it usually like on the
hottest it's like 25
26 and in veg I like to keep my
humidity like somewhere up around like
60 70% but as I come down into flour I
like to drop it down to about 50%
humidity maybe even a little bit less
the farther I get into flour um which I
mean I find it harder the farther you
get into flower the higher the humidity
wants to go so I mean I'm battling with
that as well but um yeah I like to I
like to keep it pretty steady through
the whole grow like 24
25 and uh I don't like to get any
higher than like 26 27 that's when we're
kind of it's getting pretty warm in
there so and doing the conversion right
now looks like uh Fahrenheit that would
be 7 5 to 79 so I just figure i' do
that conversion here for those folks
that do Fahrenheit instead of Celsius
okay so pretty straightforward there
when it comes to temperature and
humidity let's get back into kind of the
organic style of growing a couple other
things that you can do cover crops what
do you do when it comes to cover crops
are you doing anything at all or no um
so I I I don't do it all the time
it's I like doing it I prefer to do it
it looks awesome in your tents um but I
have a lot of times what I do for my
cover crop is I'll add um crimson
clover uh y I think it's yellow Sweet
Clover there was uh red
clover and alala I think was the other
one that I had so I'll just kind of
sprinkle some of that in there and I'll
let it do its thing and um once it
starts
getting pretty high I'll just kind of
the chop and drop cut it down and just
let it kind of be on top and they'll
just kind of keep growing up through
there and I'll just re amend everything
through that and just kind of like
Shuffle it in with my fingers but yeah I
just kind of like chop and drop and just
let everything go back into the soil
again nice and right along with that is
companion planting now I know some of
those cover crops are considered
companion plants but is there any other
plants that you haven't named off that
are companion plants that you grow um
not not indoors really like I don't
think I've ever done any companion
plants indoors but outdoors I like to
put maragold in with my plants a they
look nice and B they're another another
kind of like Pest
Management so they keep some of the
animals away but they also keep some of
the pests away as well and again they're
they're one that you know they just
basically reced themselves and just keep
growing and growing and growing I'm a
huge fan of mar Golds yeah I've got them
growing Outdoors as well I really like
the way they look and uh it's cool that
they repel pests help prevent those
pests from invading grow space so that's
some nice color into the garden it's
nice and nice night down nice and low it
gives you something to look at up here
and it gives you something to look at
down here and yeah attracts pollinators
too if you're growing any type of fruits
or vegetables that require pollination
well you know growing some flowers in
the area can certainly help attract
pollinators so yeah beneficial in
several different ways how about mul
layers some people use that mulch layers
for mostly for water retention right do
you use any sort of mulch layer uh rice
hols I like to cover my top layer with
rice hols so I'll just put like a a thin
layer in there and as I water everything
it just kind of just kind of wash as it
down and then as I as my plants are
finished when I'm I like I I do reuse my
soil um so I'll I'll break dump
everything into a bin and kind of remix
everything up again but you'll you'll
find some of these rice hols made their
their way down quite quite a ways so I
think it helps it's kind of like a
perite at that point almost it kind of
helps air rate make it more more fluffy
and plus they're organic and they break
down and I'm sure there's some benefit
to to the rice hols in the soil as well
think silica I think was one of them
yeah silica is a huge benefit to the
plant non-essential element that has a
ton of different benefits so yeah rice
hols is is a big one there that's
awesome let's get into watering what do
you use for a water source and how do
you go about watering your plants so I
do use top water I used to use rainwater
but where I am now I just I don't have
the space to be able to do that um
so City Water super chlorinated so I do
have to let it kind of bubble for at
least 24 hours so I'll fill up a big
brute garbage pail with monster air
stones in there and I think there's six
of them on a big manifold with a pump
and everything so let it bubble for at
least 24 hours before I do my first
watering out of there but I'll get i'll
get a few waterings out of that brute
container so it's like a I want to say
it's like a like a 36 gallon Reservoir
or something like that so it's not huge
but it's it's a good size and I'll throw
my mosquito dunks into that water as
well let them just kind of be in there
and bubble with the with the airstones
and um yeah then I just go from there
and I just started actually um bottom
feeding I got the AC Infinity soft
watering trays so I've gone through
about half a grow with with those and
honestly the the whole bottom feeding
method is really starting to surprise me
I do like bottom watering had some
struggles though with Organics in
particular like doing the top dressing
and then bottom watering and then not
having it really Wick all the way up to
the top and and keep that top layer
moist where the amendments were but
having a mul layer or some sort of uh
cover crop will help with the retention
of the water up the top there so exactly
so and and every now and then too like
when I when I would do a top dressing I
would want I would want to do a top
watering at least for the first time or
two just to kind of get it in there and
help kind of drive it down through the
pot and let it start breaking down so I
I do I will add a top watering in the
mix here and there but I haven't
actually done them with Organic yet so
I'm finishing up I just finished up with
a synthetic run so I've been bottom
feeding with that so I'm about to get
back into an organic run with the bottom
feeding so it'll be a first where I do a
full organic run with bottom feeding so
I'm excited for that little fun
challenge ahead of you mhm yeah I think
it'll be it'll be one more thing to just
kind of dial in and kind of figure out
as I go but I think it'll be okay right
so before you did the self-watering
you were doing hand watering I assume
how were you going about determining
whether or not the plant needed water I
would do I would go in and kind of like
feel the soil if the soil was wet I mean
then I know I don't I don't really need
to but I would also do the the lift pick
the pot up see how heavy it is if I if I
you know I go to pick it up and I lift
it right up off the ground then
definitely you know I've let it go too
long but I never with Organics I never
really let it try to get dry I never
really go for the dry back when I'm
running Organics so I always try to keep
them a little bit on the heavy side so I
just I just try to never really let them
dry okay and now with Organics do you
monitor the pH or the EC or PPM anything
like that or are you pretty much hands
off when it comes to all that I catch a
lot of flak for this but I I do I do pH
all my water and a lot of people always
you know again whether it's right wrong
doesn't matter I I just got into the
habit of phing everything from day one
and I've always pH even when I had
rainwater I still phed it cuz it would
sit out there and it would you know it'
be in the sun temperature changes the pH
hotter colder pH goes up and down so
yeah I do I do pH and I like to keep it
between like 6 and 6.5 is kind of my
range so if I hit anywhere in there I'm
good I'm happy with that okay so you're
monitoring the pH of the water before
actually putting it into your soil are
you monitoring the pH of the soil at all
like whether it be a slurry test or a
runoff test anything like that or or no
not typically okay if I if I run into
problems with anything like if if I
start noticing like there's something
going on with my plants and I and I
don't know what it is my very first
go-to and I tell everybody this before
you dive too deep into anything don't
just start trying a million things do
yourself a favor and check your runoff
before you do anything that's that's
always my first go-to so sometimes I I
do monitor that but it's not it's not
something I do all the time it's only if
I run into run into something understood
and then how about EC or PPM to get an
idea of how much nutrition is in the
medium no I never honestly I I had I had
an EC pen or whatever monitor whatever
you want to call it I had one when I
first started growing cuz I went out and
bought everything that YouTube told me
to
and uh I never really used it never
really used it like I've always been
kind of the same style of growing almost
since I started so I've just never
really never really needed it and I
found when or ganics a lot of people
aren't doing it it can be a little bit
deceiving because those amendments that
you first top dress in well they're not
going to show up on the meter they're
only going to show up once they they're
broken down in a bioavailable form
exactly if I was doing Hydro or
something I'd definitely would be
checking that but I'm not so I mean I I
steer away from that it's kind of one of
my my methods of keeping it simple I
guess kiss method keep it simple yeah ex
exactly why I mean I I over complicate
everything in life to begin with so I
mean if I can keep the garden somewhat
simple I mean that's kind of the happy
place right so got it now you mentioned
earlier in the episode that you recycle
your soil can you walk us through your
process how do you go about recycling
your soil soil so basically I'll just
dump once I'm done to run I'll cut
everything I'll cut it cut the plant
down I'll have little stock like this
left over or whatever and I'll go out
and I'll dump it into a big Rubbermaid
bin and a lot of people like to let
their their soil cook and they'll re
amend it right away and let it cook and
whatever but I I don't really do that I
just when I'm ready to go then I'll take
that soil and then I'll refill up my
pots and I'll re amend everything
sometimes I'll add a little bit a
biochar in there um what was the other
thing gypsum sometimes I'll add a little
bit of gypsum in there just to kind of
help break everything down and kind of
kickart everything again but other than
that I mean I just treat it like I'm
starting off with new soil again I get
to the end of a run my plants have used
up basically everything that's in there
and then I'll just I'll fill my pots up
and re amend as I go so basically rinse
rinse and repeat almost are you letting
those new contain cers with soil sit for
a period of time before planting into
them like they call it a lot of people
call it cooking you're cooking the soil
letting it cook for a while letting
those amendments break down before
anything is planted into it are you
doing that or you going straight into it
with a new seed um I'll go straight into
it basically with a new seed and
um like like I was saying like almost
everything's broken down and and used up
by the time I tear everything down so um
that'll re amend the soil as I'm putting
it back into the pot again and then it
needs that like week or two to kind of
break back down again so when I put the
seed into the soil it'll give that week
or two to kind of break everything down
so by the time my plant is couple nodes
tall and needs nutrients again then the
nutrients will be almost ready almost
right on time so that's pretty much what
I'm doing as well you know when I plant
into I have uh five containers that I've
been reusing for six runs now I'm on my
sixth run with the same soil and uh I
feel like there is some nutrition left
over from the previous grow so that
allows me to plant directly into it
after amending not waiting for a period
of weeks like uh some people do but
other people they safe side they'll let
it wait for a couple weeks let it break
down there's really no harm in that so
yeah either way to go about it I find
too with like amendments organic
amendments um your plant really is only
going to uptake what it needs like for
the most part like you're really not
going to kill your plants because you
amended the soil a little bit too soon
you know if you're doing something
that's super super high in nitrogen or
something that's readily available right
this second you know maybe but adding
like the 444 and kind of doing it the
way that I do it with the guy green
amendments I I've never never run into
an issue where where it was too much
food for them at the start so that's
awesome one of the things I like to ask
folks towards the end of the episode is
try to get some advice for beginners so
we have a lot of beginners that listen
in here what advice do you have for them
for those folks that are just getting
started growing organically be careful
where you get your information from CU
there's a lot of it and there's a
million different ways to grow organic
there's a million different ways to grow
period but there's so many ways to grow
organically and you can take the simple
method or you can go the very very
difficult method so my my advice would
be find somebody that's doesn't have to
be Mr Canuck but that's who I chose at
the time pick one person and stick with
their style and learn that way and don't
over complicate everything by by trying
to follow five different people at the
same time just pick one person study
what they're doing learn what they're
doing and just kind of follow the steps
because there's people out there that
have laid everything out maybe go buy
yourself a Mr growup book and uh and go
from there because you learn a lot yeah
there are so many different ways to go
about it like we said a couple times in
this episode now and I remember before I
started growing organically I was very
intimidated because of the new method
and how there are so many different
amendments out there MH and me really
just not knowing
what ones to use yeah and so yeah kind
of narrowing it down there are so many
different ways to go about it so many
different amendments you can use in
combinations I'm not a soil scientist so
I usually just go with the Blends
there's a lot of organic Blends that
have a whole bunch of things mixed into
it and you just apply this blend in veg
and this blend in flow for example or
there's some Blends that are kind of an
all-in-one that you can just apply
throughout the whole growth cycle so
that's in my opinion the easiest way to
get into Organics for sure yeah we got
mention that one for any beginners out
there not to get intimidated by all the
variety of amendments that are out there
they can be overwhelming because there
are so many inputs a lot of people want
to know can you grow with just an
allpurpose 444 and a 284 of course you
can to me it's like a multivitamin
everything's in it already and you can
you definitely can do it because there's
people that do it and they prove it time
and time again like we talked about Mr
kanuck um
but then you know then you're adding
your supplements you know for us people
when we take a multivitamin there's some
other things that we might need a little
bit more so then you can dive a little
deeper into it and learn a little bit
more like oh I want to give it some
alala meal or I want to give it some
kelp meal and then you kind of start
learning what each thing does and then
you can you can get as complicated as
you want or you can stay as simple as
you want and I guess my advice would be
to to start off as simple as you you can
and just learn it I think that's some
really good advice for sure all right
let's wrap things up can you tell
listeners how they could find you and
what you have upcoming in the future um
so you can find me on Instagram under Mr
ganx mr. Gan homeg grow the community
official on Instagram that's our we do
podcast that's our our podcast Instagram
channel uh then there's C bunny grow
who's also on the podcast and Mama Kush
420 who's also on the podcast and then
on YouTube you can find us at homow the
community and that's where we do our
weekly podcasts which is Wednesday
nights and Friday nights and then you
can find us under hgtc podcast on
Spotify as well awesome well I'll
definitely have link to Mr ganx Channel
down in the YouTube description section
below so you can easily navigate to it
and give him a follow Mr ganx thank you
so much for coming on to the podcast
today this been awesome to hear your
style of organic gardening and there
definitely some takeaways here and
appreciate your time hope you enjoy the
rest of your day thank you for having me
man this was great a lot of fun big
shout out to all the folks that follow
on patreon we've got uh just a ton of
people that keep this podcast going so
I'm going to scroll it on the screen
right now these supporters thank you so
much for your contributions there you're
keeping the studi lights on here so
we're going to keep this podcast going
thanks so much all right everybody we
will leave it at that we will catch you
in the next episode peace out everyone