welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr grew it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 108. in this
episode I interview Adam Dunn he has
been gardening for 30 years and is the
host of the Adam Dunn show which I'm
sure a large handful of you are familiar
with he is experienced growing with
several types of hydroponic systems and
also has experience with organic
gardening and that's what we talk about
in today's episode organic versus
Hydroponics if you want to see
highlights of these podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube that
is a channel dedicated to short clips of
these podcast episodes I want to
acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring free gardening
information of all plants to the general
public that being said I like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
they now have supplemental lighting
called the ion beam I have the ion beam
S11 grow light bars which are 11 inches
long and use Samsung lm301 H diodes but
they also have the ion beam s16 which
are 16 inches long and use the same
diodes it comes with a light controller
with four light intensity levels and
timer settings I'll have a link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their supplemental
lighting and the discount code Mr growed
15 works on both Amazon and their
website AC infinity.com
and we're back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I'm joined with Adam
Dunn how you doing today I'm doing good
how about yourself doing pretty good
thanks for asking so you've been
requested by a large handful of my
viewers a lot of people familiar with
your show which I'm sure you'll talk
about in your introduction here but
before the introduction let's reveal the
topic organic gardening versus
Hydroponics so you've done both methods
and I'm really interested to hear how
you've grown those ways tips tricks
stuff like that but first can you
introduce yourself tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening sure my name is Adam Dunn and
I've been into gardening now for 30 plus
years it looks like it's it's crazy how
time flies right
um I when I was growing up my dad my dad
my grandfather was a head groundskeeper
at La golf course so we had the greenest
lawn in the in the block you know it's
like you come down our street it was all
crabgrass everywhere except for our
house perfectly Green Grass and uh but
he had a really always had a good garden
and kind of you know Greek Greek
Heritage you know so they tend to love
to have their little Victory Gardens
still so that was back in New England
which is an amazing place for growing
anything really has a you know it's
different right we're out here in
Colorado now it's dry and there's very
like quite limiting on certain things
you can do and I go back to east coast
and see my friends growing pumpkins and
things and just like wow the corn you
know just all the different like just
the quality of the of the vegetables and
things coming out of there is amazing so
that's a big difference I was born and
raised in Massachusetts and now I live
in same thing in Las Vegas a massive
difference exactly the same Vibe
differently exactly because it's just
like you know the lack of humidity makes
a huge difference that's one thing
you're just like here in Colorado we are
constantly battling that you know
there's never enough water yeah it's
very dry out there similar to how it is
where I live so what about your show how
did that all come about
um you know like like a lot of things
evolution of uh of uh
you know I I came to Colorado in 2010
from I lived in Amsterdam for 21 years
and so I came here in 2010 and uh
you know that I was on a lot of other
people's shows I was on the John Doe
radio show which is uh was like a local
uh show here in Colorado and it was
really
instrumental I think because it really
like his show was like a beacon that
brought people to Colorado because they
were like I can't believe this is
happening you know what I mean so they
all came out to see the changes
happening in Colorado and I rolled into
town and I was like yeah I'll come on
your podcast and hung out with them a
bit and I realized I really like quite
liked the I like the format I got a lot
to say I got a lot of stories you know
what I mean after living there for so
long and really felt like it was a good
good medium to work with and now it's
been 10 years it's crazy it goes so
again like time flies right so all of a
sudden it's 10 years later and we're
still rocking and rolling and it's great
it's a great um I think as you know
podcasting right now is is like the last
sort of free creative place to be you
know like as long as you're not you know
working for somebody else if you're
doing your own thing you can create your
own lane which is
rare in this world you know what I mean
there's very few things that you can
actually do that with so I feel like
podcasting is a great way to get to
people and connect on a real level
and uh yeah I love the I love the no
rules part that's my favorite that's
awesome and for those tuning in uh
particularly on YouTube I'll definitely
have a link to Adam's Channel down in
the YouTube description section below
and if you're tuning in on one of the
podcast platforms just search from the
Adam dunsha it'll pop right up on on
YouTube you're on podcast platforms as
well or what oh yeah yeah I think we're
on like nine different platforms now we
go through restream so they go on on all
of them you know and uh it's been it's
actually the numbers have been going
crazy too it's like I've been you know I
I really don't pay attention to those
things and I'm not really like beholden
to numbers and trying to get higher you
know viewership and stuff but what we
have noticed is you know just
organically it's grown over time and now
we're hitting like you know 150 000 a
month or something like that on average
which is you know really good because if
you could just imagine 150 000 people in
one place it's it's quite a good crowd
you know what I mean you start getting
those crowds together you're like all
right we're getting somewhere yeah
congrats on all your success that's not
easy to do at all so that's a huge
accomplishment there yeah I think the
key the key to the whole thing if
anybody out there is listening and they
want to start a podcast number one thing
is be consistent right don't don't think
you can do one and then wow maybe a few
months later I'll do another one nobody
no nobody they want to see you on you
know like we literally we missed a
couple here and there but it's always
been just you know major circumstances
but for the most part it's always like
you feel it in your heart like I gotta I
gotta do this man I gotta be there and
they're waiting on me you know what I
mean so it's a good feeling I can vouch
for that as well consistency is
definitely key when it comes to that oh
100 worst thing is when somebody says oh
is that podcast still on you're like
what every week yeah so you want to make
sure people know yeah
so let's get into our topic today I want
to start with Hydroponics I'd like to
know to begin what hydroponic systems
are you familiar with and what ones have
you used in the past
so when I was living in Holland actually
so when I moved there in 89 it was like
you know that is like the
that is like the the crown jewel of
Hydroponics right I mean as far as it's
either it's either I'm Getty in in
Israel or it's alsmere and Holland those
are like the two
critical spots right Al smears where all
the greenhouses are outside of uh
outside of Amsterdam and you know when
you fly in right that's the thing as a
as a grower when you fly into Amsterdam
is almost like nowadays flying into
Colorado right you come in at night and
you see all the lights and you're like
that's a grow that's a grow that's a
grow that's a great now you can spot
them out and in Holland right the
airport is right where the greenhouses
are so when you land it's like you're
coming into like there it is you know so
it really gets you going so when I got
there I really wanted to learn
everything I could about Hydroponics I
really was super focused on it I was
into aeroponics at the time I was I
became the uh after a while I became the
distributor for General Hydroponics in
the Netherlands which you know now if I
look back I'm like
oh my God I like I literally had the I
had them by the balls you know what I
mean so I was like I was really like oh
I have the best food in the world
because really General Hydro
definitely changed the game for indoor
Growers on hydroponics because it really
gave you an ability to adjust your
formulas a little bit even if it was
just minor adjustments like
two one one or two two one or you know
if you you just it was quite simple you
had your grow your flower your micro and
you could bounce in back and forth
between those
but in Holland it was like you know
they're growing on acres and acres and
Acres of greenhouse like massive scale
flowers vegetables everything you know
everything under the sun
but they're also doing it from a you
know a Dutch pragmatic and I can you
know the economy of scale type situation
so when you start talking Acres of
anything
every penny counts right so so for them
Hydroponics is based on economy and it's
based on ability to push things through
the system fast because they have you
know the largest flower distribution
centers in Holland right and it's like
they the airport had they have their own
area at the airport where they do their
auctions and they bring all the flowers
in and bring it all in ship them all
over the world so you can imagine that's
like a well well oiled machine right
it's like they have they can grow a
plant and have it in a store in 48 hours
from the time it gets cut you know what
I mean it's anywhere in the world which
is amazing so so I went there like like
it was church you know I was just like
oh my God I'm going out to I'd go out to
Ellesmere and I go to these Greenhouse
Supply Centers and walk around and had
no idea what I was looking at I was just
just overwhelmed you know but I
um started working for Scentsy seeds I'm
in 93
and so that kind of got me uh got me
more on the smaller like got me more
realistic size systems because the thing
is when I went to Ellesmere I just was
like where to start right you're talking
about these million dollar greenhouses
and it just was way over my head but
when I started working at Scentsy we
started with a very passive hydroponic
system it was like a
it was like probably the most
easy least
sort of active system that I've ever
worked with and it was a I used a
basically it was like a
cement cement mixing container you know
to Classic black ones and it they'd put
a water level meter in the bottom
this is the plastic water level meter uh
put an ion exchanger on the bottom and
that was the key to the whole thing was
this ion exchanger right so it's like
little polymer balls a little red
polymer balls and you sprinkle that down
at the bottom of the container
and you fill it up with Hydro corals
with your with your hydrostones there
and you know you set your you basically
would put your rock wool blocks on top
and top feed them until the roots made
it to the bottom of the container so
you'd be top feeding
very lightly you know just kind of
coaxing The Roots down and then once the
roots got to the bottom where the water
would be because you'd fill your water
level maybe you know a couple inches at
the bottom
and that was it and I was like that was
there considered a hydroponic system I
mean that is technically it's
Hydroponics but it's like so inactive
there was no nothing happening right so
I was always like sitting there watching
it going like
there's got to be more like I'm so used
to looking at these other systems
they've got injectors and they've got
all sorts of stuff so it felt like it
wasn't I wasn't involved enough you know
and so I ended up poking the hole in the
bottom of it right putting them drain in
there screwed everything up right out of
the gate because I let all the ion
exchanger out
which I didn't you know I didn't get the
whole system but that whole that just
those little polymers was the key to the
whole system because they took in extra
you know they took in any kind of uh
extra salts and things and kept it away
from the roots and and balanced the pH
where once I got rid of it I was like oh
so I quickly learned you know that it's
with Hydroponics it's a system and the
system is important but it's also
really based on you right so if you you
know forget to do one thing or
contaminate something and so I I learned
quite quickly that it was a there's a
lot of moving Parts not in that system
in particular because that's why I was
pissed off I was like I want any more
action so then the next thing I've built
went straight from that
to aerobonics because that's what I
always think in my mind Hydroponics
meant like complicated things with lots
of I needed I needed to make it which I
realized down the road that that was the
exact reason why
I stopped you know but in the beginning
it was I think it's because a lot of
people are you know we're very into the
into the tweaking you know like and and
I felt like with with this with my hydro
systems that I was building you know I
was really into the construction of it
so I went out and built my own aeroponic
system I looked online I wasn't even
online back there I looked in a book
imagine that a book and I was looking at
the systems and it was like oh those are
PVC pipes with little baskets in them I
can do that you know what I mean so then
I went to the back to The Supply Center
that I'd gone to in elsemere with all
these parts and stuff and I started to
just build them in the in the aisles you
know I'd stand in the aisle and like
okay if I take this sprayer and have to
figure out the gallons per minute and
you know try to figure out a calculate
something that would work and kind of
bought this whole all these little bits
and pieces and took them back to my
place and uh we
we built this system
and
um it was amazing like
we over built it because we had the we
had access to the best of the best when
it came to like
hydroponic equipment right so it was all
like you had to know what it was right
so I was frankensteining everything like
oh I'll take this piece and it connected
to this one so I had no idea what I was
doing but I made a system that worked
but I made it too good like it was way
over built classic classic like
you know later on when I realized how
much I in you know I had UV I had UV for
the water I had like I went full full
stop you know the water would be cleaned
by UV it would go back into the system
and the sprayers were
um the ones that would spin you know so
they would make a lot of noise
and I'm in an apartment in Amsterdam
right and in Amsterdam the apartments
are small
you have 16 amps of power
right 16 amps for the entire apartment
including your fridge including whatever
else you got so you start thinking about
how you're gonna
how are you gonna grow in a house with
16 amps you know what I mean it was
always like a real struggle so I built
this system had it all set up turned it
on
and within
five seconds I already knew I made a
mistake I was like
oh my God I think I over built this
thing right and it started
like 30 of those little sprayers were
going off inside these things
and instantly my neighbor just started
banging on my ceiling you know or his
ceiling on my floor right I'm like oh
now what I gotta do you know what I mean
so then I realized
this is never gonna work so I told the
guy oh my washing machine was off
balance you know I've made up some story
but then I realized like I can't even
use this system so I had to like
dismantle that thing
go to slabs you know and just go just go
real simple slabs with drippers which
again you know with Hydro you can you
can take it to whatever level you want
as far as complications and sometimes
it's you know advantageous there's I've
seen systems that are amazing plants
look great but I know in my heart that
when they harvest whoever's cleaning
this thing is going to go nuts you know
I mean because that's the problem with
with
hydroponics in general in my opinion is
that your clean factor is so important
you know you got to really keep
everything just
Uber clean you know what I mean
so yeah that was so that was sort of my
start and then I realized uh
you know I went and I did Coco and
because I felt like Coco was more closer
to to soil you know what I mean it had
more of a Vibe but then Coco has its own
own limitations also you know I feel
like with with
um
like I've seen a lot of like I'd say a
big percentage of people grow with cocoa
in the industry and you see and like
within you know else and I never say it
as a dis I'm always like oh is this
grown with cocoa and they're like
how did you know you know what I mean
and it's just like it's because it comes
out in a certain band like a certain
there's not it's hard to go above a
certain point
and luckily though the low points are
tend to be better than most you know
what I mean so like the average guy has
a cushion when he does cocoa you know
straight Hydro
like deep water culture is also my
favorite when it comes to like mother
plants and big plants and if you want to
grow like I mean I've seen the biggest
plants ever grown have been on dwc ever
like well you know besides outdoor
NorCal or something or you know Oregon
but indoors like strictly indoors I saw
a system one time guy sent me a photo
from Canada from back in the early 90s
and his setup was so simple
it blew my mind because you could tell
that this guy has run this over and over
and over and over and over and over and
over again he knows his parameters right
he would grow he had him on milk cartons
right so he had milk cartons stacked up
with a with a dwc bucket on top of each
one so it's raised up off the ground
because the plant was perfectly round
right and the bottom of it was you know
stick like so it would say it was let me
see where the cameras so if it was like
up on two or I was up on one milk carton
with a with a five gallon bucket and
then the the lowest buds were coming
right almost down to the ground and the
top ones were hitting almost the ceiling
and these things looked like an
explosion like it was like wow dude
amazing and he sent me these photos in
sync and it was like empty room
and then bedroom and then full flower
room and between the veg between the
empty room and the full flower room was
like you couldn't even imagine that
those could be sustained by that just
that simple five gallon bucket but it
was because he had a separate Reservoir
and another room
with like a you know 200 gallon that fed
with um Texas controllers style you know
the old you know Texas controller that
that it's just like the the one main
unit going to the other units so
so you could otherwise you would never
be able to do this because they would
suck up all the water in five minutes
you know what I mean because these
plants are just massive but the funny
part about it was he had all these
photos and then the last photo was like
this humongous cop standing next to it
like huge like six foot seven cops
standing next to the plant like with a
big smile like and I was like oh that's
so depressing like you know what I mean
like I saw the first two pictures I was
like wow this guy's doing great oh not
so great not so great at the end but uh
it was a classic Canadian setup too
because what he did is he had he had the
nine dwcs and I think he had 12 lights
total right so he had 12 000 Watts
classic you know Canadian style hanging
right no hoods so nine hanging uh bulbs
and then or no 12 hanging bulbs with
nine light with nine plants in between
so there was light on every side of
every plant and it was amazing like the
setup was bare bone super simple
massive you know what I mean and I think
dwc is like you know when you see roots
coming out of those things sometimes
you're just like
wow like it blows your mind because you
know that that's
if you stretched all those roots out
they would fill the room you know what I
mean because they're just compacted out
so you've done several different
hydroponic systems in the past I think a
lot of folks make the mistake of
thinking that Hydroponics is only dwc
you know what I mean but there's so many
other systems out there I mean one of
the ones that you didn't mention is uh
flood and drain have you done that in
the past I I not for flowering so much I
used to do that with my vegging plants a
lot of times so I had a flood and drain
table I'd put all my blocks on there and
then once the roots were popping through
I dropped them onto the slabs you know
or into the whatever system we were
doing so flood and drain is really good
for for that's for that type of thing
because
they're they're just going for it but I
felt like whenever I was did whenever I
saw people doing flood and drain for
flowering plants you tended to get like
unless they were all monocultured if
they were all the same strain okay then
it would be easier to maintain but if
you had a situation where you had
multiple things going on it's very hard
to like lock them in because you'd over
water one and underwater the other ones
you know what I mean because they get
into these they just have different
capillary sort of action and so you'd
end up with like like over like they're
fine and veg but in flour I always felt
like you you'd overdo it sometimes
because they they're they're in a
different mode when when you're young
you can just throw whatever you want at
them and they'll take it you know but I
I feel like uh
you know the idea of hydro is is a very
enticing especially to new Growers but
what I tended to tell people was like
you're gonna learn a lot more growing in
soil just because you're not so fixated
on
on fixing the system every time you know
I mean because you come in the room
you're like oh I got a leak over here so
you're not even looking at your plants
anymore you're looking at the leak you
know and you're working on that leak and
then you go to your plants whereas on
soil it's sort of like unless it's a
water situ I mean the only thing you
really have to do you come in you're
like oh my God they're all drooping I
gotta water them before I can do
anything but that's about it otherwise
you're not so you know worried about
little little things and so I think it's
a
smarter especially from the beginning
like if you're a new grower
start you're better off to work your way
towards Hydro instead of the other way
around like that's what I did I did the
wrong I did the exact wrong way I went
straight to the most complicated thing
possible and uh
probably been like that all the way
through you know I still do the same
thing try to sabotage myself yeah I was
going to ask you when you're you're
talking to a new grower and they want to
do Hydroponics I mean there are so many
different ways to grow in Hydroponics
right what do you typically recommend
for them to start out in what what style
um if you're really if you're dead set
on doing it I would say
um well actually I would go in more with
Coco just because it kind of keeps them
in that realm so that the transition
when they decide that they do not want
to grow things ready for they won't feel
so like out of their element you know
what I mean because and also uh I feel
like the formulas that people have now
for Coco
because they're they're dialed it in so
much better like in the beginning there
was a lot of issues because of the
enzymes and because you didn't have the
right so if you're if you didn't have a
buffer if the right buffers within your
food you'd have a nightmare you know
what I mean and that that's where that's
what turned me off of of Coco down the
road was because I felt like I was
pigeonholed into having to to work with
certain I have to do this I can't not do
this if I don't do this they're not
gonna you know they're not gonna Thrive
um whereas you felt like I had much more
range when you were just kind of working
on organic side but but I did I do think
that with um
if for instance like uh
um
a kind of a like a hybrid version of is
sometimes also good too where you have
um you know you're you're giving people
like Earth boxes things like that that
have that awicking system so that you're
you're kind of in the automated feeding
but you're not quite there you know and
I it is definitely
um
uh important that you figure out what's
comfortable for you though because like
nothing worse than putting all your eggs
you know going into it so deep and then
realizing at a certain point like oh man
we've kind of wasted a lot of how many I
mean how many times do you go to your
friend's place and look in there
uh in their garage and see like the
remnants of all the grow systems that
didn't make it you know what I mean it's
just like my I have a graveyard of
things at my spot right now yeah some of
these ways can be easier than others
like you know talking about beginner
mistakes real quick uh you know I've
seen dwc systems where people try to be
sort of hands off with it and they go
ahead and all of a sudden their EC is is
skyrockets they feed a hot too High VC
and their punts are dead overnight you
know what I mean so it's like it can be
a little bit more risky than some of the
other methods of growing in my opinion
in an Organics as let's transition to
that now there's so many different ways
you can do Organics as well right you
can make your own soil mix and then feed
in Blends organic Blends from there you
can do individual amendments you could
buy bagged organic potting mix and then
go from there what's your style of
organic like how do you approach organic
gardening
uh well I'm lucky enough to live on a
farm so I have the ability to kind of
you know work with what's there and also
um you know if you're if you're growing
and that's the thing is with Hydro it
makes sense sometimes because like yeah
you're living in a place where you can't
bring soil in and out and not look like
complete and nutcase like what are they
doing in this nice house coming into
this you know so there's always reasons
for everything right
um and and with me with with Organic
like so I I um
uh I right now I'm doing uh three by
three uh
cloth pots as the square ones you know
um I like to grow with large uh
large containers you know what I mean
I'm not interested like that's that's
like when I see people growing on soil
but they're doing them in one gallons or
three gallons or something and they're
feeding them like at that point you're
Hydro you know what I mean you might as
well grow Hydro at that point because
you are feeding them every single day so
for me it's like about a two two day
with a dry back kind of feeding schedule
is about right you know what I mean like
I try not to like I don't want to have
to I don't want to have to go down there
every day but also don't I like to hand
feed everything just because it's like
that way I mean the numbers are not very
you know if it was a large scale grow of
course you're going to automate as much
as you can but when you're dealing with
personal sized Gardens I think it's
super important that you do hand water
if possible because it really connects
you to the plant like you can you know
you pick up the pot you check the weight
you know what I mean if it's in a pot or
if it's in a if it's in a three by three
you know you you know you've given it a
couple days you see a little bit of
droop you come in you feed but I really
feel like hand watering connects you to
your Garden a lot like it is really like
important that you pay attention
obviously too you know and I'm always
counting in my head like all I'm doing
is walking around and Counting
everything like counting you know like
okay this one check the weight okay
that's you know and they kind of know in
your head that's 30 seconds there you
know that's a minute oh this one and
then so I'm just constantly walking
around and poking and prodding and I
feel like it's one of those things where
you like I really don't like when people
feed like on a schedule whenever they
feel like it like it's really the plants
it's up to the plants you know what I
mean so like if I go in and this one
over here has not been feeding very much
well I'm not going to give it anything
I'm going to let it dry out a little bit
because I've seen many people who it
just becomes like a system where they're
just like doesn't matter you know
whatever you didn't eat too bad now
you're getting more you know what I mean
but then you'll see you know you can
track those plants down the road and
you'll see though they will not uh live
up to the to the ones next to them
because they're just you know they need
they need a break for a day or so so
yeah I think um
for me like organic equals that
idea of hand watering and you know slow
slow pace not trying to the minute you
want to set it all up and forget about
it that's when you you need to think
about Hydra at that point because that's
that's the kind of person you know if
you want to set it up on your phone and
be all high-tech and you know check all
your stuff that's cool and I appreciate
it and it's but a lot of times for me
it's like
it's a lot like uh
I used to work on boats right I used to
sail on boats and a lot of times like
when you were on a small boat you do
everything by hand right everything's by
hand you've got to like go in there and
adjust adjust the trim on the on the
sail run back here so but if you're on a
bigger boat
everything's automated you know what I
mean you just poop you hit a button and
so
for me I like the idea of running around
and doing adjusting things because it
keeps me in the in the moment you know
what I mean it also makes me like know
like I know when I'm going to bed like
oh
I gotta go back and check that because
it's like you're you're connected to
your garden more the minute you like
have it all on your computer or it's on
your phone or whatever it's like you're
waiting for your phone to tell you if
your plants are not good you know what I
mean it's like you shouldn't you don't
you lost it you lost your little heart
connection to your plants at that point
because you're like ah it'll take care
of it and oh [__] my phone's dead oh no
like things you know too late too little
too late and uh we've all left the uh
Reservoir running and ran up to the
somebody rang on the doorbell and you
forgot and you went and started doing
something else you know what I mean and
then you had that that heart drop moment
where you're like oh my God
and I've done it
more than most I'd say but
still makes you feel it makes you laugh
at yourself though sometimes which is
always a good thing yeah exactly right
when you're like I can't believe I just
did that again right when it comes to
like the fertilizer uh do you typically
do like the organic Blends do you do
individual amendments do you do compost
or worm castings a little of a kind of a
little guilty of all of the above in the
sense of I usually well re-amend all my
soil like because I'm doing a three by
threes I will and I'm you know I I've
played around with no-till I like it but
the problem is is that I'm also
um
nervous about
any kind of pathogens or any kind of
problems kind of kicking in and having
to like you know like once you have a
soil that you've dedicated years into it
you know what I mean it's it becomes
super critical
um that you can keep it maintain it and
and I also have sponsors from the show
so I got like you know bio 365 soil I've
got access to all so I'm like well you
know it in an Ideal World of course I
would you know be living on my farm
reimending my stuff and keeping it all
biodynamic and within the actual
confines of the property you know what I
mean but when you have people dropping
off pallets of soil to you you're like
ah probably gonna use it I mean I'm not
gonna go out and make my own soil when I
have people delivering me beautifully
made uh products so I'm doing a lot of
testing which makes it harder to kind of
maintain one system so um so like on for
instance uh what I'll usually do is I'll
have all fresh soil on my smaller runs
and then eventually I'll take all that
soil and put it outside and then
reammend it and and then bring it back
into it and use it in a different
different part of the garden you know so
every it's a beautiful thing I got
chickens and we got you know we got cows
and chickens and horses and things on
the property so it's like a constant
flow which is a beautiful thing you know
what I mean and that's where I I love
the idea of and that that's why I feel
like if you have a situation like that
then you if you're not growing
organically it'll be crazy right if you
literally have the ability to you know
take all your scraps and feed them to
your chickens and
they're happy you're happy everybody's
happy at that point
um and uh I also work with
um with cultured biologics who's also I
think Tim was on your Show recently and
oh yeah I mean you know how I mean talk
about a wealth of knowledge right that
guy amazing so like when you get
somebody like that super passionate and
I'm testing out their products and I'm
like Blown Away by the quality I mean
his
anybody who's listening to this if you
have go back and listen to the show with
Tim you will realize I'm sure how
incredibly intelligent he is but also
passionate and his his the quality of
the products coming out of his thing is
amazing like I've I've night and day
like I literally and it's powdered which
is great you know what I mean the E
online at least I mean he's got new
stuff coming out but the E online which
is what I've been running
wow it's like it is it really feels like
you're
you're uh treating your plants super
special every time you you feed them
you're just like man and then like his
supplements his liquid supplements
nitrogen he's got a nitrogen phosphorus
um and he's got like some saponins and
and
all those products I can't believe every
time I hit him up with it you know you
get that extra special feeling when you
walk back in and everything is praying
like amazing and just yeah the amount of
growth that comes off those his nitrogen
one I dropped one recently and it it
really smells right it doesn't smell bad
it's got a really weird smell it's got
like a smell of like a locker room like
kind of like high school locker room
funk which is you know if you know it
you know it and you can it's like it's a
weird but it's like uh yeah it's just
this weird weird vibe but it's but oh my
God the plants they just go off so yeah
so I have an ability to work with a lot
of cool products which makes it kind of
like
my curse is that I'm always changing my
stuff up like my mom goes nuts right my
mom grows with me and she is she'd be
such a better grower without me around
because she's so consistent with her
stuff like she's just you know can just
consistently Nails it I mean she's her
dad was the grandfather with the garden
right so she pretty much just has it in
her in her system and she never like
like every time there's a [__] up it's
because I try to do something like ah
yay and then she'll come in and what are
you doing you know I was like oh I was
just trying this new thing you know and
and so so I my my
probably my guilt my worst thing about
growing from my personal point of view
is that I'm always trying new things
which I mean I feel like it's part of
the nature of the Beast right like you
always want to improve on things but
Ann is a little bit like fashion if I
look at photos from five years ago I'm
like what was I doing
doing there
why are my plants so dark you know what
I mean I'm way over feeding them here I
can I'm always critiquing all my old
stuff and it's amazing how each time you
do something you feel like it's the best
you've ever done or sometimes hope it is
and
and there's no more room for improvement
but then lo and behold you look back a
year later and you're like oh there was
so much room for improvement it's very
similar to the whole concentrate game
and all the different things you see the
evolution of things and how quickly they
they go up and you're like if you look
at a photo again from like 10 years ago
you're just like what is that like
couldn't even identify it so yeah I
think it's uh
it's uh it's it's nice to to try
different stuff but at the same time
you know if you can lock in on something
that works for you
good good good uh rule is to continue
that same thing you know because you
will improve on it
or just be like me and always try
something different I'm just like you
where I'm always doing something
different I mean uh some of my viewers
have complained because they watch my
videos they're like hey you're not still
doing that method why what happened is
there something wrong with it it's like
no I'm just trying something new there's
so many different ways to go about it
when it comes to Organics I was growing
uh I was using the Earth dust nutrients
by the green Sunshine Company they went
out of business craft blend by build the
soil now I'm using a kiss nutrients pack
kiss Organics nutrient pack but man
you're making me want to try uh Tim's oh
Tim's is amazing and you know who else
is also amazing I'm sure you've had them
on the show before his uh dragonfly
Earth medicine I haven't had him on yet
I don't need to have them on yeah
they're amazing they're up in Canada and
they have a complete biodynamic formula
Duke uses a lot of their stuff and I'm
just there they're one of the ones in
the group like I'd say out of all the
people that are in the industry they're
like 100 doing it the right way you know
like there's no no no uh
they do not skimp on anything like not a
single input that's in any of their
products it's not or not 100 certified
organic like they
there's no like oh well we're not 100
sure no if like even if like product
that went into the compost possibly
wasn't organic they don't need they
don't they don't touch it you know what
I mean so it's amazing there there's
some you know that's the thing with with
I think uh people tend to
always think that it's like one extreme
or the other and that's why I really
feel like a kind of a combination of
everything is it what kind of works for
everybody and if you notice like
companies like veganics right back in
the day you know everybody thought if
you look at it go look into that label
and look into it
it's not because it's not vegan there's
not there is there is
two percent maybe three percent
non-organics you know what I mean but
that's all it takes right so if you want
to be extreme you have to be like
dragonfly Earth medicine and do it real
right
can't really bottle Organics and and
truly have a proper product because it's
like that that two percent is probably
the most important two percent I mean
it's like it's what's really making it
do its thing so you know organic has its
place but it has to be very you know you
have to
you also have to be a little bit like
forgiving on some things too because I
feel like you want to give the plant the
best things it can get you know and not
limit itself
but yeah you definitely should try it
you definitely need to trade the culture
it's amazing now are you also doing some
of the I like to call optional methods
which is like cover crops mulch layers
things that aren't really required when
growing organically but people do it as
well in order to try to get a better
result there's benefits to doing those
things um I do like um cover crops
mostly because I feel like it helps the
soil
um not dry out too quickly you know I
mean otherwise you get that Dusty top
Zone where you just feel like there's
not much life in the top two inches you
know and that's really where you want
more biodiver more biodiversity so like
um you know I'll I'll tend to grow
clover and barley and things like that
and sometimes in between like a lot of
times if I'm not like if there's any
um
like when I'm finished with the crop
I'll just throw a bunch of seeds in
there just to keep the life rolling in
that thing so it doesn't get all dead on
you know so but I won't do it as like as
like that is my only nutrients or the
the you know go in there and cut all the
things down and let it go back in and
that's it like I'm still
I'm still you know
coming from the world of just I want to
see some action you know I want to see
some accident go down now when we're
talking about Hydroponics versus growing
Organics there's a couple things that
are kind of controversy which will be
yield and then flavor let's start with
yield did you personally notice a
difference in yield when growing
organically versus hydroponically 100
100 yeah like I mean
yeah yeah for sure like uh the thing
about growing on hydro is you you do you
do achieve sometimes amazing results
when it comes to yield right because you
are
basically you know
um
fog wiring these things right you're
Force feeding them you're giving them
whatever you know you're maxing them out
on their EC you're pushing the plants to
its limit
um you know I've seen massive plants
especially recently too because like I
go and Tour all these Gardens and you
know it's it's it's beautiful to see but
I also know that there's pgrs in there
and I'm not really interested in smoking
any of it because I don't feel it's
healthy but I see some phenomenal growth
you know what I mean like it's some
amazing results
um so yields tend to
uh suffer a little bit in inorganic not
not all the time now there are certain
situations it really depends on your
location and your in whatever your
inputs are because organic growing for
instance Outdoors
yeah there's I wouldn't even compare it
you know what I mean because you're
never going to get a salty plant to grow
as big as an organic plant outdoors in a
large scale just because it it won't it
will not there's nothing to sustain it
at that point whereas you know when
you're growing organically Outdoors on a
scale like that
just the amount of assistance that's
going on within the mycorrhagial and you
know the rhizospheres is a completely
active Place whereas if you go on the
hydro the rhizosphere is a devoid of
action you know what I mean it's like
there's things going there's Roots
growing but there's hardly any you know
uh life down there and so for me the the
key to the whole thing is is everything
helps each other right so if you're
growing uh so like but flip but then on
the opposite end of the spectrum when it
comes to flavor hands down 100 organic
Ivy time like there's no not even a
question like and people can say oh yeah
I get I can grow it so you know people
can't tell the difference
sure sure you can but I bet if somebody
else grew it organically it would taste
better than what you know I mean it's
just like it really comes down to like
you cannot compare them because you know
the cardboard chirps you get off of
Athena is not gonna ever compare it to a
you know a properly grown organic garden
just it ain't happening I'm sorry you
know and and people can
because a lot of times people will be
like no but not from experience only
from
you know they smoked that they think it
tastes good but they don't know what
else could be there you know what I mean
there's so much more that can be there
and yeah definitely from a
from an actual wanting to smoke a point
of view like I had um we did think of
the adsi which is the out of denture
Invitational we did him
I think
2014-15 and 18. and every single time
top three organic and this is all blind
and this is by The Growers like you know
we did the classic where if you enter
you get to test so it wasn't like
you know randos it was like
you entered or you entered Hydro but you
picked organic so therefore that just
tells me it wins right there you know
what I mean like The Growers themselves
see it and appreciate it
so yeah I think you can't really beat it
now what about Bud's structure I heard
people some people say blood structure
is compromised when you're growing with
Hydroponics for example they they uh
have grown the same cultivar same cut
and organic versus Hydroponic and
they've got more denser bud structure
and the organic side of things but
Hydroponics it's more airier fluffier
bud structure what are your thoughts on
that oh yeah I think that's true too I
mean it comes down to genetics a little
bit there though also so sometimes
you'll have certain ones that just
respond better to the situation
um you know the thing about Hydro is
it's a lot of water weight right so
you've got this like
massive you know expansion and large
watery cells you know it's very similar
to like and then if you take organic
growing it's like the cell's structure
is tighter you know they sell walls are
thicker so when you take a cell wall
That's thicker and you dry it out and
you have more mass right so
theoretically and then and it's denser
so you don't get this big expansion and
then retraction right that's that
like big bud right when I was so uh in
Holland right
because the Dutch are very um
they're very money orientated they're
not so you know flower orientated they
love their money it doesn't matter what
it is if it's flowers for the kukenhof
or if it's you know whatever it is it's
about the bottom line that's all the
Dutch really care about that's where
that's why Americans who go there really
shine when it came to breeding because
we really
we're about flavors and about all these
things that they weren't about they were
only about size smell and money that's
kind of that's their that's their goal
right how big is it what does it smell
like how much money can I get you know
and so we were more like you know how
does it smell how does it taste and does
the joint even burn you know what I mean
because that would be the other thing
too you get people just pack them up
with food and don't really flush it
properly and you end up with some
terribly burning and so
um
the but what I also noticed too and you
you as you go higher up in altitude you
know your plants change too and that's
one of the things where I almost compare
like a high altitude plant to a organic
growing plant and a valley like a low
valley plant to a hydro plant because
the low valley plant gets a lot of water
right grows really tall and thin and
kind of just massive biomassy kind of
situation and as you go up into the
mountains
same genetics would be short
and more compact to insulate them better
and also to be more efficient and as the
UV increases as you go higher up and the
UV increases it it shortens everything
down like so if you go to the top of a
mountain and see the trees at the top
they're a lot shorter and Tighter and
more Compact and as you go down the
mountain it gets bigger and bigger and
when you get to the bottom they're
really big and just water so it's kind
of like similar in the sense that you
get this density issue and that density
is what I believe is the part that
you're saying as far as like because
I've seen a lot of plants growing in
Hydra which you know they look they fill
up the area
but you can just see that there's not
much there you know what I mean like
they have this especially all the Cali
strains all these new Cali strains are
really lame I'm sorry to say they're
really lame to grow you grow them and
you're like what that's it like they
don't ever explode you know they don't
have that Vigor that you're looking for
and I feel like
it's almost like all of us old-time
Growers we're always going back to the
90s right oh in the 90s big giant
Williams Wonder but you know we had like
because everything counted right like it
was like
you get one shot you know you get one
shot kid and then you gotta get it and
make it happen whereas now the
pressure's off as far as like you know
you're running a licensed facility
there's no there's no pressure Beyond
doing a good job but what's funny is
that because of that people gotten a lot
less focused on
you know like the all of the above
strains that you want which is like good
yields are good strength and power and
does all the things you want they just
go in for like the one all they're going
for is extraction that's pretty much
like that's how people's brains are so
like whatever they they take it does it
wash well right when somebody asks me is
does it wash well I'm usually like
off you know what I mean like really
that's all you care about is washing the
plane you don't even care about the
plant because the plants that wash well
are not the plants that smoke well
the plants that smoke well tend to be
you know individual nice buds that are
really like get a chance to mature
properly and they're not all these like
runny little plants and but the ones
that are runny are the ones that are
loose they're really good for making
extracts you know so you know like you
don't want to like like your really good
flour plant that's got nice compact
beautiful buds they're hard to get into
to make the product so by the time you
get into them you've tore them all up
and now you've created more you know
just more chlorophyll in the system or
more plant matter
whereas if you get plants that are
you know like
just easy there are lots of lots of
trikes on both sides and it's easy to
get to knock it all off really quickly
you're hand paddling you know
everybody's doing it by hand so they
don't want stuff that you have to break
it up you know and if you have to break
it up you're causing more
you know quality control issues at that
point so yeah I think I think definitely
uh
and also the other thing too the the
number one thing I see problems with is
pH on hydro systems right I'll walk in
and I'll be like I got a pH problem and
be like oh what are you talking about no
you know dude you got a pH problem
telling you right now look at everything
it's all single leaves it's all like
looking really stressed out you know
what I mean and that's the problem with
Hydra is that
you know you creating all of the
boundaries and
therefore there's a huge chance of
messing all up you know what I mean
because you are a human and you are not
like the plants have no problems
um if you give them everything they need
they'll figure it out right and they'll
take it in as they need to take it in
but when you're doing Hydro you don't
give them a chance because they only
have a very limited window to feed which
is like when the timer kicks on right so
the timer kicks on they're feeding they
get a little bit of remnants at the end
of it all and then it's just drying out
and you know hopefully expanding Roots
Etc but
um when it's on soil or it's on you know
organically it's like
it's kind of like a they have a
they have a smorgasbord set up in front
of them you know and so they're like oh
well I want one of those when you have
some of that you know and at the same
time the mycorrhizal and other things
are you know getting it ready for the
plants and setting it all up and then
they come in and scoop up that you know
what I mean so there's a lot more
there's a lot more going on that we
don't get and you'll never get because
it's you know at a microbial level and
it's not like it's not your decision to
make you know it's so yeah I think the
most of the mistakes would probably be
human error you know on hydro
which is
you know something we can avoid but with
with Organic you're kind of like
you just kind of try to create the the
environment for them to do their thing
that makes sense I definitely want to
get into cost perspective here but there
are folks that are on the budget right
they don't want to be spending uh
hundreds or potentially even thousands
of dollars depending on how big they set
up they want to have to get started so
from a cost perspective talk to us about
Hydro versus organic so by far obviously
organic would be cheaper to get into
now when you start talking about cost
per pound and on Industrial levels and
things like that
um
after the initial input because the
thing about Hydro is you got to buy the
system right so you buy the system and
then a lot of people they're like yeah
but I bought it once and I can just
reuse it over and over and over again so
that in their mind is their cost saving
Factor right there's still inputs right
you still got your cocoa or your rock
wool or whatever medium that unless
you're growing on so like dwc would
probably be the cheapest format of going
into it because you really only have to
buy that cocoa block each time or that
Rockwell block each time to put on top
for the most part
um whereas you know with and and so
really it comes down to like
uh from a beginner point of view
costs are kind of negligible because
we're not talking about a big system so
it might cost a little bit more for
hydro
um but the
the at the end of the day like if they
were to take their cost per gram or
whatever it would end up uh
being cheaper on organic in the long run
but in the short run
because uh you can sort of like say hey
I spent 27 dollars and I may and I got a
pound you know okay so there you go
that's a pretty good ratio whereas a lot
of times with organic stuff uh
you know the the the initial costs
depending on what you're doing I mean if
you go to build a soil there's another
sponsor of my show and he's got every
range possible Right you could go you
can spend you can also spend quite a lot
of money on on organic stuff too it is
so it really depends on on what you want
to do but you can also go like are those
guys at dragonfly arithms and they
quoted me at five dollars a pound for
their organic that's what their their
costs are
you know so five bucks a pound is pretty
damn cheap I don't think you're gonna
get much cheaper than that and that's
because of course they're on you know
they're using everything within their
farm so they're very rarely putting much
more inputs in it took them a long time
to get there and I'm sure there was you
know initial costs all the way along but
you know you you definitely can grow
cheaper
if you live in the right place
organically like if you don't live in
the right place it's not going to make
much sense but you know you're going to
grow especially if you're doing anything
Greenhouse or outdoor anything large
because I you know when you start
thinking about
I mean I've seen people do it like
Hydroponics Outdoors are like what is
wrong you're like what are you doing
over here you know I mean really going
against the grain as hard as you can
um but in a small scale I think
cost effective wise
organic
100 cheaper uh
but at the same time when you're growing
on scale to like for large licensed
producers and stuff they're going to
look at it like the uh they're going to
have a better time with Hydroponics
because it's easier for them to
calculate the inputs the outputs because
there's a very simple formula that keeps
repeating itself over and over again you
know
it's kind of my my way of looking at it
got it yeah it can be super cheap
organic they have a closed loop
operation right which is kombucha
explaining that that farm has which is
basically they're using their own inputs
that they're creating I mean you can
even go down the natural farming route
right with the the fermented plant juice
fermented fruit juice all that stuff and
it gets really really cheap then and I
think that's actually
it's one of the
the latest advancements in in
agriculture that is even though it's
ancient Technologies the fact that
everybody's tuned in on it now and it
was like maybe like
four years ago or something like that I
think it's the first time I even like
ran across ferments you know what I mean
and my friend had him in his garden and
I was like what's this he's like oh I
made that out of peaches and I made this
one out of uh mangoes and I was like
really oh wow and
I you know didn't really
like I mean his Gardens were nice but it
wasn't like I wasn't like oh my God
blown away but then later
flavor wise I started to like you know
he gave me some from that that round and
I was just like man this stuff's amazing
taste right and then so I started to
gravitate towards it and then now of
course miles is making some awesome
ferments and uh you know teaching
everybody how to do which is really
important too I think that's the one
thing if because we have access to all
these like fresh new material right yeah
it's like
turn it into ferments it makes so much
sense and so when you can make ferments
from your own plants and then
reintroduce it into your own garden it's
like you know it's the difference
between working with uh you know
local compared to like importing in
every time because when you import stuff
in
everything has to establish itself but
when you have local uh you know you have
local inputs it's just gives you that
much of a head start and everything's
like you know that everything can
survive because that's where it comes
from you know so yeah it's huge I have
yet to try some of these natural farming
techniques you know the fermented
Planters run into fruit juice but you
know it really is my goal to like not
spend any money on organic fertilizer
you know what I mean if I could send no
money on fertilizer in the future that's
that would be a huge win so I'm not
there yet but maybe I'll get there in
the future I think also like you know
worms having their own little worm bin
going is always a good move
um just don't let them dry out that's my
problem out here it's so dry and I think
oh you come back you're all sad you just
lost hundreds of more I'm saying
come back but yeah worms are great if
you can get them in your garden that's
that's a huge bonus right there yeah I
get the worm bin going and yeah so I'm
working I'm getting there I'm getting
there but I feel like at the end of the
day you know when it talks about Hydro
versus organic I have some people ask me
what's better and the follow-up question
shows me what's better for what you know
what are you looking for are you looking
to make things easy are you looking to
grow plants fast I had to go on one team
or the other I would go team organic
just because of my feelings of of a
consumer you know like if it was if it
was a producing situation and that's all
you cared about was numbers and
production I can I can understand when
people might want to go down that road
but if you're if you're doing it for
yourself and you are the recipient of
all of this material you're doing
yourself no favors by by limiting your
organic and like being and going with it
with a hydro system because you really
at the end of the day like when it comes
to food or anything that I'm putting in
my body I really want to focus on you
know having an organic I'd rather the
extra money to have organic then then
try to cut corners and I feel like with
with anything that you're consuming on a
daily you should think that way because
there will be
a reckoning at some point right and when
you figure out down the road like wow
been smoking all this pgr
might look really good but it's not good
for you I'm telling you it's 100 not
good for you you know and you can really
see the difference so we were saying
earlier about the you know natural like
or organic compared to
um uh Hydro really it's the pgrs that's
the number one issue right now and
that's the problem with most of the or
get most of the hydro formulas unless
they specifically tell you that they're
not in there they probably are in there
you know I mean it's almost like
it's almost like if you uh if you want
to get corn products right if it doesn't
say it's organic you can guarantee it's
GMO
and it's been grown in the Roundup you
know what I mean so you probably don't
want to consume it at that point so I
always feel like with anything like that
you really you're better off to uh
take the slow Road and and have a a
quality product at the end that you can
feel the safe well said well we could
get deeper and deeper into both aspects
but uh we're gonna wrap things up here
you know what you know what I'm going to
do now though is I'm going to invite you
to my show
you've always wanted to be I'm swearing
yeah but definitely come on the show
sometime and hang out with us would be
great that would be cool that'd be cool
tell the listeners where they can find
you and uh what you have upcoming in the
future so it's uh every Friday we're
about to do a show in a few hours now
but it's every Friday 4 20 to 7 10
Mountain Time
three hour show uh we do uh you know we
have lots of interesting guests but we
also you know we we're not strictly
gross show one day it could be you know
building materials the next day it could
be CBD the next day it could be THC
stuff didn't actually you know it could
be anything any and above of all
different subjects so it makes it great
you know it could be hem Crete one day
um but we have uh
yeah we've had we've had some great
guests this year with like so far we've
only we're only in February and we've
had you know add-on here at Rosenthal on
here and Tommy Chong and all the big all
the big hitters come on every so often
and and but our show is very much like a
uh a hangout you know so it's a little
bit less of a tell you what to do more
just come hang out with us and enjoy
your Fridays awesome yeah definitely I'd
love to come on that I appreciate the
invite cool yeah for sure looking good
looking forward to it well Adam this
says uh it's been a fun talk definitely
I love to hear your your perspective on
Organics and hydroponics I've definitely
learned a lot of things about you and I
mean you've been doing this for a very
very long time so really really good
Insight thank you so much for coming on
to the podcast today for those tuning in
Click the thumbs up if you enjoyed this
episode also subscribe to the channel if
you haven't already every single weekend
I'm releasing a new Garden Talk podcast
episode I love you to tune into future
episodes Adam once again thank you so
much for coming onto the podcast really
appreciate it we'll keep in touch I'll
come on your podcast and we'll go from
there that's sounds like a plan all
right peace out everyone catch you in
the next episode