welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 104. in this
episode I interview Jeremy Silva he is
the owner of build a soil and he's
actually been on the podcast once before
episode 51 where he talked all about
building soils and adding organic inputs
throughout the growth cycle this time
around we get into a variety of
different organic gardening related
topics he talks about seeds part of teas
cover crops mulch layers pH and so much
more I want to acknowledge that one of
my goals for this podcast is to bring
free gardening information of all plants
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible Bovada is sponsoring this
episode I've been using the Bovada 58
and 62 humidity packs for six years now
and they do a fantastic job at ensuring
my flowers or at the ideal moisture
content their humidity packs help
maintain us stable environment
protecting against trichome damage
terpene loss over drying and mold check
out their website at bovadaink.com
that's bov Eda inc.com I'll also have a
link in the YouTube description section
of this episode thanks to Mars Hydro for
sponsoring this episode check out their
smart growth system it's a fully
automated system with a smart app for
control plug in your equipment to the
ihub power strip and you can control
your equipment such as the lighting on
off light intensity and a sunrise sunset
feature you can also control the
ventilation system to help dial in your
environment's conditions check out their
website at
mars-hydro.com and you can use the
discount code Mr growit for discount on
any of their products thanks to AC
Infinity for sponsoring this episode
their clip-on oscillating fan is awesome
I've been using their six inch version
but they also have a 9-inch version it's
easy to clip on the side of my Groton
event and has 10 different speeds which
makes it easy to control air circulation
they do have a non-oscillating version
of this clip-on fan as well it also
connects to their smart controller 69 so
you can control the fans and other AC
Infinity equipment through their app
from your smartphone the discount code
Mr Droid 15 works on both Amazon and
their website AC infinity.com
and we are back welcome to the Garden
Talk podcast today I am joined with
Jeremy Silva once again how you doing
today hey thanks for having me on this
is great glad to be back yeah the last
episode we did together episode number
51 for those of you who didn't catch
that currently has over 150 000 views uh
insane just on YouTube alone and then
there's the podcast platforms which has
a whole bunch of other listens beyond
that but it was crazy there's a lot of
people in the comments with a lot of
positive feedback and I don't know if
you remember it but at the end of the
episode I was told people to comment if
they wanted a part two and it just went
crazy in the comments so welcome back
for part two good that makes me happier
as soon as you said 150 000 I was super
impressed and I thought wait a minute
he's got a big show I wonder if that's
nothing
that's good to hear that's a good number
no it's really really good today we're
going to get into a variety of organic
gardening related topics so just a quick
list of things I want to get into seed
spotted tees I want to get into cover
crops mulch layers p H and living soil
which is a Hot Topic and a handful of
other things which I won't spoil it for
the viewers although if you're on
YouTube you can always click in the
description section there's the time
stamps so you can skip through and see
the different topics as we go along but
first can you introduce yourself for
those that didn't catch the first
episode we did together yeah I'd be
happy to and first off I love the
rundown you just gave because those are
really good topics and I could see
myself using this for our customers in
the future so my name is Jeremy Silva
and I'm the founder of build a soil and
it started about 10 years ago so it's
pretty big year for us and 10 years in
and I you know I anticipated that it'd
be something that I would love to do for
the rest of my life I just wasn't sure
if I'd be given the opportunity and
while it's not always easy it's my
favorite thing to do and it started off
from the desire to build living soil
from scratch and living soil is the term
that was used a lot back then so it's
still around
and from that we started lab testing all
sorts of different things that brought
me to the current place where I think I
can share some pretty valuable
information with all of you awesome so
short and sweet I know a lot of folks
tune into your YouTube channel so you
guys exploded over the past year and a
half on that channel I mean geez what do
you got 130 140 000 subscribers now I'd
have to check today yeah it's been going
up and faster than I anticipated Dean
who does our editing he's a wizard
and he told me look at I'm gonna have
more than your Instagram here in this
amount of time and I said no I said 10
years of Instagram posting there's no
way you're gonna do that and
um he did exactly what he said he was
gonna do and it was a great relationship
where he's good at editing and I talk a
lot it was easy to get content so
um really happy to be on YouTube and
really appreciate all the support tons
of videos and good information on that
channel and I'll definitely have a link
to the channel down in the YouTube
description section below so people can
easily get to it all right let's start
with the first topic seed sprouted teas
so um can you break down what are the
benefits of doing seed Sparta teas and
how do you create them and how often
should they be done so this is a good
topic and I'd like to bridge it into two
parts and I'll mention up front the
first is about SST and its origin and
why we use it and I can keep it pretty
succinct but the second part is we've
moved away from seed sprouted teas they
still are very valuable but the goal was
to get the peak enzymatic content as you
learn about biology the breakdown of
organic matter is heavily enzyme
dependent and that's why you hear people
that eat raw they're like you need the
enzymes in the food when you cook it you
destroy it and the enzymes are really
important to gut health and soil Health
it's similar and so Clackamas coot Jim
um which by the way we're going to do he
just sent me like hundreds of his
pakalola one his famous genetic that he
did a back cross on and I'm I'm super
excited about it uh but not the popular
the one sorry uh we grew that one last
time that just happened that's why I'm
thinking about it but as far as Jim goes
Clackamas coot
um he was a bread Baker he owned a tree
nursery he was part of many different
um
forums where we provided information to
organic Growers and he was just looked
up as this Legend and people really
trusted his advice because he backed it
with facts and he started postulating
that hey these seeds they have the
energy of life in there they use enzymes
to sprout not nutrients and so he got
some seed and he sprouted it and there's
more to the story but long story short
he grounded blend them up in water and
he watered that to the plants and the
next day in the morning he opened
um The Grove and he was thinking wow why
are all these plants why do they have
such turgor why are they so happy right
now what's different and so over many
duplications you would get that same
experience every time and one of the
things that is interesting is when you
are are gardening it's like a pet and
you know when your your pet wags its
tail and is happy and the treat you gave
it was something of benefit and
ubiquitously across the board anybody
that uses a sprouted CT they see these
benefits and I'll tell you how to do it
it's pretty simple but the fundamental
philosophy behind it is that when you
sprout a seed it's this enzymatic
process that allows the creation of life
and it's dormant in there we'd like to
unlock those enzymes and then before the
plant uses them we steal it we give it
to our plant
and um it also crosses over where people
that eat vegetarian or not even that
just a healthy lifestyle a lot of times
we're looking at seeds as a higher
source of nutrition and oftentimes
they'll have sprouted seeds as the more
available nutrition form because that
pre-sprouting unlocks some of the
difficult to access nutrients and allows
the gut to digest it
probably also because of some of the
enzymes and enzymes are weird the most
research on enzymes is for beer brewing
because that's where enzymes are very
important for converting starch and
sugars and making alcohol and it's a
certain process to make the same
duplicatable result so you can get find
lots of research on amylase enzyme but
there's not as much information out
there on phosphatase and protease and
all these other ones that exist in every
one of those seeds and that's because
the beer brewers didn't require that but
in soil every single seed regardless of
what you get will have a variety of
enzymes that are of benefit
so you can use really any organic seed
to sprout
and to tap into this benefit
the first time that Coots shared it with
us on the Forum he said go find good
organic seed any organic seed and the
cheapest that you could access tonight
if you don't want to go online and buy
any seeds would be to go to the grocery
store and buy organic popcorn seed
because they have organic popcorn seed
and bulk available and then you can just
Sprout them in a sprouting Cup in a
glass jar you can Google how to sprout
seeds and that led to us selling the
easy Sprout it's my favorite sprouting
device and we would use those and fill
them full and then you blend that in
water and we've got a Blog article about
SST you can Google build a soil SST
recipe it breaks down like the
measurement of how many seeds and how
much water but we've found none of that
really matters you just need to sprout a
generous amount of seeds and say you
know a quarter cup of seeds can Sprout
into a whole bunch of seed and if you
take that by volume and water in a
blender you just want to get maybe a
quarter full of a blender the rest water
blend it dump that into your bucket of
water and feed it to your plants and
that's the simple explanation you can
certainly get weird about the recipe and
that's why I gave you the blog
and after that people went crazy with it
and they try a variety of seeds I've
used our cover crop that's got 12
different seeds in it so that's some
variety for making an SST
we like the corn a lot out of all the
seeds that we've tried when we get
heirloom corn the water smells sweet
it's really white it seems like it
imparts a lot more enzymes than a
typical sprouting I don't have science
to back that up I just know that the
first enzyme that they found I think it
was something in the ocean but the first
time they were able to duplicate it
naturally
instead of like from an animal was in
corn and it's called zeitin
and so that's part of the history there
um but fast forward
we started learning well these beer
brewers they're not sprouting their seed
every time now there are still malting
houses that do that they'll Sprout the
seed across the floor they have an
entire process and then they brew the
beer but typically what happens is
that's a professional job
and then those seeds as soon as they're
sprouted they dry them out
that actually preserves the enzymes and
they're active and available
and I used to think that's not possible
because these are alive but we're
basically releasing the enzyme and then
putting it in stasis
and that is just a malted seed so then
we went on the mission well what can we
buy malted seed hence of course they
want to sell it to you but they heat it
and they do that because if you roast
the malted seed to a darker color you
get more flavor and so beer brewers have
many varieties of roasting levels that
they're looking for
so we went with the lightest one the
least amount of heat and that worked
really well fast forward kute and I made
the gnarly barley and that is sprouted
barley sprouted lentils and sprouted
organic non-GMO corn and so when you're
taking these Ancient Grains like corn
and the lentils and you're adding The
Barley which is heavily available a lot
of enzyme research they've already been
sprouted and dried so now what I do is I
take that grind it up fresh in a blender
and just sprinkle it on the soil and it
takes out the step where I have to plan
a day ahead to sprout the seed if you'd
like to sprout the seed it's fine and
many of us still do that but what we
learned was sprouting seed at home if
you're trying to do this you want the
tail the little white part of the seed
that comes out originally to be as short
as possible about to just explode out of
the seed or barely have left if you get
a long tail like that much of the
enzymes have already started to be
utilized by that growth
and so if you are going to sprout some
seeds you want to arrest them as soon as
you see that sprouting and blend them up
and use them you could even dry them out
for yourself some people will put them
on low in the oven you know like just to
dehydrate them and they'll make their
own malted seed
from what we can tell there's pretty
good science at these sprouting labs and
so they are able to unlock a little bit
better more consistent percentage of
enzymes than sprouting your own seeds
but certainly they both I mean they both
produce the same reaction it's
unbelievable
so that's the whole story I wonder maybe
if you have any questions or anything I
left out that might be helpful no that's
pretty interesting I didn't know about
that that second part there I know
people were still sprouting their own
seeds but having that option the other
way to get the enzymes is pretty
interesting it was pretty interesting
that you uh even use this 12 seed blend
the cover crop blend cover crop makes a
lot of sense for use because it's
diverse and so when we first learned
about spreaded CTS we learned that
basically every seed would work and
nature does like diversity
um the other thought is well cover crop
is usually on Farm soil and sometimes
those seeds germinate and die and it's
it's a natural process it's a living
seed meal at that point even if your
cover crop doesn't grow and you let it
Sprout and then and then you just till
it in immediately it's it's a seed meal
that normally you pay money for like
soybean meal but these are better seeds
you've made them alive in the soil and
then killed them and they're fertilizer
so many benefits
um even if the enzymes aren't perfect
your sprouted seed tea is going to have
some nutrition so that makes sense so
getting into cover crops then there's so
many different things that can be used I
know in your 12 seed blend you have flax
Clover lentils veg whole bunch of good
things talk to us about cover crops you
know the benefits when they should be
used I know there's some debate on
whether you should grow cover crops
along with the plant or if it should
just be in between grows so talk to us
about that stuff
yeah this is really good
um and this is a deep one so I encourage
people to do their own research because
there's lots of great information and
some of these organic trials that are
done they have methods for 40 years
they've tested organic growing trials
no-till trials and many of the higher
producing regenerative Farms the mission
is spread where these cover crop
companies pop up because they're using
cover crop it's working so well they can
then sell seed to other farmers and they
start to receive the benefits and on
farming it's pretty clear if you have
bare soil that's not how nature intends
it and that's the conventional farming
style when it comes to organic farming
one of the benefits of a cover crop when
you first start doing research is
there's multiples but the basic senses
that cover crops are beneficial plants
that have the ability to improve the
soil quality they do that through a
number of different actions one is they
grow vigorously and they cover all of
the soil and they attract beneficial
insects
but on top of that the thing I think
they're most famous for is that Clover
legumes Clover is in the legume family
they actually take nitrogen out of the
air and they have the ability to fix
that nitrogen through its nodules on the
root and a organic process and put it
into the soil
and it does it through two methods one
is the cover crop can go can grow in
soil that your normal crop may not be as
good at growing in because the soil may
be not improved yet cover crop will grow
in there and it'll add organic matter
and as you till that cover crop in it
becomes what they call Green manure you
are fertilizing the soil by putting
freshly green grown plant that's full of
carbon and it used the sun and it grew
some of the nutrients from the soil and
you kill it and now what happens is you
turn these minerals that were down deep
it's pulled up to the top and it's
turned in organically so now your next
crop can benefit from all that fertility
and also the soil structure full of
organic matter will hold water it'll
hold beneficial life it'll hold
microorganisms worms all of these things
happen by utilizing cover crop and in a
dry climate like Colorado cover crop
Fields when done right there'll be like
a micro climate it'll be moist
underneath the cover crop the morning
Dew's on there so it's just
when you think about how nature works it
makes a ton of sense now what isn't as
natural is
when people first started using cover
crop indoors
and I think a lot of it took off because
it's kind of romantic it's this
emotional feeling to see all these
plants like a jungle growing around your
main cash crop because it feels like
you're actually farming or gardening in
a real way instead of just bare soil
with a plant
and when you consider that it makes a
lot of sense but we were told for a long
time whether it's in your raised bed
vegetable garden or whether it's indoors
then adding all these plants would be a
problem for one they would say it's
going to steal all the nutrients from
your main plant or it's going to attract
pests or problems I found most of these
gardening worries are inexperienced
gardeners having many problems and
correlation does not always equal
causation a lot of times when you know a
whole system you're able to utilize the
benefits and indoors some of the best
crops I've ever grown or when I started
using cover crop and it's hard to forget
that and I think what I relate that to
besides the fixing nitrogen all these
things which
fixing nitrogen takes a while it may not
be as big of benefit indoors but when
the plant dies it returns nitrogen to
the soil that way even if it wasn't
fixed
um but it can happen it does happen
especially when you're growing no-till
and you have cover crop going forever
um but the benefit that I think I
experienced is some of our earlier soil
recipes they weren't as balanced because
we didn't do as much soil testing and we
would just throw in according to the
recipes we read about and a lot of them
were heavy on extra inputs because more
is better right and we learned that some
of those excesses were actually
problematic some of the Amendments like
kelp if you doubled or tripled just
because you wanted to they brought maybe
some sodium or if you added too much
certain ingredients maybe there's
chloride or bicarbonate and for the most
part all these recipes work but if they
get junked up and too many of the bad
ones it takes a while for the soil to
leech it out and deal with it and when
you put cover crop in all of a sudden
you don't have to be as perfect at
watering because if you over water the
cover crop drinks it if you underwater
you're going to know because you're
going to get wilted and both the cover
crop as well as the main crop so it's
more about the over watering it helps
fix that but it also sent seems to
digest some of the problems in the soil
and then release them through the cover
crop which is no longer like too salty
or too problematic so it would like
buffer a soil that wasn't perfect and
I'd get really Healthy Growth out of the
plants and for when you're living soil I
mean that's what you want you want a a
perfect Leaf not burnt tips you're
you're trying to put in put in the
natural method to get the results and so
um for what it's worth the cover
cropping made a huge difference an
argument that you touched on
should we grow them with the plant or
not
it's a big one and I think that it's
about technique and so if you are let's
say you're growing a big tomato plant
and you know they take lots of energy
and they they grow really big
well if you grow cover crop and you grow
it 12 inches tall and then you come
spread it and you put a little tomato
seed good luck
the cover crop will absolutely devour it
take it over it won't even have a chance
but typically on a farm that's not how
it works they would till that cover crop
in they would cover it with plastic or
they would at least cover it for a week
or two that would all turn into fresh
soil then they'd go plant their crop
um but for us what we see most often is
what's called living mulch or more
companion planting it doesn't have to be
cover crop but cover crops seem to be
affordable they have a lot of the
benefits we're looking for you can also
grow herbs and you can grow some some
quick growing food crops as companion
plants but what I encourage you to do is
let's say that same tomato plant
scenario if you plant the tomato plant
first
or if you have a transplant and then you
put the cover crop in the cover crop
becomes secondary it becomes shaded by
the bigger leaves it never really gets
to take off and it's more now in a
support role where it's barely trying to
stay alive underneath everything you
have going on that to me is the living
mulch technique that's where you get the
benefit of the moisture management The
Beneficial the Predators get to live
underneath there and as you chop it and
drop it and you might add some other
fertilizers at some point organic ones
they combine and the build this whole
way is to use like a high carbon mulch
like a straw mulch and the Browns that
are the straw and the greens that are
the cover crop when they're chopped and
combined together that's the foundation
of how you make compost the Browns and
greens decompose into black Rich compost
and because we like worms in there and
all the beneficials it provides a home
where normally that bare soil would be
beat by the sun dry and of no beneficial
use to all these organisms so
like I said we could talk for days about
just this but and and that quick
conversation I wanted to try and really
give you as many directional signs to
start to research as possible
that makes sense yeah I've been using
the white Dutch Clover uh for several
years now and I did just the way that
you had mentioned which is you you grow
the cover crop and actually adding in
that mulch along with it and that's been
beneficial for me now one of the things
I learned actually a couple of people in
my podcast tell me that thrips feed off
of clover
which I thought was kind of interesting
to hear it's nothing that I have ever
come across have you heard of that
happening before no this is more the
fear I think that comes out trips feed
on everything
um so if you go on a grow and you're
planting fresh seed you shouldn't have
thrip in the seed and it shouldn't be an
issue so if there's trip there it's a
blessing now it's on the Clover it's not
on your cash crop I mean what's the
problem
um it can also be an early identifier if
you see something but thripper is some
of the easiest to deal with it's not
really a concern for most people
commercially it can be more of a problem
because they can't use spinosad and some
other ingredients
um which does make it slightly harder
but um
I tend to avoid a lot of those things
and go for First World experience and a
lot of people use cover crop
successfully and there's some
interesting cover crops that you can try
and use most of those are for management
purposes so if a big commercial facility
started using our 12-seat cover crop and
they didn't tend to
the mashing it down or chopping and
dropping or if there was a pocket that
got really out of control the vet can
start to Vine and while I like that some
people may not so they might choose
something like the white Dutch that is
no management it stays small it never
gets overgrown and it grows fairly slow
so it's easy to deal with and it can
tolerate some really cold temperatures
which is great for outdoor use
um for like a cover crop but indoors I
like the diversity I love the blanket
that the white white Dutch makes
but I'd love having the peas and the
flowers from the vetch and the lentils
and all the different things happening
and when I researched permaculture they
often indicate that getting up to about
12 different species of seeds gives you
the diversity that's required to have as
much success and an open field from
season to season where different seeds
and different things can happen right
um indoor maybe not as maybe not as
important but I like that a lot other
things you know to consider let's say
you have cover crop going
um a lot of this that we learned I think
that if I can point a direction that
would be philosophical for a lot of your
viewers really changed my life helped me
start building soil a lot of people
reference this book as one of the
reasons why they decided to go no-till
it's the one straw Revolution by
masanobo Fukuoka and it's a story about
somebody who worked in the long story
short in the chemical field this whole
life chemistry and then decided to go
back to Nature on his property basically
did nothing to it and observed and would
see how nature works and then when
growing as crops instead of growing rice
the traditional way flooded in water and
transplanted by hand they would throw
the rice in the grain that was growing
previously and I think it was barley I'm
going to get some of the exact crops off
but they would spread it while the crop
was still growing and it would germinate
and then they go harvest the next crop
and that would grow up through it
and so you started to see some of the
benefits of these natural cycles and it
teaches a lot about the no-till way and
the philosophy behind it in that book
and it's it's amazing but he would teach
people in there you put all the crops
that you you chop
down on the ground and then he would go
to the neighboring farms and they would
have them all the like the stocks lined
up perfect he's like no
it's a child like nature doesn't line it
up you're to block all of
otter and the light and the bugs and it
needs to just be thrown out there
and so with that philosophy he would say
return all of what you took to the soil
other than the Harvest
um and so a lot of indoor Growers they
do that they take all of the leaf from
the plant all of the cover crop that
they chop and they throw it all in the
mulch layer on the soil and while that's
great if you don't tend to the
environmental rules and there's not
enough airflow you can create a lot of
humidity tons of Decay and you can start
to get some of these bulb mites and you
can get a lot of beneficials but then
start composting right there and if
you're not judicious with you know
keeping it somewhat knocked down and
airflow there they'll start to climb up
your main plants and that can be a
problem because beneficial or not you
don't want them on your plants so that's
one thing to learn is that whether it's
good or bad when it comes to Nature
there is some balance that's required so
if you're going to chop and drop just
know that you should have some decent
airflow underneath there so that you
don't build up this and you know just
massive amount of decaying matter so
let's get deeper into mulch layers I
know on your website you sell the barley
straw I actually purchased some of that
a while back I use it in all my grows
but some people use wood chips uh I know
you don't have those on your on your
site maybe talk about the the reason why
and then also can you get into the blue
oyster mushroom straw log the living
mulch that you have on your site yeah
I'll talk about all of them because
whether you buy it from building soil
whether you're some part of the world
where you can't access build a soil I
want you to be able to tap into this and
so the idea with straw is a few fold
we'll be carrying like an organic wheat
straw that we use in the
um blue oyster straw logs and we're
shifting away from The Barley mainly
because any mulch works so I don't want
you to have to go look for something
specific I want to put that out there
but I'll tell you where the barley comes
from in case you're wondering why we
used to be so specific it used to be
that if you had a pond on your farm or
on your property and you wanted to
eliminate algae you would flow vote a
raft and the way you do it is take some
logs and you would tie a bale of barley
straw to it and you just float it out
there and the breakdown would cause an
enzyme release that would kill all of
the algae and make the pond healthy and
so we thought wow if we're going to
really risk chopping up stronger grow
maybe one that adds some benefit would
be of use but really it doesn't matter
any straw and here's the next thing
um be careful like if you just go down
the street or Craigslist and buy weed
free straw that's typically Roundup
spread that's why that's why it's no
weeds so we really just want something
that's like seeds are fine right you
just it's more cover crop especially in
a container Grill you can always just
pull the seeds if you mulch thick and
some seeds start to sprout you can just
take the whole layer of mulch and flip
it and now they're extinguished at least
you know on an outdoor farm you can just
use your pitch fork and flip them
um but the mulch so the straw mulch the
idea was is that we're covering the soil
keeping it moist underneath it blocking
the light allowing the worms to come up
to it and pull whatever top dressing
down and be happy and it works great
um the straw that we sell is more
affordable but it can be dry and so one
of my preferences for somebody that's
doing it
um by hand is to put it in a bucket and
pre-moist it a little bit then when you
place it it's really clean there's no
dust it's easy to do without making a
huge mess
um but oftentimes those are big chunks
and I would like chop it up so like
around around the edges of my container
to make it fit in there
um and then the blue oyster straw log
it's that's already all done and that's
part of the benefit
um I'll get in deeper because it'll take
a second to explain so people can follow
me but let me just go through the wood
mulch first and then we'll revisit so
wood mulch we used to carry there was a
local compost yard
I used to work with them when I first
started build a soil
um and he had a screening machine so he
would take his compost that took a year
or two to make and he would screen it
and all of the reject wood chips that
would kick out because they're slightly
too large for the screen they were full
of mycelium and they were beautiful and
so we would actually sell that as our
composted wooden bark mulch people loved
it but even when I used it I would
notice that that much Woody carbon it
didn't seem to break down into soil
nutrients as fast for a living soil
um but it attracted a lot of the
roly-polies
and those little guys although they seem
great and they are a benefit if you get
bark mulch and you get a proliferation
of them which they often come in the
bark
you can have a million of them and they
literally once they run out of stuff to
do or overpopulate they will start
climbing your plant they will start
stripping the stalks eating leaves
eating seedlings and this is what I talk
about with nature there's two sides to
it and oftentimes when you hear
something from Fear like oh thrip around
Clover you only get the one side and
nature is never that way and so there's
a great benefit to the wood mulch but
I'm trying to tell you the other side
that these beneficial insects that are
of benefit if a population outpaces any
predator I mean it's almost like you
need like to put some little birds in
there and eat them all or something like
it gets bad
um it's not good now I'm happy to report
it's pretty rare that you get an
overtaking of the roly-polies but that's
part of the reason why I don't recommend
wood a lot the other reason is people
ask a lot of questions and they used to
be like well is this wood allelopathic
and does it have chemicals that kill the
other tree that grows near it well that
ruined my soil you can't use cedar What
if I
basically from what I've learned
anything works is mulch but if you start
mixing it in the soil now you should be
asking questions about what type of bark
it is so um hopefully that helps or what
type of wood chip it is
other thoughts
um wood chips are used for a different
purpose than we use them for so when you
look up regenerative farming a lot of
times you'll you'll have conversations
about wood chips and the best I believe
are the rainial wood chips which are
very young trees
and when they're cleared out you have
very fresh more easily absorbable carbon
that's not so lignin that's not so hard
to decompose and you put it through a
chipper and you don't take the whole
tree just some branches right so you're
not killing a tree
but they would spread that on the
property
on soil that they were planning on using
in a year or two and that would enrich
the life and the fungus and at organic
matter and really improve the soil but
during that first year you can't really
grow in it the wood is so high carbon
all the microorganisms eat first and you
take all the nitrogen out the plants
can't really grow
another place you hear this is the hugel
culture beds if you've not heard of it
Google
h-u-g-e-l hugel culture and it's a
method of taking a whole bearing old
rotting wood and then building a mound
on top and growing that way but the
first year that wood does tend to rub
some nutrients
um so that's a thought but when stuff's
on top it doesn't really Rob nutrients
whether it's straw or mulch so don't
worry about that when you're looking
into mulching as long as it's on top
that's just a like a skin layer just
protects the organism of the soil
um now that was a lot but I really want
to talk about the blue oyster straw log
because it's a pretty simple connection
the straw that we would use it's great
but you'd have some wheat seeds growing
in it sometimes it's fine you just pluck
them
um also it's a little dry and so we had
a local mushroom farm that said hey I've
got straw maybe you could use it and
they wanted us to talk about making
compost from all their waste well I'm
not going to drive down there I don't
have the equip it wasn't it wasn't
conducive to me you know making the
compost for them or them doing it for us
but we decided to sell when they're done
growing blue oyster mushrooms they could
get another fruiting out of them but
economically once you've done one or two
cycles you don't get as much result on
the third fourth cycle so they would
just discard these bags that had straw
in it and the benefit there was the
straw had already been sterilized it
already been heated in water and made to
receive the mushroom mycelium and they
put these grain in there that have all
of the the blue oyster mushrooms they
were growing for Natural Grocers all
organic and it was inside there and they
had already grown the mushrooms and we
would just buy them used and so a
customer would cut it open put it on
their soil and sometimes another
mushroom would grow
and it was all moist and it was already
sterilized so you felt like you're not
introducing any pathogens but a couple
things would happen one they would turn
green from trichoderma it's of benefit
but it would scare some people
and then the second thing that really
put the icing on the cake is they went
out of business so I couldn't get them
anymore
um luckily man purse medicinals AKA
Kevin he works here
um he's a Mycologist and went to school
for science worked at it at like in a
white lab coat in a lab for a long time
I mean he has a whole background
and since his passion was mycology has a
flow Hood the whole deal he ran with it
and he immediately started making blue
oyster straw logs but instead of growing
mushrooms first we offer them to you
just like the mushroom farm would grow
and they are ready to fruit you can grow
mushrooms and eat all of them and
harvest pounds off of them and then
convert that to mulch or if you don't
want to grow the mushrooms the cost is
so good you can just cut it put it as
mulch and the main thing here is now
it's wet now it's sterilized and now
it's really clean mulch it's slightly
chopped up smaller to make sure the
mushrooms grow on it properly and so
when you use it you you get this like
mushroom Rich odor when you spread it
and here's one of the caveat one of the
benefits when we look at what it's made
out of so most of the earth is cellulose
that's one of the most abundant
materials out there so you think
cellulose is plant material you know
organic cell structure but the next one
that's most ubiquitous is chitin and
chitin we know activates some plant
defenses because chitin is what insects
are made of well it turns out mushrooms
are made of kind so when we get this
blue oyster straw log that's inoculated
with all this fungus and it's all white
and fully grown and you spread it out
you're inoculating your soil with kite
and Rich material which will allow those
building blocks to occur to build the
fungus that you'd like as well as maybe
activating some of that SAR or response
from the plant
um that we're after now I don't want to
say it does it I just want to say if
there's even a hype a lot thought if
there's just even a hypothetical benefit
it's worth research and so the chitin is
it's an interesting one it's spelled
c-h-i-t-i-n and we used to call it
chitin because we never heard somebody
say it out loud it's like you got to be
cheating me you know and no it turns out
chitin not chitin so that's pretty cool
I'm gonna have to pick up one of those
mushroom straw logs and try that out for
myself that sounds pretty cool it is and
it's one of those that's great because
Kevin gets to add the value a lot of
people use them for mushrooms get more
than their money's worth out of
mushrooms before they use it as mulch if
they have the discipline but it's fairly
hard to reproduce on your own you gotta
like sterilize boil water get the Grain
and so he really is adding a lot of
value by making it and I think that's a
true win-win you know so absolutely I do
have another mulch question well it kind
of relates to mulch not necessarily is
mulch but a lot of folks in order to
retain water and stuff when you guys
deal with the Earth boxes is just simply
cover the top of the soil and use a
piece of plastic so that um or some
people using cardboard board as well
they're cutting up pieces and then
putting it there but it's not actually
like breaking down like a mulch I guess
that's why you know I want to know if
you really want to consider it a true
malt but it's not really breaking down
what are your thoughts on like putting
cardboard on top
I think there's some benefit we did it
in one of our last YouTube series not to
live as the mulch but when I left town I
actually covered the recently decomposed
cover crop with the cardboard to keep
the light off of it and let the
organisms work it into soil when I
pulled the cardboard off you could I
mean the cover crop was gone it was all
so oil there's a couple little patches
but you'd work your hands in and it was
no longer six inches of plant it was
soil and so that cover is one of the
benefits of mulch if you're using
um you know a carbon Rich mulch or a
green manure mulch where you're chopping
the greens and mulching with it
those all have multiple benefits but
with multiple benefits comes some
responsibility like I said it's adding
nutrients it's decomposing and so a
simple cover removes all of the thought
of how long does it take to decompose
and is this good for my soil and it
simply covers it and cover is good
because the soil doesn't need to be hit
by the UV of the Sun and your your
lights and then the worms can come right
up to the soil surface and there's a
whole population of beneficials you
could peel the plastic back and see it
and I originally didn't like the idea of
the plastic because it's not as romantic
as I say it's not as like doesn't tug on
your heartstrings that Nature's not
always that way a lot of us think nature
and just to have all these views but
it's like nature can be pretty hardcore
you know it's a lot of like besides
Poison Ivy and animals killing each
other I mean it's not always all perfect
but when we're looking at covering it
versus the natural process at least you
get that covered and when it comes to
organic farming they use plastic a lot
now they get a really thick piece they
can reuse over and over it's not being
wasteful but when it comes to commercial
farming like if you picture a hundred
foot row
three feet wide full of lettuce or or
they're about to seed it and they have
to use machines to seed it so it's all
evenly done you can't just cover crop
and then run the seed machine so what
they would do is they would cover crop
and as soon as it got a few inches tall
they would use a machine to kind of just
lightly till it under or whip it under
the first layer so now it's buried by
the soil and then come pull that heavy
black plastic over and put rocks on it
wait a couple of weeks pull it all back
off and have unbelievable carbon rich
black beautiful soil that has been
freshly inoculated with all that that
mulch and then they plant into it so
using a cover is understanding how to
use a tool and and the earth box the
reason why we recommend that cover is we
have a lot of our customers that use
straw and cover crop in the earth box
and it works great
but the earth box is only about a cubic
foot of soil maybe a cubic foot and a
half plus the the water holding area
when you grow a big plant out of that it
can start to run out of nutrients and if
you have a regular mulch layer you can
only water through it but with the
plastic you can Mound and picture this
is the container the earth box wall and
your plant is in it you can mount three
four five six inches above the top with
compost and organic amendments
and the reason why this works is you
don't have to water on the top where the
water spills out the side you water down
below in the earth box and when you
cover that big mulch layer that's packed
as a mound with the plastic the feeder
Roots can go all the way up in it and
digest it and in the earth box normally
that much mulch material might be a
little rich but the earth box has clean
water so the roots can always access
water without nutrients to balance and
it seems to work really well so I like
the cover I just don't like it's as
appearance as much and I really do like
fresh straw with the green cover crop it
really is something like art I just it's
beautiful so yeah I've been using the
cardboard to cover on some of my recent
grows just I did have somebody comment
on one of my videos mentioning that
there's some concern that chemicals are
kind of that are on the actual cardboard
could get released into the soil and
those chemicals don't break down very
well and same thing with like the
plastic have you heard anything about
that is that say concern or what I would
say it's not a concern but I wanna I
wanna get there because their thoughts
are totally in the right place and you
should be concerned because most of the
industrial stuff is going to have some
problems with it but I would encourage
you to think of it as
a lot of these compounds the plant's not
going to take up like some people are
worried about some of the chemicals in
plastic I'm like I mean farmers use PVC
all day long to irrigate and none of
that actual material grows into the
plant but we don't want to hurt the soil
either and we want to be mindful but I
think if you go narrow focused on
something you can kind of get a little
too deep without missing the rest of the
opportunity composting by Nature
cleans it removes pathogens and
chemicals and it improves so that if I
was really going to be forced to use
something that was contaminated
composting it and then working it
through worms would give me the most
relief that at least we tried to
remediate and so when you're talking
cardboard that's mostly carbon
oftentimes it's either newspaper to a
worm bin or cardboard to a worm bin now
as a cover it's different but in a worm
bed people shred cardboard shred
newspaper they feed it to their worms
the worms don't die the worms go crazy
they eat it all but the thought is the
ink on the newspaper is a problem and
they're like it's chemicals well it's
soy based ink and it's not really a
problem the challenge I have is I don't
try and put Roundup sprayed soy that's
industrial and and my grow so I would
try to avoid it but the smarter side of
me knows that it's small amounts and the
microorganisms and the worms just rip
that to shreds as far as the actual
chemicals and what I mean is
if a chemical is in there composting
biology worms and their enzymes they can
actually take a chemical structure and
break it apart so that it's no longer
that dangerous chemical it's just the
carbon hydrogen it's just the individual
components that made something like that
it's structure
um and I won't say that you know you can
take something like a radioactive waste
and it'll be clean just because you have
some worms in there but my suspicion is
a small amount of cardboard when you see
the worms going in the grooves and
mating and the enzymes that are being
produced
I I find it very very very unlikely that
you'd have any sort of health problem
from doing that whether it's soil or
your own health and so I'm not a doctor
but I really think that you'd be fine
with some cardboard on top of your soil
but I also understand what they're
saying right some of these maybe the
glues got something in it that's a
little bit weird
um and so those are my thoughts on it
understood all right let's move on to a
viewer question so this one was actually
left in the comments section on the last
episode we did together and it relates
to pH in living soil so this viewer says
their tap Waters comes in at 8.9 pH and
after filtering it's still 8.5 pH should
they lower the pH of the water prior to
doing a soil drench if so what should
they use to lower the pH
it's a good question
um
pH and living soil has always been a big
like argument point and I'll give you a
little Spiel on soil pH
before we get into what this person
should do about their water
um because there's no one simple answer
I kind of relate it to jiu jitsu because
I grapple regularly and when you get an
answer from a white or blue belt it
might be an answer that would work but
you don't know if it works up to the
highest level
and you start to find when you ask a
black belt hey how do I get out of this
problem and then he just looks at you
and says don't don't get in that problem
you know and so it's kind of frustrating
but typically the smarter people I know
they don't have just a straight answer
it's kind of like it depends
so when we're talking about pH it really
does depend when you're on a farm and
you're growing out here in Colorado our
soil is pretty alkaline but if it's not
full of alkalinity and problematic
substances it's just full of calcium
it's amazing soil you don't really want
to lower the pH
and what I mean by that is the soil is
made up of these elements that dictate
the pH
same in our potting soils so when we
make a potting soil and we're adding
copious amounts of rock dust Clays and
composts we're attempting to mimic a
regular High organic matter soil and so
that's why we call it living soil not
potting soil potting soil is basically
hydroponic it's just a medium to hold
water
but when we get to the point where we're
designing it and we send it to the lab
you can see this percentage calcium
magnesium potassium all the different
things that are in it that's actually
what creates your soil pH
and so if you take some water and you
put a half gallon in there and it
doesn't just pour out the bottom like
you're not leaching the soil you're just
watering it the water isn't going to
change the pH of the soil unless you
strip out the calcium or add more
magnesium or dump sodium in it that's
what dictates the pH of the soil
and a lot of Growers they start reading
they're like wow plants can't take up
nutrients if the pH is off that must be
what's going on
well they also can't if you're over
watered so sometimes it's something else
that's that's causing the issue not
really the water but
um when you let's say you took perfectly
clean water and it was 7.0 pH it was
just Ro there's zero parts per million
in there
and someone tells you 5.5 pH is better
so you pH Down
I mean literally you're putting a little
bit of you're just adjusting the
hydrogen ever so slightly there's no
sodium in there there's no calcium
there's nothing that's really going to
change anything the soil will probably
change the water but what's interesting
is the soil pH is what dictates the
uptake of nutrients and the root in a
living soil grow can change the ph and
that two to three millimeter Zone uh
right around the root tip significantly
on on an exponential scale moving a
pointer to is like logarithmic it's like
much greater than it sounds and the
plant can do that so who are we fooling
if we're trying to predict the perfect
pH where the plant might be saying no
I'm trying to force the soil to be in
this range and you keep coming in and
changing it so being a steward means
trusting the soil but you can't trust
some soil that's full of salt I'm saying
a well-built soil the pH should totally
handle itself and you you just should
not have any concern of pH at all
but here's the curveball
when you're farming out here on this
alkaline soil
and you water with Ditch water that is
run off from all the other Farms by the
time it gets to you and it's high in
alkalinity not just pH and I know they
sound the same
but you can do more research on water
and I'm certainly not an expert I just
know enough to be dangerous that
alkalinity is actually the problem not
the pH it's that it's bicarbonate that's
in there and chlorides that's in there
and maybe some magnesium sodium that's
just jacking the ph and so you go water
with it and it's not like the high pH
water is the problem it's the fact that
we are already fairly alkaline and the
biology and your cover crop finally
released some calcium from the calcium
carbonate and the plant root is about to
access readily available calcium and the
water that comes in is full of carbonate
and binds up into calcium carbonate the
plant can't get it anymore so when the
biology is trying to do all this work
and our water stops IT and binds and
makes other chemicals and is constantly
causing issues pH is a concern and
what's interesting is that acidifying an
alkaline soil actually eliminates those
carbonates that are the problem not
really the ph and so now the calcium
stays available
and so I find it fascinating that
there's so much to learn about water and
I will say none of it matters when
you're on regular water it's when you
have well water ditch water things that
may have stuff in it that really messes
with your soil and can build up over
time it'd be very worthwhile to go to
Logan Labs out of Ohio go to
loganlabs.com
and go to their Water Analysis print out
a report call them whatever you got to
do and then you put the water in a
bottle you mail it to them and they give
you an analysis and they'll tell you
here's everything and even if you don't
know about a water test you can just
take the recommended numbers and compare
and see where you're high or low and
then make some guesses and then maybe do
some research
but um what's interesting about the the
person that you're saying asked the
question is they're on tap water it's
it's fairly rare to see such high pH out
of the tap because most municipalities
have rules for what will ruin the pipes
and what's good for humans and so I
wonder if that tap is connected to a
well and that's why it's it's really
well watered but it's his tap water in
which case you'd have to do a water test
because if that's just some minerals
that are you know non-problematic it
could be the heat is Waters with it it's
fine
um it used to be that the living soil
Growers would use AG cell 16h like every
watering even though it's not organic
but it's made from Sand so none of us
really cared
um but that's like 11 pH and when you
check your water after adding it's like
nine and people would water every time
and they'd be like this pH doesn't
matter
um and I think partially the The Mulch
layer and the volume of soil it could
definitely fix a lot of those issues
but in a smaller container with 9 pH if
it's full of a problem it'll it'll be
realized fairly quickly a big bed of
soil might buffer it so it's a non-issue
you can reverse osmosis that and a lot
of people say don't use Ro
I agree because it's wasteful it takes
part of the water and discards it and
it's slow and it's you know fairly
expensive but it does fix the water and
in living soil you don't like it'll work
just fine Ro is not going to hurt
anything it's just more like maybe not
the best way to do it
um so that's an answer without a soil
test you could just Ro it and you know
if it's sodium in there you're not going
to filter it you'll have to ro it and
then the sodium is gone and your plants
are going to grow like crazy in the
meantime if you're really worried you
can just go buy some water and use that
until you get your water tested it's
kind of a pain to Lug water around but
at least you know and if this was just
tap water it was 8 pH or something I
would just use it and and see you could
always buy water use it on some plants
and use your tap water in one and kind
of decide going forward
um but I I guess the gist of this is it
depends right there's no one right
answer for you and so I will say pH
should not matter but when you have
water that you know is problematic it
returns to the equine Asian and it's
important to have good water so do you
recommend checking the soil PH would
like either one of those blue lab probes
that go right into the medium or doing a
runoff pH test when growing what the
organic inputs yeah
um I mean it depends right if you know
nothing and you don't know where the
soil is from then you're just trying to
figure out a baseline maybe getting a
lot of measurements on it would be good
but for instance
I might have a high pH just from having
lots of calcium in there and the soil
not really being used in wet you probe
it and you're freshly potting up and it
reads a little high and you start
tinkering with adjusting the ph and you
mess something up
where a lot of times
you know you send it to the lab and it
might be a slightly high pH but you know
a lot of our crops like a higher pH
above neutral and it's fine and so we
shouldn't freak out living soil like I
mentioned the root tip and everything
has a way to buffer and so that enables
us to
take advantage of the buffering
qualities of the soil like in Hydro if
you're not exactly in the pH the
nutrient won't go into the plant but in
soil we have a lot of buffer room
um
and so I think that that does change
things a lot so how about EC or people
some people do PPM would you monitor
that I recommend people monitor that
when they're growing with Organic inputs
no I mean some outdoor Growers some
Growers do when they're making a lot of
um teas and solutions and I won't I'm
not going to say that you're trying to
Target some PPM some EC level but it
gives you some indication like if you
are a grower and you just fly to someone
else's farm for the first time and
you've used these tools you could go oh
the water's pretty clean it doesn't have
a lot in it I have my meters it tells me
what's going on and you might be able to
get up to speed faster but
um probing the soil PH like I said may
not really tell you as much in the sense
that a lot of people would test the
runoff and I'm like well they run off
man have nothing to do with what the
soil so we'd recommend a slurry test
and under those PH meters work but
um I kind of lost track when I was
talking the last time but when it comes
to the pH if you send your soil to a lab
and they tell you why
sometimes there's just a little bit too
too much magnesium in there and it Jacks
your pH but but it can be dealt with and
so just getting the pH reading on its
own although it might be valuable it
doesn't really tell you how to fix
anything and so now you're just going
whoa do I PH down my water not if it's
sodium in your soil that's causing the
high ph and sodium and magnesium can
just Jack your pH really high
um and so what we typically recommend is
if you're seeing a high pH in the soil
and you've tested it now you're
convinced that there's a problem you can
use a tablespoon of gypsum and a four or
five gallon bucket of water and you can
Leach that through the soil to there's
good amount of runoff and the sulfur
that's in the gypsum will rip the
excesses out of the soil and flush them
out and replace them with calcium and a
high pH soil that's high calcium crushes
a high pH soil that's got magnesium and
sodium and potassium which is terrible
so it's not always the ph and that's why
I recommend sending it to a lab so we
can see what built that pH what does it
consist of
but the EC and the PPM meters I know
some people that they're like wow this
recipe I make with the compost tea it
works so well every time they'll get a
reading and maybe next time they do it
they'll see if the reading is the same
and they'll start to share that as kind
of a baseline but right away you can see
some crazy readings in some of these
Organic Solutions and it doesn't really
mean that it's plant available and so um
in my daily life I don't use a phec any
of that pretty much ever so
yeah I've been pretty hands off ever
since I've been using organic inputs is
I haven't really needed to check the PPM
or the pH at all really
I mean there's people that test the pH
of their saliva and of their urine and
they try and eat foods that are more
alkaline causing to put themselves in a
healthy condition
I'd say 99 of those stop doing after a
few days and just eat healthy and decide
this whole thing's bullshitous food is
good food like why do I need to control
all of it you know I think that's when
we're looking for a shortcut like is
there one food that'll fix all the
problems that I have it's like no
alkaline food or healthy foods just
throw the chart away I need healthy
right let's move on to another topic
here I want to get your thoughts on
sugars so a lot of people are adding in
Molasses for example some people use
honey or brown sugar what's your overall
opinion on adding sugars in throughout
the growth cycle
you know um this is one I'm not an
expert on and I have my opinion and I'll
share it with you and it's based on you
know the last 10 years of build a soil
and previous to that just growing for
myself and
um I think a lot of it was Hydroponics
grow stores selling sweeteners that made
sense because you're like I want oozing
sweet resin and I want flavor and so it
just makes sense the human mind is like
oh yeah that'd be good I mean you'd hear
people adding Kool-Aid to their water to
get more grape flavor out of it you know
it's just like there's just so much out
there
um and a lot of it comes from the best
intention as far as our thought process
like even Flushing
I get flushing the medium but you're not
going to go pull a non-mobile nutrient
that's in an elemental form that it's
not it's plant and pull it out like a
straw
and so
um there's lots of considerations there
but um
yeah just
I have a hard time thinking that certain
sugars are going to make a difference so
let me bring it all back around glucose
fructose sucrose there's all these
different percentages and different
ingredients that you might add coconut
water is one of my favorites it's got a
good number of all of those but the
reason why we use the coconut is not
because of the sugar I mean it may be
one of the big benefits but it's because
we've researched the coconut and it's
human health impact and all the enzymes
that are in this big seed or droop and
the liquid that's in there has not yet
formed the coconut it's like the elixir
of life and it happens to be full of
sugars because biology sugars they need
I mean sugar is like the energy of the
sun when you look at the plant
and it's producing what we call root
exudates and it's feeding the soil it's
basically feeding liquid carbon which is
a sugar to the soil
and it's incredible but when we just
start dumping sugars in we may be
stimulating biological responses that
the plant wasn't looking for when it's
supposed to be in control of its sugar
production to the soil and so I
typically see people using sugars more
in a compost tea
and the goal of the compost tea
originally so you all know was that we
were not making a nutrient tea at all we
were trying to take microorganisms shake
them off of the compost by bubbling them
have enough air in there to stimulate
them to be alive and happy and give them
a food source that they could devour in
doing so you'd multiply billions of them
and if you did the timing just right
you've got the most diversity before all
of those strong ones ate the weak ones
and you'd pour that on your soil but the
goal with the sugar being used in the
compost tea was to fully
finish the sugar before you applied it
to the soil meaning the microorganisms
devoured it not the soil
and so sticking to that a lot of us
weren't like looking to just go dump
molasses on the soil it was more just a
compost tea thing
and molasses has been used for a long
time it's got other trace minerals in it
it's got some other benefits
um and the other thing that that came
out was a lot of the compost tea Brewers
from The Elaine Ingham crowd would say
you can't add molasses it's going to
feed the wrong microorganisms and then
you're going to hurt your plant I've
never seen that happen but I definitely
agree and understand that certain food
inputs might stimulate certain
populations of microbes versus others
but in my mind plants produce sugars and
so I don't think they can be bad just
throw the baby out with the bath water
personally I use a little coconut water
I would not be scared to add a molasses
occasionally but I would avoid adding
sugars all the time and I certainly
wouldn't buy a sugar that says pineapple
or banana or like some flavor that it's
going to impart I don't think that's a
benefit
um and then when you look at Molasses
like at the Growth Store oftentimes it's
the cheapest molasses because you can
feed it to animals they get beet
molasses they water it down so it's easy
to pour and they make a good margin if
you go to the grocery store and buy
organic molasses that's fairly expensive
in a little bottle so we carry a bulk
supply of organic sugar cane molasses
that's you know better quality but
um I don't think it's necessary I think
the plants are going to produce its own
sugars if you're growing cover crop
they're going to be putting sugars out
and using them in a compost tea great if
you'd like to experiment with it I think
one of the reasons why the coconut water
works as a finisher is because it's high
potassium not just that it's high sugar
and historically when it comes to like
nutrient growing not living soil you'd
start heavy and phosphorus and finish
strong in potassium and that's the
methodology even in knf that kind of
discuss some of these things so
maybe that's part of the benefit that
we're seeing right
um
I I hope that answers your question did
you you have like a specific it does
Point like the coast here
no I just wanted to get kind of your
overall thoughts on I've been using I
used to use molasses all the time and uh
I find myself using it less and less you
know really I've been just using the
build soil craft blend been using that
one cup per plant every 30 days and it's
been getting me through the growth so by
becoming more and more hands-off as the
years have gone on and molasses is one
of those things that have just have
stopped doing yeah and you don't need to
replace it with another cost and
um craft Planet it's funny because I'm
the same way I never thought I'd I like
any individual ingredients but you don't
have 20 big 50 pound bags at your house
and scooping out of all of them so the
craft one I'm the same way I take it
home I use it for most things but the
coconut water is probably my still last
sugar that I that I use but when I think
of it I don't think of sugar I just
think of freeze-dried liquid enzymatic
coconut you know but I can't put enzymes
on the label and me trying to test how
long the enzymes are alive and all this
stuff
um I mean early on there was a forum the
living organic soil forum and that was
through Afghanistan that we started
after I see mag closed and
um one of the arguments in there was how
can you guarantee enzymes in the Coconut
it dies immediately and we found white
papers that would show that it survived
but these white papers would keep it
Frozen the whole time
so I don't want people to think they're
guaranteed enzymes but the most direct
replacement for a sprouted seed tea
which we discussed would be coconut
water it's the seed it's the inside the
liquid that we're all after even human I
mean human health there's a million
articles on drinking coconut water for
human health and so it's basically a
human sprouted ziti like it and so you
can use that as well the problem is
people would go buy like harmless
harvest the best freshest coconut water
you're spending like eight dollars to
like spray your plants I mean so the
freeze-dried makes a lot more sense so
or if you live where there's coconuts
right that's even better I'll have to
try out the coconut water I haven't
tried that yet uh and if anybody's
wondering more about the craft blend we
actually talked about that in length in
the last episode so the previous episode
we did together will definitely be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below as well a couple more
things I want to get into before I let
you go here one of them I want to get
into is worms so worms is something I've
added into my garden I had the red
wigglers and European night crawlers I
know a lot of people use the African
nightcrawlers as well but talk to us
about incorporating worms into the
garden this goes back with our whole
theme right there's mulch we talked
about seed teas because of enzymes and
that natural process worms don't just
walk up to food and start eating it what
they do is they rub up next to it they
have a mucous membrane that exudes these
enzymes that are in response to the
material that it's next to so if you
make a worm bin and you fill it full of
maybe phosphorus Rich material you'll be
getting more phosphatase enzyme to break
that down once the enzyme does its job
the worm can then absorb through its gut
that material that's all bacteria broken
down and sludge now and then it can
improve and utilize it for its own life
and what comes out is actually usually
better than what started and so the
worms have unbelievable benefits now I
will put the caveat that they are an
Invader of the United States our forests
were built by fungi and the worms came I
believe down from Canada it could be
getting this all wrong but when they're
now in the forest layer they eat that
mulch too quickly and that's no good for
the trees because they're relying on it
for banks of years of nutrition and the
worms can just devour it so it's great
for us that are growing fast growing
annual plants because we want that
nutrition on tap and the worms are
phenomenal in our vegetable Greenhouse
when my wife just produces these rows of
tall Tomatoes all that's under there is
some craft blend and some nutrients and
the worms they go pull it down and they
bring it into the soil and make it
available to the plants it's like this
engine that produces this constant
nutrient Supply
and it's faster than just waiting for it
to decompose so worms are great we used
to recommend the worms the red ones and
the night crawlers I tend to lately just
prefer the red wigglers nightcrawlers
are fine our our thought process was the
red wiggler stamp top the night crawlers
go everywhere but now I kind of like
just I just like them in the top I don't
turn it all into a worm bin the red
wigglers stay more where the food is and
it seems to work really really well but
I'd imagine all of them are fine if you
go dig around your property and clay
soil you'll find earthworms that aren't
a composting type of worm and those may
not be of the same benefit because
they're more for compaction and things
they're not really going to break down
material as fast
um but I think the thing to take away is
that they're part of that enzymatic
puzzle they create enzymes they help
break down that organic matter that
lives in the mulch layer and that turns
into plant food the last question we get
is how many right that's the next
question how many do I
my my recommendation is that we want to
put less than you need let the worms
multiply to homeostasis where they're
happy and that size soil container you
have if you do the reverse and you say
above five are good or 100 are good I'll
put a whole pound I just bought online
in my one container and partially
because you're like what do I do with
the rest of the worms if I don't use the
whole pound we'll start a warm bit and
then you have a Perpetual Source but if
you put a pound of worms which is the
Thousand red wigglers on average into a
small container of soil you're going to
turn that into worm casting so fast the
worms are going to overpopulate start
ditching and climbing out dying and so
I'd rather not start with too many and
have them die into what's balanced I'd
rather start with even two 10 20 50 a
handful and let them multiply to what's
perfect for your soil so that's my
thought yeah I actually started a worm
bin year year and a half ago now and I
haven't looked back you know I free
worms I said well I made that one
investment right to get the worms to
begin but now you can just grab them
Wherever Whenever yeah you have a bunny
come over you're like yeah some worms
okay I'm from the worm bin and put him
into my pots whenever I want so yeah
definitely worth it in my opinion okay
so towards the end of the grow you
believe in a fade or senescence at the
end of the growth cycle right now do you
believe in leaching or flushing when
growing organically and let me Define
those two real quick because there's so
many definitions out there leaching
defined as not feeding any organic
inputs for the final few weeks of the
plant's life and flushing as defined as
running a large amount of water through
the medium in order to reduce the
nutrition to starve the plant should
Growers Leach or flush their soil at the
end of the growth cycle no I would
actually switch those two but what
you're saying is fine meaning when most
people say flush they're like in Hydro
they switch to no nutrients yeah
absolutely definitions right but
leaching traditionally means you're
leaching out your your gra everything
has to come out on a farm you leech you
don't flush but as long as we're clear
on what we're talking about I agree with
neither and what I mean by this is that
we worked really hard to build this soil
up and one of the benefits of living
soil is that you see the genetic
potential and the genetic potential what
I mean by that is it's going to
determine on its own when the end of its
life is and it's going to start to
senesce regardless whether it's
fertility in the soil or not
part of what may help this is some
colder temperatures slowing the biology
down and the release of nutrients
something we'll use cold water to do
that and that also stimulates some of
the colors and some of the mimicry of
Colder season coming into winter and to
the Harvest
but getting that runoff it's not going
to change anything
um it I think that the thought is that
you run it off so hard that your soil is
now devoid of nutrient and now the plant
must starve
but this is like saying someone who's 90
on their deathbed is going to eat all
your Thanksgiving dinner they don't even
like it's not even a thought the plant
is dying on its own it's gonna stop
taking food up okay I think you could
probably stop watering
the last week or two and a big bed of
soil it has plenty of water and it just
doesn't need as much now that it's
ripening it's done growing basically at
that point and you'll notice because in
Hydro if you pick the genetic and grew
it and maybe you weren't familiar with
exactly when it should be harvested at a
certain point you're going to say oh the
schedule says switch to flush well guess
what it's going to send a sense it's
going to start to fade because it has no
choice but when you're living soil I
like to give it that choice and it may
not start to fade on week seven or eight
it may fade on week 10 but it does it
and it does it because it's done and at
that point you know you've maxed out
your genetic potential you've gotten all
of the different terpenes and flavors
and everything that you want peaked out
and you're you're finished and so I do
like to see the fade I will see I see
say I see difference in some genetics
quadrant two in our YouTube series right
now I just took a video
um one's dark purple and leathery
looking and the other one's faded ye
lime yellow and green and so they both
senest in their own ways
but flushing would maybe take that
purple and tone it down just a bit like
running water through or just plain but
I don't think that's a benefit in living
soil and that turns me back to saying
like look at what's in the plant is
already in the plant pouring water on
the media is not going to change that
what it can do is if there's nothing in
the soil at all and you've prematurely
taken everything out of the soil because
you leached and flushed and all those
things
well now the plant is going to mobilize
nutrients from its Leaf anything mobile
into the bud it's going to use that as
food but guess what it's still eating
it's just it's just eating its own
leaves
um so I still feel like it's kind of a
viewpoint but um
I do say harvesting a dark green plant
early because it wasn't finished it's
not as good as a finished product
I'm not saying that it's because it was
faded but finishing that plant properly
whether it was a light fade or whether
it stayed somewhat perky green as long
as it showed you that it was finished I
get great great results out of the end
material
um and you know there's other tricks too
like tomatoes if you know it's getting
really cold you can actually just go cut
the top off of it and it'll force it to
finish fruiting faster so that you get
tomatoes before they freeze
all plants kind of have a reaction to
trying to produce and stay alive
finish their job and to come in there
and start to just dump water or pretend
like you have to flush I don't think
there's any reason to do so so well said
well Jeremy we have covered a ton of
different topics in such a short period
of time and I have a list of other
topics that we could get into so if you
guys want to see a part three maybe we
can drag him back for a part three
sometime this year maybe let us know
down in the comment section below also
list some questions you have for Jeremy
maybe I can go over those in the next
episode as well Jeremy tell the viewers
how they can find you and is there
anything upcoming in the future that you
want to talk about
um nothing right now our soil is the
best it's ever been it works
phenomenally well we've gotten more
quality control in the back end lots
more testing and I'm just happy that we
get to keep investing into this process
because it's making a better and better
product for a customer and I get to
experience the benefits of that as well
the way to find me is at buildersoil.com
we've got really great team of support
you can email support at buildersoil you
can live chat go to our Instagram the
main goal is that we want to provide the
best quality ingredients to empower you
and your grow and that has to come with
the education so you use them properly
and so you can check out our YouTube
channel as well which I know you've
mentioned but that's really everything
it's simple we're just trying to have
fun grow plants and as you turn this
into a hobby and you start to turn it
into a passion it turns into a lot of
questions and a lot of wonderment and a
lot of research and so um these episodes
like when you get to ask me questions
they're so much better than just some
FAQ where I read it aloud there's some
interaction and I think you you picked a
lot of topics that were really good like
in order so I think this is gonna be a
good episode I I really appreciate you
having me on yeah I appreciate you
coming on I'll definitely have a link to
Jeremy's YouTube channel down in the
YouTube description section below if you
enjoyed this episode click that Thumbs
Up Button also subscribe to the channel
if you haven't already every single
weekend I'm releasing a new guard dog
podcast episode and I'd love for you to
tune into future episodes Jeremy thanks
once again much appreciated hope you
enjoy the rest of your day awesome thank
you see you guys peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode