coming up on garden talk benefit of peat
moss is it's very acidic and to that
acidity we can load it with calcium
that's alkaline and that brings us to
the ph that we desire and that also
creates a situation where the plant has
access to a lot of calcium if you're
intelligent and building infrastructure
and assets that allow you to manage your
farm without buying it again every year
you can start to create profit margin
for yourself i do not want to to put it
lightly that if you're making soil and
you're counting on it the local compost
could be the thing that that bites you
so make sure that's good but what we
found
is that doubling your container size
usually increased your yield by about 60
for a living soil it was better to use
pumice and rice holes and that became
one of the standards for the base
even if you don't stop what you're doing
add one new thing and make some soil
from scratch get your own hands in there
i think you'll never go back if you try
it
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 51. in this
episode i interview jeremy silva he is
the owner of build soil and he has a
very deep knowledge when it comes to
organic gardening he talks all about
building a good soil the foundation he
also gets into the feedings of organic
inputs that happen throughout the
plant's life great information for those
of you who are just getting started in
organics thanks to all of you who
support this podcast or patreon if you'd
like to support you can do so by going
to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
big thanks to happy hydro for sponsoring
this video happy hydro now has complete
grow tent kits and many of the kits
actually come with my beginner grill
book the kits consist of ac infiniti
grow tents an ac infinity ventilation
system your choice of lighting whether
it be spider farmer hlg the green
sunshine company or grower's choice so
home living soil nutrients oscillating
fans and more i will leave a link to
happy hydro grow tank kits down in the
description section below and you can
use coupon code mr grow it for a
discount on their products
thanks to ac infiniti for sponsoring
this podcast they sent me over their
grow tent which has a canvas density of
2000 d making them the thickest grow
tent on the market today it has an
aluminum plate that mounts your
controller to the grow tent with the
light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has 50 thicker steel
poles and carries two times more weight
than the standard grow tents coupon code
mr growit will get you a discount on
their products and i'll leave a link to
their website down in the description
section below
and we are back
welcome to the garden talk podcast today
i am joined with jeremy silva from build
the soil how you doing today hey thanks
for having me on what's up guys
doing pretty good man doing pretty good
happy to have you on there's actually so
many people countless number of people
have commented on my videos and said get
jeremy on i think one of the comments
said you and jeremy together in an
episode would be magic
so
you know once i hear all these positive
comments about you i'm like let's see if
we'll come on you know maybe he'll come
on and uh spit some knowledge you know i
appreciate you asking that's how
everything works and when i said um
hello to you guys i should say hello to
you but i was also saying hello to
everyone and i appreciate them asking
for us to interact because
um unbeknownst to you dean who does our
video editing had pointed you out
immediately when we started youtube and
said this guy is professional he's
helping people and he's got a good
platform and
then to have you reach out i thought wow
how cool is that full circle
and um because of that respect it was
just a no-brainer for me to come on i
didn't feel like you were going to be
some
weird show that i hadn't heard of that
was uh not going to be good for business
or something and i also saw a big
opportunity you talk to a lot of people
that maybe you haven't heard from us yet
and so i look at as a big opportunity to
maybe share more of the message if that
makes sense
absolutely for sure i think one area
where you're clearly known for is
organic gardening and i really want this
episode to be i thought it'd be most
appropriate to have it getting into
organic gardening right so more
specifically i like to cover the
foundation building soil and i also want
to get into the organic feedings
throughout the plant's life but before
we get into all that things i like to do
with every guest is introduction so can
you tell us a little bit about yourself
and kind of how you got into gardening
yeah sure
my name is jeremy silva and i started
build a soil
almost 10 years ago it feels like more
than 10 years but it's kind of like
where's the day where it became official
and
i came into gardening
maybe differently than a lot of people
but i'm finding it's more of a normal
story i grew up in a cul-de-sac i grew
up where this was not normal
and so for me when i finally
saw it like my grandma had a vegetable
garden i was young so i didn't didn't
mean that much but when i moved to
colorado in 2009
it became something that i was
fascinated by and the fact that you
could just take a potato
dig a hole i mean
arguably you don't need to dig a hole
now that i've learned about no-till
gardening ruth stout she would just put
in the mulch but you could put one
potato and come back months later and
have a dozen potatoes and it's like
nature's 3d printing it's so abundant
and
i was also at that time um wanting to be
more positive wanted to create
a lack
maybe more stability by knowing hey at
least i can grow my own food
and i was also growing medicinal plants
and so it seemed like all of that came
together as sort of a gateway to turn me
into somebody who cared about gardening
and i never thought that i'd be like
yeah gardening
but it's been huge in my life and it's
taught me a ton besides
uh just about the result but there's a
lot that's affected me as far as the
process and the discipline and so
because of that
over a decade ago i was in a place where
i was looking for where my life was
headed i had a lot of changes that
happened when i moved to colorado
and i was working somewhere that i
wasn't really excited about and my
american dream was to have some small
internet business
that would allow me the freedom to
garden more and go disc golf and
snowboard and kind of live the life that
i've dreamed about and i had no family
at the time and so it wasn't a huge risk
but it was still really scary i went
into my job on a saturday with almost no
reason i'd thought about it and i quit
and i figured if i didn't do it i was
too comfortable i was going to wake up
it was going to be 40 years from now and
i'll be doing the same thing
and
it was hard but i made the decision
and everything worked out i had like a
propane tank that was hard to buy one
time a few things that happened in
between as part of the story but
eventually um i placed a few ads on
craigslist and people started buying
worm castings and then i was always
answering questions on the forums and
all of a sudden it turned a corner where
we had more orders than i could deal
with i had to start hiring employees
and it went from this little idea that
might pay for a couple bills to a huge
opportunity that
consumed a lot of my time and i had to
decide is this really what i want to do
and
it's been the best decision i've ever
made build a soil now has about 40
employees
and we have a vegetable farm and we
distribute to multiple countries as well
as all over the united states
and none of it would have been possible
had i not just made that
you know five second decision to walk in
and quit and say this is what i'd rather
do with my life and so
um that's pretty much the the story in a
nutshell if that helps
yeah absolutely i'm a customer of build
a soil i actually did a whole bunch of
stuff like a good haul during black
friday you guys have a crazy black
friday sale every year so i actually did
a haul and then actually did an unboxing
video to show my audience kind of what i
got from you guys
and people seem to really like that one
i know you were blasting out content on
instagram for a long time finally made
the switch to youtube
and things have blown up for you on
youtube channel i mean you got your
it's just so much good information you
have a 10 by 10 with all different quad
you know several different quadrants in
there different things going on you're
showing your audience how to grow
organically you know use your products
and do things in a sustainable way can
you talk to us just a little bit about
your youtube channel kind of what you
got going on there yeah definitely so
for those of you that don't know we have
a 10 by 10 grow tent and that came
serendipitously i had it at my house
i moved i no longer had space for it and
i decided well there's we're moving our
shipping area out of our retail store
and we're moving that into its own
building so i had the space in the tent
and i decided to throw it up
and man it was really nice to come into
work and have this oasis that i think
most people are looking for when they
set up a greenhouse they want to walk
into a jungle and have it be
um a little bit of peace in their life
and it was great and um we were already
documenting four by four grow tents and
the idea of sharing it in a walk-in
space became an idea and so we started
doing different methodologies we'd have
some customers that had raised beds we
had some customers that wanted to do
sub-irrigation or five-gallon containers
or small containers and we don't always
recommend it so the youtube channel
became a way for us to
prove it walk the walk show people that
these things actually work and for me
when i was learning that's all i paid
attention to there's a lot of
information a lot of people that want to
teach gardening that have never done it
but i've watched some videos and they
kind of teach what they feel should work
and that leads to a lot of problems so
it was unique i think to have a producer
that didn't sell just other people's
stuff and actually showed you how to use
it in a method where we could fail just
live in front of everybody usually you
see these girls start and then they just
don't update
right like ah it didn't go that well um
and that obviously put a ton of
responsibility on us to perform that's
what it should feel like like if you're
gardening for your family back in the
day and you didn't produce
that's a problem right and it doesn't
always go perfect so the 10 by 10 has
basically been just a display of that so
if you're interested check out the 10 by
10 we do
as you mentioned a different style in
each quadrant and we're about to start
the next 10 by 10 series um in the next
month we've got a little bit of
groundwork delay so
awesome i'll definitely have a link to
jeremy's youtube channel down in the
description section below and then if
you're on one of the podcast platforms
listening to this just search build a
soil on youtube and his channel will pop
up and you can check that out so we'll
do a lot more this year we've got the
vegetable farm where we've threatened to
document it and it's so much work we
don't usually take the time to but this
year we're going to be documenting a lot
of what we do on our vegetable farm
because
there's a lot of little tips and tricks
and we want to share it so i'm looking
forward to that this year i get advice
from you because i just started
vegetables well honestly just started
like three years ago you know what i
mean i got a little little something
going on you know with leafy greens and
stuff and yeah i i like to watch your
content there and get tips from you on
that so thanks for doing the vegetable
content you know yeah definitely
building soil let's get into it so
you're often recommending coot's mix you
know you give credit to him give credit
where credit is due he does the one to
one to one ratio so 33 3.33 percent
33.33 to 33.33 percent what do you say
33 33 33 moving forward but the first 33
is the base so sphagnum peat moss
coca-cola pit moss can you talk to us
about what those things are
pros and cons to them and which one you
generally recommend to use yeah
absolutely so
i've noticed there's a lot of confusion
with new gardeners about volumes they
get kind of straight like weird almost
like they're over thinking recipes so
the 33 33 33 the easiest way i think to
describe it is it's a three-part recipe
to make the base
one part of each ingredient that happens
to be 33
if you want to add another part you can
some people add some biochar or
something and they'll call it a
percentage but at the end of the day
where all these formulas came from were
based on what was available in size and
so if you're using peat moss we'd
usually go to the local supplier home
depot or something garden store they
have either a three cubic foot or more
commonly the 3.8 cubic foot of peat moss
and it's in a big bale and it's
compressed so you have to fluff it up
when the 3.8 was fluffed we found out by
just manually doing it by bucket most of
us found there's about six cubic feet of
material in there
and that's where we started the recipe
so one bale of canadian sphagnum peat
moss 3.8 cubic feet that would be
considered six cubic feet of peat moss
to that if that's one part we would then
add one
part of compost so six cubic feet of
compost
many people use worm castings and
compost but the base recipe is just at
least it has to be one part compost one
part peat and one part aeration
aeration
most people were familiar with perlite
it's the white little pebbles and all of
the miracle-gro soil in the fox farm
and on the on the forums what the guys
were doing that were making soil from
scratch
is they were trying to make a conscious
decision to be unique
choose a better ingredient if they could
and make it a more sustainable
ingredient if possible
and so people started questioning the
use of perlite we found out that
we can go deeper i could talk all day on
it but essentially instead of using that
for a living soil it was better to use
pumice and rice holes and that became
one of the standards for the base
so building your own recipe from scratch
one part peat moss
one part compost one part aeration a lot
of people use black lava rock red lava
rock there's pros and cons to all of
these and i'd be happy to go into a
little bit of detail there for you but
once you built the base
now the idea was how do we amend it how
do we add
minerals and nutrients that are going to
feed the soil and in consequence feed
the plant and how do we get it in some
sort of balance well before i took any
soil testing classes before i read any
books and before i understood
i would just blindly follow recipes i
found online and so how we found the
koots recipe was
a desire from the grow forms to document
side-by-sides which is still kind of
what build a soil does we just document
what we do
and i ran a recipe from afghanistan who
was in the farm at the time i ran
the true living organic style we ran the
sub cool style recipe
and then something was telling us to try
this coot's recipe because he was just
it was so simple right he only added
kelp neem crustacean and a mixture of
rock dust and calcium
every other recipe from the form was
like 30 ingredients you know guanos and
blood meals bone just everything in the
kitchen sink
and so i made the recipe and to honor it
i actually went up in the forest and got
some forest litter to make it really
alive and it was one of the best
experiences i'd ever had growing it was
the first time that every single plant
that i planted was all uniformly
healthy and it wasn't like one was
rented and stunted with
leaves that were you know curling and
twisted
and so that i think that connection
really brought us to want to share that
recipe with everybody and everybody who
uses it swears by it and i think all of
us eventually move on once we understand
to tinkering with what we want out of it
and i think that's what anybody should
do you get a recipe for the best meal
ever do exactly what the chef says and
then tinker it to your preferences
and the coots mix has been a really good
way to do that so
i noticed that you mentioned sphagnum
peat moss but you didn't really touch on
cocoa or pit moss is there something
like against it on a sustainable side of
things that you know prevents you from
from going towards cocoa or pitmas for
that base
um it's pure quality so every decision
we made at build a soil was to have the
best quality regardless now that we're
getting bigger as far as scale
we have multiple desires one is to have
a very sustainable recipe that is more
environmentally friendly and i'll
discuss the pros and cons of that
because we're a little hypocritical kind
of mixing soil bagging and shipping it
so sustainability is very important but
our goal when we started the recycled
logo as far as build a soil that's
because we all recycled soil we would
keep it
not necessarily that we were recycling
our ingredient to be the most
sustainable in the world but we all also
cared about
probably even more than the carbon
footprint the treatment ethically of the
animals
and not
giving our money to the monsanto
subsidiaries and so the desire to like
not use bone meal or not use a
particular ingredient oftentimes chem
came from who it was funding
and what those animals were fed like if
a cow is fed roundup sprayed crops
and then their waste is deemed approved
for organic use we said we don't want it
that's not good enough for us and so
when it came to peat moss we trusted
cute because he said that was the best
quality and when we did soil testing
eventually we found that when we made
the same recipe with coco coir it didn't
hold as much nutrients it's cation
exchange capacity its ability to
magnetically hold the nutrients was
lesser than
and that's a big benefit when it comes
to hydro because now you can flush it
out fairly easily and you can load it
back up with what it needs but in soil
that was one now arguably it's not
terribly different so you could still
make a great soil with coco coir but
coco core is mined on
it mind it is procured from islands and
other places far from here
and it is one of those crops that now
can be grown
non-organically
and those chemically grown coconuts can
be harvested and sold as organic cocoa
core because any waste from a farming
industry is deemed approved for organic
use so now you're questioning where
you're getting the cocoa core from and
depending on the continent or i'm sorry
depending on the location you get it
from it could be near the ocean and it
could be very salty
and in organics they don't buffer it
with the chemicals so a lot of the cocoa
core that you buy is already buffered
with
chilean nitrate or it's loaded with
different minerals to offset some of the
challenges that cocoa has and so an
organic soil company they can't just go
buy the pre-charged cocoa because it has
chemicals
and so then you have to use raw cocoa
and raw cocoa is a little bit more
neutral on the ph
and while ph isn't mentioned a lot when
we talk about organic growing it's
important it's just that the soil is
normally
the derivative of the ph not the water
so talking about it every day is not as
important right you can't change it like
you can change the hydro water that
dramatically changes the uptake of your
plant but cocoa core is a little more
neutral the benefit of
peat moss is it's very acidic
and to that acidity we can load it with
calcium that's alkaline and that brings
us to the ph that we desire
and that also creates a situation where
the plant has access to a lot of calcium
and it's now in the target ph where if
we're starting neutral already we have a
little bit less choices as far as how
many minerals we can load it with so
that was part of the concern
personally for me because i loved peat
moss made these recipes
the way we run build a soil is to teach
what we do and so for us to offer a coco
mix was disingenuous
and now we're only getting the point
where we've had a lot of customers
request it we have data on it we know
that it works we're considering
releasing a coco version we also have
some wood fibers in the past they were
very alkaline and they were more like a
money saver but there's a couple of
products in the market that are very
acidic made from wood and they're very
sustainable because they grow very young
trees and they harvest them into a wood
pulp that's more like peat moss but
those are robbed nitrogen so you can
only use a percentage so the most
straightforward for the home gardener is
to use peat moss and then what happens
is
occasionally they'll go in a gardening
form and they'll tell them peat moss is
ruining the world and so then they go oh
i don't want to do that i'd rather use
coco coir or whatever so now the burden
of knowledge is that cocoa is freighted
in using fossil fuel on big tankers that
are locked up because of trade war
issues and coming from other countries
and that's volatile and then when you
get it it may be salty maybe not maybe
there's some it's not as straightforward
where peat moss
overseas across the pond they burn it
for energy and they have very small
amounts of peat moss so using it is not
sustainable
where here in the united states we get
it from canada and the canadian peat
moss association has a very tight lock
to the point where i can only get so
much allocation of peat because they
only mine so much and it restricts what
we can produce last year we made about
10 000 cubic yards of soil and we're
slated to go to over 20 000 cubic yards
of soil this year
peat moss is going to be a real issue
for us as far as availability but as far
as hurting the earth that availability
is capped because the canadian
government won't let them mine it in a
non-sustainable fashion and so obviously
it's not the greatest to go dig up
portions of our earth but
the peat moss is arguably less of an
environmental impact than the cocoa core
depending on how you look at it
and either way none of them are
sustainable as making your own on-farm
product and so ways to do that that koot
talked about back in the day would be to
make your own leaf mold you rake the
leaves in your yard you put them in a
black trash bag and let them sit there
for a year and they turn into black leaf
mold compost which would be a good
suitable replacement for peat moss
and then the other alternative
would be to we've considered this to
build a soil we're still looking into
the numbers but setting up a worm farm
that only recycles cardboard and paper
and that way you have kind of a new a
lesser nutrition worm casting that could
act like a
peat moss if you will
but pmos is ancient
and it has a lot of benefits and it has
biology and it makes a very very good
soil so i hope that sharing this data
with you at least will let you know no
matter how you make potting soil kind of
a hypocrite as far as sustainability the
better answer is
we keep our soil we don't throw in the
trash so once you make this it could be
a lifetime that you're keeping the soil
that should ease in the burden a little
bit
the old way was just to literally throw
the soil away every single time and get
new soil and the whole idea was well
um we don't want to
make a mistake so just throw it away buy
new soil and as long as the profit was
there it didn't matter now we're all
wanting to make sure that we're
more sustainable but also
the profit margin is pretty tough in
farming so we can't just all afford to
throw everything away we've got to be
intelligent one of the ways that
organic farming can win is that it has
ways if you're intelligent and building
infrastructure and assets that allow you
to manage your farm without buying it
again every year you can start to create
profit margin for yourself
while improving the land so
we use peat moss
and there's also pit moss which you
mentioned
we just found that it doesn't produce as
quality of the soil i really like the
idea of using it it's lightweight for
like hanging flower baskets there's huge
benefits to using it but it essentially
looks like it looks like
you took shredded newspaper or shredded
paper from your literally from your
paper shredder
because of that it's off-putting like
there's ink on it you can see
and i'm sure it's soy-based ink so it's
not bad for potting soil but
it doesn't scream the highest top shelf
quality it streams recycled and so we're
wanting to work more with pet moss but
the blends that we've made rob so much
nitrogen that now we need to offset that
and it's not quite as sustainable in
that regard
but
the future is that build as well is
going to be putting a lot of research
into the wood pulp the cocoa core
and the pit moss to find recipes that we
can use different percentages of these
not to be so dependent on peat moss so
hope that answers your question
lots of good information there for sure
so your first 33 base next 33 you
mentioned compost or some people use
worm castings now there are several
different types of of compost right
which one do you generally recommend and
are there any that should be avoided
yeah this is a difficult question
and this is what's kept organics
out of the mainstream for a long time
what i mean by that is if you're in
california and you're on the grow forum
and you're talking to a guy in florida
you can tell him use this nutrient use
ro water ph it and use this cocoa core
or this rock wool or this bucket of deep
water culture and they can produce
ideally basically exactly the same as
what you're producing
and then you can have an intelligent
conversation back and forth about the
differences
the environment might be slightly
different but you can game that right
acs and humidifiers and everything so
now we literally created the duplicated
to grow environment in organics as best
as we could do is say we'll find some
local compost
now the guy in california in florida are
having night and day different
conversations and they're trying to help
each other out and have no idea how to
do it
so compost quality is of paramount
importance and that's what kept a lot of
people away from making their own soil
they would go find some compost on
craigslist they'd make a potting soil
follow the coots recipe and all their
plants would die
so there's a few things to consider one
you can find local compost and a great
way to test it is put a plant into it
you can mix it down in your soil recipe
at a 33 recipe
you could go a little lower and you
could put three or four containers one
with ten percent one of thirty percent
one with twenty percent just see how
they do
um within a week you're going to know a
lot more than had you not done that
however
a lot of times if you find a big compost
yard they should have a lab test on it
they can share it with you
what i've found is most these yards do
not know what their own compost test
means and so they share it with you and
they just hope you don't either and then
everybody goes well it's tested i should
use it and then they buy it and it
doesn't work and they go oh no i bought
it was tested
we'll test it for what it's typically
like the local compost for instance
there's so much compost around me i
would love to use it all because then i
wouldn't be paying freight on better
compost
but when you get it tested lab it has
potassium that is maybe 10 times the
phosphorous level and sodium that
matches it so
it's alkaline and it's full of stuff
that we're trying to keep out of our
soil recipe so if you use any more than
five or ten percent
like the 33 we're suggesting it'll just
fry your plants
that's what unfortunately a lot of
municipal compost is so if you're
fortunate enough where you have a
gardening club locally or you have
people that are active like michigan
california there's a lot of states that
do have some premium inputs you're gonna
have to go by word of mouth like who's
got the best compost that everybody
knows about is the goods then from there
you can probably trust it a lot better
and that's how gardening's always been
done you trust the recommendations
you're given you find the guys got the
good plants the good nursery the good
soil
what build a soil did to build a
business is used testing and data to
take some of that guessing out so we
have to trust we can verify
and so i would recommend you learn a
little bit about that you can always do
a test on your compost um if you're
commercial and you're looking to buy
compost i would test it before i buy it
if you're just a home gardener you can
read the test that they have and maybe
understand it better and we could do a
whole episode just on that
but one of the things you can do is
typically worm castings is a safer bet
worm casting will reduce the problems
and what i mean by that is if it's
locally made compost from people just
dumping green waste and they compost it
it could have some residual herbicides
in it and the compost may be too young
it could have dewormer from manures
where once the worms have worked it even
if that was originally in there it's
usually ripped to treads
and the biology and enzymes
make it safer it's one of the magic of
the worm so i find a lot of people use
worm castings in their recipes because
it seems to be less
wild as far as quality and then here's
the other weird thing that happens when
you go to a large-scale worm casting
producer they typically make a
casting that is not
it's not very rich in material and
nutrient it's so quickly made
which means that it's unlikely to cause
a problem in your soil recipe so worm
castings often is the default
for a long time people would just guess
and do 50 50. so for their one part
33.33 of compost
they would go half compost half worm
castings and they'd make their recipe
all i'm going to leave you with is that
if you're going to get compost and
you've never heard of the brand before
like we recommend malibu and ollie
mountain not because they're the best in
the world but because they've been
proven to be standardized so you can
make a recipe at known percentages and
it will
duplicate what we're experiencing
and that works really really well but if
you don't have access to that
when i was on the forums historically
coast of maine was a great brand on the
east coast malibu and oldie mountain was
good on the on the west coast and if you
couldn't find those what you would do is
just reach out online and go through
what i mentioned
just growing a plant in it i mean if you
put a tomato plant straight compost then
it grows you're probably fine
if you dilute it percentages and it does
well maybe you found something great
so i guess what i'm trying to say is you
don't always need a lab i don't want to
paint this picture that you have to be a
scientist to grow organically but i do
not want to to put it lightly that if
you're making soil and you're counting
on it
the local compost could be the thing
that that bites you so make sure that's
good
okay and then the last 33 is aeration
and there are several options for that
you already talked about some perlite
rice holes lava rock pumice biochar
right can you talk to us get a little
bit more details in regards to some of
those things kind of you know their
benefits if anything should be avoided
or be aware of yeah let's talk about it
so aeration
originally what we did on the forums is
we would look for something more natural
than perlite the reason was we found
that perlite was obsidian which is not
an unlimited source it's like a black
beautiful rock
and they mine it and then what they do
is they run it through a factory with a
lot of energy
and that puffs it like popcorn and so it
expands and that's what you see is the
white very lightweight material now if
you understand that most the products we
buy on the shelves are are basically
we're paying for the freight
like if you go to a grocery store most
of the cost of that didn't go to the
farmer it went in the freight getting it
there and then we try and put as much on
one truck as possible so freight
ends up being the biggest portion of
what we pay as far as a hidden tax and
when it comes to soil it is a lost
leader at a lot of hydro stores and it's
heavy and it's hard to get it there they
have to buy a whole pallet at a time to
justify the freight so perlite is like a
game changer when they started adding
perlite not only is it really fluffy for
the cells starting off thousands of
seeds in the in these commercial
greenhouses
and light weight to send all the starts
to home depot for everybody's garden but
it's also a whole bag of soil is pretty
light you can sell two three cubic foot
in one bag throw it over your shoulder
because it's peat moss and it's perlite
well the idea in living soil was we
wanted to keep the soil forever
so that's why we started using larger
volumes but we also looked at the
aeration and when you keep soil around
forever the perlite starts to break down
right away the powder and it starts to
float up to the top of your recipe when
you're watering
and it doesn't lend itself to keeping
without impaction over a long period of
time so we were wishing to get away from
that
for a number of reasons not sustainable
not really a real mineral like it was
puffed up
even though arguably it holds a lot of
air like it has some huge benefits to
soil
but what started to come out in the
forums was lava rock is very porous it's
a microbial condo it's made from the
minerals and where are good where's good
food made in the world hawaii pacific
northwest anywhere where volcanic
activity created really abundantly
mineral rich soils so we thought oh
we're using lava rock and we started
buying lava rock and the red one is more
iron rich and the black one might be
more rich i'm not positive but
potentially manganese but at least less
iron and so we were playing with recipes
there and it makes a pretty good soil
but i will tell you the lava rock it's
heavy and it's not quite as good at
being an aeration amendment more than
just a drainage it doesn't hold as much
oxygen in the soil
now it works and it works well but the
learning curve from building a soil like
if you were to just go to a healthy
organic farm
dig out their black rich soil and put it
in a pot and try and grow
and now in a container
that container the biggest challenge
even though it might test well is the
physical characteristics will make it
almost impossible to to keep the air and
the water in there
enough to make the plant grow it's just
going to be over water right away it's
going to get stagnant in areas
that's why potting soil
is mimicking the native soil but to be
in a container it has to be different so
we we put some lava rock in a bucket of
water and it would sink we did some
character we did like some research on
the porosity and pumice it floats in
water it's closer to what perlite does
but it's real in the sense that it's
just mined from the earth people use it
in other industries so there's a lot of
data like they use it in the beauty
industry for foot you know lotions and
scrubs and all sorts of stuff to be uh
to help with skin
and because of that there's lots of
testing done on it to make sure it's
safe so it's really logical to go that
direction
also people build water filters with
like biochar and pumice and all sorts of
weird things so pumice became a go-to
it's lighter weight which means it
didn't ruin the freight
and it held air and it's a good
microbial condo which we need the
bacteria to live in all those little
space
it has so much surface area a lot can
happen there and then from there we
thought well rice holes they use because
it's lightweight and it replaces perlite
because it adds drainage the reason why
is it's made of silica and so all the
growers on the forums were like man
we're all buying silica that'd be great
if we could just put some rice holes in
there and add silica
and what kept us from using 100 rice
holes was the fact we wanted to keep
soil forever so you're thinking well if
i no-till the soil and the rice holes
are eaten by the worms over the first
year or two and they're gone where's my
aeration
so the goal was okay of the 33 aeration
let's use like 10 or 15 percent of that
as rice holes so worst case we still
have a lot of pumice in there best case
we get some fluff out of the rice holes
and we get some long-term silica
so that was it and people started saying
you know what i'll do whatever i have
pumice rice holes i'll use 100 of one 50
50 didn't matter as long as i used it as
one third of my recipe now i will tell
you you can use less compost some of our
best recipes are closer to 20 compost
they tend to they they tend to balance
out
much better and then you can add
minerals and amendments more pointedly
to your recipe so the old coots recipe
at 33
that's because he made his own
vermicompost with his own amendments in
it he was done at that point a lot of us
when we're unsure of the quality of
compost we're adding more to that
so
sometimes all you have to do is reduce
the percentage a little bit and add
maybe a little more aeration and a
little more
peat moss and you can make a spicier
compost work very very well and what's
easy about organics is
if you didn't overdo it you can always
come back later and brew a tea or top
dress and give it more later so kind of
like an athlete can only eat so much
protein at one time we can only front
load our soil with so much nutrients at
once before we upset the balance
eventually if this is sustainable we're
going to have to come in and
intelligently add more as we go so
that became the goal
other things variation you mentioned
biochar
biochar holds about 10 times its weight
in water
and so because of that i try not to
categorize it as aeration because if
someone used 33 of that
instead of one of the others it could
cause a catastrophe it's very carbon
rich one of the things you can learn
about organics is that carbon is very
important it feeds the biology that then
breaks down and makes the nutrients
available to the plant but
too much carbon can rob nitrogen
and that can upset the balance and so
there's this carbon to nitrogen ratio
that makes good compost and just front
loading your soil with too much biochar
can be a problem so good rule of thumb
if you're not familiar with the biochars
to use maybe maximum five percent
there's definitely times you can use
more but without knowing for sure i
would just say it's all one-third make
my base and you can add an extra
percentage of biochar to that
but i i more consider the aeration to be
pumice
perlite and rice holes or lava rock
those are the four main now some people
have used pea gravel some people
literally take hydrotin the clay balls
from their old hydroponic grow and they
go well i don't want to waste them i'm
going to put that as an aeration
it kind of works as a drainage as taking
up space in your recipe but it's the
hydrogen clay is so smooth there's no
porosity there
and in our experience it just doesn't
work very well so
um take that for what it's worth about
for vermiculite
vermiculite is something that we don't
use here but it is of benefit and part
of the reasons why is i just want my
crew breathing and dealing with it like
eliminating perlite vermiculite is
fantastic for the crew the air quality
is already bad enough one of our goals
for 2022 is to improve the air quality
in our soil mixing building that we just
built
and so keeping some of those ingredients
out is always a benefit but vermiculite
has a very high cec
it's very lightweight and people use it
to hold water so it becomes more like
biochar in that sense so for instance
let's say you're a producer and you're
going to have 100 000 little seedlings
that you're starting and you're going to
sell them to home depot eventually
if you're growing something that is it
needs to be dry
you would want to do their peat moss
perlite recipe because you could water
every day and it would just dry out if
you're wanting something to hold some
moisture for a little while so you can
lower the irrigation and this and the
plants you're growing don't mind being a
little more moist or they prefer it
you're going to get the recipe with a
little more vermiculite in it
so from a soil building perspective it
has textural qualities as far as holding
more moisture
but the one reason why i would consider
adding it to a recipe right now the way
build a swell does it is it has a very
high cec
and so the the difference in potting
soil
is that potting soil
while it has cation exchange
it's not really used it's not really the
same in soil the cad exchange is based
off of clay
minerals that have broken down in the
organic matter for thousands of years so
it's very very real to base your whole
farm off that map but a potting soil
that math is more like a gut check it's
not as accurate
so we haven't ventured to the
vermiculite but if we wanted more
nutrient holding capability biochar
vermiculite
things like that can potentially hold
more in your recipe if that makes sense
okay
and then after you have your 33 33 33
mix organic amendments should be added
as well so microbes will work to break
down those organic amendments turn them
into nutrients that they
take i've been using the build of soil
craft blend the past several grows and
my plants love it
what are the options for initial
amendments that could be added to the 33
33 33 mix
so i'll go over what kutz recommends and
i'll also give you some rules of thumb
to go by so that you're not blindly
following my recipe a lot of this was
based on steve solomon so steve solomon
the intelligent gardener's got a great
book he's in tasmania i was talking to
him right at the onset of covet and
he's just been a very he's been
inspirational to me and been willing to
take my phone calls and so i'm always
asking him questions about some of this
stuff and he had this three-way line mix
that he used and it was like dolmat lime
agricultural lime and gypsum or
something like that and so coot
referenced the three-way lime mix but he
always wanted to add uh glacial rock
dust and eventually change that to be
basalt and that's because it's a
volcanic rock dust so
coot's recipe was hey if soil is made of
rock dust ground up in organic matter
that's what he wanted to duplicate
so the rule of thumb for the coot's
recipe across the board was a half a cup
of each one of your nutrients you're
adding per cubic foot
a cubic foot came to be known as about
seven and a half gallons if you look
online
its mathematic formula is anywhere from
6.8 to 7.5
depending on and what i mean by that is
you can fill a perfect 12 inch by 12
inch by 12 inch box you can make it
exactly one cubic foot you can fill it
perfectly with peat moss and call it one
cubic foot but then you can just press
it down with your hands and now is that
really a cubic foot or is there room for
more
so we use seven and a half gallons for a
cubic foot
and if you add a half cubic foot of each
one of your amendments you should be
safe
maximum that we like to see is up to
three cups
the koots recipe is only one and a half
cups of nutrients you can always add
more later i think less is more and
that's the way to go
then on the mineral side you could add
up to about a cup or two of your
favorite mineral totaling no more than
four to six cups of minerals four cups
of minerals per cubic foot is the koots
recipe half of it two of those is rock
dust
most people would mix some glacial and
some basalt or you just use all basalt
the other two was a mixture of your
calciums very very important number one
mineral for plant growth is calcium
calcium calcium it's everything so
he would usually add oyster shell flour
and that was the calcium side
or an ag lime or a mixture of the two so
that's what we started doing we would
mix in two cups of basalt
uh one cup of some oyster shell flour
and one cup of some gypsum and funny
story when i first started this i didn't
know there was a difference between rock
dust
and he was encouraging me to buy local
so i messaged and i said all i could
find was calcium sulfate and and they
can't even sell it at the local farm
store so they told me it's going to be
like 50 cents a bag they were 50 pound
bags
i was blown away so i bought a whole
bunch of them brought them home and i
used that four cups of gypsum
solely as my rock dust and it was one of
the better recipes i'd ever made
so that's when i learned that overdoing
calcium especially gypsum was not
necessarily a bad thing
but to round it out
we wanted the coot's recipe specifically
one and a half cups of amendments four
cups of minerals
and so what i'm
telling you is like if if you have
alfalfa meal
you could add a half cup of that to this
recipe and it would be fine
but his recipe is one half cup kelp meal
one half cup crustacean meal and one
half cup neem or karanja better yet a
mixture of the two
that's the fertilizer
and if you learn about it a a neem or
karanja that's a seed from a tree so
that's a seed meal soy is another seed
cotton is another seed the reason why we
don't use soy or cotton is they're the
most gmo pesticide sprayed products
around the world and then they're
totally approved for organic use and so
you could be growing in roundup without
even knowing it
that's part of the reasons why we avoid
some of those and the karanja is a
nitrogen fixing tree
it's an um it's good for the earth okay
and it's very clean on heavy metals and
everything else so adding that in as
your seed meal that's great
the kelp meals for all the
micronutrients the entire periodic table
comes from the ocean and the kelp has
hormones because it grows
it grows feet in a day it is one of the
fastest growing plants so kelp
big reason all the trace minerals all
the magic from the ocean neem or coronda
a seed meal that's where the protein is
going to come from that's like if you're
vegan or a vegetarian you need the
protein from the nuts and the seeds and
all that not just from the from the
lettuce there's none in there
then the last one was crustacean meal
and crustacean means a mixture of like
shrimp or crab
the reason why coot recommended that was
very simple it was calcium carbon it was
loaded in calcium it had some protein
from the leftover meat that might have
been in the crustacean right had some
phosphorus but really it had this
advantage also that the shells are made
out of chitin
and if you don't know chitin is the
second most abundant substance on the
earth first is cellulose next is chitin
chitin i used to call chitten i have no
idea what it was c h c-h-i-t-i-n
uh you gotta be chittenden we used to
joke until we learned it was chitin
wasn't as funny then
but chitin is something that plants have
come to use
potentially activating their systemic
acquired response their sar their in
their defense system kind of like when
we talk about having an immune system
and the reason why is insects are also
made of chitin so it would i i guess it
would make sense that if titan's around
maybe that means insects are around and
there's some sort of defense response
there but there's benefit and we knew
that so his recipe was simple but
arguably not simple in his choice for
why
so to keep it basic
half cup of crustacean meal half cup of
kelp meal half cup of neem cake or neem
seed meal it's the same thing just words
that's one and a half cups of total
amendments per cubic foot a lot of
people just doubled that thinking
ah if that's good twice as good
but what we learned since is that kelp
less is more it has arsenic in it it has
lots of trace minerals in it it's better
to keep that one at a lower level you
could double the others if you'd like if
you know you have a really nutrient
hungry plant
one of the other things that a lot of
people did is they would add their
favorite extra they would copy the koots
recipe and then say you know what i'm
going to add a half cup alfalfa and i'm
going to add a maybe a half cup of fish
bone meal or guano or whatever their
their favorite thing was that they
couldn't not use
and in that way the koots recipe is
really the
the infinity base recipe that everybody
uses and then soups up according to
their own needs like if you're going to
go to really small containers you might
up the nutrients a bit and top dress if
you're going in huge containers you
might just keep it standard if you have
a local compost you might lower the
percentage but it was such a working
model i think it's what took off like
wildfire out there for people to just
trust that they can make a soil from
scratch that would actually work right i
mean when you're
making something from a recipe online
like for food
typically you want at least one review
saying hey this didn't taste awful it
did work and then you go okay cool i'll
try the recipe that's what happened
everybody had success in the kudz recipe
so
i have to ask like i mentioned i use
build a soil craft blend right and i
swear and you probably know this 24 to
48 hours after watering it in is like
this putrid smell like the smell is just
i thought somebody was dead in the room
or something at one point
what is that horrible smell so after
your top dress because i don't get any
odor out of it no i know the water in it
if it gets wet or if i brew it right
yeah you water it
so typically what i do though is i i
wiggle it into my mulch layer now it's
covered in worm castings and mulch and
so the odor just typically can't be a
thing but um what it is is there's
crustacean meal and if you ever smell
some old crab i mean get pretty gnar
when it's breaking down right and
biology that's of decay is what's going
to make those nutrients available
there's also fish meal there's fish bone
meal in there um and then there's
camellina meal and it's a weird one
because it's a wild flax and it's kind
of like mustard in the sense that it
smells
unique and it's got like this
the oil that's in it because they don't
de-oil it first it's almost like
like linseed oil or something like it
has like a turpentine like it has a
weird odor and so you can block you
combine the protein it's rich in protein
that wants to kick off that fermentation
you've got neem in there which smells
like garlic mushroom gnar like it's just
weird mean cake is gnarly if you're not
used to it smells gross
and you combine that with like the ocean
stuff and then you get it wet and we did
not build this to be a potpourri of good
smells we built it solely with the
intent of making a diverse
fix-it mix if you will uh uh what can i
add to my soil without having to guess
every time
and the craft one actually came from a
buddies last name's craft we didn't call
it craft because it was crafted his last
name is craft and he grew a lot of
plants and he's like bro can you just
mix all that together so i don't
have to do it and be a good seller and
it's one of our best-selling products
and what i did do is i took his idea and
instead of just blindly mixing it
together i measured the npk of all of
them put them equal by weight and then i
did some testing to make sure p was
above k and it actually made some sense
from a soil testing background
and it's our favorite product we use it
on the vegetable farm because
i mean for us to get
two bags of fish meal two bags of kelp
it's just there's a lot then the mice
can get into it then you have to unroll
the bags so bringing a tote of craftland
to the farm it's just all in one scoop
and now we can tell anybody that works
on the farm if you're doing a bed grab
one big scoop 18 pounds and amend the
bed with it and if it's a
longer season crop we can say do double
and it makes it easy and so then all of
a sudden growers were telling us even
before we knew it was going to be
popular that it was their favorite
product and so when you're researching
amendments we mentioned a half cup of
each
no more than three cups
the craft one gets confusing because
there's minerals in there as well so i'd
recommend most people have kind of
followed our recipe that's on the bag
there what to use
but
um you can go a little above like if you
take three cups of nutrients and the
four cups of minerals per cubic foot
that's about seven combined cups
i would say be less than that with the
craft blend because it's not as high a
percentage of minerals as if you made
the coots mix from scratch and because
of that we use craft blend as our
supplementary meaning
we'll make soil according to the recipes
and then craft blend will now from now
on be the amendment to because we've
already front loaded with so much
minerals the minerals don't necessarily
go anywhere and like the basalt is not
going to disappear in the first cycle
so now the craft blend becomes in a
great addition but where craftlin came
from if you look up steve solomon he
would teach you how to make an organic
fertilizer mix
and he would recommend that you added
something with phosphorus
something that had the seed meal
and he would also add something that had
like the kelp or alfalfa like to have
the trace minerals and so it was a way
to construct a complete recipe if you
weren't just
buying something off the shelf
that's where craft blend came from
and the immediate reaction growers get
is because it also has some calcium and
some magnesium in it which you all know
if you're in hydro it's like cow mag
will fix a lot of things right and so
immediately when they're watered in or
top dress
before the biology even has a chance to
break some stuff down they're getting
some mineral release right away which is
very helpful oftentimes
um
yeah craft blend is one of my favorites
so thanks for bringing it up yeah it
makes it really really easy i mean you
mentioned what you could do for initial
amendments but you could just do the
craft blend right if you want to keep it
simple just you absolutely can now
here's the thing when i used to go to
the garden store and try and buy like a
pre-blended organic you know there's a
lot of companies that have individuals
like you could go buy alfalfa or you
could go buy fish bone meal but when i
got to the blends i didn't like it and
here's why if you go to the local
gardening store or the hardware store
and you grab an organic blended
fertilizer all purpose or tomato
fertilizer or rose fertilizer they'll
even put pictures of roses on there as
if the rose has a particular diet that
it prefers
that's not the case and so i don't want
people to be misled that a tomato needs
a specific fertilizer medicinal plants
annual flowering plants tomatoes they
require the same thing so there's
nothing special about them obviously we
all feel our chosen plant that we prefer
to grow is going to be special to us
some people love tomatoes and it's the
only plant that matters
but just because of that doesn't mean we
need a special fertilizer for it and so
then you'd flip the box over and you
start reading it well guess what they
did to get it organic listed you had to
use ingredients that are approved for
organic use they don't have to be
organic
and when you read it
it reads like
what has the highest profit margin now
that i understand it so you read it you
go oh cottonseed meal soybean meal uh
what is the other one that's really
popular that's uh highly contaminated
uh cotton and soy are two of the big
ones but then you'll see bone meal and
blood meal and all these waste sources
so essentially if you're a fertilizer
manufacturer you'd be like hey you got
some waste can i have it for free
perfect and you'd clean up shop form
handle the freight that's how a lot of
these fertilizer businesses came to be
and so when i'm reading a box that says
cottonseed meal magnesium sulfate bone
meal i'm just reading cheapest on
the market with the widest profit margin
and when you think about cotton
it's not fed to animals so the it can be
literally sprayed at harvest to make
clothing out of
and then as soon as you do that and
you've taken what's made for cotton all
the waste is now considered approved for
organic use
it can be very toxic and so now people
are carrying more and obviously there's
been huge instances where some of that
waste killed big gardens and they had to
do research about how it happened so
we're all learning but
when you go to the typical garden store
comparing it to craft blend
night and day difference in the quality
of inputs and that's why we continue to
produce it it's a nightmare to make i
mean
truckloads of materials from all over
the country have to land
and be here and all 13 ingredients or
something have to be on the ground at
one time and multiple thousand pounds
then we have to weigh them and mix them
and i kind of wish we hadn't done it but
at the end of the day
eventually it might get big enough where
we can have maybe a machine that helps
us with all of the blending of it but um
it's really really good so
i feel like we should also quickly touch
upon container size
it seems with organics it's often said
that the bigger the pot size the better
talk to us about pot size yeah it's a
bigger buffer and what i mean by that is
if you're in a small container it's
doable so when i first started learning
afghanistan um
was
on the forum and showing his growing a
lot of us borrowed from the vision we
saw he had like a room that was full of
like home depot buckets there were like
a hundred of them there and they were
just stacked bamboo poles everywhere it
looked like you're gonna gouge an eye
out just walking in there
but it was in five gallons and he would
literally just dump it out on the tarp
re-amend it and plug him back in and go
and i'm like dude that is epic and
around that time a lot of people were
saying well what happens if i just don't
dump my soil out so
um
they were just making compost teas and
keeping the same five gallon there and
planting right back into it and it
became clear that if we grew a pretty
big plant a five gallon container was
almost root bound and cannibalized to
the point where re-amending it or
recycling it was probably the better way
to go
and so to offset that we didn't want all
the labor like literally dumping 100
pots on the ground in the tarp shoveling
it and putting it back in was it's it's
no small task
and while it sounds great on paper when
it's the fifth time you've done it and
you just don't want to do it anymore
you're looking for a better way and the
no-till became the goal
and mountain organics blue jay away at
the time was starting to do back-to-back
no-till cycles and everybody was
increasing container size a lot of guys
were growing like hundred gallon pots
and then we wanted to see how far that
went and it seems like there's some
magic
somewhere around container size that
we're still learning like a big
container but still getting close
to maxing out the volume creates a
better finished product than one that's
so big you never even come close
but what we found
is that doubling your container size
usually increase your yield by about 60
and there's a lot of studies that show
why
we found that plants are intelligent and
because the nutrients aren't immediately
available in soil
they're dependent upon the speed the
biology can feed him at in a five gallon
container if we consider it like a
bioreactor we put organic amendments in
and biology breaks them down and feeds
them to the plant when our plant really
starts growing because we get the grow
room dialed the grow lights are good or
we're in the sun and it's just raging
good environment greenhouse whatever
now the biology just all of a sudden
can't keep up your plant is is growing
faster than it can keep up with the way
to bypass that is to give it more soil
so now the root instead of being
circling on itself looking for new food
can just go further away from itself
looking for new food in fact the world
record tomato grower he would do this he
would make his own compost he would make
his holes he would mulch it and he would
irrigate it but then he'd go plant vetch
a nitrogen fixing plant like eight to
ten feet behind his rows that would grow
and fix nitrogen in the ground when the
plants got bigger in their growing
season their roots would tap into the
nitrogen the veg produced and then hit a
surge of growth and they would never run
out
and so the bigger container size started
being the mimicking of the earth of what
would produce more yield i mean you can
see the guys in cali would put 400
gallon containers out grow 99 plants and
they're all 10 pounds plus so we knew
bigger could be bigger
but as far as indoor goes if you're
calling a four by four space your space
a lot of people were hesitant to add
more soil they're like five gallons a
big container that's plenty big
but when you do it for a while it just
seems so small you look around you're
like well i can fit way more in the same
four by four if i'm growing four plants
and five gallon buckets what's the
difference if i just make them 30
gallons it's still a four by four grow
tent
and what we found was the difference was
significant in a 30 gallon or 100
gallons something that really
was more soil per canopy
five gallons times four that's only 20
gallons under your grow light
but if you put
30 gallons now you're talking 120
gallons in the same 4x4 space
and now you just didn't run out of food
you didn't have to be an expert at
feeding and making the right tea and
then when you were done you used less
than half of what was available so you
could
arguably guess with some craft blend and
still have a pretty balanced soil and so
what we tried to do just like life is
take our highs and take our lows and
flatten them to a curve that was more
manageable a big container of soil makes
the big harvest
it's just like this it's not like you're
depleting the soil and when you flatten
that curve it seems like everybody gets
better results now are there people that
are using smaller containers in living
soil and doing well yes a lot of times
they'll use maybe a little bit less
light intensity to grow really high
quality without driving the plants so
fast it outpaces biology or they will
flip to flower significantly sooner or
they will put it out on the patio when
it's just a small tomato plant they're
basically not trying to overgrow what
they're using and so i think in living
soil
what we need to do is picture the final
size of our plant and try and match the
soil somewhat similarly to that as above
so below
and there's no breaking that rule when
it comes to organics so to fill a 4x4
canopy completely
full of yield i think the best way is to
fill it full of soil
here's the the other side of it though
when you're brand new
if you really don't know about watering
you could easily under water or over
water a hundred gallon plant much
easier than a five gallon the 5 gallon
or a 10 gallon you can lift it and you
can go that's way too heavy even i can
tell that i'm brand new but that seems
way heavier than day one
that's probably has plenty of water
where when you have 100 gallon or
several thirties you're kind of slapping
them and lifting them and like i don't
really know
and so then it becomes that you must
know that your watering style is working
and we have some rules of thumb for that
but
that really does determine your
container size
a lot of people will ask me how to
choose their container size and i always
recommend
maxing out as much as you're comfortable
with that's always the better answer
the caveat is learning to water so in a
four by four space
i love doing 15 to 30 gallons times four
or 100 gallon or
a big planter now
in a 4x4 i prefer a 3x3 planter if i'm
going to use something square then i can
step a foot in and reach to the back i
can have some airflow where the tent's
not right on my my grow container
so a 5x5 tent would be great for a 4x4
but these are rules of thumb you can
break every one of these rules the
reason why experts can break rules is
they know the consequences of that and
they offset it so if you're in a small
container and that's all you can do
keep your light intensity a little lower
keep your plants a little smaller before
you go into flower and i think that will
make significant quality differences in
organics we're not trying to just
maximize yield
we're trying to increase yield
so long as quality is brought up with it
but if there's a cost in quality we'd
prefer not to do that
and that's what we found so i hope that
people listening to this may be
encouraged to go up slightly in
container size i find that
10 to 15 gallons is the minimum to start
no-tilling in my opinion you can
definitely do fives but it's not as easy
our last 10 by 10 series are five gallon
containers we had three of them on a
drip system
they were ugly the whole way and harder
to deal with and took more daily
interaction but they produced what's in
you know what's finished product now is
you wouldn't be able to tell the
difference it's arguably just as good if
not better than the other ones but what
was better than the other was the yield
and the effort i got way more yield for
way less effort and to me that's why
bigger containers is very attractive so
lots of good information there for sure
so we talked about building the soil you
know 33 33 33 adding the initial
amendments
now these initial amendments they're
going to break down and the plant will
uptake the nutrients and the soil can
get depleted so oftentimes additional
feedings are required throughout the
grow
when does the first feeding typically i
know it's going to depend on pot size
and stuff like that but generally
speaking
when do you first look to do that first
feeding and what does it consist of so
there's a couple ways to look at this
when we first started most of us had
bare soil
on top meaning no mulch no top dressing
just
rich organic soil that we mixed
according to these recipes put it in the
container and you go
and what we would all do is before the
plant showed any hunger
just maybe once a week or a few weeks
after we got started and the plants were
visibly growing happily and we know
they're stable now
then we just brewed compost teas
and back then
micro man tim wilson
great guy totally transparent with info
he would geek out he'd be like you need
one point three four percent of this and
what so we were all trying those recipes
and essentially the most basic recipe
was worm castings molasses and you'd
bubble it for 24 to 48 hours and you'd
water it in
and there's a couple things that happen
from that one is we made a lot of
microbes
and when we poured them in the soil even
if they did nothing but die
their dead micro bodies would feed the
soil so it didn't have to be perfect and
then you know the molasses has some
trace minerals in there and the compost
had some npk
so making these compost teas once a week
or so usually got great results but we
wanted more
and so we started to find out that is in
organic farming you would apply what
they call a side dress or a top dress
and there's some implications to what
that meant but
essentially the way the forest does it
if we're trying to mimic nature is the
forest drops all its leaves
and it slowly starts to break down and
animals die and bugs die and everything
and that eventually feeds the soil and
it takes time
and fungus is what really built our
forests here and built our soil and
worms eventually kind of took over and
they're now part of that process but
they were an invader
either way worms build soil fungus built
soil and so when we started looking at
how we would want to feed it we said
well how would we make nature i mean no
fertilizer salesman's going to the
redwood forest and saying hey you need a
little more nitrogen to grow 200 feet
taller it just happened and so in a
living soil we started thinking instead
of mixing it in there where it has to be
accurate or it could be too much what if
we just started pouring it on top and i
got to tell you at that time
everybody was doing the opposite of
nature it was crazy so they were doing
sub cool and sub cool was a great idea
he would mix a really potent soil with
tons of nutrients and since it was just
off the chart
full of nutrients you couldn't really
plant right into it i mean some plants
maybe right but some of these land racy
plants they just did not want the
nutrients so what you would do is you
would put that in the bottom of your pot
this spicy rich soil and then you put a
really light soil with no nutrients on
top the idea was you put your plant in
and it doesn't go into the hot nutrients
until it's ready for it and then it's
balanced
but nature does it the opposite it has
all of the minerals and water down below
with no nutrients and it pours all the
nutrients right on top and slowly decays
them into the soil
and so as such the plants have actually
developed this feeder root system that
lives up top to eat the food and it
develops these water tap roots that go
down to get water and minerals deep from
the earth depending on the type of plant
so in living soil what we do is right
away you don't have to wait
because when we mix it in the soil it
could be too much if we overdo it but
once you put the 15 gallon pot let's say
of your homemade
three-part recipe
and you put the plant into it you could
literally top dress some craft blend or
your homemade version put some more worm
castings on there and cover it with
mulch and put a few worms in and you
could do that day one and the reason why
like if you buy fox farm they say don't
feed it for a few weeks is it's already
charged with food
where in our soil it's charged with
amendments that are going to take time
to break down
and so we want that to be there and it's
a balanced amount but when we put stuff
on top we're day one creating the
biomimicry of the forest that's
eventually going to start adding food
from the top which means that as our
plant grows and it eats the soil we made
for it it's going to go i wonder where
my food is and it's going to start
reaching up to the top putting feeder
roots up there especially if we use
mulch and it'll say oh here i'm good
i've got more food and then you can feed
it right through the top
and when you develop this is game
changer we used to top dress and not a
lot would happen it would take weeks
every time you'd water it in and kind of
go in there eventually it would break
down but when we added worms that would
eat it and immediately make it available
and we covered it with straw some mulch
of some sort it became shady
the light wasn't hitting anymore the
worms would go right up to it the fungus
was growing underneath it and all of a
sudden the feeder roots would literally
set up shop and they would hang and wait
and next time you top dress you could
see the roots like literally matted
right there and they would start to work
on your top dress within days so all of
a sudden it became
oh you got to be three weeks ahead in
organics too well if i build from day
one this feeder root system
i could go top dress every couple weeks
if i want and they're going to make
immediate good use of it and if any is
left over well it's on top and the thing
that we found is that plants annual
flowering plants when they go to die
like they've lived their time
they're going to die whether they have
nutrients or not which means they're not
going to just be continually forced
feeding themselves they're going to stop
taking up nutrients
some of them now the idea is that they
will stop if they can in hydro they
can't because they need water
and the nutrients are already in the
water which means for them to drink
means they're going to get nutrients
whether they like it or not but in soil
where you have underground aquifers and
food up top the plant can almost start
to self-fade
to sense to senescence is what they call
it and even if there's an abundance of
food in the top dressing
so long as you're slowing watering down
and the biology is not breaking it down
completely because the plant roots have
said i don't need it anymore the plant
will still fade and it will still
senesce even though there's nutrients in
the soil which sets you up for the next
round
without completely depleting it so
for the new grower that's setting up
their container don't be scared to top
dress right in the beginning because by
the time you get into full fruit
production and flowering that top dress
will start to be available to the plant
and that's how i build my what i call
the checking account that's in the mix
it needs to be available and the savings
account and when your plant can say oh
my checking account's pretty good but my
savings account is great it will put
more fruit out
where if you don't have any of that even
though your soil is good your plant's
not stupid it's not going to put out
more than would kill itself
and so you might be cheating your plant
by not building that checking and
savings account and here's what's nice
is in a big big container you can put
less in your savings account across the
surface and the plant will react better
because there's a bigger buffer of soil
you don't
like if one cup was the perfect amount
in a five gallon
well it might be a ten cup range in a
big hundred gallon like you could over
under do it without causing a problem
and that's where container size comes
back into play now
feeding compost teas i'm never scared of
but if you're buying like liquid fish or
anything that's arguably potent i want
you to wait in your soil recipe until
the plant starts to show some hunger
meaning
in living soil you'll start to see like
dark green will be just a little bit
lighter hue of green and as you're
growing you'll start to think oh she's
hungry the plants are a little bit they
want something
you can start to feed those liquids at
that point but they're so instantly
available
you can't guess a month ahead of time
like you can with organic amendments if
that makes sense gotcha yep well it's
episodes like this where i wish this
podcast was two hours but it's only one
hour we just scratched the surface on
things there are so many other things
that we can talk about i have a feeling
the audience is going to be demanding a
part two so maybe in the future we could
do a part two and kind of pick up what
we left off i mean we could get into ipm
seed sparta teas cover crotch mulch
layers all that stuff i think that would
make for a great part too if you're
willing to come i would be willing i
want basically like i also practice jiu
jitsu one of the things i learned there
is that the black belt to be the best
teacher he literally has to teach the
fundamental basics every day over and
over and over again because that's all
that matters when they win competitions
oftentimes it's a day one move they used
and so this base recipe could be all
that you ever need to know and some
people don't require getting their black
belt and learning the nuances of
that just doesn't really help them get
any further
and so because of that i would be
honored to do more of these with you and
hoping that maybe instead of me saying
it over and over again they can just go
to the episode and watch from different
people and what i've also learned from
jiu jitsu is that just because one black
belt told me doesn't mean i don't want
to hear it from a dozen others that
might describe it differently and help
my brain understand and fully connect it
and internalize it so
for whatever reason your viewers really
like the way your style of answering and
asking questions and our growers like
what i do but we're different and so
combining our efforts i think reaches
more people and i'd love to do it um ipm
could be a whole episode
we could really go down the rabbit hole
soil testing all this but from today
what i want people to get from it is
that soil building if following some
good principles doesn't have to be
rocket science and they should they
should absolutely even if you don't stop
what you're doing add one new thing and
make some soil from scratch get your own
hands in there i think you'll never go
back if you try it well said
so wrapping things up how can the
listeners find you and what do you have
acquiring in the future
a good question build a soil.com is the
best way to find us we also have a
youtube at build a soil we have an
instagram
you can come down to the store anytime
see our vegetable farm see our indoor
grow here where we demonstrate all of
it's very transparent we're in montrose
colorado in western colorado
beyond that
as far as the future goes we have a
number of things that we're working on
right now um that we'll be sharing soon
we've got a new powdered veg growing
product that helps if you're in smaller
containers helps if you need something
for foliar
so we'll be releasing that soon
um otherwise most of what we're working
on at build the soil is just quality
control and scalability without giving
up on that and that's just a lot of
logistics and boring business stuff we
could talk about all day but i'm more
excited to talk about the soil stuff and
as far as new
a lot of it's just old school so nothing
terribly new coming out just a repeat of
the the mantra of the build a soil way
of mimicking nature and using what works
awesome like i mentioned the beginning
of this episode i will have a link to
jeremy's channel down in the description
section below if you enjoyed this video
click that thumbs up button i also love
to know in the comments section below do
you want a part 2 if so put part 2 in
the comment section and let us know some
organic methods that you do you know
whether it be building soil or feedings
so on and so forth love to hear about
that in the comments because there are
so many different ways to do this and
sharing those best practices within the
comments i think can be value added for
many people if you're tuning in on one
of the podcast platforms please leave a
rating and review particularly apple
podcasts and then subscribe to the
channel if you haven't already every
single week i'm releasing these garden
talk podcast episodes and i would love
for you to tune in to future episodes
jeremy once again thank you so much for
coming on to this episode today i think
it was a banger i think there's a lot of
people that are gonna have value from
the information you put out and keep
doing what you're doing man it's good
stuff for sure thank you so much and uh
nice shirt by the way yeah you got the
family i had to represent
well that's our farm if you want to
follow that that's at build a soil
family farms on instagram um we'll put
it up on youtube this year as well and i
hope that if you guys have questions and
you if any and you ask them on the mr
grow it on this episode i'm going to go
in afterwards in the comments and i'll
try and answer anything that i maybe
missed so please ask anything relative
to the content today and i'll be sure to
answer them
awesome all right that being said peace
out everyone see in the next episode
[Music]
you