welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned in
to the guard Talk podcast this episode
number 163 in this episode I interview
Macho Grahams Grahams be Savage he is a
fellow content creator with nearly 2,000
subscribers and he grows both
organically and synthetically and that's
what we're going to talk about in
today's episode the medium feedings pH
PPM and more will be compared Macho
reveals several things that he does in
his garden when growing both ways in
order to get better plant growth if you
want to see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said I
I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
electric sprayers with a 2 L capacity
and an adjustable nozzle that can go
from a strong jet to a fine mist spray
their sprayers are battery powered and
can be used for 3 hours on a full charge
no pumping required and it's a one
button operation click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their sprayers and the
discount code Mr Grow 15 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend consists of
several ingredients in one so you no
longer have to buy individual bottles it
includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and used to
discount code the stash Mars Hydro check
out their new 2025 M6 clip fan it has a
five blade design 10 speed settings
delivers a maximum air flow of 350 CFM
and you can choose between 45° and 90°
oscillation angles also their
Valentine's Day flash sale is going on
right now from February 10th to 17th go
to their website at mars-hydro
[Music]
docomo and you can use discount code Mr
Grow to save even more and we are back
and I'm joined with Macho Grahams
Grahams be Savage how you doing today
I'm all right how you doing today
brother doing pretty good man thanks for
coming on to the podcast today we met in
person a couple times couple times
already now yeah yeah actually the
Grower's Gauntlet was the first time
I'll never forget when we were done with
the event AC Infinity was giving away
some of the equipment that was there and
I one one of the things they were giving
away was a grow tent and it was all
fully assembled and everything I'm like
I don't think anybody wants this and I
walk outside and I talk to you and I'm
like you're giving away a grow tend
anybody anybody want it and you're like
yes I'll take it and you live in
Illinois so getting from California to
Illinois you actually you went so far to
to do that it was pretty funny I'm glad
you mentioned it CU a lot of people
didn't believe it a lot of people didn't
believe that you were the reason that I
actually came home with a 4x4 from the
trip so that's cool man yeah I really
appreciate you hooking me up man I
wasn't expecting that at all yeah me
neither I didn't think they were going
to be given that way all that stuff I
think people had lights not even in
boxes and stuff like so yeah it was
insane it was awesome really really good
event though but yeah I'm glad you
decided to come on to the podcast today
we're going to be talking about growing
a couple different ways here growing
Organics and synthetics you grow both
ways I think it's really important to
know some of the differences between the
two I know me personally when I first
started I was growing with synthetic
inputs and then I switched over to
Organics and I was trying to do the same
things that I was doing with synthetics
and there are some things that are
different so going through today and
finding out kind of how you do things
growing both ways and I think there's
could to be a lot of tick ways for folks
that are listening in that they'll be
able to apply in their own garden so
really excited for this conversation but
before we get too deep into it can you
uh give us an introduction tell us a
little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening well I'm M grahs and
I started ging about a almost a year and
a half ago now and it was really because
I just wanted to grow my own you know
you don't really know what's going on
out here you don't know what everybody's
putting into their into their stuff and
I'm starting to get real weary on what's
out there so I really wanted to take
full control of what's going into my
garden what's going into my body awesome
and then what is your style of growing
are you an indoor grower outdoor I know
you said you grow both with Organic
inputs as well as synthetic inputs what
medium are you in as well yeah right now
I've only been able to have the chance
to grow indoor and I'm growing both like
you said organic and synthetic so for my
organic gr I'm using Builder soil 3.0
and I try to run their whole line all
build of soil the whole build of soil
family and for my synthetic grow I
haven't stuck to one Coco yet but I've
been switching around from different
Coco companies okay got it so a little
bit of both soil and cocoa you got
experience do them both so some people
might be listening into this and they
might be not knowing fully what the
difference is between organic and
synthetic can you break it down for us
well with Organics the way I grow I try
to get everything set like before I even
plant my first seed you know I need to
have all my nutrients everything that's
going to be taken up within the grow
already set whereas in synthetic it's an
inert media the cocoa that I use there's
nothing in there and I'm adding my
nutrients as I go every day I'm feeding
nutrients every day got it and we'll
break down your feeding regimen here in
a few minutes yeah there are quite a few
differences between organic and
synthetic I think uh organic a lot of
people think of all natural things that
come from the earth for example
sustainability is something that can be
mentioned when it comes to organic some
of the differences in techniques we're
going to get into that now as far as
watering medium container size that you
can use and so on and so forth let's
jump into medium first when you're
growing organically what medium do you
use I think you mentioned soil right and
then what's in that mix to begin well
it's already a pre-made mix from Builder
soil so they come out with a pretty good
bag 3.0 and it's everything already
prepared so you're ready to go to flow
once you're ready to go to maybe a few
weeks before you'll add your your stuff
that you're going to need so I'm adding
craft blend I'm adding Kashi I'm adding
Thrive okay yeah I've pulled up the 3.0
recipe here it's got so much stuff in
here too much to name on
everything fish compost we've got
biodynamic compost worm castings trace
minerals hum make the list goes on so
it's a very long list of things that uh
that included in this recipe I've heard
a lot of people having really good
success with build of soil soils I think
they have a handful of them but I think
their most popular one is that 3.0
recipe that you mentioned yeah ever
since I started using it i' I've been
sticking with it I haven't had a problem
with them I could stick a cut a fresh
cut the directly in there and it'll grow
no problem and with Organic another
thing that is worth mentioning is you're
really relying on the micro life in
order to break down those amendments not
all the amendments in there I mean some
can be soluble right so when you water
it in it turns into a bioavailable form
that the plant can then uptake but for
the most part A lot of these are going
to need that after the watering the
microbes go to work then and they break
down those nutrients and make put them
into a form that's going to be available
for the plant to uptake so that's a big
difference there that uh we didn't
mention before now when you're growing
with the synthetic bottle nutrients are
you just in Cocoa you mentioned that and
kind what 7030 cocoa perite mix okay and
there's no amendments that you add in
prior to planting you're just using the
bottle nutrients is that correct yeah no
I actually got a salt nutrients so it's
no bottle yeah it's all dried nutrients
powdered form got it no and then what
container size are you using when
growing organic When I grow my Organics
I go anywhere from 5 to 7 I wouldn't
mind growing a little bit bigger but
right now that's all I'm able to grow
in as far as my synthetic grow when I
grow my synthetics it doesn't really
matter I've seen I could grow in a one
gallon pot or in a five gallon pot and I
can still get the same results depending
on how much I'm feeding I hear you yeah
on the organic side of things you often
hear people say the bigger the better
you know what I mean but you can't
certainly get away with say smaller grow
pots and I know what's small is
certainly subjective but I think a lot
of folks would consider 3 gallons 5
gallons as being smaller containers even
maybe some people might say seven
gallons or 10 gallons are small they
prefer 15 gallons or more I personally
ran Organics in I've tried three gallons
I've tried five gallons seven gallons
I'm up to 10 gallons and actually gotten
easier and easier as I moved up in pot
size and that's one of the biggest
argument for folks that are growing
organically is they say the the bigger
the pot size the better now certainly
there are downsides to
running a bigger pot size but having
kind of a bigger pot size and having
more nutrition in there it just can be a
lot easier kind of retaining moisture
and so on and so forth now with the
synthetic I agree with you like right
now I've got two gallon grow pots that
I'm growing with the synthetic nutrients
so on the smaller side of things and
I've also run that with three gallons 5
gallons seven gallons so I've tried out
a variety of things as well and I really
do like growing in those smaller ones
particularly two gall
now if you're hand watering it might be
there might be an advantage there to
being one of the larger pot Siz you have
to water as often yeah but if you're on
an auto watering system like I'm on the
blue mat system with two gallon
containers it's it's fantastic yeah
those blue mat systems are amazing I
actually need to give me one I'm still
hand watering myself so yeah I got a
couple self-watering bases but I need
more yeah it can be so much easier to
just dump water into a reservoir for
example and then have your organic
inputs in there and it's just slowly
dripping down as needed under the medium
it's certainly beneficial so for
feedings I want to get deep into this
one because this is I think is where a
lot of people get tripped up for
Organics you had mentioned that you're
using the build Sol 3.0 recipe so it's
not really going to need any additional
nutrition to begin right no not to begin
with depending on what's pot size you're
using how big of a plant you're growing
how long you veg for you could
potentially run out of that nutrition
rate that could be completed from The
Medium so is that the case for you and
if so what organic inputs are you
providing the plant with as far as in
veg I haven't had a problem like in my
plant will go through the whole veg
cycle fine it's when you're flipping
into flour now a lot of people see the
organic they see the bags and they hear
water only and it'll get you so far
water only but it's not going to get you
the quality that you want if you're only
using water so before I go into flour
I'm adding the craft blend and I'm
adding a builda flour and that's going
to help me get all the nutrients that I
need later on cuz in organic it's going
to take a lot for everything to break
down so you want to prepare your soil
before you get into flow okay so you top
dressing before flipping the flower how
long are you usually doing a veg for uh
it depends I've done one month vegges
I've done two month vegges I notice with
the 2 month wedge I'll get a bigger
yield at the end so 30 to 60 days and
then uh before flipping a flower you'll
top dress and do you just do that one
top dressing before FL flower or you
also doing a top dressing kind of
midflower uh sometimes mid flow too I'll
add some
stash I'll hit it up and yep okay yeah I
know roughly people do every 30 days but
really depends on again you know what
what size container you're in how big
the plants are so on and so forth yeah I
feel like in the those five gallon pots
just at one time in the beginning before
I flp a flower it's it's enough yeah the
plan's been doing good I haven't had no
deficiencies towards the end and I'm
happy with what I'm getting awesome so
it's just craft blend and then build a
flower are there any other inputs you
use on the organic side of things
whether it be worm castings or any
additives or anything yeah there's uh
wor castings in the in the craft BL Leaf
but I'm also using a Bashi and there's
another bottle it's a th that's also
comes with from the build Sol family
believe that's uh Yahweh I'm mistaken
drive botle and that's being applied at
the same time as yeah the Bild of flower
okay so yeah pretty easy regiment there
when it comes to Organics a lot of
people uh I think that's one thing that
a lot of people like is you're just
really doing a few two maybe three
sometimes maybe even more top dressings
and then it's just water only from there
so that definitely makes things a lot
easier when it comes to feeding now on
the synthetic bottle nutrient side that
powdered line that you're talking about
what is the name of the line that you
use I use strive nutrients uh pretty
simple line it's a two part system and
the a&amp; B from Veg to flour it's the same
ratio so you don't really have to wor
about calculations or anything like that
yeah real simple line that sounds pretty
easy are you doing a full dose according
to their feeding chart are you doing
like a half dose and how often are you
doing feedings so I'm filling up a 5
gallon res resir and that probably lasts
me about 3 to 4 days and I got about
four plants growing off of that right
now okay and then are you just you're
just scooping it out with a container
and then Watering your plants as needed
yeah yeah well I got a water hose now
and it's a lot easier so I could just
water my plants is within two minutes
you know everything's done and yeah it's
real easy that's cool now are you doing
uh I think you mentioned in the
beginning you're feeding every single
time so anytime the medium dries out
you're giving dose of nutrients have you
ever done the every other feeding where
you're watering one time then you're
feeding the next time then when the
medium dries out you're watering again
and going back and forth I know it's a
very common technique when it comes to
using synthetic nutrients have you done
that before or is it just straight
nutrient mix every single time yeah when
my synthetic I haven't done that I've
just been giving the nutrients every
time now have you run into any toxicity
issues at all no no I haven't had no
problems sounds like a really easy
lineup to use yeah I like it ever since
I started using it I don't think I'm
going to switch over I mean I like using
other lines too like trying different
stuff but I'm really set with that one I
really like it you have to adjust the pH
at all that's a common thing that people
look at when using synthetic nutrients
is they mix it up in their nutrient
solution and then they'll adjust to the
pH what does your pH come out to before
and and then what do you adjust it to
before I adjust it it's usually around
68 7 and I try to get that down to 6 58
6 around there 5.8 or 6.0 what do you
use to adjust down uh just the G General
Hydroponics pH Down got it I believe
that's a phosphoric acid but I'm not
100% sure but yeah those acids are very
commonly used in order to adjust the PH
down now with the Organics are you phing
at all like are you monitoring the pH
whether it be not at all that's thing
about it yeah I mean I know I can but
the plant's been showing me that she's
doing good and she's she's fine she's
happy so I don't think I need to change
anything on that side right now that's
another way that it makes things easier
as you don't have to adjust the pH at
least in your particular case I'm not
sure you know we'll talk about water
here in a minute but your initial water
source is certainly going to tell you
whether or not you need to do that pH
adjustment some people comes out of
their tap at 8 pH or higher and like I
have to adjust the pH or else I come
across problems but if your tap water or
your filter Oro whatever water source
you're using if it falls within that you
know six to seven range roughly
sometimes it can be up to 7.5 pH people
swear that they add that in and they
don't do any sort of pH adjustments and
their plants are fine yeah when when I
check mine out the top it's at seven but
I still like I let uh I let my
reservoirs air overnight I'll stick a
AirStone in the in the water let that
sit for at least 24 hours before I give
it to any of my PLS yeah it's also said
to help eliminate some of that chlorine
that's in there all that extra stuff
that you don't want to give yeah yeah
depending on your local water source it
uses either chlorine or chloramine
although if chloramine is included
that's one thing that people really have
to be aware of is that isn't something
that is just going to if you have it sit
overnight it disappears it's more of a
stable molecule versus the chlorine a
lot of people just let it sit overnight
some people let it sit and have an
AirStone in there like you do some
people put it in light they said that
helps with it dissipating well my first
6 months when I started growing I was
buying water so I was just buying
distill water every day and that was
getting expensive after a while man so I
started testing with my tab water and
the plants didn't really give me too
much of a reaction to everything normal
the same so I just stuck with
that man I can only imagine yeah I had a
buddy who lived locally he was buying
water every time he was buying reverse
osmosis and it adds up I personally
think over time it's going to be worth
it to buy a system that you can actually
install like underneath your kitchen
sink for example because they're pretty
small and uh a lot of these are now a
one:1 ratio before a lot of the old
systems are a 1 to three so what do I
mean by that it's basically for every
one gallon of RO water that you get out
of the the system there three gallons
would be wasted yeah now like I
mentioned it's a one to one so for every
one gallon you get only one gallon is
wasted and so um yeah buying that which
is uh 200 250 bucks roughly for that
particular system I'm talking about the
one: one system it can certainly save
you money over the long run versus going
and buying either reverse osmosis or
distilled it could be very very costly
doing that Avenue yeah I'm definitely
looking into getting something different
and picking up a system for the house so
I don't have to worry about the lot
anymore now how about the EC or PPM
let's start with Organics are you doing
any type of monitering of the EC or PPM
not on not on either one of them really
like the only thing I monitor is the pH
on my synthetic
side and that's about it like it's hard
for me to check the PPM or PM and like I
just try to focus on one number and
stick to that a lot of people play the
numbers game and they chase it and
they're just driving themselves crazy
but like until I see my something going
on with my plants where I feel like I'm
doing something wrong or I'm lacking in
something then I'll start paying a
little bit more attention to that yeah I
think a lot of people on the same take
the same route that you do when it comes
the organic side of things in particular
where they are mostly hands-off when it
comes to both pH like we mentioned as
well as the EC and the PPM yeah but
they're coming across problems some
people do check that both the ph and EC
or PPM in order to see hey is there a
lack of nutrition or is there too much
maybe there's too much nutrition in
there has caused a toxicity issue
checking on an as needed basis seems to
be the theme for a lot of folks growing
with Organic inputs now you had
mentioned with that with synthetic those
that synthetic line using the powdered
line you're not checking the EC or PPM
of that which I think a lot of people
might say that's a little surprising
there not to monitor it have you come
across any issues like with toxicities
in particular or any
deficiencies no not yet no ever since I
started using this line I swear I
haven't had no problems that's awesome
I'm gonna have to check out that line
maybe even try it in the future it
sounds like a real easy line to use
especially if you're you're using it
you're not having to check EC or the PPM
because that's a common thing lot of
people do though to make sure that the
nutrient solution going into it is the
range they're looking for or they'll
check the runoff measure measurement so
they'll run the nutrient solution
through and then they'll check the the
runoff and make sure that the ECR PPM is
kind of within certain ranges so you're
not aiming for particular ranges for the
different stages of growth when you're
going with the synthetic inputs no no
not I'm just monitoring the pH levels
and that's it interesting I really
recommend that line for anybody who's
new and thinking about getting into
synthetics it's been real good for me
like being a new grower I haven't had no
problems and yeah yeah I really like it
awesome that's good to hear so you
already mentioned using tap water now
how do you go about the waterings of
your plant are you kind of checking the
medium and seeing if it's dry or are you
kind of on a schedule maybe we'll start
with Organics how do you go about
watering when you're using the organic
inputs well I used to have it on a soft
watering base it would just drink as I
wanted to and I would let that dry out
maybe once a week and then I would top
dress the water in
like the everything that I top dressed
to feed into the roof system the self
watering base will hold about maybe
three days of water two or three days of
water and when I check the level on it I
notice it's getting dry I start checking
the weight of the actual pot itself so
I'll pick up the actual pot see how
heavy it's getting or how light it's
getting that's the that's been the
easiest way for me to check and when
growing Organics you have only been
using the self-watering is that correct
yeah yeah now how about when you're
growing with the synthetic inputs are
you still doing a self-watering or you
top watering or what I'm top watering
yeah every day I'm top watering in since
you're in Cocoa more of an area medium
doesn't hold on to the moisture as much
you're doing every single day you're
going in there and doing a watering huh
yeah I wanted to use a softw watering
basis but I've heard people have
problems when they're feeding synthetics
ble feeding so I don't want to run into
problems I don't really want to
experience them either so I'm just going
to keep keep doing has been working for
me for right now so I'm just tap
watering every day it's not broke don't
fix it right yeah yeah exactly exactly I
mean you call it's always fun to
experiment but just as long as you're
just experimenting maybe on something
small not your actual Garden you know
yeah so pretty straightforward there how
you go about your waterings I want to
get into pests next let's start with IPM
things you could do to prevent pests
what do you do in that case I've had
problems with Pest and I had a bad bag
of in the past that I had to deal with
fungus
NS and to get rid of that I had to use a
mosquito bits so something that I had a
water into into the into the Coco every
day for at least about a week till I got
rid of that but I normally keep uh
sticky traps around now so that's always
a good monitor like just to keep an eye
on things it's not going to stop you
from getting them but it's going to tell
you if you have a problem or not [ __ ]
STS are such a pain man I battle them so
much they seem to come and go so often
it can be certainly be frustrating when
you have a a crazy outbreak it doesn't
sound like they have been too crazy for
you though have you come across any
major pest infestations whether it be
spider mice thrips anything like that at
all no just the fungus luckily that's
all I had I guess you know they say
you're not a real grow so you get spider
Ms and stuff I guess I'm not a real girl
yet I'm still learning yeah I've never
heard that before
yeah I heard somebody say that at the
girl shop the other day okay I guess I'm
not a real girl yet I don't know what
I'm doing I guess I guess agree to
disagree on that one I know people who
have been growing for five plus years
and they've never come across pests so
that's great going to call them not a
grower exactly right like come on man
that's funny I'm glad to hear that you
haven't come across any major
infestations it could be such a pain man
I had uh I had aphids Outdoors one time
and it was so disheartening it was on
actually my bok choy and I went in there
it was Harvest day and I was like ah
going to harvest some bok choy my first
time growing it I was super excited it
was purple Lady B choice so was like
completely purple and I went to go
Harvest it and I'm just just loaded with
aphid it's kind of like borrowed in and
it was just H it was disgusting I was
like oh no how the heck am I gonna eat
this stuff you know so well that's one
of the things about growing outside
right is like you can't really control
too too much what's going on out there
Outdoors is a whole different
Battlefield now are you doing anything
as a preventative like sprays a lot of
people use sprays particularly like in
the veg stage in order to kind of deter
pest or prevent pests from coming in do
you do those at all or no no I haven't
had to yet so I mean I know everybody
everybody's telling me to go ahead and
just get some preventive maintenance
going on before it happens but I haven't
had the chance to experiment with any
different type of sprays yet
but I'm always willing to try something
all right pretty straightforward there
I'll keep my fingers crossed that you
don't come across any
infestation we'll hope for the best on
that Avenue yeah now what climate are
you in um the the temperature range that
I try to keep is anywhere from 75 to 80s
maybe about 60 60% humidity level maybe
a little bit higher in the beginning but
towards the end I'm dropping it down and
that's probably the lowest I'll get is
about 60% around 60% for the whole grow
is that correct no I start off like in
my best Stage I'm aiming for a higher
humidity level I'm probably around 70 to
75 so as I'm going flipping into my next
stage is when I'll start lowering it and
probably towards the end the flow I'm
probably down to about 60% are you
supplementing CO2 at all or no uh no no
no no I want to get some type of system
going but I haven't had a chance to
experiment that yet no I noticed when I
had my my garden in my bedroom when it
was still small my garden was still
small my plants were grown a lot faster
and I believe it was because of the CO2
that I was able to provide for them now
that it's in a separate room yeah I see
the difference yeah oh yeah that makes
total sense I know some people who work
out in their grow room in order to
release that CO2 that helps their plants
I thought that was pretty funny yeah so
that's temperature humidity and CO2
let's talk about some mistakes that
Growers make starting with Organics are
there any mistakes that you made or
mistakes that you know of that people
make when growing organically yeah my
first organic grow I I read the bag and
except the water only so I just watered
only the whole way through all the way
to flour and I quickly realize that that
wasn't the way I mean there's only so
much that why is going to get you but in
flow you're going to need to add all the
extra stuff that you need you're going
to need all your nutrients I think a lot
of people run into that problem because
they see that on the bag water only and
they think they're good for the entire
grow and then they come across problems
and then they give up on Organics
because they uh they're not happy with
the result they thought it was water
only and all of a sudden they think it's
something else that they're doing in the
grow but yeah I think a lot of people
fall into that same trap now how about
when growing with synthetic nutrients is
there any mistakes that you can think of
that uh that maybe you've come across um
the only Mi I have so far was my pH pen
so I didn't have the proper pH pen and
it wasn't getting right so when I
started feeding my nutrients I wasn't
getting the grow I was expecting to see
and when I finally got a new p and I
seen that my old pH was way off and I
was able to adjust everything and get
everything correct right away I I
noticed the difference like the very
next two days the pants were taking off
yeah that's happened to me before as
well man those probes on the pH pen I
wish they lasted a lot longer now you
can use storage solution which is is
recommended right because if you're not
uh keeping that probe in storage
solution at all times really when you're
not using the pen it can dry out and it
dries out so quickly and then you come
across inaccuracies and you have to
actually buy a new probe and some of
these meters they don't have replaceable
probe so you have to buy a whole new
meter so I learned my lesson a long time
ago about keeping it in storage solution
and uh thankfully it lasts a lot longer
but yeah you still need to calibrate too
I mean uh I typically calibrate there's
some really good meters that I've got
away with not calibrating several months
and without calibrating and they've been
still accurate but I think General
recommendation is every month or so to
calibrate and actually that's a question
I'd like to pass off to the audience the
folks that are listening in for the
folks that use a pH pen how often do you
calibrate let me know down in the
comments section below but yeah pH pan
man that uh that is something that can
definitely be thrown off over time and
and you definitely need to keep your
eyes on that because that could cause
problems with your plants and I
recommend getting the going I mean
there's a lot of Cheaper versions that
are available but I wouldn't recommend
that you know which you you're going to
be using I got a AC Infinity one I
got yeah yeah I've got the all-in-one AC
Infinity one I've been using that for uh
since it came out so moving on one thing
I want to ask you about I like to ask
this every now and then advice for
beginners for the folks that are just
getting started growing with Organic
inputs what advice do you have for them
uh if you're going to be listening
to other Growers and taking advice in
from other Growers try to stick with one
grower don't go from one grower and take
advice from another girl and another
girl or get tips from another girl cuz
it's going to mix everything up you know
try to find somebody that you could use
as a mentor maybe
and and stick with their with their girl
style
so you could develop your own I think
that's really good advice people do mix
things when they shouldn't mix
particularly like amendments will kind
of try to play soil scientist and like
oh I heard from this guy that this is
good to add in and oh this guy says that
this good to add in and all of a sudden
there's an imbalance of nutrition and
the medium and some elements are locking
out others you preventing uptake from
happening and uh they're coming across
problems so yeah I agree with you when
it's kind of like stick to somebody's
regiment that you're following maybe
just go with what they're going to begin
in until you've kind of seen some
success there then kind of experimenting
from there because when you're mixing
all these different things you can
certainly come across problems and uh
some could be hard to correct yeah with
Organics it's a it's a lot harder to
correct because it's going to take time
for the stuff to break down or you know
it's not going to be the whatever you do
is not going to be readily available so
you're not going to see if you corrected
it or not for another week maybe two
weeks sometimes yeah 100% do you have
any specific tips for growing
synthetically that you'd like to give to
beginners don't don't get stuck to one
line maybe don't be afraid to try new
lines you know there's a whole bunch of
different nutrient companies out there
there a lot of them are doing the same
thing just put different labels on there
so don't think just because one brand is
more popular or more expensive it's
going to be better know don't be afraid
to try new things but just always make
sure you got your pH levels right
another question I like to ask towards
the end of the episode can you list off
top three strains that you've grown and
kind of what you like about them uh one
of them was just recent it was a Chad
westports no joke it was a real real
easy girl she grew out nice and frosty
super Frosty she purped out real nice at
the end and when I harvested you know
she was real good she came out real good
real good uh real good effects and I've
only gotten about a year growing so it's
only so much that I got growing um one
of my other favorite ones that I had was
uh Back to the Future I don't know if
you ever had the chance to try that one
that was a real good one that taste bu
genetics okay yeah they B out of UK I
believe but that one too she was a real
big yielder real fat long colas when you
open your tent you you're going to like
what you see you know she's going to
give you what you want she's going to
give you a nice good smell nice good
effect
good narcotic effect I have to check
that out do you have one more for us
yeah chop Cherry I don't know if you
ever had chop Cherry that one beautiful
plant she comes out real purple super
purple the actual nugs are purple not
just the leaves so she's real Frosty she
smells real good like a real strong
scent a fruit punch with a hit of gas
little bit of funk in the back end but
yep that's definitely one that I plan on
keeping around for a while man that
sound's right up my alley who's the
breeder on that I believe that was
exotic or Relentless one of the two I
had to double check and I'll get back
with that one okay sweet man well this
has been awesome dude we've went through
quite a few things when it comes to how
to grow organically and then how to grow
with synthetic place kind of really how
you do things in your garden and that's
really what this podcast is all about I
have people from all different
experience levels beginners intermediate
advance and they're really just talking
about either kind of area that they
specialize in or how they do things
within their grow so really happy that
you sat down with me today and talked
about how you do things and I definitely
think there's some good takeways here
particularly for the folks that are just
getting started growing and uh yeah man
we'll wrap things up here can you tell
listeners how they can find you and what
you have upcoming in the future oh I
appreciate you having me on I really do
um you guys can find me on YouTube Macho
Grahams gransby Savage and Instagram
same name m grams gr Savage and just
look out for videos coming out on
YouTube that's where I'm focusing on
more right now coming out some content
sweet well I'll definitely have a link
to Macho's YouTube channel down in the
description section below what questions
do you have for Macho or what questions
do you have about growing organically or
synthetically let us know down in the
comment section below and yeah what tips
do you have for growing with Organic
inputs or growing synthetically I'd love
to know that in the comment section as
well definitely want to give a big shout
out to the folks supporting on patreon
patreon.com /m grow the folks being
scrolled on the screen right now are in
the producer tier special thanks to you
100% of the money donated through
patreon goes right back on the podcast
it keeps his podcast going so thank you
so much for your contributions there
well Macho thank you so much for coming
on to the podcast this has been a great
chat I'm sure we'll cross paths again at
some point and I'm looking forward to
throwing one or two up in the air with
you yeah hell yeah can't wait for man
can't wait to hang again all right
everyone we will leave it at that thanks
so much for tuning in and I'll catch you
in the next episode peace out