if you have your environment dialed and
you also are dialing in your feed
ph dc temperature all that stuff is
dialed
you can come out with a very nice
product it doesn't matter what the line
they all have
the same kind of stuff in them just
different ratios and that's why they can
put a different
name on it you can make a serum of
lactic acid bacteria
and that's inoculate you can use in
water and give to your plants you can
spray
lab on your plant it'll prevent mold and
then when you
water it into the soil it breaks things
down readily
the aeration i like to use pumice and
then
the second best i like to use is a
hydroton clay and then
if i have to i use perlite you can get
it to the point where you just take like
a size of your pinky you just put it in
a 55 gallon drum and you just inoculated
the whole drum
with fungus beneficial fungus and that
fungus was
captured indigenous in your area right
outside
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and this is garden talk episode 8. this
episode's guest goes by the name
beast coast farmers he has been growing
for over 15 years
and does both indoor gardening as well
as outdoor gardening he grows a lot of
vegetables
house plants and of course that
medicinal plant that we've all grown to
love
in this episode he reveals his gardening
methods he mostly does the
no-till living organics method but he
also talks about some things when it
comes to growing what synthetic
nutrients
because he does have experience using
those as well some of the techniques
that he talks about in this episode
are a bit more advanced just a reminder
that this podcast is for growers of all
types
beginners intermediate and advanced
growers but if you are a beginner tuned
into this episode
there's definitely some information for
you and here as well if you're watching
this on youtube please click that thumbs
up button
if you're on one of the podcast
platforms please leave a rating or
review
i think on apple podcast i believe we
have two ratings so far so
maybe after this episode we'll have
three i hope before we get into the
video i would like to give a quick shout
out to our sponsor for this episode
our sponsor for today is organic rev the
team at rev sent me a sample of their
organic growth stimulant
and so far my plants love it it's
certified organic
and consists of a naturally occurring
source of carbon it also consists of
humates and microbes it can safely be
used during all stages of growth
from seed all the way to harvest it can
increase germination rates
it can increase root mass it can reduce
transplant shock
and it can make nutrients more available
visit organicrev.com to learn more about
it
and also leave a link down in the
description section below so you can
easily click on it there
that being said let's get into the
episode
all right beast coast farmers what's up
man how you doing
good how are you my friend doing good
good it's been a while since we last
talked we actually had a
conversation a few years back i actually
just reposted
the conversation we had it was me you
and then chris from happy hydro
uh reposted out on my channel we
actually a lot of people don't know this
we actually filmed that like i think
like two years ago or something like
that
yeah i know it's been a bit it was a
good time though i wanted to definitely
follow
up you know even up in a little bit yeah
yeah so when i reposted that
um got a lot of positive feedback of
people in the comment section
um know that they got a lot of value out
of that episode so
oh yeah a lot of people had reached out
to me too you know on instagram
um you know just you know just telling
me that they got you know good
information but they also just wanted to
go a little deeper
into like um you know figure out exactly
what i'm using with my soil
you know it's cool not you know not just
five people it was like maybe about
30 people that hit me up yeah yeah you
know so you're definitely reaching a lot
of people man
that's awesome that's awesome yeah and
that's what i hope to to accomplish in
this episode is kind of digging down to
that next level of things
you know exactly what you do in your
processes
um you know we all grow a little bit
differently right you have your
methods i have some methods that i do
differently um the people are listening
they all have their individual methods
and goals and so on and so forth so
that's what i kind of try to accomplish
within the show or podcast
it's just really talking one-on-one with
growers
finding out what they do in their garden
and then the listeners can
listen in and potentially implement some
of those best practices in their garden
so
it's been helpful so far and uh
definitely glad that you're back for a
second
second time around yeah i appreciate it
too and it's like it's not what we all
do you know we see other people doing
things you know
um right you know but then we we take
all different people
to make it our own way you know yeah i
love that you know
so for those that are just seeing you
for the first time maybe
once you tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into growing
all right um you know from uh from a
young age i was always
in the plant um i would i would be you
know inspecting
inspecting them you know checking out
their flowers uh real close
and uh you know my dad he would you
would have a vegetable garden every year
as
far back as i can remember i'd admire
you know the way
you would have everything lined up you
know everything would be healthy
um you know i i would just want to
figure out how to do it myself
um my grandmother to my nana uh she
would have house plants they would live
for years you know and look beautiful
and i'd wondered
how to do that too and when i got older
i was starting to get
my own skills you know and doing that
stuff nice
yeah my my grandmother actually grows
vegetables too and that's i think that's
one thing that's kind of strengthened
the bond between me and her is that
we have something to talk about right we
talk about the vegetables growing and
just growing
so it's really cool yeah and then you
know you can take it a step further you
guys can enjoy them together
you know you put them at the table you
know it's not just you get it from a
supermarket you guys can enjoy something
you grew together
it's great you know i love that and uh
but how i got into growing though you
know like
you know i just from growing other
things yeah
you know and then i started growing
cannabis at an early age you know
i just was hooked to the growing
candidates um you know i just wanted to
figure out how to make the best flower
for myself primarily you know um because
i
want to have to rely on other people to
get it simple as that you know so um
you know later on it just honed my
skills in that that way
cool um so last time we talked you were
growing 100 organically
primarily growing outdoors you had
mentioned that you've grown indoors in
the past
are you still growing uh organic no-till
living soil
outdoors oh yeah for sure you know um
everything i do outdoor
um is all organic um i don't i like to
be conscious of
you know uh the ecosystem and what's
going into
the river or something if i have a lot
of runoff you know so i like to not use
synthetics i like to just use
soil and water and you know keep it
simple
um just like you know just like nature
and stuff like that
but indoors um you know i will i will
use the synthetic indoor yeah
and i checked your instagram you are
going indoors now i saw some plants in
there
before we hop deep into the outdoor
organic side which
will primarily be this episode um just
talk a little bit indoors can you just
maybe briefly talk about you know what
size grow room you're in
indoors how many plants you're running
what you're using for lighting things
like that
yeah so um it varies you know i have a
about an eleven by eleven flower room uh
my veg space
is ten by ten um but i with that veg
space it does a lot more than just uh
power my my flower room um it you know i
got out
you know my outdoor locations um i'll
veg plants up
you know as big as i can get them coming
into season and then put them into um
you know large volumes of organic soil
and just let them go crazy you know just
to get what i can
as far as like lighting
in that 11 by 11 flower room i'm using
leds
using the fluent spider two eyes and i
just recently bought some
of the spectre pros i'm just really
liking the leds you know what they're
giving me
um structure you know flower structure
and then
my veg space i'm using t5s in the cloner
t5s out of the flowers still under t5s
and then i move them on to under like a
315 cmh a couple of those
to uh ready them for the for the flower
room
um but uh for plants like how many
plants i put into them
into that flower room it'll vary like um
since
um you know legal plan counts 12 i like
to stay at
12 you know nothing over 12 in flower
even though you could fill a canopy with
however many
you know small plants to fill a canopy i
like to just keep it at that legal plant
so like google plant counts so
you know for my four lights like a six
to nine plant
is where i keep it at nice not not too
not too big a pots either i keep them
at most you know six gallons the biggest
spot to go up to for indoor
i would since that what line are you
using for synthetics
right now i'm using house and garden um
and uh you know
you could literally use general hydro a
and d
you know and if you have your
environment dialed and you also are
dialing in your feed ph
you see temperature everything all that
stuff is dialed
you can come out with a very nice
product doesn't matter what the line
they all have
the same kind of stuff in them just
different ratios and that's why they can
put a different
name on it got it so even though you
primarily grow organic
and you know you're all about organics
passionate about that um
you still do utilize synthetic nutrients
yeah i do know for sure i do see a use
for it indoors
you know like when you're you when
you're in small volumes of soil
and um you know you still want the plant
to be fed and progress
and get bigger um say for mother or um
whatever production say like i was
saying my my uh
veg space how it it does more than just
power that power that one 4x4 flower
you know um with synthetics i'm able to
achieve that you know i can clone
hundreds of clones however many i take
off i can have them all rooted ready to
go
and and then i put them and then outdoor
i can put that
into um an organic medium and then it's
organic after that it's
it's you know i'm just giving it uh in
organic inputs
okay so let's flip back to the organic
side of things let's um
let's start from the kind of the very
beginning with grill pot size
so you can talk about what grill pot
size you use and what type of grill pot
to use
i use all all types of pots for indoor
and outdoor indoor
in particularly for synthetics i like to
use plastic just because you can just
pop them out
real easily for transplant um it's clean
up is really easily
uh easy i don't like how like if you're
going to use a smart pot
cloth with synthetics you're going to
have to wash
the synthetic out of the cloth you know
if i'm
with living soil um i like to i like to
use a breathable pot
um like a smart pot um grassroots fabric
pots
uh those rain science you know a lot of
different kinds of breathable pots but i
just like when the air uh the
roots can air prune to the sides um and
then also
um it's able to you know breathe more um
and dry out
not stay too wet but for indoors for
living soil uh like if you're gonna do
for
for the pot size for its last pot for it
to flower in i don't go anything less
than 30 gallons
um anything less than 15 gallons i mean
so you should do 15
or nothing less than that basically
because if you're gonna if you're gonna
do that you're gonna have to give it a
synthetic or
supplement with something outdoors
um you know i'll use um 1 to 45 gallons
100 to 200 gallons i like to
build trenches and fill them up you know
and do raised beds so for those that
don't know
maybe you're watching my channel for the
first time i've been growing for
11 years now and i think eight years my
first eight years was just all synthetic
nutrients three
gallons five gallon grow pots indoors
basically my entire time i've grown a
couple outdoor plants but
i don't call myself an outdoor grower
but i've slowly ventured over to the
organic side of the thing so i'm trying
to wean my way off those bottles
and a method that i'm trying is um
and i've been recommended what i've been
told is seven gallons at the minimum
for um for organics and i keep my plants
very small so that might have to do with
it as well
so a technique that i'm going to try
this time around is
vegging out in one gallon containers
kind of shaping it the way i want to
shape it and then
shortly before flipping to flour go into
that seven gallon
that's you know heavily amended with the
organic nutrients
that way hopefully it makes it through
most of flour if not the entire flour
right
kind of giving it that last super soil
right before flipping to flower so i'm
going to see if that works but
i probably will after listening to you
and and some other people
you know 15 gallons 30 gallons is
probably yeah
yeah but that's when you know your
timing may be better than mine you know
my timing isn't
isn't always on point you know so my
roots are definitely bigger than the pot
you know um you know so like i i love to
shape a plant before it gets into that
medium like i was saying like vegging
plants indoors i can veg them with
synthetics
get them to a big you know big state get
them into an organic medium
and then they you know um their vascular
system can can um
become you know with organic meat uh
nutrients instead of synthetic nutrients
you know and there is a little bit of a
transition
period you know um but like we were
saying though um when you take like a
small
one gallon or something and then right
as you transplant it
you flower very shortly after that the
roots are still having gotten into that
seven gallon
you know it there could very well be
enough food for the plant
um especially if you do multiple of
those you know
definitely have the plants at a
manageable size you know that a good
airflow can still
be achieved um you know it's all about
timing and stuff
like i'm saying my timing isn't always
on my clones are
aren't always as healthy as i want them
when i want to put them in flour
you know or something like that so it's
like i'm usually using a veg plant that
i have
that's been vegging for a while that i
put in that's got it
okay so what is uh actually in your mix
i do like to use my
make my own soil outdoor because i'm not
i don't like to buy you know
yards and yards of some company soil it
does cost a lot you know
especially when i have things on hand um
that i could make myself
um so like i would start with like a
base soil and you need to just source
you know good quality earthworm castings
or compost you get that and
you combine it with cute moss and some
form of aeration
and the aeration i like to use pumice
and then the second best i like to use
is a hydroton clay and then
if i have to i use perlite the reason
why i don't like using pearlite too much
when you buy it in quantity there's a
lot of dust that i kind of need to
um clean clean out uh you know so i'll
use the top of the bag
and then once i get towards the bottom
i'm you know i'm not like dumping that
the rest of it on there you know i don't
want to have that dust in it
um but uh yeah so i'll start with that
as a base oil
i'll combine those three things together
on a certain ratio so like what i like
to do
is they um third third third so 33 33 33
mix
um of the compost earthworm casting
peat moss and aeration and once i get
those
um mixed together i have a base soil and
that base oil
you know depending on the quality of
your earthworm castings
and your compost can get you through
many weeks of veg
you know give you plenty of vegetative
matter you require for
for flour um and then
so what i do with that base oil is is
make it into super soil you know and i
had amendments
i uh add amendments to that the one that
i use um and what i've been using for
many years now
um is the claddin's coots recipe and
it's a little bit of a modified one
which is super simple which is like i'm
saying you start with that base soil
so and then per cubic foot you do this
ratio uh personal per cubic foot we put
a half cup
of mean seed meal a half cup of kelp
meal uh half cup crab meal
and then you put a fourth cup of gypsum
and then another half cup
of oyster shell flour and then two cups
of basalt rock dust and i'll mix
that into uh per cubic foot
and however quantity i need and then
i'll have my super soil after i let it
sit for 60 to 90 days about
um definitely you know definitely you
don't want to use it before then
because you say sorry did you say 60 to
90 days you let it sit
that's um especially in quantity you
know if you have a small batch
you know and like a bin i'm sure you can
get get away with it being
faster you know um but like when you're
controlling moisture content and you got
to move
move a big pile i i 60 to 90 days is
just where i
you know before i put my plants until
i'm like comfortable with the plants
there with no problems you know
uh because that mix so that mix that i
told you is um
is a pretty uh hot mix too you know so
like
if that's that's a no-till mix because
you'll be able to get
you know multiple multiple runs out of
it with giving just little top dress
you know um or something like that a
couple other things i do like to add
into it which makes it a little bit of
the modified one is uh insect fresh
alfalfa meal and fish meal you know so
i'll i'll use
those sparingly with as much as i have
whether it be on the bottom of the pot
before i plant or
while it's already established on top
i'll kind of talk through some of that
stuff on
uh sometimes but um you know as far as
my mix goes you know
you could use in-depth inside you know
um
you know or or just outside um but
outside i would also add more organic
matter whatever organic matter you can
have that's been sitting around for a
while
whether it be rotting wood maybe at the
bottom of your pot you know it can just
kind of retain water good
and stuff um you know especially for you
know say a huge
uh hubel trench you know which is
utilizing rotting wood
and culturing fungus in that wood
whether it already be in the wood
you know um there so outdoor you know
the mix that i would use it just
as much organic matter as i can get
together to make the volume bigger
um to to uh for what i need say it be a
large
trench for a hugel you know or or a
large rage bed or something like that
but i also like get bag soil too i'm not
afraid to use uh some companies
like stonington from coast to maine
right out of the cloner a lot of uh like
any of my cuts all all the clones that i
have that have been around for a long
time
go solo cup right in the stones and you
know water with water
and just been for like for weeks you can
keep it in that and
they're no with no problems you know um
and
that's why i like to use some bag soil
another one roots organic 707
i won't use it inside because um usually
it has bugs but
outside i'll you know if i'm short on
some quality
soil i need to veg some plants in to get
them bigger early in season i'll go buy
some roots 707 to get them
into a bigger volume to not be sitting
in the pot they've been in for a while
um uh nectar for the god sunshine for
our view
another good one you know build the soil
i love build the soil they're light mix
their 3.0 mix
all stuff that i'll use for sure that's
all good living soil bag
you know before when i was when i was
growing up they didn't have these types
of
bag soil you know there there were
companies that were that were doing this
type of stuff
got it let's talk about water which type
of water
do you use for your plants ro tap
distilled what makes most sense for my
location and situation always use our
water
probably for um with when i use
synthetics you know i like the idea
i like the idea of just starting with
just straight water you know nothing in
it
and then me being in control of what i
put in it and then what the plants
get you know so um you're completely
scared in the ship
you know when i think about synthetics
um when i
i use pre-filtered well water um at
locations i'm growing organic you know
so while water's got minerals in it um
from where you're at that you'll you'd
be adding to the
adding to the soil or the water already
so it's just
you don't have to um take it out other
other than like when i say pre-filter
iron you know so i'll i'll have a
pre-pre-iron filter before
um i give that to my plants because you
could definitely give too much iron to
your
your plants in water especially when you
can see it when it's like brown and
brownish from a couple
a couple uh spots that one tap water all
right so like say
uh it's from a town i i don't like to
use that at all just because
unless it's um pre-filtered pre chlorine
filter so de-chlorinated
because i just don't like the idea of
having chlorine um
um and especially with organics because
it could
you could destroy you know
microorganisms
uh so you know pre-filtering your tap
water
especially if you're in the city you
know because they are 100 adding
chlorine to it
you know um if you if you take some
water and res it
uh and if you have to use tap water and
you don't have a filter
you could like read some water and a
friend told me this you could
just literally stir it with your arm and
your your skin actually takes the
chlorine out of the water pretty
effectively
um and you don't have to do it very long
you do it for five minutes
four or five minutes not even not even
and you take a large percentage
like 80 percent of the chlorine out of
the water so it's pretty interesting
wow yeah right and you just mix it with
your arm
you know um so someone that doesn't have
the means of uh
the filter this and that they you know
but you're using tap water and has
chlorine in it
that's a way to take it out because your
body is a better you know might as well
we we filter out in the plant um you
know and especially not just the plant
the organisms that are are working with
the plant yeah i know
um so how long would you dip your hand
in there do you say like
well like i'm saying you know like um
say like it's a 55 gallon drum
stirred around with your whole arm for
four minutes like and that's
that's even a long time you know and
it's obviously you know sitting there
for
four or five minutes just stirring with
your arm but it that literally takes out
about 80 plus percent of
the chlorine that would come out of your
tap water and when you think about like
you go into a pool
and you come out and you smell like
chlorine and that's it
it's absorbed into your skin quite quite
quickly you know
and then the alternative ways to
dechlorinate would be just to you know
let your water sit out for
24 hours or so in light is ideal right
and then
um some people like air stones in it too
right air stones will kind of help
with dechlorinate gotcha yep um i
i may have heard that you know may off
gas but i've just heard
you know i've heard if you know if you
don't have a filter and you don't have a
way of deploying it
dechlorinating before you know just just
literally starting it with your arm
takes so much out
it's so simple and once my friend told
me that i was like damn i'll just you
know do that just to ensure that my plan
is even houseplant you know
sure how sponsors turn around you think
it's nothing but it's like you do it for
a little bit you're actually you're
actually making an effect on the water
because
your body your skin is absorbing it you
know that's interesting i didn't know
that
i actually tried to do a run with indoor
grow with tap water now my tap water
comes out at
485 ppm
so that's really high i think five over
500 is against like epa guidelines or
something like that so
are you in like are you in like an old
old building or like a cat uh like a
city city yeah yeah gotcha it could be
old pipes
you know very old pipes maybe it must be
yeah and i was looking at the water
sample report that they release
and it's like 80 ppm sodium so i think
that's like pretty high
and that's like it just destroyed my
plants like my plants i've never had
as unhealthy of plants before when i
used tap water and that's even when
with dechlorinating so like i've been
avoiding i've just been using ro for now
on
sodium yeah sodium will make your plants
look terrible i'm sure you know
and then it makes you realize how how um
how important
your water source is you know like your
starting water you know that's when i'm
thinking about synthetics it's like rl
you know just
oh i test it it's just zero ppm you know
it's like liquid gold to me when i think
about it you know
because you can dial you can dial it
into a t it's not gonna like uh you're
not gonna have many swings
phys up and down i don't know yeah
so speaking of do you ph your water all
right so
for synthetics um i always love to dial
you know
just dialing it in knowing what they're
getting um you know whether
you know i like to know the in and out
you know i'll even test my runoff um so
i do like to ph my water when i do feed
synthetics
um outdoors um depending on your
starting water you know like if it's
really high or low like you're saying
you know your your town water or
whatever the ph is i'm sure they have
haven't picked out quite
stable ph but like at my farm um
you know we have like a 6.2 to 6.5 well
water you know we don't have to change
that at all
you know so um but depending on our
input that we put into that water
whether it be like a t
brew it'll change the ph but i'm not
worried about
uh changing the ph of a t brew you know
something like that you don't have to
it's like there's so many buffers for
organics like in the organic medium it's
it's a buffer zone itself
you know there's so many different ph
ranges happening um you know it stays in
stable zone you know so like you can
give it
you know something that's a roundabout
and it'll become stable
um you know so if you're giving water to
a plant and it's not
it's not a living medium then you're
going to influence the
that ph very heavily just by the giving
you know
it's like um if you water to run off
you're resetting
um that that pot you know every time
so what if you gave it a certain ph
you're heavily going to influence it
it's um you know whether it goes up or
down well water out
when i make my super soil you know out
at the at like a farm location
while water right out of the hose you
know right onto the threat onto it not
having to worry about
ph because i know that i already tested
it that it's already in my range
basically
yeah yes yeah cool it is important
yeah you know because if you're not in
that range you know then you know things
aren't happening exchanges aren't
happening with the plant
and nutrient and um yeah you could just
things go really awry when you're not in
the right ph so
for sure you know it's good to know it
okay so we talked about pot size we
talked about your mix the initial
amendments that you put in there kind of
how you
how you're doing your watering um let's
talk about cover crops so you've planted
your seed
do you do any cover crops and when do
you plant them would you plant them at
the same time or
or different time or what gotcha um
yeah you know so i i kind of just always
used um
white dutch clover you know it's very
very available easy to get
uh buckwheat another one easy to get
um vetch you know
alfalfa so like a couple different kinds
of clover you can use um
red um crimson medium red
um yellow clover you know all good all
good ones but uh you know what you know
what they're doing
is um you know promoting mycorrhizal
fungi population you know and that's
what you want in your meat in your
organic medium
um when i start it you know so um
i'll start i'll use white dutch clover
from a solo cup
you know one gallon net all the way up
because
if the plant has not grown into the pot
completely and the top soil is not like
root system when you water it you'll
you'll have a disturbance of the medium
um you know and then when you start to
continuously water um it's not going to
evenly water the pot so if you have if
you have that white dutch clover on the
top
at whatever stage of growth you have
another root system for you to just
water on
um you can water heavily and it's not
gonna you know it'll drain better
because
those root systems are penetrating down
you'll just have a better um
oxygen oxygenation of your root zone um
just from having
just a little bit of white dutch clover
at whatever stage you grow um
but i i use a 12 seed cover crop
from from build the soil um and then it
can it consists of a lot of stuff i just
said but
it's also got like uh cow pee it's got
um peas like forage peas you would eat
you know uh
the buckwheat but consists of 12
different kinds of seeds you can
put you i i put that in the pot prior to
planting in it
um say like a couple weeks get
everything germinated it's all going you
know
and then even at the end of the season
you know um
after you crop your plants you got your
immediate your beds
or whatever outside um primarily beds
you uh you plant your cover crop in the
winter
even in the wintertime and uh as soon as
it comes to season you know they're not
going to germinate depending on how the
season goes when it's thaws and stuff
but a lot of them will potentially um
germinate as soon as the season comes
you know so you will also plant more as
the season
is there you know but it's like you
already put
seeds there that will germinate as soon
as they're able to outside
naturally you know so at the end of the
season when it's gonna go in the winter
and your beds are gonna be sitting there
all winter
plant coffee crop um and then in the
beginning of the season before you
plant lynch cover crop you'll have when
the when the soil is barren
and doesn't have any other other uh
plants on it yet
then you you know you plant these
beneficial
things and then you're gonna have less
weeds kind of you know you don't have to
um
chop and grow you don't have to choose
selectively weed you know you already
have
beneficial there um coverings covering
the ground
which will um take competition away the
other things that would have germinated
aren't able to germinate because you
have a more developed plant there
already
you know so the earlier you can get a
cover crop on the ground outdoor
is better you know as early as possible
and then when the ground is really
thawed to plant ganja you know then get
your ganja in the ground
okay so cover crop uh what about mulch
layer
so you know common practices for for
when growing organically is also have a
mulch layer on top of it you know
uh some people plant their cover crops
and then put the mulch layer immediately
over it and have the cover crop kind of
grow through the mulch layer
what do you use for mulch layer and how
do you apply it yeah you know it i mean
everyone's different methods but you
know aside from my my
living cover crop which acts as a you
know a mulch layer
i like to use barley hay rice halls
oak leaves you know whatever organic
matter for outdoor particularly you know
whatever organic matter you can just
kind of chop up put on top your soil
just to make it so the sun isn't just
hitting your top soil directly it's
you know it's not it's gonna make it dry
out faster than it should um
when you can have uh any kind of
any kind of cover it could it could even
be a
completely dead you know say you just
put like um
like those row covers um cloth i mean
you know just
a cloth cover and it's and it's gonna
make it so just the sun isn't hitting it
directly it's just staying a little
more wet you know more homogenous you
know longer that's definitely the
purpose of having mulches
i i know people that don't use them but
because their irrigation strategy
is you know they're monitoring their
moisture
so you know they're just continuously
irrigating and this is primarily indoor
and when i grow outdoor it's like you
you're dealing with the sun you know so
it's you
you gotta um you gotta use like living
cover crop
you know leaves mulch some like i'm
saying any kind of organic matter that
you can get together to put on top
you know just just to make it
more wet because what that's going to do
is just prevent
promote life you know you could have uh
roots growing right to the top layer you
just kind of
put pull back your your cover crop or
your your hay or whatever
and then roots are growing right up into
our worms or are eating things up to on
top
you know yeah i learned the hard way
when i first switched to organics is i
live in a very dry climate i live in the
desert
and you know that top soil drying out i
mean the microbes are going dormant
right they're not
actively breaking down uh the organic
matter at that time right so
yeah me not using mulch layer i kind of
screwed myself especially with the top
dressing right because you're applying
the top dressing
if you're not putting a mulch layer over
it well then if that top layer dries out
you're not getting the break down and
your plants are seeing deficiencies
that's what happened with meat at least
so yeah the importance of a mulch layer
particularly for for someone like me
yeah living in such a dry climate
yeah you know these are you know these
type of strategies that you can do with
you know you know it gives you options
you know you're in a desert
you know if you're grown with you know a
different medium you just keep on
irrigating it you know that's it you
just have to keep hearing you want to
retain water you know
watering it the least amount of times
that that's more sustainable you know
um so especially if you're growing food
outside you know you'd be
say irrigated at night you're in the
desert irrigated at night because if
you're if you're
you're here again during the day it's a
lot of evaporation happening you know so
if you just irrigate them all throughout
the night
potentially they can get through the
whole day without being watered so yeah
you don't depend it depends for sure
and i think you also mentioned in a
previous conversation that you also do
like the
cut method where you're kind of cutting
down the cover cup and then laying that
down
or um i don't know if you mentioned the
leaves if you do like any
defoliation and and lay those down as a
cover cup as well do you do that at all
oh 100 multiplayer
shop oh definitely so chop and drop with
no-till
you know and with using you know these
living soil methods
you can just take all of your especially
no-till method because you're utilizing
worms in
a you know living soil system you can
just take everything that just
came off of that plant vegetably and put
it back into the pot or
you know or bed that you used um and
think about it as like the only thing
that comes out of that pot is the actual
nugs itself in the end you know
everything else can go back into it you
could chop up the
stems everything and get it back onto
there mulch it back into it you know
cannabis
stem mulch is you know best especially
if it was
or grown organically you know um
and uh so like we were referring to say
like your mulch
uh grows up too much you know it's
getting out of control
starting to grow up to you know and
starting to make airflow with strict
airflow you could cut it back to a
manageable level and then you could take
all that organic matter
um put it underneath the living uh cover
crop
and then um it's gonna stay wet it's
gonna stay green
for weeks literally um and and worms
will be able to have an opportunity to
uh to feed on it for that time
instead of it say it'd be on barren soil
top soil
and say the sun's hitting it not indoors
strengthening it it'll turn into
carbon you know it'll it'll lose its
moisture and become like a dry
crinkled leaf so quick you know instead
of you just putting it under something
you can literally just put under a rock
like i'll take like a lot of chop and
drop like say like uh leads i take off
the plant
and i'll just take like uh one of the
rocks i have in the alleyway
i'll just put it underneath that you
know and that's just worm food
you know and within a few weeks it's
already earthworm gas since it's already
turned to
you know turn to soil what type of worms
do you use
nate you know the native worms in my
area i like to think about it as i'm
creating a you know
somewhere for them to live you know like
my uh um
my dog beds my hugel mounds uh my raised
beds
they all are like connected to the earth
and have a way
of native native uh worms to come into
it and i don't even have to buy worms or
add any worms you know but
if i i have bought worms and the only
ones that i have bought are red wigglers
you know so um those are really good
living soil system
basically you only have to you know if
you want to
uh buy stuff for a living soil uh for
indoors all you really need is just red
wiggles but you can diversify it
and go outside and go get some stuff
like you're gonna go fishing and you go
get some
forms outside and then you bring them
inside so you have a worm bin
and then you put them in your worm bin
and now you're diversifying your
your work you know your worms yeah then
there's also what the night crawlers so
the the red wigglers is kind of up top
soil and then the night crawlers kind of
lower
part of the soil yeah yeah yeah i forgot
to say
african nightcrawlers you know that's
another great one they definitely are
able to um
to get you know deep you know they're
they're fat some of them look like
snakes you know
um and uh yeah afghanistan those
you know those two for sure the red red
wigglers and the african nightcrawlers
and like i'm saying any native worm that
can that can come and
live there that's beneficial and stuff
so i know you already kind of said a
little bit of advice but you have any uh
advice for somebody who's just trying
out worms for the first time maybe
you know is there a specific amount they
should use for a size grill pot or
or what yeah like uh say like you're
putting uh worms
um into a 15 gallon soil
15 got like a handful and that's like a
perfect amount you know that
and especially if that soil is you know
good living soil system where they're
able to proliferate and
you know um and reproduce and those eggs
are
you know they're not just gonna you're
not gonna water something on it's gonna
kill everything
uh i mean if you're gonna start out new
you know try and have a worm bin you
know because then you can buy worms
and then you you know like i'm saying
other than just your
your your pots you're growing in you
could have them reproducing and
you could just take kitchen scraps and
you know have them
make soil um you know if you're if
you're using if you're going to start
out using worms it's great you're just
going to be
building soil for yourself i know um
yeah love worms okay let's flip over and
talk about ipm
i know you really like to talk about ipm
in our last conversation you talked
quite a bit about
ipm what do you do for ipm i like to
incorporate
you know beneficial insects um
uh like another like again you know i
like to have the beneficial insects of
my area come
and inhabit you know my um my garden
and and i invite them in you know um
so i don't have to order them basically
so like mantis ladybugs
um pirate beetles you know lace wings
tread or my other different kinds of
predator mites as far as sprays go you
know
outdoor i'll use like aloe vera flakes
neem oil
um karanji oil um
yucca for fighting like a pest
i'll use the karanja oil and the neem
oil as like a
like right away it'll kill them you know
it's like direct
i'll i'll prune everything off the plant
and then i'll hit him with i'll hit him
with that
karanja but if i'm not and i'm just kind
of doing preventative spray
you know you know to prevent pests and
mold
it's always like a uh aloe flake um
with yucca which is just a wetting agent
you know just so things stay wetter
longer
um so i think of it and um and it's like
you're just kind of washing them down
um periodically whenever you want you
know you can put be on your own schedule
um your own itunes ipm schedule for your
outdoor plants just kind of wash them
down with
aloe indoors i i spray
a couple things 203 and 209 from sns
i'll also root drench a couple of those
whenever a problem like if i have like
fungus gnats i'll i'll
also drench 209 for like a whole week
and i'll uh
i'll i'll eliminate the fungus gnats
refer for synthetic you know indoors
i know jay plants for outdoor jade plant
speaker he'll spray
periodically uh em5 can build the soil
um you know which is keeps things very
sterile
and it's organic so he'll do that all
throughout
you know his processes until he gets the
flower which then he doesn't
doesn't uh spray anything and i feel the
same way i don't like spraying anything
in flowers like your ipm
is the preventative you know
preventative for that um proper pruning
air movement
you know that's crucial you know uh
that's all that's part of an ipm
regiment you know um
periodically making sure there's enough
air flow um
and your air quality and your spaces are
are adequate for the plant's health
and stuff like that it's super crucial
um
indoors i'll spray plants with citric
acid
you can make your own solution of it but
i like to just use the big
time exterminator which is just
basically citric acid dilute you know
uh and that i've i've used that i've
killed thrips i've killed um aphids
uh on clones which i took from outdoor
brought them in
um and they and then after a couple
weeks i see i see thrips and stuff on
them i'll spray them with that with that
um citric acid uh
every day for two weeks and uh like i'm
like i'm power washing the plant
and i'm and and i get them good you know
that stuff
you know so that's another good uh
another good thing to use that the
plants aren't going to be negatively uh
affected by and you can douse them with
uh with a dilute citric acid you
definitely don't want to be
you know used too much that's why i use
uh the big time exterminator you know
they're doing the dilution for me i
don't have to put
any uh you know i don't have to dilute
it myself and [__] up you know
things like that got it now are you are
you rotating these
sprays so you're doing it like a
different spray yeah okay yeah
for sure yeah like um yeah all those
ones i listed you know i'll i'll
i'll uh i'll switch it up um and and
uh you know when i switch it up i i'm
not running into problems you know the
only problem i run into
indoors is just a couple like nap you
know or something like that which a lot
of growers can have problems with but i
use nematodes
and uh and a couple sprays to get rid of
them
quickly you know one other thing i use
for an ipm is that cap and jack
dead bug you know that's a good thing i
like to have things that i can just
spray all over the plant and it's not
going to negatively affect it
um you know even though i i did list uh
that meme and karanja you 100
can use too much you know you want to
use be sparing you want to just think
about it as you're
you're you're kind of putting a
sunscreen on your your plant
um and the plan and then an insect or
something
won't enjoy it if they come and try and
eat it something like that you know you
don't want to put too much
because if you use too much oil sun is
hitting it and you put too much oil
you can burn your plant just from the
sun magnifying against it
you know and especially when it's in
water so water and oil
and then the sun you're literally just
magnifying it on on the leaf it'll burn
it
okay so we talked about how you you have
that initial mix and you're adding the
abandonments
it's super soil right and and
you're trying to get through the entire
grow with just that
super soil now do you do any type of top
dressings
throughout the grow at all if so when do
you apply them and what do they consist
of
i apply worm casting to plants at
all stages you know uh quality earthworm
castings i'll just put it right on the
top soil and water them in real good um
like i'm saying at any stage all the way
to end of flower if i want you know top
you know earth earthworm castings are
great um
top dress i top dress compost and i'll
water that in real good
i use bio live um down to earth
fertilizers you know that's uh that's
super simple
um top dress that on i'll do that like
when i transplant
like maybe after like three weeks in the
flower
i'll you know i'll uh hit i'll put some
bio live on top
it just consists of like it's fish bone
meal um
fish meal alfalfa meal crab meal shrimp
meal
lambonite and kelp you know so just a
bunch of organic stuff
whatever you have laying around when you
start buying you know a lot of bags
of organic amendments make your super
soil you're gonna have a lot of extra
stuff
so um you know whatever's laying around
at a time you can you can kind of give
them a little boost and top dress that
on when it's needed
when they're at when they're kind of
asking for it got it so you just kind of
look at the plant kind of read the plant
maybe you see
it fades a little bit and then and then
you apply it at that point okay
yeah definitely and depending on the
stage you know just depending where
they're supposed to be
you know where um what i know where
they're supposed to be um at certain
stages of flower or veg
um and uh and like i'm saying like i'll
top dress when i like
when i trans when i freshly transplant
or say if something has been sitting in
a pot for a long time and its roots have
taken it up i
definitely have to get something on top
for it to start feeding again
because the ganja plants root system uh
it's like a
it's like a upside down um iceberg
it's feeder roots they're all on top
when you have it in a pot it's like it's
it'll like take up the pot but if it was
on the ground
it would just spread out like spread
right out it'll it'll penetrate pretty
good
so um a clone will penetrate the ground
14 inches
and a seed will penetrate into the
ground 36 inches
and that's because of the tap root and
um you know so
you think of it like oh well i have a
pot that's long you know bigger than 36
inches and went all the way to the
bottom
that's those are feeder roots that would
have been on the top and they literally
just go
down you know they're in a pot they're
in a pot and they're restricted being
restricted in all all
you know all directions so it has to
compensate for that now do you
incorporate any sugars into your garden
i don't i mean i use molasses sometimes
but you know someone said to me like oh
that's like putting tar
all over your garden you know i i
understand when you use too much of it
but i know people that use it sparingly
and have good results you know so
sometimes i will use it when i
want to see a fattening in flower you
know to give a boost to the population
of microbes
you know because those are what's going
to work for me so that's the that's the
reason for using a sugar you know as a
food source you know um but
it's like there's other food sources
other than you know
i i just i haven't they've dived into
using others
other kinds of sugars one thing i i do
use is brown sugar
but i use it to um to make
korean natural farming inputs so k f uh
like
fpj um from fermented plant juice or
making um a fish amino acid faa
so you know you could just take fish you
know or plant
and you weigh them out and then you add
brown sugar and
the brown sugar is taking out the water
out of that you know so
you know i'm using it i'm utilizing the
osmotic pressure of that sugar
but then i all i'm also use it it'll
act as a food source you know for
microbes when i water that
in as well but uh not primarily straight
brown sugar you know i won't just put
brown sugar in the water and not water
that in
so you know molasses and the brown sugar
from
my uh k f inputs are the only two sugars
i use
gotcha yeah what about microbial
inoculants do you use any of those
um i like root wise organics um in
for indoors great white mammoth microbe
at you know azo um em1 em1 is uh
is lactic acid bacteria well not just
lactic acid bacteria but um
you know that's another thing i'll add
i'll make my own lab
um you can take you can take uh
unpasteurized milk
right you know right out of the cow and
you mix it with water that
you add you take rice you wash the rice
off you watch this
wash the stock start off the rice and
you take that rice
washed water and you mix it with the
unpasteurized milk
and you can you can make a serum of
lactic acid bacteria
and that's inoculate you can use in
water and give to your plants you could
spray
lab on your plants it'll prevent mold
and then when you
water it into the soil it breaks things
down readily
and think about it as like utilizing the
stomach
of the of the cow um it's bacteria it
has like five stomachs and it has
these lactic acid bacteria you know in
its stomachs is the same thing as us
but you know we have lactic acid but
they also have they have five stomachs
of it you know
so you're utilizing what that does in
its stomach
in water and then you put over on your
soil and it helps break
things helps break organic matter down
into a soluble form of plants
the other k and f inputs i'll do you
know
which i learned from online chris
through chris trump uh are uh
imo one through five so you'll take
indigenous microorganisms
um which is fungus uh
bacteria living living in your you know
outside in nature
um and you'll you'll capture it and
you'll get that
into a state that you can then
um put into water which then
and you know makes the spores go into
solution and then you water that in so
um that those methods are are um
something i'm very new to the the imo
135. i haven't
dived into it i just know a lot about
him and the way i even know a lot about
them i just literally go on youtube
and go to chris trump's uh youtube and
i'm taking notes on it you know
um until i get my own experience you
know i'm getting good at it
um but you can get it to the point where
you just take like the size of your
pinky you put it in a 55 gallon drum and
you just inoculated the whole drum
with fungus beneficial fungus you know
and that fungus was
captured indigenous in your area right
outside if you have like a
field or something and underneath the
tree
that that you go and you you look under
some leaves it's nice white mycelium
growing that's the stuff
you know you can get that in your own
grow room um not just outside
because that's the best types of
microbes you can use is what's
in your area that grows best in your
climate uh another another kind of
inoculant though you know i'll take
freshly picked mushrooms i got like
beach mushrooms that are growing um
kind of in a low low area on my property
and i'll just take those fresh i'll put
them in a tea bag
that i'll like i would brew a compost
tea in
and i'll just soak those 24 hours very
heavily aerated
and then just water that all over all
over the bed and then i'll take what's
in the bag
and i'll just mulch that on the top
layer you know i'll take that all those
chopped up uh
mushrooms i harvested a couple of few
days you know yesterday
and then just mulch that all over the
top soil um
i've seen uh you know big blooms of of
mycelium come after i do that
so con area to compost teas let's talk a
little bit more more about that
what aerated compost teas do you use do
you do any like nutrient teas
seed spotted teas anything like that i i
like to do
compost tea um in particular um
i'll take earthworm castings i'll take
nice quality compost
and just make a nice aerated tea with
just those things you know
because that's that's a real benefit you
know whenever
you can brew it up you say you want to
do it two to three times a week
and you can you don't have to do the
same key every time you could do just
compost
that you do another tea tea brew of um
uh you throw some mineral in there you
know you basalt
you put oyster shell you flour you could
put some kelp or
whatever like i'm saying whatever you
want to put um
in small amounts and brew it up into
solution but another thing with with
brewing
is the time you do it because you don't
want it to go anaerobic and it can go
anaerobic really quick on you so say you
brew it for
say over 24 hours and i don't like to do
brews more than 24 hours now now that i
learned that type of stuff
you brew it and then you stop the
aeration you don't feed it and you let
it sit there for
not even a day it is very heavily
anaerobic um you know and
and uh you can make things go awry in
your soil system
with with giving them large volumes of
anaerobic teeth you know
or if it's too concentrated and you
don't dilute it i'll definitely make a
tea and then dilute that and then give
it to them
as far as sprouted seed cheese um i
haven't
i haven't used sprouted teas much um at
if
you know if not at all i've taken some
corn and sprout and
done some stuff with corn but um i've
just heard that it can
negatively affect uh fungus um it's
definitely
um going to help the the root system
because it's sending
sending signals um with enzymes that
those
those those seeds had but you could
with the with the possibility of it
negatively affecting you know what i'm
trying
a population of fungus that i'm trying
to promote and
and have lived you know i just don't try
it you know
um i may try it on small volumes of soil
like 30 gallons
and i'll through some seed and i still
haven't done it in all my experience you
know i
um i just know you could pop see you
know sprout a bunch of corn or sprout
seeds
blend them up and then give them the
plants and and it helps them
um i have friends that do it and tell me
it gives them bigger buds
and like i said but then i have people
that tell me it negatively affects
their their fungus that's just why i'm
hesitant to do that it's probably
cute but as far as other oxygenated uh
compost teas fungal
fungal teas you want that type of stuff
to as
often as you can do it like two to three
times a week is a good time is a good
amount a lot you know
um and and sparingly you don't have to
root drench you can just give a little
bit to them
just to keep the soil moist one more
thing about the cheese um
so i i was looking you know i'm building
a tea brewer
right now and i see a lot of people on
the market inflating
the volcano um style which is like you
just it's a big bubble tech
tech and it just sends a big you know uh
amount of air from the bottom up
instead of um doing you know which is
another another kind
of the cyclone you know there's more
moving parts to that cyclone
um key brewer that you'd have to clean
or or whatever but um the volcano one
less moving parts um and it and it
brings you to dissolve oxygen levels
faster so those that's what i'm looking
into i'm just retrofitting a v bottom i
already have
um with a couple things um so i went to
synergyagpro.com
which took me a little bit of time to
find this and they have a stainless
steel manifold
that goes with with clamps on the bottom
of your
uh your v bottom and uh and then you can
hook up
you know a diaphragm pump to that as
well as a
air pump and
in particular you want to use diaphragm
pumps because if you use another pump
with a propeller
you can you can um negatively affect the
microbes you just brewed and
so you could negatively affect them
while you're pumping them to your plants
if you're not using a diaphragm pump
yeah and you're using a pump with a
propeller you know it'll just chop the
little guys
up real good i i just recently i just
recently learned that too which is
pretty intriguing
yeah that is interesting yeah you know
diaphragm pump
type diaphragm pump when you're feeding
when you're feeding a
compost tea you know or you uh you know
do something by gravity or hand feed it
or something like that
so i have a viewer question from the
last episode that we
we filmed you were talking about a
geodesic dome that you were just
perching
purchasing at the time so first off if
you can just explain to the viewers what
a geodesic dome is
and then also how you utilized it how it
turned out for you
the geodesic dome you know it's a dome
made from triangles
and uh that structure itself is super
strong
very very you know it can take a snow a
snow load
um that's why people like using for
greenhouses
you know so say my mine is
rated for 100 feet of snow it's rated
for the an alaskan snow load where the
snow will fall and not melt and then
continue to snow
you know um so the geodesic dome is just
very nice strong structure and then i
have the polycarbonate plates
on the outside of it so it it's rated
for 25 years
some people when they have their
polyethylene coupe houses
you got to replace it sometimes every
season maybe if you can get by maybe
three years two to three years
and then you're replacing your plastic i
like the idea of just being you know me
use buying the extra investment and
putting down for polycarbonate
and then um i don't have to replace that
for 25 years i just clean the panels off
on the outside and inside and keep them
you know quality
i haven't been posting much about it the
town that i that we're growing in
um just kind of gave us a hard time when
we were first starting out
you know they saw a lot of plants um and
they came
they came knocking basically you know
and they're all hemp plants though um
but uh i just haven't been posting for
for that reason you know we're kind of
keeping it on the gl
um i will be posting about it in the
future um
once once we're more comfortable we're
doing a lot of retrofitting but uh
soon with that with it um we're we're
going to be installing
the agnetix lights with um either
radiantly heated beds or um
benches and uh which are really cool
because um
those those that will help uh heat the
environment as well
you know so um we're we're excited for
those retrofits um
soon but uh yeah hopefully down the road
um i'll be able to post more about it
um on my instagram but also i'll be
having you know a youtube
that i'll be uh i'll be doing that will
be primarily about the hemp
um so people can look forward to that
about the geodome all right a few more
questions and then i'll let you go
so what advice do you have for growers
who are just getting started with
organics
it's definitely the laid-back form you
know
of growing um you know you have more
more of a buffer zone you know you could
kind of mess something up and it's not
as detrimental as growing
with with salts you know so that's a
good
good thing about you know going down
this this rabbit hole kind of um
but you don't want to you don't want to
go into it thinking you know everything
um you know things could be going well
but then you're
presented with something that's foreign
and you're just not ready
you know so um you definitely want to
kind of wrap your head around
everything that could um what's going on
what could happen
um because uh scaling is tough you know
doing it on a small scale is um
weight really doable but doing organics
on a large scale
you need to be on your toes for sure um
but it could be the very laid back you
know for for growing in on a small scale
and be
the style that people want you know to
get it on cruise control though
like yeah like you need to wrap your
head around it because that's what it
can be
you know it can be you just you're just
watering it you don't have to be doing
much ph of anything and it can give you
more time to do other stuff
so you know and maybe check out chris
trump you know on
on youtube because uh he's one of like a
mentor
and and someone that that um even me you
know with all my experience i'm just
learning so much from every day i take
so many notes and i still need to uh
get into um that um k and f
uh techniques more you know because they
can be so beneficial
um and also maybe follow build the soil
on instagram
check their website out so much free
information everything you could want to
start out as a
you know a home grower you could just
get shipped right to your house you know
and um which is great you know that you
never was an option in the past
um to be to do this organic stuff you'd
have to really look into it
and figure things out yourself which is
tough um
so checking those dudes out it would
give you a real um
one-up for sure that's really good
advice really good advice so
um how can listeners find you and what
do you have upcoming in the future
all right well uh you can you know uh
reach out to me on
on my instagram east coast farmers um at
the east coast farmers
on instagram dm me anytime um you could
uh i'm gonna have a website up
pretty soon i'll be selling uh apparel
um you know grinders
you know these kinds of sweatshirts on
it peacecoastfarmers.com
um and uh but yeah you know and then
another thing the youtube channel which
i'll have a little bit down the road
hopefully this year about the
about the hemp and the geodesic dome um
that you know you could just look up
east coast farmers on youtube
you know we'll we'll have it um and
thanks to you you just type in because
farmers yours is the first one that pops
up
yes yeah hell yeah cool all righty well
uh east coast farmers thank you so much
for coming on
to my show for um well actually this is
the first time you're coming onto this
show
but we had a conversation before thank
you so much for coming on
whole walls of information we covered uh
a lot this time around
so thank you so much everybody who's
watching i will leave a link to his
instagram down in the description
section below so
head on over there give him a follow and
uh
yeah that's pretty much it any final
words i just want to thank you you know
having me on here it's a you know great
opportunity i like the idea of you know
reaching so many people
and uh getting you know good information
out there you know i got it from
others individuals that are you know
trying to get free information out there
like myself too you know so
um we just keep passing that along and
uh hopefully we see a change happen you
know
um in our community for the better you
know and i yeah yeah but it just you
know i appreciate you having me on here
man and
you're doing you know good things with
your youtube and stuff
thank you thank you now of course all
right man have a good one
take care all right man yeah take it
easy
[Music]
you