what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris
aka mr grodd and welcome to my talk
channel this is episode three
of four on the happy hour podcast this
podcast was actually posted on a
different youtube channel
that youtube channel no longer exists
but i figured i would upload this
podcast
to this channel because there's a lot of
good information within these episodes
in this episode i talk with the beast
coast farmers
he is pretty big on instagram he is an
outdoor grower
he does no-till living organics those
are two highly requested
things for this channel outdoor growing
and no-till living organics
in beast coast farmers he has a ton of
information when it comes to this
he's more on the commercial side of
things he's managing hundreds of plants
however nearly all of this information
can be applied to home growing so
if you're a home grower this is
definitely a good podcast to listen to
if you're either doing organics or
looking to get into organics i do
actually have video on this episode it
may not be the best quality but i do
have video
the last couple episodes didn't have any
video so this is an improvement right
but enough of me rambling on let's just
get into the episode
hey everybody we got beast coast farmers
here how you doing man
good not too bad uh we got mr grower
here too how you doing brother
doing pretty good another day another
day in paradise
another day another dollar we're
pretty stoked to have beast coast
farmers on here today i've followed his
instagram for a while
his instagram is beast coast farmers so
yeah man we're just gonna ask you some
questions about your growing style and
go from there word uh mr growit i know
you have some questions for him first so
i'll kick it off yeah i'll kick it off
this time all right so tell us how did
uh how did everything start with
cannabis how did you get into cannabis
and then also talk about how you started
growing how you got into growing
well um my growing came right after i
[ __ ]
like the same season that i had smoked
for the first time
i had started growing that same season
because there's
seeds in my blood but uh um
that i had a i had a i have an older
brother he's four years older than me
and so when i was 10 years old he was 14
and um he was
he was starting to smoke around then and
um so
i was blazing with him when i was 10. so
like i uh he threw away a lot
he threw away the seeds that he had
taken out of the bud
and um and i had remembered that those
seeds were in the trash
and i went through the trash and uh took
him out
and it was actually like right in summer
time it was like the end of june
and um i just you know jeremy i looked
up online dude straight up germinated
those seeds and put them outside
um and just started growing right from
there
right from right after 10 and right up
right every season after that
i you know i was able to get plants
either veg inside
start them outside start them outside
that season
because i didn't have anywhere to grow
indoors at the time but every season
after that i had an outdoor crop
and you know coming all the way until
now but uh
you know i the more i looked up looked
it up in line
and stuff and saw others doing it and um
you know
saw saw this industry coming coming
forward
and i knew that it was going to be you
know legit not just
you know for a job market you know and
um uh that's why i
that's why i like put my i don't know my
heart into it kind of
so your very first grow let's talk a
little bit more about that because
that's usually painful for people right
um your very first grow you said you
used basically bag seed
basic bag and you grew outside i had
like
um you know so i grabbed uh miracle grow
soil you know and uh just straight up
just
started doing trial and error like um
before that
before they were out they put were put
outside they were in a uh
a cardboard box they had like some cfls
in it i made like a
small exhaust and intake dude like this
is all when i was like 10 years old so
and uh it was in my closet and then my
mom finds it and they're like my mom's
like
get these plants out of the house you
know for sure and then right
the day after that like i already put
them right outside so like
yeah that's what kind of started my
outdoor growing like it kind of i was
like
in the beginning dude i was all about
chems it's funny like
hydroponics chems and growing indoor
completely sterile
you know my my organic side just kind of
like
came from just keep keep on growing
outdoor every single season just um
you know and like like you're saying you
know some people's first grows are
absolutely terrible and
stuff and stuff but um you know like
mine wasn't too bad
in the beginning you know i've had you
know some terrible [ __ ] happen indoor
but i had a lot of that trial and error
when i was a little kid you know like
learning like drainage and um and uh
just you know proper like weight you
know how much you should water a plant
and then
and stuff like that did you run into
like bugs and stuff outside when you
first started
like how did you deal with that i was
right about to mention that like
i uh i have never seen a a spider mite
in my outdoor garden
ever in my all my years are growing and
um i've you know i've gone i've gone to
other
other places not far from my area and um
you know i've seen you know infestations
and [ __ ] so it kind of like
it's pretty funny to think about but i
also have like right next to me
uh cranberry bugs so they also spray
pesticides so that's just one thing i
can
i think that's been keeping them on bay
all these years you know maybe the
the cranberry bug pesticides that they
spray
got you yeah i have i've seen [ __ ] like
i have um
i have problems with um potato bugs
ever nope inch like in inchworms like uh
you know
there's uh the the tomato beetles too
and then those
those um uh those uh
corn boring worm the boring corn worms
they like bore
into the stem and like you'll they'll
leave like a
small hole looks like somebody took a
drill and it'll look like
some sawdust that's coming out of it and
what they're doing is like
just you know eating up the stem and
then just like taking that stuff and
shoving it out their hole
and uh those are a [ __ ] dude [ __ ]
what do you so what do you use them for
pesticides then
uh basically it's like um it's a fung i
use a fungicide
uh like i've used i've been using
serenade for a long time and that's a
bio fungal side
that's just um but uh insect for like
insects and [ __ ] it's usually like just
part of my
ipm management you know like i'll just
be like spraying them
especially after a rainstorm because a
rainstorm will wash off any uh
beneficial bacteria and yeast that's on
your
that's on your plant that's on the leaf
surface so like after rain you'll you'll
do ipm or foliar
and usually what i use is uh for my
foliar or ipm
um neem oil i emulsify neem oil with
yuccas
with yucca so like i also warm the water
first so i have a little bit of warm
water
and then mix my my neem and then yuck
into that
and that's what emulsifying means yeah
emulsify
will uh is um helping helping an oil go
into solution
and is like really good for that you can
also use potassium silicate
silicate um ag sil16
that stuff is a really good emulsifier
but
it's just good for also using that
silica will will raise the ph
of your leaf surface so that will
prevent mold and also
by using that neem oil and coating it um
also aloe vera so aloe vera and neem oil
those two things will coat your will
coat your leaves and your plant
and it'll actually make it so like
insects don't like to eat it so
if you have it on there before um
you know before these insects even come
you know then
then they won't even like to bite onto
it you know and
it become a snack for them you know um
also another thing
is having a healthy living cover crop
like i've found
like having that clover and
things living on top just makes it so
there's another food source other than
your plant for insects to eat
and it'll also make it for other insects
to come to the to it you know so
there'll be some
there'll be some uh um you know some
competition
and that brings us to like the next uh
part of this that i want to talk to you
about
and well one more thing about the
pesticides do you worry about spraying
that stuff like neem oil and stuff in
bloom
yeah so like um usually like the reason
why it's called ipm is because
um it's it's all it's all um
you know you shouldn't be able you
shouldn't have to use anything in bloom
you know you're preventing
you're preventing all okay happening the
whole time so that when you come to
bloom
um it should just be smooth sailing you
know and uh there's things that you can
do you know that
you know like straight you know which i
don't do like burn sulfur or something
like that i believe that
you know it'll it'll come onto your buds
and it's going to degrade
your product what i think with with pm
is you should just do better pheno
hunting and also better um
like ipm and also fully like um
just better pruning like pruning is just
like
you know if you're there every day then
usually [ __ ] doesn't go wrong you know
too much you know
it's like um something has to develop
over a few days for it to go wrong you
know
so it's like for you yeah for you to
have a priority on those plants dude it
helps so much especially when you're not
mixing
chemicals um and then giving it to them
the fact that you even have to dedicate
time and the ph
and do all that stuff you could be
searching for things that are going
wrong or something like that you know
and uh my experience with all um with um
visible pottery mildew
like you can you can um you can spray it
with
uh with um like a hot like a diluted
hydrogen peroxide um usually i get it in
like 30 plus percent
and then dilute it in there and then
it'll that'll that'll kill it on contact
but you need to follow it up with
something you know to um
what i say is like put the sun put a
sunscreen on after you wash it
wash everything off you know um because
because some people think that
pm is a systemic and it'll always be in
the plant but
in my and also my experience with
outdoor you could take a plant
dyeing a pm straight almost dead and if
you transplant it and as long as the
root system is still
healthy enough for it to take it take on
a new pot or take on into a new bed
then it'll it'll promote growth that new
vegetative growth that is unaffected by
the mutant
and then um also the uv light will help
literally kill the mutagen as new plant
is growing
so there will be a time where you can
take a cut of a fresh
of a freshly growing of freshly growing
plant matter
and then be able to re-sterilize that
and it'll be no pm you know i've i've
seen
i've seen cuts that have been brought
outside with pm brought indoor
and then now they're fine you know
because of that method right right
and dj short actually like um says that
a few things about that in his uh
in his bro journals about how the uv
light just kills pm outdoor and how
and how you can just take fresh cuts
like that who so you're
the uv light from the sun you're saying
yep the uv light in the sun so around my
area june
is the highest uv index so if you're
trying to [ __ ] pm up and you have an
indoor plant then
you should take all your plants out from
indoor and if you want to save them or
something like that then
put them outside in june transplant them
all june you'll veg them and you'll do
[ __ ] to them to uh
to help them and then take cuts off them
and try and save them usually like
people just
toss it you know like unless the
genetics are very
are very uh priceless or or valuable or
whatever
and um when i was looking at your
instagram most recently i saw you're
growing in
what looks like a lot of fabric pots and
you're you're doing the no-till method
with the
cover on top can you explain to
everybody like the like
the noobs what you know what that's
about yeah sure no problem so like um
you want to start with a base soil and
the base soil you can make in a few
different ways
like you can do a ratio of 100 to like
um 20 25 25 50 or you could do 33 33 33
um
of peat moss compost to
aeration and um and your variation being
like perlite
uh you can use perlite but in my opinion
probably the best two
is hydroton and pumice pumice being the
best and then hydroton being the second
best
and then um you you mix those those
those three things together um perfectly
you know and then you have base oil
and then what you add to that base oil
um is
amen dry amendments you do you do like
um
the i did clatimus coots a little bit of
a modified cladimous cou
recipe which is um it's a half you do a
half cup
two to uh per cubic foot of base oil
then you add neem seed meal kelp meal
crab meal insect frass
gypsum oyster shell flour and then
uh two cups of basalt and then
another thing that i added was um was a
half cup of uh alf alpha meal
um and uh once you mix that up you know
you let it you let it uh you let it cook
for six to nine weeks you uh you mix it
all up and you add you add like you can
add just water i had added just water
because i was lazy but you can mix up
a lactobacilli acid you can mix up uh
you know even a compost tea or fish
emulsion fish emulsion will definitely
help you know jump start it
and um like what i was saying about that
cooking like uh there's a lot of um
decomposition going on so uh and a lot
of like the
the fungus the mycelium it's uh it gets
very hot so like
um that's why you need to let it cook
like there will be a phase of the plant
where
um its root system knows that this
decomposition has gone on it goes into a
weakened state but it literally bounces
right back from it
you know but usually you just want to
wait until that um the temperature of
the soil has gone down
and the decomposition is starting to
slow um
but but that means since the
decomposition has been slowed
a lot of the plant availa a lot of the
available nutrients you know is now
plant available
um and not in a different phase in
addition a different form
um what i had what i had done for the
first the
so a 45 gallon pot is uh 1.5
cubic feet for the first foot at the
bottom i had put
um base soil i had put a super soil and
i let that cook in in those pots with
nothing on top for
for about about five weeks and then i
put and then i had um what i had done
recently is finally got
base oil the rest 0.5 feet in the rest
of the
75 45s that i had and um
and then because you don't have to make
your whole soil super soil you don't
have um
you can only make you can just make uh
three to six inches at the bottom layer
fill the rest up with base oil and then
just leave that top and then you can
just do like a top like
inch of super soil on the top and that
and that'll be
that'll that's a no-till pot you can
know you don't have to um
till that for its whole entire lifespan
you know like you mix it up once as long
as you mix it up well enough the first
time
all you got to do is top dress after
that what is your crowd
or your cover that you put on top yeah
so like um
i had i had made sure that that it was
very airy and i actually added a little
bit more pumice and hydroton on the top
but um
like i have this 12 seed cover crop
that's from build soil
i i i i maintain a living cover crop
and like what i was saying you know when
you have another food source then
insects literally won't even eat your
cannabis you know especially if you're
spraying your ganja with
a foliar it it doesn't make it taste as
good as things that aren't sprayed with
a foliar like your cover crop you know
all right that's what i'm thinking yeah
so they'll they'll um you know they'll
eat that and they'll literally just turn
into
insect frass right on your topsoil you
know making plant available nutrients
for you
um but another thing about the living
cover crop
is that its root systems will help move
macro micronutrients
around in the soil in that 45 gallon pot
for the client to use
so like if the if the ganja hasn't you
know said
hasn't gotten down to it yet and the
cover crop is starting to get um
nutrients on the sides it'll just bring
it right to where it's needed
um but uh you can kill you can kill that
cover crop
after it's gone to seed so like you keep
it alive you let the flowers come you
let all the um
let all those things turn to seed and
then you can just kill it you know
and put that mulch uh hay top layer on
on the top
um one thing that's really crucial is um
not letting the sun when you when you
say like um
when you're doing a selective weeding
and um there's some bad weeds there's
the grass is popping up and then you
uh you take it and you uh
you uh crush it up and then you put it
on top of your soil you don't want the
sun to hit it directly
if you can have some hay or something or
or mulch that you can put on top of that
um it'll since it was just living um
and it's still green and stuff and it
has a lot of nutrients still in it
um if the sun were to just uh hit it
directly
it would just bake that off and it would
um it would turn to carbon quickly
um if you had put that mulch layer on
top those plant available nutrients
will you know it'll stay wet for days
and then uh worms and mites and
everything will
will come to it and um since they're
that
it's like staying moist on the top layer
that's also you know another thing about
living keeping a living
mulch layer or even just any kind of
mulch layer the sun isn't hitting your
soil directly you know
so so like it promotes more root growth
towards the top it keeps your group
your top your top few inches at a cooler
temperature
for for um to stay homogeneous and wet
that's awesome man that's some uh next
level [ __ ] like
oh it's it's like you set it all up you
know like one a few times you know
and then it just sets it you know it's
like a smooth sailing after that
um there's so many more just one plant
in a 45 gallon pot
yeah exactly so like i have like all
those um
they're looking small it's just you know
that's for my winter crop all those will
be done
towards december you know the end of
december and they'll be uh
supplemented light all the way until you
know um until the
uh the beginning of november you know
and that's like
you're saying winter crops so he gave us
a little bit of details before the
podcast can you tell everybody about how
you're
going into your winter crop yeah so like
all those
all those plants are um are outside at
the moment until they can be moved into
my greenhouse my greenhouse is getting
its electrical done
but um like you want to supplement light
like we're getting into uh
we have about two weeks left of veg and
we're it's starting to transition into
flower naturally outdoor
um you know um we're getting about at
the end of this month we're about 14
hours of light and then
we'll get down to 13 and we won't even
achieve a a full
uh a full 12 12 until um november i
believe
um but the reason why i'm supplementing
supplementing light is to keep them in
that vegetative state you know
so you have lights in the greenhouse
that you're gonna use yes
uh i'm gonna i'm gonna have 10 uh
thousand watt double ended
and uh oh damn dude yeah hell yeah so
like uh
it's gonna be filthy yeah so um so and
also like if it's a cloudy day
you know i'll turn those all all 10
lights on and make the sun happen for
them you know
yeah yeah but um like that [ __ ] with the
winter crop man
like you just got to make sure you're
supplementing light properly if
you're if it's starting to get too cold
out then you know you need to you need
to
adequately heat them because environment
is so key dude you know like we're
just blessed when we come in the season
that that mother nature gives us you
know the perfect season but
um i'm definitely gonna have to have
like potentially a propane heater
i don't need a dehumidifier um i'm gonna
potentially
potentially need a humidifier for
wintertime uh to add
moisture to my greenhouse you know and
stuff like that but uh
it's gonna be really cool for sure it's
and not many people grow on a geodesic
dome a lot of people are growing you
know traditional hoops and uh
you know whatever the forever flowering
companies are
you got pictures of that up right yeah
yeah i don't have too many pictures of
the actual like geodump like i will
i will like a little bit further down
the road but like um
uh because of my area just because of my
area you know not many people
in my area and for the viewers watching
i don't know if you mentioned your
instagram yet it's at beast
coast farmers i'm looking at it right
now um
are you strictly an outdoor grower now
are you 100 percent outdoor or
i'm i'm moving towards that man like um
i i want
all production outdoor like i can have a
greenhouse where i can
be propagating and vegging and mothering
all that stuff and then have a
greenhouse where
because it'll it'll be continuously
heated you know all the time no matter
what it's no matter what the season
and um but by all means you can have
you know say cloning or mothers or
veggies inside but
i'm moving towards no flowering indoor i
haven't been flowering indoor for
for like two years now and it's been all
outdoor
so how many plants do you typically
run um indoor like um
well outdoor usually well outdoor it's
hundreds it's usually in the hundreds
wow and like last season i had done
uh like 250 and they're all in vary in
size and pots and beds
and at one location and i actually
seeded every single one
earlier in that earlier last year i had
been i i was bringing
my seed stock to maine to trade with
some growers and they actually got taken
by the police for me so i lost like like
five years of breeding
and then yeah well the last year last
year i was like all right well i'm just
gonna chuck pollen everywhere
and now i have seeds forever yo but at
the same time dude seed making dude it's
like
you know you don't have to make f2s f3s
if you do it right the first time like i
i had pheno hunted uh like 2000 seeds
so out of 2000 seeds i found five males
that were insane so i just let them hit
the wind you know
and out of those 2000 seeds i found 250
females that were you know
very very good like some of them you
could
you could be completely dry and they
don't wilt they just still pray
you know even though they're completely
dry and you can kick them over and [ __ ]
um that's that's just from unique
unique lignin uh structures and [ __ ]
dude it's
i think a lot of this dude like a lot of
growing and um
is having a phenotype for your area you
know
um say like if i take some cali southern
cali seeds and then
take them to northern you know like
maine or something you know you'll have
you'll have some adverse effects
happening
for sure or if you take clones that were
under sea level or
above sea level and do vice versa you
know that's why people need to have
acclimated strains
and make their own you know because um
making your own strains
they'll grow perfectly where you live
you know just by making a few
generations of them
so with with hundreds and hundreds of
plants that you're managing at a time
seems like a lot of work there what
advice do you have to people who are
trying to do the same thing
you know what management advice and dude
i i just
i recommend just doing the organic route
you know like
it's easy you know like there's like
less
things i need to do for them and the
plant health is
maintained you know on a larger scale
you know
um if you were to give plants chemins
you need to
um you know have every plant
being wet the same way and then flushed
or
whatever and also um a lot more plant
diseases and
um things can happen from that you know
so like i i just recommend going down
the organic road not
not going the chems and having to water
things in to achieve what you want you
know to final results and stuff
because you're just spraying them with a
hose at this point really right like
are you wanting to tap water or do you
have like a ro thing set up
i don't even have ro do like i i used to
do i used to do rl you know like
um i i don't i'm not working with city
water you know or anything like that or
chlorinated gotcha
i have i have two separate wells for
both my locations
and like it's you know well water the
wall water i'm pulling is
uh my first one is 80 tds and the other
ones
is 120 and um oh wow that's low
for especially for well water yeah and
um what's in it
is magnesium calcium uh
small amounts of iron silica you know
all [ __ ] that i'd be adding to it it's
pretty funny you know
and you'd even you even drink it or put
it on your skin it makes it soft from
its mineral content
so like just from that like giving that
to bacteria or or giving that to a
fungus you know stimulates it
um watering is definitely a key though
man
like i i don't just i don't always just
give them water like
the more you give a plant the better the
bigger you'll get in terms of
teas you know and brewing teas um but i
can by all means i mix up soil that can
just be sustained with just water
beginning to end
like that cute mix like from uh the
clatton's cooth recipe
i'm gonna have to look into that yeah
for sure like that's right on
bubblespoil.com
i had spent a lot of dough on build a
soil uh this season even though i'll
probably
try and uh source some things on the
east coast um and only have to order a
few things from them next year but um
but by i mean like they're the [ __ ] they
give you free information you know
in the whole nine yards what has been
your biggest yield
so far too big
probably 25 30 pounds
like that of of scentsy you know yeah
that's a that's a record breaker for the
podcast so far i'm pretty
sure that's like you know at one time
you know and uh
the the money that i had spent dude to
do that like it's
nothing dude it's like it's it's almost
it's almost nothing it's like
it's like my the ounces and the pounds
are
are the ounces are like pennies about um
with with using organics and using the
sun and [ __ ] like that
so that was that was an outdoor grow and
then how many plants was it
roughly that was off like 80 plants
okay like and but you know usually you
know like i can yield
off of one plant i can go over you know
like 2.5
you know and um bigger than that you
know it's all about the veg
it's all about filling in a screen you
know too
uh it's gonna be funny like this is this
season is the biggest season that i've
ever gone and then
like next season you know even bigger
and bigger it's how it's always been
like uh i when i look at your instagram
like you talk about filling in a screen
you're not scrogging all these plants
are you
um no but the ones that are going to go
into the geodome that's going to be
a scrog net completely 500 like almost
531 square feet of scrog
and oh wow yeah and that's you know the
canopy will be six
up about six and a half seven feet tall
so you'll be on a step ladder
you know just looking at the canopy it's
gonna be sick
and you're going to um you're so
i noticed like you're doing like you're
you're training the plants and pulling
them down like the branches down
yeah like and i do that every day you
know i could i have uh the bamboo i just
found actually a local like uh
um bamboo spot to just go get mad bamboo
and like start doing
more training but um i i complete you
know you don't have to top your plants
either you can um
you can regul you can you can uh get
oxen to be
you know regulated just by bending the
plant oxen is uh the hor a growth
hormone that that uh
is responsible for the elongation and uh
when you when you take off the apical
meristem
uh you're you're you know um
it's like a shock to the plant you know
and it's i don't know
um it can be beneficial but by all means
all you
if the plant is able to just be bent um
and then held down in that bent position
then you're achieving the same thing you
know
but better you're you don't have to do
any kind of stress like cutting the
plant up
uh you're maintaining more growth matter
are there any books that you can like
reference that you've learned this stuff
from or is it all just from like
trial and error and the internet i've
i've definitely i've been
reading a few books like um teeming with
fungus teaming with microbes teaming
with nutrients
mycelium running uh
but you know and um a lot of a lot of
trial and error dude you know higher
hybrid
you know videos for so long dude and
like
i got i literally did a huge you know
like um
uh like 25 gallon like a few 25 gallon
dw
well uh rdwc all connected and [ __ ] and
uh and um
replicated his style you know and i love
it i still to this day i still love
hydroponics and i still respect it
but i just won't go down that route
again it's just uh it's too wasteful
you know you just you know
you don't you don't think about what
when it where it goes down the drain
on a small scale you know it doesn't
matter you know if you're not if
when you get to a larger scale and
you're dealing with hundreds of plants
then you should
you should be you should think about
what you're putting into the ground and
then where that
water going and all that because anyone
can just you know spend money you know
on chems and then just
spew them on anything you know to make
money or something like that but
that's not what it's about yeah for sure
bro i agree with you there
um and i agree that doing a large scale
with chemicals
is gonna be i mean like how are you
gonna be able to afford to do that
it's like yeah you know by all means you
know like unless you did you could spend
a thousand dollars and get 10 grand back
at you easily you know
over that you know with or whatever
it's it's funny how uh how much it
actually costs to make a pound
with chems it's it's not much money but
you're making waste you have a lot of
it's there isn't any kind of you need to
go back to the hydro store
when you're done you know and go get
more nutrients um
for sure you know it'll pay it off but
that product isn't as superior
the growth hormone regular in in the
pgrs and whatever they
they do give you a bud structure that it
looks better
than organically grown bud um
but it's not it won't smoke better it's
not going to be better for you in the
whole nine yards
terpene content the terpene content from
organic and
by using the sun it's unmatched you'll
never be able to
get the terpenes that you get from
outdoor indoor
you know just uh that's just the way it
is what was your biggest catastrophe
in growing definitely indoor
uh powdery mildew indoor you know i have
i've gone through fighting the battle
through flour
is that the third powdery mildew indoor
we've heard it seems like almost every
podcast powdery mildew is brought up
and then at least it's not like spider
mites or some [ __ ] you know yeah
um definitely pm dude it's insane like
it
what i think is just like um powdery
mildew for indoor dude
it's like it's if you even see that dude
it's like
catastrophic has catastrophe you know
like did it crush your yield or what
yeah it the fact that you see it it's
cutting your yield
like it's it's um you shouldn't fight
the battle
going into flour you know if you see it
in veg already don't flower
you know it's like um cut everything
uh get new genetics uh don't don't
accept genetics from somebody you don't
really know very well
and then start or start from speed and
start with a very stellar sterile room
um sometimes doing that is this is the
better option than fighting the battle
anyone dealing with pm dude it's like
you should really rethink about what
you're doing you know because um
it's it's just a battle not worth
fighting you should always be doing ipm
uh integrated pest management so you'd
never see that [ __ ] you know
you should have your you know a regiment
that you you know everyone has their own
regiment
that they do and um it's it's crucial
like um
you can make a a lactobacillic acid very
it's very easy to make you take
um you take rice rice wash water so you
all you do is you take rice
and you add some water and you um and
then you mix it around and then
you strain out the rice and then you add
it to uh
raw milk at um a 1 to 10 ratio so one
part
wash water 10 part milk and then you let
that
you let that uh you let that sit for 48
hours
and within within 12 hours within 24
hours it'll already start separating
uh cheese curd at the top and then
lactobacilli acid
serum on the bottom and you just take
the cheese curd you can make
meat cheese out of it and then that
serum
on the bottom is is an ipm you know like
you you should spray
lactobacillus on your lactobacilli acid
on your plants like
almost every day you know like or like
three times four times uh four times a
week or something
i feel like people are going to get a
lot of value out of here in that well
dude
yeah and um uh like
korean natural farming is like something
that everyone needs to start doing
for growing their food growing for their
ganja and all that [ __ ] just
the amount of money that it takes to to
to make the end result you know it's
just
it's insane like too just low right
you're saying mainly low dude like for
like
hundreds and hundreds of acres to
adequately like water that with say
fermented plant juice would probably
cost you like
maybe fifty dollars you know if you know
for a hundred acre for like three
hundred eight pm
yeah and uh all you gotta do is grow the
plant matter you know
it makes sense yeah right so the smaller
time people i don't know if they're
gonna
be getting into it like the newer i
don't know like the new growers but
yeah man i mean when i was a new grower
like what i was saying it's all about
chems so i was just looking into what
company
is doing you know it has the best prices
and the best results and everything
it's super easy to get like to walk into
a grocery store
yep like the first time i walked into a
grocery store i bought
like a lot more than i needed i know and
like
i'm sure they had smile on their face
yeah
like exactly i mean that's the thing
about going in the grow shop and like
looking at a magazine
yeah is they're gonna try to convince
you that you need to use as many bottles
of nutrients as possible regardless of
the company i mean they're all there to
make money
and so exactly but there's a reason
there's ten part systems and not
three parts yeah you'll see the organic
side and it'll just be a little
you know it'll be a little section you
can go into and you know
um everything else is chems everything
you know chem's everywhere
and the i'm sure the people in there
won't won't
you know um you know bring up anything
about organics or
or whatever if unless you ask or unless
you're looking for it you know
right because the margins aren't going
to be as good for they're not going to
make as much
as much money selling you organic stuff
and on top of that like the marketing
that these companies are doing it's
pretty cool like you go in there and you
look at all the nutrient bottles like
they'll make a bottle of salt look cool
yeah for sure dude
right and it's and everything's just you
know got the same [ __ ] in it
and in different quantities and whatever
else
or for sure it's easy to get lost in
there yeah and to say that it's you know
like um
it's tested or it's um it's commercially
you know it's used like advanced
nutrients i was like contacted by the
like east coast advanced nutrient guy
and he's like oh
you know you should start using a
commercial nutrient or something like
that i'm just like
you know i always just delete that the
years you know when i was younger like i
had poured chems right on an organic
garden you know like
hot general hydroponics and i had
yielded
i had yielded more than i would have
yielded but you know i had hurt that
ground
you know and it um and then it would
need time to repair itself you know
um and for those salts to fully leach
off and drain off and
for whatever else but like i saw like
what i don't know like what the effects
are since i've lived in the same place
and that's another thing i actually have
not moved my whole like i've moved one
time from one when i was in third grade
to where i am now and i haven't moved
and i've grown bud here my whole life
so like that's the reason why you know
like i i'm pretty good at growing where
i live you know
and um especially yeah yeah
yep and um noticed i've noticed since
i've been doing um
since i've gone the straight organic
route and
i've seen life come to my come to my
land you know there's more worms in my
bed there's
you know there's dragonflies everywhere
there's mantis there's ladybugs
everything you know before it wasn't
like that like ever
you know the soil wasn't as fertile and
when you start when you start doing
organics and you start getting better at
it you promote life
and you promote [ __ ] to come to your
[ __ ] to work for you you know basically
that's awesome dude yeah for sure so
having the knowledge that you have now
if you can go back in time and talk to
yourself before you start growing
what advice would you give to yourself
just go the living soil route
[ __ ] hydro [ __ ] chemicals like
i dude it's it's funny how my mindsets
change dude like
it's so it's funny to think about i i i
say that to myself a lot is if i if i
knew what i know now
but back then you know i wish i could go
back in time and talk to myself
don't we all bro don't we all i'll be
like don't spend all your money on food
every day
what's up coming for you are you working
on any projects in the industry or
anything like that
i do have my geodesic dome so i'll and
you know that's going to be that's going
to be dope i'll be able to push out
a good a good portion of uh of
organically grown blood every
like three to four months but another
thing that i'm doing in massachusetts
there's a uh
a large dispensary that's going there um
i
i i will be growing for them with my uh
with a good friend of mine and we only
need
six people to run the whole uh 50 000
square feet
so um and and that's going to be grown
with chems
but i know i know um i'm confident in my
abilities that
that you know that chem grown blood is
going to be dank you know
dude i gotta join them out there man
that's not that far to drive yeah for
sure yo like um
in massachusetts there's a lot of
hurdles you gotta go through you can't
grow straight organics in
in and in commercially for massachusetts
at least uh
you got there's like too many um there's
too many uh
standards the like the heavy metals um
and a lot a lot of other things it's
just and also mold
and things like that like if you have a
living soil and you have uh mushroom
sporulating in your indoor environment
you'll have you'll have um
uh mutanogen on it you know and it'll
it'll it'll spark your uh
and it won't pass or something like that
so i got you
you gotta like grow with water and
rock wool and cocoa and all that and
then flush it and then
you know that's just the way it's going
to be for right now but yeah
tons of people do it and they succeed
and ori origron
um i i really admire his uh his way that
he's
that he's doing his um dispensary i'm
sure
i'm sure oregon has a high standards as
well i'm pretty sure massachusetts has
the highest standard in the whole
country
which kind of it's uh makes it harder to
you know make a product to put it on the
shelves but in my opinion that's cool
because all the
all of the patients will be getting a
higher quality product but
you know um what he does is he takes a
pro mix
just straight you know straight pro-mix
and uh he uses dragonfly earth medicine
um which is an organic water-soluble
nutrient and that's it so all he uses is
uh
those two things you know and that's
he's not using any kind of chemical
um his by-product is uh three gallons of
uh of
of pro-mix you know which she piles up
you know hundreds of those three gallons
and piles them up and then uses it for
outdoor organic views you know
instead yeah they're using rockwool
which takes like 4 000 years to
decompose and
it's glass and you know you know i've
seen i've seen his instagram and shit's
definitely legit i don't i might have
even reached out to him but
i don't doubt anyone that grows indoors
with chems just because of
um just because of how sterile you need
to be and how careful you need to be
with indoor
and all you guys i mean mr growit like
everybody who has a youtube channel
and or an instagram that's just sharing
their knowledge and information
like you guys aren't really getting much
out of doing that like you're doing it
for the love of
the industry like maybe someone maybe
some people are making money now
but after they've like grown a bit but
like when you start doing that and you
don't have any subscribers or like
all these people are just doing it to
share information and help the industry
and so
i definitely like a lot of my [ __ ] that
i've learned has definitely come from
you know my own trial and error but like
i've definitely talked to the right
people and and um and instagram has
definitely helped me
like tremendously meeting people you
know and um seeing and you know coming
to this final consensus of how i grow
now
like um putting information out there
dude it's not like it's not a secret you
know especially with
growing this but growing bud it's not
secret and people shouldn't
have to hide their methods they should
just you know give it to everybody
um right which is pretty funny to think
about how uh
there's this like colorado colorado
grower um
he he was like um his company wanted to
like fire him and take his notebook
and like they never got his notebook and
he just left but
it's pretty funny how they you know they
think they need it
yeah if they get you know that that that
method you know then they don't need the
person
you're doing it it's funny which is
totally wrong yeah totally wrong dude
it's like
i've been steering that ship you know
right where can people find you what
what
shoutouts do you have contact me on
instagram for now my
my uh my youtube is definitely up and
coming i i have a i have a homie that's
been helping me film
and uh we've compiled a lot of film so
we just got to do editing
well i think we're ready to wrap it up
man yeah ready to wrap it up thanks a
lot for coming on really appreciate it
yeah i really appreciate you guys having
me all right have a good one take care
thanks again brother thank you guys if
you click the video on the left that'll
take you to the other podcast episodes
that we did
and the video on the right is
automatically generated by the youtube
algorithm
until next time peace