what's up everybody if you got don't
know me my name is Chris aka mr. grow it
and you watch a mattress channel here I
have the perfect works are a two
thousand LED grow light perfect works
sent me over this grow light and in this
video I'm gonna unbox unit I'm gonna
test the power output and I'm also gonna
do a heat test I'm not gonna go over all
the features that this girl light has in
this video but I will leave a link in
the description section below so you can
learn more about it okay here is the box
and the first thing out the box is a
user manual this user manual includes
installation instructions recommended
hanging Heights and information about
daisy chaining this next sheet is gonna
have some more information on the light
it also includes some information on
another model that they sell the RA 1000
and this sheet shows apart test readings
at different heights next thing that the
box is a power cord after that is a pair
of rope ratchet hangers here is a wire
hanging kit and lastly is the LED grow
light the power test I'm gonna use the
apogee mq 500 power meter this meter
measures from 389 nanometers to 692
nanometers and the measurements are in
ppfd I do these videos just to give you
a general idea of what the power output
is it's not going to be a hundred
percent accurate I take measurements and
grow tents which have reflective walls
that could increase the numbers so just
keep that in mind the flower and
coverage area for this grow light is 3
feet by 3 feet I'm taking measurements
in a 4 foot by 4 foot grow tent so I'm
gonna try to keep my par meter in a 3
foot by 3 foot space I'm gonna take
measurements at 3 different distances
these are the recommended hanging
Heights listed in their user manual 24
inches 18 inches and 12 inches I've
plugged the grow light into my kilowatt
meter and it shows 1.91 amps pulling 228
watts from the wall alright let's get
into the measurements
[Music]
what do you think of these measurements
let me know in the comments section
below just a reminder that there is a
link to this grow light in the
description section below and I'll leave
it at that thank you so much for
watching and until next time
ace
[Music]