what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and i'm back on another video got a
vegetable garden update for you this
week nothing too crazy i'm definitely
not an expert by any means when it comes
to vegetables i like to just dabble in
them a little bit you know but i do have
four pepper plants going right now and
some lettuce so i think i'd bust out a
quick video and show you what i got
going on but before we get into the
video got to give a shout out to ac
infinity for hooking me up with this
gift box i actually opened up this gift
box on one of my live streams on twitch
if you're not following me on twitch go
to twitch.tv
mr growit i'm on there doing lives you
know one to two times a week times i
have a guest on there as well in the box
there is so many goodies got some
stickers candies
some shears
and a controller 69 developer edition
and they're not just hooking up me
they're hooking up you as well they
actually provided me with a discount
code for my viewers you can use code mr
growit for a percentage off of any of
their products so once again thank you
ac infiniti for this gift
[Music]
all right here we are in my two foot by
four foot grow tent this one is by ac
infinity you can see i got the lettuce
there got a couple freaks in the middle
and then there on the left side of the
grow tent i have four pepper plants so
these pepper plants are actually a
variety called bullnose peppers looks
very close to bell peppers but they're a
smaller version of them let's actually
start off talking about the bowl nose
peppers these ones are coming right
along definitely got some fruit forming
so far
[Music]
you can see right here i'm shaking them
this is in order to allow pollen to drop
down and pollinate the flowers the
flowers will then turn into peppers once
pollinated so you can see right here i'm
peeling off the flowers around the
pepper that's forming there i think in
the future i'm going to use a swab to
actually grab pollen from the flowers to
pollinate them i've had a couple flowers
that actually dropped off they weren't
pollinated doing the shake techniques so
hopefully that'll help pollinate more in
the future this plant has quite a few as
well
this one back here a little bit bigger
of peppers
i've got one two
and then there's a third one here as
well
fourth plant back here i've got quite a
few peppers on here these ones are
bigger as well than the front two ones
this is the biggest one of them all
this one i would say is pretty close to
harvest i'd love to know when you guys
determine when to harvest peppers let me
know down in the comments section below
i mentioned on my last video that pretty
new to peppers this is my first round
growing peppers definitely going to
continue to grow them out in the future
i love hearing feedback i love to hear
what you do in your garden that helps
you and makes you successful growing
them so maybe i could take some of those
best practices and implement in my
garden so yeah let me know what tips and
techniques you use on when do harvest
these plants are grown in one gallon
containers so a little smaller of a
container than some of you may like i
know in my last video there were several
folks that said that i should
potentially grow in larger containers
whether they be three gallon containers
or five gallon containers but a little
bit bigger of containers some have said
that i would have gotten a little bit
better of a result however i see lots of
folks growing in these smaller
containers one gallon containers so i
know it is possible i do have a little
bit of space constraints so that's why i
chose to go with one gallon containers
this round but hey maybe next round i'll
go with a bit larger of containers i'm
gonna have a separate video with an
update on these two freaks this video is
just gonna be on the vegetables moving
on to the head of lettuce that i have
here this is actually the container that
i had the cut and come again i had half
of the container buttercrunch lettuce
and then the other half spinach the
spinach didn't do very well at all i
think it's because the hotter
temperatures that are on here they like
the cooler temperatures you know low 70s
even into the 60s or below that they can
survive in and some actually say the
lower the temps provide a better flavor
anyways talking about the lettuce here
buttercrunch it's actually about to bolt
so i am going to harvest this
turn this into a salad i think next time
around i'm going to grow probably two
maybe four
heads of lettuce in one seven gallon
container in the future i don't think
i'm gonna do the cut and come again
method again just because i don't eat
that much lettuce some of it went to
compost good amount of it actually went
to compost all of these plants were
grown with organic amendments i used
earth dust nutrients by the green
sunshine company this round and they're
all grown under the es 180 led grill
light also by the green sunshine company
i said in last video but i'll say it
again this light is a little bit of an
overkill for vegetables in my opinion
this light is more for medicinal
varieties i have this light actually dim
down i believe all the way to the lowest
setting because these vegetables they
don't need as much light as medicinal
varieties although the peppers actually
probably could take a good amount of
light but lettuce doesn't need that much
at all on the outro card here the video
on the left is the previous episode with
these vegetables that i spoke about and
the video on the right is automatically
generated by the youtube algorithm
thanks for watching until next time
peace