coming up on Garden talk feminized seeds
are seeds that are 98 to 99 female
plants so you pop them and you are more
than sure that will be females I never
start with seed plants I always start
with clones that are tested that are
very well known that are very very
valuable the most important thing on a
breeding project like I said is the
genetics that you breed with
and the health of the plants the veg
nutrients the high content of nitrogen
will help create and harvest a lot more
seeds than if you use a bloom nutrient
if you do this right from one plant you
can get like thousands of seeds
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is Chris aka Mr Grow it
and you're tuned into the garden Talk
podcast this episode number 91. in this
episode I interview grow more stress
less he is a plant breeder and focuses
on creating feminized seeds and that's
what we're going to get into in today's
episode he talks all about his style of
breeding and how to create feminized
seeds if you gain value from these
episodes please click the like button
and also subscribe to the channel if you
haven't already that way you can be
notified when new episodes are released
if you'd like to support even more visit
patreon.com Mr grew it there are various
rewards set up for those of you that
support and you could pledge any amount
that you'd like 100 of the money that's
pledged through patreon goes right back
into the podcast so thank you all so
much for your support there before we
get into it I want to acknowledge that
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free gardening information of all
plants to the general public that being
said I'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible people thanks to grow
strong Industries for sponsoring this
episode they have kind LED grow lights
which allow you to control the veg and
flower spectrums independently allowing
you to maximize quality and yield and
they also have Lotus nutrients a
nutrient line developed by Growers for
Growers to completely replace the
typical 9 to 12 Bottle recipe with an
easy to use three-part system to see
their products in action check out their
first ever grow strong grow off go to
their website growstrong industries.com
linked below and use the discount code
Mr Grow it for 15 off AC Infinity is
sponsoring this episode their clip-on
oscillating fan is now released I've
been using their six-inch version for
over six months now and I absolutely
love it it's easy to clip on the side of
my grow tent and it has 10 different
speeds which makes it easy to control
air circulation they do also have
non-oscillating versions of these
clip-on fans these fans are currently in
high demand when they sell out of the
fans which I expect them to often you
can pre-order them for the next release
you can also use discount code Mr Grow
it if you're buying off their website EC
infinity.com that discount code works
for all AC Infinity items or discount
code Mr Grow at 15 if you're buying off
Amazon spider farmer is sponsoring this
episode coupon code Mr Grow at 5 will
get you a discount on their products
check out their new sfg bar style series
of grow lights they have the sfg 300w a
four bar fixture for a 2x2 or 3x3 growth
space the SF g860w a a bar fixture for a
4x4 or 5x5 grow space and the sfg 1000w
a 10 bar fixture which is also for a 4x4
or 5x5 grow space go to their website at
spider Dash farmer.com or search for
them on Amazon and don't forget to use
the discount code Mr grodd5 for discount
on their products and we're back welcome
to the Garden Talk podcast today I am
joined with grow more stress less how
you doing today I'm doing great and I'm
so honored to be on your show yeah glad
to have you on I know there's been a
large handful of people that have
requested for you to come on so I'm
excited that I finally got a hold of you
and was able to get you on here I it's
my pleasure I've been watching your
shows and your YouTube videos for a long
time so it's a pleasure to be on your
show right now that's so cool to hear so
today we're going to get into feminized
plant breeding you know more and more
people are choosing feminized seeds over
regular seeds I think they really like
the ability to grow plants from seed and
for it to always be female not have to
worry about male plants so in this
episode I like to have more of a
beginner friendly conversation in
regards to getting started breeding and
then creating feminized seeds but first
what we do with every episode is an
introduction so can you tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got into
gardening yes uh my name is Vio my real
name is abbreviation from vrl I'm coming
from Eastern Europe Romania uh I'm
coming from bodybuilding background so
I've been bodybuilding for the last 18
years of my life I started bodybuilding
when I was like 13 years old and right
when I started became a passion for me
and I got obsessed with bodybuilding and
I wanted to become a professional
bodybuilder from like when I was 14
years old so
um I follow my dream and at 20 years old
I came to us to compete in a
bodybuilding show and I stayed here uh
for the rest of the remaining time I
come here in 2008 and I reached my
lifetime goal to become a professional
bodybuilder at 30 years old after uh
almost 16 years of chasing this dream
and coming all the way from Eastern
Europe Romania to us was a huge
transition but uh
I always had that passion to to for
bodybuilding and I want to make it all
the way where I put my dream at so right
after I finish bodybuilding and I
reached my main goal to become a
professional bodybuilding kind of I
start to kind of get depressed because I
even had another thing to aim for you
know I reached my goal that I was trying
to get for the last 16 years now I'm
here and I'm kind of kind of lost I
don't know what to do anymore so that's
when I discovered growing and I
immediately got passionate about growing
you know I start with three little
clones back in 2019 and
it became a passion right away like
right away I was there every single
second opening my closet door to check
on the plants and doing research for
like hours and hours and hours and
losing nights uh watching YouTube videos
watching you and all the other like
people on YouTube uh on how to and
trying to learn how to grow and going
back into my little Growing Experience
and things evolved pretty fast for me
because I dive so deep into it like with
bodybuilding I put everything I had all
my focus and all my uh my time into
growing and I um I evolved pretty pretty
quick from my first grow in a closet in
uh in uh in soil with uh Flora not Flora
Flex with uh with with
um with salt nutrients
I I I get I got into my second grow
where I did deep water culture and I
grew one single plant in a five by five
space where I got massive results uh
from that plant I got a massive yield
and I got great results and that built
my confidence also I want to mention
that the plant was in my life while I
was doing bodybuilding it helped me
reach my goal to become a professional
bodybuilding by
um give me relief from pain because
bodybuilding is a very very demanding
sport where you have to lift a lot of
weight and you have all kinds of joint
pains or muscle pains so I used the
medicinal properties of the plant long
before to start growing so when I
started growing was like I really need
to learn everything about this and I
dived you've been to it and that's where
I am right now awesome and then how long
have you been breeding when did that
come in and what I like to ask I've had
a handful of breeders on this podcast in
the past small handful and I like to ask
them what makes you a reputable breeder
okay first of all I'm not considered
myself a breeder yet I aim to become one
of the best breeders in the game but at
this moment I'm not considering myself a
breeder I'm just learning and experience
and doing all kinds of projects to
perfect my uh my skills but I'm not
considering myself a breather yet I've
been breathing just for a little uh over
a year now
but like I said as with growing I'm
diving deep in and I'm doing a lot of
research I'm um I'm listening to a lot
of books about reading about plant
health and everything like that so
um I'm trying to perfect my breathing uh
projects every single time I'm doing it
and uh what made me different it's the
passion that I put into the plant the
energy that I put into the plant and the
approach that I have of of breeding that
will get later on will get on later on
you know okay and then before we
actually met here we talked about what
the what the topic would be and I sent
you some questions in regards to
breeding and the first set of questions
I sent you was was inbreeding right
going from like F1 F2 F3 and you had
mentioned that you haven't really
ventured into that Avenue yet that you
specialized in feminized so that's kind
of what we're going to focus on today
but for those that don't know feminize
can you break it break it down for us
what is meant by feminized so in simple
words you take a
fell clone plant and you reverse it with
a
with a spray uh and you turn it into a
male and now you take the pollen from
these female slash male plant and you
pollinate another female plant and you
get five feminized seeds so feminized
seeds are seeds that are
uh 98 to 99 uh female plants so you pop
them and you are more than sure that
will be females uh the thing with the
feminite seeds they are not as stable as
the regular seeds that mean they can
harm if the genetics are not mixing
together well but what I'm what I'm
getting it is
if you pop regular seeds and you want
just female plants you have chances of
50 female 50 male so you are 50 50 but
if you pop feminine seeds you have got
99 chances to get female plants and
probably the Herm present is less than
if it's a good project less than one or
two percent you know you pop uh ipok for
example my last run 33 seeds I didn't
have any harm and then I pop another 72
seeds and I have just two herbs so the
Herm percentage can vary uh from
cultivar to cultivar from genetic to
genetic you know how well the genetics
are combining themselves so either way I
consider feminizing seeds if you if you
try to grow female plants a more
Advantage where to go than regular seeds
got it and then kind of taking a step
back there's a lot of folks that are
just getting started with breeding you
know and they they're kind of limited on
the space that they have what would you
say is the smallest size grow space that
someone can do this type of breeding in
I mean you can do these types of
breeding in any kind of space even if
you have like a two by two tent or
whatever you have you get uh you get
your plan that you want to reverse and
you start spraying it with the reversal
spray and you need to have another plant
so the smallest project that you can get
done is just bring two plants you get
one plant that you reverse and a plant
that you will uh pollinate with so it
can be a two by four space even a uh
yeah two by four two feet two plants or
a two by two you can get this done in
any kind of space you don't need a lot
of space and if you do this right from
one plant you can get like thousands of
seeds so you don't need a lot of space
you need the minimum possible space that
you can grow two plants in it you know
okay and then it's far as tools and
equipment so I think a lot of folks that
are getting into breeding they already
know how to grow the plant regularly I
think a majority of them you know maybe
99 of people already know how to grow
the plant or at least they should know
how to grow the plant and they're just
getting into breeding are there any
other like separate tools and equipment
that they would need in order to breed
there is no apps like different tools or
things that you need in order to breed
all you need to do it is to to grow the
plants healthy and you just need to have
your reversal
um plan in place you know you need to
have the timing right and you need to
have to know how to grow super healthy
plants because uh my point of in my in
my breathing my main point is the
healthcare you keep the plants the
better you will you the better the the
genetics will will inter like will mix
with each other you know you need to
it's like humans when you try to when
you when humans try to make kids the
healthier the parents are the healthier
will transmit into the into the children
so that's what I'm trying to do with the
with the plants keep them as healthy as
possible uh during before and during the
breeding process so the offsprings the
seeds will be super healthy uh seeds
with the best genetics possible you know
that's so that's that's what's all come
come too so what would actually happen
if the plant did have like deficiencies
like say the plant was yellowing or
something like that towards the lower
part of the plant and it was pretty
minor and they went and they did they
started that reversal process with the
spray
is there like what are the downsides to
doing that versus starting with a
healthy plan I mean you got to mention
that the the health would go down to The
Offspring right but uh are they going to
see any issues during the reversal
process I don't know exactly what to
tell them from now because uh they uh
there can happen a lot of things but
from my point of view you know when you
have mineral deficiencies in humans like
folic acid in a pregnant woman or a
Calcium deficiency in a pregnant woman
that will transmit into the kids you
know you have folic acid deficiency uh
the the kid can be born with birth
defects with uh Channel I don't know
exactly how it's called birth General
defect or if the mother have vitamin D
or calcium deficiencies the the the kid
can have different like bone uh mineral
deficiencies and like different you know
different uh problems later on life and
being into the bodybuilding and health
health side of the things with humans I
translate that into my plants as well
because it's kind of the same process so
I cannot tell exactly what will happen
but I can say that the healthier you
keep your plants the better you'll the
better genetics you can create uh on
your seeds you know the healthcare
genetic you can transmit into the seeds
Okay so if the plant were to have
deficiencies during that reversal
process like you mentioned would there
be potential mutant plants that happen
or like uh crazy characteristics that
come out of The Offspring because of the
uh it's very it's very possible to have
like
um mutant plants or I would say more
likely to have more harm her problems
later on because the DNA of the plants
didn't mix and uh stain the right the
place that it's supposed to you know so
it can be more like a more harm chances
or more mutant plants or uh seeds not
germinating correctly later on so there
can be a lot of problems but I cannot
point exactly because uh the science is
not yet there yet on the plants what
will happen if uh this plant will have
magnesium deficiency or so on but what I
can say for sure is that the healthier
you can keep your plants during the
breeding projects the better you are uh
you are off with your with your
Offspring with your seeds and genetics
later on you know all right and then as
far as the seed to use to begin a lot of
people say that regular seeds is the
only thing you should use and that you
should not use feminized seeds for
breeding are there any risks with
starting with a feminized seed and using
that reversing that versus a regular
seed okay first of all uh I don't like
to start with uh with uh with seeds you
know with seed plants I start directly
with the genetics that are very very
well well known uh very well the
characteristics are that I'm looking for
you know I'm starting with with genetics
that
already good you know they are selected
they are breeder Cuts they are cuts that
are very valuable because
the whole
the whole thing boils down to the
genetics what genetics you can bring to
make a even better genetic right and
when you start from seed you have a huge
variation that you can you you can you
can pop a hundred seeds and you cannot
find one good plant on a hundred says
you know so that's that's the thing I
never start with uh with seed plants I
always start with clones that are tested
that are very well known that are very
very
um valuable you know they have the
characteristics that I'm looking for the
the THC the the medicinal properties
that I'm looking for the the color that
I'm looking for the Vigor that I'm
looking for you know so I never start
with seeds I'm starting with uh with the
Clones
and I'm trying to get the best genetics
that I have access to so anybody can
they can breathe but the main thing is
what genetics you start with you know
because not everybody have access to the
best genetics in the world so that's
that's that's one of my main focus
finding the best genetics and hunting
the seeds that I'm creating to find the
best genetics that I can bring into my
other other genetics you know so you
don't really worry about if that clone
came from a seed that was regular or if
that clone came from a plant that was
feminized started from a feminine as
long as that clone as long as you know
that the mother plant was a healthy
plant produce what you were looking for
within the genetics you'll use that
clone you'll grow it out and then you'll
reverse it exactly exactly I don't care
if it came from a feminazi seeds or a
regular seeds all I can is to be stable
to have a lot of value to bring a lot of
value to my breeding project you know uh
yield uh collar medicinal properties uh
uh the plant structure uh figure in
flower in veg and all those things you
know I don't care if it's come from
feminized or regular seeds all right and
then getting into the characteristics it
really depends on the breeder what the
breeder is looking for in the plant what
do you look for within a female plant to
use for breeding uh first of all I'm
looking like I said for that high value
uh genetics that has
um
what people are looking at the moment in
the market you know and people right now
in the marketing are looking talking for
high medicinal properties like high
percentage of medicinal properties THC
CBD and so forth
also people are looking for very good
bag appeal so color again it's a very
important thing uh purple uh color plant
will be more appealing than a green uh
green plant also I'm looking for
Frost the whole Frosty and how good the
bad look the structure of the bud
how how well the plant grow in veg how
much the plant yields and so forth you
know and also there are terpenes that
our people are looking for some people
are looking more for uh sweet candy
turbs and some people are looking more
for gas and OG kind of uh trains so it
all depends what what you're looking for
and there are different customers that
are looking for different things so I'm
trying to breed for everybody to have
something good for everybody you know
understood yeah it's so subjective and
uh yeah it really depends on and again
with the breeder or the the Breeders
customers are looking for so yeah I
appreciate you explaining that one so
let's get into the actual reversal
process using the sprays so there are a
couple different ways you can go about
it right there is colonosova there is
silver Theo sulfate for short STS
there's also gibberic acid and I know
you said you don't have experience with
the gibberic acid so we won't talk about
that but I believe you have experience
with those dsts and the colloidal silver
yeah so let's start with STS walk us
through the process how do you go about
doing the sprays when do you spray how
do you spray so on and so forth so the
only thing that I've used on my plants
is the SDS spray the abbreviation for uh
for the SDS spray so basically that come
in two bought two two bottles that you
need to mix up and create a spray that
you'll spray your plant your your your
reversal plant for three weeks for the
first three weeks of flour so uh you
take your reversal plant you put it on
flour you put it on a 12 12 schedule
light schedule and right away you start
the process of spraying the plant you
can uh usually I spread between one and
two times a day for the first 15 to 20
days of flour and in 20 uh in a 15 to 20
days you should start seeing instead of
flour you should start see pollen sacks
forming
so that's when you know that the
reversal process was successful you
start seeing pollen sex you have started
seeing a male plant instead of a female
plant with flower plants
the main thing and what I've done wrong
in the past and I want to uh mention
right here it's the timing so
um I start my breeding projects a year
ago putting the reverse the plant that I
refers and all the other plants that I'm
trying to pollinate putting them into
flour in the same time
and uh
by the time that my plant was reversing
was a little bit too late in flower for
my for my flower plants to be pollinated
and create seeds so I want to mention
that the plant that you want to reverse
you need to put it in flour and start
spraying it uh at least two weeks
between two to three weeks
uh before you put all your flower plants
that you try to pollinate them so I
started reversing my plans uh today for
the next two weeks and then I start my
other female plants that I'm trying to
mix with this male plant reversal plant
into flour and then I put them all in
the same tent and I'm kind of doing a
open pollination I put the reversal
plant in a corner of the tent and I'm
putting a fan blowing right on that
plant and when the time it's gone the
pawn sacks will open and the pollen will
go in the whole tent I'm also taking the
plant I'm trying to keep my reversal
plant in a smaller kind of pot because I
want to be able to take that plant and
shake it above the other plants when I'm
seeing a lot of pollen on the plant
because
just by having a flan blowing on the
plant sometimes is not enough you have
to actually when the time it come take
the plant and shake it above the other
plants so all the pollen will go on the
plants so by doing this a link two to
three weeks for the reversal plan to
start reversing you get the perfect
timing for the for the for the other
plants to flower and be ready to get the
pollen you know and uh that's how I got
the best results and the most seeds
because when I was putting the reversal
plant with the with the other flowering
plants the the female plants in the same
time in flower was not enough time to
pollinate and have the seeds made
matcher and be ready to harvest in time
you know
so that's basically the whole process
you just take your reversal plant you
spread for three weeks you bring you you
start the flowering process two weeks
later on the flowering plants and you
just pollinate that other plants the
most important thing on a breeding
project like I said is the genetics that
you breed with and the health of the
plants because as in humans
if you're trying to obtain if if you're
a kid you'll try to have your kid
playing NBA and you are a five five and
your wife it's a five five uh tall
person you don't have the genetics to
have your kid playing in NBA whatever
you do you know what I mean so genetics
are the the main part of this breeding
game you know finding the right genetics
to Bro to breed and then the health of
the plant all right so let me just make
sure I understand this correctly because
I've never done I've never created
feminine scenes before I do have my own
cross Brisco G cross with Pakistan
Valley but I'm doing inbreeding so I've
actually done eat inbreeding all the way
down to an F3
creating feminized seeds is a different
process so let me make sure I understand
what you had just mentioned there which
is the plant that you're going to spray
you'll flip to a 12 12 light cycle
flowering light cycle you'll spray the
plant for the first 14 days you'll
you'll apply that spray once more more
likely like 20 days 20 20 days 15 to 20
days but at the 14 day Mark that's when
you're taking your other plant from Veg
and putting it into flour exactly
exactly okay and so then that plant is
going to start to flower and you're
continuing to spray that other plant up
to the 20 day or 21 day Mark right yes
and then at that point the plant has
created pollen sacs or it's starting to
create pollen sacs and then the timing
should match up to where the plant that
you're going to pollinate is ready for
pollination and the plant that you've
sprayed is releasing pollen and then you
take the plant that is releasing pollen
and you're actually you know letting the
oscillating fan blow pollen in to the
environment you're doing the open
pollination you're even taking the plant
grabbing it up and shaking it over the
other plant I've done the same thing on
the last run I did pollination uh pick
up the plant I had a two gallon
container is what I was in and shaking
it over there the plant to make sure
it's really well pollinated is that
pretty much what you had just mentioned
did I explained that correctly yes
that's that's pretty much what I was
mentioned uh I also want to mention that
when you spray your plant when you put
the plant that you reverse you don't
spread into the tent with the other
female plants because you run the risk
of spraying on the other plants and
reversing the other plants so I take my
plant and I spread separately from the
other plants and um when the plant is
all dry I put it back into the tent
another thing uh these STD STS
this SDS spray it's a very very
um
it's very
um how cold
very sensitive to the light and
temperature so when you spray your plant
make sure you are not spraying it with
the lights on and in a very hot
environment you know I like to take my
plant that I reversed
let it sit outside of the tent or need a
bathtub for 10-15 minutes I spread then
I let it see to dry it up for 10-15
minutes and then I put it back into the
tent are you spraying just once a day
are you spraying multiple times a day
once a day usually but sometimes I'm
doing twice a day like especially at the
beginning or to make sure that the plant
is well spread and will reverse
correctly also I want to mention that
you better have
multiple plants reversing than just one
based on your space that you're
breathing for example I I like to
breathe in five by five tens and I like
to have at least two plants that I
reverse same genetic but two plants that
I reverse
so I make sure that I have enough pollen
to pollinate the whole damn because it
you don't want to get to the point where
you reverse only one plant and you don't
have enough pollen to pollinate all your
other plants you better have extra
pollen or more pollen than not enough
another thing that I'm encouraging
encouraging people is like I said that
time time frame of two weeks you can
take one of the plants and do it to
start reversing it two weeks before but
you can have your other plans start
reversing three weeks before or you can
have three plants like one week before
the you put other in flour two weeks
before and three weeks so you make
because different uh genetics reverse
different and release pollen in
different times so you are if you never
reverse that plan before you don't know
exactly when the pollen sacks will open
for sure and how much Poland they will
produce so you better have more pollen
and more chances to to to pollinate all
your famous uh other plants than less
you know all right and then that plant
that you are reversing on the plants
that you are reversing how big are you
growing them generally and you mentioned
you like to for them to be in smaller
containers what size containers
uh I usually like uh if I do uh in one
gallon Parts I do one gallon pot cocoa
or I do uh the big I think they're
called Big Mama or whatever the eight by
eight uh broccol cubes
so even I do in the big rockle cubes or
one gallon pots and when I'm trying to
pollinate I get a nice dry back so the
plant is super light and I just go and
uh shake it over the other plants
um
the plant I like to be at least like two
feet tall I I don't like huge plants
because when you have huge plants they
cannot sustain themselves anymore and
you get like like the buds will get
heavy and you they'll flop over I prefer
to have few different plants but smaller
ones that I can work better with you
know if I have uh two plants and are two
or three feet tall uh it's a lot easier
for me to pollinate the other plants
when the time come what do you use for a
fertilizer uh for fertilizer I use
Athena AG nutrients it's a salt based
nutrients and uh
a lot of people ask me but Organics are
not better soil is not better uh and my
my answer is uh always do where you can
keep your plants the healthiest possible
if you can if you have your plants super
healthy in soil do it in soil but if you
never use soil or anything or whatever
works for you whatever can keep your
plants the healthy as possible that's
what you need to use it doesn't matter
if it's uh if it's organic or synthetic
nutrients because will give the same
input to the plants or will give the
same nutrients the the synthetic
nutrients the salt nutrients will give
the direct input the organic need to be
break down by uh organic matters and
give to the plants so for me organic is
a little bit more complicated than soil
it's a little bit more complicated and I
believe it's a whole science how you can
keep your plants healthy and create a
nice uh uh
microbiome into the medium that can feed
your plant and the salt nutrients are a
lot easier to control and keep your
plants healthy so my choice is uh salt
nutrients because I can control
everything to a tea I can control the AC
I can control the pH exactly where I
want to be and I can keep my plants
super happy and healthy healthy
understood okay so you've got your
plants growing you've reversed a plant
you also brought your other plant in
that you're going to pollinate you've
done the pollination process what
happens to the reverse plant after that
are you collecting pollen at all or are
you just killing off that plant that you
reverse because you no longer need it
usually usually reverse it plants are
not producing
as much Poland like a real male plant
you know so usually it's not much Fallen
left after I pollinate the plants I
think the plants so hard that is no
pollen left into the plant by the time
it's finished so usually I don't make
sense I don't have nothing to collect I
just throw them away and it's an easy
process I can do it anytime I can take a
plant and reverse it take only three
weeks so no makes sense to keep it
around I just got it and uh I spread out
the other plants into the tent and I
continued the the breeding the seed
maturation of the plants you know so the
seeds are forming in the plants Buds and
uh I guess my next question would be how
long is that plant growing like how long
should the female plant grow and then be
harvested in order to maximize the yield
of seeds right because I imagine that if
you're harvesting too early you have a
lot of immature seeds do you just let
your plants grow and grow and grow and
grow until they're basically dead and
then Harvest or what's your process for
harvesting so uh usually my process is I
let my plants go as much as they want so
I watch my plants I don't even count how
many weeks I cannot tell you I do like
after I pollinate another five or six
weeks but usually it's a little longer
process than flowering plants for um
for bad you know for medicine for
medicine it's a little bit like probably
like uh a week to two weeks longer
process so I like to take my time and
watch the plants uh uh how deep it form
but
um definitely I don't like to see my
plants Dead all the way dead I'm
harvesting my plants and I like to see
my plants still green and vibrant so I
don't do any kind of flushing or
anything I like to keep my plants
healthy as long as I can and um
what I usually do I take a small bod
towards the end and I check the seeds
and see uh if the seeds are mature
enough or I need to let them go but like
I said leave them a longer longer it's
better than cut them short so let them
go for as long as they need check like
Bots for for to see how the seeds are
inside if they are still green give them
another week or so don't rush them and
um and that's how how you do it
um you need to learn to read your plans
and know when to take them down
but like I said it's a little longer
like usually two weeks longer uh if you
cut your plant like your your female
plant that you use for breeding if you
in if you cut it in flour for medicine
uh at the day at week eight or nine let
the the seeded plant go for 10 or 11
weeks you know because you want May uh
match your seeds inside the pot you
don't want green seeds you want all the
way matter seeds so you get the best
germination rate possible that makes
sense so when you do harvest the plant
the process of breaking up the buds and
kind of sorting out the seeds what do
you do for that are you just like
breaking it up by hand and then putting
it into like a seed cleaning machine or
what uh I do everything by hand so I
have a dream Bean where I break down or
I put all my seeded Bots and I start
breaking in down like into like like
like very fine material and seeds all
mixed together and then it's a process
of shaking that that dream Bean where it
separates the seeds from all the the
green material you know and you then
take it by hand and you whatever however
you want to do it
um like I said I'm at the beginning of
my my road and I'm not doing like huge
breathing projects where I need uh uh
separating machines or anything like
that my process is all handmade I take
the seeds by hand I pack them by hand I
do everything by hand for the moment all
by myself
uh and pretty much that's it so
everybody need to find their own methods
that work for them definitely it's a
very meticulous process taking all those
seeds uh by hand but uh it's all worth
it I in my opinion got it I do want to
go back to hermaphrodites so we talked
about a little bit earlier in the
episode but I want to get a little bit
deeper into it what do we need to know
about hermaphrodites I hear horror story
after horror story after Horror Story
that people are getting feminized seeds
they're planting them and they're
getting a whole bunch of hermaphrodites
so what do we need to know about
hermaphrodites you know what are the
chances they occur and how do you avoid
getting hermaphrodites so hermaphrodites
are uh plants that are female plants but
uh they start developing also male
characteristics so they start so they
are 99 female plants with uh with
flowers but they got uh pollen sacks few
pollen sacks and usually those falling
sacks come at the bottom of the of the
plant
um
with all the feminized seeds
especially if they are first generation
so you take uh uh so on uh genetic and
you bring that to a different genetic
for the first time the chances of
hermaphrodites are a little bit higher
and there are chances of hermaphrodites
for sure but I think the main factor
with hermaphrodites is the way you treat
your plants
when when you grow them like the
environment uh where you keep your
plants in the light schedule and how you
stress them because
um
I I pop a ton of seeds from different
people my own seeds and I don't have a
bunch of of hermaphrodites because my
environment is on point it's it's uh
it's what it's supposed to be and I
don't stress the plants in the first
three for the weeks of flour because
feminizing seeds get very easily
stressed in the first three weeks of
flour and the plant will be like oh I
need to survive and put my generation go
prepare to my generation so I pop a
pollen sack so I can pollinate the plant
and create seeds so I can reproduce you
know that's when a harsh environment you
have a harsh environment you know but
when you have a nice good environment
where the plants are thriving and they
are super healthy they don't really have
much reason to hermaphrodite you know
what I mean they don't have they don't
have a reason to hermaphrodite as if
they are stressed out so the main thing
with the hermaphrodites is keep your
plants
keep your plants as healthy as possible
bug free because bugs can stress the
plants as well feed them correctly don't
over feed them don't give them a ton of
light the the usual mistakes that I see
people doing it's too much light too
much nutrients
keeping the plants too wet you know uh
and um
that's that's how you get hermaphrodites
and uh like I said the the
hermaphrodites can happen even with a
good environment because it's the
genetic that cannot be sometimes is not
stable you know but uh that's that's
that's what it come about it's uh
hermaphrodites happen because the plant
want to procreate and continue her genes
uh in a stress environment you know but
if you don't give a reason for the plant
to think that will die and she's all
thriving and healthy she don't really
have a reason to hermaphrodite on you I
feel like there's a way that you can
avoid getting hermaphrodites as if the
breeder actually does testing or sends
their seeds out to be tested first
that's a common practice is people will
take The Offspring and then they'll send
them out to a group of people whether
that be 5 10 15 people and have them
grow it out and see if there are
hermaphrodites or not then if every
things all well off of that batch of
seeds that they've gotten tested then
they distribute it to the community in
your opinion how many people should test
the genetics before releasing them to
the public it's all it's all based on
how big of the of the breeding is if you
have just a small tent you cannot send
to a thousand people you know your your
seeds because you'll have no more seeds
you know but uh I like personally to
test my genetics so I pop all my all the
seeds that I create before I release
them I I I I germinate them first to see
the germination rate and also I like to
hunt my own seeds and find my own
Keepers because that's the main reason
why I'm I'm breeding first of all to
find my own genetics that I can later on
bridge with so first of all I I'm the
one to to do all the testing I'm the one
who do the the German Financial red test
and I'm the one who grow
the plants first
and then I got a couple of friends that
I trust
they can give me feedback and I give
them seeds and hey bro can you pop those
seeds for me and give me feedback but
like I said the number of people that
you give your seeds it's based on the
how big your your project is you know
how big your project is but uh like I
said I like to be the first one who
tells them and I have few people but uh
yeah that's how how it goes I mean that
makes sense you don't want to you know
if your yield of seeds is 500 for
example you don't want to send out 10
packs to 20 people and also there's 200
seeds gone you know more almost half of
your seeds are gone so I get what you
mean by as far as scale and also also
also it's very important to who you give
your seeds to because you need to be
very very trustful people that have very
good growing skills because if you give
to people that are not have the right
growing skills they cannot give you the
right feedback they will pop your seeds
and they'll not germinate because they
don't know how to germinate or they will
harm because they don't have the right
environment you know what I mean so I
like to keep my circle uh tight of the
people that I've trust and give my
sister to try and get the real feedback
from them but the main test that has
right now because like I said I'm not a
big uh breeder I'm not considered that
is even myself a breather yet
it's it's me that's like if it if the
seeds uh cross my standards then they
are good to go for other people as well
you know to send to other people so I
have very high standards and uh I like
to try the seeds to grow them myself
before before I send it to other people
understood so after you've completed
that run you've harvested the plants
cleaning I want to get into that a
little bit it's a common question that
people have because this this pollen
still within the tent right so what do
you do for cleaning between runs to
ensure that the pollen from the previous
run is completely gone so uh I do the
same thing with all my growth is nothing
specific that I'm doing with uh with uh
with the breathing tents but I got a
bottle uh like not like a spray bottle
it's like a it's like a container like a
two gallon container spray like electric
spray with battery and I mix
um I mix Chlor like chlorine from
Walmart I get the Chlor with water and I
mix like 10 20 Chlor and rest water and
I spray the whole tent everything I
spray everything with Chlor and then I I
get my gloves on and I get
um the paper towels and I wipe out
everything in the tent
so simple and basic uh cleaning you know
pretty straightforward there yes so
we've gone through quite a bit here
we're getting up towards the end of the
episode one of the things I could ask
towards the end is did we miss anything
and also do you have any advice for
beginners who are just getting started
with this process yes like I'm not
afraid to share my whole experience with
everybody like so like of the breeders
in the game they try to act like there
are secrets that people don't need to
know because we are the only one who we
need to make those seeds and so forth
but I'm like to be an open book and help
people in the community to make their
own seeds and I encourage everyone to
try to reverse a plant and create their
own seeds you know with their own
genetic and like I said the main thing
is the genetic that we breed with and
the the health of the plant but I want
to touch down a little bit into the
nutrition of the plants into creating
seeds because it's a little bit
different than the nutrition of the
plant when you create a flour for
medicine purpose you know to for smoking
or so on
um so when when I feed my plants uh for
for seeds I'm not using blue nutrients
as I usually do with my plants that I'm
growing for flour and I'm actually using
veg nutrients because the nitrogen into
the in the to the veg nutrients the high
content of nitrogen will help create and
harvest a lot more seeds than if you use
a bloom nutrient with a lot of
phosphorus as potassium so that's what
I'm doing I'm always using new uh veg
nutrients vegetative nutrients with a
high nitrogen content and sometimes I'm
using a nitrogen boost
at the end of my uh of my of my uh
of my plan cycle to measure those seeds
out so people when they they grow for
flower they use PK boost to boost their
their flour you know grow bigger flour
when you breed you try to use as much
nitrogen as possible of course you don't
want to burn your plants your nitrogen
but you want to have a lot of nitrogen
on that on those plants so they can
create a lot of seeds
that's that that that is the point that
I that that I wanted to make for the new
breeders that they start bringing the
timing of the reversal and feeding veg
nutrients are uh very very important
other than genetics that are the most
important makes sense thanks for uh
thanks for expanding on that one so
wrapping things up how can the listeners
find you and is there anything that you
have upcoming in the future that you
want to talk about I have a lot of
things uh coming up I'm trying to to
like I said uh to become a very well
known breather I want to take uh this
breeding stuff all the way to the top as
I did with bodybuilding no matter how
long will will take for me I know will
take some time but I'm very eager to to
to to create the best seeds and the best
genetics in the world and create as much
value you for my customers as possible
through my seeds so I'm working all on a
lot of projects at the moment
people can find me on Instagram at grow
more stress less 2.0 because my main
account grow more stress less was take
down by the Instagram also I have my
breeding account on Instagram it's grow
more fire
also I'm partnered with uh with my
partner in Miami and we got uh
hydroponic online hydroponic website
it's called grow moreextreme.com it's a
website where people can find all their
hydroponic needs at very very convenient
prices we also focus on very good
customer service and helping people
succeed you know we don't just try to be
the next hydroponic or breeder we try to
help people succeed on what they do
because we realize that if we can help
people succeed we are automatically
succeed as well you know so that's
that's my main goal help people succeed
putting a lot of value into my into my
uh projects that I do with breeding with
Hydroponics and everything that I'm
doing hearing and also I'm hunting a lot
of of my seeds trying to create to find
great uh genetics in Clone form
that will bring again a lot of value to
my customers thank you so much for for
having me in your show and I really
appreciate the opportunity to be here
sweet yeah and I know you also have a
YouTube channel and for the folks that
are tuning in on YouTube I'll definitely
link that channel down in the YouTube
description section below I also do want
to pass off a question to the audience
here listening in I know there are quite
a few people who create feminized seeds
I like to know how do you do it let me
know down in the comment section below
I'd love to know the way you do it
because there are several different ways
that you can go about it that's right we
are always learning and I would like
personally to read all the comments and
if anyone has questions for me
specifically please leave them down
below on the on the comments and I'll
come back and I'll promise I'll answer
to everybody questions that they have
for me just uh just mention my channel
my YouTube channel grow more stress last
so I know you mentioned and mention me
on the comment so I can come and answer
to your question all right well if you
enjoyed this episode click that Thumbs
Up Button subscribe to the channel if
you haven't already every single weekend
I'm releasing a new podcast episode
it'll be great if you joined into future
episodes Theo thanks so much for coming
on this has been this has been
insightful I've definitely learned a few
things like I mentioned I have never
done this process before so I learned
and I'm thinking about doing this
process in the future so I'll definitely
refer back to this video when time comes
so thank you once again and I hope you
enjoy the rest of your day thank you so
much for my absolute pleasure and I'm so
glad that I was hearing the show sharing
my passion with uh with your followers
thank you so much have a nice day peace
out everyone catch you in the next
episode