coming up on garden talk because after
the sun comes out and the plant starts
photosynthesizing the stomata close and
all that good stuff so you really want
to harness that
early on in the day like as early as
possible before sunrise as the sun is
coming up that's very important to get
the most out of it plants require
different things at different phases of
the plant's life the big thing is imo or
indigenous microorganisms the microbes
have such a large factor in soil and how
it all works together you realize that
that's really more important than
supplementing nutrients natural farming
inputs within this brew as well and
you're multiplying those microbes from
your imo into the water for 24 to 36
hours usually
nature knows what it's doing and then
we're trying to observe and mimic that
as much as possible
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden talk
podcast this episode number 59. in this
episode i give you blue but some of you
know him as bluegrass green thumb on
instagram he has been gardening for six
years and grows plants such as moringa
trees comfrey alfalfa fruits veggies and
a lot more he's big into the natural
farming approach and he's also big into
plant science in this episode he talks
about plant science that isn't really
taught or even talked about much thanks
to all of you who support this podcast
through patreon if you'd like to support
you can do so by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero cost for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible
thanks to aec infiniti for sponsoring
this podcast they sent me over their
grow tent which has a canvas density of
2000 d making them the thickest grow
tent on the market today it has an
aluminum plate that mounts your
controller to the grow tent with the
light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has 50 percent thicker
steel pulls and carries two times more
weight than the standard grow tents
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their website down in
the description section below thanks to
spider farmer for being a sponsor a new
grow light they released here in 2022 is
the
se1000w this was designed specifically
for those of you who run co280 grow
space and really want to maximize the
light intensity it has a 10 bar design
for an even light spread pulls 1000
watts from the wall and comes in at 2.9
micro moles per joule efficacy the
recommended coverage area is four feet
by four feet or five feet by five feet
use discount code mister growth five to
save on all spider farmer products and
i'll leave a link in the video
description section below
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with blue but he goes by bluegrass green
thumb on instagram how you doing today
doing good man how are you
good good welcome to the podcast yeah
thanks for having me i'm stoked to be
here man
yeah glad to have you on um today we're
going to get into a ton of plant science
that isn't really taught or talked about
much we have a decent sized list of
things to get into and i think this
episode is going to bring a lot of value
to those of you who are big into plant
science
but before we get into some of the
topics we have a pretty decent sized
list today that we can go through
can you do an introduction maybe tell us
a little bit about yourself and how you
got into gardening yeah absolutely
so i am
blue or bluegrass green thumb on
instagram and a couple other platforms i
am an indoor gardener i am a farmer i've
grown several plants in many different
scales many different situations i've
managed large-scale nurseries
kind of been hands-on with plants for i
think we said six or seven years now
kind of on my own
farming and gardening and plants have
been in my life for as long as i can
remember
my grandfather was a farmer he's cattle
farmer he did dairy and beef he did
tobacco corn you know kind of everything
he has hands and everything and i got to
be a part of that um you know sitting on
the tobacco center and
helping plan bailing hay the whole nine
you know probably in the way more than
actually help but you know it's kind of
been been part of me for a long time so
it kind of resonates with with my soul i
guess but yeah that's uh that's really
my background right now it's uh i'm kind
of shifting into more of an educational
front he's teaching natural farming
techniques and teaching sustainability
just kind of
shifting mindsets from conventional
ways into more sustainable
ways and
i feel personally that it builds us as
human beings as well and we all know
that the the world might be able to use
some uh some of that good energy right
so that's where we're at right now
absolutely i know that just our short
conversation that we've had through
instagram that you're really big into
the sustainable side of things and the
natural farming um
and so that's what uh the suggestion for
the topics for today and i'm sure we'll
get into a lot of things that relate to
that
awesome
so let's do
let's see we have a long list of topics
like i mentioned where do we start let's
start with talk to us about nutrient
cycle theory yeah so
mostly what i do is it comes from uh
korean natural farming is the
methodology the system
uh one of the big philosophies within
creature farming or k f
is the nutritive cycle theory
and this theory basically suggests the
uh that your plants require different
things at different phases of the
plant's life all right so early in the
seedling through vegetative stage you
know they can require more nitrogen
the crossover a transition phase
requires something so like in the the
korean philosophy is like they compare
it to a woman during pregnancy you know
she craves something sour
and so phosphoric acid
and one of the k nf inputs that we make
is water soluble calcium phosphate so it
kind of it feeds that that sour craving
so to speak in that transition phase and
then you have your ripening phase
so basically it's it's
the theory is
the right nutrients and the right amount
at the right time so
within the sorry within the the k f
system we have all of these different
inputs that are used
at specific times at specific rates and
it all kind of plays into that nutritive
cycle theory
you mentioned phosphoric acid and i want
to kind of circle back to that really
quick because that's something that is i
mean you mentioned you're using it in
korean natural farming right
a lot of people use it as it's ph down
is commonly phosphoric acid and a lot of
people are worried that phosphoric acid
if they're using those ph down products
they're killing off microbes what's your
take on that
um it's there's a lot of factors in to
play there really
um
you don't like in a living soil type
situation there there's a lot going on
in there with microbiology and humus
humic acids fulvic acids a lot of these
things kind of create a buffer
within your soil and unless you're
applying it in like extreme amounts it's
not going to really affect much
now speaking in terms of like a sterile
grow medium that you're supplementing
only like salt-based nutrients and stuff
with i'm i honestly don't have enough
experience or research into that to
say for sure but i feel comfortable that
if i were to apply something like that
into my soil
the the biology there is going to take
care of it and not going to cause issues
okay that makes sense
now i know an area that you have a lot
of experience on and they really want to
talk about is imo
you talk to us about imo what that is
how you make it so on and so forth
absolutely
yeah so
with within korean natural farming the
the the big thing the the base of it all
is imo or indigenous microorganisms
and you'll notice within k and f
like k f there's a lot of abbreviations
so i'm going to try to you know
reiterate these as we go but
yeah imo's indigenous microorganisms um
when people first get into korean
natural farming the first thing they
want to go for is well how do i make my
nutrients
you know because it's just kind of the
standard mindset i need to i need to
figure out where i'm gonna get my
nitrogen or my potassium my calcium from
which you know to a certain extent is
important but
when you realize that uh the microbes
have such a a large factor
uh in
plants
in general in soil and how it all works
together um you realize that that's
really more important than uh
supplementing nutrients because
look at the the tallest trees in the
world look at the healthiest ecosystems
in the world
who's fertilizing them who's going in
and you know tilling those places who's
spraying them with pesticides
nobody because kind of nature takes care
of itself it adapts it overcomes it's
you know evolutionists the strong
survive and they adapt overcome and make
things happen basically so
the thought behind imo
is you want to
collect these microorganisms
from these thriving areas
so you've got a really healthy thriving
forest that hasn't been
you know adultered by man
and
you can find these patches of
leaves that have stacked over years and
years and years under that you can
usually pull that away and find
life in abundance you know visible
fungal strands and a little critters and
crawlies
so with imo we're collecting those guys
because those are the strong guys right
those are the guys that are going to do
our nutrient cycling that are going to
make our plants resistant to pests and
disease
and all that good stuff
so
we're collecting those
and we put them in a
a storage
state or as my my mentor chris trump
says
cryo-freeze you know kind of using a
sci-fi term there i've always liked that
um you're mixing this collection on
an undercooked rice
basically a simple food for the microbes
to kind of grow up into
and after so many days if you have a
good collection you mix that with brown
sugar and it's it makes it shelf stable
basically
indefinitely if it's stored properly and
then from there we're multiplying that
out into larger substrates into
different phases of the imo process
there's imo1 which is the collection
phase
imo 2 which is that cryo freeze stage
where you mix it with brown sugar
imo 3 were
growing those out onto a substrate
usually a carbohydrate and a carbon
source like
i use rice bran
oats crimp oats rolled oats for a
carbohydrate source and then usually
something like wood chips or leaves or
sticks from the backyard as the carbon
source tube
for that process that's imo 3.
im04 is when you take that and you
introduce that to your your native soil
you're kind of creating this
social gathering so to speak of the
microbes you've collected from these
different
thriving ecosystems and marrying them
with the microbes in your soil that
you're growing in
kind of getting everyone a check and
balance type situation everyone's
situated sorted out so when you
inoculate your soil with this im04
everything's smooth and balanced there's
no shock there's no you know everyone's
confused and the plant is kind of show
oh i'm stressed out you know there's
chaos going on in the ground
but yeah so if you're essentially
applying these big strong microbes that
have helped these forests and valleys
and
mountain life thrive for so long
and you're growing that out basically
and applying it to your plant so you're
creating a similar ecosystem in your
soil that your plants are growing in and
those microbes for the most part take
care of everything else and these other
inputs are kind of just supplementing
those microbes to do certain things so
when you make that
imo solution
how long is it good for do you need to
use it right away or can it sit on the
shelf for a period of time or what
so imo that's another cool thing that's
another really cool thing about it once
you get to imo 2 like if you just have
that collection mixed with brown sugar
you can store that indefinitely in the
right conditions you know you don't want
it to dry out you don't nothing like
that
but you can take the serum it turns into
a liquid that brown sugar kind of if
through osmotic pressure pulls all the
liquid out and stores it you can mix
that liquid with water and just water it
in that way that's the most basic way to
use it now
you can once you take its im03 it gets
you know
100 times better it's you know an
arbitrary number but it gets a lot
better
imo 3 also can be stored indefinitely
it's dry when it's done it's um just dry
product that's inoculated basically uh
same with im04 indefinitely you want to
store it in something that is breathable
you know like a burlap bag or something
like that you don't want to store it
outside in the rain and nature it needs
to there are certain conditions it needs
to stay in but um you can use it that
way the imo 3 and 4 you can top dress
with it you can mix it in your soil if
you wanted to you can also make what's
called liquid imo
with any of these o2 i'm a three or four
and it's basically like a compost tea
but you are using some of the other
natural farming inputs within this brew
as well and you're multiplying those
microbes from your imo into the water
for
24 to 36 hours usually and you can apply
that to your soil implants as well okay
yeah the liquid is what i was kind of
mainly referring to because i actually
had another guest talking about imo
pretty recently greens goddess i think
you might have actually watched that
episode but she had the liquid right
there
and that's one thing i didn't ask her is
how long is that good for um so it's
good to know now i am pretty new to imo
i haven't created it myself
i know there's lots of listeners that
are in the same boat as me there are a
lot of people that take notes during
this
and
a lot of people ask for sources
in addition to it
are there any books that you can
recommend or websites or anything that
any additional sources that you can
recommend that people can learn more
about imo
absolutely
so my mentor was chris trump
and chris trump was um one of the
i think he was the first person the
first farmer in america to utilize these
techniques on a large scale
and he actually had master cho who came
up with
korean natural farming back in the 60s
he actually came to hawaii where chris
trump was and kind of taught him the
process and everything but anyway i i've
learned under him i went to one of his
like in person classes he has a lot of
really really great videos on youtube um
explaining each part of the process
how to collect imo how to you know take
it to the next steps all the other
korean natural farming inputs he's a
really great teacher if you have
the opportunity to take one of his
in-person classes i highly recommend it
a lot of this is
hands-on and you're you can't really
truly learn it until you experience it
hands-on done correctly because of
olfactory senses right you see something
and you know if it's good or bad smell
it you know our memory with
smell is pretty incredible you smell a
good imo pile one time but you're like
okay you smell it again i know this is
good and also with bad it's good to
experience those things so hands-on is
great now
uh so
chris trump on youtube eric weiner or
drake
on youtube he uh cgnf hawaii there's a
lot of resources there to kind of dig
into
but yeah big thing is hands-on training
if you can get a certified instructor
somewhere highly recommend that
some really great
things to look into as well
not specific to k f or korean natural
farming
the teaming with series it's a series of
books teaming with microbes teaming with
fungi teaming with nutrients
jeff lowenfeld is the author and he does
a really incredible job of explaining a
lot of this kind of scientific stuff in
a way that most people can make sense of
and you know i find myself still
revisiting those books frequently
because it's like i learn constantly and
as i go back something else like oh well
that makes sense and you think about it
before you know
highly recommend those things big time
is if you're just getting into all this
that teaming with microbe is actually on
audiobook now for anyone who is an
audiobook person i was listening to it
on a recent plane ride that i had
and uh it's definitely an advanced more
advanced like if you're a beginner just
trying to get into it sure go ahead try
but i think a lot of things will go over
your head
but still
it's definitely a lot of great
information and you're right it gets
deep into the science on a lot of things
talking about inputs uh you said there's
a lot of misconceptions about the
different inputs that are used um i mean
there are so many different inputs that
people put into their soil right what
are these misconceptions that you're
talking about on these different inputs
yeah so specifically to the the k nf
realm uh you know when people first get
involved again they they typically go
for where are my nutrients coming from
so they like to go towards the like fpjs
and ffjs you know everyone wants to make
a banana ferment right off the bat like
oh there's there's my balloon booster
there's my potassium and that's not
exactly how it works
please don't go to the store and buy
plant material to ferment for your
plants it defeats the purpose and i'll
explain
but
yeah so like fpj the fpga and ffj are
more of
uh hormone
enzyme supplements um they are microbe
food
as well and they kind of work in a sense
that uh they can they can trigger the
mic the microbial
they can trigger the microbes in your
soil to
respond the way that they need to for
the phase that that plant is in again
going back to nutritive cycle theory so
if you're making an fpj out of the the
shoot tips of a fast-growing plant in
the vegetative phase you're kind of
quote unquote harnessing the energy from
that plant right so when you apply that
to your plant as a foliar and in your
soil those microbes can be like oh this
is what i need to do in conjunction to
or in relationship with this plant to do
what it needs to do i'm going to bring
this nitrogen to the plant or this or
this and those that consortium of
microbes is going to wake up basically
and do what their role is in that plants
phase because the microbes also change
throughout
the life of your plants too you're going
to have a different consortium of
microbes and veg as opposed to you know
light bloom
so these these fpgas and fjs they kind
of
feed and wake up those microbes so to
speak to do what they need to do for
that plants
phase
um so yeah fpga is not a nitrogen input
it's not a um
you know it's not that your your
nitrogen your vegetative type feed comes
from faa or fish amino acids
um so when you're when you're applying
these nutrients
you should also be applying them with uh
these other
inputs that's another big misconception
is well i'm just gonna you know spray my
plant with fpj well you know you don't
want to do that because
then you're applying just a bunch of
sugar to the leaves of your plants
basically and well you're really setting
up a buffet for pests at that point so
if you're applying
let's say faa and veg you want to do a
foliar spray
the nutrient input should also be
applied with what
is called maintenance solution by some
sos solution
so anyway that is a combination of fpga
fermented plant juice
brv or brown rice vinegar
any organic vinegar will work
just don't use white distilled vinegar
and ohn or oriental herbal nutrient
so all of these
inputs in this maintenance solution
actually work together in a sense
the vinegar
it acts as a cleanser it can help with
pests and diseases
but what's really cool about it is it
can actually act as a catalyst for
whatever you're spraying on your plants
the the vinegar itself can
like the amino acids and stuff and it
can attach to these nutrients and
compounds and make them smaller
basically make the water molecules
smaller so they can enter the plant
stomata easier
right and get more out of it basically
there's a lot of benefits to having all
this together ohn
has warming or invigorating properties
it's anti-pathogenic it's a prebiotic
basically and again the fpga in there is
kind of steering the microbes to do what
they need to do so if you're applying
faa for veg you want to wake up those
microbes for the vegetative phase right
so that's that's that's very important
you don't want to apply any of these
inputs by themselves
maintenance solution is pretty much
applied with every
nutrient input within the knf system
you mentioned how some of these inputs
can trigger hormones i want to get
deeper into hormones because that's
something that we haven't really talked
about much on this podcast in particular
can you talk to us about hormones you
know what you know why they're important
so and so forth
yeah that's a that's a deep one um
so you know all plants have
plant growth hormones or they're kind of
like natural pgrs so to speak but
they're naturally produced um it's part
of
what the plant does you have different
things like auxin uh gibberellins
cytokinin abscess acid uh ethylene
and each one of these hormones plays a
specific
role within the plant
um
so for example what oxen oxen is known
for the elongation or shoot growth
basically apical dominance of the plant
so auxin it kind of promotes apical
growth in the plant um
cell cell elongation
is a technical term so it kind of shoots
up and it can help with root growth as
well so one
um majorly known oxen is
endo acidic acid
that's the naturally produced within the
plant so if you go look at a lot of the
like rooting hormone supplements your
gels and dips and stuff like that you'll
see
indole-3-butyric acid
so basically all that is is a
synthesized version of this auxin that
is naturally occurring in the plant
right
it's been isolated and you're basically
applying this this oxen to your plant to
help promote rooting
so
like with fpga that's that's a lot of
what we're harnessing when we make those
those ferments
and
i'm going to tie all this together now
when you make fpga one of the
the characteristics or one of the things
you need to be mindful of is when you
collect the material to make it out of
it's that it's done before sunrise
right and a lot of people
kind of ignore that especially in the
beginning because they don't really see
why it's like i just need the nutrients
out you know plants leaves or whatever
so plants have circadian rhythms just
like
humans do
if you've ever noticed
your plants and
when the lights come on or the sun comes
out oh they're usually you know they
start to they pray up and they look
happy and then as you get closer to
those lights turning off or the sun
going down they might start drooping
down a little bit well that's that's
kind of the plant in a sense waking up
and going to sleep with that circadian
rhythm
now with these hormones you know things
like oxen
in the morning time as the sun's getting
ready to come up these plants are
expecting
these lights to come on or the sun that
come up
right because of the circadian rhythm so
they take that energy and they shoot it
to the plant's tips get ready to
photosynthesize for the day they're
going to take all this in and do their
job so the hormones are going to be in
the highest concentration
at the tips of these plants at that time
in the morning because after the sun
comes out and the plant starts
photosynthesizing the stomata close and
all that good stuff so you really want
to harness that
early on in the day like as early as
possible before sunrise as the sun is
coming up that's very important to get
the most out of it right because these
these hormones play such a huge role in
the
benefits of all this
the oxen again it'll
sell elongation it'll make the plant
basically grow faster and it has that
energy that you harvested from that
plant you're applying it to yours it's
going to make it grow you know you've
got your your gibberellins your
cytokinins they all play a different
role some cause branching some cause
cell division
so like actually producing um
plant
basically your leaves your stems and
flowers
so you're harnessing all that from
whatever
you're making your fpga or ffj out of so
you also want to
harvest your plant material based on the
phase that that plant is in
right you don't want to take a plant
that is blooming or fruiting
and make a ferment out of that and apply
in the vegetative phase because that
balance of hormones is going to be way
off right
with the way these they all kind of work
together you change the ratios a little
bit between these hormones and it'll
cause your plant to do all kinds of
crazy things i've just with tests and
trials i've tried some of these inputs
intentionally wrong just to see what
kind of results would happen out of my
own curiosity and it's extremely
powerful stuff man like i'm not gonna
lie these these inputs are very very
powerful so it is important to do it
correctly in order to get the results
that you desire
but yeah
you can get enhanced growth better root
development there are enzymes within the
fpga that play all sorts of roles and
breaking down nutrients and taking care
of pest issues and powdery mildew fungal
diseases all of that so
that's super interesting you mentioned
pgrs i think a common one that people
talk about a lot is
i have trouble pronouncing it but
plaquetrobuterazole tacloban i think i
did an okay job yeah
do you know anything about that i mean
that's that's one of the ones that uh
are highly frowned upon if people use it
because i believe it contributes to
cancer as a link to cancer or something
like that do you have any info on that
yeah it's definitely a carcinogen it's
made for
ornamental plants
not consumable plants
so right off the bat that should tell
you not to use it on something that
you're going to
ingest in any way shape or form but yeah
it's a synthetic plant growth regulator
and basically i believe what it does is
it inhibits gibberellic acid production
within the plant so that so gibberellic
acid is another cell elongation hormone
you know it kind of makes things shoot
out grow tall big your your stem
basically
it promotes that growth
so when you block those hormones
from being able to function the plant
stays squat short it doesn't grow as
much so it
sends more of that energy through other
hormones and sends those nutrients to
the other parts of the plants like
floral development and it can make them
more compact denser heavier weight but
it really messes up a lot of other
things too you know like
don't do it there's so many other
options
out there
like with even within k nf a lot of
these inputs can kind of promote similar
type results without putting your plant
through that without you know putting
toxins into your plant soil and body
yeah so
one of the things you mentioned is a
real compact dense buds i think that's
what it's it's mostly known for is
people will receive this bud and it'll
be super compact and like why can't i
grow my plants to be this dense of buds
right but it's just it's unnatural and
it's not healthy so um yeah i'm glad you
you expanded on that a little bit and
let us know exactly what's going on in
the plant and you know why it's bad and
so on and so forth
enzymes let's flip into that
what do you know about enzymes
uh
quite a bit well i won't say quite a bit
i've surfaced leveling a lot of it but
enough to kind of talk about it i guess
enzymes play a very important role in
all of this right so microbes produce
enzymes um you know like i said you've
got this big consortium of all these
different bacteria fungi yeast and they
all they all do a different thing they
may work in conjunction with each other
or whatever but they'll excrete uh these
enzymes and what these enzymes do
basically is break down a certain thing
and make it into a like plant available
form
basically so one of the big things right
now is
like soybeans so it being amino acids
right because it's it's it is an
incredible input all of that complete
amino acid profile it has all these
precursors to different plant functions
so
one of the ways that that is made
is by taking enzymes and converting the
high protein content within the soybeans
into available amino acids and some
enzymes that are responsible for
that process are things like papain
which is the milky latex substance that
comes out of a skin of a unripe papaya
like if you find a green papaya and just
like scrape your fingernail across the
skin you'll see this white oozy stuff
come out
spa pain and that is a protein digesting
enzyme
if you look into like uh gut health
supplements uh digestive enzymes are
probiotic a lot of times you'll see pat
pain in there
or bromelain
uh barmelane is found in pineapples
another protein digester so basically
what they'll do is they'll take these
soybeans and they'll add these
protein digesting enzymes to break down
the protein into
amino acids which are then
readily available for the plant to
uptake and so with like fermentation and
things going on within the soil
a lot of these similar types of enzymes
are being produced to break down
different things whether it's you know
proteins or carbohydrates and fats or
whatever it may be
the more diverse and abundant your
little biology is the more these enzymes
are being excreted a lot of them are
responsible for
like pests they can take care of pests
too so if you're spraying your whole
plant your grow area and everything with
liquid imo and these microbes are kind
of living everywhere on the surfaces of
everything you've got all that action
going on you've got photosynthetic
bacteria on the leaf surface that are
converting nitrogen from the air making
it available to your plant right on the
leaf surface
you know
all of these things so enzymes play a
very important role in making
things available to our plants basically
from um just organic matter
so that's that plays a huge role in
everything that's incredible so you're
saying that there's some bacteria that
can actually take nitrogen from the air
convert it and then the plant intakes it
through the stomata is that right
yes photosynthetic bacteria you can look
into that
nitrogen fixing bacteria so things like
legumes you know soybeans or clover
they actually
have these microbes that can convert
nitrogen that is available in the soil
or air into a form that is available for
plants to uptake and that comes from the
bacteria okay yeah i use clover right
now as a cover crop and i've heard it's
good for nitrogen fixation
but for my understanding the plant would
create it and release it into the medium
is that incorrect
no you're absolutely right um
it's a symbiotic relationship right all
of this kind of works in symbiosis like
you can't have one without the others
like baking a cake and taking out one
ingredient what do you end up with
usually not cake so um yeah it kind of
works in that sense the the plant can
photosynthesize and take nitrogen from
the air and it shoots exudates down and
uh has a relationship with these
microbes and the exchange that goes on
and takes place and then the mycorrhizal
fungi are like oh there's free nitrogen
over here my plant says it needs
nitrogen so i'm going to pull it from
over here back up to the for the plant
in exchange for that plants exudates and
or food for me or whatever i may need do
you feel in your opinion clover is
beneficial in both large operations as
well as small operations like i've used
clover in small grill pots before and
somebody said that's pointless it's not
really doing anything for your plant it
needs to be in a large pot or you need
to be outdoors and use clover and have
that by your plants what's your take on
that
um
different situations are different but
there there are benefits that you could
still gain even if you're not getting
the nitrogen fixation like uh we're
talking about such as having that
uh mulch you've got a living mulch
basically right so
another very important thing with
within all this is
microbial development and fungi in
particular
and when you have a a cover crop that
you know is an inch to three inches
growing above your
surface of your soil you've got this
micro environment basically
in that area and if you've got a top
dress like amendments or a mulch or
something there
you've got this perfect environment for
these fungi and bacteria to come into
and do what they need to do to break
down this organic matter quicker for you
and to thrive and populate right whereas
if you just have bare soil on top of the
light sitting here baking down on it
those guys don't want to be there that
you know like you you want that that
moisture to stay consistent you want
that environment to stay consistent
um a general rule of thumb is
uh 70 shade 30 light
that's kind of like the the perfect
little environment or climate for them
so you're getting benefits like that for
sure and as it grows and you're chopping
it down you're reintroducing organic
matting into your soil which is
nutrients which is micro food which is
eventually going to turn into humus and
organic acids that can act as chelators
or
make nutrients available to your plants
add carbon all that good stuff so yeah
it's definitely beneficial
i will say that
you really want to make sure that you
have your
biology on point if you're going to
utilize something like that
i have seen situations i've had
situations where things like clover and
cover crops can actually be an
attractant for pests
you know it can actually bring things
into the garden because even if your
plant that you're growing is healthy and
thriving if these clover down here
aren't exactly
um
thriving then you've got a buffet
because pests go after weaker plants
they're easier to penetrate they're
easier to get nutrients out of
so just something to be mindful of you
know keep an eye on it at the very least
for damage um
like look at it as much as you look at
whatever
main plant that you're growing really be
observant in all of this observation is
key i think another concern for people
is that cover crops uh it's often said
that they're robbing nutrients
from
your main plant that you're trying to
grow
is that a concern at all for cover crops
to rob nutrients or you know use up
nutrients that your main plant is
going to need at some point
not really a major concern
indoors it might be a little bit
different but
it shouldn't be to an extent that you're
noticing
observable effect or impact from it
especially if you're you know mending
your soil properly or
supplying your plant with these
different inputs that
are nutritive inputs i don't see it
being that big of an issue now i don't
have you know experience like
side-by-side testing it or anything like
that or can't link you to any studies by
any means but
just uh
using the logic that i have i don't
think that that is as big of an issue as
people make it out to be okay good to
know
next up we want to talk about
hermaphrodites i know you uh that's one
thing on your list that you want to talk
about talk to us about it what do you
know what uh what do you want to explain
to everybody
yeah and a lot of this is it's it's more
known knowledge but it still probably
needs to be brought to the attention of
more people so everything that i do
really revolves around how
things happen in nature
um big nature observer because
uh nature knows what it's doing and then
we're trying to observe and mimic that
as much as possible
so i uh i went down
you know a rabbit hole years ago
like why do hermaphrodites happen
and what it comes down to
is uh survival just like every other
plant response basically is some sort of
means of a survival response or stress
response
so if a
a plant is growing in the wild
it's it's
major intention is to reproduce
just like all other species i need to
grow up be healthy reproduce so that you
know my my genes can carry on basically
and in a situation that
a plant isn't in ideal situations and it
it has
factors that
stress it or make it think that its life
is coming to an end or you know it might
not make it out on the other side or
it's not been pollinated
it can send
um
it can
produce
these different ratios of hormones
within itself basically as a stress
response like a last minute resort
basically to
reproduce and carry on
the next generation
so
that for one is something that just just
think about right like
hermaphrodites don't necessarily mean
that the plant itself is inferior right
so that's that's kind of the mindset
that we have is like oh those are weak
genetics you know like well you know
maybe maybe not we could be looking at
it all wrong like oh this plant has the
ability to do what it is intended to do
in nature really well
you know it's all about perspective in
that sense i guess you know we do grow
for
production and stuff like that and that
can hurt our our final product i just
think that that mentality in general and
that looking at it that way kind of um
i don't know it it it changed some
things for me right like um like just
looking at something as being inferior i
see a lot of people you know they get
bashed over you know hello i found a
hermaphrodite and this pack of seeds i
know it's the only one out of a thousand
plants but that breeder ain't doing his
job you know like
come on man this is nature we're dealing
with you know
your plan is trying to survive and
you've got it in the situation it
doesn't like
so
taking that
knowledge and thinking about the
particular
genetics that we're growing
if you've got a land raised variety of a
plant from
somewhere let's say close to the equator
and you put it in a situation
where its environment its
light schedule temperatures humidity the
microbiology
is so drastically different from where
it originates from what do you think the
plant's response is going to be
stress
right
so things to factor you know what kind
of climate is my
indoor area what kind of you know
genetics do i need to be aiming for does
in nature did this this particular
combination of varieties would
would it prefer you know shorter days or
hotter temperature or more or less
humidity drier soil what kind of little
consistency you know what i mean there
are certain things you can do to get
close
but
again observation think through how does
this happen in nature and you can learn
a lot from that that applies to more
things than you realize such as this i
just finished a cultivation certificate
at utah state university by dr bruce
bugbee royal hines mitch westmoreland a
lot of guys that are deep into the
science of things and one section they
had was on hermaphrodites and what
they're saying is there's no
how do i word this
it's kind of like inconclusive at the
point they feel it has to do with
exactly what you said genetic there's a
genetic factor into it and there's a
stress factor into it those are the two
main things but they're still continuing
to study that now you mentioned their
instagram that some k f supplements
could potentially prevent it can you
expand on that yeah so this is
definitely not hard data and i don't
want anyone to take this as such this is
some trials that i
plan to run in the future and i want a
few more people to get involved so we
can have some more data
but going back to using these inputs as
hormone supplements
right so if you've got
a plant in the transition phase and the
reproductive um
ripening phase
you're you're using these fermented
plant inputs for that phase
and i i i have a theory that if you had
a particular plant that was prone to
throwing pollen sacs or bananas or
whatever you want to call it if you can
supplement that plant with the right
ratios of hormones that the plant needs
in that face to do what it needs to do
that it might prevent it from
shifting its own hormones into oh i need
to you know change my stuff up to
pollinate myself to
to carry on my generation
kind of acting as like a precursor so to
speak to doing what the plant you want
the plant to do crop steering in a sense
now i know these are bold statements and
bold words i'm probably going to get
blown up for this one but it is
something that interests me and i think
there might be something to it so i want
to play with that and see what we can
come up with there because that might be
a natural uh alternative or solution to
some of these headaches that we're
dealing with and it might make it more
enticing for people to really dig into
the realm of natural farming too so if
we can get that win then that's a win
for
everybody that is really interesting and
i'm definitely glad that you're digging
down there something that clearly
interests you and you you're taking
action to try to experiment and figure
things out there so that that's cool to
hear
um
epigenetics this is kind of a hot topic
i mean there's some people that
don't believe in epigenetic drift for
example can you talk to us what uh what
you know about epigenetics
yeah and
not super scientific
uh about it but there are certain
factors that i've noticed firsthand
in particular with seeds
i've noticed that well and you know
cuttings clones as well
if you've got a variety that has been
especially for multiple generations
developed in a like a living soil
situation with a robust microbiology
it's all proper nutrients and all that
stuff in the right conditions it's
healthiest thriving um
the the thought is that the next
generation the seed is going to carry a
lot of that information
uh so that it can it's ready to respond
to a similar situation right it's kind
of thinking back to taking a land race
equatorial strain and growing in canada
you know that that seed it knows like
what to expect
you know that that's within its dna well
i i think that
a lot of this
uh
tech kind of plays into that too
if you've got a variety or a clone that
is used to growing and being produced in
a sterile situation
and then you throw it into
a bed that's had im04 inoculated into it
for the last 10 years it might freak out
it might not do good at all and vice
versa you know
all of all of my strains that i've
developed have been developed in living
soil and you know if you throw those
into a sterile salt based type
situation i can't guarantee they're
gonna do real great you know um but i
have seen that i've gotten seeds from
many different breeders and i do
everything pretty much the same way i've
experimented with salts and different
things just out of curiosity
but i have noticed
that the breeders i get from that
practice similar uh methods as myself
tend to do a lot better right from the
get-go you notice it even from the seeds
sprouting out of the soil
it's uh it's pretty wild they just tend
to be more vigorous and robust and happy
healthy they don't have as much damping
off or stress issues and they just
generally thrive
and
there was there was actually i did a
phenomenon 50 seeds and there were like
five seeds from and all from different
breeders and there was one that was a
strictly salt-based grower breeder and
that was the only strain that none of
them made it
you know and that could have there could
have been several factors involved there
for sure but i just thought that was
interesting too
and that that's really like what
interests me and what i uh think about
as far as epigenetics is concerned
i won't get into genetic drift and all
that stuff that one's yeah i don't need
to be blown up from my thoughts on that
one but uh yeah
all right fair enough
awesome so uh we are getting towards the
end of the podcast here thank you so
much for coming on blue this has been uh
this has been awesome definitely dropped
some good knowledge bombs of uh some
science that isn't really talked about
much or taught about much like you had
mentioned to me through instagram
so wrapping things up tell us how can
the listeners find you and what do you
have upcoming in the future
um i'm on instagram as
bluegrass green thumb
this is actually probably the first time
that 98 of the people that follow me on
there will actually see me or hear my
voice so hey y'all this is blue it's
your boy
um so yeah find me there we've got a
patreon rolling officially finally now
i have a discord set up i'm doing some
exclusive content tutorials breakdowns
stuff like that going on we've got a
really great community there come hang
out with us yeah that's really my main
things right now again this is i've been
kind of behind the scenes for many years
now so we're getting things rolling in
towards this uh educational direction so
look forward to hearing from you guys so
is this a face reveal uh
yeah it is
hey there we go yeah nice it's an honor
it's an honor to have your face revealed
on the podcast
this is all very important stuff to me
uh something i'm very passionate about
very passionate about spreading and
getting other people involved in so
having this kind of platform and
opportunity to talk about it and spread
some information is really huge to me so
thank you so much thanks for coming on
and sharing and for those watching on
youtube i'll definitely have a link to
his instagram down in the description
section below and if you're on one of
the podcast platforms just search for
him you'll find him on instagram pretty
easily there so if you enjoyed this
episode click that thumbs up button also
subscribe to the channel if you haven't
already every single week and i am
releasing a new garden talk podcast
episodes and i would love for you to
tune in to future episodes
blue once again thank you so much hope
you enjoy the rest of your day you as
well man thank you so much peace out
everyone
[Music]
you