welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned in to the
Garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 157 in this episode I interview
cardier crops he has been on the podcast
once before episode number 74 where he
talks all about plant breeding we
continue the conversation about plant
breeding in this episode but we narrowed
down the focus to creating feminized
seeds he also tells us several stories
about crosses that he has created three
of them being released this week if you
want to see short clips of these podcast
episodes search Garden talk clips on
YouTube I also have a gardening Channel
where I show the plants that I grow both
of those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said
I'd like to thank the sponsors of to
today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
controller 69 which can help automate
your environment's conditions it'll
automatically turn on and off equipment
to help control the temperature humidity
VPD light schedule and even the
oscillating fans click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about the controller 69 and
the discount code Mr grow5 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend consists of
several ingredients in one so you no
longer have to buy individual bottles it
includes corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi it can be
used in addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use to
discount code the stash
and we are back and I'm joined with
cardier crops how you doing today man
I'm feeling it loving life man got to
love life well welcome back this is your
second time on the podcast first time
was actually episode number 74 Back July
16th 2022 two years ago man time flies
and I was sick at that time I was I was
had chest issues and had some breathing
and yeah so this one's going to be a lot
a bit more active bit more engaging than
the last I was Dam near my dad did the
last oh I remember that yeah listened to
listen back a couple days ago and I
remember that I was like oh man he
wasn't feeling good he still did it
still battle through it I wasn't feeling
good either and then we just we got it
done what we do man you know the love it
I would hate to go out in life and not
be able to do interviews and do the
things that you love to do so I if I was
a croak over at that second I've been
happy that went out like a soldier you
know but even if we weren't feeling 100%
still the episode did very well well it
got 46,000 views and we talked about a
whole bunch of different things in there
your story some of your breeding
techniques we got into today I want to
get a little bit deeper into things that
you do within breeding specifically
creating feminized seeds which is
something you do and you have a lot of
experience with so I think it's going to
bring a lot of value to the audience
because a lot of people like f so let's
get into it and and you're trying to be
you being super nosy but it's okay it's
all good I I'll share as much as I can
uh you know but it's all good yeah well
I know there's a couple different ways
you can do it which we'll get into it
first before we get too deep into it can
you introduce yourself for those that
didn't catch the first episode we did
together yeah for sure man I'm cardiac
crops and I've been growing since 1996
in the soil started outdoor uh went
horribly wrong came to indoor found that
it's a lot better because you can have
control but I've been growing you know
behind the scenes for many many years
and uh you know come 20 about 2018 is
when I went online but prior in 2012 I
had a delivery service I really got into
breeding U really heavy and um you know
started Native Sun genetics and was I
did not start the company to help people
at the time other than my flower because
I was in the streets you know it was
other than the flower I was really
geared to making genetics that would
work for me and and separate myself from
the crowd but it wasn't until 2018 when
I found found out that after I started
helping people online I saw you know I
saw an issue a lot of people had issues
with genetics either they were very
expensive which I can agree because you
know it takes a long time and a lot of
effort to create genetics but two is
that people were getting scammed there
was a lot of issues going on so the
people I was helping in my network which
is up to 24,000 people in my private
group on Facebook was you know they just
wanted good genetics and they wanted to
talk to the breeder and that was another
thing they didn't they didn't have
access to breeders you know you buy
seeds and then you'll never get to talk
to a breeder rarely happens so it was
really cool cuz I was able to offer that
and that's where I started free Hol it
Friday in my group which we do to this
day where I hook up people for with
seeds on Fridays and kind of do the go
along to help them out help people out
play little games and things of that
nature but it wasn't until 2018 and when
covid hit in 2020 that things really
took off because again this is what I
love to do I love to create and and and
you know breed and whatnot but it wasn't
until that time that I saw people needed
help and that's when I just decided to
offer some of my genetics to help out at
no cost so it wasn't like I came into
the game and just put price tags on
everything was like boom boom I mean my
network could tell you I I did it out of
love and out of passion and I just
enjoyed doing this um I was already
financially okay in life doing what I
was doing in life so it was just a fun
time for me to to take this on so you
know that's kind of where it started me
and then you know again helping people I
found you know when I started helping
people online I found the greatest joy
in watching someone struggle with
something I love to do and overcome
those struggles and grow their own herb
and
generate whether it's profits or whether
it's more more in our Network pounds
after pounds I have people who grow so
much herb now they don't they give it
away Christmas time they give it away to
their friends and so that that's a great
joy not only that they're passing on
what I've taught them to people so the
genetics keep us tied in the knowledge
keeps flowing and U it's it's it's just
been a a great thing to experience
because when you're authentic and you
know what you're talking about and you
enjoy this
realm hey this is what I this is what I
like come here to do this is my purpose
so that's a that's a bit about cardier
and ative Sun genetics and uh you know
we're here for the people man that's
awesome man yeah I'm a part of your
email list and geez it seems like you're
always hooking up your audience and you
got some really good prices on genetics
as well actually when this episode is
being posted it's a day after Black
Friday do you have any Black Friday
sales going on right now that the
audience should know about yeah
everybody loves our Black Friday sales
because again our genetics are already
so low people say how why how why even
some of my friends say you're crazy
because you're kind of jipping yourself
and I say well you know not really
because ultimately again I came in with
the notion to help people out so when
you come in like that and you know you
get 100,000 people hitting and talking
and this and that you know you could you
you're taking care of a lot of people so
you're not looking at the financial side
of things you're looking more at the
brand and more of the products that are
are moving in the Creations that are
moving so when with Black Friday coming
up you know we have something going on
and now that black Friday's here we have
our creation that's going on and I took
your chill out OG and uh I was able to
be blessed by you now I don't ever work
with other breeders I don't I've been
asked by many other breeders let's work
on projects together but I feel the
money is always the first thing that
they see they see large networks and
they want to work uh but the chill out
OG I saw something there I see how you
are passionate about the people you help
and almost we're on the same wavelength
in terms of the passion and wanting to
help folks so you know this year's drop
is going to be very special because it
has to do with someone that's passionate
like yourself and then someone like like
our team that's passionate about our
work and what we do so we have three of
my biggest hitters that have done very
well over the past seven years that's
the cardier cookie which is our our
strain that started everything our
Bugatti which was tested over the past
five years dropped on Halloween five
years ago and uh just took over our
Network and people absolutely love it
and a sour I'll tell you a bit more
about because it took forever it took
seven years to get this cut from an OG
who comes from La that is based in
Phoenix now um and he's a street legend
right now I'll tell you more about that
but that was so hard to get my hands on
because you're talking about OG Kush
from 1990 I think in the 80s ' 89 and
then a sour diesel that he worked on
from 92 until now and and and he's been
able to cross those to create a s Ro G
so you know I I just felt like yo I'm
going to bring some stuff to the table
to match with what you got going on and
and you know create some magic so that's
the drop that's happening now for Black
Friday and uh really excited about that
really excited I definitely want to get
deeper into those genetics later on in
this episode I'm really honored that you
actually kind of partnered up with me in
order to uh to do this and I definitely
want to also find out like what you saw
in the chill oo G that really sparked
your interest so we'll get into that
here in a minute the sale runs until
Cyber Monday I assume we go until Cyber
Monday but I kind of like to leave it
open because a lot of times folks you
know wives or husbands still want to buy
those stock stocking stuffers uh up
until Christmas so I leave it normally
what I do is leave everything open until
everyone takes everything and kind of
just honor that and then we close that
down and and uh that's that's the end of
that but I really try to damn near
giveway it's almost like a giveaway um
just out of saying hey appreciate you
guys for the year so it's worth checking
out it's worth taking advantage of and I
can guarantee that the the end result is
worth every bit of putting into your
garden awesome well if you can give me a
YouTube friendly link I'll definitely
toss that in the description section as
a pin comment as well yes sir we'll give
you a YouTube friendly link and people
go there oh all day man you know they
like to mess with us for some reason I
don't I really don't know why let's get
into breeding now one thing I remember
about our last conversation was you said
you started out pollen chucking and you
had felt well it seemed like you felt
like that was kind of a mistake first of
all what is pollen chucking and can you
kind of compare it to what you do now
which is selective breeding yeah so you
know uh breeding is very easy but being
a great breeder is very difficult so
what I mean by that is pollen chucking
is no more than growing you know you
grow 20 seeds and they photos and then
you get a male and a female and the male
pops up and the first thing that comes
to people's mind is oh I have pollen I
can pollinate these these ladies and I'm
going to have seeds and you're
absolutely correct um
but that's what we consider polu because
you never really got to find out about
the genetic you didn't you don't know
anything about the males uh you don't
know about the history of the line or
there's just so many unknowns you're
kind of you're kind of shooting an arrow
aiming at a Target in the dark and uh
when I did that in the beginning uh many
years ago it nothing was coming out
correct at all you know it wasn't coming
out right at all um so that leads a
breeder to what we call phenol hunting
and so phenol hunting is essential when
it comes to looking for the proper
genetics I mean it's it's
it's it and it takes skill to actually
pheno hunt when it comes to the rub when
it comes to the smell when it comes to
the end product it's funny CU sometimes
I don't even smoke you I don't have to
smoke the end product people say well
how are you able to because ultimately
when your senses are all there when you
smoke you kind of mess your senses up
right but sometimes during throughout of
breathing I did it with the chill out I
don't won't smoke for two or three
months so I can get the full essence of
the plant the rubs the smells and all
bring in all of the essence of that my
fingers don't have Bud smell on them and
I can really get a full vibe off of that
but what happens is you know when you
Chuck you're just throwing pollen on
there you're taking seeds now you would
literally have to pop 100,000 seeds to
find that one whereas if you understand
selective breeding you would say hey you
know what I have a a bad female right
here one that is superb and supreme now
I can take another Supreme clone and
another Supreme clone but then when it
comes to the males now that's what you
select and that's what you're going
after I've bought a mail before for
$1,000 which we'll talk about later but
I've bought a mail for a thousand people
thought I was insane but I understood
that you know breeding is you know is is
you know you take Lisa Leslie and and
and Shaquille O'Neal you're you're
probably gonna catch a seven-footer in
that Jean line seven out of 10 times and
so that's kind of what it is you know
just like dog breing you're not going to
take a a stud that is champion from all
across the country and then go around to
Roo's house around the corner who breed
pit bulls and he's got all kind of weird
pit bulls and just breed that dog you're
G to get a so so pit instead of breeding
with a woman across the country who has
a has has a a another champion that's
been you know labeled a champion in his
own right or her own right so blending
those two together nine times out of 10
you're going to get a very great
Offspring
so when you when you pollen Chuck you
are not creating the best genetics that
are out there and we see it all over we
see it a lot we see people there's so
many since the last time we talked
there's probably 100,000 seed banks that
popped up and how many of those are
pollen chucking and how many of those
are truly doing fenal hunts with large
facilities
and super rare I I I highly doubt it you
know uh
so that's that's my take on PA and
chucking man yeah and our last episode
we went into detail and like
characteristics you look for and males
and females we went over so much stuff
so at the end of this episode I'll
definitely link the previous episode we
did together so any viewers or listeners
that haven't tuned into that episode can
go to it after this one so femin seeds
are becoming more and more popular right
you had mentioned kind of pollen
chucking you take a male and a female
and you cross them and then you get
seeds out of that well that's going to
give you regular seeds right so those
seeds when you plant them some are going
to turn out to be males and some of them
going to turn out to be females now you
can create feminized seeds instead which
is a whole different process couple
common ways to do it are with STS
another way to do it was with collodial
silver I know some people use both of
those things in order to do it how do
you go about creating feminized seeds
you know great question man um you know
I went on when I first started the femin
siege run first I was against it
because let's start there because the
truth is femin seeds you're stressing
the out of out of the plant you're
stressing her you're you're constantly
with the sprays and and whatever you do
there's a few ways to do it because you
could use a spray or you could use
stress so you could literally stress the
plant enough to where she her herodes
herself uh separate from the other plant
so if you have one female in there that
you want to you want to stress and and
flip uh you could do that in a separate
tent and just stress the heck out of
that female or you could do the spray
now I went
online I was so totally against it
because again I'm I like the natural
process and the the photos and and doing
this natural way but you know everybody
was yelling for fims and I wanted to
help help our Network out make it easier
for beginners so I go online I buy the
sprays the issues with a lot of the
sprays online which are good some are
good and some are bad some are not so
good is that you don't know how much
of silver nitrates in there you don't
know their recipe and they're not going
to they're not going to tell you the
recipe even if they place it on the
bottle they could be
so now you buy these products now you
spray and you follow the directions
sometimes it works and sometimes it
doesn't and so now you're kind of like
you know this spray didn't work I think
I invested a few few hundred dollars
into different sprays and it just didn't
work and so I kept studying doing
research and I found out that you could
really make your own spray and so that's
kind of where that's where I started so
I bought my own silver nitrate crystals
online and then the sodium uh sulfate
online which are the two the A and B so
anytime you see sprays out there they're
like mix a with mix with b um uh and so
I make my own a&amp; B now I've done a lot
of research a lot of experimenting you
can overdo it and stress the plant too
much to where she won't even flour so
I've seen people where they had the the
plant won't pollinate it'll have flowers
but it won't pollinate and that's
because the spray may be off or that
genetic just doesn't want to work well
with with the the a BS and whatever the
case may be um or you could or you could
not do enough and she only has a few
flowers that that tend to set and again
may drop some pollen but not enough
pollen then the lighting has to be on
point and whatever else because that has
an effect on the the pollen and the
production as well
so when I started to make my own mix and
start to experiment on my own I started
to see much more success um then you get
into the world of S1 and then you you
would then get into the the uh the
crossing of others a lot of people don't
know that when you when you take a when
you reverse a female and she's reversed
and you pollinate another Offspring then
you still have to you don't have to but
fenal hunting that new Offspring now if
she sex S1 is basically sexing herself
so when that when you when you flip that
when you flip her and you spray and she
starts dumping on herself and she sex
herself that's an S1 because she sexed
herself so you though that Offspring is
going to carry almost the similar
characteristics of the mom because it's
almost like a replica almost like a
clone uh but the problem with S1 is a
lot of times they are because it was was
stressed and it's a Herm a lot of times
you're going to find some hermh going on
uh with The Offspring can you phenol
hunt that out you can but again it still
carries that that genetic makeup where
it's it's so possible now does it Herm
the entire plant no what you'll see is
it'll Herm The Bottom some of the bottom
bottom Buds and you can pluck those off
and just continue to allow it to grow
and sometimes it affects and opens up a
few pollen sacks you get a few seeds or
whatever but for the most
that's why I never really wanted to do
films because I know what we're doing to
we're we're playing God and we're
creating it's like us trying to create a
you know take my cousin and create
another cousin just like that cousin
like you know say that's kind of what
we're doing so uh but when you go into
the another Offspring your chances of
hermaphodite kind of are they they go
down because then you're taking it and
it's not a self-pollinated it's using
the reverse pollination on another
Offspring another female so it gives you
a yray of of some Herms in there some
not some that aren't Herm that would
Herm and then from there you need to
fenal hunt that you need to fenal hunt
those Offspring Have to from there you
find a female that uh is stable and you
could then work that female to uh you
know to bring her to a a stability but
again to to to without cloning if we
find a female and you want to use that
female in and let's say uh for feminize
that that stable one you would didn't
have to S1 You' still have to S1 so uh
but using you know anybody out there
that's looking to do it you know and
really do some research because there's
tons of research online now you know you
can go anywhere online and and kind of
find uh information about creating your
own type of spray and I would say start
there and experiment and and kind of
come up with your own recipe because
ultimately what works for me is working
in my room my environment and my setup
but um you know are there sprays out
there that'll work yeah there's there's
sprays that'll work as well so to each
is to each his own you know I know some
of these sprays I actually got one of
the sprays before and it didn't work
right and one thing to keep in mind is
the shelf life so I actually got the
product and waited a year and then tried
to use it and it by then it just it's
not good I think if you get light on it
as well it kind of spoils it you got to
keep it in the fridge well I make my and
and I keep it in the fridge and it lasts
about 90 days um that's what well that's
what I've come to find out with my
sprays I don't let them go any longer
than 90 days and I I still think that's
long because I think I do like 60 days
and it's out so I I'll run through a
crop and then run through another and
then I'm already making another mix but
yeah like I said like I said you know
people got to understand we're in a
Market that is very hot even though it's
about seven years old it's still at it's
still peing so people are out there
trying to get it any way they can
they're making all types of crap and you
know making a profit and so if it works
or not damned if you do damned if you
don't but they made their profit and
they're off they're off getting someone
else's money so just got to do as much
research as you can and kind of figure
out your own recipe for sure and the
alternative to buying a product would be
to create your own like you mentioned
you've got the the two different things
that you created especially if you're
serious if you're if you're being
serious about this if you're just trying
to make money next month or two months
or three months and you're just trying
to make some money and trying to
hustle then then then you need to stop
because you're going to run into brick
walls you you end up you're going to end
up creating crap you know if you're in
it for the long haul then study you know
the more you learn the more you earn
study figure it out through through
knowledge and then experimenting and
trial and error and then then bring
something to to the market that the
people and yourself can enjoy because
then your name will you know kind of
ring a lot longer and so with the STS CC
me from WR so there's differences in how
often you should spray between STS and
then clodo silver the STS cck me from
wrong but it's once every four or five
days you spray and then the clodo silver
I believe is every day too right right
so the clodo silver yeah you you because
of the because of the the amount I
believe the STS that's why you would do
every 4 days um and and you know it's
it's a much higher uh concentrate you
could thin it out but it's much higher
whereas with codal silver um yeah you
can spray you know each day which that's
what I do for 14 days until the bud
starts to sit so I'll spray and spray uh
um they say spray at night time but you
know when you're lighting when you're
not rocking with 20,000 watts on one
plant I think you're okay to spray um
with lights on but you know I do
underneath and above and on the bud
sites and and after about two weeks
you'll start to see the bud set now STS
sprays I never had any I had never had
luck with those there wasn't there
wasn't much luck with STS sprays it was
like I said more of my silver nitrate
floal silver um and you know I buy the
crystals which you know then you know
you move around they they they dissolve
you're good to go I know some I have I
know people that take real nickels you
know a battery with some distilled water
and they kind of do that and that that
you're stripping the silver from that
nickel and that turns in but you don't
know the percentages you have to like I
said there's just there's so many ways
to skin a cat with when it comes to
creating
FS um just got to find your recipe got
it and you kind of already answered the
my next question which is if you create
infomed seeds those offsprings are you
going to have more chances of Herm
treats in there and you kind of already
revealed that yes the answer is yes is
that correct it's a mandatory yes and
when people say oh these plants Herm
well no doubt if you really understood
how her how fims are made it's made from
her making a plant stress and in
hermaphodite itself and that's the
that's the that's the downside to fims
that's the only downside yeah we can get
into weight we can get into some other
things but that that to me that's the
ultimate downside is that if you're
going to run fims anybody that's out
there that's just getting involved in
this game and and saying hey I just got
away from Autos I'm jumping into fims
you you have to keep in mind that this
is one of the cons of
femin and you know you could blame the
breed or are you want to but as long as
you understand and you know the rules of
engagement you know you know you should
know what you're getting into um most
definitely so then should you avoid
breeding with femin seeds because of
that you know that's that's a give and
take because ultimately I've bred with
fims before and what I've seen actually
is my photo that's what this is why I
have the tester program this is why we
do so many different test of man I have
people in in Jamaica South Africa uh
Colombia and we're all testing different
environments and all this and that what
I what we found from the thousands of
people is
that you get a higher return on
females when you use fim in a photo
across
it I found that I found that like you
still get
males but your you know you get more
females uh out of the batch so you've
created your mixture whether it be STS a
clodo silver and your spraying the
plants the frequency that it needs to
and the plant reverses right it's a
female and it reverses it starts
creating pollen sax and then starts to
release pollen shortly after at what
point do you pollinate a female plant in
order to obviously pollinate that and
then have that female create the seeds
if you're not doing the self pollination
okay so that's that's that's a good
question because you want to start
spraying a week before you start
breeding so and this is where I messed
up a lot in the past and anyone out
there that's trying to figure this out
this is this is a great tip is that you
don't want to put your female plant in
that tent and then all of your other
females and start spraying and call that
one of flower you want to start spraying
your female plant a week before you do
the flip so you're still in veg what I
do is I grab my female and I kind of go
outside or you know take it out of the
tent or whatever and I'll spray that
plant um and then put it back in one
week prior to to
flipping so then when it's time to flip
yeah all the plants are in there we're
already going into flip mode and then uh
you know I continue to do my spray and
what this does is it gives the it gives
the female plant an opportunity to start
her start the start the confusion if you
will like oh man I got hit with this
spray what's going on you know I'm being
stressed out you know time for me to
convert and so by the time week one a
flower comes into play she's already
she's already you know I would say you
know mentally ready to convert to
hermaphodite
it's already there so now when when you
get to week one and week two of flower
and your buds are starting to set she's
now starting to produce the pollen at
which if you did it and let's say the
plant is in week three or four and the
buds already starting to set I noticed
that the the take from her to the to the
other plants they're not as it's not as
good it's it's just not as not as good
I'm I'm not sure why but I've tried it
numerous times and it just doesn't take
as well
um when you do the week prior to flower
okay yeah usually what I'm doing cuz I
do in breeding I have one cross which
you're well aware of you did and I um I
bet you I bet you it's a chill out
OG and I've had best luck around day 20
a flower you know that's when there's so
many different pistols uh showing and
once I hit that with the pollen man I
get a real good yield of seeds now after
it's pollinated you've got a obviously
grow the plant throughout the whole
flowering stage and then harvest the
plant are there any different growing
techniques for growing those pollinated
plants versus just regular plants that
you're going for a flower run like for
example I had a breeder on here before
he mentioned that for pollinated plants
he continues on the veg feeding
according to the nutrient chart for the
entire run he says that he swears that
he gets a better I don't know if it was
yield of seeds or more healthier seeds
but he he just stuck to the veg light uh
veg nutrient regimen for the whole grow
do you do anything like that whether it
be nutrients or lighting or environment
or anything I I you know what I I do
pull back on my nutrient feed um uh be
it that when you're trying to grow flour
that is supreme you're you're you're
adding your microbes you have your
enzymes jamming you're really dialed in
and you're tweaking things as you go and
you're really focused on uh the the
quality of the bud that is being
produced the cool part about is once you
once you once the pollen starts to hit
and those pistols you talking about
start turning brown then you know it
took meaning that you know when she's in
her 28 30 day of flower and you start
seeing those brown tips start to start
to do little curl and get brown the
sperm hit that ass you know she's
knocked up baby you know so like you
know it worked and from that point on I
just make sure she's nourished I don't I
don't I follow my same regimen as if I
was flowering but I pull back so I don't
need to invest into tons of microbes
tons of enzymes they do I still offer
that to the plant of course but I kind
of pull back and what I also do is I I
stress the plant a little bit now what
I'm not stressed like it's going to hm
itself but I stress her in terms of
allowing her to pull nutrient up and
pull the food up because if I just make
her lazy then what I notice is those
seeds the development of the seeds don't
start to form as fast as I want them to
uh meaning they they're they're not uh
it's hard to explain they're just not
forming but when when I pull back on the
nutrient and I make the plant say
where's the food and start searching
throughout the media the plant starts
uptaking much more nutrient and then I
start seeing the the the the food
actually goes to the seed because
remember you know it's all about the
seeds at this point not the flow and the
flower is still budding I mean you still
get Bud you know you still get all this
and that but it's all about the baby in
the womb now just like a prenatal pill
if you know a woman taking a prenatal
pill is really targeting specific
nutrients within her body so that prenat
is specifically going for there so
that's when I still push my phosphorus I
still push my magnesium I'm still giving
this plant what it needs but I'm pulling
back because I want the plant to consume
and to pull those nutrients up without
being lazy and saying a this stuff is
everywhere I don't want to eat today I'm
I'm good on that note so it's it's just
my philosophy now when it comes to
trying different methods I've never
tried doing a veg all the way through um
um you know because the seed is still a
flower it's still flowering and it's
still producing and you know um I I'm
not sure there's much research out there
that that's you know says hey this is
the right way this is the wrong way cuz
we still I still produce a lot of seeds
from from uh the way we perform it but
I'm going to have give give it a try on
the whole veg you know on the veg run
but uh I really don't change much of
anything other than pulling back uh and
I like to use LED
lighting I've noticed that LED lighting
works better than HPS and
CMH um it's much more softer it's not as
harsh on the plant remember they're
already being stressed out so and and
and I say this in terms of the female we
are we are perming or we are you know
reversing uh I've noticed that there's
more pollen with LED lights uh than than
using CMH or HPS and only thing I can
think of is that it's you know it's a
it's a lot harsher there's much more
ppfd being being hit uh from a CMH or
HPS so I don't know seems to work that's
interesting and so after you've
pollinated it you're not actually just
going until the normal Harvest window
right you're kind of pushing it longer
than the normal Harvest window according
to the Breeders recommendation right cuz
it's not a regular flower run you're
actually your goal is the seeds to be
developed so I heard roughly 8 weeks
after pollinating is the earliest that
she should Harvest how long do you let
the plant go until you're actually
harvesting so that's that's that's cool
it's interesting question because
ultimately I've had stuff finished in
six weeks meaning the seeds now the bud
wasn't done and that's what I found
interesting was the bud wasn't done you
you Scope it out they're clear as day
but the seeds are dark so a lot of the
blueberry that the DJ Short that we
found and we we hunted and the
F6 since they finish in a uh in the
60-day the 75 day time frame we've
noticed that in six weeks these seeds
are already damn near developed and and
they're they're complete um but the bud
wasn't done you know it still needed
another week or so but uh you know maybe
even two weeks but that's that's on that
note now there are some that you need to
push like the cardiac cookie that we
worked on a chill out I actually had to
let it go a lot longer because it has a
lot of sativa traits in her so the the
seeds form where your chill out was done
two weeks
prior you see what I'm saying and I I
think that has to do with the Pakistani
that's in there because you know the
Pakistani is much more of an indicia
driven so you know it's going to finish
a lot sooner where Mas sativas more my
cookie is more sativa like 7030 so I
could see that happening uh but yeah it
really depends on the genetic and how
the genetic is going to perform that's
like saying again you go back to humans
or or animals that's that's like say you
know you take 10 women that are pregnant
you know not every single one of them is
going to go to that nine Monon marker
there's going to be some ladies that are
ready to pop out a month early some that
are you know you know just different
times so then you start factoring
nutrients and all this and that and
you're finish and there's so many
variables that that that take shape but
I seem to allow to I I watch the plant I
pay attention to what she's telling me
and I kind of nurture her until it's
time to give birth and then you you
could tell another thing I do is I kind
of um because the top and the bottom top
middle and bottom are all going to give
you a different look a lot of the top
buds are going to be a bit wider or a
bit they're not developed yet because
it's New Growth the middle is going to
show you exactly what's going on in the
bottom you're going to the bottom you're
going to get these dark seeds because
they're it's they've been done but so
what I do is I kind of pluck from the
top middle and I kind of see where
that's at and if I can take my fingers
and I could start to crush um you know
uh and it and it crushes and it's watery
then I know that the top piece still has
some time to go but in the middle if I
can push my fingers together like this
on the seed and I could feel some some
strength I know that we she's on she's
right there right the other trick is or
the tricky part is that sometimes the
seeds aren't
dark a lot of people don't talk about
the gray seeds I love gray seeds to me
gray seeds are they're the truth to me
and I've let them go 12 weeks and they
don't get dark they're a breed of their
own they're they're
aliens they don't get dark they're Grays
and but what I've come to find out is
that you're a lot more sativas and a lot
more of the the silvers the silver for
hazes or the silvers you know they they
like my cardiac cookie you're going to
they're gray seeds and they're hard like
rock hard like you got to put a slit in
them and soak them in water for four
days to get them to even pop and they're
just extremely hard then you get some
that are just soft and and dark and real
easy to pop so um again to answer the
question you want to pay attention to
the plant and what the plant is saying
and kind of you know you'll be nosy in
week eight seven eight nine and maybe
even 10 to really determine and you'll
pluck a seat out and you'll know it's
finished you'll know you'll know okay we
can hang got it yeah I think that's a
misconception about the gray seed
something that's not viable or it's
unhealthy came from an unhealthy plant I
mean that's just definitely a
misconception there the best I've ever
grown the best I've ever grown come from
Gracie yeah and just to clarify on the
uh talking about Pakistan Valley the
flowering time for that is 45 to 55 days
so it's a a faster one which is one of
the things that really sparked my
interest uh and one of the reasons why I
like to use it for my breeding project
was that it had that fast flowering
that's something I tried to bring out in
further Generations here now you made
several crosses with the chilo G I have
to ask why the chillo what did you see
in it that you liked Okay cool so the
Pakistani I wasn't too worried about
because I I I I did like the fact that
it flowered early I knew that okay
whatever we we do with this it's going
to bring the the flowering time down on
my that cardier cookie um and I knew it
would add a bit more size and a bit more
indicia to that uh that's that's one
thing I like but that wasn't why I chose
inside you have your Tahoe OG which is
one of my favorites one of my favorite
Stingers you know out there from all the
cultivars I've ever run uh another
classic is you know peanut butter breath
you know you start digging into the
peanut butter breath and those are those
are two Classics to me so when I was
looking at the background of it I was
like this is this is pretty cool that it
has two of two flavors and two
offsprings that I really enjoy and I
already knew exactly what I could do
with those considering I have a cookie
already I have an OG already right
that's that's our OG Supreme the Bugatti
is bananas because you know the
Bugatti's got the the gorilla runs in
there so it's got Gorilla Glue runs and
then it's kid off off with biscotti so
now we're talking gelato and all these
different flavors it's already new that
we would be able to bring what you have
into play and I knew you were working on
it and since it is an F3 that I captured
I I I I knew that I would be able to
find something out of that mix it would
be easier to Target what I needed to
find out of the C2 Cent so really I'm I
I was in search for the Tahoe OG I would
have to probably pop 10,000 seeds to
find that one one that is truly Taho
gleaning uh I didn't get lucky on that
but I was able to pull out the the
Pakistani which is dominant in in in The
Offspring but then also some of the
Tahoe is in there but the the peanut
butter really showed more with the fenos
that I grabbed and that's fine because
again uh you know it's going to it's
going to blend well with the the cardier
cookie going to complement that really
well I was really looking to because I'm
working on my OG line right now so have
a lot of cookie work and so uh I want to
take it back to the OG side so that's
what I was really like geared up to to
look for but you know I add some more
cookie to to the line and because these
will be f1s in the Sour OG we're going
to find a lot of OG powerful genetics
within that Sour OG I don't think we
find it in the run the the the Bugatti
and I don't think we find it with the
cookie side so that's what makes this
project kind of cool cool is that we
have three different uh varieties and
they're really going to have three
different flavors but be some of the
best of the best sitting up there with
with some of the best cultiv bars and
I'll say it right now
guaranteed guaranteed yeah I always like
to hear about people have grown the
chillo G or bread with the chillo G like
what they like about it so it's really
interesting to hear your uh your aspect
on that one I want to get deeper in some
of the cultivars that you created let's
narrow it down to kind of the ones that
youve work with and use the chill OG to
cross with cardiac cookie the Bugatti
and the Sour OG those are the three main
ones let's start with cardier cookie
tell us a story about it you know what's
the taste smell effects how does it grow
so on and so forth everybody brags about
their children their children are the
best right
so I'm going to brag about my baby and
for good reason because number one in
the creation of the cardier cookie it
put me on the couch because of financial
with my wife and the what I did to get
her to create it uh number two my
friends and people thought I was crazy
uh so how it all started was I had a
delivery service and the delivery
service was going well that's where Big
Mike comes in with the sour because I
was buying flower off my guy you know
that was part of my my system you know I
was growing my own seeds I had
everything that you thought of on the
market we kept things rolling our
delivery service was doing very well but
I was just like every other delivery
service the only thing that was
different was my personality character
in our in our delivery people were just
we were top-notch in that field so I
knew that the only way for us to be
separate and to be different from
anybody was to create our own genetic
and I knew it would take a while and I
knew it would take money this was the
time in the era of the cookie era 2012
and you know you had burner out there
and you had all these you know the
cookies really started to take flight
well
um fast forward to
2015 during this time I'm still
experimenting um I came across a guy
online who won the 2015 C High Times cup
for his
concentrate and I'm not going to bring
his name up and I'm not because the dude
the dude is is something else you know
he's not too liked in the community uh
but what I enjoyed the most was that I
knew what he had so it's almost again
it's almost like breeding dogs and you
know somebody that won this won a won a
you know a champion has champion dogs
and you're not trying to buy the dog
from about their character you're trying
to buy an offspring so you could do
something with it and that's how I
looked at this guy he was really jamming
on the East Coast I'm sure a lot of
people have heard of him but I said hey
man I reached out to him and I was like
hey man I I like what you got going on
you know at this time I'm buying cuts
for like $100 $150 and I asked him I
said hey man would you be willing to
sell me a cut and you know he said said
yeah one cut $2,000 I'm like man this
dude is this dude smoking CRA I was like
this dude smok I'll never give somebody
you know that this was my mindset and so
I kept talking to him and he's like bro
you just don't know what he was like
really pushing the fact that you know
you don't know what you have once you
get it and I'm like whatever man and I
we talked about the background so he
used the animal Cookie and then he used
another Girl Scout cookie but again he
had proof that he won a 2015 cut it's
concentrate if there's proof in the
pudding and it was ringing in at 31 to
33% so I knew I had to have that and
start with with that creation so we
continued to talk he finally sold me a
cut man Chris one cut for $1,000 he
decided he said okay bro I'll give you
three Cuts now now let me let me explain
this he gave me three Cuts unrooted for
a
th000 and sent them to me unrooted for a
thousand you talking about shake them up
roll them you know cuz if they want to
root it he's not giving me a refund and
if he didn't send them I would have you
know so my friends were like man are you
crazy bro you could have just went to
Cali and all this and that and I was
like no man I'm Gonna Roll the Dice on
this roet
so he ends up sending them so I go to
Western Yun I send him the money uh and
lo and behold they show up I immediately
put them in and I start to grow them out
now now I get a hold of a guy in Cali I
had some connections in the Bay Area in
Southern Cali you know I've been had
connects there so I reached out to my
connect I said yo man I'm looking to to
get some clones but some some top-notch
clones uh my search guided me to a guy
named cookie Dave he was known in the
Bay Area a lot of people know new cookie
Dave from the 2012 era and uh you know
but cookie Dave he wasn't trying to give
his females off and I thought this was a
perfect time because like I'm down to
buy a male cut now who buys male male
cuts but then I get hit with another
thousand long story short and at this
point my wife is like what are you doing
what are you thinking of oh my goodness
all this dead your delivery service is
going great you don't need to make
anything better and she just didn't
understand that I was like because I
used to breed dogs and we had champion
dogs so I knew that the only way for us
to become champions in this world and
separate ourselves was to do this so I
bought it man we argued bro I slept on
the couch a few nights cuz I wasn't
trying to hear it and uh the male plant
came I grew the females out from what
was sent to me from the female side uh
things worked out really well I crossed
those two I started to work on that line
and I couldn't find anything for a while
finally um we had a I think it was 2016
or 17 we had the I I entered the Earl
cup here in Phoenix and I don't ever
enter cups I only entered the Earl cup
because I didn't want want to send my
stuff off to the labs to get tested and
if you enter in the Earl cup you can go
under an alias and put your stuff in
there and they were going to run test
for you so I think it's like 2016 17
right around that area so that's the
reason why I entered So I entered
it and uh my offspring that I created
came back at 31 317 or something like
that with a 4% CBD and I was ecstatic
because I didn't care about winning the
cup I didn't care about any of that I
just knew I was working on something and
I carried the female line and I had the
cookie from the male so I knew I had
something very powerful very good and
that's basically was the base and the
starting point of my of my genetic line
I said I have some to this day it's what
eight years later and I still have it's
not the original but I still
have the cut from the cut from the cut
from the cut from the cut of the very
first one that I that I produced um I
even done some back Crossing where I
kept the original went down the line and
came back to keep her strong and it's
the reason why people say how did you
get 79 cultivars well it's not truly 79
cultivars what I'm doing is I'm working
my line into other cultivars to keep
that genetic I created strong because
then I go down and come back to some
Originals so it's keeping that's why
when you grow the blue faces when you
grow a lot of my work the antidote cook
you see the original in there and it
still holds the power because my goal in
the beginning was to get power and
flavor those are two difficult things to
do when you're trying to create a
genetic and I don't care who you are
where you're at I've seen some top Elite
flow and I'm like o o and then you're
like o oh flavors there but man this is
like smoking on a flavored cigarette
electric cigarette or something so
getting those two match is very
difficult and that's what we were able
to do with the cardia cookie is is bring
that now to now to to add to that so
when it was done not only did we get it
tested it did really well I was looking
for the Earl Cup results the other day
to so I could you know put more proof on
it but when we did uh when we did the
research on everybody that entered there
was nobody even close the closest was
like 25
26% right and I told Jim Morris who was
the owner of the C I called him up I
said man Jim there needs to be award for
the highest THC content bro this is bu
this is BS bro least you know D and he
was like ah but the judges they go off
flavor and all this and that I'm like
it's cool y'all can have that but you
know so I just I knew what I had so now
now we now it's time to go take it from
the garden to the people
bro I kid you
not the the bud is so
fire that when we ran out people would
put down 250300 for before I even
started the next crop for their for
their Oz they were doing
pre-orders for this
flower no BS pre-orders I it was blowing
us away because like you're already
giving me money for a product that isn't
even in the soil yet that's magic man so
when I started the line I knew I had to
to to come up with you know I had to
start with that as my
base now that created so many offsprings
if you look at my website there anything
that says cardier cookie we got the
cardier cookie BX which is back cross to
the original we got the bxf uh 33 which
is the 33 offspring that with that's a
bit bigger so but no matter what
anything with the original card cookie
in it Supreme hands down if you're a
connoisseur you know what time it is so
we got into the Bugatti the
Bugatti there's a cool story about that
because um I really wasn't focused on
the Bugatti like I'm not again I'm big
in the flavor but you know I what I do
like about the Bugatti is the gorilla
glue and the runs that's in there the
gorilla runs that I I created those two
and you know made my own blend and then
I brought it to the biscotti because
everybody was talking about runs and
biscotti at this time you know everybody
the names sell and this and that so when
I made that mix I I I I knew it was fire
it's it's it's a great strain to have in
your garden I knew it was fire I knew it
was on point but there was a guy in my
group his name was Cliff Hall and I
helped Cliff out so much and he was part
of my tester organ in tester club and he
got the a pack of Bugatti he was some of
the f one of the first people to run the
Bugatti and he he ran the Bugatti and
and before I go to there it's named
Bugatti because it dropped on Halloween
so Bo batti
and so he's running the Bugatti and he
finds some some some magic inside of now
he didn't pop all 12 I gave 12 beans he
popped six um he had some magic come out
of there at this time he's training a
guy in Colorado named Carlos J menz and
he's trying to teach Carlos what I'm
teaching him and he's relaying this
information in this whole nine well long
story
short I didn't know Cliff had cancer and
I didn't know yeah I knew he was a burn
victim that that gave him a lot of
issues with his health um but I didn't
know he had cancer
and Cliff passed
away and you know that was touching
because when I would talk to
Cliff I didn't know this man from a hole
in the wall but he would tell me things
like your grow hand is dope I've ran a
lot of seeds in my past 45 years of
growing and you produce some really
great flour and keep going young man and
he just kept offering me these wise
words and these great compliments and
and I was not being humble at the time
because I'm thinking oh you know you
know I'm I know I'm making moves I know
I'm doing good things but you know the
words he was telling me didn't impact me
until I knew that he was no longer here
and what he was basically saying is you
know when you have a gift or when you
enjoy something in passion in life you
know rock with it and run with it and
and make that part of Who You Are and
that's all he was trying to relay to me
and so the cool the story doesn't end
there now he passes and remember he's
teaching Carlos how to
grow I find out through Carlos he
reaches out to me because he says hey my
friend Cliff who was in your network
passed away I was like oh no I was like
oh man he goes but before he passed he
sent me some
seeds I was like I was like all right
yeah the lemon pie face and a lot of
stuff that I was working on and he goes
he was he wanted me to take over his his
seeds and grow them he goes I tried
running the
Bugatti and I
failed and I was like well what' you do
wrong we went into the what went wrong
he goes I'm not sure but I got three
seeds
left and I want to run these for Cliff
and I was like you know
bro go ahead and pop those hopefully you
find a female out of those because those
were the original f1s and I said I want
to help you through an entire
crop no money no bro I just want to help
you through an entire crop and he's like
b b
b so he finds a
female just out of luck finds this
female and she's superb and we document
the entire Journey so he starts to grow
it out gets his clones he does a tent
and he blows it out the water bro and
that was kind of like full circle
because that was Cliff's home
the young man wanted to learn how to
grow he washes the herb and you know
does his own washing and stuff like that
but the young dude was able to grow the
Bugatti that was handed to Cliff and
it's just the full circle of of you know
this relationship and Carlos and I are
really great friends to this day he
actually sent me the cut so the Bugatti
that I got now is the cut that came from
Cliff's pack and that's the Bugatti
that's gone into the chill out OG
see what I'm saying so Carlos ran that
and did one hell of a job with my
assistance and from this day forward
Carlos is yielding like four or five
bows in a in a 4 by when he was doing
only a pound at a time and it you know
his his growing came up he you know it's
something that we share together with
cliff and uh you know that's that's the
story of the Bugatti man and why it will
always be part of our and every body in
my group they know they knew Cliff
because Cliff was loud he was in the
group and oh yeah cardi ate this and
cardi that and a lot of times like I'm
like you know I don't I don't need all
the you know you you're you're you're
dope and I don't need all that you know
what I mean I'm just doing what I come
here to do but people knew who Cliff was
when he would always brag about me and
say oh he's the best and all this and
that and you know so when I told the
story about him everybody we we all you
know we we felt Cliff but everybody
knows that he was running that Bugatti
too so that's a story on the Bugatti man
um when it comes to the sour like I said
it took seven years to get it from Big
Mike uh the Sour OG is sour diesel the
Argin Sour Diesel from the early 90s and
a OG Kush from the late 80s and this
gentleman I'm speaking of is from La
Watts LA and he's 71 years old so he's
an OG he's not he's not your he's he's
he's not your person that just started
to grow last year you know when we talk
about pollen chucking and then so he
goes by the name of Big
Mike uh many people knew you know 15 20
years ago he was moving bows and you
know there's industry and there's in the
street I've I've majority of my career
was in the street because that's how I
started and that's how where I come from
so when they went IND the street he
didn't want any part of it he's like man
my my systems been working my people
smoke on me you know all the brothers we
know people we know they smoke good they
don't need to go to dispensaries they
don't need to go here there they get it
from they get it from their source and
that's just the way it's been going and
that's who Big Mike was now he had this
OG that was just just dumb good big
yielding great flavor but he would never
come off a
cut never bro I offered him 2 G's 3 G's
5gs no no no boy no boy no this ain't
this ain't that commercial boy this
ain't that commercial this that truth
this is for the people right here this
truth um but four months ago you know
cuz age starts catching up on your ass
you know you start getting older and you
know you start thinking like what I'm
gonna do with my life what I'm G do with
all you know that what I'm G do so big
Mike hits me up he's like yo and now I
used to get herb off big mik CU that's
how I help run my delivery service I'd
be like yo I need a couple y I need one
or two break through do my thing and uh
so now he's really small scale he
doesn't do anything crazy just kind of
laid back but you know he calls me he's
like he's like hey man come over here
man come over here come hang out with
your boy and that was that was odd you
know because I'm not in the streets
anymore like that so I go over and we're
chopping it up and he's like hey man you
know you've been doing your thing and I
see what you been I see what you're
doing he follows me in the whole nine
and that day long story short he blessed
me with a cut better the Sour
OG and he says you know you know I can't
keep this crap forever and I can't take
this with me when I go you know and he's
like you know you've been jamming young
your young blood keep working and so he
gave me that OG plus he kind of knew
from my my circle that I've been working
on this OG line um so you know so he
blessed me with that and uh I'mma tell
you right now bro in the garden it's so
hard when you show videos of people you
know CU I I have it in some of the
videos that's that's connected with the
chill out and you touch it dog if if
you're a true connoisseur and you
remember the 80s and the 90s I didn't
start smoking till 96 but if you
remember in the 90s A lot of that OG
that was moving around from east to west
that's that that's that that's that
original that's all the players all the
hustlers all the Ballers that that that
Blaze from St Louis all my connects and
everybody when you talk about an OG
blowing OG that's him you know what I
mean so that's one of the reasons why I
wanted to bring it to the stage because
number one you have a great stage what
you're doing helping people and like I
said on the same plane we're on in terms
of helping folks knowledge bringing U uh
great genetics to the table you know I
found that this was a place this was a
time to allow a hidden OG like big Mike
to come out he don't want any
recognition he don't want he don't want
his face on YouTube he don't want to be
he you know he just wants it to be known
that yeah you know a Grower's Hand by
the name of Big Mike from our local area
yeah he's let it be known so I said what
better place to put it to and connect it
with a man that's kind of got Network
cracking and knows people all around the
world unlike ourselves in the breeding
area you know we have our Network in our
breeding Circle and uh that's kind of
why chose the the sour immediately chose
the sour I was like this is perfect so
the three that we have lined up for the
Black Friday drop in a whole nine you
know it means a lot it's more than just
saying hey these are some seeds we're
just putting out there and we're trying
to make some money because I'm going
tell you the truth they're all going to
go into the tester phase and if you've
been around and people know know what we
had the tester phase is about we're
talking 75% on all like dropping down
the damage of nothing because we want
people to get it in their hands and to
test and to run and to experiment before
we say hey we found winners we found
Classics we can chill out these crosses
and and these are our retail prices at
which people in our Network and people
in your network that come along and join
this they will then be able to you know
still live live and and be part of those
discounts in the future uh to continue
to grow some of this work so it's more
about legendary as opposed to uh just
creating some stuff to put out there and
get some money off
it's spits Way Beyond that man three
incredible stories thanks for sharing
that that's one thing I want to get
deeper into in future episodes I think
the audience really wants to hear
stories behind genetics because well
often times you go to a website you look
to uh purchase genetics and you see the
name and you see a picture and that's it
there's no background info so being able
to Showcase that in a podcast episode
here I think is uh you know entertaining
and add some value for folks that are
shopping for genetics so appreciate you
sharing that we actually just passed the
hour mark on this podcast so we're going
to wrap things up here can you tell the
listeners how they can find you and what
you have upcoming in the future yeah so
you know cardi crs.com or NSG club.com
NSG club.com is where we you know bring
people in to become part of our Network
again we have a great community on our
website we've created a website uh with
a a good forum area and also a group
area to where when you get our genetics
you're able to then uh grow our products
and share within our community and kind
of talk with other people uh the same
with the chill out and the same with
everything we got going on you'd be able
to join these join these forums or
community and and talk within there but
you can find me there I'm not big on
like Instagram and and you know our
YouTube channel because we get blocked
so often with the whole deal I kind of
just laidback off all all that you know
what I'm saying and you could just find
me on my website cops.com you can add me
as a friend in there and that's the
other great thing Chris is that you know
um I'm front and center so whatever we
put out you have someone there's
somebody to answer to that to that you
know Offspring or whatever so that's
what I like to tell my people it's like
hey I'm here you know I'm not running
from you I'm not telling you something
crazy I'm not trying to hustle I'm right
here I want us to produce the best of
the best so you can find me there NSG
club.com you can click the link below if
you guys want to you know be part of the
entire tester movement it's something we
do on our end to just work with hundreds
of thousands of people around the world
so uh but big UPS to you man appreciate
you know you have me on appreciate you
and what you do for the community and I
look forward to continue to work with
you and uh see where this leads us you
know down the road Absolutely I'll
definitely have a special link YouTube
friendly link down in the comment
section below and a pinned comment so
click on that link and then you'll get
hooked up and yeah got to give a shout
out to the patreon folks as well the
patreon.com mrgo you keep this podcast
going thank you so much everyone who is
being scrolled on the screen right now
special thanks to you're in the producer
tier so definitely helps a ton keep this
podcast going and I can't thank you
enough cardier thank you so much for
coming out of this podcast once again
I'm going to link in the outro card the
first episode we did together so once
you all finish with this one click on
that one and you can get there and
continue on the conversation we had a
real good conversation a couple years
ago still relevant information lot of
good stories in that one as well and
yeah that's good stuff thanks so much
for coming on and hope you enjoy the
rest of your day no problem man you do
as well and I'll be back I'll come back
on and there's lot many more stories So
Stories are what keep us going so much
love everybody and uh I'll let you boy
peace sounds good peace out everyone
catch you in the next episode