welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their
Garden what's up everybody if you that
don't know me my name is Chris aka Mr
growt you're tuned in to the Gard Talk
podcast this is episode number 122 in
this episode I interview Kyle kushman he
is an advocate educator and journalist
and has been gardening for over 30 years
one of the things that he's most known
for is his plant training techniques and
that's what we're going to get into in
today's episode Kyle talks all about the
various plant training techniques with a
focus on increasing yield if you want to
see short bite-sized clips of these
podcast episodes search Garden talk
clips on YouTube I also have a gardening
Channel where I have over 130 videos
showing the plants that I grow in my
garden I'll have both of those channels
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the general public
that being said said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out the humidifiers which can help
increase the humidity in your grow space
their humidifiers have 10 different
levels and spart control features such
as VPD and humidity programming so you
can get precise humidity control click
the link in the description section
below so you can learn more about the
humidifiers and the discount code Mr
Grow 15 works on both Amazon and their
website AC infinity.com stash blend
stash blend consists of several
ingredients in one so you no longer have
to buy individual bottles it includes
corn steep liquor seaweed extract humic
acid beneficial bacteria silica and
micro risal fungi it can be used in
addition to your synthetic base
nutrients or be used in living soil
systems simply mix it into water and
water your plants with it you can get it
at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use to
discount code the stash spider farmer
check out their glow series supplemental
LED grow lights the glow series includes
red LEDs 650 to 665 nanm which is
beneficial in the flowering stage the
glow R40 is for a 2x2 or 3x3 grow tent
paired with the main light below 500
watts and the glow r80 is for a 4x4 5x5
or larger grow tent pair with the main
light above 500 watts discount code Mr
Grow at 5 works on both Amazon and their
website spider-
far.com and we are back welcome to the
Garden Talk podcast today I am joined
with Kyle kushman how you doing today
Sim
salabim that's an old Johnny Carson
reference I don't know where that came
from but if you're over 45 you may
remember
that yeah I have no idea what that
is Johnny Carson used to do a bit called
the Great carnap back where you might
remember this where he wore a a gold
lame turban and uh he would give you the
answer to the question before the
question was read and he would he would
hold the question up and he would tell
you what the answer was and then he
would open the envelope and reverse
engineer the joke so that the question
came last oh that's funny yeah that's
clever thanks for coming on to the
podcast today man I started doing this
podcast back in 2021 and I've been meing
to get you on there's been a hand a
large handful seems like they come in
clusters of people who are requesting
for you to come on they're like we need
to see a Kyle kushman Mr girl collab we
need to see it we need to see it it did
happen on your channel right on your
podcast a couple months back that's
right so for those of you that uh didn't
catch that one I'll definitely link that
episode down in the YouTube description
section below but I finally got you on
my podcast and we're going to talk about
I was trying to figure out what we would
talk about there's there so many
different Avenues we can go we're going
to go plant training but you know we can
also go PL old I have such a legacy just
way too much to choose from exactly no
there was so many different Avenues we
could go I mean breeding was one of the
ones I really thought about but I was
like you know what let's keep it with
the training first you have do a variety
of training techniques you have your own
really signature training technique
which we'll get into but we're going to
keep things very Elementary this time
around right so very beginner focused
we're going to talk about plant training
methods and the focus on really much
increasing yield I know not all plant
training methods are done to increase
yield but you can certainly get a larger
yield from doing some of these plant
training methods but before we get too
deep into the episode can you do an
introduction tell us a little bit about
yourself and how you got into gardening
oh that's good I'm glad you focused that
question like you were GNA ask me about
tell me about yourself and I was like
you know I was born in a little Shack in
soset long you know yes how did I get
into growing that's a good question um
it's really a good question so this was
about uh 19
87 this is about uh three years after I
would have graduated high school and um
I had a pod I was I was a pod dealer and
um I had a job and I was a pod I was a
pod dealer like you know you're you're a
local pod dealer you know that you know
you went over to his house and you hung
out and you smoked a joint you picked up
a bag of and you went away and uh the
guy who supplied to
me I had just moved into a new uh I got
a really cool apartment it was actually
a condo with a walk-in closet he comes
over to visit me and I show him around
my house and he says yo if you let me
grow in your closet I'll split it with
you and literally at this point I had
never even like I had never even uh
visualized that you could grow indoors
like you don't Vision every plant that
you come across in your life like how
does um sumac grow or how does you know
like you don't have a visualization for
every PL food and fiber plant and I just
didn't at that point and he says well
yeah you know I have this little Emily's
Garden thing and you know I'll give you
a couple of containers of powders and a
little pH test kit and a
light and and I grew and so so now the
whole idea was to produce the product
rather than have to like get it from
Mexico or
Colombia and that was how I got into
growing because my dealer was
unsuccessful in his attempts he tried
several times he got caught by I believe
his mother growing in his house and then
he grow at his brother's house and his
wife caught them and then he came to me
and he was like and and yeah that's
that's how I was introduced to grow
that's awesome and you come so far since
then I mean you've been a writer for
High Times magazine for over 20 years
I'm Oak University you've got a place
there you've won several cup Awards can
you kind of get into some of those
things no it was just a it was just a
journey of really just putting one foot
in front of the other you know um it
really wasn't until um I met High Times
which was a complete accident uh not
that I met well yeah it wasn't until I
met High Times that I thought that
anything was ever going to come of this
except I was going to end up in jail one
day eventually you're going to get
caught selling or now growing or dealing
or eventually you're going to end up in
jail one day and uh that's what my mom
thought and it was never happy thought
and then one day I walked into a head
shop a tie-dye shop called Not Fade Away
tie-dye in News New York and uh the
owner there asked he said I'm going to
close up for lunch you want to smoke a
joint with
me sure and then I went to reciprocate
and I pulled out my weed I showed him my
weed and he was like oh my God he's like
you ever wanted thought about wanting to
be in High Times magazine my girlfriend
knows somebody there and there he goes
then I met High Times magazine that's a
long that that's a long story right
there I mean I I dropped out of high
school and um I got my GED and joined
the army and I I really literally like
loathed reading and writing it wasn't
something that I ever did for pleasure
but then when somebody offered me a
job all of a sudden I was
like I'm G to try to kick this in the
ass and that's what I did I kicked it in
the ass and the first 12 months I had 13
features I had 13 pieces in 12 issues in
the first year and that secured my job
there and and then I just continued to
learn more you know about the whole the
culture all of a sudden I was an
advocate you know I like I took a job as
a journalist which I was really proud
and honored to have and I figured and I
found out that I could do that and then
along with that which I'd never realized
came this
advocacy
which I'm a very intentioned person I'm
a very purposeful person I don't do
things incidentally and and then I
realized that this was another great
intention and I I took that on
wholeheartedly and then started
traveling the country first and the
world and meeting all these amazing
illuminaries you know from Keith stra
from the the director of normal and and
the early days of the Hempfest Vivian MC
PE and the peace heathens and and all of
a sudden I'm in the plan rooms with all
these people these amazing events and
I'm just
like I was I was I had never felt
anything similar to how honored and
overwhelmed I was with um a feeling of
purpose when all of
this just evolved I mean like it it I
could write a movie or a book about that
subject
about me that's it's pretty much the
whole ball of wax it's like why am I
still here why are we talking to Kyle
kushman right it's it's all wrapped up
in that um not just the fact that I the
door opened I put my foot in it and and
gave it my all but then that I took
on Happily the whole advocacy thing and
this the normalization and the
legalization and it's just it's just a
fabulous fabulous life I wouldn't I
wouldn't recho it any other way honestly
well I think I can speak on behalf of
many of my viewers is that we appreciate
your contributions over the past 30 plus
years you know you've done so much
between High Times and and breeding and
Oaker University and winning several
cups and all that stuff you've got a
very long history of advocacy and uh we
appreciate you so thank you makes me
feel really good thank you as well and
you know continue the tradition and
there's more more people that need this
information every day so you
know home Growers that's that's the new
advocacy for me it's home Growers nice
nice so what is your style of gardening
I'm sure you've done so many things over
the years but say current state what is
your style are you indoor outdoor
organic synthetic soil cocoa so I am a
homeg growner you know um I don't have a
commercial company I don't have a
commercial branded line um of course I
represent homegrown go very happily um
but I'm just a homeg grower and I put my
my hom grow online on my Instagram and I
share it with people and um and and yeah
that's where I'm at you know I've I've
done I've done and seen it all pretty
much from the the containers the 40 foot
containers buried in the ground up in
spyrock and meno with the
generators and you know garages and
bedro rooms and warehouses with 250
lights but now I'm I'm lucky I've ruined
my home for a 10x10 so I have a nice
10x10 with four LEDs all adjustable and
all climate controlled and uh I try to
keep it as non-consuming as possible
yeah I'm just like you homeg grower I
can max out of 12 plants here so pretty
fortunate I know some of the states are
can only max out at six so I feel
fortunate that I can do up to 12 and um
yeah really fun so I think we relate a
lot on that we're indoor homeg grower so
on and so forth now you are you in soil
or coco primarily what do you do there
you know I only gave soil a couple of
runs and I just I I I was I was never
ready to make the transformation the
whole shift in my head to it um I'm um
the only thing I can say about Coco
versus uh swagnum Coco Blends or you
know predominantly swagnum soiless is I
find that um they're more consistent
throughout in other words it doesn't the
I find Coco changes its properties a
little bit at some point when all of a
sudden it breaks down now that might
have
been old cocoa like you know not your
grandpa's cocoa and maybe theyve uh but
I always found that it was a little uh
less consistent as far as the uptake and
the release of actual nutrients um
so I've always just stuck with soil
soiless um and um I like using a higher
pH I like a pH closer to seven than six
got it so pretty straightforward there
all right let's uh let's get into the
meat and potatoes of this what
everybody's been waiting for training
plants so like I mentioned earlier we're
going to keep it pretty Elementary here
let's start from the beginning what does
it mean to train plants and what are the
benefits well basically you know there's
very few um agriculture natural crops
just as a comparison that in the in in
performing their duties that they don't
train in some aspect uh a good thing to
look at is when I moved to meno I
noticed all the grape Vines and every
year they harvest the grapes and then
they literally cut the vines back to
vert to nothing to the stump and they
regrow all the vines every from the
spring through the summer and uh that's
because they're directing the energy to
the fruits they know how much fruit they
want to get
versus you know you can control the
cluster of the grapes by how much
vegetation is ends up at the end of the
time when the fruit set happens it's the
same kind of thing
with and so if you just left a plant
under its own devices you would have
less
nodes and uh less flowering sites and
they'd be more spread out over different
various Heights and so by training or
supercropping uh whether it's um low
stress training or whether it's high
stress training you're you're taking the
opportunity to manipulate the plant
and uh decide on the number of flowering
sites you want in relation to the plant
size and also you know how long your
whole crop cycle is so it gives you the
ultimate control um and um you know it's
not as complicated as I just made it
sound now I think another good example
is fruit trees right so like uh fruit
trees you can let them grow wild right
but a lot of people have that one main
trunk that comes up right and then the
top branches are all fruits it's pruned
that way it's trained that way in order
to try to get the highest health
possible of fruit so uh we do the same
thing with these medicinal plants The
Orchards you'll see they they harvest
them and then within a month or so they
go back and they trim them all down so
they look like they've all got a pretty
little haircut so that they roughly get
the same number same size of fruit you
know maybe add per for growth but uh
yeah it's very important to uh to
maximize growth and to minimize vertical
height and to maximize we usually most
people will run out of horizontal height
before uh vertical height I'm sorry
vertical height before they run out of
horizontal height in a home
oh yeah absolutely so when it comes to
these medicinal plants talking about
yield how much higher of a yield can you
get from a trained plant versus an
untrained plant that just grows
naturally um another analogy so you know
if you have a plant
that is
leaning maybe you look at it you can
tell it needs a steak or something like
that right a plant that is staked rather
than a plant that is leaning will always
grow faster okay
so by providing certain um support and
uh and uh
limiting the growth underneath uh nodes
that are never going to get developed
branches that are never going to see the
light of day you're increasing your
yield right
there okay that's that's uh Far and
Beyond when you get into even just um
the
exposure of the nodes or increasing the
uh uh capacity for the plant to uptake
nutrients and or water by bending and
breaking and things like that real you
know severe things so um it's really um
it's exponential you can do one uh
technique and it's going to help some
you can do two techniques it's going to
help a little more you do three
techniques all of a sudden you're going
to see a substantial increase in yield I
completely agree and I I think that also
goes down to how long you're vegging
these plants how big are these plants
you actually growing right I mean if
you're keeping things small just doing a
30 40-day veg me personally my
experience I've grown a untrained plant
right next to a plant that I've trained
and I went from 5 ounces to 8 ounces so
I got 3 ounces more from that train
plant so yes you can certainly in my
experience just keeping a small hom
growth style can certainly have several
additional ounces just from training
your plants so I think that's one of the
reasons why people practice it so much
one thing that I did learn pretty
recently just in in last few years of um
touring uh large grov uh Santa Barbara
and something like that I noticed a
guy who of course you know they need
thousands and thousands of clones you
know to to to do these Acres of outdoor
green houses or even hybrid green houses
and I noticed that you know um you know
when I take clones I probably take four
five even 6 inch clones because I have
all these I can bury it a couple of
inches and I'm going to top and do all
these things but you know when you take
commercial agricultural clones they're
usually pretty small they're usually two
to three inch clones and what I was
noticing was that basically as soon as
they had grown an inch and rooted they
were topping them and I asked him I said
do you really do you do that all the
time do you top your clones so early and
he explained to me how this is a really
important technique because I used to
wait until the plan was virtually
developed like fifth node seventh node
uh you know multiple sets of full leaves
and branching already coming out then
I'd use this spiral staircase technique
where I take a leaf from each side to
open it up no top your plants as soon as
possible because what that's going to do
is as soon as you top them it's going to
uh encourage lateral branching and now
your lateral branching is going to be
the height of your plant instead of
having any apical top whatsoever
virtually so that's something that I did
learn early is top as early as you are
comfortable with and so topping for
those that don't know is really just
taking the top of the plan and either
pinching it off or using trimmers to
trim it off to you a a pincher or a
cutter I've always been a pincher um uh
you
know I I never had any trouble
visualizing where I was supposed to do
that you know the top of the plant is
just simply the top of the plant and you
you should just take off a a burgeoning
newly opening set of leaves and pinch
and then of course there's that that old
um
technique that came about from a tip of
the month that I wrote in High Times
magazine that got uh labeled fine and I
love the fact I love this story
because
femming everybody would swear it means
bleep I missed missed right because the
theory was that if you cut it cleanly
like with a scissor that it's just it's
not going to grow back and then the two
uh nodes that would have popped out on
the side of the stem is what's going to
take over and you have a nice clean V
but if you kind of mess it up and make
it all messy
uh sometimes very often nodes will shoot
out of there in addition and sometimes
there three four five crazy numbers of
them shoot out depending on your growth
rate and
stuff but it was never intended to be
fimming the the the tip of the month
came from a dude who signed his letter
Thim I believe it was his name it was
from Thim didn't say anything about
missed just the culture itself attached
that acronym to it and I think that
that's
hilarious that is hilarious I had no
idea that was the case I heard the the f
I missed I heard that one but I didn't
hear about it actually being somebody's
initials or name or whatever yeah I love
that so when you do the topping or the
fiming what node are you waiting until
the plant has grown up to before you do
your first topping or fil well I used to
wait for five maybe even six or seven
complete sets which would mean that
you'd already had one or two sets of
branching coming out and so the top of
your plant
is it least several inches taller than
those side satellite
branches um and like I said what I saw
in a commercial setting was is that um
you know do it as soon as you know that
your plant is
flourishing um and that's going to allow
you to um have a wider plant rather than
a taller plant um because the the plant
is just
programmed to grow as tall as possible
because in the big bad jungle the actual
jungle where things grow the one who
grows the tallest gets the most sunlight
and very often ones that don't grow T
enough don't get any sunlight and
literally just croak and die so um so
yeah so I mean uh it's going to depend
on where you took your cutting but so
that's why I say it's not really it it
doesn't really matter the actual
maturity size of the plant how many
nodes it has what matters is is that
you've planted
it and uh watered it and the roots that
were coming out of your clone are now
coming out of the media in which you
planted it as soon as you see that it's
acceptable to top it understood for me I
usually grow from seeds so I am kind of
one of the guys who are counting the
nodes and I usually do like the fourth
or the fifth now do you just do one
topping or do you do you know your
initial top and then top some of those
side branches that kind of grow up well
it kind of depends on whether you're um
you know if you're growing for
commercial um then you really try to
condense practices into the most
effective most efficient and I think
that that's probably a singular top and
probably a singular transplant you know
um into its final home when you have
options to you know I see these guys
growing on lines where they they
interweave the plants and they make them
look all pretty and they put them
through the chicken wire and you know
um
I think one top is is most of the time
is going to be access uh uh uh
sufficient um it's only when you and the
and I'll say the reason why I say that
is because by the time you get to the
thought of topping a second time on that
same plant I think that there's a better
way of utilizing that
vegetation than there is topping it off
um of course the secondary goal of
topping other than yield enhancement is
uh maximizing your uh the space that you
have and if that
top that you're thinking about topping
again is because if you bent it over or
tucked it under somewhere uh it would
just be uh growing outside of the ver
the horizontal space that you want for
that plant then you should take it off
um so that's you know that's my
explanation is is one one top should be
sufficient but if you feel like if
there's some satellites that are growing
out of the way and you don't think you
can weave it somewhere or put it
somewhere efficient then top it again
and of course the nodes will just take
the place um no
topping uh no topping once you flip
flowering unless you missed it you
should you should know by then whether
you want to use that piece of
vegetation to gain mature flowers or not
if you noticed a piece underneath that
you missed and it's not going to do it
get rid of it if you if something is
shooting up and you don't like it but
the best thing to do would be to bend
that down and just secure it with a
twist tie or a piece of string or super
cropping technique and then utilize that
vegetation rather than chop it off and
throw it in the garbage really good
advice there yeah and I'm with you on
the one top I've you know I've done it
so many ways over the years top once and
then tops those branches top those
branches again and I played around a lot
and I find myself in you know the past
five plus years really just doing that
one top letting those side branches come
out and then just doing low stress
training from there which we're going to
get into here in a little bit but uh but
yeah the one top one of the main reasons
why I do is just to get that side
branching there's some fenos out there
that I'll grow and I don't need to top
at all the side branches are just
natural it's good to go but having that
one top in there really helps with those
side branches and bring things out
horizontally like you like you mentioned
right I for example I'm finishing up 6ot
tall plants in my tents right now and I
think I top those three
times so that I could end up with 22
dozen tops you know maybe even more um
so that's a six foot plants I top them
three times depends on your goal yeah
yep so awesome so we got topping we got
fing I do want to get into one of the
things you're most known for which is
the chiropractic training technique can
you describe what that is how do you
came up with it and how to do it so on
and so forth I love that name too
somebody along the way like 10 years in
started said hey that's like
Chiropractic kushman Cairo kushman
Chiropractic I was like I was I was
calling it
supercropping and basically super
cropping to me is is any technique that
enhances yield you know hence super
cropping and
uh the the Cairo came interestingly
enough uh a long long long time ago it
was like literally one of the first
stories I was ever sent to cover for
High Times magazine and I drove there
from New York across the border in um
Ontario or something no it wasn't
Ontario it was uh
anyways uh and I was going to meet uh
one of the few legal
patients in Canada like just like us
there was only a handful of them back
then and uh it was a h a young cat he
was like 18 years old he was living with
his mother and they were only allowed to
have two
plants and so he had two
plants one each under a th000 watt
parabolic do you remember those seven
panel 45 in parabolic reflectors it
looks like a dog cone collar around an
exposed bulb turned upside
down I actually used those for a good
the first eight 10 10 years of my
growing and so what he did was because
he was only allowed to have two plants
he basically had the plant right
underneath where the bulb
was and he had the plant
trained like a
candleabra so the bucket is in the
middle and he's got a little bit of
stock coming up and as soon as the stock
starts he's got a branch trained out
like this and there's little nodes
sticking up here and here and here and
he's got a branch coming this way and
then there's nodes sticking up here and
here and here so if you could picture
underneath this parabolic light the
light hangs down to here he has a plant
that is all trained out with all these
branches and all these no standing up so
that the ones on the outside are the
same distance from the bulb roughly 2T
from the bulb you know two and half as
the one underneath it and so he created
this
Arena underneath of this plant and he
did it with a combination of bending and
twisting and he was using
um it was like a floral uh the wire they
use for floral arrangements to keep them
in place it's a real stiff wire and it
was the most amazing thing I ever saw
and I being uh more lazy than he he had
more time on his hands than I did to do
that one thing I guess and I had a a
real job I just started finding a way to
twist and bend and then kind of like I'd
massage the plan and as I'm doing this I
slowly bend it over I'd first break the
inner herd and then slowly bend it over
like this until it's sat down
perpendicular and then take my thumb
underneath and do a little pinch little
just a little pinch just enough so that
it couldn't grow back up there it was
much more efficient for the plant for
the tip to just grow up and so without
all that wiring and all that tiring I
came up with uh that supercropping and I
started doing this candleabra shaping so
that so that I could one keep my lights
low
to all of the budding
sites
and
um and that's and so the the techniques
before me that was like scrog right and
the thing that I didn't like about scrog
was um it locks your plants into place
and being a
journalist I always wanted to be able to
find the best angle for the
photograph and so I developed that
along with the TP technique where you
take uh three stakes and put them in
like a tripod in the bucket and bring
them together at the top like this and
then you tie strings from the top of the
Tepe down to the branches so that you
could support the larger branches in the
end uh and you I I still had autonomy on
the plants so it was just a it's like me
holding my pen I hold it like between
this finger instead of this I always got
to be different for some reason that's
really interesting so you were you were
the creator of the super cropping huh I
didn't know that well you know I don't
you know I'm sure that it was uh you
know it's like I didn't create uh
veganic farming you know when
I designed Vega Matrix but I did
highlight it I did kind of bring it to
the Forefront and that's maybe what I
did is you know I I I I brought it to
the Forefront that you could do these
Uber
manipulations I used to tell this story
about somebody who told me once
literally this old man he said yeah when
I grew we grew in the woods and stuff
you said when I put my seeds in the
ground I'd come back later in the season
and I would just stomp on them I just
stomp on crush them boom boom I'd walk
through the garden two or three times
and then the ones that grew back up were
the strongest ones and I didn't have to
worry about going too tall so people
could see them it's like they're weeds
and you know it's it you can you can
manipulate these things is amazing I
suggest I don't have any sites committed
to memory but if you look around there's
these uh plant
artists um all over the internet that
are doing these Bonsai you know did you
know that you can Bonsai any plant yeah
oh yeah I've seen it it's not a people
think that a bonsai tree is a bonsai
tree it's it's Lally you can Bonsai any
plant and is
extremely extremely conducive Ive to all
kinds of manipulations the trick is
which ones get you there the fastest and
which ones are just ornamental right
yeah and you can be very extravagant
with things like you mentioned or you
can keep things simple and just not even
doing a topping or a fimming or really
doing any high stress training
techniques where you're damaging the
plant at all you can just do what's
called low stress training right just
bending the branches down can you talk
to us about low stress training what
that is and maybe how you go about doing
it well I use low stress training as a
as like I said a second or a third
technique I've already done several I've
already broken the the the the main
stock you start off right at the bottom
of the plant um and people wonder when
when you do this I don't do it when it's
early or young um I usually do it um I
used to do it a lot but I F found one or
two really good treatments at the right
time is the best thing so um
like a week or so before flowering um is
really all you need you start at the
bottom and you in opposite directions if
you if you stabilize the plant you'll
hear a snap sometimes it's pretty darn
loud and and if you let go the plant's
not going anywhere you've just broken
the inner herd and then you work your
way up every inch or so and break and
every Branch you do that like that and
you create these really nice Knuckles
that uh make the plant stand on its own
and also you're increasing uh the the
cap the capillary action inside the
plant where its ability to take up water
and
nutrients and so I start with that and
then um as the plant progresses and I
have these branches that are
outgrowing even after I do you do the
topping at just the right time you're
still going to have you know two weeks
in three weeks in four weeks in whatever
your avenging is I only like to do two
or three weeks usually you're going to
have a couple of branches so the second
so as I'm going back for my weekly
supercropping kushman CYO treatment
that's when I'll do the where I massage
it and I bend it over and then crack it
right where I want it so I'll look at
the plant from the above and I'll find a
spot where that Branch if I bend it over
is going to take an open spot and I bend
it there and then finally when the
plants are kind of like their shape is
all good and I'm like a week into
flowering or maybe two weeks into
flowering and I see what's going on now
I'll use a passive technique to just fit
finish off where I want everything and
that could be by putting a steak in at
an angle and then pulling this Branch
over to the steak and just clipping it
to it so that now there's room in
between the branches so you're opening
up the center of the plant or simply
taking a branch that I've already
um without a stake and just finding a
node where you can attach a sling and
then just uh putting a a hole in the top
of the bucket and then pulling that out
slightly and securing it to the rim of
the pot and so now that's a good way of
opening up so those are passive ways
where you're not um you're not damaging
or wounding the plant uh you're just
moving things to make the absorption of
light more ideal and the actual um the
actual physical uh uh structure of the
plant so that you're filling in spaces
and taking advantage of opening up the
pl so that your secondary and your all
all the lower inter nodes get light and
even canopy is a Grower's best friend I
like the way you explain that you
explain it so a beginner can pick it up
and even just bending the branches out
to get light in the middle is definitely
beneficial it can definitely help
increase light down in to penetrate the
canopy and that can certainly help
increase yield overall so appreciate you
explaining that one another thing so
just to SP a little bit is you know um
well okay what I was going to get into
was you know and the next thing people
want to know is about de leafing and
denoting yeah let's get into that I was
going to talk to you about that so um
this is a very important part of
maximizing uh your plants so that you
get the right amount of uh full mature
flowers as opposed to all kinds of
errant little undeveloped um
ly uh immature stuff so um what I like
to do is um the first time I clean up
the
plant I clean up the plant um so uh what
I initially wanted to say was so when
you're when you're manipulating the
plant and uh manipulating the branches
to maximize the light coming in you're
going to have all kinds of leafage
everywhere popping up and big leaves
from the interior what I say is interior
leaves interior pointing leaves you
always remove okay because they're going
to be cutting covering something up so
that's an easy one
um I think the trick is is to leave both
uh nodes and um the lower
leaves because those are your solar
collectors so if you lollipop as they
like to call it the first time you clean
up your plants and as you're denoting
you remove all those lower leaves you're
going to slow the growth of your plant
down um
I dare say 10
15% unless you're growing at a very high
density if you're growing plants that
are allowing to be receiving each their
own full intense direct light meaning
they're not smooshed up against each
other don't remove those lower leaves
until later on when flowers start
developing and you're really worrying
about air flow and stuff um because what
you want to do is you want to get down
underneath the canopy of your plant and
look up into the light and everywhere
where you can see from the ground and
you can see the
light that's photons of light that is
getting wasted it's going from the light
and hitting the ground so if you have
leaves intermittent leaves even though
they may be three nodes down from the
main leaves okay if you've got a leaf
here and a leaf here and a leaf here and
a leaf here it's collecting secondary
light and a little secondary times four
five on each plant adds up to
substantial light and that adds up to
root growth uh and taking up water and
nutrients so uh don't remove that stuff
the first time leave it through veg and
leave it into early
flowering um and uh and so uh when you
get ready to flower about a week in
about two weeks before like when you do
the first chiropractic is when I'll
start denoting and what I do the first
time is it may sound crazy but I
denote either just leaving the tip and
like one or two nodes or virtually all
the way to the tip I will leave no nodes
I may have eight nodes on this branch
and I'm only I'm going to den Noe all
the way to the tip and I'm going to
leave all those little leaves in between
that are there and it's going to be bald
all the way up to the tip now that's cuz
I like to grow a lot of sativas
and now I'm a week before flowering that
means this plant is going to stretch for
another 3 to four weeks giving me
another six seven eight nodes from where
I left it and that's going to take away
all my
lar and I don't have to go back in and
do it again now if I'm growing an indica
or a hybrid I'll leave the top and just
two extra
nodes and then by the time bud set
happens you've got your six to eight
nodes anything below that is garbage but
if you lollipop and remove all those
leaves the first time you do that you're
going to slow the plant down that's an
interesting way to go about it I haven't
heard anybody doing it that way was
something that I probably want to try
out in the future because uh yeah I
totally get what you mean by that it can
certainly slow things down if not done
properly and the other thing too is when
the plant um the re the the plant wants
to grow sets of leaves you know what I'm
saying I mean that's what it's going to
do right so if you if you have a nice
long hearty Branch you know I'm growing
you know you grow you you're growing
plants that are a foot tall that are
going to flower at two 2 and 1/2 feet
I'm assuming okay that's kind of an
average size height a two and a half
three foot tall flowered plant um you're
going to have nice long Hefty branches
that are a foot long and they're going
to have lots of nodes on them and
there's going to be four to five leaves
in between there from the top and the
bottom and uh I'm telling you you leave
a branch for a couple of weeks of
vegging where you would have taken off
those four or five leaves it's not only
going to grow slower but it's going to
stretch more in between the nodes
because it needs to throw out more
leaves because it's trying to replace
what you took away so what about like
defoliation though like just plucking
off leaves or like Leaf tucking do you
do any of those well that's how I
learned that uh leaving them was so
important because when I was really
young and I was 25 years old 24 years
old I started
growing I didn't have any guides well
there was actually the Ed's guide was
out um but uh I found that um tucking
was very useful and I'd do it several
times a day I would go into the garden
and I would tuck them down and they
would pop back up again and I noticed
that they were blocking you know
branches and nodes that I wanted to do
so I tuck them down again um but then I
learned that if you leave the
exteriors um and wait and and develop
the interior of let let the interior the
the branches of nose develop on the
interior that it's a big increase the
just how much energy that plant can
absorb how many photons of light as
opposed to the surface
area just use Ma everything is life is
math right so if you've just removed um
if you Den Noe like later on where I do
like I'm now I'm a weak into
flowering and I'm going to remove every
leaf that is not 50% of the height of
the plant any Leaf that's not 50% in the
middle or above that's when they go and
so now I get the nice air flow and I get
more water turnover and all of that like
that um but before that those so that
those few buckets that I'm pulling off
and you fill those few buckets imagine
the surface area of supplemental light
like I said just get underneath and put
your eyes and look up and if every where
you see a crack that you see the actual
light
array that's if it don't remove that
leaf imagine like pulling it and now you
see it now you yeah I'm getting a
little no I I understand and I agree
with you I like to leave all a lot of
the outer leaves for the reason you
mentioned and also some of the lower
leaves and one of the things that was in
one of the videos I created gosh it had
to have been five or six years ago now
that's on my channel talking about
lollipopping and deing ation is leaving
kind of the lower set of leaves right
above the lollipop I used to lollipop
but uh I typically still do a quarter to
a third of the plant and then um that
first batch of leaves leave them some
people take them off and um I usually
leave them it kind of looks like a skirt
I call the skirt technique is leave it
there because another reason why to
leave it not only for light penetration
like you mentioned is like you want to
capture some of those photons that are
there those are solar panels but this is
is also going to help you identify if
there's a problem happening right some
of these problems that happen are going
to be on those lower leaves right like
nitrogen tox nitrogen deficiency for
example starts at the lower leaves so
like you can you're able to still see
that and then take action right away
versus if you were to remove them well
you might not notice as quickly so I
call those indicator leaves and that was
taught to me by an old outdoor grower um
you always want to have some of the
largest oldest leaves because they are
the only in the only early indicator of
some of those nutrient deficiencies and
uh um the there's another reason I like
to leave actually the some of the older
largest leaves is because again it goes
back to the photography and the
journalism it just looks really amazing
when you have that original Seven bladed
leaf that ends up turning all fall
colors you know and it's it's this big
it's as big as a dinner plate and
there's the plant behind it like that
it's just makes for a great photograph
absolutely yeah I've had my fair share
of very large leaves that I've I've
taken pictures of it's uh it's exciting
really is so of all these training
methods that we talked about you've done
quite a bit over the years to many
different plants what are some of the
biggest yields that you've gotten from
plants that you've trained I'm always
shooting for yield it's so funny it's
like I I tell everybody I always try to
grow the best not the
most but really let's get real
Adam you know I'm Adam before I was Kyle
and it's like that's why how I overgrow
my garden all the time it's like I'm I
don't I don't really intentionally set
out to grow the most but then once I get
started I'm trying I'm I'm putting so
much energy into maximizing everything
from from cycling the plants as much as
possible to develop the most prolific
roots to uh literally not overdoing it
but feeding hard because the plants want
food in order to produce a lot of fruit
you know and really overdoing it and
then and then of course I can't get in
there and take pictures of the plants
anymore because no they're so big that
they just they it doesn't look like
they're supposed to anyways um what was
the question I lost the question largest
yields like biggest yields you've kind
of gotten from trained plants the
biggest plants I've ever grown indoors
are actually probably might be in my
tent right now um and they're equal to
the ones that I did uh back in Mendo
days um I grew a little bit over a pound
of plant and they were uh Sage Master
Adam duns th seeds
sage and I grew uh was right after I got
arrested believe it or not in
mesino and the trial was pending and
everything but they didn't take away my
rights to grow so like literally I got
out of jail the next day and I went and
planted six plants so so I had medicine
and
um and so at that you know it's so
you're only allowed to have six so
I grew them to the ceiling and probably
vegged them for you know I don't know
three two or three months two and a half
months or something and uh a pound I
think the it was close to a pound and a
quarter indoors in my basement and and
that's what I've got now I've got these
20 gallon um 25 gallon pots six foot
tall I vegged them for 90 days and um
they're just finishing up their eighth
week here right before I get to go to
Barcelona I'm going to be be harvesting
here pretty quick and uh they're going
to be 12 to 16 or 18 ounces each so I
got I only got eight plants it makes it
really easy take care of you know a lot
of trimming yeah but it's really easy
cuz everything is just super super chunk
col is and then the there's really not
much trimming to do on some of this the
the varietals that I'm playing with um
The Grape Ape and the the Cherry Lopez
is like little here and there and it's
just very very yumalicious then mixing
easy yes so kind of getting towards the
end here I want to get some advice from
you really advice for beginners think
about back when you first started
growing and uh you were a beginner and
if you could tell yourself what you know
now what advice would you give your
beginner self well uh back then my
beginner self would not have told
anybody and my first crop that I ever
grew would not have gotten
stolen but besides that um you know it
really is
uh the plants that are the healthiest
are going to be the most potent and
yield the most so focus on growing
healthy
plants um and the key to doing that is
observation
um unlike a lot of other skills that you
acquire it takes um a lot of uh doing
over and over and over again training
muscles and brain and coordination and
all these things gardening is really
more about
observation and if you can uh uh by
observing you what I call you learn the
language of the plant and the plant will
speak to you not out loud necessarily
but the plant will speak to you and you
will learn uh what the plant uh the
plant will Express itself in different
ways whe when it's happy versus not
uh when it needs water um and and and
you know it's a living being you know
some people will argue whether it's cian
or not I'm not here to get into that but
it is a living it is alive and um
so uh
observation um you know check in on it
now and then every time after you water
and you'll get a sense very quickly as
to whether it liked what you gave it or
or not um and then you have to assess
was it just the you know you know
there's other factors but just
observation and
um and try to remember that uh a plant
is not a machine it's not like a car
where you can put higher octane gas in
it and just hit the throttle and make it
go faster it's it's um uh there are
sometimes when you have to treat it like
an animal where it's a living thing
where you can hurt it and so you have to
observe like if you suddenly you're
gonna get a guinea pig and you never had
a guinea pig you don't know what to feed
it you don't know how to take care of it
you have to observe so observe and uh
and then and then there are other times
when you can treat a plant like it's a
machine when it's like um it doesn't
know you don't you can keep it in
vegetation vegetative state
forever and it won't matter it's not
going to get hurt and wonder why the the
sun isn't going down um and develop you
know uh so it's a combination of uh of
techniques that you learn through mostly
through observation and then of course
trialing out well said well we covered a
lot of stuff in this episode in regards
to plan training and increasing yield I
appreciate you coming on today can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and is there anything upcoming in the
future that you want to talk about well
I'm Kyle kushman 420 on Instagram and
that's my my main Outlet uh besides uh
YouTube which is uh sponsored of course
by homegrown Co and how great is that
that you can now have access to all
these just hundreds of Rial and um so uh
there is lot you can search uh either
homegrown or Kyle kushman on both
YouTube and on Google and there's
tutorials that we've been doing now for
uh eight years plus hundreds of hours of
cloning and drying and planting and
harvesting and and uh strain evaluations
and what they're good for and different
ailments and so there's a there's a
whole lot of video out there that I've
put a lot of work into and uh that's
what I'm most proud of um and uh and
then uh yeah don't forget I didn't even
say it once don't forget my podcast we
just had an awesome episode with Jim
balushi you know we did a Christmas
episode with you of course Mr Gro and so
we're now in our second episode we're
well along in our second season rather
and um that's on all streaming platforms
and uh I'm really enjoying doing that
and going to bring some really
interesting guests in the future awesome
yeah really great podcast once again
thanks for having me on and for the
audience I'll definitely have a link to
that episode that I did with him on his
podcast down in the YouTube description
section below along with a link to get
to him so uh you guys can easily access
how to get to Kyle's social media Kyle
thanks so much for coming on this has
been awesome I really appreciate your
time today you broke down a lot of good
information in regards to plan training
and I think it's really valuable for a
lot of my audience so once again thank
you so much and hope you enjoy the rest
of your day you as well you're very
welcome and uh uh grow your own
everybody peace out everyone catch you
in the next episode