coming up on garden talk a hollow stem
compared to a solid stem will relate to
typically higher production in trichomes
we can stress a female out and make her
create manners then that means the
hermaphroditic trait is dominant her
pain profiles from that stem rub i
always stress that it's so important one
particular alleles are one particular
version per gene that is homozygous
status that's what we want to achieve
when you see f2 f2 f2 that's when we've
opened up to the most choices of
phenotypes and our characteristics and
our elios is what we call them that's
when we start our selective breeding
process don't get discouraged
understanding is going to take your time
understand that you definitely are going
to have to have a passion for gotta have
a love for it because this is literally
your life's work
what's up everybody if you that don't
know me my name is chris aka mr growit
and you're tuned into the garden dog
podcast this is episode number 31 in
this episode i interview zaza genetics
he has been gardening for six years and
he grows a variety of plants such as
collard greens tomatoes squash kale
medicinal varieties and watermelons he
is also a breeder and that's what we're
going to be getting into today he's been
breeding for 15 years started out with
dogs then transitioned over to plant
breeding in this podcast episode he
talks about plant breeding on an
intermediate level thanks to all of you
who support this podcast through patreon
if you'd like to support you can do so
by going to patreon.com
mr growit before we get into it i want
to acknowledge that one of my goals for
this podcast is to bring zero costs for
information about gardening all plants
to the general public that being said
i'd like to thank the sponsors of
today's podcast to help make that goal
possible dutch pro is a sponsor of the
podcast coupon code
mrgrow10dp will get you a discount on
their products they are a plant
fertilizer company that has been around
for over 30 years they originated in
amsterdam and their nutrients are
available in several countries across
the world they have everything needed
for proper plant nutrition from base
nutrients to additives and ph regulators
i will leave link to dutch pros amazon
store down in the description section
below and don't forget to use coupon
code mrgrowit10dp
for a discount on their products a big
supporter of this podcast is spider
farmer they sponsored this podcast and i
use their led grow lights spider farmer
now has a bar style series of led grow
lights they have the se 3000 a four bar
fixture for a three foot by three foot
grow space the se 5000 a six bar fixture
for a four foot by four foot grow space
and the sc7000 a six bar fixture for a
five foot by five foot grow space i will
leave a link to spider farmer down in
the description section below and you
can use discount code mr grow at 5
during checkout for discount on their
products thanks to ac infiniti for
sponsoring this podcast they sent me
over the grow tent which has a canvas
density of 2000d making them the
thickest grow tent on the market today
it has an aluminum plate that mounts
your controller to the grow tent with a
light proof pass-through for cable
routing the frame has fifty percent
thicker steel pulls and carries two
times more weight than the standard grow
tents
coupon code mr growit will get you a
discount on their products and i'll
leave a link to their website down in
the description section below alright
now let's get into the episode
all right we are back welcome to the
garden talk podcast today i am joined
with zaza from zaza genetics how you
doing today
thank you for having me man it's a
pleasure yeah glad to have you on we're
going to talk about breeding today so i
actually did a video with vader og
from ocean grove genetics a while back
we did a beginner video on breeding and
this one i feel like we're going to get
more into more intermediate things now
some of these questions some of the
viewers might ask and they might say
you've already talked about this on the
last video but a lot of things with
breeding i feel like are subjective
right like when we start talking about
traits and stuff that breeders look for
so we're going to get into all of that
that's why some of those questions are
asked on both that video as well as this
video or a podcast episode i should say
and then i did actually have people
submitting questions through instagram
so if you're not following me on
instagram
mr.growit follow me on there and you get
a chance to ask questions in the future
to future guests so before we actually
get into the nitty-gritty of plant
breeding can you tell us a little bit
about yourself and how you got into
gardening
yeah yes my name is salam originally
from new jersey
born and raised so um
my initial passion for gardening um
started ironically sounds weird but it
started with dogs
we learned a family tree of dogs and
that kind of
ended up learning through research that
it was well connected with plants as
well in gardening
my gardening experience started about
five years ago outdoors
vegetables
uh
kale
collard greens all the good stuff um
especially um it kicked up really
uh in the last couple years with the
whole virus thing and everything
everybody wanted to kick up their immune
system and you know so we get into all
the natural plants and medicines and um
that's that's kind of where my my garden
started about five years ago outside
actually with the vegetables
nice and i know before we started
recording you had talked about how you
started with dog breeding 15 years ago
and how a lot of that knowledge actually
transfers over to plants which i thought
was pretty interesting and we're going
to get deeper into it i got to ask in
your opinion what
makes a reputable breeder you know why
are you a reputable reader i thought
that was a good question from somebody
through instagram that asked that
definitely um that's important too
that's a really good question
as far as me transparency um
transparency
and education like that's that's the
most important thing being able to
educate not only your friends and and
your fellow bromies or gardeners but
also
you know if you have followers if you
have customers whatever your niche is
whatever you have uh educate each one
teach one um and and i think that's what
makes uh a reputable breeder being open
with everybody you deal with gotcha
now there was somebody who asked a
question through instagram he's got a
very small space
and he wants to know how much space do
you need to
micro breed i guess you can call it
right what's it like the smallest space
that you can actually breed in
that's that's a new term but um
it's new to me but um it doesn't take
much space at all that's the good thing
about breeding um you know when you
think
uh in terms of gardening you tend to
need a lot of space as far as generally
creating
vegetables and flowers you know you tend
to need more space but when it comes to
making seeds you don't need as much
space typically ideally uh two by four
tent uh if you cook two tenths would
even be better um you know but that's
pretty much all you would need what's
your setup look like
um i run a 2x2 i'm sorry 2x4 i'll also
run a
4x4
um i did have a 2x2 up but i took it
down uh my my uh mother i have a mother
uh mac one which uh
typically got way too big she's about
eight feet tall she got way too big for
her two by two so that we
don't use anymore gotcha so as a home
grower you can definitely do breeding
you know just a couple tents you can
definitely get away with it so that's
cool
now let's talk about selection process
so this is where it's kind of like
it's gets into subjective right it comes
down to breeders preference okay so
starting with male plants how do you
select your male plants for breeding
so male plants is a tricky one too
because typically you'll never
really know it's really hard to
determine what treats a male is going to
pass off to a female offspring you know
it's kind of like similar to like um
you know if a dad the dad is it's going
to be hard to look at look at it dad and
say
i wonder what his daughter's bra size
may be once she is born
you know
well it's really similar to that and um
we we have ways and tricks that we
um that we can kind of
you know use our best
uh kind of give us the best idea of what
would be a good true male breeder and um
stem rub stimulation of the you know
getting kind of getting the idea what
those terpenes strong terpene profiles
and that typically will relate to good
flavors and
strong plants ultimately medicine and as
well um
hollow stem a hollow stem usually
compared to a solid stem
will relate to typically higher uh
content as far as production in tribe
homes
if that's something that you're
interested in
and probably the
biggest one structure as well structure
and bigger
vigor is um probably the biggest one um
a vigorous growing uh vigorous ground
plant is going to be
one that you want to
use using your
you know your
it's just your lawn
gotcha now i know some burritos they'll
stress their plants you know whether
they do training or some folks will let
their plants grow naturally do you let
your plants kind of grow naturally
christmas tree style or are you like
training your plants and kind of
stressing them out in certain ways to
kind of help determine whether or not
that's a selectable plant
absolutely stress testing is very
important as well um at different stages
you definitely want to stress test the
mail for the selection process and
that's probably the only reason i would
ever train a potential
male for you know breeding would be to
uh you know stress test
um training uh
defoliating
uh bending twisting turn and all that
good stuff um that's pretty much you
would only do it for that reason not
necessarily for flower production now
what about like feeding i guess kind of
in relation to stress testing in a sense
to
you kind of give them like a lack of
nutrients i think some breeders do that
they'll run low on the nutrients or
they'll try to go heavy on the nutrients
to kind of stress and see how the plant
evolves and then kind of make their
decision off of that do you do any of
that or
well spiking nitrogen is typically good
a really high spike in nitrogen kind of
give it a little overdose of nitrogen
will uh be a good
you know stressor
um i don't necessarily me personally i
don't uh under feed
this um i think it'll take too long to
kind of get the results that i'm looking
for
as to where a spike in nitrogen is going
to give you that instant
kind of indication of this plant and
whether it can you know how hearty it is
okay that makes sense
so the plant's been growing male plant
you have identified meal plane you
flipped it over to the light cycle for
example and now it starts producing
pollen sacs pollen sacs produce you know
first time i ever grew a milk plant
seeing the pollen sacs within a couple
weeks and like opening within i think
within three weeks like i thought it was
just super quick you know and i wasn't
expecting that the first time around do
you collect pollen and save it and store
it for breeding in the future or do you
just let your males grow to a certain
point put them in with females and kind
of let them get down and dirty yes
that's a good question too so typically
it's
i mean ideally you want to do the ladder
you want to be able to sit a male in
there with the females and ultimately
through my experience i've seen a
difference in um
seed production uh bigger beautiful
seeds and better offspring um even the
female they seem to react to knowing
that the male is in the tent with them
and um they seem to perk up they seem to
be happier uh it just seems like a
better experience overall for the
females um but that's always not ideal
as far as you know
you can't always do it so it's much more
convenient to have pollen stored and uh
be able to you know just uh put it in
you know soap or just pollinate the
plant especially in the terms of when
you when you have to store pollen for
back crossing
uh back crossing is very important when
you're trying to stabilize the line so
that is um you have to slow power for
the most part in that sense
can you tell us how you store the pollen
uh well i would um pretty much
uh well depending on whether it's
autoflower or photo period it's a really
big difference so um like you said like
um
actual male plant is gonna have an
avalanche of pollen like it's gonna be
impossible not to you know so easy to
collect it you pretty much just wanna
make sure that you
dry it out and
then store it within the uh whether you
want to store it long term you want to
put it in the freezer and a little glass
jar or
you know or a refrigerator if you plan
to use it
really soon
but autoflowers is a much more
intricate process you're gonna really
have to go in and actually use tweezers
and pull the pollen sacs in most cases
the pollen is much less viable it's much
less there it's barely any so you want
to um collect it by tweezers as many as
you can pollen sac bar pollen sac at
that point i would then use um a
strainer like a bowl strainer
um i would use the bowl strainer and
kind of
shake uh shake everything i got in the
bowl strainer to um get the little bit
of pollen if so if i can get it that way
perfect if not much comes out then we
got to kind of individually break each
one open
with the tweezers and
remove each and every pollen sac because
um
that's when you get into moisture
moisture can
destroy pollen very easily immediately
and make it non-viable so you have to
make sure that you um
typically i use dehumidifiers as well
when i'm collecting power in that room
you want to lay it out
flat on the table if possible have a
dehumidifier keep the
humidity at least 40 or below if
possible
um you know that's the ideal
setting for pollen and
you want to uh
let it dry out for a couple hours make
sure it's completely dry no no pollen
sets are in there clean it out good and
then you can collect it once it's dry
and stored in like same way with a
regular mail with freezer or fridge okay
that makes sense somebody through
instagram asked i don't know if this is
true or not they said they hear that
keeping pollen and baking soda picking
powder can help so would mixing the
pollen into baking powder in order to
stabilize the humidity work i wouldn't
do it personally i've never heard that
method myself personally but um it's not
something i mean
it's always something worth looking into
or you know um we learn every day so
i'll definitely be looking into that
after the show i'll tell you that yeah
it was the first time i've ever heard of
it either i thought it was an
interesting question to bring up so
let's get into a female plants so you
know selecting the female what do you do
what characteristics you look for so on
and so forth
so the female selection process is a lot
more fun in my opinion you know everyone
loves females you know so in this case
um
it starts really early uh and and that's
why uh you
you know that's why we use or that's why
i use the power the paper towel
for germination is um that's that's when
the selection process starts in many
cases um
if those tap roots don't come out really
vigorous and strong you know i'll put
them to the side you know i'll mark them
but you know you want to start that
selection process right there within
that paper towel and um that's when the
fun begins you know you get to actually
see and you know you do the same stem
rubs and but you you know you know it's
going to be a female so you pretty much
it's a visible it's a visible thing when
you have um
multiple plants to select from
typically uh you know you just gotta
know what to look for
so you're you're even from the beginning
you're killing off plants right away
from when they're seed now are you
looking for things while they're growing
in veg seedlings are you wiping out
seedlings are you i'm right now
not all the seeds are going to make it
out of the paper towel uh even even the
ones that have uh decent tap roots that
they may not you know if i'm looking for
real real bigger then i need to um make
sure i'm only picking the biggest
strongest ones with the biggest
strongest tattoos and then from there
yeah absolutely um we we start the
stress test on females pretty early as
well so because um you know that
hermaphroditic trait can uh that's when
it'll come out in a female pretty early
during the veg stage whether it's light
or uh you know heat or those are
typically i'll even use artificial when
um you know exploring high winds on it
and um
nitrogen spikes and things like that
typically if that if that trait is
dominant uh we just want to we can bring
it out pretty pretty early during the
veg stage in a few
pretty easy
so you get the female plant growing all
the way into flower you know as it's
going along you're you're killing off
plants are there any particular
characteristics that you're looking for
in the female plant i don't know if you
touched on that typically the same that
we look for within a a male besides um
it's just it's just a lot more obvious
like trichome production of course when
you know you're getting those trichomes
really early and uh all hanging out on
the fan leaves and you know those are
always really good signs um you know
terpene profiles from that stem rub i
always stress that it's so important on
my lives we always do it as a fun you
know fun thing together we get up there
and we're all rubbing and we're like hey
oh my gosh you know
you know it's always a but it's such an
important thing because it really does
give you those profiles and gives you an
idea and um you can you can see the
differences even within the same
genes you know you can see the
differences and smell the differences
and um that's that's a big selective for
me and um
but but during the late flower stage you
just um
kind of just want to
your focus is so much at that point it
begins so much on seed production at
that point so you kind of you kind of
back off what we typically would
normally be using for a normal uh
medicinal plant uh and producing flour
you know the phosphorus and then the
potassium and you know we kind of kind
of back i mean potassium is okay but the
phosphorus and stuff we typically back
off and uh kind of just keep running a
little nitrogen and um
and whatever else we may need but um at
that point
yeah you're pretty much already selected
once you get to that stage
okay so you've actually selected the
female within the flower stage at the
point where it needs to be pollinated
you don't actually
grow a plant take clones finish off
plants
oh yeah oh um
well yeah for males mostly we we we use
cloning as a big for males but um
with females i don't necessarily have to
cut as many clones you always do as a
precaution
typically just to be sure and always be
able to go back
but males sometimes you're cutting two
clones per map
just to make sure that they all get out
there successfully and you know you want
to test them and make sure it's just a
lot more testing uh clones with a male
than it is a female
okay so you are actually completing the
female smoking it
and then taking the clones of that
female and using that to pollinate
yeah it's a lot of painful yeah
typically
yeah all that's pretty much the whole
program is cloning
male and female mostly clowning because
you got to be able to go back every
vegin we do some reversion at times um
with females we re veg um i particularly
don't do it as much because um we got
cloning you know
as long as you're working with a that's
why i try to select early on in the
process so we don't have too many
females to have the clone from
but with males you kind of
it's a much tougher process you you know
i try to use other
other people to help me in that case
when it comes to males because meals you
don't want to even
sit them together you know even
separated from females even them
together they'll even
cross pollinate each other like not well
not you know but you don't want pollen
from one male being on another male that
you
you know because it happens so you want
to
actually separate them individually as
well
you know it gets kind of tricky so
clones are very important
okay that makes sense and now around
what day of flower do you typically
pollinate the females
ah well we try to pollinate exactly
around the time when we're seeing those
first
white pistols start to bunch up
you know we've seen those white pistols
because we know those are the pistols
that typically catch that pollen and uh
whether you uh if you have a male just
hanging in there you might want to you
know just shake a shake a little bit in
there and uh you know you always kind of
want to start your mail off earlier
you know you want to start the mail off
earlier and uh once because the female
is going to take you know especially
with a regular metal it's not much you
really have to do in that case unless
you you've stored polling you're
bringing it back
uh
to artificially inseminate
okay and then
what's the ideal flower time once
pollinated
for healthy seeds
that's a good question yes so
typically
seeded flowers take longer to develop
they usually take longer than an
unseated um
female and
in general seven weeks um
eight weeks
typically you'll you'll generally notice
it's when it comes to see you know
season general it's a really visual
thing
um
not really much you can sort of sort of
similar to trifolds it's really visual
thing
you know once you see the uh
the casing kind of cracked or
you know you kind of visually see the
seed it looks like it's developed based
on color and size that's pretty much all
you determine determining factors right
there i gotta imagine that genetics has
something to do with it as well right if
you have like a 12-week
flowering uh
flowering strain right
it will probably need to go longer than
the seven eight weeks that you mentioned
so but yeah i mean i think you bring up
a good point is like um because i've
technically i'm a breeder yeah i don't
call myself a breeder but
vader og called me a breeder because
i did one cross i made one cross it was
brisk grow g cross with pakistan valley
so technically i'm a breeder but
i know exactly what you mean when you
say that it's kind of like you can see
like the calyx is open with the seed
popping out and you can see like the
color of the seeds and so on and so
forth so you kind of get an idea then
it's visible so i totally understand
what you mean by that one so okay so i
know the answer to this next question
but i'm still going to ask it just
because there's an audience here that
probably doesn't know the answer some
people don't know the answer should
pollen from a female producing nanners
be used for breeding so the banana is
the
the male stamen that comes out it
depends on how the manners were created
so if we have purposely stressed the
female
um to create manners in a sense of like
light stress or heat stress
that's not and and then we we
bring that that
hermaphrodite methodic trait
uh out to the forefront then it was
dominant in the first place right so we
don't want to use that for breeding
stock
now in a sense where
manners were created
by the female herself
in that last ditch effort to you know
self-pollinate and preserve her own
genetics in that sense
she wasn't uh that that most likely that
homophobic trait wasn't dominant in her
she did it herself uh you know towards
the end thinking like oh you know this
is the end of my life cycle got apology
i haven't been pollinated got a pollen
so in that sense it's really good
because technically that's uh
self pollination which uh the offspring
uh of every self pollination are gonna
be 50 more stable
and um so that's why i say it gets
tricky when we use the term
hermaphrodite or hermit uh it's really
important in knowing how it was
developed and you know we've got two
different type of hermes technically we
have um ball sex
which um which typically come from us
reversing a female whether we're using
colloidal silver or uh jubilee acid or
whatever method you're using within
stopping the product the the production
of ethylene and and causing the female
to then create male parts so in that
case that's also not uh the
hermaphroditic trait most likely is not
dominant in that case uh it's most
likely recessive and um
you know depending on you know it could
be either way but
you know you would know if you know in
that case
because we wouldn't use it in the first
place but
in that case yeah it's most likely not
dominant it would be dominant in the
case where we
use stress to create manners yeah that's
that's not good we don't want to use
that as breeding stock okay we'll get
deeper into feminizing in a little bit
here i want to stick on
hermaphrodites for one a few more
questions here so
should pollen from
pollen sex coming from a hermaphrodite
so their mafia i'm talking about is say
the plant grows
flip it over to flower stretch on
pistols
shortly after you see pollen sacks there
should that be used for breeding
no so that is what we're talking about
in the case of a natural herb okay
that's that's more of a natural harm
with that well that trait is dominant in
that and so that that's gonna also pass
off that dominant trait to the offspring
uh and many of those uh offspring are
gonna have or just like you you said
going to flower and produce pollen sacks
and then you did mention through
instagram that it's important to
understand the hermaphroditic trait what
are some other things that we should
kind of know about that that you haven't
talked about yet
just
knowing and being able to answer ask the
qualifying questions to a breeder so um
in many cases uh you know
growers they get the
hermes you know they get the herme
hermaphroditic treat and they panic and
they say oh what you know what's going
on you know the breeders blaming you
they're blaming the lights they're
blaming the you know they're blaming the
humidity oh it's your environment the
you know the growers like no it's you
you got bad genetics you're not stable
so we have to find a medium and the
medium is education so if you know
what
to look for and you know what to expect
and you know why um this may have hurt
me in the first place then you you're in
a much better position you know as to
no one having to point the finger and
say could you say hey well maybe i i
might have let this female uh uh you
know sit for a little bit longer than i
normally should have and you know i can
tell that's probably why i may have six
or seven seeds in the bud here
but um or if you know you
you know you
you're dealing with unstable uh genetics
and that is a thing that is a real thing
and that's why when we're dealing with
uh f1s and
you know
really dealing with the uh
uh unstable even with f2s we're dealing
with a large variety
of genetics so you want to uh
really do your best to take your time
and be patient and stabilize your
your genetics as much as possible so
that uh it goes both ways and you gotta
meet in the middle of education so
okay that's good info
feminized seeds let's move on to them
they're becoming more and more popular
people love to be able to plant a seed
and just about always
guaran just about guaranteed that it's
going to be female 9 times out of 10 or
maybe 9.9 times out of 10.
how do you create feminized seeds
um through reversing the female and
stopping the production of ethylene
the ethylene uh
once you stop it or once you slow it
down the female starts to
create
pollen sex and male parts
and uh that's that's what at that point
we can typically pollinate a female and
create feminized seeds so all the
offspring
will be female offspring and there are
several different ways you can do that
right do you want to touch into the
different ways collateral silver
gibberellic acid can you talk to us
about those ones
yeah so uh
colloidal silver is probably the most
popular one um something you can
actually even make at home i mean i
don't make it myself
i do uh typically make my own
mixtures of colloidal silver uh
individual guys that i try different
things but typically you can go with uh
50 parts per million 40 parts per
million colloidal silver which is a
actually silver you know a silver and a
distilled water a little bit of
conductivity in there and then you got
colloidal silver um
that's pretty much my recommended method
uh that is probably the most popular
method in my opinion um so
it's pretty simple that that's that's
typically how most breeders will reverse
a female when would you apply that
uh during i will start around
two weeks three weeks vegetative stage
you want to start uh you want to start
as early as possible you want to hit the
corners you want to hit as much it
depends i mean how you're you know you
have different methods of reversing as
well some breeders might just want to
reverse one plant
only one branch rather i'm sorry one
branch as to where uh you know me
typically i'll reverse the entire plant
so i start really early i just start
spraying the entire plant but if um
you're more concerned about just one
branch then you might start
just focusing on that one branch
covering the rest of it um and uh being
able to spray that one branch in about
three weeks two to three weeks and uh
some people two to three four times a
day it's kind of up to you and it's
really strange specific uh you you know
that it's pretty strange specific some
some strings are really hardy with it
you don't like to be reversed so you may
have to apply a stronger solution more
more times per day uh and some are
really sensitive to it so
but that's typically the method we use
okay so you're doing you're spraying in
veg and then are you flipping the
flowering let them flower and still
continuing to spray or when you stop
that spray it depends on autoflower or
photo period so in a case of autoflower
um
you kind of know when she's reversed
when she starts growing those uh bowls
of pollen stacks you can kind of you can
stop with you know and with a um
a male or i'm sorry a photo period you
want to just um
start in about three
give it about three four weeks of uh
about a month of spray flip it to flower
and um continue for about another two
weeks
and you should see
you know you should see the results
probably within a week or two so
basically what will happen the plan will
start producing nanners right and then
you would harvest bananas or how does
that or it would self-pollinate and then
you would it would just grow seeds on
that particular plant
well
in the case of a reverse female she's
gonna grow actual power sets like a male
would okay so yeah we're actually
stopping the process of ethylene which
um
causes her to kind of turn into half men
so in that case it's not necessarily
nana's nanners are always gonna be
related to stress
whether it's bad stress that we caused
or whether it's stress that the female
caused on her own
but um
those um
those we don't want to collect for we
don't want to collect nanos for uh
pollen uh
to use as um
uh you know a gin you know we don't want
to breed those
we only want to breed male pollen sets
balls so we can kind of relate it to
that if it doesn't have bulb if it's not
balls then we don't want to use it to
breathe gotcha how about gibberellic
accent
acid yeah i don't i don't use it as much
i don't i don't
i mean i i use it a little bit in a
mixture that i've tried
that i'm working on but i don't i don't
i don't recommend it uh i would i only
recommend colloidal silver
because um that's that's what i've
always used and that's what i'm always
i'm just starting to try a new mixture
but uh
i mean either way i always go back to
just quarters so we try we experiment
with different things all the time but
you know that's how we learn
yep what's the best way to stress a
female without using chemicals
stress a female without using chemicals
if you want to um
stress test stress in order to kind of
get them to i guess self-pollinate and
create feminine seeds right okay so so a
female is going to self-pollinate our
own so for for anybody interested in um
wanting to um
getting to stabilize you know first-time
breeders i would recommend
self-pollination being that
rotalization is what what is the term
realization is where we typically will
let the
mm the female plant uh take a little bit
longer than we necessarily would and
we'll end up with some seeds out of that
so that's gonna be stable it's going to
be 50 percent more stable the offspring
than the mother plant was as well as um
you know it's a good way to kind of get
your feet wet
but we don't ever want to
stress a female out purposely to use her
power to create
because if we can stress a female out
and make her create manners then that
means the hermaphroditic trait is
dominant
in her genes so we don't want it she's
not breeding stock in that case we want
to put her to the side we don't want to
use that
okay yeah that's interesting that wasn't
as good so that was a listener uh
question it was through instagram
that's a really good question because it
does get really tricky and that's why i
always stress to um
get as much education as we can as far
as the hermaphroditic trait and
manners and pollen sex and the
difference between the two and how nanos
are created how pollen sex can be
created and um
how they relate to feminized seeds
because everyone loves feminized seeds
it's like i want feminize i want yeah
you got feminized i want feminize and
i'm like you know so you know sometimes
i'm a pain because i'm like hey hey
check this article out you know if you
don't know do you know about this and
why why do you really want feminized
seeds you know you know do you
understand that the risk and the risk in
feminist seeds because it is a little
bit of risk you know we're dealing with
hermaphroditic traits and so you want to
go in and when you
when you go to a breeder and you're
asking them for feminized seeds i also
want my my team to be able to ask those
follow-up questions well what generation
has your feminized seas been bred to how
long have you what are some of the
traits that you breathe for with within
your feminized seats what's the chances
that they might i might get manners uh
during early in the flower stage now you
asked a breeder these type of questions
and they're like hold up you know either
they're gonna be legitimate or they're
gonna back off and say you know what i
don't want your business get out of here
you know and um that's that's the kind
of we want that on both ends we want we
want to be educated
makes sense
yeah just one last thing on that last
question this particular person said
that the question was how do you stress
a female to her without using chemicals
he had mentioned he's been using light
to do that he would move it from 12 12
to 18 6 cur for a couple days and then
back to 12 12. so you're saying you
shouldn't do that because it's it's it's
stressing well you can do it so we do
that to to
just
to look for sexual stability so that's
the only time i use light or heat in
order to stress a female because i want
to see if she's sexually stable enough
now if i know if i put light on her and
she she's um she withstands it and she
doesn't hurt me then she's sexually
stable so she's good breeding stuff but
if i put light on her and heat or her
and she terms out then i'm you know i'm
cutting her she's no good she's bad
because if i use her to breed if i use
that pollen that was so easy to flip
like that into a herm then that pollen
is also going to be uh or the offspring
are also going to have that treat
dominant within their genes
gotcha and you mentioned heat can you
talk to us about a little bit more like
what how much heat like when do we apply
it so and so forth in order to stress it
that way yeah i mean uh 80 85 and up i
would say 89 90 any 90 and up is a good
indicator of uh heat stress
if you can go to 100 if you if you can
um but anything anything above 89 i
would say is
typically
90 depending on your environment
depending on the strain everything is
really strain related too
you know especially
we can get deep with that indica and
sativa you know related stuff and you
know so it's so related to that and how
how they handle heat and stresses
but um yeah i would say 90s
is a good uh
stressor
but yeah like light is definitely a good
stressor you can um you can apply light
and and definitely flip flip a female to
her but
once she does that we she's no good
good info okay good to know autoflower
seeds another popular thing out of are
more and more
yeah so how do you create those seeds um
same way
those are generally feminized seeds uh
most likely
they are regular as well but the
popularity uh popularity of feminized
seeds and autoflower kind of ran neck
and neck so
now we just got
feminized autoflower everywhere and
same process we reverse a female with
colloidal silver and uh use that pollen
collect that pollen it's a much more
intricate like i said it's a much more
uh difficult process uh
requires much more patience and much
more time consuming but um that's what
you want to use a you know definitely
have your tweezers handy and be able to
collect each individual pollen sac as
they uh as they develop and uh
collect as much pollen as possible to be
able to use and store if it's even
enough to store
but that's when it gets tricky
autoflowers there's more and more seed
banks that and breeders that are
releasing autoflowers and they don't and
actually end up being autoflowers so
stability comes into question you know
and
i heard you have to breed multiple
multiple levels down in order to
stabilize what exactly does it mean to
stabilize a variety
so to stabilize is simply just reducing
genetic variability just reducing
variability
ultimately we want to
achieve heterozygous
i'm sorry homozygous status we want to
retrieve homo homozygosity in a sense
where uh
that's just one phenotype
uh two two particular one particular
alleles or one particular version per
gene
and um that is homozygous status that's
what we want to achieve
through generations of selective
breeding
um we we
we dumb it down in just one
phenotype
and that's uh that's what it is to
stabilize the strain okay and then for
autoflowers in particular i heard you
need like i mentioned you go down
multiple generations is there
is it like four generations down or what
was the do you know
well either way um it's multiple
generations if you're stabilizing the
string you're never going to be able to
stabilize the string without going down
multiple
uh f2 f3 f4 f5 you'll get to you may get
in that's the thing too so stabilizing
is also
in the sense of the breeder uh what you
may consider stable may not be stable to
me
so you may think like hey i got my
greens you know i got my vigor i got my
big buds i'm stable you know but most
important is sexual stability we have to
selective
however long it takes to selective breed
and inbreed or
line breed or inbred line ibl in terms
of what we call ibf uh we have to go
down that line in ibl for several
generations until we remove
the hermaphroditic trait as well as try
to catch all of the things that we like
uh
trichome develop our production uh you
know
you may want purple buds as well but all
of those are secondary to sexual
stability and sexual stability takes
years that takes
four five six seven generations you can
pick up on the cool stuff along the way
but um until you run into that roadblock
of uh
after about the eighth eighth f eight uh
f7 f8 you'll run into a roadblock of our
being technically sterile where um you
you're like okay now
um i'm
sexually stable uh but no further i can
go that's when we back cross that's when
we go back to the parent
we bring out that stored pollen and uh
you know
then we can go back and re re-enter some
of those traits that we loved in the
beginning that's the correct way to do
it but yeah it's going to take years no
matter what if you want to have a good
line it's going to take years that makes
sense
good information there
okay so next one is another listener
question it has to do with the chart so
i'm going to put this chart on the
screen right now if you're watching on
youtube if you are on one of the podcast
platforms maybe you can explain it for
them this chart that i'm showing right
now you can see you know from the top p1
male p1 female and then it goes down you
get your f1s your f2s f3 is f4 z5z6 and
then actually it connects back
to a p1 new generation first could you
explain this chart for us in layman's
terms all right so so p1 is going to be
the parent uh the parent generation
that's what we starting off with uh
mother and father
so that is um
that is uh where we're basically
starting off the the generation the
outcross of the mother
and the father
that is the start of their generation
and that's um
that's those offspring are going to get
us into f1
all right those offspring are gonna are
gonna get us to f1 so the difference
between f1
and f2
is
f1 is the
start using the parents
f2 is the actual start of the line
of the inbred line using the offspring
so
in this case when you see f2 f2 f2
that's when we've opened up to
the most variety
the most
choices of of choosing our phenotypes
and our characteristics and our elios is
what we call
our versions of what we uh that's when
we start our selective breeding process
that f2 generation and then from there
is what you pretty much see
is the selective process of
him picking or
whoever it is picking picking certain
offspring there and um
you know breeding them together
and as we go down
we just run into different generations
uh
at attempts to stabilize the strain you
got a and these are all
um characteristics
that are being uh selectively bred for
uh we go down into f4 f4
so yeah he kind of stops in f6 and
that's typically uh at that point where
i would generally
back cross back to the parent and that's
where you see p1 all over again so it's
funny that's how we spoke just about
that right before so that was that's
cool
really cool chart that's that's genetic
mapping right there that's what we use
for uh you know
use to for reference gotcha gotcha so
definitely a good chart to have on hand
the question that had in regards to this
chart is
if two parents are bred together which
level of generational offspring will
show the strongest level of expressions
and terpenes
okay so that is a awesome question
but we're not necessarily going to so
what so
you'll get the most variety in the f2
generation so you'll probably find your
your best options and your strongest
terpenes and variety right there in the
f2 generation because you'll have more
to choose from okay that's where that's
what that's what we want to start our
hunt for that's what we want to start
looking into f2s a lot of people think
it's f1s that are you know i mean i
think that was the misinformation that
was passed around
yeah it shows you right here in the
chart you see the f1 is um only limited
amount of offspring compared to f2 we
have a wide variety we kind of open up
the gene pool at that point and we get
such a wide selection and that's where
we start the selective breeding process
to say hey because we're going to get
instability as well we get a wide
variety where we get instability so now
we have to focus on selective breeding
and making sure that we stabilize or
work towards stabilizing by picking the
right
picking the right uh
the right offspring
now what's your opinion on breeders
releasing f1s versus releasing f2s work
versus
you know is there something that they
should only release
stability purposes for example do you
feel like in your opinion that breeders
should only release stable genetics that
are you know f5s f6s or whatever
that's a good question but i can't say
that i would suggest people only because
we need genetics too we need we we need
to experience you know we need to
experience so um if everything was
stable it's like that would be a perfect
world right we don't want to live in a
perfect world we want to be able to um
experience these things and
apply some of the education that we that
we learned into right right there uh
hands-on and to be able to do that you
know i don't i don't have anything
against f1s but you gotta educate like
me personally i uh you know i educate my
people and say hey this you know this is
f1 typically i only offer it in a
certain way typically like an auction or
something like that but um
and when i do you know i make sure that
they understand
like hey you know and it's sort of like
when i deal with dogs you know if i sold
you a puppy i'm like man hey you gonna
send me pictures or you know you like
you know i'm calling every week they're
like all right man she's good you know
but that's kind of same way with the
genetics you know you want to it's like
your offspring or your children you know
you kind of want to follow up and make
sure that the new parents they're okay
they're well taken care of and that they
don't run into any issues so typically
when you do that it's not a problem
giving out f1s you just got to keep a
good relationship and customer service
is always first
okay that's a good answer talking about
dogs i want to touch on this real quick
it doesn't have to be a long answer but
can you tell us like some of the things
that are
the same for dog breeding and plant
breeding and then also some things that
are different for dog breeding versus
plant breeding
yeah for sure um
literally when it comes to the
the genetics of it everything is exactly
the same besides
being able to reverse that's literally
the only thing that's different um even
when we come down to clowning um you can
you can clone a puppy especially uh
nowadays that's why eventually we'll
we're evolving into the tissue culture
and
people clone puppies using titu culture
and you know
through our gardening we'll eventually
start to see people
preferably creating their clones through
tissue culture because you can store it
for much longer um it's that much
similar to where
there's only literally one
um difference as far as that that i can
tell reversing being able to reverse a
female i don't really know anything else
that's different
x y chromosomes everything's literally
the same um even some of the terminology
um that i learned
years ago through
you know it connected and i'm like wow
okay like hybrid vigor and it is a
different term in the dog world but it
means sort of the same thing um in the
plant world that's interesting yeah i
was just curious on that one so i have a
few more questions for you
what advice do you have for someone
who's a beginner breeder or someone who
is considering starting to
breed have fun man
have fun don't get discouraged
understanding is gonna take your time um
understand that uh
you definitely are gonna have to have a
passion for it uh you gotta have a love
for it because this is literally your
life's work so and when you look at it
as your life's work uh and you have fun
with it at the same time nothing else
really matters man uh you know do it for
fun do it for your own personal use for
your own medicine for your own
but your own love you know your love of
it you love it of gardening and you know
you'll be fine
i like that i think that's really good
advice for sure so wrapping things up
how can the listeners find you and what
do you got i'm coming in the future
well instagram uh the real zaza genetics
on instagram um follow us
you know you can follow me any of my
team shout out to my team it's so
important to me miss blunt love reviews
um carrot top crocs
no limit edibles
um
but yeah so we have a couple
collaborations going on with thc tone um
uh greenhouse healing we got some major
collaborations tino's genetics we got
some uh collaborations going on with
these guys coming out really soon and uh
other than that you can find us on
instagram
cool i'll link his instagram down in the
description section below so you can
click on that give him a follow zaza
thank you so much for coming on to the
podcast today
man i appreciate you definitely learned
quite a bit here and i thought it was
pretty pretty interesting here about the
crossover with the dog breeding as well
and we got deep into some things that i
wasn't expecting to get that deep into
so i'm really glad that i had you on the
podcast today dropping some knowledge so
really appreciate that if you guys
enjoyed this episode click that thumbs
up button as many thumbs up as possible
trying to get this uh trying to get the
youtube algorithm to show up and
people's suggested feeds and that helps
commenting helps sharing helps if you
for some reason are not subscribed to
the channel click that subscribe button
post these podcast episodes every single
week usually it's on saturdays sometimes
it's on sundays but every single weekend
we post a new podcast episode not just
on youtube but we're also on podcast
platforms apple podcasts spotify just
about anywhere podcast platforms are
available this podcast is available and
if you're on apple podcast in particular
please leave a reading and review we
passed 100 ratings reviews going for 200
if you're listening on there and you
want to take a minute to
leave a rating review i would greatly
appreciate it once again zaza thank you
so much for coming on just dropping some
serious knowledge bombs on this podcast
episode i think it was great hope you
enjoyed the rest of your day yes sir
truly humble man have a blessed day
brother
[Music]
you