welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey everybody for those of
you that don't know me my name is Chris
aka Mr Grow and you're tuned into the
garden Talk podcast this is episode
number 143 in this episode I interview
Zaza from Zaza genetics he was on the
podcast once before back in 2021 episode
number 31 where he talked about breeding
on an intermediate level this time
around we're going to continue the
conversation I have a whole bunch of
good breeding questions for him this
time around and somewhere submitted by
viewers like you he talks about Herms
back Crossing breeding autof flowers and
so much more if you want to see short
clips of these podcast episodes search
Garden talk clips on YouTube I also have
a channel where I show the plants that I
grow both of those channels will be
linked down in the YouTube description
section below one of my goals for this
podcast is to bring free information
about gardening to the General Public
now that being said I'd like to thank
the sponsors of today's episode who
helped make that goal possible thanks to
AC Infinity for sponsoring this episode
check out their all-in-one pH pen which
measures pH EC TDS and temperature the
sensor probe is replaceable and it comes
with stor solution and calibration
Solutions click the link in the
description section below so you can
learn more about their all-in-one pH pen
and the discount code Mr Grow 15 works
on both Amazon and their website AC
infinity.com stash blend stash blend
consists of several ingredients in one
so you no longer have to buy individual
bottles it includes corn steep liquor
seaweed extract humic acid beneficial
bacteria silica and micro risal fungi it
can be used in addition to your
synthetic base nutrients or be used in
living soil systems simply mix it into
water and water your plants with it you
can get it at stash blend.com Link in
the description section below and use
discount code the stash and we're back
and I'm joined with Zaza from Zaza
genetics how you doing today what's up
brother good to see you man it's been a
minute thanks for coming back onto the
podcast this is your second time on here
first time was on episode 31 September
12th 2021 so several years ago and that
one has over 52,000 views on YouTube
alone and I think it's got uh I don't
know another 10,000 Plus on audio
platforms so it did really really well
we talked about intermediate plant
breeding we're going to continue that
conversation today although I mentioned
intermediate there are going to be some
beginner things in here as well I'm sure
we'll touch upon so don't want to scare
away any of the beginners you know
you'll definitely be able to um grasp
onto some things on here that we talk
about today but first can you introduce
yourself for those folks that didn't
catch the first episode we did together
absolutely my name is Salam Salam Sims
uh better known as Zaza owner of Zaza
genetics uh I've been a breeder here uh
for many years um started out with
animals many many years ago um and
eventually transitioned into PL so
um uh New Jersey is where I'm from and
um I'm so happy to be here once again
awesome short and sweet and I highly
recommend after this episode you guys
seek out the first episode I'll
definitely have that Linked In the
description lots of good information on
that one and yeah let's continue on the
conversation here I want to start with
inex traits so first of all you hear the
word hermaphrodite a lot or Herm and
somebody in the comment section said
that's an offensive word is that
actually offensive should it just be
interex trait should we are we changing
things or or what um hermaphroditism is
is a scientific term so um you know and
when we when we think in terms of the
vocabulary and language is super
important especially being able to tie
those uh those certain words to other
words words and definitions and actually
being able to get that hands-on
experience so you want to practice with
um the actual scientific word as close
as possible so I recommend
Hite definitely no need to change it
okay and then I want to get a little bit
deeper on you know what a hermaphrodite
is so there are a couple different ones
right there's a female plant that shows
pollen sax and then there's a female
plant that shows nanners two different
ones can you explain the differences
between the two
absolutely uh so a natural Herm which
which is genetically coded um it's it's
there in a natural state um it it is in
the gene pool it can't be uh removed the
code per se cannot be removed it can be
um bred to a recessive state where where
it doesn't expose itself uh through
through selective breeding but a natural
Herm uh shows its characteristics by the
actual sack that we're familiar with the
ball sack um it it the pollen sack
stores and collects pollen and then its
objective is to once it's full open up
and release pollen to pollinate any
female uh you know within 3 mile radius
or whatever it may be uh so ultimately
it has a certain look the the balls
which are separate from the female parts
you you won't see them together you'll
see female parts in one place and balls
on another and um the the have the
agenda to basically pollinate a female
using that pollen sack um inside of that
pollen sack are staming um Stam which we
know as nanners so basically nanners on
on the other hermaphrodite uh which we
we tend to refer to as uh stress induced
a stress induced hermaphrodite will show
naners or or Expos naners and typically
its agenda is much different because
it's hidden it doesn't necess
necessarily want to be out and about and
show everybody what what it has going on
right like like the the male pollen sack
wants to just open up right there out
and about for you to see uh this is more
of hidden um because the agenda uh and
the reason why she's pollinating herself
using these
staming is because she feels stressed
enough to feel like she needs to
reproduce and possibly preserve her
genetics in case of an emergency
situation basically okay and you
actually have a video on your YouTube
channel the title is why your plants
should never Herm can you answer that
question here for us uh because it's a
sign of weakness um it's it's what we
know as an undesirable trait uh and any
any undesirable traits should be removed
to selective breeding uh by the breeder
uh you don't ever want to uh release a
product or or put a product out um and
and it shows any undesirable traits
similar to um the dog world if you're
buying or selling a puppy you don't you
don't want to have an aggressive litter
of puppies and you just you know selling
them that's that's a super undesirable
trait and that needs to be removed
before any you know anybody else can can
be in contact with it so same thing with
Herms so a breeder are they able to
quote breed out the hermaphrodite trait
or is it just go from a dominant to a
recessive and it will stay as a
recessive and there's no way of actually
breeding it out getting it out of there
completely that's a that's a really good
question so um it that is the case for
the natural Herm where like I said
genetically it's still going to maintain
um its cating within the gene pool but
you can breed it to recessive where it
doesn't expose itself nanners on on the
other hand they will be able to be made
recessive because it's due to weakness
it's due to um and and and it's that
that that that's more so closely related
to Darwin's theory of evolution in in
natural selection when we think in terms
of Only the Strong Survive um all
weakness can be removed um and it's not
coated it's a it's a what we know is an
inheritable treat uh weakness or Stam or
nanners inheritable treat so it could be
removed completely but one of the things
to kind of keep in mind is like when the
plant gets all the way towards Harvest
right and you push it even further it
could show nanners would you consider
still consider those weakness or like
all plants are going to pop out nanners
at the very very end if you push it too
far right well that's still that same
mechanism of stress that wants to you
know saying hey man I'm way past Harvest
time I haven't been pollinated I don't
like this something needs to happen now
um and that's still a sign of weakness
it's still a sign of stress
um a plant will um probably we could
it's safe to say that most plants will
exhibit nanners if you put it past a
certain um but some to the point where
you could actually identify them and see
a whole bunch some where it might just
be one nanner throughout the whole plant
because it's that strong enough to
resist um based on you constantly
selecting for Only the strongest stress
testing is very important so that's this
all directly related to stress testing
and only Strong Survive got it and I
think we're actually going to be getting
into stress test on a separate podcast
episode we invited Zaza onto the from
the stash podcast and we have a Hot
Topic I don't know if we revealed that
Hot Topic to you yet or not but it's
going to be something along lines of
grower error or breeder error and I
think there's a fine line there because
sure plants should never Herm if it does
Herm it eventually falls on the Breeders
for not doing that stress test as they
should before releasing it to the public
but what if it's a grower error such as
they're just blasting with too too much
light like too closely they just they're
they're doing something wrong within the
grow too high of temps or whatever
they're they're stressing out Beyond
naturally stressing it out so we we'll
hold off on uh any comments on that
that's gonna be that's a whole episode
itself and I think it's gonna be a
really really good one so I was ready to
go right at it man I'm I'm glad you
stopped me man tune that was a good one
tune in to from the stash podcast that's
with me Rob from CLTV and pigeons 420
that's going to be a whole separate
conversation which I'm looking forward
to last question I'll have on Herms
before we move on this is a question
from an Instagram user so I actually
reached out posted an Instagram story
and asked folks if they had questions
for breeders this was a question they
want to know why are there so many
intersex plants popping up more often
across multiple
breeders because there's multiple
breeders popping up they they they don't
a lot of a lot of guys who consider
themselves or call themselves breeders
don't really grasp the concept of what a
breeder truly is so um they think it's
just as simple as one plus one and it
makes two and you sell two and and you
know when you got a ton of people doing
that you're going to end up with a ton
of undesirable traits throughout the all
of these different genan pools man man
that's tough yeah it me makes sense it
seems like everybody's a breeder
nowadays you know what I mean and
there's a lot of inexperienced people
and they think that just need to take
pollen from one plant and put it onto a
female plant and then everything's gravy
from there which is far far from the
truth so yeah that's it could be very
reason why a lot of these breeders are
having intersex plants because they're
just not doing it properly let's get
into another one of your video topics I
was looking through your channel by the
way Zaza had a a great Channel That's
dedicated to breeding and uh I'll have
them linked down in the description
section below so you can easily get to
his channel but lots of great great
breeding topics one of them is
stabilization versus uniformity so can
you talk to us about that yeah um
stabilization a term that we hear often
um stabilize the or this this this
strain is stable or you know um and I
think it's thrown around very Loosely um
when we think in terms of uh
stabilization stabilization happens per
Gene uh per Gene and trait so uh you
stabilize and isolate genes and traits
uh one at a time sometimes it's many
times it's give give and take so you
have to uh be be very mindful about how
you select but uh ultimately um that is
overall understanding so if someone's
like yeah my strain is stable and
they're really just referring to
uniformity of cross uniformity is going
to be complete homozygosity we spoke
about homozygosity and heterozygosity in
the the first episode we did originally
and that was kind of the introduction
for a lot of people to to those terms
homozygosity being complete uniformity
uh versus when you hear someone say hey
uh that strain is stable uh what they're
really referring to would would have to
be that that that strain is completely
uniform meaning that each Al for every
Gene is identical for Mom and Dad so Mom
and Dad each offer you two versions of
uh a trait or or you know and those
versions can either be different or they
can be identical uh if if Dad is
offering you a copy of blue eyes and a
copy of brown eyes that would be
considered heterozygous if Mom is
offering you a copy of blue eyes and
then another copy blue eyes that's
that's homo homozygous completely uh and
and if we have every Gene in every Alo
within the population identical on both
sides mom and dad that is complete
uniformity but you can just imagine the
time I mean even to get to the beginning
you you you're going to need a start
point of about 20 years of selective
breeding just to be okay now we can work
towards uniformity
so a trait can be stabilized within a
year two sometimes you know depends on
what your objective is talking about tra
I think a lot of people know what
they're looking for when it comes to
females whether it fenal hunting and
then using that for breeding or what
there's so many different things you can
look at and we that's I think another
thing we talked about in the first
episode but when it comes to males I
think there's a lot of confusion you
know what traits should people be
looking for when they're cultivating
males and and selecting for breeding can
you give us some examples of things you
can look for in regards to traits for
male plants AB absolutely um first one
um that is most important is Vigor
athleticism uh you want uh the most
vigorous of the um population uh to
start with and um then you can look at
flower um production and tpine
production you can do stem and leaf rubs
in order to see if you can get a little
tpine profile uh but ultimately um I
think Khalifa uh genetics my brother
Aladdin over at CA genetics said it best
uh he said it's it's really similar to
you um trying to determine a daughter's
uh BR size by looking at her dad so it's
like I I don't know you know cuz we we
we only want the female right but um how
how do we uh ultimately make a good
decision on a true breeder male when it
comes to um selecting and ultimately I
would suggest taking you I did a video
on on picking Ms too um so so for more
in-depth explanation you can go back and
look there but uh yeah
tpen um Vigor and athleticism number one
that I mean as long as you got that you
can you can W that's the most important
how about the cluster of flowers on a
male plant is that yeah absolutely okay
so that is something that's valuable to
look at and also structure as well is
okay yeah all good all good um things to
look for after you find the most
vigorous plant so um and then you can
ultimately make the best decision of
what you think the female may come out
to be but clone clone clone that's going
to be your ultimate key to going back in
time you know whatever clone and
document clone and document I clone
everything and I document everything
this clone I like it because it is I
like it because of is I'm keeping it for
this reason um and then we do that in
stages so this is early veg this is
Middle veg this is late veg this is
early flower mid so uh you know we can
keep track of everything and go back and
when our with our selections how about
the stem rub technique for male plants I
know there's some people against it they
just don't believe in it they think that
the smell is going to be different when
they do a St R in veg versus flour for
example do you feel the stem rub
technique is something that know first
of all do you do it and when do you do
it if you do it I do it um a little bit
towards like mid veg um I want to
see not necessarily because that is true
um typically that Aroma profile does
change once you're inlow the actual buds
it's not going to be the same as the
greenery that you're rubbing on but it's
the the kick like if I get a nice boom
you know hit me in the face and I'm like
like okay that's it you know that's
that's nice so so you're not necessarily
looking for identical Aroma but more so
um effect of how how you know like oh
that's potent you know that's you know
that's that's fire you know whatever um
that's that's kind of what you're
looking for not necessarily the exact
Aroma okay and then color another thing
that a lot of people go after I've got
male plants that had some purpling on
the pollen sacks which I thought was
pretty cool and I always thought to
myself I'm like hm if I select this over
some pollen sacks that are you know all
green for example does that give me a
better chance to have some colors that
come out in The Offspring oh yeah sure
absolutely and um when we think in terms
of back Crossing there so many different
and that's that's that's back Crossing
is is is a topic within itself I think
uh it's is another uh tool that's very
Loosely um thrown around uh and and
people have uh little to no knowledge
when it comes to back Crossing they
don't understand it you know most most
people's understanding is you take a
mother to the to The Offspring and
that's a single back cross that's a
simple single back cross and it has its
own purposes but then you have a a a
trans a more more uh more in depth back
cross uh where it's it's recurrent where
um you're continuously back Crossing
through five or six times in order to
receive a certain percentage of the
recurrent parent you have a recurrent
parent and a donor parent uh the donor
parent is there strictly to offer you a
a particular Gene um so that Gene is
going to be fixed into your Elite line
versus you could and this is what having
knowledge uh gives you confidence
because um in many cases you would take
your Elite line whatever it is you're
working let's say um it is missing one
particular thing like uh resistance but
other than that it's topnotch perfect so
you would be willing to take the most uh
crappiest of plant as long as it has the
proper Gene for mole resistance and do
an outcross once you make that initial
outcross you end up
50/50 that 50/50 you're going to select
based on that Gene that you that you
you're tracking down um which is mole
resistance you go back to the recurrent
parent on a back cross that then makes a
new population of
2575 which means 75% identical to the
recurring parent 25% to what we know as
the donor parent because we only need
one thing from it and as long as we
continue the further we continue to back
cross to the recurring parent we push
out the genes for the donor parent until
eventually end up with about 98.6% at
about six six times if I'm my math might
be wrong but about 98 88.6% um identical
to the recurring parent but um only
maintaining one thing which we selected
for which is that mole resistance so
everything else the the the not Frosty
the run all of that stuff is pushed
out and that is a uh uh that's a real
back cross a single back cross is a
little bit different it's going to give
you the ability to take uh a gene from
one parent and uh introduce it into the
background of another parent but it's
50/50 still so you still have 50% of the
genes from the donor and 50% so it's
going to be a a much faster um result
but a lot of work that needs to be done
behind it versus a recurrent back cross
which you can instead of just
introducing a new Gene you're fixing the
Gene and then we have third the third
back cross which I'll mention real quick
and I I won't keep rambling on but um
it's it's a test trait uh a test cross
I'm sorry and and a test cross is
basically um using a back cross as a way
to identify a certain Gene that may be
dominant and determine um whether that
Gene is dominant or recessive and end up
with the correct ratio uh by by back
Crossing so if we end up with a one to
one then we know it's a heterozygous
dominant if we end up with a completely
um all the same dominant of all The
Offspring we know it's homozygous
dominant and that's a test cross which
is also a back cross as well so do your
research on back crosses everybody is
not that simple it's it took my guys who
have a really strong I mean three years
in just the basics it took them about
four days they really grasp the concept
of back Crossing it's funny you got into
back Crossing that was literally my next
question for you perfect and you didn't
even get a list of the questions this
time around man you're freestyling it
here so that's funny that you got into
back crosses what's a reverse back cross
hm a reverse back cross that I'm not
necessarily familiar with okay cuz I'm
growing a gelato
41 reverse back cross and I wasn't
entirely sure what that was it sounds
like it may be a certain mechanism that
was done before the backat cross like uh
It reversed the plant and then backat
cross something like that and it just
add in compound but that's technically
not a type of backat cross we have a
test cross a recurrent backat cross and
then a single backat cross those are the
actual back crosses those three um but
um yeah it was labeled as
RBX RBX okay there you go reverse yeah
so a rever probably reversal uh done
first and then a back cross so that's
that's fine as well I mean it's just a
compound of mechanics and and that's the
thing I think people get really confused
as well is that all of these different
mechanics s1's back crosses or reverse
back crosses uh whatever it may be are
just tools within your toolbox um
F1 F2 F3 every every time you make a
move you end up with a new population
that population has a a new purpose for
your ultimate goal later down the line
so when you see people selling uh this
back Cross or that back cross ask some
educated questions uh what type of back
cross was that what was the purpose of
that back cross um from my understanding
a donor parent and a recurring parent
are used to introduce a particular trait
which trait were you using and why are
you selling it that's what I need to
know I need to know why you selling it
because it's super important for you and
your ultimate goal right you you your
ultimate goal maybe 20 30 years from now
is to be complete uniform right complete
uniformity you want to make the perfect
strain for people um and uh you you can
only do that by preserving all of your
popular I have Dead Ops OG um I'll give
you an example you Mr Grow was the only
person that ever ever touch a S1 um many
years ago three I think CU and that was
only because I knew I know you didn't
like uh you know you would go test your
stuff to make sure it was female so so I
went into one of my population I said
all right well I'm you know give him the
s1's um you know that way he don't have
to test them but probably got about 20
something 20 I don't know for sure about
20 over 20 different populations Just
For Dead Ops so different F series
different back crosses different and and
they all have to be identified they all
have to be documented and we all have to
uh keep track of them so that 10 years
from now I don't know what I have to go
back and use oh man boom I got this from
10 years ago this back cross that I did
to do this oh it's perfect this exactly
what I need and I'm still working dead
offs 10 15 years from now but now I'm
even closer to uniformity um so so it's
just those tools so don't sell your
tools don't sell your F1 F2 F you know
F1 is is is where you are going to be
introduced to um hybrid Vigor and
heterosis your your potential of and
that's a phenomenon so it's not
guaranteed it's one in a million it's a
it's a treasure uh you're looking for a
treasure chest so you can't you don't
want to sell that you have to dig and
search and hunt for that um hybrid Vigor
and if you can find it um man you got
you got you got you got a gem and then
F2 is different because now that's the
only way you're going to expose your
recessive traits that's my only way
that's my only chance the only shot I
got to expose the recessive traits I can
go back in time I can go back in
ancestry I can see great great great
great Granddad I can see how he used to
walk I can see all of these different uh
just by going back in history um and and
we do that so um all of those different
mechanisms the s1's the f1s all those
different things they just different
Tools in your toolbox don't sell them um
each one has its own purpose uh document
that purpose make it important to you
and once it becomes important to you you
would never want to sell it you have to
understand your objective and what you
which direction you want to go you want
to go left you want to go right you want
to go up you want to go down you need to
know that before you move so um when you
have purpose like that you ain't going
to sell you know I can't sell that I can
give maybe a couple to you you know but
I can't sell so whenever you see me
selling these packs of Dead Ops it's um
stuff that I called out of my population
so and this is the thing once you get
your Gene pull to a certain strength
that's why stress testing is the most
important strength stress and
athleticism is most important vigor once
you get it to a certain point
um then you can be confident enough to
know that you won't have any
undesirables that other people will
complain about so I can give you my
throwaways but you won't complain about
them because they're not going to harm
on you they're not going to be stunted
they're still going to be good they
still you know it's it's just that I
don't for whatever reason I'm selecting
toward a certain direction and I have a
certain OB Ive and I need to accomplish
that by removing anything that's not
within
that uh which doesn't you know fit
within that criteria I want to bring it
back to back cross for a minute here
inbreeding so when you're working an
inbred line from my understanding you
get to a point where you should actually
back cross now I don't know if it's like
an F5 or an F6 but if you go if you
continue to go down the line apparently
you can come across like weird
characteristics or something like that
so in order to avoid that you would back
cross can you talk to us a little bit
about that yeah so um when you
continuously go through the
mandelian road to inheritance through um
F1 F2 F3 F4 uh eventually you do lose
that what's most important to us Vigor
this is why I always stress Vigor Vigor
Vigor because it's the alpha to your
Omega so when you continuously going
down down down you're losing all of this
vigor athleticism um and the only way to
uh uh repair that is to back cross now a
single back cross um can be somewhat
effective um it can be somewhat
effective it it just depends on how much
inbreeding depression you have so if you
have a severe case of inbreeding
depression then a single back cross
won't suffice you'll need to
continuously um but still it's going to
be a recurrent back cross it's it's
going to be a different type of back
cross and then um you know but just uh
for for a smaller uh less uh dramatic
case of inbreeding depression then um
you could just do a single go back to um
the the the right parent Vigor super
important that's why you always start
with Vigor you can you have the freedom
to move about when you know you have a
strong Foundation good another question
from a person on IG the question is does
a photo period need to be brought to F4
and and or stabilize before breeding it
into an Autoflower so that's a good
question so um we'll stay we'll stay and
I'll be able to answer that by staying
on the topic of back Crossing um if I
was to create a Autoflower I would do it
through a series of recurrent back
crosses um that is the method I would do
my first initial outcross with a photo
period and an Autoflower boom end up
with 50/50 half half then I would select
the best autoflow from the new
population to back cross to the photo
period eventually like I said we we'll
end up if we go to five six seven times
back cross we'll end up with
98.9% identical to our photo period but
now the autoflow
gene should now be dominant the problem
is is that the autoflow gene itself is
much more complex than just the photo
period Gene right the the autof
Gene is and I don't want to get too uh
complicated but we we understand melion
inheritance to be F1 F2 F3 Mandel uh uh
Gregor Gregor Mandel and his F1 F2 F3 F4
right that was 1865 it was a long time
ago from what he taught us others have
then started to you know understand
different methods and ways so um there's
non mellian um inheritances as well so
when we think in terms of
Mandel's uh laws we think of dominant
and recessive when we think in terms of
non-mendelian
laws or inheritances we we're thinking
about incomplete dominance uh
overdominance pseudo dominance thing um
and Autoflower is an example of
incomplete dominance meaning that two
genes are expressing themselves at the
same time in um a way where neither one
is fully committing so it's
incomplete versus uh a photo period
which is a complete completely dominant
trait uh within within a photo period um
and that's just the complexity of the
autof flower so to answer your question
um a backat cross would be the way to um
if you wanted to Cross or create your
own autl a recurrent backat cross and
then once you get to about 90 something
per you need to do a series of selfs uh
probably you'll need to do some self
pollinations uh you'll need to do some
Mandel stuff you'll need to do some
whatever uh whatever mechanics that you
have in your toolbox you'll need to be
ready to pull them out so that you can
make your auto flow but it won't be just
as simple as uh Crossing this with this
it's it's going to be pretty but it's
going to start with a nice series of
recurrent back crosses okay now could
you hear me out could you take a photo
period in an autoflow
do that cross right and then The
Offspring is going to be
50/50 take an auto flow from there
confirmed a reverse it and then use that
pollen to like an S1 create an S1 then
would you have feminized autof flowers
at that point the whole offspring of
that or or no well well no it'll it'll
still give you a it'll just be a
percentage so every Everything is a
percentage and every you you think about
it like every cross starts half and half
and then every time you do another
successive cross you knock off another
half so now it becomes 75 25 um and when
we think in terms of
selfing it's not half and half it's more
so like 100 because um it's breeding to
itself so it's doubling up on whatever
genes that uh the the mother is already
expressing so whatever genes um that
shows dominant or recessive will be
double uh what it was in her population
once she selfs herself so it's a little
bit much more faster um when you
thinking in terms of selfing and and you
do get a higher percentage I think it's
uh 75 to 25 off the bat if I'm not
mistaken so I'm I'm terrible at math but
I'm I think that's about
it you touched upon testing a little bit
but I want to get a little bit deeper
into Tes testing so somebody creates
seeds and before relasing to the public
they do they should do a series of tests
some people just release to the public
don't do any testing which could be very
harmful right because you're you're
pushing things into the population that
it could be you know high percentag of
her aphrodites for example maybe the
intersect traits ends up being dominant
and then you've you've released it to
the public and all these people are
getting hermaphrodites happens with the
donuts triploid right it doesn't seem
like they tested did a very good job
testing that because a large percentage
I want to say 70 plus perc and we don't
know for sure ended up showing interex
traits I'm trying to avoid using the
word heraf I don't know why he said it
wasn't offensive but but anyways what is
an ethical way to go about having
gentics tested before releasing to the
public first of all understanding um the
mechanics of knowing what you're doing
like no one I think if people knew what
they were doing then they would
understand what was required they would
be more excited about um because they
they will have the ability to create and
really actually create and and have
influence on um moving and fixing traits
and and you're like oh man I didn't know
I could do this so I think once you get
to that point you you take it seriously
versus people just taking one you know
and then selling it and then selling it
and you know they never even see
anything they don't know what's going on
they don't they don't know what they're
giving away they don't know anything but
if you actually get here to a point of
understanding and learning and get a
strong foundation in the basics you do
become the Creator and you do take pride
in that and and you look at things
differently no right would you recommend
like I don't it's so subjective right
it's like if you're breeding you got a
batch of seeds do you then give it out
to say disperse 100 seeds to people or
500 seeds to different people around the
world and then have them grow it out and
then kind of give you feedback is there
like is is that a good number or should
it be kind of a percentage of the total
number of seeds you get or or what no no
you should never um that's a red flag
too that's an indication to me that the
breeder is not um doesn't really know
what's going on because um as a breeder
I need to build up my eye for selection
like it's not easy and I I constantly
say this all the time um 10 plants okay
cool 20 plants cool but you hear people
all the time man I'm that's not a phen
hunter phen hunter is thousand plants
you have no idea what it would take to
look at a th plants with all these
subtle differences so you really have to
train your eye and start with the 4 10
20 and gradually you start to notice uh
changes within how you see things and um
that that right there is is is what's
required uh starting small and then
building your eye up so that you can
select but not just trying to throw out
a million plants it's not going to to be
conducive to it's not it's going to be
counterproductive H okay interesting how
about testing for pathogens H vroid big
concern these days and that can be
within the seeds right if you had a
plant that hot plate and viroid and you
use that for breeding it could
potentially end up in the seeds and you
could potentially disperse some do you
recommend folks get seeds test or or
plants tested prior to to dispersing
seeds and we're just talking hot plade
and viroid but there are other pathogen
out there as well right so what's your
take on that absolutely especially if
you are operating these large facilities
and you are doing this um for profit if
you're doing this to sell seeds and make
money and you you know you you you have
a big facility and all these things you
need to take every precaution um and you
should uh go over and Beyond uh when it
comes to stress testing performance
testing um just like um any responsible
breeder would um I'm I don't want to
release I don't want anybody to see
anything that is created by me but
that's less desirable like I don't I
don't even even with the notation of
saying hey um this is just testers man
don't worry about it if it if it looks
messed up don't even worry about it it's
just no that's not so so nothing leaves
my house messed up it's it's already
built up strong confid is ready to leave
the door when you step out the door do
you walk out you you know like messed up
pants halfway up you know dirty you
having [__] no you you dress up you
brush your teeth you you get yourself
together and then you leave same thing
these seeds these these genetics don't
leave your house unless they are are
ready to to dress and impress so you
don't have like a team of testers that
will test your stuff prior to releasing
you just do everything 100% your eyes
your testing doesn't leave your house
unless you're confident with everything
that you are looking for you want it to
be yeah never um uh never never uh
believed in in testing um and I come
from the dog world too so um there is no
no testing um if if I'm looking for
undesirable trait that undesirable trait
could be aggression I can't just hey man
hold this dog and let me know if it's
aggressive one day the dog pulls you out
the bed you know you like so um
ultimately yes it's the Breeders it's
the breeder's responsibility for sure
okay
let's flip it up I want to talk about
your Creations here what are some of the
most exciting or unique strains that
you've developed and what makes them
Stand Out gotta um so dud Ops OG is
probably uh my my favorite it's a a
hybrid Cross of two land races from two
different areas and um two sort of
heirlooms uh and uh that is skunk number
one in UK cheese and on the other end
there the Kash plant and um the uh
ubekistan land race and um one from a
cold region one from a warmer region but
um land race just the land race
influence and being able to uh see the
history of of of just the Bal how rich
the history is with um being able to um
use that and know that it is responsible
for creating some of the uh most
valuable hashes around the world you
know for thousands of years right from
that region in Northern Afghanistan and
um learning The Villages and learning
the different um and then uckan the
colder region over there so I I love the
L race uh influences um I uh for me it's
just another baby of mine um it's
nowhere near complete uh it's probably
like 5 years in the in the workings
right now I've been working on it for
about 5 years so um and we constantly
just prioritize and um figure what is uh
important at the moment um whether it's
the customer is requiring something you
know it's always a way you can make it
better so um Dead Ops OG I would have to
say I don't have too many strings I have
a bondas glue which is a autoflow um
that's usually always on the back burner
uh rarely do I ever work two strings at
once um it's it's not that easy um it
requires tons and tons of population
like I said so if I'm over here messing
around with 13 14 different batches of
dead opsy I don't want to be doing
nothing else with no other seeds so um
you know rarely do I ever work two
strains at once so um I am working on
the autoflow though um it's a Siberian
ruderalis times de Ops photo period so
we're doing the uh autoflow from scratch
using the recurrent backat Crossing
method and um probably some further
self-pollination to lock it in um
probably take about three four years
three three years I'm assuming hopefully
awesome yeah I had the opportunity to
grow Dead Ops I think I had the f2s I
grew out like two of the f2s and then F4
good got some okay good you had some
okay I thought I gave you S1 was they
feminized I don't think so I don't all
right cool maybe that wasn't you
sorry like d could no wonder you was
looking at me like that like I
was I wasn't sure but yeah I'm pretty
sure it was an F2 you probably remember
better than I do I'm tell you I'm burnt
man I'm burnt but it got some really
good results off the f2s and I know that
kind of opens up the the the
characteristics a lot on that generation
and the f4s it was cool to see like what
really more of what the breeder is
looking for more what you're looking for
man that
fuel oh I loved it so um actually I'm
running out of stock right now I got
probably got to plant another one and
it's something I would definitely want
to keep on hand at all times to consume
you know I really like it a thank you
man that's a vote of confidence for sure
and um I'm I'm sure I still got those
same populations hanging around like I
got s1's I got f1s I got you know all
Dead Ops so um and they all have a
different purpose man they all have a
they're all just a tool in the toolbx
and when you realize that that all of
these tools and you realize how
important they are and you realize your
end goal and you you start to see
certain strategies that you want to imp
imp then everything becomes important
you can't sell that you're like man what
if that guy opens up a pack and gets
what you know gets what I'm looking for
that helps me finish what I'm doing over
here so it's all about U being objective
and and knowing that uh it takes time
man it takes time it's not going to be
overnight you know we don't we don't do
this to to make money off of it um you
do this and you find other ways to make
money around it but no breeder um is
really into this uh for for money um I
mean you might see some dog guys that
that have successfully been able to uh
capitalize off of new newly created
breeds but um when it comes to guys who
really
understand uh the objective of a breeder
um money becomes like the last you know
we don't we don't make money man we we
preserve genetics we save endanger
species man we we we we actually have a
hand in doing something great and being
a part of History uh and saying man that
pterodactyl over there man he was about
to die but I was able to help bring
those eggs back and you know whatever
whatever it may be uh a dog a puppy a
cat a rabbit um if it's endangered um
and you know you have the ability to
help recreate and and and replenish um
and and not only that but um enhance so
make it better um so that other people
can have too that's that's what this is
really all about and if you walk into
any of your local uh uh uh shops
whatever you want to call them um none
of them have land races um they don't
have that available for you because
they're endangered species as well so
just think about that the next time you
are looking for your next uh two mother
and father to breed together um think
about some of these poly hybrids who are
responsible for
um almost eradicating our history when
it comes to that and lamb races and wild
types are the history we can't just do
away with them we can't just be excited
uh off the off the lack of knowledge and
just be excited off the names and the
pictures and and you know um the hype uh
and and then forget all about our
responsibility and our history so we got
to keep it around it's clear that you
take an ethical approach when it comes
to breeding and that's definitely one
thing I admire from you and uh you know
behind the scenes I we've had
conversations through DMs and stuff
where I'm firing off breeding questions
on you and you know you're somewhat of a
mentor towards me and really chill o OG
the only cross I've ever done is uh
somewhat influenced by you and your
direction so I appreciate you amazing
job too doing an amazing job man just
keep going keep going take your time man
don't don't you know realize what it is
you want to do you want to go left you
want to go right it's your choice you
know and then you take your time and
make that choice but uh you know it'll
it'll it'll be something of a household
name 15 years from now if you stick to
it 20 years from there make it so that
people remember it for for for good
reasons and um for the guys that are
just Chuck Chuck Chuck Chuck Chuck Chuck
Chuck you'll never have a household name
nobody will ever remember it man because
you don't even remember it
like who was that can remember the
strain he created like last week because
he creat so many but uh you know chilato
G has the ability to to to be a legacy
within our industry man so just keep
chugging at it will do man will do so
talking about the future what trends or
Innovations in breeding are you most
excited about and how do you see the
future of breeding
evolving that's a good question man I I
I I hold this game to such a high
pedestal um so a lot of times my my
peers unless it's like my team or you
know they don't really grasp the concept
they don't see that far and um and I
always tell people if you need to see
where I'm looking at if you need to view
things from My Lens then you have to
step outside of our community our
community is not okay it's not a place
where they support education and they're
going into the colleges hey learn this
learn this about your community they're
not doing that so but when it comes to
um breeding dogs breeding daisies
breeding corn breeding strawberries they
are doing that that's where you learn
the mechanics you need to step outside
and I think that's that's the largest
mistake of many of these um so-called
breeders is that they start here as
Growers and they think it's just that
simple and then boom they don't realize
that that education is not going to come
from here because it's not here it
breeding well breeding this plant is not
a thing it's not a it's not a thing it's
it's not even a real thing yet so we are
so far ahead of time when it comes to
our industry step outside of our
industry learn the real mechanics and
then prepare yourself for the future but
uh to answer your question and not
ramble on um I hold it to a high
pedestal you can't take a pig to a pig
competition without it being registered
I need to know his registration number I
need to know the name the father the
mother the seven generation pedigree if
it's going to be in this competition
that's a pig I mean uh and and it should
be the same for for what we do uh
everything and all of these cups man I'm
not even you can't even walk up and say
you want to be inside this cup unless
you have a a 20 generation pedigree
going back to lambri that can show every
mother father and ancestor in the
lineage and if it's gaps in that
ancestry then we can't consider you a
pure bread we can't consider you a
thorough bread we can't consider you a
pure species we just can't because
there's no proof of registration here I
can't bring my dog matter how cool my
dog looks it does back flips it can swim
across the ocean it can do all these
tricks but when I bring it to the dog
show if it's not registered uh with a
three generation pedigree on file then
like n it can look like all the other
Jack Russell teras but um it could
outperform them all as well but they
won't even take you serious if you don't
have the proper registration paperwork
and I think um that's where I want to
see this place that's where it will be
it's going to take legalization
federally one day and it's going to take
some genius coming out of high school or
college to code some program that's
identical to what they did over there as
seed finder um if you ever uh you know
familiar with that then they they have a
database with the lineage and that is
super important um from dogs to horses
to pigs to corn to everything that we
take seriously the fruits and vegetables
you eat in the supermarket all require
that lineage that documentation they all
require it or it can't be bred within
what we got going it's a mut you
consider it a mut seeing that the how
the industry is right now there are so
many pollen Chuckers and people just
creating random crosses and pushing it's
hard for me to even visualize that far
ahead and you're probably right it's
just me being a general consumer small
home grower it's like man imagine if we
could get to that level to where like in
order to enter a cup you have to show
documentation like we're not there yet
but that would be cool if it w right
like that's that has to be the next
level right because it's the norm with
everything else yeah everything that's
legal is the norm uh it nothing nothing
we we eat nothing we consume nothing um
none of the Liv stock animals pets none
of those are considered pure unless it's
registered with because that
registration and those that pedigree um
it gives you the ability
to what we say uh what we consider
confirmation it gives you the ability to
conform to to to the breed standard so
um if you have all your registration you
have all your paperwork you have then I
can take you seriously and look at your
dog and then check them out and say the
ears okay the oh the tail has a little
Crook in it nope not breed standard it's
not right so even if we pass that
registration it's still that just gets
you to the initial test of saying let's
now let's look at your dog and see if
it's a real pure dog uh it has all these
champions in his bloodline and in his
pedigree let's see if it's a champion as
well um or if it's just uh a dog with
paperwork that we don't consider um
breed standard so same thing with with
you know and and this it is hard to see
because one thing we have to understand
too um our industry and the guys that
run our community that have been running
the community big companies um pollen
Chuckers whatever they have us
desensitized to weak genetics um they
have us desensitized to hermaphrodites
they have the especially the new
consumer um and I try to come I I try to
combat that by saying no um there's
nothing you can do to my plants to make
him hermaphrodite nothing you can do to
make him expose weakness that's that's
my responsibility um I'm I'm willing to
say that and and and announce that uh so
that other people can take it serious
enough so that they can um be able to do
the same thing we'll keep fighting that
good fight man and hopefully we see some
positive change here in the Future Let's
uh let's wrap things up can you tell the
listeners how they can find you and what
you have upcoming in the future yes sir
uh Zaza genetics.com the website we'll
do a uh Mr Grow at 50% off coupon code
as well
too and uh so all you guys want to check
something out just use coupon code Mr
girl uh Instagram Zaza genetics.
official catch me in the Discord man I'm
in the Discord every night um 9 p.m. we
used to do classes every night but the
the team my current team has uh they
kind of they kind of smarty art man they
like they bore me now because they think
they know everything they super smart I
need some new fresh Minds man to kick it
with me in Discord let me let me rock
with you man let's let's let's uh let's
let's build you up man let's get you
prepared and let's drop you off in the
community to to combat this uh this this
breeding uh epidemic that we have known
as pollen chuck all right we're going to
change the game way or the other through
qce that's quality community and
education we bring quality to the
community only through education so hit
me up man I'm always in the Discord Man
9 9 900 P p.m Eastern um always willing
to chop it up with you great stuff man
I'll definitely have a link to Zaza's
YouTube channel down in the YouTube too
I always forget it's a new
YouTube it's fairly new so um thank you
thank you we we definitely need some
subscribers for sure yeah so click the
link in the description section below to
get to his channel uh lots of good
information there lots of topics that
aren't really covered anywhere else
there's not a lot of breeders that are
making YouTube content knowledgeable
breeders I should say making YouTube
content so uh it's the channel I tune
into every now and then and whenever a
new video pops up I'm usually clicking
on it and I'm just like learning every
single thing I'm I'm learning from so
keep doing what you're doing man I
appreciate you shout out to the patreon
folks that keep this podcast going
patreon.com grow 100% of what is pledge
through there go right back into the
podcast you keep this podcast going so
thank you to the patreon supporters and
we've got a question for the audience
here what should we ask them favorite
cultivar what do you think that's a good
one yeah a good one what's your favorite
cultivar let us know because I'm always
looking for new genetics and I'd love to
see what you guys have grown out
recently that is your favorite yeah let
us know maybe I'll uh grow something out
in the future all right Zaza well thank
you so much for coming on the podcast
once again hope you enjoy the rest of
your night much love brother peace peace
out everyone catch you in the next
episode