welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned in
to the Garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 158 in this episode I
interview Ames High he has been guarding
for 20 years and grows a variety of
plants he's big into stress testing
plants which is what we get into in
today's episode everything from the
types of precision stress benefits how
he goes about the different stress
techniques and more if you want to see
short clips of these podcast episodes
search Garden talk clips on YouTube I
also have a gardening Channel where I
show the plants that I grow both of
those channels will be linked down in
the YouTube description section below
one of my goals for this podcast is to
bring free information about gardening
to the general public that being said i'
like to thank the sponsors of today's
episode who helped make that goal
possible thanks to a Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
humidifiers which can help increase the
humidity in your grow space their
humidifiers have 10 different levels and
Smart Control features such as VPD and
humidity programming so you can get
precise humidity control click the link
in the description section below so you
can learn more about the humidifiers and
the discount code Mr grow5 works on both
Amazon and their website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend is a 215 plant
additive that can used with synthetic
bottle Nutri nutrients or in living soil
systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seaweed
extract humic acid beneficial bacteria
silica and micro risal fungi check it
out at stash blend.com Link in the
description section below and use the
discount code the stash Mars Hydro check
out their ad light blue supplemental
lights coming soon there are two models
for blue each coming with two LED bars
ADL light blue 30 and ADL light blue 55
these lights Target 440 NM the blue 30
has a coverage area of 3 ft x 2T while
the blue 55 has a coverage area of 4 ft
x 2 ft also the Christmas sale is going
on right now through January 5th go to
the website at mars-hydro
docomo and you can use discount code Mr
Grow it to save even more and we are
back and I'm joined with Ames High
cannabis how you doing today pretty good
bro thanks for having me yeah thanks for
coming on to the podcast we actually met
in person at MJ biscon 2024 man what an
event it was really really cool to meet
you and uh yeah it was a good vibe dude
thanks man it was super crazy to see all
you guys huge honor huge honor so we
talked about having you come on the
podcast and I asked you you know what do
you want to talk about and things that
you kind of specialize in you said a
bunch of different things but you really
like to focus on hunting and also
Precision stress that really perked up
my a little bit because Precision stress
I don't think it's talked about enough
things that you can do to stress out the
plant that actually results in better
things happening to the plant whether it
be stressing to cause more tricomes
making it more hardier plant more
vigorous more resistance right to pest
pathogens things like that so we're
going to get into all of that in this
episode kind of what you do to stress
out your plants and kind of what you're
looking for in the plants but first can
we do an introduction tell us a little
bit about yourself and how you got to
into gardening I'm Amai cannabis I've
been gardening for almost 20 years now
uh been a huge passion started off as a
hobby and then saw the science behind
everything and it really just became
like a big drive and like a dream
honestly never thought i' would as far
as I have been um it's kind of
crazy um but let's talk about some
plants man let's talk about this how I
grow yeah absolutely yeah man tell us
what is your grow style overall grow
style are you indoor outdoor are you
soil Coco Hydro what's your style so I
really started Outdoors um did not do
good too good with that there's a lot of
mold a lot of issues just did not did
not like fighting Mother Nature so kind
of moved indoors really really use a lot
of Coco use
promix um what was the other
brand honestly no it's mainly promix
yeah promix for the the win uh use the
straight cocoa and then I'll add in my
own um peite and a couple other things
to to make it nice and Airy um that is
like when I preferably grow but like
when it comes to like the science side
of things I grow in all kinds of
different medium because especially like
when I'm chasing certain stress factors
you know it's easier to hone in on like
maybe like a pure cocoa like when I'm
doing droughts I use a lot of pure Coco
go do you use mostly organic inputs or
are you doing synthetic or are you Sanic
so I jump around a lot with that one too
sorry I'm all over the place I got mad a
DHD got to keep moving you know got to
do a lot of things so my main go-to is
really like a Sanic approach I really
have been dabbling in more Organics as
of recently um I kind of shied away from
it in the beginning because I I wasn't
really too keen on the whole like time
release you got to like get this this
mix in right so everything breaks down
at a certain time and I wasn't too fond
of that and it really
like can't you can't play with it you
know what I mean and so like if you're
trying to like do a lot of salts and
like Chase like something that is really
like resisted against your salts you
can't do that in Organics you know so
yeah um I hope yeah I hope that answers
your question yeah kind of getting the
Best of Both Worlds there they're using
both organic and synthetic inputs mhm
nice so getting into stress what are the
benefits to doing these Precision stress
techniques the overall idea is you want
to find the most resilient plant the
most resilient plant to all of these
types of traits oh well not traits um
sorry all of these types of
stresses so you can find um more
leniency in the garden right so you you
don't have to be as worried about your
plant like getting some type of
uh we'll just use a a like tobacco
Mosaic or something you know more
resilience to something like that you
don't have to worry about it spreading
this much but it doesn't mean that you
shouldn't still practice like
cleanliness in the garden you know
always pract practice that never use the
same scissors on on two different plants
you know um just because it is resilient
doesn't mean you should just give up but
the whole idea is for it to go into
bigger commercial facilities and then
find more
um more benefits and more more less
problems right cuzz like if you do if
you do um your wind training your wind
training will get a bigger structure
right you you can get more yield from it
depending on if you can find that more
resilient plant that can handle that you
can get more structure better like
stronger branches
you're the watering the watering is a
good one you're watering um the root
system is really what's happening for
the droughts your root system is
creating a bunch of we'll say Pockets
inside of the roots right that are
really holding that water so when there
is no water they can red drink that up
it's a a biochemical pathway Pathways or
something like that I can never remember
the actual term
sorry uh but there's a bunch of benefits
to these it's not just cuz I like
cousing my plant's a bunch of stress you
know um the idea is when you breed with
them right after you after you're
induced these stresses and you keep
breeding through the line right and you
keep going on and you find these traits
and you hunt out the the more most
resilient ones you can turn around breed
that into like say a plant that you R
like and you can try to pull that from
that plant into a plant that you want
right there's little a little bit more
breeding into it than is what I'm saying
but that's the whole idea in like a
general term got it and I know some
folks will do Precision stress
techniques in order to get more
secondary metabolites to be formed you
know a lot of these stress factors
actually lead to more triome production
and uh you know we're growing these
medicinal plants that's what a lot of
people are really aiming for is the
triome production right so fig got in
that one yeah yeah there are a couple
different stress factors biotic and
abiotic can you break down the
differences so biotic will mainly be
your outside sources really like your
natural natural stuff like your plant
will have like fungi it'll have viruses
it'll have um bugs you know all that
kind of issues that that's more of your
biotic your abiotic will be your heat
from your light your your droughts your
salt
um there's a couple other ones sorry
pruning transplanting goes in there wind
stress is all in there mechanical
stresses was called yeah I think you
said salinity as well the salt stress
flooding drought light yeah all that
good stuff mhm let's go into detail on
both of them maybe we'll start off with
abiotic which is uh I think more
commonly used as stress temperature
maybe start there do you stress the
plants at all using temp temperature if
so how do you stress it and what do you
look for in the plant heat is one that I
I definitely do use because a lot of
people um will have that issue you'll
see a lot of tip Burns and a lot of
growths like really doesn't matter where
you go you can see at home grows you can
see them at commercial grow you're going
to see tip Burns all the time so I've
been chasing heat as one of them yeah uh
crank up the light mainly I just crank
up the light to everything she gots I'll
add the wind try to keep keep the the
try to keep it in there relatively nice
but to where it's still nice and hot
right and is what I do is I'll start
breeding I'll I I'll throw a plant I
throw a couple plants in there right let
them do their thing breed them out let a
first cycle come through I already know
all the first Cy going to be eh breed
them again same once right and I'm not
reversing any of these I'm trying to
keep them as open as possible try to
keep that
genetic pull right we'll say is open as
possible so I will get a bunch of uh uh
diversity right cuz if say I start with
something that has already been um we'll
say locked in okay like we'll say use a
medical plant as examples so like you'll
find f6s and stuff like that if you use
something like that you're not going to
find a lot of that diversity because
they've already locked it into certain
types of traits that they you know
they've wanted but I want other traits
right so we start from the top get them
going keep them cycling and as you're
cycling you'll start finding certain
plants will produce traits that are more
resilient to these like factors so like
the heat an example it won't you won't
see a bunch of tip burn it'll start
being it'll Thrive it'll be nice flushed
green other plants alongside of it
you'll see that they're burning so you
know that you're still doing the right
type of factors right you're still
inducing that stress to the point where
other plants are naturally like H I
can't do this
you're trying to find that guy you know
yeah so that's more or less for the heat
one um I do wind as well because I I
liked seeing it um there's a lot of a
lot of benefits from the wind one cuz if
you if you add a bunch of air like for
example the way I do it is I grab a box
fan and it sounds crazy but I'll just
take a box fan crank it on as high as I
possibly can and I literally will sit it
right in front of the plants just
blasting it blasting it to the point
where the plants are just all sorts of
Droopy right and I keep doing that um to
help build up uh what is it why do I
forget the name of
it the cell the cell your wall right cuz
it essentially it's like breaking your
arm right if you break a bone right or
fra fracture it to be precise sorry um
if you fracture a
bone it'll heal over time and it'll
it'll heal stronger right A lot of these
branches and stuff with most common
plants that we we all love right they're
the same way if you add in fractures
micr fractures along these branches they
will come back heal stronger and it
helps promote more flow through those
you know those branches so you get more
energy going to the the output of your
you know flow I do a lot of biotic
stressing uh I actually introduce a lot
of uh PM into the grow cuz I'm trying to
find PM resilience so I can breath that
into other plants um that PM resilience
is the same way as that you would you
would do for your light you if you want
to start like trying to find something
that's resilient to that kind of trait
you do the same thing that you know pre
lights that one has a lot of ups and
downs because you know once you start
bringing in like molds and like bugs and
all kinds of other stuff it's really
hard to like start keeping track of it
making sure it's contained in one area
you start having to do a lot of other
like uh uh I PMs and stuff like that
really trying to mitigate any type of
spread so you don't have this test
happening over here and then you spread
that mold into like something over here
that you didn't want the mold you know
so yeah so for the PM that's pretty
interesting that you actually introduce
it in to stress the plan out and just
see if it's resistant or not how do you
can you break that down in details like
what do you actually do to that do you
just increase the humidity and kind of
cause pm to occur in one area and then
bring that plant into another area to
see if it infects another plant or like
what's the detail on that one so I work
at a commercial facility as well um and
I I talk to a lot of other commercial
facilities just trying to help out give
them you know some insight that I
have um a lot of people that I know in
the commercial facilities are dealing
with certain like uh PM big issue big
issue in commercial sites and then uh
fungus Nets fungus Nets and those both
of those so if I still some of the oil
for the fungus knats because that's
another one that I do sorry we'll get to
that later um uh steal some of the soil
from them they just the top 2 in because
that's where the the fungus NS like
laying all their eggs that's where all
all like a good amount of that activity
happens for them top 2 in of that and
then still a branch that is infected
with PM something that is like heavy
infected take that bring them both back
in take your take your bugs put put them
in your bug site take that branch and
literally just put it into the room add
it into the room add a lot of wind in
there and let let it do a natural thing
that that PM will naturally spread right
um because I'm trying to stay as natural
as possible I don't want to literally
just go in there and rub the PM plant on
them because that that's not natural you
know I want it to spread naturally so it
tries to fight it naturally and in
nature it would be the plant next to it
or itself I guess but the plant next to
it catches PM it's not likely to catch
it as well because it's going to spread
over right that's my whole idea with it
got it yeah you're actually the first
person I've ever heard of uh doing it
that way it's pretty interesting it
reminds me of I had a buddy in
Massachusetts who grew out chillo G
along with a whole bunch of other plants
and he always struggles with high
humidity and unfortunately a lot of his
plants got powdery mildew but the chill
out OG which was in the same room didn't
get it he's like dude I need to show you
this look this is resistant to powdery
Milo I'm like dude that's awesome I'm
glad you got at least one plant that
wasn't infected and I happy that it was
actually the strain that I bred so
appreciate you sharing that with me but
yeah it is something that I know that
quite a few Growers do look for
resistance to pathogens such as a
powdery Milo so I'm glad you brought
that up I do want to back up to
temperature to kind of get a little bit
more into detail on that one talking
about heat blasting with heat what
temperature what what heat do you go up
to in order to see if the plan is
stressed or not uh around the 96 to 98
Zone cuz I don't want to push too past
too far past 98 because most things will
burn at 98 regardless you know what I
mean so like that's really that that
maximum threshold and I only keep it
there for
like maybe 5 minutes tops and then I'll
bring it back down and that's just to
like how do I explain this if you look
out in nature right nature is always
different the light the pen like the
light penetration that we're getting
from the Sun is always different no
matter what throughout the day it will
change right and so at certain peaks in
the day there might be times that that
there's super hot heat just beaming down
on you you know what I mean and so I'm
trying to like like keep it as natural
as
possible um without going too far
because I know when like like I said if
you if you push the limits too far
that's just unnatural and what once you
start pushing the unnatural limits
what's the point of what you're doing
because if if I sit here and try to like
find a plant that goes up to 10 and
something you know so some crazy
number okay that's cool and all but in
my eyes it's kind of a waste of time
because whoever is going to really like
you know going to find that you're not
going to find a single moment in time
that outside where your surface
temperature is going to be over like 120
degrees or something you know what I
mean it's crazy yeah I know one of the
things that folks look for when they're
doing heat stress is they look for
plants to flip over and show intersex
traits right for Maite plants they're
looking for the the uh plant to
potentially show nanners right and
breeders in particular they will just
scrap that plant they'll call it off and
they won't use it for future breeding
projects also looking for certain types
of fox tailing cuz there's certain
strains that after uh heat is induced
there's a lot of fox tailing that will
incur I'm trying to find the one that
won't you know what I mean because like
I like Fox tailing sometimes because it
looks cool but otherwise for your
overall like production as nah you know
what I mean I know there are mixed
opinions on Fox tailing some people hate
it some people feel like it leads to a
more AER structure some people like a
bag appeel others love it uh I know some
people who wash and they uh they said
they get a better result washing because
of uh more looser areer buds coming from
the fox tales and so yeah we got people
who love it people people who hate them
so I thought that was kind of funny yeah
no it's fun to fun to look at in my eyes
but otherwise besides that uh that's not
for me yeah me living in the desert I
encounter it quite a bit it's sometimes
tough specifically in the summertime it
always reaches
80° F and I'm lucky to keep it you know
under 82 degrees F sometimes it creeps
up a little bit more than that lately uh
you know in the new household here I
just moved in here I little bit better
of cooling situation so I am able to
control the temps but my last place man
it was touching 86 plus degrees and I'd
see a lot of fox tailing happening on on
some genetics because of that not all
genetics will fox tail but definitely a
good amount will
and uh yeah he definitely contri can
contribute to that also I know infrared
light excess infrared light I think uh
5% or more 7% or more can actually lead
to Fox hang as well the uh ES300 LED
grill light by Green Sunshine Company
you know rest in peace that uh company
no longer exists but that was a very
popular light and their first version
had a lot of ir in it and so a lot of
genetics were Fox selling because of it
and people were like what the heck's
going on so he revised he put out a V2
with actually less IR in it and that
actually helped to solve the problem
there so figur that was worthy of
mentioning okay so we talked about
temperature you kind of said a few
things for lighting but if we can get
deeper into that amount of light and
spectrum of light some people will just
blast it with excess light to try to
stress their plants other people will
give certain Spectrum in order to stress
the plant what do you typically do in
regards to light stress both I do a lot
of uh I switch between I have a bunch of
Lights I have the what are they called
the bulb lights HPS and MH HS HPS sorry
there's too many too many abbreviations
man the HPS I have a th000 watt of that
I run that in a 4x4 okay that's a lot
Max that out that's a lot right um whole
lot of heat coming off that thing so I'm
constantly running an AC bi it to try to
keep them temperatures I 100% understand
what you mean I live a high desert so in
the in summertime I feel you on that
like when I don't want it too high it
starts reaching up in them higher levels
so I'm like okay I guess we're doing a
higher test today you know um I do
switch it between that and led I have an
LED
650 um Mars
Hydro Crank that and I swap them in
between the Mars Hydro I bring closer to
the plant um because I don't know I I I
heard it I heard it back in the day that
it's just it's a good thing to do like
you could run them closer and like some
I don't know I just stick to what I know
yeah but I keep switching in between
that because of that same that same
sentence that I was saying earlier like
go outside you never get the same type
of light penetration I'll say you know
so switching between LED and hid so you
got the different spectrums there now do
you have a par meter are you measuring
the amount of light that is being
emitted onto the plant and then are you
increasing that to see if it stresses
his plan or not I had a par meter broke
it um so I started using the app on the
the what is it the photon Photon app I
think with piece of you know with the
piece of paper and
everything I don't trust that so I'm
currently trying to get a new one but
yeah I usually do test it um
what is
it the or is it a bricks me bricks meter
I think it's a bricks meter bricks
refractometer yeah I think that's what I
think that's what I had I can't sorry
I'm bad with
names yeah but I do I do I have a big
sheet if I should have brought that I
should have brought that I'm sorry dang
always messing up on something I usually
every show every it doesn't matter what
I'm doing at least one one thing I
forget like to bring um I was going to
bring the sheet so I can tell you
literally like I have a chart that I
write down everything so like this month
I'm running this and this were the
results you know always taking notes
because if I don't take notes then how
am I going to know you know and I re
well it's about about a month I recently
switched to stop taking notes and
actually recording so I can see the
entire plant and I can like literally
have the evidence of what's Happening go
through um time date it and then that's
technically my notes now it can be so
helpful to take videos and pictures and
have those as your notes or
documentation right so I have been
filming my plants for nine years now and
I can look back on my hard drive and see
the plants that I grew back in
2015 and uh it's it's interesting to see
the different growth and like remind
myself of what that look like how it
grew so on and so forth one mistake I
made is actually organizing that footage
instead of doing like
2015 Vlog one Vlog two Vlog three and
just dumping footage in there of all
different plants I had to go back and
organize into different folders by
strain really or cultivar and so that
way I can look and see okay when I grew
up the gelato 41 backcross let me look
into that folder and I can see
everything about that versus trying to
dig back at a a certain year at a
certain Vlog number so I learned my
lesson on that one but I totally get
what you mean by filming or taking
pictures of it how that can be helpful I
just kept losing all my notes I I had uh
used to have a what are those
uh you know the books that don't have
the the wire going around it um and
they're usually like black and white
yeah those like perfect binding ones or
I think they're perfect binding that
yeah binder yeah you know which one I'm
talking about had a stack like this of
all my notes that I've been taking I
lost half that stack and and multiple
moves and so dang I got to start
recording stuff cuz I just put it on a
cloud and then I always have access to
it you know what I mean there you go yep
that would work great okay let's get
into drought stress next so do you do
any type of drought stress if so how do
you do it and what do you look for in
the plant so with my drought stressing I
do pure cocoa right and then I will
water it one day let it let it run stop
about the third day the third day is
when it's really going to need your
water you're going to start seeing that
that droop down if you gave it that full
saturation on that third day on what is
it I'm running in three gallons right on
that third day you should start seeing
your your plant drooping down a little
bit that's when you know that that's
that's about how how long you can go so
I will stretch it farther and farther
and then start seeing what plants are re
reacting the most and at that time
that's that's the ones that I'll start
breeding with the ones that are more
resilient to that I'll take that plant
cuz I want that and I'll breed it and
I'll try to find that trait in that
plant again the next cycle and you just
keep doing that um the idea is just to
find something that I could potentially
water it this one day and then go with
maybe like a 4 to 5 day stretch without
watering and it still be just barely at
that droopy Point that's like the real
Pinnacle of what I'm looking for because
with that then it gives people the time
period of say you have to go to work and
you can't really go into your garden
it's okay tomorrow just catch back up
onto it you know what I mean and so it
gives you plant a little bit more time
and more leniency for neglect you know
what I mean cuz
the whole reason honestly like I got
into growing was I watched my mom um
when I was a little kid I she used to
love gardening uh she just used to be
mad all the time because she did not
have a green thumb and bless her soul
she tried so much but she would forget
to water it and that was the main issue
for her you know what I mean and so I
always wanted to find a plant that was
like super resilient to it like Cactus
you know a cactus cactus cactus what is
it there's a couple of them but like
Cactus is the most notorious those live
out in the desert go Forever Without
Water you know what I mean still do
perfectly fine have juices running in
them like come on be ideal pretty
straightforward there now on the flip
side flooding is the type of St really
overwatering a lot of people call it
instead adding so much water in there
that the medium's oversaturated do you
do any of that stress if so how do you
do it and what do you look for in the
plant actually I do that one with my bug
stress um with the fungus Nets
because when you get all that excess Mo
like moisture in your medium that's
really what you're those
little sorry I'm almost SAR that's what
those little bugs like I I do not like
those
things pain and pain to keep it like
contained they always
spread but
um I actually do that and it really just
goes back in that same basis like you
can find that there's more plants that
when you are watering them uh more
excessively you'll start getting a bunch
of like toxicities and stuff depending
on what your feed is and stuff like that
you'll start running into all kinds of
issues like the plant will start turning
all kinds of colors right um that
actually leads me into like the cold cuz
I do cold as well the cold temps I try
to water with colder water sometimes as
well to see you know which one's going
to react the most I'm trying to avoid
the purpling in our medical plants I
know it does it in um the Tomato
sometimes does the
purpling uh there's a couple other
plants that it does it as well but yeah
let's move on to Salt stress do you do
this at all if so how do you do it and
what do you look for in the plant so I
don't have a a meter technically to read
my salts I really just run at a higher
uh PPM PPM or EC is a lot of people
measure by those yeah yeah yeah I just
run at a a lot higher one for that that
test so like I'll push into the threes
and fours instead of like the average
1.6 you know I'll try to get as high as
high high as I can I'll stack um do a
lot of bottom feeding for that that type
of test to try to pull up the salts so
they stay in there and Stack Up um
that's mainly how I do that as the
plant's growing are you looking for like
EX ively dark leaves curling nitrogen
toxicity for example and then are you
like culling off the plants that aren't
able to handle that high you see or what
100% yeah there's uh you you literally
what you said literally all of those the
um the nitrogen is M mainly the one that
I'm looking for though because I find
that the nitrogen issue is the biggest
issue in my eyes that a lot of like home
Growers deal with because they don't
pull off the nitrogen when they're
supposed to and so they start like
having excesses of it and that's where
the issues start lying in and really
that's that is literally what I am
searching for when it comes to that that
that stress test got it and I know
running higher EC can actually stunt the
growth as well so the plant might look
nice and green and healthy but like just
stays it just it stays squat right it
stays the growth has been stunted so I
assume that's another thing you look for
MH yep they just do not move
yeah literally
been two weeks nothing and just sits
there looking healthy yeah yeah no no
that one gets me sometimes too because
like I have so much going on and I'll go
in there check on it all right so this
test is working this T come back okay
it's working and then come back again
wait a second okay wait a second you you
guys aren't moving yeah no like yeah
that gives me all the time reminds me of
my hydroponic grow the first one I've
ever done I've grown in soil for 14
years and then just tried hydro and uh
one thing I've learned is from somebody
else they had mentioned that sure you
can try to run a higher AC you're not
really going to see nutrient burn as you
would in soil like it's not as apparent
but you'll see more of a slowed growth
and that's exactly what when I was
reaching these higher ECS touching
upward of 2.0 EC some people say that's
excessive for running in Hydro deep
water culture to be more specific people
said you can get away with the smaller
one and any higher than that you could
actually see stunting so I actually
backed off and went down in order to try
to prevent that stunt of growth from
happening that's literally why I'm
trying to get into soil and stuff
because it does give you that quicker
reading on that um I shout out to bobiz
because bobiz is really they hooked me
up with a starter kit of uh they have
some liquid organic nutrients so I'm
going to try that see see what that's
all about and run a couple test see what
happens super excited awesome let's move
on to Mechanical stress so things that
fall under this would be like pruning
for example training transplanting do
you do any of those things yes I do I do
the pruning so normally I will prune it
at your sixth Sho right um most plants
once it gets like it's sixth Sho you
prune it there so it gets a little bit
more growth and then you naturally prune
it depending on what type of plants that
it is um it's depending on really how
much you want to prune it but in the
medical
plant six sh six shoot 2 weeks um after
that and then 2 weeks before you flip it
into flower that is really the standard
that I've ran by um but when it comes to
the test I'll I will prune that I'll
prune it every week just to see and and
really what I'm looking for is it to
Herm out when I push it into flour
because that's like a common one
um lack of lack of development like
you'll get a lot of like like tops and
stuff but like they'll just be little
guys little guys and um that's something
that
I again if I see those two things I'll
kill them off um I'm really looking for
something I can prune as often as uh
there's a bush that's like a Bonsai I
can't remember what it's
called a awesome little Bush you have to
you have to prune that thing all the
time though because it it it grows crazy
um and I'm looking for something like
that because if we can get that type of
vigor right in the plant and still be
able to prune it top it get it like just
just constantly chopping at it right and
the idea is we get it like that we get
massive yields off that one plant
because we can train it easily easily
right B bend your branches down and like
your wise so they come down get plenty
of crazy tops everywhere and it'll just
be amazing but a lot of plants can't
handle that kind of training yeah I've
seen some people do some crazy things
when it comes to training and Topping
stripping down all the leaves to
foliation and really just having it
mostly naked take almost every single
leaf off of the plant B flipping flower
and let that thing grow back and
sometimes you don't even think that the
plant is going to
survive and uh you see their progress
weeks later and the plant grows just
fine so it's pretty interesting to see
kind of how much you can actually take
off the plant and how it rebounds and is
able to grow and get to harvest from it
yeah like uh the what is it the swazi
swas
methoding however however it's
pronounced right um I like that but I
like pushing it a little bit farther
like really pushing it to its real Max
just to see how far I can go to push
that specific genetic or or or strain
right um to it Max that's the best way I
can put it because like you were saying
like even at even at commercial
facilities that is one of the funnest
things to do teaching people how to like
cut back a mom or something like that
sometimes just go over there grab the
plant little bundle it up and then take
go down half of it take some loppers and
chop half of it off it looks disgusting
the plant looks like it's going to die
everybody freaks out the first time see
it and like just give it a little bit
comes back even bigger like I love that
but if we can start that at a at a a
younger like age in the plants
development and it not
have detrimental like problems then
that's what I'm really looking for like
that would be key that's a keeper for
you huh mhm 100% I want to go back to
another thing that you spoke about which
is the fungus Nets how you take taken
soil from a commercial facility that had
fungus gats introducing into your garden
what exactly you trying to get out of
doing that all right I'm going try to
get into the science of this you bear
with
me all right so plants when they are
being attacked by certain types of pests
they uh what is it e ethyl methylene I
can never remember remember the actual
chemical that it starts to produce the
plant will produce this this chemical
right to try to F fight them off and in
doing so it usually results in like a
higher tarpine yield and so something
something along that sort right
depending on what type of insects that
you are really introducing is really
depending on what type of um we'll say
pheromone pathogen I I I can't never
remember the name of it sorry I gets me
every time but the idea is you build
that resistance and that resistance is
shown in your
uction um in certain types of oil
development I hope I'm saying that right
and you can correct me if I'm wrong
could be wrong with that one that one is
really just a newer test that I've been
I've been playing with you know what I
mean yeah I've never heard of the the
people introducing fungus nets for a
stress now when you introduce them and
they're you know you got the population
going say you're done with the test how
do you get rid of the fungus nuts I like
a zerol um cuz it it really works as
like
a what is it called a
sterilizer it is zerol 2.0 is what I
really keep keep I keep a gallon of that
thing around um it's essentially like a
peroxide just a high concentrated
version of peroxide and you keep that
down throw all everything away you spray
everything down clean everything bleach
everything um the buckets clean those
out make sure that the soil that that
you are has been contaminated make sure
you bring that away from your home
facility wherever you're doing your test
do not do not let that stay sit around
because if it sits around and there's
still moisture in it then they just keep
breeding and it will spread and good
luck after that point you're a brave man
for introducing fungus knots
intentionally and doing the the uh
stress testing because me personally I
struggle with fungus Nets and I just
want them gone I but I understand what
you're uh what you're going for there
what are some challenges when it comes
to doing some of these Precision stress
techniques
well don't think that you're going to
have a good yield like your yield is a
big problem um spreading uh any type of
cont like contamination that's another
big problem yeah honestly those are like
the biggest ones those are like the
really biggest ones because you burn
through a lot of plans don't like doing
all of these tests and trying to get to
your end result you will will say like
this you do 10 right you're probably
going to keep one if you're lucky if
you're lucky off that run if you're
lucky off that run right because you
have to St stay with in in a regular um
a regular kind of idea um you have to
stay
with non feminized stuff
right because you want to keep that
diversity right so you're going to start
10 plants maybe one survives so that's
all 10 plants that you ran throughout
this entire test that you
probably might have thought that maybe
one was going to survive you might be
able to smoke so you know
no more often than not your killing
plants are you starting from seed and
only doing seeds or are you doing clones
as well seeds and clones a lot of seeds
and clones
um specifically like you start off from
your seed to keep that diversity and
then uh depending on what type of tests
you want to run you would cut the clone
from that and then cut your clone from
your mail as well so you can keep them
those type those specific genetic you
know pools we'll say genetic pools
together and then once you got your
clones you take your clones and put them
in different tests got it so I imagine
you are letting the pl grow up the from
seed cutting the Clones having the
Clones off to the side pushing some to
testing right Precision stress testing
keeping the ones that you've cloned you
have them kind of separate you're not t
stressing some and you're stressing the
others or what yep yep the if I if I
start one strain um 100% already know
from the beginning I'm going to test
this strain I know for a fact that I'm
not going to run this for any type of
medical use or anything this is just for
testing then I will grow that out to
about about yall like L as soon as I got
like four branches on that plant I will
cut off three of them and then I'll
leave that one branch um those three
other branches set one to the side the
other the other two right into testing
that main plant right into testing that
one I'll save um as the control cuz you
got I use that pruning the pruning meth
method for that first one the mom that
is that prune that is the one that I
will consistently go back and sit here
and chop away at um one of the plants
I'll push into the PM room the other
plant I'll push into um the bug room and
then I have the control room understood
that makes sense so the next question I
want to ask as we get towards the end
here what are the top three genetics
that you've grown as in like for the
resistant traits or just top three that
I personally enjoy top three in your
opinion what you enjoy kind of maybe
name off the The Strain and then uh kind
of what you like about it Afghan because
that is an um that's a really good
drought I've grow I've grown that a
couple times like the original Afghan
not like any of the crossed afghanis
like the original land race right um I
found that that one fights a lot of
droughts and that I think that goes back
to how it was
initially like bred out and found you
know like they used to grow it in big
fields and then they would flood the
they dig canals right along the the
sides of each each row and then they
just flood it and that's how they did it
um and that that ground would dry out
often and then they just come back flood
it again
um it builds so many tra it built so
many resistances like I think this is
really why we know it is what it is
today cuz like it works for a lot of
things um another one uh what is it blue
dreams honestly I like blue dreams um
not because it's res resiling to
anything it is a pain for a lot of
people to grow like it is not a beginner
strain um in my eyes
personally um I just like the way it
tastes it's a good one it's really good
and then for a third one I like Alaskan
Thunder [ __ ] that every like the the the
legendary how it's everybody's like no
it's not real it's not Alaskan you know
I'm looking for it I had it one time and
gold gold got me set classic yeah yeah
I'm a big lamb race guy nice yeah the
reason why I asked that question is cuz
we have a lot of people that are tuning
into this that are shopping for genetics
and they like to hear what other people
are growing and their experiences kind
of growing now what they like about
those particular genetics so I
appreciate you revealing that to us now
I'm sure we could go on and on but we're
going to wrap things up here can you
tell the listeners how they can find you
and what you have upcoming in the future
uh you can find me on YouTube Instagram
really honestly any platform I'm
everywhere I stay I try to stay in touch
with the community as much as
possible um I got a bunch of bunch of
events that I'm about to be starting up
uh grow alongs competitions you know all
kinds of stuff like that so make sure to
follow it's going to be crazy
again thank you for having me awesome
I'll definitely have a link to your
YouTube channel down in the YouTube
description section below so people can
easily get to it want to give a big
thank you to the folks on patreon that
support this podcast directly thank you
so much the people being scrolled on the
screen right now in the producer tier so
you get producer credits appreciate your
support here and uh yeah we're going to
continue on this podcast I want to thank
you for coming on to the podcast uh I'm
actually going to be on your podcast
your show and and a couple weeks from
now so uh on the what is what do we have
the 31st New Year's Eve New Year's Eve
man we're going to start off the new
year New Year's Eve I'll be on your show
so keep an eye out for that appreciate
you so much for coming on to the podcast
today and hope you enjoy the rest of
your day you too brother thank you again
for having me it's been a huge honor no
problem man peace out everyone catch you
in the next episode