welcome to the Garden Talk podcast where
we interview Growers from all over the
world both beginners and experts seeking
to learn more about what they know about
gardening and how they do things in
their Garden hey what's up everybody for
those of you that don't know me my name
is Chris aka Mr Grow and you're tuned
into the garden Talk podcast this is
episode number 134 in this episode I
interview Mama Kush 420 she has been
gardening for 6 years and has big into
training plants in order to achieve a
higher quality and yield and that's what
we're going to talk about in today's
episode she talks about the pros and
cons of training plants details on how
she does several different plant
training methods and give some good
overall advice for beginners these
podcast episodes are cut up into short
clips and posted on the garden talk
Clips YouTube channel I also have a
channel where I show the plants that I
grow I'll link both of those channels
down in the YouTube description section
below one of my goals for this podcast
is to bring free information about
gardening to the general public that
being said i' like to thank the sponsors
of today's episode who helped make that
goal possible thanks to AC Infinity for
sponsoring this episode check out their
cloudray Gen 2 oity clip fan their nextg
clip fan has been re-engineered to
provide a longlasting motor and
customizable air flow for all stages of
your plant's growth cycle it features 10
speeds and 10 Dynamic win modes to
simulate outdoor air flow in links with
uis controllers for Wi-Fi app control
click the link in the description
section below so you can learn more
about their cloud R clip fans and the
discount code Mr Gro 15 works on both
Amazon and the website AC infinity.com
stash blend stash blend is a 215 plant
additive that can be used with synthetic
bottle nutrients or in living soil
systems simply mix half teaspoon of
stash blend into a gallon of water then
water your plants with it ingredients
include corn steep liquor seawed extract
humic acid beneficial bacteria silica
and micro risal fungi check Che out at
stash blend.com Link in the description
section below and use the discount code
the stash Mars Hydro check out their
updated FC and fce series of LED grow
lights they have grow lights for several
different size grow spaces and all grow
lights in those series now have the
Samsung LM 301h diodes you also notice a
new foldable design with their larger
fixtures there is an optional Smart
Control Function where you can plug in
the I connect smart controller and
control the GR through their app go to
their website mars-hydro
docomo to save on any of their products
and we're back and I'm joined with Mama
Kush how you doing today oh fabulous
thank you so much for having me this is
amazing yeah thanks for coming on I'm
excited to have you on today to talk all
about plant training and a Hot Topic a
lot of people do plant training there
are several different ways to go about
it several different styles of plan
training and we're going to get into the
different styles in this episode and
find out how you go about plan training
so really excited for this but first can
you tell us a little bit about yourself
and how you got into gardening oh
absolutely uh thanks again for having me
my name is Mama Kush 420 Mama Kush um I
am part of the homeg grow Community crew
over on YouTube and
Instagram and uh I've been growing
plants for about 6 years now don't have
a green thumb at all everything that I
do I have diligently learned from the
YouTube gurus such as Chris
here uh so this is something that uh I
never thought I would be able to do but
with hard work and dedication I've
learned how to grow and I've learned how
much joy that these plants can give to
you awesome and what would you say your
grow style is are you indoors Outdoors
are you in soil cocoa Hydro are you
synthetic organic what's your style well
I'm doing a little bit of everything
right now actually it's it's really fun
right now in the garden uh so I am
mainly indoors but I am from Canada and
we are allowed for recreational plants
so those are my outdoor girls so I have
my medical Garden indoors and then my uh
Freedom Four as we like to call it here
uh those are my Outdoors so I've just
recently put them out in the in the m
long weekend is when it's safe for us to
put them
outside and I am mainly an organic
grower uh but currently I am using an EB
and flow system that I am loving it and
I'm so I'm dipping my toes into that
little bit of a I I think it I call it
like a like baby Hydro it's like Hydro
but not really Hydro because it's just
you know it just soaks and and drains
soaks and drains so it's like to me it's
not like I'm a chemist so I I'm I'm
really excited about that and um and
that's first time running synthetic uh
nutrients as well so that's that's been
a big learning curve for me so right now
a little bit of both but mainly indoor
and organic awesome and for the record
that is a real background I had asked
her before we hit the record button
unbelievable beautiful beautiful
background I am so so jealous of that
thank you actually my outdoor girls are
going to be watered with lake water all
summer so um I'm just going to go down
the stairs to the beach and grab a scoop
of Lake water and uh get all the good
microbes from from the natural lake and
that's what my outdoor girls are being
fed this year that's so cool and for
those listening in on podcast platforms
can't see this she's right on a lake and
there's a bunch of greenery there and I
know you're from Canada and it's just
I'm just jealous that's all I got to say
about that one it's beautiful it really
is
thank you we it is definitely our little
piece of heaven here so let's get into
plant training I figured we'd start with
kind of the basics you know what are the
benefits of training
plants I I I feel the benefits are one
it's so fun oh my goodness that's like
the main benefit right there it's just
so fun to play with the plants um but it
it adds structure to each of the
branches so uh later on um they can hold
up their own weight
and the
more girth girthier the the branch the
easier it will be later on in flow to
hold up its own weight I don't like
putting trellis Nets and and that sort
of stuff over my colas it's just too
fussy and it just it makes me mad I just
get frustrated so I like to train them
early and get them nice and strong so
they can hold up their weight later on
awesome yeah there are definitely some
really good benefits to training plants
you know one of the things that I
particularly like is that it helps with
the distribution of light in a sense
right because if you are in a grow tent
for example and you just letting the
plants grow naturally Christmas tree
style you typically have that one Cola
that just kind of comes up and dominates
well those lower branches aren't going
to receive as much light right and so I
know it's genetic dependent and stuff
like that but you could see kind of
lower quality on the lower buds but you
know a lot of genetics these days it's
it ends up being just fine but if you're
training and you have you're training
the plants you're manipulating the
plants so they are even canopy across
the entire grow space well then you've
got that light shining down and there
have actually been some studies where
you can get a higher yield from training
versus not training so that's I think
that's another reason why a lot of
people do it but there are always
downsides to things as well right what
are the downsides to plant
training oh breaking a branch there's
nothing worse than just being a little
too rough with that and and breaking a
branch and you know I'm such a good
Canadian I was oh sorry my little girls
I always always feel so bad and I I run
out and get my painters tape and I try
to save them as much as I can and you
know um but if you can't save it you've
always got yourself a nice clone if
you're not running an auto flower if
you're running if you're running uh a a
a a proper girl that you you could just
cloner and so there's really
no downsides other than you might get an
extra clone out of
it I would say one downside I've got one
in mind which is that it's just it's a
little bit more work right you getting
in there spending the time to do
whatever type of training you decide to
do we're going to go over the different
training types here in this episode but
anything from just tying the branches
down to high stress train techniques
where you're topping the plant actually
removing some things it takes a little
bit of time right now that's not to say
that the reward isn't going to be better
cuz it it certainly can be so yeah
that's the only thing I can really think
of as far as like a a downside to plant
training yeah see I don't consider that
being a downside because that's time I
get to spend with my girls that's part
of the fun part right like that's just
you know I get to tune out the world and
I'm I'm just that's I'm just in tune
with with my girls in the tent and
taking care of business in there so yeah
that's probably why that didn't come to
me I didn't I don't think of that as a
downside so that's that's one of the
perks great Point great Point yeah I
know there are a lot of people who are
are you know they monitor the amount of
time they're in there and they try to
reduce the time that they're in there a
lot of people have real automated
systems now to where they don't only
have to check in their plants once a day
if that and they're in there for a very
short period of time so yeah there are
some people who really just try to limit
the time in their Garden so they can do
other things or there are people that
really love the garden and they want to
spend more time in there so really
depends on how you are as a person
exactly and and training's not necessary
so if you don't have the time to get in
there that's fine you know if you do
it's wonderful and so rewarding great
Point yeah it is a completely optional
to do all this stuff you can let the
plant grow naturally Christmas tree
style whatever and get to a harvest I
know that's uh back when I first started
growing I didn't want to do any training
I was afraid to top the plant CU I just
like oh no I want this to be successful
I don't want to destroy the plant right
so like I let I've had several Grows
Where I just let the plants grow
naturally but you know as you get more
comfortable growing and more confident
you uh tend to manipulate the planet a
little bit more and more and see what
they can take and you can be really
rough with them for sure I find you just
one good training session you know if
you don't have a lot of time if you're
just about to flip you know maybe the
week before a flip just give it one good
training session and I mean that's
wonderful as well you don't have to be
in there every day uh moving this leaf
and moving that leaf you can go in and
just give her one good training session
and it's you'll still see benefits
completely agree yeah you can definitely
go about it that way you can definitely
be very efficient when it comes to
training as well by kind of planning and
stuff and and knowing exactly what
you're going to do and stuff like that
so so when do you start training plants
and when do you stop training plants so
I like to start actually quite quite
young uh as soon as I see that their the
true leaves have come in and they've got
a little little bit of um meat on their
bones let's say you know they're not
they're not the baby baby seedlings if
you can tell that they're they're
starting to grow then I I like to just
bend bend them over just slightly just
you know just enough
to give them a little a little crooked
and then they bounce back from that and
then the next day I'll come in and and
I'll bend them the other way the other
direction and then they'll bounce back
and then once I start seeing uh a couple
of nodes starting to show up then I'll
get a little bit more dramatic and I
actually start when their seedlings I'll
just go in and take my tip of my finger
and just give them a little a little
flick sometimes just to kind of wake
them up and stimulate them and let them
know hey come on it's time it's time to
get going here we got uh we got some
growing to
do a train early train often that's a
motto that a lot of people go by I
personally I think I usually wait till
like the third node then I'm doing
something you know I'm either doing a
Bend or I am doing some a topping but
yeah as far as the bending I mean just
manipulating that way that's really low
stress training is there any other type
of like low stress training you do are
you TI like when the plates gets bigger
are you tying branches down to the side
of the grow pot or anything or how do
you go about like low stress training
throughout the grow cycle so once once
the girls have have uh say reached about
the third node that's when I start
getting a little bit more aggressive so
I will start bending them over a little
bit more dramatically and then once I
see that they're bouncing back uh fairly
quickly I'll actually start introducing
Bud clips into the mix so as soon as the
uh the stock is um sturdy enough that I
can bend the top over and it can take
the weight of the bud Clips um they uh
they get it right from right from the
get-go so then I'll bend them over so
they'll now be at um at a at a certain
angle and the top will raise up then as
they grow out I will add an additional
Bud clip until they reach the edge of
the pot and uh this is something I've
added into my garden over the last
couple of years and I'll never turn back
I used to I used to uh use paper clips
and garden ties and and all sorts of
things this has made it so simple these
clips and the weight of the clips
actually helps stimulate the growth of
the the plant as well because there's
something heavy when they're when
they're small of course when they're
small um but as they as they get
stronger and they get more Vi vigorous
uh you can add more and it's just so
much fun to add all these clips in and
then when you when they've grown into
them and you you almost make like a
staircase with your branches and so you
start from the center and you make these
staircases all the way out to the edge
of your pots and when you remove the
clips it is the most amazing sight to
see those legs once they're all cleaned
up they have those that I call it like
the staircase to Heaven I just love it
that's so cool you know I actually
haven't used any of those particular
style of Clips I see a lot of people
using them I've always wondered how well
they actually helped train the plants
how many are you actually using per run
uh it it it really depends on on the
cultivar uh but at least probably about
five or six at the minimum uh cuz what I
like to do is spread it out from the
center and spread it out and these uh
these clips are in such a a wonderful
angle that they don't stress the plant
out they don't um over hyperextend it I
guess the word would be um so they are
like
ergonomically correct um but you can you
can add as many or as little as you want
if you just want to bend the top over
and not have to go in and fuss and mus
with the with the rest of the plant you
can just do the one uh I like to add
lots and just get those girls as spread
out as I possibly can and then
eventually they stay there you only need
to have those clips on for for a week or
so and then the plant has been trained
to go in that direction then you can
move them around and you can play with
the different branches and and really
maximize your canopy I was going to ask
if you leave the clips on does the stock
end up does the branch end up like
growing into the clips and kind of get
stuck or what um actually that's the
beauty of these clips so we're we forget
you know we you you forget these things
inside the inside the plant they are
actually meant to break before they hurt
your plant so if you put it on the stock
and you put it down at the bottom and
you completely forget they will actually
it's it's a safety mechanism they will
break before they hurt your plant now
your plant is is very um Adept to
growing around things and and sometimes
you'll you'll see that the the the stock
is like growing melding into it and it's
now become part of the plant but it will
never hurt your plant because they will
break they will snap in half now I've
never had that happen that's my goal I
want to get I want to get this
thing so big that I want them snapping I
want to test this
haven't had it happen yet but they are
they are very safe and that is a
wonderful safety mechanism in them and
um they are uh very well thought out
it's a very well thought out product for
those just listening she was holding up
the bud Clips by Bud trainer so I'm
familiar with that brand I'm actually
I'm thinking about picking them up I'm
looking at on Amazon right now 20 bucks
for a 20 pack so not too bad I mean you
get you reuse them over and over again
as long as they don't break like you
mentioned but uh you reuse them over
over again per gross so think I might
pick some up and try it out and you can
actually throw them in the dishwasher as
well I have um from when my my children
were small I have a a small basket that
we used to use for their bottles and uh
I just put them all in the basket and
run it through my dishwasher and then
they're clean and sanitized and ready to
go for the next time so don't ever throw
don't overthrow ever throw those little
baskets away because they're
wonderful easy to clean I like it yep
have you you ever heard of the no
technique plant
training no this is just fascinating I
don't I please I heard about this and
I've talked about it on our podcast
before I actually had uh I think it was
pigeons 420 I had on a podcast and we
talked about plant training because he's
he's big into it and uh I don't think he
knew what it was either but if you
search on Google you'll find no
technique plant training which is
basically all it is is just one Bend so
you're letting the plant grow to a
certain point bending it down 90° and
then that's it you're not doing any
other training beyond that and the
thought is that the other branches that
come up you're going to have a whole
bunch of branches kind of coming up and
that they should be even uh but it's an
easy way to do training if you're kind
of looking to ease your way into it
right you don't want to do a whole bunch
of different things you just want to try
one thing no technique plant training
you might want to try that so fig to
mention it oh that see that's the bud
Clips would be perfect for that you put
one clip in and you're done there we go
you don't even need the 20 pack you just
need
one how about Leaf tucking that's
another sort of training that people do
throughout the grow really is tucking
leaves down and that allows light to get
kind of get down into the canopy more do
you do any Leaf tucking at all if so at
what point in the grow do you usually do
it uh I like to do leaf tucking actually
uh during flow so uh when I prep the
girls to go into flour they get a good
defoliation I I clean everything up but
then as those leaves come back within
the next 3 weeks during that that burst
of growth uh I will tuck leaves because
those are the solar panels you don't
want to you don't want to strip all of
the leaves so I will tuck them to to um
make sure that the flower sites are
exposed okay yeah that's typically when
I'm doing it as well although I have
found value in doing it in veg sometimes
like after I topped a plant and I've got
those two branches kind of growing up
those two top branches I've actually
used leaves to kind of that are
underneath the branches directly bring
them up over the branch and kind of tuck
it so the whole branch is kind of being
tucked down with that pedal from the
leaf below it don't know if everybody
caught that visual if everybody was able
to visually understand what I was
talking about there but that's I think
the easiest way I kind of kind of
explain it that's been helpful
particularly trying to get some of the
lower branches to grow up so after
topping is done keeping those top
branches manageable and allowing the
lowers to catch up other than that yeah
flowering as well is we're just in
flowering just kind of tucking leaves
down underneath Bud s sites and stuff
and trying to get light down into the
canopy so it's helpful so we mentioned
topping a couple times and really that's
just cutting off the top of the plant or
the top of a branch of the plant you can
do it several different ways I usually
start either the third fourth or fifth
node I'll do my first topping and then
it helps the lower branches kind of grow
up oftentimes I do a second top as well
the the the branches that come out from
the first topping top those again and
then uh helps them more and you can
continue to do that I've topped cheese
to where I had 32 different colas kind
of coming up and in my opinion that was
a little bit of an Overkill I don't
think I'll ever do that much growing
indoors in particular um you know I like
to stick at eight or 16 tops is my
personal preference do you do topping at
all if so when do you usually do topping
I have talked in the past uh I'm I'm
more into I've lean more into the low
stress training now um as opposed to
topping but I'm not opposed to it at all
sometimes I will be low stress training
and then oops there goes the top so I
guess we've topped
it it happens um but uh but I I I don't
focus on the topping as much as the the
low stress training uh I just found that
the the results were almost better
without the high stress early on got it
yeah and it's you know it's so debatable
some people like oh well if you're
topping you're doing high stress and
you're slowing the growth of the plant
kind of debatable to how much it's
actually slowing down and yeah you can
totally get away with just doing the low
stress training without doing any
topping throughout the whole grow so a
lot of people do it that way and uh yeah
at that point you're not really slowing
down the plant grow grow at all huh so I
take it since you haven't really played
around with topping much fing is another
thing you probably don't have much
experience with or or what I I have done
it uh when I was when I was learning I
tried everything and you know it's
that's what you do when you're when
you're learning you try a little bit of
everything to see what uh what's your
style and how you would like to to have
your garden R run but I have tried
fimming before and I don't know the
leaves weren't pretty it didn't look
nice it just it l it looked messy to me
and I did I didn't like it and I didn't
really see much more of a a benefit I
would rather I would rather top than fim
just for aesthetic reasons
only I hear you yeah I've done it
accidentally numerous times countless
number of times and really for those
folks that aren't too familiar with what
fimming is really it's it's kind of like
a topping but you top at the wrong spot
you top a little bit too high and
instead of it splitting in into two
branches it can go into three it can go
into four so you go more than just the
two and I've had multiple times where I
just got three branches out of it which
I was like oh that's pretty cool I
thought it was always going to be four
nope it can actually just split out into
three different branches and the story
behind it is actually uh wrong in a
sense to where a lot of people say
that's a story behind fimming is that
some guy tried to top and he missed and
he's like F I missed insert the swear
word there but F I missed and then so
that's where fim came from but I
actually recently learned from Kyle
kushman that uh he had mentioned in the
podcast episode I did with him that that
actually isn't the case it was really
somebody who submitted a question into
High Times and they signed their name
fim and so uh yeah that's it's kind of
funny to see how that story was just
randomly created and now it's that's not
actually it but uh yeah he he would tell
more details on it if you guys want to
warp back to the episode I did with him
there's time stamps on every episode so
you should be able to click right into
when we talk about fing and you can hear
the story behind it uh because I
definitely didn't didn't say it properly
I probably butchered it a little bit but
for the most part yeah apparently
somebody signed the name f it wasn't
actually F I missed wow you know the
that's how these urban legends are are
created you know like the the whole myth
about how 420 was created and there's so
many different
different you know versions of the story
I'm sure we've heard them all you know
so I mean how do you know which one's
right you don't right you just got
assume let's move on to super cropping
so is that something you do at all or no
oh yes oh yes I love my super cropping
that you're talking about Kyle kushman
uh I do the kushman Chiropractic it is
something
I that snap that pop that you hear I
just
it brings me so much
joy yeah so I like to I like to Super
crop as soon as it's I I like to do it
uh right before I'm about ready to go
into flour maybe about a week or so uh
when when the plant has the structure
and is ready you know I'm like okay I
know I'm you're ready to go I'll get in
there and I'll start from the very
bottom and I'll pinch the branch uh with
one hand on each side and I'll give it a
little twist so it's like you he he he
says it's like um like the Chiropractic
like you're you're popping the spine and
I'll do that to each and every branch
and I'll start right at the very bottom
and I'll go all the way right up to the
very tippy tippy top
and the I the only caveat I would
suggest is don't water right before
you're about to do that cuz you can snap
off a branch a little bit uh easier if
there's a lot of water inside your
plants if they just
had a nice big drink and you give it a a
pop the pop is a little bit more
satisfying but you you run the risk of
breaking a branch a little bit more
somebody's got to do like an ASMR video
with just the cracks that are happening
from the cop that' be funny oh my
goodness if you've never if you've never
experienced it before just do yourself
one one favor and just do that one
little twist one hand on each side of
the branch and just give it a little
twist not much just enough to hear that
pop and oh so satisfying so you only
doing like a pop is it still like the
branch still kind of Sting up straight
or are you like manipulating enough to
where it's a flopping
over um at this point I've done all of
my training uh to where my plant is
exactly where I want it to be so I don't
I don't usually do a super crop to the
point where I'm flopping the branches
over unless I need to um but usually all
of my training is done three going into
this stage um so the the the plant is a
beautiful Globe shape and I'm just
popping those branches to make sure that
they she's got those Knuckles to to be
able to hold up the weight later on
that's exactly what I heard from other
people I think it was pigeons 420 who
mentioned he does the same exact thing
to where every single branch in order to
try to strengthen up the branches so
that way when they're flowering they're
able to hold up those big fat buds a lot
easier than if you didn't do it so it's
something that I haven't done on every
single Branch before maybe one grow I
will do just for fun maybe it's content
right I use super cropping a little bit
differently and that's really only in
flour I use it just in the first three
weeks of stretch right so the plan is
still stretching upward now if I'm not
able to do low stress training because
I'm still trying to maintain that can
even canopy and so those first 3 weeks
of flower and the lead cyos changed
plants are still stretching the heights
are changing right for each of the
branches so if I can't bend them all
down and keep them even well sometimes
those Center branches those are ones I
can't really just pull down with the low
stress train so what I'll do is I'll do
a super crop let that let those branches
flop over and then the the outer
branches really will will continue to
grow up and then it will kind of be even
the goal is really to have it even by
the end of the stretch phase so that's
really the only way I use super cropping
myself and that's the goal out of all of
this training is to get that even canopy
to get the maximum light available and
the maximum we can from the plants yeah
and it could be so helpful for sure
let's move on to lollipopping now Lolly
popping is categorized into the training
area right people say oh well it's
actually pruning it's a pruning
technique it's not a train technique
well okay let's just include in the
conversation whatever way you think
about it let's include it let's talk
about lollipopping so what is
lollipopping and do you do it at all oh
I love a clean leg oh I love a clean
leg so lollipopping is taking the uh the
foliage from the bottom of the bottom of
the plant all the way up to the canopy
to where you would like your canopy to
begin and uh it's to help maximize the
air flow
inside um I I always I always always
tease on our on our shows that uh that I
I it's Friday night get your get your
legs shaved because uh that's another
term for it is shaving up the legs
shaving up the girls uh to have that
bottom area nice and clean and there's
you you it helps with pests it helps
with airflow so so much it's just a
clean nice clean area and when do you
typically do it uh throughout the life
actually as as much as I can I will try
and keep those that Center area as clean
as possible but right before flower in
that in that week or so right before
flower is when I just strip those girls
right up and uh give them a real good
training session and and really that's
the that's the key is right before about
a week before flower is to get all of
this done so then the plant has time to
recover before it has to start focusing
on creating those big beautiful buds
that we all want yeah I'm the same way
I'll do it right before flipping the
flower often times really during stretch
phase the first three weeks there still
can be some growth down there so I'm
usually going in around you know day 14
to 20 something like that to where I'm
doing another strip of the lowers and
it's not as much right I've done the
bulk of the work before flipping the
flower but there is a little bit of
cleanup that can still happen and then
as the plants continue on from there
into flowering you can get little buds
that kind of form down on the lowers and
I'm usually plucking those off as well
and um yeah so I'm just like you we kind
of doing a little bit throughout the
whole cycle really yeah it's I I find
it's just maintenance if I'm in there
and I'm I'm seeing a a spot that needs
to be clean up just take care of it now
it just saves you work later on and then
that energy is being focused to where we
want it it's not where you know when
nobody wants to trim the lar right so
you know you get rid of it just get get
those big beautiful flowers and I mean
that's the goal we that's that's what we
want
yeah it definitely helps with the upper
growth that's for sure and yeah all the
lar just ends up in my trim pile these
days I don't I don't trim that anymore I
used to but uh my standards have gotten
a little bit higher since then so ends
up my trim pile or you know I could end
up in a compost pile as well so either
or another thing that's kind of looped
into a training category but some people
say hey no it's Bruning is defoliation
right what is defoliation and when do
you go about doing it oh defoliation is
just getting rid of those uh big fan
leaves that are covering up what you are
trying to grow you know you you you want
to keep like I said earlier try and keep
a clean a clean space and get that air
flow and uh if you have too many leaves
on top of each other you can get micro
clients and get clients climates excuse
me and um moisture and then you're
you're opening yourself up to problems
at that point so just to keep that air
flow is to defoliate to get rid of the
um the leaves that are going to be a
problem later on um I like to defoliate
again that that right before flower
that's I I give them a a really big
stripping but I'm actually doing it
throughout the whole grow I'm trying to
prevent those microclimates from showing
up and um you know I've never I've never
had an issue with powdery mildew thank
goodness but uh that's something I
because I live in a lake um
there's a lot of moisture in the air and
uh we have a lot of foliage there's a
lot of green in the air so it's
something I try to prevent as much as
possible and defoliating uh keeping a
clean airflow canopy is is the way to do
it I'm just like you yeah late veg
really before flipping to flower I'm
doing pretty heavy defoliation and then
I do that flip and then within the first
three weeks that stretch period foliage
is still continuing to grow so often
times I am pling off leaves looking to
pluck them off day 7 14 21 those are
roughly the days where I typically am
just looking at the plant saying hey is
there anything that needs to be removed
at this point try to make sure there's
air flow going through the canopy making
sure there's not if there's stagnant
spots within the canopy that's a good
area for pest to congregate right it's
like y there's no we don't leave room
for those pests to party there's no
partying in our
tents and then sometimes what I'll do is
and it it's genetic dependent right cuz
some strains are going to be more
bushier than others so sometimes I might
they like 45 in flower and I'm like you
know what I can pluck off some leaves at
this point and get some light to come
more down into the canopy to touch some
of those Bud sights there so that's kind
of how I personally go about defoliation
pretty similar to you yeah I like to go
from the top as well uh a lot of people
look from the the bottom up but
sometimes if you just put your head over
top of the canopy and just pretend
you're like the light looking down and
think okay where can I get where can I
get some some area and it could just be
one or two leaves that's all you need
and you've just maximized your growth
yep absolutely how about the scrog
technique have you ever done that before
I've tried but it's so
frustrating I I like I like to move my
plants around and and to be able to
shift things around
and and to have things stuck in one spot
it's it's a little difficult for me I I
I I have tried but it's just not my it's
just not my thing I just nope I can't do
it yeah it's it can have its own unique
challenges that is for sure uh for those
folks that don't know what scrug is it's
basically just putting a net into your
grow space flat across your grow space
and then training your plants within
that net and some people will weave
branches in and out of the net other
would just tuck under the net entirely
keep tucking keep tucking all the way
into flower some people stop doing the
tucking at like day seven a flow some
people stop that day 14 of flour so
there's it's really subjective on when
you stop talking but after that you just
get the upwards growth and the idea is
that you filled up that net entirely
kind of maximizing the growth space and
you're resulting really in an even
canopy yeah it's something I've tried a
couple times in the past I'm just I'm
not a yield guy anymore you know when I
first started growing sure I was going
for yield and measuring things out and
and trying to get higher and higher
yield but I'm just growing for myself
now I mean I have friends and family
that come into town so I don't really
need yield I can just get what I'm
looking for just GR in the plants with
regular training other other types of
training I should say and so um it's
something I kind of shied away for
although there are definitely several
good benefits one of the main ones being
is a higher yield doing the scrug
techniqu so yeah there's a different way
to go about it and that's the beauty is
each person um you know has their own
way of gardening I mean Troy kills it
Northern scroger kills it with the
scrags you know that's his thing that's
you
know it's that's what works for him and
I'm sure he's tried other methods to
find what works for him so each person
that's why that's it's so wonderful that
we have such a an amazing Community
right now that we can talk about all our
different methods so you can can find
what works for you you know and you can
take a little piece from here and a
little piece from there and and build
your own it's oh just amazing that we
have this platform yeah it's so
beneficial to be able to see all the
different ways to do it and and kind of
picking and choosing what you want to
implement in your own garden and and a
big shout out to Troy Northern scroger I
mean he is really we can consider him an
expert at this point at the scrog
technique he he literally has a show
called scrog school he's teaching step
byep how to do the scrog technique so if
anybody's interested in that and happen
to not know who Troy is or no than
scroger just search for him on YouTube
you'll come up with the scrog school and
um it's really really detailed class on
how to scrog and he is a really really
great result and even if even if you
don't are not interested in scrogging he
has a way of teaching about the plant
that is just so captivating it's you
know it just if you're not interested
scrogging even just learn learn from him
about the plant it's just bow down to
try so yeah scrog technique s c o stands
for screen of green there's also sogg s
OG SE of green have you ever done that
method before I have in the past and
that's that's a lot of fun uh you just
take a a bunch of small plants and you
fill up as much as the canopy as
possible you have to be careful with
that one though because sometimes you
know they start off little you forget
that they can double or triple in flower
so you have to make sure you leave
enough room room to groove in there so I
believe the uh the rule of thumb is 50%
so you cover 50% in uh your veg plants
so then your your floor space in veg
plants so then by the time that they
grow and they they Bloom they will be
100% in your in your canopy and uh I
find it's a lot of work I like to I like
to grow big plants myself but I have
tried it before for fun and uh you can
get a lot of flavors in one small tent
that's a method that I actually haven't
tried out should put it on my bucket
list to try out in the future though
that's for sure it's super interesting
to me I mean it it just seems like such
a cool technique does seem like a lot of
work if you're handw watering but if
you're doing like an EB and flow system
like you've got I'm sure it makes things
a lot easier and um I think you get the
best result if you're do it from clone
right because they're all kind of the
same you know coming from the same
mother plant and you should see similar
growth across all the plants versus if
you're growing from seed or even
different cultivars it could kind of
make things uneven as far as your canopy
so often times it's genuinely
recommended to be from clone all the
same across the board another thing I
want to ask about actually is lighting
now uh how does this relate to training
well some folks say that they reduce the
amount of lighting when they're doing
some of these training methods whether
it be high stress training or low stress
training they they're reducing it a
little bit because they don't they want
the plants to kind of recover from the
training do you feel like the light
output should be kind of lowered or or
changed at all while you're doing plant
training I don't adjust my lighting for
the training um unless I can see my if
my girls are stressed and they are not
bouncing back from the training then I
will adjust the lighting and I'll give
them a cloudy day I'll I'll I'll lower
that lighting and and give them but you
know the sun doesn't the sun doesn't uh
stop shining because the wind is blowing
right these these girls have got
to if they're in my garden they better
stand up
so you know if you're not strong you're
out it's like Spartan
here yeah so the only time I would
adjust the lighting for training is if I
saw I I went too hard and they were not
bouncing back so then I will lower the
lighting a little bit and give them a
cloudy day and until I see that that
they're get get their footing again and
then bring them back up again got it now
what about the temperature and humidity
are you doing anything differently in
the environments where you're training
plants versus not training plants or no
no everything's I I just keep everything
um I have everything all dialed in it
just stays there I don't I once I have
it dialed in I don't like to fuss and M
with things because that's when problems
happen you know you you'll adjust
something and then do something else and
then you you can't figure out where what
happened and and where the problem arise
so I try and keep everything as simple
as possible and uh so everything just
stays the same and I I adjust the
humidity and stuff for flour and vet
that's the only two times I change what
do you typically aim for for temperature
and humidity throughout the grow cycle
uh during a veg I like to keep it at
about um 80 75 to 80% humidity um I'm
going to talk in uh Celsius because I am
Canadian so I don't know what the
conversion is but I like to keep it
around uh 26 to
27° in the in the
tent uh so not not too hot but nice a
nice summer day I like to keep it a nice
summer day nice balmy spring summer
day and then for flower I I keep the
same temperature and then I bring my
humidity down to about 50% got it and
doing the conversion here you said 26
which is 78.8 De and then 27° C is 80.6
De according to google conversion here
so for those that are in
Fahrenheit awesome so I'm trying to
think are there any other plant training
methods that we didn't talk about that
you'd like to
discuss well I do like to do one thing
um to my girls that uh is not very
typical but I like to take a leaf blower
to my girls and I have an indoor Leaf
well it's not an indoor it's an outdoor
leaf blower but I have it indoors I in
in my setup and I take the leaf blower
and I actually have this part of my IPM
it's part of my IPM and it's part
training both I will take my leaf blower
and I will blow the tent and these girls
are swaying and moving and it's like a
like a hurricane in the in the tent and
uh the girls always respond with a thank
you the next day they are stronger they
are healthier they
are you know praying to the light Gods
uh but I'll do that and then I'll sprad
with IPM so if there's anything sitting
on those leaves they're getting blown
right off and then I spray I'll fog the
tent and zip it up and then I never have
a problem it's so fun you just see them
swaying in the
wind that's wild what age like how long
has a plant been growing for oh they're
they're usually in a good veg like they
are good six weeks in they've got some
good roots on them they're strong
they're healthy they've been able to
take my abuse up until then and then
it's like all right let's see how far we
can take you and then and they always
thank me they just absolutely love it
okay yeah I wasn't sure if you were
doing it for seedlings it' be blowing
seedlings right out of the
medium I'm aggressive I'm not
mean that's funny I never heard of
anybody doing that before do you have a
video of that by chance maybe on your
Instagram or something or what I do
actually on my on my Instagram yeah I
have that uh I have it actually posted
it's I've got it um pinned pinned is the
word yeah I've got it pinned to the top
of my reels on mamush 420 on Instagram
all right mamush 420 on Instagram I'm
gonna go on there and check out the
pinned one that's awesome what advice do
you have for beginners who are training
their plants for the first time don't be
afraid Don't Be Afraid these plants want
to grow and they have survived millennia
before we showed up so just don't be
afraid if uh if you're you're concerned
start slow start slow just start with a
slight Bend and see how and see how how
they respond but really these girls can
take a lot a lot a leafblower for
instance please don't be afraid just get
started and if you have questions
there's people out there that are
willing to help you along the way so
please don't be afraid to ask questions
or investigate or just try just get your
hands in there and try all right good
advice so let's uh let's wrap things up
here can you tell us how the listeners
can find you and what you have upcoming
in the future oh absolutely so uh thank
you uh so mam Kush 420 on Instagram is
my main page I have a backup page in
case Instagram decides to take me down
so that's mam Kush uh 2.0 is my backup
account I only have the one uh so if
anybody's trying to impersonate me I
only have the one backup account uh you
can reach me also at homow the community
official on Instagram we do a weekly
podcast on
Wednesdays uh over on YouTube homerow
the community and on Friday nights we do
a special uh groy Gardens where we get
to see The Gardens of the community they
can come on to the show and ask
questions and show their grow and come
and hang out we do a little campfire
afterwards where we can just sit and
hang out and just chat uh so that's
homerow the community on YouTube so we
we we're all over the
place sweet I'll definitely have a link
to mam kush's page down in the YouTube
description section below and if you're
tuning in on one of the podcast
platforms just search for you'll find
her mama Kush thank you so much for
coming on to the episode today to talk
about plan training it's been fun
conversation and yeah there are so many
different ways to go about this process
you really just got to try things out
and figure it out on your own see how
much your plant can take and take it
slow like she had mentioned anybody can
really have success to and plan training
as long as they uh give it a shot and be
patient with it thank you so much Chris
this has been
absolutely amazing I'm just my I'm
tingling right now I'm so excited thank
you I'm glad you enjoyed it okay I'll
let you go and uh yeah peace out
everyone catch you in the next episode